so hi everybody my name is Ellie and
today I'll be talking about Katina which
is an efficient verify non equivocation
scheme built on top of Bitcoin and
Katina is actually a very simple idea
but it has surprisingly powerful
applications like public key directories
so let me start by explaining the title
so what is this non equivocation thing
and to explain this or use a public key
directory as an example and this
directory every time period I would
publish a digest si of the directory and
that digest is simply a Merkel three
hash
so what non equivocation says is that at
every time period I the server only
publishes a single unique digest si so
for instance at time one Baba now let's
see the same directory s1 and when the
directory is updated at time Atlas and
Bob and others will see the same history
of digests s1 and s2 so this is good
because Allison Bob can monitor their
own public keys and detect impersonation
so in this case Alice checks she's okay
Bob checks he's okay and what this means
is that if a server wants to impersonate
Alice or Bob it has to do so in plain
sight so for instance here the server
inserted a fake key for Alice the trick
Bob into using it but because of non
equivocation Alice and Bob see the same
directory and Alice can detect this fake
key this is not to say that their
secrecy is preserved because Bob could
use that key anyway before Alice have a
chance to detect it and yell to the
world that she's been impersonated but
this is to say that such attacks don't
go undetected which is a step forward so
to summarize non equivocation just
simply means saying the same thing to
all of the people even if the thing
you're saying is incorrect at the
application layer like this statement 2
here where Alice was impersonated at
least we can detect such incorrect
statements now what is equivocation well
at time two the malicious server could
simply publish to digests s 2 and s 2
Prime so when s two Alice's key is left
intact but Bob is impersonated in s 2
Prime Bob's key is left intact but Alice
is impersonated
so when Alice checks in her view
everything seems fine her key is the
same however Bob is impersonated there
and Alice will use a fake
Keifer Bob when Bob checks in his view
everything seems fine but Alice
impersonated and Bob will use a fake key
for Alice so as a result and then in the
middle attack is possible and this is
kind of undetectable Alice and Bob don't
have a way to check that they are seeing
the same directory for that they would
need a secure Channel but that's what
they're using the public key directory
for in the first place to establish
that's with your channel so this is kind
of a bummer if you say different things
to different people in a public key
directory you can equivocate and you can
man in the middle your users so we'd
like to solve this and this comes up a
lot in public key distributions for HTTP
secure messaging and pretty much any
work that says we assume a PKI
and it also comes up in tor directory
servers which can equivocate to victims
about the set of onion relays and the
anonymize them and it comes up in
software transparency schemes where a
software vendor like Bitcoin itself
would like to make sure a no malicious
binaries and hits name have been
published
just like in public key distribution
Bitcoin needs to see the same
transparency log as all of the people
downloading Bitcoin so what are our
contributions so we built this Bitcoin
based append-only lured that is as hard
to forecast the Bitcoin blockchain but
importantly it's efficiently verifiable
you don't have to download full blocks
the verifier log in particular you will
need to download 600 bytes per statement
a statement is something like a Merkel
tree hash a publicly directory digest
and you only need to download 80 bytes
for a Bitcoin block you don't need to
download the whole block and we
implemented this in Java and our code is
open source so the outline for the talk
will be first let's go over Bitcoin and
explain how Bitcoin transactions work
and how Bitcoin preventible spends this
is super important to actually
understand how Catina works then I'll go
over previous work then I'll go over our
design and how to scale it okay so this
thing comes up a lot these days what is
this blockchain is just a hash chain of
blocks block and contains a hash of
block and minus 1 so each block has a
hash pointer to the previous block and
the arrows indicate hash pointers here
each block has a Merkle tree of
transactions and everybody agrees on
this hash chain of blocks the a
proof-of-work and
which I won't talk about too much but we
do assume that it works so attacks like
the one Maria described are problematic
and we do need to fix those in order for
our assumptions to be to be reasonable
so let's talk about Bitcoin transactions
they have two purposes the first purpose
is to just mint coins
so here transaction a says hey look ugly
key Alice Alice with public key Alice
minted for bitcoins and says that is it
has this thing called a transaction
output that little circle over there and
the output just specifies the number of
coins and who owns them and the second
purpose is to transfer these coins so
Alice might want to give three coins to
Bob and leave a fee to the Bitcoin
miners who managed this blockchain and
for that Alice would create this
transaction be with another output that
says bkb has three bitcoins so now the
question is how do how do we link this
transaction to the previous one we do
that via something called a transaction
input the transaction input has a hash
pointer the output being spent
so here transaction a is being referred
to by the input and transaction B and
more importantly transaction bees import
has a signature that authorizes the
transfers the transfer of coins from TX
A's output to TX P is output so
furthermore what you can do in Bitcoin
is you can embed data in transactions so
we actually leverage this to build a log
Alice can put up to 80 bytes in in that
transaction exp yeah so to summarize
here Alice gave Berkeley bitcoins
Bitcoin miners collected one Bitcoin at
a fee output specify coins and who only
those coins at the public key inputs
have hash pointers two outputs being
spent and specify a signature under that
outputs public key and this can keep
going Bob can give Carol his bitcoins he
can transfer to bitcoins to Carol pay
one Bitcoin to the Bitcoin miners and so
on and so forth and importantly what
Bitcoin actually guarantees is there
cannot be double spent so here for
example the way Bitcoin does that is by
maintaining this very simple invariant
it just says that a transaction output
can only be referred to by a single
transaction input so this picture right
here simply cannot happen in
you cannot have two different
transactions that have inputs pointing
to the same output Bitcoin doesn't allow
to do you do that Bitcoin miners prevent
that from happening so the moral of the
story here why did I tell you all of
this the reason I told you all this is
because I want you guys to look at this
picture and understand that either tx2
can be in the blockchain or txp Prime
but not both so when I first realize
this I thought this was really cool
because if we can put statements in
these transactions we can also
implicitly prevent equivocation so now
we can either have s2 or s3 Prime but
not both so this is the key idea behind
Catina and it's actually a very simple
realization so okay let's go over a
previous work now so the way previous
work builds a log on top of Bitcoin is
by just embedding statements and
transactions but they're kind of
unrestricted about how these
transactions relate to one another so as
a result if I want to be certain that
there's no s3 Prime and the blockchain I
can't do any better than downloading
full blocks to be sure that I haven't
missed the data stream prime I could ask
a Bitcoin tears appear not to filter the
block for me but that node My Luck or I
would be vulnerable to Sibyl attacks on
the Bitcoin peer-to-peer network where a
bunch of malicious nodes are created
that just lied to me so this is not not
not very good for efficiency so our work
simply requires that a new transaction
spends the previous one so the
simplicity tells us that there's there
cannot be an inconsistent statement
because it would require a double scrim
so basically the difference is quite
simple it's just this if I had one slide
for the presentation this would be it
okay so let's talk about the design in
more detail we have this thing called a
lock server so this can be the public
key directory that I talked about before
and it starts with some bitcoins and to
start the log it issues something called
the Genesis transaction of the log this
is the first transaction in the log and
it's basically the logs public key and
the way it does it is by just sending
coins from itself back to itself and
paying a fee in the process and now to
issue the first statement in the log it
creates TX 1 TX 1 has an input that
spends gtx
put coins are again being sent from the
server back to the server and because
tx1 spends gtx there cannot be an
inconsistent tx1 prime that commits a
statement s1 prime because that would
require a double spend and so on and so
forth if you want to issue the next
statement you create a tx2 that's n CX
on coins are being sent again from
server back to server
inconsistent statements cannot happen
without a double spend so what this
means is that if the server is
compromised it still cannot equivocate
so in particular here if the server
wants the issue two statements s3 and s3
prime it has to double spend the output
in pxq which Bitcoin miners prevent so
this is nice because it's hard to fork
as the Bitcoin blockchain to double
spend in Bitcoin the best you can hope
to do is for the blockchain but it's
efficient to verify and I'll talk about
that in a second the disadvantages
however are that before we can accept a
steal for example we need to wait for
six more blocks that we built on top of
block n and this is just a heuristic and
practice you might actually want to do
more so that that amounts around an hour
delay before you can accept the
statement and the other thing is that
you can only issue a statement every ten
minutes this is because it doesn't make
sense to issue two statements in a block
you might as well just merge them into a
single statement and Bitcoin blocks are
published every ten minutes and we have
to pay Bitcoin transaction fees to do
this and when we go to paper the fees
were low I think they were around 12
cents I think now however they're more
like 70 cents Bitcoin went up so let's
talk about how clients verify this log
so suppose I have a mobile phone that is
a let's say a messaging app like
whatsapp and I have this lock server
that is what tasks public key directory
server and I have the Bitcoin
peer-to-peer network which stores the
blockchain and it has around 7,000 nodes
in order to audit the log I need to have
the logs Genesis transaction so this is
important to understand this is the
public key of the log I can only prevent
equivocation with respect to a log and I
need to identify a log with a Genesis
transaction so once I have that I need
to get it from a trusted source I ensure
that all the statements I get are linear
history of statements so the way I do
that is I asked
Bitcoin peer-to-peer network hey what
are the next block headers I get back
the headers there 80 bytes each I verify
the proof of work then I ask the log
server hey what's the first statement in
the log this guy tells me hey look it's
the x1 it has the statement 1 in it
here's a muckle proof and this whole
thing is just 600 bytes I check that tx1
spent GTX I check that tx1 is in the
Bitcoin blockchain by verifying the
miracle proof and I keep doing this I
ask for four new block headers I ask for
the next statement I verified that the
transaction spent the previous one I
verify that the transaction is part of
the Bitcoin blockchain and as a result I
get non equivocation if I wait for
sufficient Bitcoin blocks on top of
block and here for example so this is
great because we only need to download
very little data in particular with the
current size of the Bitcoin blockchain
if we had 10,000 statements in a log we
were only bound with 41 megabytes which
is an improvement over previous work
which kind of requires you to download
full blocks to be really certain you're
not being equivocated - okay so let's
talk about scalability so this is kind
of a problem because the Bitcoin
peer-to-peer network only has 7,000 full
nodes and each node has around 117
connections I believe and that amounts
to around eight hundred and nineteen
thousand incoming connections that this
network supports so if we had a bunch of
Catina clients for a public key
directory for a popular app like what's
app and each client opens up around 8
connections to this network we kind of
unintentionally DDoS Bitcoin and
obviously we don't want to do that so so
to fix this problem we introduce this
thing called the hello relay network and
this is just a way to scale up to the
Bitcoin core due to peer networks
capacity for incoming connections and
the setter relay network just download
the block letters from the Bitcoin
peer-to-peer network and allows Catina
clients to fetch those block headers so
now or the Catena clients can connect to
this network and request block headers
and we can implement this in a bunch of
ways with volunteer nodes with existing
blockchain explorers like blockchain
that info with Facebook feeds Twitter
feeds
github feeds and so on and so forth
there's actually one implementation in
etherium that
that serves Bitcoin headers we had the
etherion watching and there's a bunch of
way to building this and importantly if
someone hacks the setter relay Network
it doesn't by itself allow him to
equivocate the attacker still needs to
take advantage of an accidental fork in
this point or the attacker still needs
to adversarially mine however if the
attacker does have control of this
network adversely mining attacks can be
somewhat easier but the same thing is
true for an attacker who would control
the Bitcoin peer-to-peer network so in
that sense we hope that we haven't
introduced too much bigger assumption
than the Bitcoin peer-to-peer network
this is really just an extension of it
yeah so to conclude what we did here is
we enabled applications to officially
leverage bitcoins publicly verifiable
consensus so clients only need to
download transactions selectively rather
than the full blockchain this amounts to
downloading 41 megabytes for a small log
rather than gigabytes and why I think
this matters is because we can hopefully
build better public key directories with
this we can maybe secure things like
certificate transparency against
equivocation we can build pork
intestines transparency on top of them
on top of this we can definitely build
software transparency schemes very
easily with the Catena log and in
general we can take any fork consistent
system and give it full consistencies of
things like sundar sporks integrity so
on and so forth and yeah for more please
read our paper and I'll leave you with
this picture of previous work in our
system and our coders at that edges
[Applause]
hi Christina in territorial Northeastern
University so it seems that what you
really need is this abstraction of
system like digital currencies and the
double spending Bitcoin is one of the
many did you think about I mean you're
coming from MIT sa room and there's
several other zero cash and so did you
look at other Bitcoin like systems and
what is exactly what you need from them
and how generalizable is what you
propose because for example there are
attacks against Bitcoin double spending
and why majority is not enough into
things like right yeah so I did look at
it here iam I think the the reason I
didn't use etherium is because it has
these other problems with it's perfect
for consensus that people wrote papers
on the other reason is that etherion
block headers are too large actually
much larger than Bitcoin block letters
this is not in the paper I just realized
that after actually and another reason
was at the time when we wrote the paper
we wanted to implement this and there
was no way to do light verification in
aetherium this changed by the time our
paper got accepted so I could see this
being also done in aetherium and would
be interesting to see what the bandwidth
would be because the Tyrian blocks
headers are bigger and there's more of
them uses a different consensus
algorithm hey Alistair Chicago's
acquittal so I'm going to stick into
yourself bits of it as hard to fork as a
Bitcoin the thing is that it's not
extremely hard for Bitcoin we just don't
do it because you you're going to double
spend five bitcoins to know that much
money right but once you move to that
double spending is actually attaching
into an encryption aren't you worried
that this makes Bitcoin more vulnerable
to such attacks by using it and in the
process will actually break a bit going
because the letter agencies would try to
double spend right yeah so that's a very
good point how hard is it the fourth
Bitcoin and will it get harder if we
build other things on top of it like
this or like colored coins and people
have looked at this and I don't have any
answers to that question
I really don't know I hope that Bitcoin
becomes useful enough and people want to
further secure it and it'll be hard to
fork so far we've had accidental Forks I
hope I hope it withstands attacks that's
all I can say I think there was a paper
in CCS from a service showing like how
hard it is for Bitcoin and like you can
double spend if it's worth like a few
thousand K dollars right yes you know
that mass yeah for NSA to add the
breaking internal encryption right right
it couldn't yeah that could be sure yeah
so at the moment you listed a few of the
applications of this which makes sense
when it costs well for 70 cents are
there more applications you have in mind
that you could use if it only cost one
Center Microsoft to do a non
equivocation hmm you know I didn't
really think about that too much I was
so excited about public key distribution
I'm like wow this is really cool
Oh everybody is just doing it slightly
inefficiently and you can do it
efficiently I think public distribution
is the killer app not sure I'll get back
to you on it
okay all right let's think ally
[Applause]