everybody my name is Nikhil Tonio
and today has been done what it was
our intern at Georgia Tech so I've been
working with Chang Jiang Zemin and Wang
cube about the marshal a PhD student at
UC Santa Barbara and if my advisors let
me graduate in September I'm going to
join you recommend an assistant
professor so the work in going to
present today is about starting from two
permissions and ejecting the UI feel the
loop you actually look is something like
this well basically give the UI the UI
shows something to the user and the user
clicks on something through the same UI
and reacts to it any UI actually updates
itself so that the user understand the
UI is affected to protect it so it's
actually look this paper has two main
points the first one is to show that if
an attacker can kind of eject the input
and output channel in a passive and
active way then the attacker can do a
lot of this stuff and the second point
is it's actually possible to do so
because of many design building
abilities we identified and these
vulnerabilities
let us implement a number of new types
which we call cloak and dagger so we
started from two permissions let me
introduce you to permissions view the
first one is system and at window
informally we call it drawn table and
basically with this permission and
application and draw arbitrary overlays
on top of the screen arbitrary in terms
of shape the content prosperity and
sport and you can create it overlays in
two ways either clickable so that
they're going to get a click and be not
right about this or pass through so the
click goes through and reaches what's on
the bottom of it okay these permission
is used quite a lot 10 percent of top
5,000 application including top apps
like Facebook Skype uber and so forth
the second permission is what we call
accessibility service and app can say
hey I want to be an accessibility
service and this service is basically
mechanism so that application can help
users with disabilities and it's
actually quite powerful for example if
there is some you I think the changes is
going to get notified and of some the
user clicks on a button is going to get
notified or it can also be active and
inject UI events such as clicks there
also number of apps using the system for
example LastPass is using a civility
service to automatically fill your
passwords in now this
Aries is very powerful but there are
there is kind of a boundary right and it
shouldn't be able to us sensitive
information for example password fields
and if you check the documentation you
will see a warning like this where since
privates could be compromised any event
fired in response to password
manipulation
they're not going to contain the
password so if you call for example get
text method on a password widget you're
going to get the empty string okay now
before I go for the with the work and
show you what we can do with super
missions I want to address one question
that I'm pretty sure it's up in your
mind why would a user be so crazy to
enable these permissions right and you
know if they use a nice name of them is
not so straight attack and you know the
user might understand was you know well
we found out that this that is actually
a way to get these two permissions
without the user understanding what's
going on the first point is that the
drone proper mission is actually
automatically granted for applications
coming from the Play Store and there was
quite a surprise for us but it turns out
that is not a bug is actually Google
decision because of many many
applications are using this and you know
now in the past it was automatically
granted and now changing this behavior
who create a lot of backward
compatibility issues the second point is
that we have a new attack based on free
checking so that from the drone top
permission we can actually get the CBD
service without having the user
understanding what's going on so it's
actually reasonable to get these two
permissions to make it worse the list of
permissions is never shown to the user
specifically for newer Android we're
moving to a runtime granted permission
where you would see pop-ups but the
drone top is already granted in
accessibility we have the attack to get
it without notifying the user and to
make things even worse these permissions
are special and they're treated
differently by the framework and for
example if you go on Android 6 and this
is my proof of concept is actually
asking for the super missions but if you
browse on the permission item they're
going to see no permissions why because
they're special and so to actually see
the disappears regarding permissions you
will need to browse to special
permissions
who can draw on top and things like this
similar for the accessibility service
there is a dedicated manual so that you
need to go there manually but children
are not gonna sit here and
you know now I'm going to show you how
with these super missions we can do
really bad stuff now before I continue I
have a super quick introduction about
clean checking attacks what I'm going to
present now is already known the goal of
the target is to lure the user to click
on the ok button this guy
well the attacker does is to create a
Novelli on top and then he creates a
button ok in a way that when the user
clicks on it the click actually goes
through and clicks on OK button
after which for example in this case the
application has the accessibility
service enabled
okay now this was notified to Google
acting one year and half ago from some
researchers who say well that's a
problem and we're going to fix it the
reaction was introduced a security
mechanism called the obscure flag the
full flag basically tells the ok button
widget that when there is a click if
this flag is set it means 8 once a user
when the user click there was actually
something on top so you should not trust
this this button ok so it's actually
useful to understand if they were
standing on top the widget the good
click our point here is who says that
you need to cover the but the target
button to do CLE jacking the Audis we
want the user to look at every button
about we cover everything else but the
ok button like this you know given the
current state of humanity respond it's
actually pretty easy to convince a user
to click on the a button the user is
actually going to click it so from a
conceptual point of view the design
issue here is that there is no context
information for the application to
understand the user have enough
information to authorize this this
dissipation and there's a ok button for
the stivity service so it's one of the
most dangerous ok button and that's the
best protection mechanism up there as
well now so I believe the obscure flags
but the mechanism is conceptually broken
and you know the framework should be
sure that the entire UI maybe was free
of overlays otherwise there can be
confusion and the other problem is that
we have a new technique we call it
concept context-aware clickjacking
and we show that we can a multi-state
projecting attack where we can actually
lure the user to enable CBD service
we just need to eject three clicks these
three clicks do not need to be
consecutive very near in time there is
no guessing involved there is no timing
in the unit's figure out it just works
in a deterministic way now before I go
to what you can do with a CVT service on
to step back and say okay let's talk
about your subscribe like mechanism
because we found out it not only is not
useful but it actually can be abused to
do even worse things now we have a new
attack we call it invisible grid attack
and we dis attack we can record all the
keystrokes by only having the drones or
permission so there is no clear jackin
there is nothing like this okay and it
works by using the obscure flag at the
side channel the tag works in this way
imagine this is the phone lay down the
target can create a number of overlays
like organize one hope each other and
these overlays are invisible and the
clicks post so according to the user
nothing is actually on the screen in a
goal of the targets understand where is
the user clicking okay so we found out
there are some flags so that you can set
up this overlay so that no matter where
the user click these overlays are going
to receive a motion event okay of course
these events are not going to contain
the click coordinates for security
reasons but at least they are notified
what we found is that these motion
events actually contain obscure flag and
so the trick is the following if you
click on number one well number one
impact point is actually low so
everything is same I'm not a secured
however if you click on number two the
impact point is actually higher than
number one and number one it's a
atmosphere so the attacker can actually
collect the patterns of Oscar bids any
cannot understand where the user clicks
based on these obscure bits if they're
set or not
and the irony is that these actually
security mechanism and here we show how
we can use it as a channel now the way
you weaponize this is to create multiple
overlays maybe one over each of the key
of the keyboard and now basically you
know exactly what the user is typing of
course during aerial attack these
overlays will be invisible now the big
problem in our opinion here is that
there is a clear violation of the
principle of least privilege why would
an application be able to create
invisible valets right and another
problem we found
that the window manager is extremely
complex there are hundreds of legs and
you know there is the risk of
introducing unexpected channels like
they want to show now and the other
problem we identified is that it seems
like UI Security's like an afterthought
is I don't want to say the Google
doesn't care about this but what our
feeling is that it's less understood
thing and it's you know less systematic
than enough protection mechanisms
against buffer flow or things like this
now back on accessibility service
working with you about this well we are
we found another design issue which is
by default all UI objects are considered
non security sensitive and we know in
security the security should be the rule
not the exception and so you know the
password fields are actually protected
you cannot get the password however you
need to forget some important new eye
objects for example we found the widget
considering the actual keyboard are
actually considered as normal and so
whenever you press Enter key the CBD
service is actually generating an event
and you know exactly what the user type
is having even if you have starting a
password saying goes for two-factor
authentication tokens with the Google
Authenticator application everything is
not protected my favorite is actually
the security bed through which a lock
the phone so whenever you click on one
of these buttons there is an event that
reaches the malicious app and so we can
steal the pin we can actually inject
between a lobster phone and the sharing
the cake is that we can do this while
keeping the screen completely off
because apparently the CBD service
doesn't rigueur other system that says
oh maybe I should I should go up so we
have a scenario basically yeah the user
actually staring at his phone on the
desk and you know he needs to lose
complete trust in in the form you have
no idea about what's going on now you
have other attacks where you know you
can mix the super missions interesting
way for example we knew like variation
of a phishing where you know get the
Facebook up and then the user is about
to enter the credentials or to destroy
something on top of it you know as
classic phishing the user is going to
interact with us and put the credentials
in in traditional phishing attacks now
the user would you know the password is
gone but the user would find itself not
logged in so he has a chance to be
like understanding of what would happen
with a CVT service instead what we can
do is to take the via Facebook up take
the password we stole fill it in click
login and the user is actually logged in
so there is like complete UI like in the
middle attack and the user is absolutely
no change to Texas another variation is
that we can use a drone top permission
to draw something on the screen like a
video in a way that the clicks pass
through so the while the user is
actually checking the video out we
actually do bad things in the on the
bottom and so in front of the user we
can actually I don't know install a
secondary malicious applications enable
all the permissions and then we can also
do some cleanup steps such as this
missing all the recent views maybe
uninstalling the initial malicious
applications and things like this now I
hope I convinced it is attacks are
pretty bad and the other question is out
of this practical well we do the user
study I recruited 20 human subjects and
we tested three most technically
difficult acts we had CLE jacking
selling godmode a distillation and
skelter fishing in the results are
pretty bad rejecting nobody got it the
epistle Asian novel in the student
meeting selfie fishing 1802 any fell for
it two of them found some graphical
glitches turns out they actually trigger
a bug in my prototype so what I did is
actually to fix the bug and then I gave
the phone back and pulled it guys I'm
going to attack you let's see if you can
detect it and even if I told them they
were under attack they had no clue if
the runner attack or not so we believe
this attacks are actually practical the
other question we asked these guys do
you know about these super missions by
the way well it seems they don't the big
problem here is that you know since
these permissions don't appear in the
classic list you need to browse to
special menus well if uses an unknowable
dispar mission to the first place why
would they go around in special menus to
find them right so there is a like a big
Delta between what we think users know
and what they actually know so how can
we fix this but the first thing we did
was to responsibly disclose this box to
Google so we started with the simple
bugs let's say and to see I was going
and so we started with invisible attack
and it was recognized as moderate
severity but unfortunately it's not
fixed yet
and then I reported you know
accessibility service documentation
states you cannot see the password and
you know we found you can unlock the
phone with the screen off and things
like this well it was not well received
at the beginning so what happen is the
following markers one fix work is
intended at which point I said guys you
know there is a security note and I can
do stuff the dual documentation says you
shouldn't be able to do okay
mark is a severity with point which
point were extremely happy champagne
everywhere and so forth however one
month after said we are not gonna fix it
because limiting those services would
render the device unusable and we have
the product that we are mixing things
like I don't know how to fix it with it
should not be fixable right and so we
kept pushing the guy the documentation
says otherwise
we are gonna update the documentation so
this is this is related to the security
not saying that you shouldn't be able to
get the password I'm still fighting with
them saying guys you shouldn't be able
to unlock the phone automatically with
the screen of 50 studies from we might
have my updates later anyway so okay
we're not going to get money with this
fine we have the Creed jacking technique
he actually works in all version of
Android which is pretty bad and
everywhere I try to look or you know the
reward things and which bugs actually
qualify for this and there is something
like this there what they say some
classes do not qualify and guess what
Ted jacking which is a likely jacking
and you are addressing do not qualify
for this which made me really really
said well come on guys I'm a PhD student
extremely poor I'm going to be a
professor in France so economic wise my
situation is not gonna improve I relying
on this money but you know now killing
about my point is that it's it's a quite
tricky to communicate these things
through bug issues because it seems that
you this UI bugs are not perceived as
like top tier bugs and we hope that this
work is gonna change the perception
about this so what we did for the solar
cells Mali and would be for the next
ones where this opportunity to share the
paper with Adrian logic with the head of
end of security so
best of our understanding is that this
paper has been read and consider
seriously by the by the team
unfortunately we have currently no news
about what's going on with the fixes and
so forth and all the attacks I just
presented and over also the other ones I
have in the paper are actually still
working latest version of Android even
with the latest security patches now we
also have a number of shorter and
commendations for Google the drone top
permission really should not be
automatically granted and you know now
I'll show you how to abuse it that was
hitting a report a couple of weeks ago
showing out this permission is the same
permission used by ransomware and so now
it's it's weird when you know it's so so
much powerful permission is actually
automatically granted and the other
point is that maybe applications
requiring requiring both permissions
should be vetted in a specific way
so I did a quick experiment I would have
a super malicious app like the dynamic
code loading requiring super missions
and you got accepted few hours and I
think is still there and as I made this
eight months ago or something of course
it's not weaponized right but you know
the attacker in theory could flick the
bit on the back end and then serve
malware and so since the number of apps
requiring both of these clinicians
should be quite low maybe manual waiting
should be possible in this case in a
paper we also described a number of ways
to secure the UI we try to propose
secure apps and widgets things like this
or guarantees that the West should
enforce for the secure apps in widget
and we in certain scenarios
maybe we should have something like
system perhaps like the web pop-ups we
know like where you cannot really
configure them it's like something with
a message with the icon of the app
generating this and that's about it
because I don't have time to describe
our proposal but all the digits are in
favor so I'm going to conclude we
present the Clos conduct clock Agra tax
we believe a stealthy powerful and
practical and these are new ways to
abuse these problematic permissions that
we were aware the big point of this
paper is UI security bugs matter I
strongly believe also now these are the
whole and give fruits for the attackers
and these are much more practical to
actually implement also relate I mean
with respect to you know low-level like
things and exploitation and there is a
big difference between you know we can
also fix
we should not fix it so we are
personally still try to fight to try to
make end of security better we put up
more information on a website you have
more details about the responsible
disclosure process and things like this
we are going to try to keep it updated
with Google reaction this is my content
information if you work for Google and
of you think you can help us out please
which is out we would love to talk to
you thank you very much you temper may
be two questions
Isaac chef Cornell I think this is
really great work and it's a example
that as long as you can slide something
between the application the user no
matter how good your security system is
under the hood there can still be
problems do you think would be more
acceptable to the powers that be to
limit the power of applications that
draw on top to create simulated clicks
and user input than it would be to limit
the power of applications the draw on
top to create simulated pixels for the
user no I'm a surrogate saying you want
to limit the power of these drawn tops
so that they can still show arbitrary
pixels to the user but they can't
simulate user input to applications
underneath oh it's so busy they're
saying okay don't stop you can draw
whatever you want
but all you want to avoid that clicks
pass through they relate there will be
there will be an option but you know I
think there might be some cases where
that's actually a good feature to have
in a sense that you have these overlays
and but I agree with you that there
should be probably removed there is a
much easier way to fix this at this
point at least for this short term
recommendation you know
nothing should be shown whenever you are
playing with the settings application so
if the and this wouldn't break
applications right because you can make
the application believe that the valley
is actually displayed the system would
just not displayed the application
doesn't know it so it's not that
facebook chat edge is going to crash
because the so that's one practical way
and still that you can have this
pass-through overlays but yeah there
might be a way
sighs lineage from Splunk and in a
previous life let's say up to 2015 we
were collaborating with you and we did
some work on android and markets inside
so so first question is actually judges
to know whether it is still prevalent so
you have I think more than 200
privileges in in Android right and we
figured out that only 40s or so are used
but those 40 grant you anything right
and did you really have to go through
the effort to explaining it how this
this series when basically all users
automatically grant anything that's a
that's a very good point my personal
belief is that yes we may use a problem
the sense that you know they are super
excited they want to bind everything on
the other side you know that's not a
good excuse to not try to fix system
security so agree with you as though now
I think the you know could be very
simple even without these types to get
some previous app permissions because
the users just give it to you but you
know on the other side this problem is
something I can fight with we go and you
know it should be fixed no matter what
because even in like a security savvy
person actually we fell for it
actually I think also the human subject
I play with during this parent or PhD
students at Georgia Tech so these are
security people and they can also pay
for it so that but so in just a short
last one so the implications of them not
fixing this
so is this basically draw on top
affecting pop-up notifications is the
same privilege and you know that some
applications are anyway running in the
background even when you're logged out
so are they concerned with that or or
something else so for the drone table I
think it's just technical issue in a
sense we have uses specific
functionality of this obscure flag and
honestly we show that it doesn't matter
even if he's not there we still can win
so I think they just they should just
disable this propagation of obscure flag
and so if you just do this is not gonna
affect any existing application so
unfortunately we asked for update we
didn't get any so we know it's
considered as a bug and they're gonna
fix it but I don't tell more information
in this thank you okay thanks a lot
[Applause]