yes thank you very much though this is
joint work with my colleagues
[Music]
Armando Andre and Franco and it's on
formal verification of confidentiality
guarantees in a distributed social media
platform so the motivation is that on
the web and on social media platforms in
particular you just want to share
information sometimes publicly but
sometimes also privately with friends or
family for example and for this purpose
of platforms provide privacy settings
where the users can configure the
visibility of the content and there's
attentively enforced using mechanisms
like access control but getting this
enforcement rights is notoriously hard
so a small park and implementation for
example missing access control check and
easily lead to confidential data being
leaked so in this work is wanted to
follow a more rigorous approach and use
information flow control so capturing
the confidentiality requirement as
information flow properties and then
formally verifying that there are no
unintended flows of information in the
system and the system that we have
looked at is the prototype of
distributed social media platform and we
had started developing this in previous
work and for this paper we have extended
it to a distributed system so you can
now deploy the system at different
servers which they can then communicate
with each other and this allows users to
add friends also on other servers and
exchange content with them on other
servers so this is similar to existing
systems like the aspera for example for
the verification of the system we have
formulated and proved a compositionality
result for a very expressive notion of
information flow security and we have
formalized all of these results so the
verification of the system as well as
the underlying theory and
interactive fear improver either the
hole and the code is available on the
website so let's look at the concrete
system we called it cosmetics it offers
the basic functionality that you would
expect from a social media platform so
after logging in you can browse a
contest that has been posted by the
users you can add new posts the title
text image and you can also configure
the visibility either it is a public
post or it should be visible for your
friends only and you can manage friend
lists add friends for locally on the
same server as well as remotely on other
servers and so this is what the system
looks like from a user perspective let's
look at the architecture so we have
started by specifying the functionality
of the system in the interactive fear
improver either the Biasi isabel's
built in functional programming language
and essentially specifies the steps
function of an automaton so the actions
here are the user actions for example
create a new post or add a friend and
then the function gets the output that
is been displayed to the user and the
advantage of doing this in a theorem
prover is that we can directly contact
the security proof on this specification
on the one hand on the other hand
isabelle also has a cogeneration feature
that we have used to export this step
function as executable scholar code and
this actually forms the core of the
running prototype and around it we have
the wrapper that makes the actions and B
outputs of this kernel available to of
that application that method on top of
it so these outer layers they are
implemented manually so they are trusted
but this kernel of the system
corresponds quite directly to the
specification that we have verified
so as I said we wanted to map the
confidentiality requirements to
information flow properties and the
notion of information flow security that
we have build upon is course bounded the
disability or BD security and it is a
generalization of southern classical
notion of knowledge usability and here's
a brief reminder of how it works so we
use trace based semantics of the systems
so we consider the behavior of a system
in terms of the its set of possible
execution traces and we model the power
of the attacker using an observation
function all that map's a trace to the
observation of the attacker so this
contains the information that the
attacker can directly gain by observing
or interacting with the system and then
the model bottle confidential
information is using a secret function s
so this extracts the confidential
information out of a trace and now the
security requirement is that it must be
possible to change this secret without
changing the observation so there must
be a different possible trace of the
system with a different secret but the
same observation and this means that
from the viewpoint of the attacker this
observation doesn't tell them which one
of the secrets has actually occurred and
nandi disability requires that it must
be possible to change the secret and an
arbitrary way which is typically too
strict for realistic systems including
our cosmetics so BD security at another
parameters of this called be the
excessive vacation bounds where because
vacation means control information
release and it allows us to specify in a
fine-grained manner which secrets have
to be indistinguishable of each other
so this then allows us to specify
essentially exceptions to this strict
quality of knowledge ability so we can
in other words
specify what the attacker is allowed to
learn about the secret so how have you
used this for our system
we considered basically two classes of
confidential information the content of
private posts there should be visible
for the friends only and the friendship
relations between users and we want to
verify that for example the content of a
friend only post cannot flow to a user
who is not the poorest supposed to learn
about this because they are not friends
with the owner
so the attackers that we consider here
are users of the system and arbitrary
but fixed set of users and the
observations are therefore the actions
of these users perform and the outputs
that they get so these are the green
arrows here and the secret is for
example an update action to post that
you want to keep confidential and now
the security requirement is that whether
or not this secret input has occurred
the observation must stay the same until
[Music]
the observers gain the truth limit
access to the secret so for example the
owner of the post could decide to add
one of the observers as a friend and
then they are allowed to learn about the
content until the owner decides to
remove the observer again as a fence
then everything that happens afterwards
should be kept confidential again so we
have quite dynamic bounds on the
information release that wants to allow
here in the system and for details on
how we formalized this I refer or to
displayed and also to the last year's
paper at ITP where we discussed this in
more detail the focus of the current
paper is on how to verify these
properties in a distributed setting so
as I said we have extended the system so
that it can be deployed in on multiple
servers and they can communicate with
each other so we have edits
corresponding communication actions both
to the system specification as well as
to the
Greta's and the outer layer and for the
verification we have verified that the
secrets they've had confidential in the
presence of inter server communication
so I think for each secrets a server can
act in two roles either sending a secret
or receiving a secret and we have
verified that the confidentiality of
both secrets generated locally as well
as secrets received from other servers
is preserved and we have verified this
on the level of individual instances of
the system and we have been used the
compositionality results to lift this to
a security property of the overall
network now the problem here is that
information flow security is typically
not compositional in general so this is
well known this is already been observed
in the 80s and compositionality can fail
in particular if for example I am the
security guarantee of one a component
relied on environment assumptions that
are not satisfied by the other component
and so the small example here you see
two systems that exchange and observable
message and both of these systems
individually are secure in the sensor
that is possible to insert a secret
message without changing the observation
but the problem is that the two systems
do not agree on the communication
protocol so on the ordering of the
secret or the observable observer the
message which means that here
synchronization fails and we have an
observable difference in the behavior
depending on secret messages so the
conversation is insecure and it has been
a lot of research on compositional
notions of information for security and
we have looked at the literature but we
have not found on existing framework
that allowed us to compose these dynamic
declassification policies that we had
verified for our system so we looked
into the literature at existing
frameworks and try to adapt
some of the insights there to come up
with sufficient conditions for
compositionality of bidi security so we
make some assumptions some of these are
straightforward so we assume that the
observations and secrets are compatible
in a certain sense so for example if the
sending of a message is secret for one
components then it has to be secret also
on the receiving end but as basically a
prerequisite to be the shape of the
security properties fit together we also
assume observable network traffic so
this means that we assume that all
communication on a network is observable
to some degree not necessarily the
content but at least effective
communication happened so there's a
similar in spirit to assuming all of us
the network attacker who can inspect
network traffic up to parts that are
protected by encryption and we made
another simplifying assumption here that
we call secret polarization which means
that any given individual item of
confidential information so for example
the content of a post always originated
in exactly one node of the networks and
so this localization of the secrets this
helps avoid problems subtle problems
that might occur otherwise this where
the scheduling of secrets may interfere
with the scheduling of observations and
by having this assumptions it's allowed
us to simplify our proofs
considerably so with these assumptions
we obtain the compositionality results
and that allows us to compose security
properties of network of systems and the
main strength of it is that it is
quality agnostic in a sense that if this
assumption assumption salt then you can
basically compose arbitrary poly
this and intuitive to see what the
result is if you consider a policy in
terms of the amount of information that
it allows to be released to the attacker
then basically this composition takes
kind of the union of the amount of
information and this is allowed to be
released to their data so we combine the
policies of the components for cosmetics
we have chosen the policies so that they
match each other which means that our
end result is that the security
guarantees of the sole source nodes of a
secret are preserved in the network so
for example Luther declares that post as
friends only and then this setting is
enforced throughout the network you'll
see some statistics of the verification
on the left side and you see the size of
the verification of the monolithic non
distributed version of the system and on
the right is the distributed one and you
can see that the size of the
verification has roughly doubled when we
added this distribution and one of the
main factors here is that we had to
verify these two rows of each server
sending and receiving a secret and we
were able to reuse a lot of the proofs
that we had done for the non distributed
system but it was still a considerable
effort to verify this distributed system
so today's a few thousand months so it
was not automatic but it was feasible so
to conclude we had verified which
security properties for a prototype of a
distributed social media platform or at
least the the kernel of it and an
abstraction of the network and but
there's a port a lot of
future works that might be interesting
for example and as I said at the moment
the outer layer is trusted also any
client sites of the JavaScript for
example that is running in the browser
is trusted so it might be interesting to
look into how the canyon and maybe
extend our security guarantees here
there are also certain limits of code
generations or the code that is
generated by Isabel is quite inefficient
so any improvements here on the
efficiency of the code would be quite
useful and also relaxing the simplifying
assumptions that you may use in
particular the secret policy
polarization for example it would be
useful to allow our results to be
applied to a more broader class of
systems so um here's the home page as I
said the source code is available so we
can take a look at it and this concludes
my talk thank you for the attention
[Applause]
unridden of del wa for so I have a
question about your diagram the one with
the comparison of the previous system
and then year yes yes what's the unit of
measurement on the Left axis unit of
measurement 25,000 right it's aligned
over the big hold I forgot to mention
okay so verification is basically
approves your verification here means
the the the actual verification of the
security properties of the concrete
system the security forever is the
underlying theory so the this in the
disability case it includes the
compositionality result and it's absurd
proof and the system specifications up
to one it also grew and when adding the
distribution feature
okay thank you and the second question
is could you give an example of the
dynamic declassification policies that
you needed that weren't in the previous
work here to set for exam
here when we consider the the
confidentiality of a post this is
controlled by the so if the user selects
friends only then this just means that
all these friends should be allowed to
be able to learn about the content of
this post but of course the the list of
friends of the user evolves over time so
it might be that at some point of the
execution history the observer is a
friend of the owner of this post and
sometimes not and this might change
several times throughout the execution
and the properties that they verified
they they protect the confidentiality of
anything that happens in phases where
the none of the observers is friends
with the with the owner of the post and
at the point where they were observers
edit the dark version of the content is
released basically to the observer
anything that happens during phase of
friendship is released if the observer
is deleted as a friend anything that
happens afterwards is kept confidential
and so on so the kind of policy that we
have formulas here okay let's thank
Thomas and all the other speakers again
[Applause]