um Thank You Brandon introduction a
machine from Princeton University and
today I'm presenting our workout counter
Raptors they starting to work against
active volcano tax and this work is done
in collaboration with Annie Atmos on
Nick sinister moon shell and critique
metal electrons in university internet
communications are not anonymous so
consider this simple case when a user
visits a website the ISPs to learn the
destination identity of the site that
the user is visiting and on the other
hand the destination also learns the
source identity which is the user
furthermore any we're not able to
eavesdrop on this internet communication
can learn the same information by simply
looking at the ARP IP headers and this
properly means even if the communication
is encrypted to counteract the problem
an Olympian system should such as poor
have been designed toward provides
anonymity by hiding IP headers and
prevent attackers from associating a
source with the destination poor does
that by relating traffic on top of an
overlay network composed of three types
of relays as shown here and the Tory
client selects three release one of each
type to build a tor circuit anonymous
communication takes place by forwarding
traffic across these consecutive tunnels
so there's no single entity in the
middle of the process can know both the
source and the destination at the same
time however poor is known to be
vulnerable to have a correlation
analysis the traffic entering and
leaving tor is highly correlated so na s
level adversary' who is on path at both
ends of the communication as showing a
graph here between the client guard and
between the exit and server you can
perform the statistical correlation
analysis on the package traces at both
and the anonymize the users but what is
na s level ever story that's not
currently on path and yes you want to
observe the tour traffic and that is our
focus active attacks on tour that
anniversary can launch active EGP
relative attacks to get himself on paths
and observe the tour traffic these kind
of routing attacks enable on-demand and
fine-grained attacks on the Tor network
and here is a very simple example it's a
partial internet apology and the aes3
here
that's our militia is and he wants to
observe the Tor traffic now going to the
guard relay which is in a s1 so he's
announcing the same / 16 prefix that a
s1 is announcing and trying to get the
traffic routed to a s3 the attacker
instead of eighth one which has the
guard relay so this is a really simple
example of what's a BGP hijack and these
types of PGP attacks are real and they
have already affected Tor network in the
past this is a news article in April
2014 the English set which is one of
Indonesia's largest hemic communication
providers leaked more than 320 KBT
routes over 2 hours among the victims
there were also 44 twirl relays and 38
approached our guard relates that
actually has direct connection with the
torque line these kind of active attacks
motivated our work on counter rapport
safeguarding tour against active routing
attacks and we made three contribute
incidents in our work first
we perform the measurement study in
order to understand the vulnerability of
tours to this kind of active routing
attacks we then designed a new tour
guardrail a selection algorithm to a
proactively defend against these attacks
we also developed a live BGP monitoring
system as a reactive defense so first I
will go into the measurement study
or connections get routed according to
BGP this is a simple AF topology we have
to torque lines here the torque light
one is in a su and another for point Q
is in eighth for and they both use the
same Touareg art really
that's an as1 if one is announcing the
slash 16 projects and the traffic
arrives to the poor gartrell aeneas one
based on this route he announcement now
our bad guy is 5 years
he wants to hijack the traffic to the
tour guard he is 1 so he is announcing
the same / 16 prefix to its neighbors
let's say a s story Alice threes and
further propagates the announcement to
more neighbors including a s 4
so at this point as you can tell from
the graph the traffic diverges on the
internet for our a is 4.1 years that is
in a s - he is actually resilient to
this attack because as2 still prefers
the route announcement the path to the
true origin a s that is s 1 and still
stands the traffic to the real guard
really where as a sport where the pork
want to it is for on the other hand
prefers the route QA s five-year
taquerias instead of a s 1 which is the
true originates that has the tour guard
and as a consequence the torque line 2
is not resilient to this attack and this
example illustrate the key insight in
our measurement study that we want to
measure the probability that the torque
line s is resilient to high-tech attacks
on its guard relay or in other words we
want to measure the probability that the
torque line would actually believe the
announcement from the to originate where
the guard really is instead of the
fourth origin or the attacker here we
show our evaluation for the hijack
attack resilience considering more than
52,000 areas in total on the internet
apology we also identified more than
1100 aces that contained or released
at our potential victims of the attack
this graph shows the hijack resilience
of each of these tore related assets and
their corresponding tore bandwidth we
can see there are two clear outliers on
this graph Oviatt and online SAF so they
both have very hard for bandwidth
meaning that they're handling and
observing a lot of a huge amount of tor
traffic well on the other hand they both
have relatively low resonances to attack
compared to other Pro related areas
the next question we want to ask you is
ok so can OVH and online SAS you'll be
good choice it for some kind despite
their overall low residence and the
answer is yes this graph shows the
hijack resilience of the OVH and online
FAS but across different clients we can
see that there is high huge entity in
the hijack resilience if here there are
some points with for some clients the
hijack resilience is are really low on
with creation on SAS that's in the lower
left part of the PDF on the other hand
we have more than 20% of the clients
that actually have very high hijack
resilience with OVH and on SAS that's
the upper right of the graph so what
this can tells us is that and this also
provides the key insight to our next
part of the work which is gartrell a
collection that we should really
consider this new notion of resilience
when taking a tour really um if I hijack
resilience we also presented the results
for resiliency to interception attacks
in our paper which is not presented here
so interception is actually a more
sophisticated attacks than hijack
if you're interested refer to a paper
for I think that's also a very
interesting measurement study
next I will talk about our new Torah
Gartrell a selection algorithm first
question is why do we focus on the guard
because God really is at a very
important position in the Tor network
that it has direct connections with the
tork line so he knows where the client
is and also the tork line actually uses
the same guard for an extended period of
time
which is contrary which is not the same
as middle and exits that are frequently
changing and we selected for each new
tour connection and again the key
insights we bring from the measurement
study is that we want to choose a
resilient guard based on the client
location this is how we incorporate
resilience into the relay connections
for each guard relay we're going to
compute a new weight that combines the
hijack resilience of the relay from the
client area as well as the bandwidth of
the relay we also have this configurable
parameter alpha that indicates how much
weight we want to put on the resilience
versus the bandwidth and the note that
with alpha equals to zero that's when
we're not considering resilience and all
these algorithm becomes the same as the
current vanilla tour relay selection
algorithm that's been with only and as
alpha goes higher means like higher
weight on resilience opposed to
bandwidth this graph shows the
probability of being resilient to
attacks with different alpha values in
the algorithm and again alpha equals to
zero that's the blue line on the left it
corresponds to the vanilla tour
bandwidth only selection and you can see
that the resilient probability is low in
that case but the interesting thing is
that even with a very small increasing
alpha value like alpha equals to 0.25
there is already a clear increase in
resilience to highjack attacks and this
increase can go up to you 36% on average
that's when alpha equals to 1 and up to
six percent maximum for certain clients
so it means that the algorithm benefits
certain clients more than the others for
instance if a client already has high
probability of being resilient under the
current regulatory relay selection
algorithm then it's space for
improvement could be low on the other
hand for clients with low resilience if
spent this algorithm could bring huge
benefits next we show the performance
evaluation on our counter Raptors
algorithm we use the shadow simulator
and we use the default configuration
with 400 clients and 100 web servers we
evaluate the algorithm using alpha value
equals 2.5 so it means that we're giving
equal weight to the resilience and
bandwidth of the really this graph shows
the download time for 320 kilobytes of
data we can see that there is not really
a difference between vanilla tour and
our counter Raptor in this case this one
shows a bigger much bigger download site
with five megabytes of data and there is
a small performance loss in the counter
report compared to the network
finally we present our live EGP
monitoring system on tours the system
does live monitoring on all routes to
tour really prefixes and the goal of the
system is to increase routing
transparency in tour so people can
actually see how the routes are - all
the Tor relays and notice if anything
changes in real time we also perform
anomaly detection again in real time
based on the welcome data we use three
techniques for the anomaly detection
original check frequency analytic and
time analytics and both the analytics
are new techniques that we're developing
our system and I haven't been used
before I won't go into the details of
each of these techniques
but the key insights behind both both
the analytics is that attacks are
usually infrequent in short-lived
compared to benign announcements we
evaluated our system from several to
many classes and we injected nine
simulated hacks into the data the length
of frequency of which are modeled after
past real-world attacks we also perform
the real-world attack like a frequent to
evaluate our system here are the results
both the frequency analytic and time
analytic have really low false positive
rates and both of them were able to
detect the simulated attacks and the
real world attacks that we performed the
results for these ml analytics highlight
an important characteristic about the
Tor network the most tour prefixes are
relatively stable compared to the rest
of the internet that they're announced
by a single s in other updates this is
the reason why the analytics are able to
detect the attacks whereas at the same
time having low false positive rates
those are the three parts of our work in
summary we perform the first measurement
study to understand the vulnerability of
the Tor network to active attacks we
find that high band height or bandwidth
release may have low resonances we also
design a new guardrail a selection
algorithm to protect for users from
being affected by BGP attacks and we
deployed a live BGP monitoring system to
increase the routing transparency in the
Tor network we also have the our project
website very on that's the link on top
of the slide all the information are
there you're welcome to check it out
we've also implemented our tour relation
election algorithm in the tour client
the call is up on github
that's the link in the middle and if
you're interested within having some
ongoing discussion on the tour de
minimis about the potential of actually
implementing or integrating these
senses into the like live real tour
Network you can say that again please
join our discussion on the tour deaf
mailing list method I'm ready for
questions can you say a word on counter
raptors effect on passive resilience so
the ability to do correlation attacks oh
yeah sure um so in order to do
correlation analysis on toward the
adversary needs to be on both ends of
the communication so we're pretty much
preventing the adversary from getting on
to the client and guard end of the
communication right you're making a
you're making node selection more
predictable possibly um depending on
your definition of predictable we're
using a different way to select cars
because right now they're purely based
on bandwidth which is predictable in a
different way now we're kind of shifting
the focus a little bit towards oh we're
going to pick more resilient release
based on the client location so that
chances are that they will well they
will have lower chances of being
effective in case and hijack happen on
their guard the van
question baby but we can go shove off
line you have any other questions so you
mentioned that you did the real world
experiments ethically can you say a few
words about what you mean by that
exactly I'm sure so we use the peering
framework which is the same framework I
think another paper used that was like
2/3 presentation of Bitcoin 1 basically
that we have a machine set up at
Princeton and we have VPN tunnel setup
with two different
ASA's let's see so we make the
announcement through one yes and then
after that we make the same
announcements to another yes that we
have VPN homilies and the announcements
that we're making is a dedicated IP
block that's that was kind of
temporarily owned by us for the sake of
the experiment so no one else is using
IP blocks so we're only kind of
affecting or hijacking our own traffic
very nice thank you right if there are
other questions let's thank the speaker
[Applause]