my name is Donna she coming from the
Penn State University today I'm very
glad to be here to present our original
work about critical function detection
pouring of frustrated binaries this this
technique can be used for Marilyn
Alice's and Meredith malware detection
so the technique is called a bit precise
symbolic loop mapping this is a joint
work of Penn State and UT Arlington
so our first our first to start from a
brief introduction of the background
knowledge about the crypto function so
in this talk the curve the function
means the encryption and decryption
procedure so as we all know there are
lots of different applications of
critical functions first from the bright
side crypto functions can be used for
sending and receiving messages via
untrusted channels and also they can be
used to for saying and verifying some
digital distinct natures and on the on
the other hand in time side mirror
authors can use crypto functions to hide
mail signatures and also use them to
create our peckers and walk around
firewalls allow some encrypted channels
which are invented by the mailer
developers and asked if the functions
can also be used by mirror developers to
create ransomware so if you do a search
online for the crypto functions in mail
where there are a lot of these kind of
mused reminding people that this is a
more and more important problem nowadays
especially recently the very famous
ransomware called wanna try it can
encrypt Yodas file and data and inquiry
algorithm and after the users to pay a
ransom otherwise their data and file
will be lost
so given that there are lots of these
kind of crypto functions in malware
so it provided challenges for malware
analysis and malware detection so if we
can identify those curve the functions
it will be very helpful for mayoral
analysis so generally speaking there are
several advantages first crypto function
detection can provide starting point for
reverse engineering for packed emails
because the true Miller behavior will
happen after the decryption procedure
and the second why's that early security
analysts they want to pay attention to
the to the familiar behavior early not
the unrelated encryption and decryption
functions so if we can identify those
functions it will provide an start it
will save time for those new analysis
and third lines that since the
ransomware early use the encryption and
decryption procedures so if we can
identify critical functions you it will
provide some help for identify ransom
oils and at last
somewhere where developers can customize
crypto functions so if we can identify
those customized equip the function in
other programs
then it is very likely that those
programs are mails from the same author
so so far we have answered the person
that why we need to detect crypto
functions so the next question is that
how fortunately there are some
attributes in crypto functions that we
can utilize to to detect them firstly
that crypt functions usually have lots
of bit wise operations like end or
negate the second why's that
early crypto function are the it has a
very cool transformations which can
represent the semantics of the crypto
algorithm
surely they are implemented as the
several oops structures the third one is
that scribble functions are your lay
standard based there is a kind of very
detailed algorithm specification about a
given curricular function and at last
cryptic functions surely they have lots
of well-known reference implementations
such as some open source libraries
libraries so the existing method have
used this utilizes the kind of
attributes tools to check through the
functions generally there are two
categories of methods static methods and
dynamic methods so in static methods a
lot of this stagg measures are heuristic
based they detect the crypto functions
by identified some by using some
heuristics like entropy and some magic
constant values and so on
another group of static method is the
program and as its based they use some
signatures like data flow graphs to
identify the crypto functions and on the
other hand the dynamic method most of
these kind of methods rely on identify
the input and output relations so here
here I show an example here suppose that
F is a function we want to check whether
F is the implementation of TA which
means tiny encryption algorithm so first
we can we can fit the same input impulse
F and ta then we check the output if the
output are the same then it is very
likely that F is an implementation of TA
so it's like a testing style method but
unfortunately there are still some
challenges to those existing methods
so first the in static methods
for the heuristic based the standing
methods because those heuristics the
realized on is thoroughly they cannot
catch the essential semantics of their
crypto algorithm so they may suffer from
false positives and false negatives and
those photos static static methods based
on signatures those signatures can be
hidden by obfuscation techniques on the
other hand in Inked dynamic methods
actually they can resist some kind of
control packages but the problem is that
they rely on they rely on identify the
input and output relations but they are
existing some some existing methods like
data of occasions and customized come
crypto algorithms which can change the
input and output the relation so here I
show an example of a simple data
obfuscation so in the normal version of
the program there are two 16 bits in it
is verbal a and B but in the office
carrier version there's only one integer
or 32-bit integer variable X actually it
is a combination of the a and being the
normal version but if you use dynamic
method 2 it has this kind of programs we
cannot identify the input output
relations things the input the number of
input variables are different the you
earlier is listed two versions of
programs are different so this is the
nofa station also in in spouts us that
we really need a more fine-grained
matter to identify groups of functions
so here we propose our method to
overcome the limitations first is that
it is a new solution to detect the
filter function
the technique is called bit precise
symbolic blue mapping and our method can
catch the fine grandma
of criminal transformations and also it
is a resilient to control + km the data
process at beach level so in one
sentence our technique to increase
please check checking on Lu bodies in
the reference program and the target
program so here here I'll show a big
picture of the whole technique first so
we have to reference programs we all we
have two programs when is the reference
and when is target program we run to
both of the two programs to get 2x
different races here the blue line means
the reference trace and the target line
the red line means the target address
and then we run look it's a loop
detection on both of the two traces to
expect the loop body after that were
wrong with symbolic execution to
transform the loop bodies into pooling
formulas here FX and GX so address we
check whether those two formulas are
equivalent if they are equivalent then
we say a crypto function is detected so
generally there are six steps in our
technique firstly we need a reference
implementation and then we love to
access increases and then we do loop
detection Peter simple execution and
variable mapping and a task that we
check the equivalence of the two former
works so I will go through this whole
procedure step by step
so first the reference implementation we
need a reference elimination which is
your selected from a very well known
implementation of the crypto function so
here I show exam of TA the reference
implementation should contain the call
transformation of the crypto function
which can represent the semantics of
that crypto algorithm so here is the
mental body of the TA of that we run
both
the reference program and the target
program to get to excuse increases the
traits content
runtime information like opcode operand
register values and the memory exact
value and aggressive after we get the
two traces we're on loop detection on
both of the traces actually here we
detect the two types of loops first is
unroll the loop but it is actually a
like a series of repeated instructions
so here in this example there are two
loop bodies both are instruction 1 2 3 &
4 notice that here the track address are
different because they are unrolled
loops the second type is the loop body
which can end with jump instructions so
here in this example there are two lue
buddies went to instruction 1 2 3 4 and
instruction 1 5 6
notice that here look although body
could include a branch instruction so
different loop bodies although they jump
back to the same address but the the
body could go to different branches in
different execution so the new body
itself could be different after we
extract the loop bodies we're wrong big
symbolic execution on the loop bodies to
transform to transform them into boolean
formulas so here it's the our core
contribution we actually extract the
fine-grained semantics of a critical
function so in all those formulas the
formula the variables here are all
pulling formulas are pulling variables
so here I show example of the reference
formula and target formulas so X 1 X 2 X
3 here are includes of the reference
formula and the UN you to our output
formula also available and in similar in
entire program the y1 y2 and y3 are
inputs and the villa and rate watt
output so the next step we need to
compare to check the whether those two
groups of formulas are essentially
equivalent so but before that we need
because they are actually two different
formulas we need to map the variables
together so that we know how to compare
them for example here we need to know
which input variables of in the
reference probe it means a reference
formula is exactly the input in the
target formula so one simple way is just
do a permutation to try different
possibilities but things here in our
formula all the variables are bullying
variables so just like a yearly hundreds
of those variables so simple permutation
will cost performance problem so here we
propose a variable matching algorithm to
map the input variables and output
variables this is time limitation I
cannot go into the details of this
algorithm if you are interested you can
find more details in our paper so here I
only show the final result of this
mapping algorithm so we can map the
input and the output variables so given
the variable mapping results we can go
further to generate the final
equivalence checking equation so we
first so we replace the map the input
with a same symbol such as here we map
the X 1 and Y 2 x 2 and y 3 and X 3 with
y 1 then we we replace X 1 Y 2 is 8 X 2
y 3 which be and X 3 y 1 we see and
after that we also connect the map so
output the variables together to
the final equation so this is the final
equation we need to check at the last
step we use the theorem prover to check
whether those equations are actually
equivalent if they are equivalent which
means the target program the nobodying
the target program is essentially the
same has the same ik semantics of the
reference program so if they are
equivalent we say our cryptid function
is detected so far we have go I have go
through all the steps in our technique
we evaluate this technique from three
effects first one is the from the
effectiveness we try to detect five
fruits algorithms
taa ESRC for md5 and now say we try to
use our technique to detect some the
crypto algorithm seeing some common user
with the libraries like open SSL and
lick equipped with all passive
obfuscation techniques and we also use
our techniques to check or customize the
crypto algorithm which is then X key a
variant and also windows our technically
to detect some malware samples you now
accept experiments all critical
functions are detected the second
evaluation is about false positives
we feed some normal programs which
heavily have a piecewise operations into
our tour and there's no false positives
identified and the last evaluation is
the performance actually when analysis
usually take like 15 to 40 minutes and
based on our observation the loop
detection is the most time-consuming
part so to in summary I will propose a
new method called a bit symbolic loop
mapping to detected groups of functions
this method can catch
the finder and the semantics of the
function and it is resilient to control
and data of class occasion and we also
have our tour a demo tour open sources
you can download it and play with it and
have fun thank you that's all questions
yes good yes John Criswell University of
Rochester's so interesting work one
question I have though is um if your
technique were to be deployed in the
wild then wouldn't attackers start using
say modifications of existing algorithms
so for example maybe doing a EES but not
doing as many iterations or creating
sort of ad hoc encryption algorithms
that perhaps don't have cryptographic
strengths that are just different from
your reference implementations will mean
a the developer the mellah developers
can customize some crypto algorithms
right right because your is essentially
what you're doing is a one from one
functional match between your reference
algorithm and one that you're looking
for right yeah yeah that's that's a very
good question yes so actually in our
method I can we actually we can detect
the kind also customize the crypto
algorithms for example in PA the malware
developer can change the magic number in
their in their personal implementation
but in our technique it can be handled
but if they are using a totally
different the implementation
I guess that the our solution is that
you can find a new reference
implementation and pulling into our like
a library yeah okay let's chat
afterwards Thanks thank you you explain
some of the challenges of previous
approaches what's the drawback of the
the dataflow analysis approach oh you
cannot handle obfuscation because
dateable if you are using data flow
graph as a signature
simple application can totally method
right but all you need to do is see when
you change one input of data does all of
the output change right like you just
you rely on confusion and diffusion and
say does this look like a crypto
algorithm not pinning down the actual
algorithm I'm sorry right you you just
say does this obey cryptographic
properties if I change input slightly
all of the output changes yes and that's
completely resilient to occupation it's
just input/output dependent yeah that's
dynamic rather here you are talking
about a data flow graph right well you
can do that just from the control flow
the data flow okay let's yeah hello we
can talk about this details uh my
comment is a very similar to the last
one if I if it a loop is taking in data
that appears to have some simple
correlation ie it's not random and if
the output is uniformly distributed
zeros and ones then it's a crypto
algorithm and it doesn't actually matter
what the internals are and I believe
it's possible I believe that someone
will come next year with a paper that
shows how they can obfuscate crypto
algorithms so they don't even seem to be
using arithmetic or boolean operations
so I really think the definitive thing
is as previous questioner said you know
what are the properties of the algorithm
if it's crypto it's pretty easily
recognized actually that's a very good
question I think your recruitable
functions are not that easy to customize
and to customize and to change so it
requires a very strong background
knowledge so essentially the core part
of that credit function is
really fixed the there are very small
numbers of location in that for the
function that the mayor developers can
change so surely our method can catch
the core part of that algorithm so
surely this core part will not be
changed so one less the short cushion
just describe to the previous question
make you could have an obfuscation where
a single loop is split into multiple
loops or multiple loops can be combined
into a single loop since your technique
check the equivalence of loops from the
friends implementation and the given
implementation how do you handle that
kind of obfuscation where you combine
multiple loops and you split the
existing loops into multiple loops you
mean how to combine the loop and let's
say you have an office station where you
split an existing loop from the
reference implementation into multiple
loops one possible solution is that in
the reference implementation we can
because we are using Waialua body we can
actually combine the tool to little
balancing the implement in the reference
implementation so I'd like to try the
different combinations this is a one
possible solution thank you okay so
that's a song vestigial again and this
concludes our session Thanks
[Applause]