my name is Reza chakra and this is a
joint work with my colleagues at Cornell
Tech on how to reason quantitatively
about privacy machine their machine
learning is the electricity of new
technologies and plays a very important
role in many services in the internet
because it's very useful and for its
wide applications it has been provided
as a service but Google Amazon Microsoft
and many others in such services the
service provider gives you a training
API through issue upload the data to the
cloud and ask for training and model for
example the classification model and
later on when you want to use the model
you can coolie the model using the
prediction API and ask for predictions
for example to ask for classifying and
unloading built image as shown in this
slide the prediction is a vector of
probabilities that assign the
probability to each class here are show
of these probabilities in an abstract
form using the length of these bars
please and an image of a car and get the
probability of whether this is an
airplane automobile and ship truck and
so on this is a very good example of
black box training and access to
machinery model the model remains in the
crowd of the user does not have direct
access to it does not know the type and
architecture of the model does not know
the parameters of the model cannot
download the model but can only
indirectly benefit from it through the
prediction API and when asked for
prediction it has no observation on the
intermediate steps of doing that
prediction either this isn't very useful
many applications for example if you
want to build a new mobile app and want
to benefit from it you have some data
you want to build a machine during all
of you use this service later on with
single function call you can ladle the
data that you receive later on and you
will be charged based on the number who
is that the ask for the issues this is
very useful but when I look at this ask
the question of whether piece framework
and in general machine learning models
leak information about their training
data note that at the time that you ask
for predictions the data is gone you're
interacting with the model that was
previously trained on some data that
could be insensitive so is there any
leakage about the data through the model
to answer this we study information
leakage through the eyes of an attack a
particular inference attack which is
known as membership inference attack the
question here is whether an attacker who
used the model can learn whether a
particular record was part of the
training data or not so the attacker
sends the query gets predictions on that
query and wants to know whether that
data that was in the inputs query was
part of the training center not you
admitted if attacker is successful in
such attack it indicates that there is a
significant amount of information leaked
about the training date membership
inference attack is not new to the
privacy domain is not exclusive to
machine learning it has been studied by
researchers on releasing summary
statistics on data sets so consider for
example we have a data set and the
average value of each attribute is
released the attacker
serving this summer Statistics wants to
know whether particular record was part
of the the data set and the assumption
is that the attacker has some
information about the underlying
distribution of the data or for example
has some data samples from the same
distribution and what the attacker does
is to use some reference data that is
assumed to be sampled from the
underlying population and runs a
statistical test to find out whether the
timing data records is more similar to
the statistics computed from the
reference data compared to the
statistics which is released on summary
statistics in the case of running
membership interest agar machinery
models the problem is much more
challenging because we don't have a
direct function that is computed on the
data as I explained before we have this
indirect access to the data in the case
of black box setting the setting this is
much more challenging because we have no
knowledge about the parameters of the
model we have no access to the internal
computations of the model and we might
not have much knowledge or gain no
knowledge about the underlying
distribution of the training data so how
can you go about exploiting the models
predictions and find the members of the
training data the main insight to attack
the main intuition of our time is where
machine learning models tend to behave
differently with respect to their
training data compared to the data that
I haven't seen and this exhibit itself
in the phenomenon known as overfitting
where the accuracy on the training data
is much larger than the prediction
accuracy on on the test date so I
exploit this for the attack consider a
hypothetical
you through which we explain the
intuitions of the attack and different
steps of the attack
suppose that I have access to the
training data of the model that I am
attacking if a query the model we got
data get the predictions I get some some
probability vectors right some
classifications for different classes
suppose that I have some data also
outside the training data the query the
model and get some classifications of
that data the only thing they need to do
now is to find a way to recognize the
difference between these two prediction
vectors these two distributions one
distribution that is coming from the
data inside the training set and one
distribution that it reflects the
predictions on the data that is outside
the tracks so what algorithm should they
use for this purpose the method that we
use you is called machine learning
machine learning is exactly what we want
to do we want to train a model an attack
model that observes the prediction
vector and outputs of the probability
that this prediction vector is coming
from the members versus the non-members
so it's a binary classifier the main
question and then the big challenge here
is that how can it train such an attack
model without having access to the to
the training data of the target mod note
that the main goal of this attack model
is to learn the behavior of the target
model with respect to training data
compared to the data outside of trains
so our idea to
train the metallic model without having
access to the training data is to learn
that behavior not from the target model
but from some other models that we call
shadow modes assume that we know the
type and architecture of the target
model and assume that we have some data
that is sampled from the same underlying
distribution has the training date of
the target model we can train some
models because shadow models and we
train the attack model on the
predictions that these shadow models
produce under training data versus the
test date if the type an architecture of
these models is the same at the top and
architecture of the target model and of
course the parameters are different and
if the the date on which they are
trained is similar to the data that the
tiny model was trained the Nativa of
these models with respect to their test
and train is similar to the behavior of
the target model with respect to its own
test on train the question is how can we
know the architecture and type of the
shadow models specifically the black box
setting of machine learning as a service
what we have no idea what a little idea
what they train and to overcome this
practical challenge basically it's easy
to notice that the attacker also has
access to the same platform as the user
would train the target model so I can
create an account and just ask Google
for example to train some models for me
and if I ask for the same classification
model and sorry the same classification
tasks are for similar type of theta
there is no reason why Google
trains a dramatically different model so
these shadow models are of the same type
and architecture as the target modes the
next challenge is where can I get the
data to train the shadow bones well in
the simpler case if I know the type of
data that was used to train the target
model then I can also go and collect
some real data which is the same type
and train my shadow models say for
example if the target model was trained
on some genomic data then I can go and
collect some other genomic data and
train animals on them but in in the in
the harder case in more realistic case I
might not have much knowledge about the
type of the data or the features that
were collected have for train the target
model in this case we suggest to
sanitize data for training the shadow
models if you want to sit guys data you
need to have some score function that
tells you how good a synthetic data is
and in our case we have a very good
Oracle that could help us to build that
score function and that Oracle is the
prediction API our intuition is that if
the model is very confident in its
prediction and some sample input data
this is a good indication that that data
is similar to the data that was used for
training the model and we use a search
algorithm to find those high confidence
input data you can use different search
algorithms you means use a simple
kilkanin that word and we start from
some random or
and each iteration we changed some of
the features of the data and we move
towards the area where the prediction
confidence is higher and higher where we
then keep the the high confident records
so if you look at the overall framework
that we have here we have access to
model through a prediction API we use
that synthetize on data we generate a
lot of data as much as we want using
this algorithm for synthesizing data
then we train as many shadow models as
we want on that data using the same
platform then we create the shadow
models with their own tests and train
data and we generate labeled data for
the italic model and we train the attack
model and at the same at the time that
we want to use the attack when we want
to know whether particular single detail
record was part of the training set of
the target model we query the target
model with that target record you get
the classification the prediction vector
we pass it to the attack model and it
gives us the probability of membership
of that record we use this methodology
to evaluates privacy of many models that
we train locally as well as a model that
were trained by Google and Amazon here
we show the results of our attack on
Google machine learning as a service you
can find the results of any other
attacks in the people the data set that
we have here is obtained from a cankle
competition for classifying customers
the features are binary and indicate
whether a customer has purchased a
particular item or not the total number
of classes is a hundred this plot shows
the distribution of the accuracy of the
membership in France attack over
different classes so if you look at one
point in this plot it shows the two
multi fraction of classes on the y-axis
for which the attacker can obtain a
membership in France precision up to
certain value on the x-axis so I can
tell you that if you train shuttle the
models are real data for almost all the
classes the inference precision of the
attack is the box 0.8 the overall
accuracy across all the classes in this
case is 0.93
which means that if the attacker labels
a prediction a record as member or
non-member in 95% of the cases is
correct these actresses dropped the bid
when we train the shadow models on
synthetic data and the reason for this
is that the quality of the single beam
data that we generate is not the same
for all the classes so for some classes
the model produces some poor quality
data that we use for training the
shut-ins
I want to reach right here that we get
this accuracy without knowing the
training algorithm without knowing the
model type and architecture without
having access to the parameters of the
model and in the case of training the
shadow model on synthetic data we don't
even know the data distribution and
despite all these limitations and
limited amount of knowledge the attacker
can get up to this 90% accuracy of
finding out records on member of the
training
and which ones are not of course it does
not mean that for all models and all
types of data we can get accuracy up to
this level because this metric shows how
much information could be lead for for
this platform then could be compared
with the amount of information that
could be leaked from other platforms of
course if the model is
privacy-preserving and is trained in a
privacy-preserving manner it should be
secure and robust against these attacks
let's look at the big picture here when
we train a model we have data universe
we have some samples from that data
universe that we use to train a model
and there are two big objectives here
the privacy objective and the learning
objective the main question with respect
to the privacy of the model is whether
the model leaks information about the
data in the training sets and the main
question with respect to the learning is
whether the model generalize to dig
outside the training set so what do you
think about these two objectives they're
pretty similar they're very consistent
with each other
in fact overfitting is the common enemy
of the two if a model is over fitted it
is not going to generalize to the data
outside the training set and it's going
to leak a lot of information about the
training aid this is very promising
because for the first time in the
history of data privacy the utility and
privacy are not in a direct conflict
with each other in fact it is possible
to train models that are utility
preserving and at the same time
satisfied
my privacy requirements so let me
conclude my talk with this optimistic
message Thanks