thank you for the introduction again my
name is the
today I want to talk about how we write
the uncertainty for college binaries so
that they can enjoy the protections of
rescue only memory this is a joint work
between Stony Brook University and since
on research America so the names in
black of people from Stony Brook namely
me Donita reach out it might Pfizer Lulu
and the names in blue are people from
stem cell research namely one when I'm
out of high official Kumar and one
Boston so first of all what is sorry
what is ask Yannick memory or zone and
why it is useful so this primitive was
first introduced by researchers from
Stanford and UC Berkeley back in
tinnitus
they say that Co content cannot be
viewed in the memory and around their
time they use zone to present a software
piracy and recent years zone has another
calling which is to help defend against
the dynamic memory disclosure based
correos attacks in which the attacker
firstly kakko pointer and then use a
memory disclosure primitive to
dynamically harvest the co gadgets so
that without any a priori knowledge
about binary layout the attacker can
assemble these gadgets and then hijack
the control flow so naturally you will
use them to prevent the gadgets from
being read we can stop the attacker at
step two and recent years however vendor
start to keep up for example in 836 you
have EPT a memory credential keeps any
answers before you have zone directly
configurable from kernel and here is the
earliest kernel patch that I found that
try to enable them on arm 64 platforms
you can see that it dates back to May
2014 which is three years ago so why
after three years this primitive is
still not massively in use yet
well things well one of the major
reasons is that it's non-trivial to
enable zone or code binaries for example
in this figure
it shows memory layout of the College
binaries and you can see that in this
memory page Eriko and data interleaved
together and because long can only be
enforced at page granularity that means
all the data inside
memory page are now readable which will
break the program so a very high-level
idea would be first you separate the
code and data into different pages and
then you need to probably update all the
references because if you miss any of
the reference this will break the
program as well let me first explain why
the memory layout looks like that
so basically this is the legacy issue
back in the old days when people judge
make the elf at the e.l.f file standard
they do not consider re only or as
secure only and s queueing as
incompatible as a result they put those
read-only data sections together with
code contents in order to get a more
compact binary in consequence you have
those elf headers and those meta data
sections such as canoe has a place
together which the codes action such as
PLT and tax notes that they are treating
orange bars inside the text section that
represents the inline data and after
that hex you have the rioni
data sections and he a transactions
there are also read-only that plays
together with those contents so other
than the code data locations of
regarding the references for a normal
elf binary you have intersection
references intersection references and
lastly you have even references from
external module for example the dynamic
loader we want to access the Alpha
header and those meta data sections so
does the C++ runtime that means by only
examining these are one of this module
itself you can now comprehensively
resolve all the references if this
situation is not messy enough for you or
to scare you away from trying to solve
this what about there are still some
unknown references from the external
module for example in our experiments we
found that the Android our runtime wants
to access three only section of the
title binary so now let's revisit the
high-level idea again firstly you want
to identify that cube of data throughout
the talk I will use a scalable data on
at this time to refer to all the orange
area in
studies figure so you see that because
in line data are still prevalent in um
binaries so there are past research has
shown that under such situation to tell
you data
apart from code precisely is in
principle undecidable regarding the
references hopefully I have convinced
you it's very hard if not impossible to
comprehensively resolve all these
references so facing such challenges we
made the following design goals for
North firstly regarding a code data
separation where you want to have
analysis with very high precision we
want to make practical trade-offs which
means that we want a superset of the S
cubed data but only a subset of the
references which we're resulting
something like this in this figure the
green ring represent the data collection
result that we want but on the right
side this small blue green represent
actually the mixed references so because
of these trade-offs we also have the
security codes that's there we want to
expose as Klesko as possible meaning
that this query rings to be very small
and we also want to enforce this runtime
security policy based checks to tell
apart the attackers from the legitimate
mr. references and we also want us to be
very practical by having low runtime
memory overhead and new external be
exclusive to other code binary hardening
solution such as fine-grained
colonization and the CFI also North's
binaries to be d'argo compatible meaning
that the revision binaries they can even
run seamlessly on other unsuitable
platforms even without nor support and
lastly we want to enforce loam or
modular bases so now let me show you the
high-level North's components of and how
they work together to achieve these
design goals first of all you are we
have pieces and disassembler which will
collect the supercell LPS cubed data as
well as the intro module references and
then this result will be fed to a
whistle to an pattern which will
calculate new binary layouts and then
packaged binary and then this repackage
binary can be loaded by a loader during
a load time that will update all the
collected references also enable zone or
modular basis you see that because we
only update the references at load time
is again preserve the drago
compatibility and lastly during runtime
we have a monitor as a runtime module
that will handle the mr. references as
well as performing this access policy
checked in this work wheels android as
our reference platform before i diving
into how and disassemble the works I
want to first share with you some
background so that you can know the
rationale behind and disassemble it
analysis first of all II am 64 I thought
they say that the instructions are all
four by aligned and has fixed sized also
the PC register is no longer directly
accessible and the most importantly they
only expose a very limited set of
instructions to perform PC relative
addressing and this combined with the
fact that since Android 5.0 google has
removed the non-key I loaded from the
dynamic loader which means that if you
have purchased you android phone within
the last three years chances are there
or the binary things either form a
position independent so very mind these
two observations let's see how in this
assembler works first of all you start
with the linear sweep which will give us
a over approximate set of instructions
represented by the green area and then
it does this what we call guided data
collection so remember we observe there
only a limited set of instructions can
be used to collect the obtain the
pc-relative addresses and so we base our
analysis on this limited set of
instructions namely the LDR literal and
ADRA DRP and we check the data load
operations initiated by these
instructions so this will give us a very
precise set of the data represented by
these three orange bars in the green
area and then chances are that this set
of data is still not complete because
while we are checking the
the code if we encounter some memory
operations or ingre branching stressors
that we cannot resolve then we lost the
checked in such situation we mark the
current tracking data as unbounded and
then perform this on board data
expansion which will extend the current
to check data backwards and forwards and
you will reach a valid instructions by
valuing instruction I mean that during
the back row expansion we stopped at
either the arrow branching chosen with
the valid targets or in European
instructions which we will check the
used registered certified API property
and during the full extension we stopped
at either the targets from evaluator a
branch instruction available in C
instruction or a some set of function
starts that we obtained using static
analysis so up to this step a superset
of the executable data are collected
then and assembler will go ahead to
collect the intro module references
which could come from at least dis
following list of sections so for the
sake of time I want have I won't dive
into detail for this part but in the
paper we discussed what kind of program
practice will result in the references
from these sections so if you are
interesting this detail please refer to
our paper and then this result is given
to a matcher which will calculate the
new memory layouts specifically the new
location of the edge cubed theta in
which process is also taking to
consideration the reference address in
wrench and you will omit a stop code to
help access is relocated data this new
data location if necessary and and then
empecé will append in noise related
metadata to the end of the elf this
again is to ensure the backhoe
compatibility so the news relating
metadata includes the duplicating line
data the references locations and
displacement the stop code and lastly
the north header that can tell a loader
where to locate this metadata so during
loading a loader propose three of these
subtasks that tagged with LD 1 LD 2
history in hell do you want we set up
the nose pocketing data which I will
discuss in the next slide also mapped as
Cuba data to the new location
accordingly and in ld2 it redirects all
the dynamic load accesses to the new
read of the location by updating the
dynamic session and lastly in LDS
readjust all the references and then
enable zone or modular faces I want to
show you how unloader works with this
simplified program loading process so
first of all you start with as Cuba
loading you can see we do LD 1 LD to
accordingly and then the control flow is
transferred to the dynamic loader which
will load all the dependent libraries
and for each one of them the module we
also do LD 1 LD 2 and after all the
modules required by the process
appropriate loaded the dynamic loader
will go ahead to symbol resolution and
relocation and we do LV 3 at this point
if we do it here because some of the
references are only available during
this time for example those from the G
ot section and by doing that we see here
we have a higher coverage on the
references lastly the program can start
and run so if you have the question what
if the program load the library during
runtime you can see that because of our
traces of timing to perform these three
subtasks
this is naturally handled by unloaded by
doing this step 2 and step 3 again so
during runtime a monitor will help
resolve these missed
references and also perform this before
policy checks policy checks and
currently we have a default policy of
that we made based on our experience
which we believe is like a very good
balance between compatibility and
security basically the policy says that
the code can only access is identified
superset of the SQL they are region also
for the inline data they should only be
allowed for your hosting functions which
are these over approximated ranges that
we obtain using static analysis and
lastly for compatibility reason we mark
the convention
by our headers and those non coal
regions as ylist before now and the
right side this is the bookkeeping data
I mentioned in the last slide so in this
linked list each note is a represent
module in your process and you can see
that each one of them has their own
policy and whitelist which we were outer
need to adjust them if necessary so we
believe this policy does not hurt
security for the following two reasons
first of all even the attacker can read
the SQL data region this are part mostly
contains only invalid data for example
it looks like this so they are they
cannot be executed and for the second
reason because of the policy about
England data now the attacker needs to
use multiple members disclosure work in
order to explore the execute data in
different area so now that I have
finished introducing how north's works I
want to compare you with the set of
related works from the angle of how to
enable zone so in the first line of work
they enable zone by recompiling and
we're linking the program so that the
binary emitted by the to churn when
loaded will have code and data separated
nicely but it's required source code on
the second line of work they provide us
very handy data analysis to identify
subset of SQL data which is group a it's
not enough for our purpose and we
believe the most comparable work to
northeast hi Dan I then also want to
identify the superset of X cubed theta
and here is how hiding works so this
figure anxiety grows green rings
represent the function node of a call
graphs in that program and hide em
starts from the entry points and then
from this recursive disassembly and then
also as well some static analysis to
identify this subset of the call graph
and then they mark everything else as
data you see that because of the
limitation of static analysis being a
vertically will identify some code as
data so compared with hi them these two
works actually has their own advantages
for example in the in the scope of I'm
it's more precise because it's analysis
depends on specific unsuccessful eyes or
knowledge but high Liam's approach is
actually architecture independent on
they can handle other cultures such as
x86 and because of that their
disassembler is also robust against the
Iranian disassembly which is naturally
not a problem for insisting for anyway
and the note is more systematic because
he can handle a has a higher coverage on
the references and also North is enabled
on the real world mobile systems so I
want to show you our evaluation results
during our evaluation with three set of
the binaries in the set as to one in
consists of 313 system would be system
einar's they are all stripped come from
the commercial phones and we use them to
run our data analysis and learning
except as to with the lat 20 of the
critical system binaries and then
convert them and then run our
functionality tests in the last set we
use UNIX pants to measure runtime and
memory overhead so regarding the data
analysis so we set as one in which
process we observe 132 out of 313
binaries has reported inline data and
for this real friend doing the analyzed
process they require this unbound data
expansion which means that the rest of
the 132 binaries can be analyzed nicely
with the guided data collection in this
process we also observe a 28 of binary
search for demo we have identified more
code as data but regarding the data
missed we do not miss any but this is
after we are manually filter down
reference data such as the padding's and
signature strings etc because making
them unreadable will not break the
program so we do not count them as
forced negatives we also observe that in
this amongst binary sleep and regard as
we buy curating and ourselves has
reported much more in line data than
other animals
- regarding the functionality test we
converted those critical system binaries
including the QC complete the contour
ivory or and those important system
demons that you cycles are in studies of
extremely researcher they are used to
support your day-to-day tasks such as
launching up new new application making
phone call or render frame buffer et
cetera
we also converted the low-level complex
libraries such as lips silly pen and
then we enable them and during our
personality test week knowledge survey a
failure
lastly we run the UNIX punch binaries we
converted them and around them on this
Qualcomm Snapdragon 808 chip with two
divided memory also known as the Nexus
5's form and we compare it with the
original binaries and in this process we
observe the average runtime overhead
peak memory overhead and the file size
over had our negligible and notice that
is one benchmark with the exact CL that
has much higher runtime overhead because
this is benchmark actually is doing us
just testing only exact see this Court
has seen it just keep calling exact on
itself and this will trigger our
bookkeeping data set up and keep
triggering this locking and locking
mechanism that's the reason why our
exhibits higher overhead so in summary
we firstly perform a systematic study of
the code data separation problem on
those cots binaries and notice the first
comprehensive solution for enabling zone
from 64 platforms in which it makes
practical trade-offs to tackle the in
principle undecidable code data
separation problem eating has the
security such that it exposed very last
code to the attacker and also enforce
this runtime based policy checks and
noise features the practical design such
that is support the modular zone
enforcement's it covers as curable as
well as libraries and those common
parties such as one
library loading and no expander is
tobacco compatible you can run this
converted binary even on other stork
unassisted for phones with seamlessly
and also the north is now exclusive
although I didn't discuss explicitly in
the talk by the notes does not introduce
any change to the dataflow of Cobra our
property of the program lastly would
perform large-scale evaluations on
real-world mobile system binaries in
which we show that those can precisely
collect the data also the rewritten
binary incurs negligible runtime and
memory overhead so with that I want to
thank you for attention and take any
questions you might have
[Applause]
ok you can comment on the applicability
of your techniques on x86 which is
clearly more complex and exactly also
why we have the confidence to say that
it can cover insist avoids because of
you know the specific insisted for
instruction set architecture and because
they only have this limited set of
instructions that can be used to obtain
the relative addresses and this does not
receive it on the x86 architecture so
this is not applicable to exa districts
right all right let's send the speaker
again
[Applause]