thank you I'm Abe Clemens this work was
done in conjunction with similar
collaborators Nate Colette chaste
jin-kyu Rob Bochy and Mattias pair
Suribachi and Mattias Ferrer my co
advisers and I'm a second year PhD
student at Purdue University I'll be
discussing protecting bare metal
embedded systems with privileged
overlays so first off what is a
privilege what does a bare metal system
a governmental system is a system
without an operating system it runs
directly on the hardware there is no
separation between well there is no
kernel or operating system if there's an
operating system it provides lightweight
threading and is compiled with the
application there is no separation
between user space or kernel space it's
all one memory space these systems have
very tight constraints on memory and run
time and energy a large system would
have like a megabyte of memory for code
and 120 kilobytes of RAM this would be a
kind of a larger end bare-metal system
some examples of these systems are
Amazon's - button smart door locks
engine controllers sdcard controllers so
inside of your sdcard there's a
microcontroller that handles flash we're
leveling this is an example those run
bare metal code Wi-Fi system mounted
chips these are in your cell phone
they run the Wi-Fi connections because
of the constraints the small memory
sizes low power requirements Security's
often just left out as an example
Google's Project zero this last earlier
this month disclosed that they'd found
vulnerabilities that broad comes a Wi-Fi
system on a chip that enabled them to
just by having Wi-Fi on your phone on
take control of your application
processor they were first able to take
control of the Wi-Fi system on chip and
then use that to elevate and obtain
accesses within the kernel on the
application processor so security on
these systems is important on it's just
been left out so let's look a little
more closely at these embedded systems
this is a memory layout so an important
thing to know about their layout is it's
fixed everything is physical memory down
at the bottom you've got flash this is
where you
code would be located and your code will
be at a fixed address if everybody's
using the same micro that's where your
code is the RAM same thing fixed address
every and it will be you know usually in
the middle as you go up you have
peripherals that are mapped into your
memory I'll often refer to these as
memory map registers if you want to
control one of these things you read or
write that fixed address of the i/o and
they also contain some security hardware
but will find that everything on the
system runs with the single execution
domain everything runs as route if there
is security Hardware it's unused or
trivially bypass as an example because
everything is in route and the security
hardware is configured by writing to
fixed memory locations where it's
located a single memory corruption
vulnerability with a label you to just
turn off any sort of security Hardware
that's enabled any sensitive i/o would
be always accessible your RAM any of
your global data or stack is unrolled a
stack smashing code injection global
data corruption in your code and your
stack employed no Rob defenses
essentially we're sitting 30 years back
when these devices from desktops today
so we have defenses for all of these on
desktops why don't we have them on these
systems one of the chief challenges to
this is there's a single application
there's no separation of privileges all
of these defenses we have on your
desktop rely on usually your operating
system to configure the permissions for
your memory pages we don't have an
operating system to configure the
permissions because configure them just
in the one applica configure them in
your application your application can
just disable them the systems like a
memory management unit they have no
virtual memory this limits all of your
defenses to physical memory and so you
have a small space so LSR doesn't work
because you have a very small memory
space again the small memory size of
limit diversification they also mean
that any defense that you apply must
have a very small memory overhead and
the same thing with run time constraints
combined these have led to security just
being left off these systems to address
this
we've developed epoxy which we then
acronym for embedded privilege over lay
across pegs hardware for why software
it's an LLVM compiler and we targeted
for our brief concepts the cortex-m
series of microcontrollers it protects
against code injection control flow
hijacking data corruption direct
manipulation of i/o and chief to its
protections or is this privilege overlay
this creates two privileged levels a
privileged and unprivileged level using
some static analysis attic analysis and
this is foundation to us enabling other
defenses to be applied so I'll go
through each of these protections and
how they're applied throughout the
remainder of this presentation first
though our threat model we're assuming
an arbitrary memory corruption there's
an attacker with an arbitrary memory
corruption if the attacker either wants
to obtain execution or corrupt specific
global data they does not have physical
access to the device under attack we
require that the hardware supports to
privilege level execution modes so
privileged and unprivileged execution
modes we need a memory protection unit
this is a piece of hardware that's in
modern microcontrollers that enable
setting read write execute permissions
on physical memory and then we also
require that the memory usage be
determined a priori the maximum memory
that the application will use has to be
able to be determined a priori which is
a restricted restriction on these
systems that already exists we have such
small memory space you have to know that
it's going to be able to execute within
the memory that you have so as I go
through this presentation I'll take this
out the application I will show here and
I'll build up the defenses around it so
here I'm showing again that applications
memory space with the everything is
privileged right and everything is
accessible so so go through the defenses
all change colors and add to the
defenses and show how they work so the
first approach that we believe perform
is called privilege overlay this creates
the multiple privilege lairs it's all a
result it enables a developer to assume
access to all memory locations so the
developers developing an application for
these systems they have all this F
Kayson has to manage all the hardware
needs to be able to access it but for
security requirements we need to
restrict access to some of this so that
it's not trivially bypassed for example
the memory protection unit if the
developer enables it but we leave
everything is privileged then it's too
easily turned off however this one
application has to be able to enable the
memory protection unit so the way we do
this is we let the developer assume
access to everything within you static
analysis to identify any privileged
operation so a privileged operations are
instructions that are defined by the
architecture that have to have
privileges to execute an example to be
enabling and disabling interrupts and
then we also identify access to any of
these peripherals that are required
privileges for example the memory
protection configuration unit or
developer defined sensitive i/o so these
again are fixed memory locations where
the where you read and write to access
these peripherals so our static analysis
identifies these reads and writes and
automatically elevates privileges to do
this we inject several different pieces
of code with epoxy so we configure the
memory protection unit this is code
that's injected automatically by the
compiler it enforces death or data
execution prevention and research access
to these sensitive peripherals or
sensitive registers we reduce the
executions privileges of the entire
application which kicks the whole
application out of privileged mode and
then we insert requests to around
restricted operations and then we
elevate those we have a handler we check
the handler to handle those requests so
I'll go through an example show how this
happens so in this example the orange
denotes privileged execution and we've
got a UART that is located at the
address dead beef and we're reading from
that you are this is a sensitive
operation so when we apply privileged
operations the first thing we'll do will
kick the application out of privileged
mode so blue denotes on privileged
execution then we will the static
analysis will identify that this read to
this fixed address
is sensitive so we'll insert a request
for privileges just preceding
it will drop privileges immediately
after which results in just a small
orange section with privileges executing
so as you can see we reduce drastically
the amount of operations that require
privileges and enable this operation
than just this operation to occur with
privileges so after applying privilege
overlay if we tie this back to desktops
we have enabled death we have data
execution prevention this means that our
RAM or our global data and our stack are
set to read write know execute you can't
execute them stat code injection has
been stopped we in our code our code is
set to read execute it's no longer
writable and this provides our code
integrity and there are some small areas
which require privileges but the rest of
it's unprivileged execution and finally
any sensitive i/o is also restricted to
privileged privileged execution the
further protected system we apply
defenses against Rafa tack we use state
stack and diversification save stack is
from the code pointer integrity project
from OSD I in 2014 it protects against
stack smashing the way it works is it
takes those static analysis on the
program identifies any variables that
are unsafe and moves them to a separate
unsafe stack an unsafe variable is a
variable that either its address escapes
the bounds of the current function or
it's used in a pointer arithmetic in a
way that we can't prove is safe and then
only those functions which use variables
that are unsafe actually use a the
unsafe stack frame so the problem is
that relied on virtual memory we don't
have that so we have adapted it to this
bare metal systems the way we've done
that safe stacks of split stack approach
so split into two two parts we move the
unsafe stack to the top of memory change
its direction so that it's growing away
from global data we use the MPU to
configure our guard region which is
inaccessible to both privileged and
unprivileged execution so in this way we
have a separate region for the unsafe
stack we have a separate reason for the
stack we've isolated all on
they flew globals up into the unsafe
deck region and then the further
protection we apply some diversification
so the way that we apply diversification
is epoxy takes a seed based off that CD
generates a unique binary when we look
inside this binary we have the RAM and
it's a green area we've got unused
memory we take that unused memory we
break it up into five chunks of patty
these five chunks of padding we
distribute throughout the remainder of
the application portion goes to
providing at randomization to the stack
address part of it combined with the
data the BSS and then between the heap
and the unsafe stack when we look in the
data section there's a number of global
variables in this example is get ABCD
those are randomized along with that
padding to help increase the entropy
that we can create with this the BSS is
randomized in a similar manner this
diversifies the ramp diversity the code
we have functions foo bar Baz r2 and foo
first thing we do is we inject a handler
this will to handle any inappropriate
execution we then fill the rest of
memory with jumps to this handler
essentially single byte instruction or
four byte instructions which jump to the
handler we randomize the location of
everything which enables any-any this
random with all the locations of all the
Rob gadgets in the code and if execution
ever goes to a place which isn't
expected to execute it will go to the
tangler enabling it to be detected so
after applying all of these defenses we
have unlocked I saluted unsafe locals to
their own separate stack the global data
is protected stack smashing has been
prevented on the sacrificed a stack we
have Rob protections from diversity and
Rob
well it's essential for with all of
these protections enabled we now have
protections against Rob code injection
access to global specific global
variables and access to sensitive i/o
it's important though for these systems
that they have small overhead in
performance so to evaluate this we
evaluated the Beeb's benchmarks which is
a suite of 76 different applications
that are adapted to measure
performance on bare metal applications
we evaluate 75 of these one of them
allocate more memory than my system has
so then in these tables we've got
runtime on top power on the bottom SS is
safe stack only so value binaries with
only 50 occupies second ones privilege
overlay the center column which has
we've only applied privilege over
England all the defenses on the far
right column from it you can see that
our average we average one around 1% for
overhead and our powers about 2.2
percent we also tested three IOT
applications these applications as you
can see that there they always use under
10% of energy or runtime and we'll see
and that the energy and runtime are
highly correlated with the exception of
the pin lock or the first one that it's
blocking on i/o is reading from a new
serial port and because of that the
execution time gets hidden but the
energy distribution does not get hidden
we have very limited ability to make
entropy on these systems we have very
little memory so we want to understand
how Roth attacks would work on these
systems so to do this we compiled a
thousand variants of each of these
applications and then we looked at how
many gadgets was existed across all a
given number of variants so in the
center we've got you know the two column
represents the two gadgets survived and
then last represents the number at which
the last gadget survived across two
variants so for the worst case we have
around 107 so around 10% there was 10%
of the gear or 10% of the variance will
be have be able to be attacked by one
gadget and since gadgets or Roth attacks
usually require multiple gadgets the
ability to create a good Roth attack
that's scaled across a large set of
devices would be greatly hindered by the
application of epoxy then we want to
compare how many privileged instructions
we execute to do this
took free artists which is a very common
operating system used for bare metal
systems it has a secure version it's
very infrequently used that uses the
memory protection unit to apply some
coding data execution prevention
however by default configuration it
doesn't even do that
so we've poured the applications to free
archive MTU and you find that we use the
well under 1% of instructions are
privileged and free our custom view
around 95% required privileges this is
because free artists requires that if
any instruction uses privileges the
entire thread also requires privileges
in conclusion we fast forward bare-metal
security three decades by recompiling an
application we've provide
state-of-the-art protections which are
comparable or exceed those currently
deployed on the desktop we don't require
rewriting an application provide song
track protections vice an adapted safe
stack minimize the number of privileged
instructions executed and diversify all
memory we also meet the runtime
requirements for bare metal systems and
memory and energy we've also open
sources our compiler is available the
following location any questions legend
I am Veloz NXP Semiconductors so I was
interested in the performance figures
that you showed we're actually using
epoxy gave improvement or how should I
see these figures and can you explain
why okay so it's a diversifying compiler
so the instructions change from each
binary and so the way we did an
improvement or speed-up is sometimes by
randomizing locations of functions it
enables the compiler to identify
additional optimizations the other
things that occurs is sometimes you have
long jumps and short jumps essentially
it would require a different number of
instructions so by randomizing the
binary we obtain a different mixture of
basically immediate addressing versus
absolute addressing okay thank you so I
also have a quick question when you add
any when you are identifying sensitive
operations do you need users to annotate
the code to tell you where sensitive
data is so I in an hour
currently all the sensitive operations
are accesses to peripherals which have
fixed addresses that are set in the
hardware so for those that are specific
to like that are coming across an
architecture say arm arm cortex-m force
the system control blocks have the same
address on all of those those ones are
compiler handled automatically if I as a
developer say in this act is miss
context this serial port is sensitive I
want it to be sensitive then you can
provide that to the compiler and it will
include it in its analysis you didn't do
that you experiments as closely the pin
lock actually applies to the UART in the
pin lock it senses to find it sensitive
okay thank you any other questions ok
let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]