it okay so
everyone the button
so I am the product at CMU and today I
will talk about how the particle can be
used to vision about the such an attack
so it is I work with my colleague at CMU
now so actually if you are familiar with
the information flow then you know about
the non-interference property so the
knowledge of authority figures so no
high information no high security flow
to the now security so in other words so
the high security the North will affect
the loud security so if we consider the
the effector so who can offer the public
output and consume the public input of
the program so if the program satisfied
then only difference would be so then is
the Itsuki again this article so however
in practice so the start of the high
security or the now security so they are
public information and the this open
section of the program is observable so
that means they are not security so and
the non-interference property say
nothing about the information flow to
the distort consumption for example so
third if we consider an attacker so who
can observe the public output the side
of the data and the total resource
consumption program and also seek and
control the public input so now so the
nun interference would be cannot be used
to reason about the the security of this
program again this attacker to file for
the book so we consider here a simple
sequence or search program so this
program so to execute only delete item
until a mess for the key file we
consider a setting where the need is
high security so that means the contain
until it is secret and the output is
high stability - and the third key is
now security so in the public
information so which is a so this
program is satisfied the
non-interference booty however if we
consider the
research consumption and the size of the
security list as a now security later
then there is an information flow from
the high security to the the different
conception because the difficult system
depends on the matching position of the
turkey in engine in the security needs
so an article but of the way the differ
conclusion though we can learn about the
secret content of the list so two
seasons about this you know this Kyle so
in practice so describe attack is called
the circular attack right so to reason
about this kind of attacks a wisp of all
the new notions of the notion about
resource aware non interpret so what is
the meaning of this awareness little
friend so first so it's either no heart
activity flow through this now security
so that means so it ends toward the the
classic non occurrence property moreover
if the high security later the size of
the high security later effect then it
requires on the execution of the program
food you the content dessert consumption
so the effector if we observe the
different conception of the program so
that the observing resort consistent are
laughing about the heart activity so at
a vigil to only the start of the high
security later to affect the dessert
construction so come back to the
with example so here I provide an
implementation in functional language
okay moe
so we you assume that so suppose that so
the Sun could go consume the Vsauce and
other operation consume no detox so here
are in the thick command to indicate
that so the first electrical cost
quantitative list and other operation
cost 0 basically
so because the dysfunction auto voiture
own items in the secret list from the
beginning to the end of the list so the
the total number of core
equivalent to the length of the list so
by the definition so the program satisfy
the requirement interval T and in fact
this program is currently accepted by
our site system so I will talk about the
participator at a welfare program okay
so in the work so we propose
quantitative language by sources to
reason about the fractional attack -
first we design visual tactical tool to
group program such that the resource
consumption is content if the size of
the inputs are fixed second so we desire
security paxton so it is a on the
classic information flows oxygen and it
cooperates with the resource item to end
for the digital we're done attention
purity practically we also provide a
method to quantify the amount of
information leakage when the program is
non content detox program and we also
provide an interactive and automatic
program repair positive to transform the
guilt I program into the website program
so if it also I will focus on the design
of the security system and other things
so you can find the paper so from a high
level view so our work at follow the
first user provides our psychic
model so the model specified
so this soft conception of realities in
the programming language and second the
either for biosecurity labelled napping
so that map's their variable to the
security level and the program circuit
then the system will check whether the
program satisfy the awareness of
impunity it's lost you can use
interactive and automatic Reaper
positive to transform the the filter
program into the website program so
about the security circuit and the
desire security tactical so the party to
be beyond the sender information flows
item so that means are all that data
type and updated with the security level
however here we allow to form of
government
so here the PC is a program culture
security level so it is to check the
implicit information flow at in the
center info information flow tactical
and the gamma is a security context so
that map the variable to the security
level security type and what is the
meaning of the document so that is under
the security settings Rama and the
program culture PC so the equal P has a
security type s and it satisfies the
non-interference property if the
documents have the content occasion then
we equally satisfied the resort we're
learning the property so that we D d CQ
again the spatula attack okay and how we
can
see Lisa when Anita for annuity with the
site title so given that program or the
only person satisfied in traffic none
interface with it so then there are two
ways to end focus see this aware
non-interference body so it is they are
the global and locally reasoning so
first method is Global's easily so we
used to be either this or PI system to
check the whole program is a Content
resource consumption so this method is a
but it requires her to reason about part
of the program that are not affected by
high fertility later e the second method
is no collision e so we answer that so
every committed equation in the program
branching on the high security later he
contacted for construction
so this method is not sufficient because
it can visit the valid program and
accept the invalid program so for
example this program so the insufficient
of the local reasoning
so here the reference on is reverse the
input needs so it is the content
resource consumption in terms of the
total number frontal call so I assume
that the referent only invented in the
ahkamaat language okay and B is high
security boolean variable so in the
first program F 1 so the if statement is
a Content deferred consumption because
here is the diesel consumption is 0 for
the most part of the external however
the tuple equations of the function f 1
does not satisfy the resource when an
interface so them is here if we owe you
only the local reasoning so we will
visit we will accept the invalid program
ok
and in the second example the if
statement is not concerned with us
consumption however the super expected
the function f to satisfy the resource
aware not interpose booty to eat again
here it will only the no code easily
letter so we will visit this valid
program so to overcome the issue so our
security pack system is mix of global
and local jiggly so it ends with us to
every expression affected by high
security is digital where nani different
person or it is your subject question
about this or aware not interval each
person so it is our because at the end
to the total this what consumption is
the content so about no code easily if I
have the the some important II one so
it's a bit far the resource when an
interval body and I have another sub
expression e2 it also satisfies the when
a little woody and they are connected by
or now security later so I can conclude
that so the super expression e satisfied
the resource aware learning different
property for our party term so capture
the locals easily for the book the
packing rule for the now security
condition expression so here if I have a
both one of the if equation so they
satisfy the digital where nani token
booty so with the corn and ovation here
and the conditioner of the it's equation
is now security later and then i
conclude that soldier if a person
satisfy the this one on Interphone
property about global disney so assume
that I have a tutor expression e1 and e2
so they don't have the
the total we're not interpret woody and
I have a super expression e it is a
constant default conception equation
that I can conclude that so the super
liquid should be satisfied the reason
we're not listed for new booty so our
security system captures the global
leaders reasoning by cooperating with
the resource ID system so here if I have
the equation e so it satisfies the
classic non-interference property and it
is well type in the default PI system of
the mean it is the contributor
consumption that I conclude us
so the equation e satisfied the reason
we're not linked the first property to
boost the content because program so we
use the resource pack item so here I
only with an overview of the research
bicycle and the detail you can find the
paper so the research item is by on
v.i.c pink items using too potent of
methods of the a motif analysis so here
in our title if the port enter cannot be
greatest our creators so the difference
which is the in deter potato and the
final code enter give the exact the
third consumption of the program so if
the final potato is 0 then the emitter
potato gives the content without
conception of the program so about
evaluation so we have a implanted
working prototype so it can reason about
the program with the resource
consumption in linear and polynomial so
we evaluated the the tool with the
common primitive function and the
function related to cryptography and the
function related to later megabyte query
so here we the model is specified
different cosmetic so for example the
number of evaluation step the number
frontal call or the 35 cosmetic so to
sum up if the talk so our interview
about the notion of resource aware
London's different routine to reason
about the such an attack and the desire
of the security tight system so it is
combine the classic information flow
item and the resource item for tracking
both information flow and the resource
consumption behaviors of program so you
can try the tune of the lead website and
we want to unroll it about the
limitation of our apples so here we see
that so our PI system can not reason
about the efforts of the compilation
tool and the hardware platform for
example it cannot even about the
compound optimization the garbage
collection as in the bigger talk and
also the cut trees the hardware cutting
mechanism or the instruction we dictum
in the hardware platform so add a future
work so we want to make the pot model to
capture the effects so I will end the
talk now and thank you and I happy - I'm
happy to take the question
any questions is there no alcohol take
the opportunity to make an adult husband
for for wench and he will be on a job
market in the next higher season so if
y'all have openings please get in touch
with Kim thank you
so Sandra clicky from UC San Diego so
you had via the tick function as one of
the resources so if you're doing
something with the tick function is the
resource to the developer have to
annotate their program with the function
lo ultimate in fact so that users can
analyze the program using the pluggable
we in interval X and we provide the
tick's command for either to specify
what is the code model of the primitive
in the programming language but here we
in our implementation so we we implement
for the oak emotional risk of the subset
of the oh c'mon memories thank you
um yeah um so your paper mentions that
that there is a long history of work in
this area and then it says something
about what distinguishes your current
work from the prior work and as I
understand it it says that the
difference is that the attacker is
allowed to observe the final resource
consumption I don't quite understand
that can you say anything about it so
actually here so the effect models are
so we only allow the article to octa the
the final and total default consumption
of the program and the us we don't know
that the article can observe the default
consumption in between the execution of
the program okay let's take a speaker
again
[Applause]