okay
now we're live uh i
i wasn't expecting this so this is a bit
of a bit of a scuff for me but um
yeah sorry about that uh
delay but uh here's
angela fernstrom with sub security as a
web developer
all yours
this person and
i am getting feedback from someone um
there we go um
very cyber security and privacy
conscious person
and was learning a lot more through the
course of that relationship
um but my professor said the mentalities
just don't go together web devs want
everything as open as possible and then
security wants everything locked down
and closed
relationship didn't last but what did
last is the importance of cyber security
in my job
because in my opinion web development
and security not only can go together
but really should
so as a webmaster for what has quite
frankly been a lot of projects over the
years
i've always felt that part of my job is
to be at least
somewhat conscious of the security risks
and concerns for each individual
project sometimes those risks are a
little bit much
smaller they're things that just come
with having any kind of online presence
and then other times the risks are a
little bit more serious and it really
just varies
depending on the project most of my
career has centered around fields that
tend to be a little bit more security
sensitive than others might be
i've worked for the idaho department of
administration which
is now the office of information
technology services the idaho department
of finance and i now work for the
federal courts district of idaho
and then in my volunteer time i
typically end up creating websites
for youth or security organizations
this has included several girl scout
events b-sides boise
b-sides idaho and then also idaho
infraguard
so throughout this please keep in mind
i'm not a security professional
i am a web developer who is doing her
best to keep security a priority in her
life and her career
but i'm going to walk you through some
of the websites and projects that i've
worked with
in the past and i'm hoping that
with you seeing my thought process you
can kind of see what someone outside the
security community
sees as a risk how they implement what
sort of precautions they can
and maybe get a little bit of an insight
in how some of your devs might think
so first off let's take a look at some
of the projects
the first site is one that i'm pretty
certain you've all visited it's actually
the besides idaho website the event site
for this event
um security event websites that i've
created they all tend to have the goal
of conveying
information event information like the
time and place the event schedule
how to get tickets how to submit a talk
important links social media stuff
community resources just all that sort
of stuff
the idaho infraguard idaho website is
similar in a lot of ways
they want to convey information about
the organization how can you join how
can what are some current and upcoming
events what's contact information
links to those events and information
about the local board
so i've also worked on a lot of
government websites
part of my job at the department of
administration was to help agencies that
didn't have a web developer
create and manage their websites the
ones that i've worked on have primarily
been information repositories for the
public
these websites share information about
the agency like what
they regulate which can sometimes be
confusing they have contact information
sometimes they have laws rulings and
regulations that the agencies control
sometimes the agencies share licensing
information and requirements they have
legal decisions fees and fines industry
news stuff like that
and then now working at the federal
courts we also have information about
our judges
we have information for lawyers if you
get a jury duty notice we have
information about that
orders and rules and then also because
of the way the idaho district court is
structured we actually have probation
and pre-trial services information as
well
so then covet starts and government
websites
have a ton of extra contact information
they have extra forms they've got
information about if the physical
location is open or closed
allowing more online submissions of
forms sometimes agencies have
implemented online chats
and just across the board it's been a
ton more
traffic and then the last thing that i
want to look at with you guys
is a couple of girl scout websites the
first one it's pretty similar to the
b-sides idaho
site it's an event site event
information registration form
done the other one though um
this is a site for an event that
averages 1500 people
and when we initially talked about the
website the requirements had
processing and storing of health
histories medication info
full contact info which includes phone
number email address and physical
address
emergency contact information birthdays
grade levels
driver's licenses which is both the
driver's license number and a scan of
the card
car insurance info information uh girl
scout id numbers and then on top of all
of that
we're supposed to be processing credit
card payments that one's going to be a
mess
so i'm sure you guys are picking up on
some of the risks that
i did but i want to show you what i
picked up on when i
start working on these projects so first
up the security sites
security industry websites they have a
reputation of being
tested as a good word for it a few years
ago some of the infragard chapter
websites were actually targeted in a
series of attacks by hacktivists
the and then the infraguard site also
kind of has an extra layer of
risk because that falls into both
security and government website
categories
as infraguard is a public-private
partnership with the fbi
on the topic of government websites
there always a target like always
some of the government website specific
risks that i've personally seen
are being defaced denial of service
attacks and
accidentally posting non-public
information which is also a fun one
of course there's a ton of other risks
and government sites aren't the only
ones with these risks this is just in my
experience
one of the worst fears of a government
agency is ending up on the news
and any one of those will get you there
almost immediately so that's a problem
then lastly the one that i'm sure you
guys are all cringing over
is that girl scout website that first
one
i'm not as worried about registration
form was on another site
it wasn't actually any input on my site
i'm also not quite as worried about
these sites being hacked into or defaced
as i might be for government site or
the security industry stuff
the other website though that big
website that one touches on some of my
absolute deepest fears as a web
developer
we're not collecting any analytics so we
don't have to worry i'm not as worried
as much about kappa but we are dealing a
lot with hipaa
pci pii laws and it's for kids
so the site is going to process a ton of
information for over a thousand miners
plus all of the adult volunteers that
are involved
and then on top of that when i'm working
on a girl scout website one thing that i
am always worried about
it um are predators and then posting too
much information about the event photos
that are being shared to promote the
event
again not only is this straying really
really far into regulatory waters and
privacy issues
these are kids that we're worrying about
so
as a web developer how do i deal with
these issues
for the simpler sites like the security
sites and that first event website for
girl scouts
one of my go-to methods of sort of
securing the site
is just making it as flat as possible
i've been told that this could be called
security through simplicity
i don't know if that's real term but i
like it and i'm keeping it so i'm using
it
um i obfuscate email addresses i
sanitize the form input if the
organization insists on having one
stuff like that again if we use the b
sites idaho site as an example that site
is
all html css and javascript there's no
input from the users
the page is put together on the server
it's sent to your browser
css makes it look pretty javascript
makes it do fancy things because i'm
using bootstrap
that's it it's not a perfect website
it's not the most interactive it's not
the most amazing or groundbreaking thing
you've ever visited
but a simple flat website is exactly
what we needed for the event so that's
what i delivered and that tends to be
the case for most events that i've
worked with
when working on a government website i
thankfully have
other teams that i can work with and
lean on i have worked
i work with the security team server
team networking teams
to make sure that the infrastructure in
and of itself is secure to begin with
and then on top of that i have to do my
job so in one instance
as part of the web team we were dealing
with a denial of service attack
the solution that we came up with was to
set up the system to dump requests from
a given ip
if they sent too many requests in a
certain amount of time
other times the server team has sent
through an urgent update that we need to
install like right now
we've also set up alerts for suspicious
activity
and we can configure that to be sent to
specific teams if needed
for example one of the agencies that
i've worked with they send an email to
the security team if an ip gets a
certain number of errors in a given
amount of time
so in addition to working with other
teams i have to make sure that i'm
following secure coding practices
again go to method of this is kind of a
simple flat site that i mentioned before
offers fewer attack vectors harder to
get into stuff like that
but honestly in today's world that's not
always an option
especially with everyone interacting
with everything online
so stuff like sanitizing form input
training end users making sure patches
and updates are always installed
up and up to date those things all
become very important
government also has an added kind of
risk
of is this really for public consumption
that's a problem um to mitigate this
i will usually double check everything
that someone sends to me to post
i'll check with my manager i'll check
double check with the person hey are we
sure this needs to be posted
but really that's something that
shouldn't be only on me as the developer
that needs to be a cultural and training
thing in the agency
and then we're going to look at that
girl scout website so
pretty sure you can understand why i was
like nope
i'm not doing this those requirements
are way too much
i don't want to mess with hipaa pci pii
this hits all three of those
and i'm not avoiding them to hide what
i'm doing
and it's not necessarily because i'm
afraid of them it's because i don't know
how to do them
right all i know is enough to know that
these things are an issue this is a
volunteer group
we don't have the funds to hire a
security professional who does know how
to do these things right
and honestly that's a lot of work so the
first thing that
we looked at is assess the need of the
site
do we really need to be collecting all
of that information
and unfortunately the answer was yes the
only thing
that we could actually remove from that
list of requirements
was the mailing address so what do we do
now
we outsourced so first thing we did was
we found a service that actually
specializes
in excuse me in youth camp health
histories
literally all they do that's their thing
so what we're going to do is we're going
to direct the girls and the adults to
their site
to complete the health histories and
then as we've been working with the
service we were actually able to
customize
the forms that we give to the adults to
accept the driver's licenses car
insurance information that we need
this company they've got security in
place they know what they're doing they
have their hipaa stuff figured out this
is what they do
so we don't have to worry about that as
much
also from a more physical security
standpoint
having everything in a really organized
easy to access location for our nurse
on site is going to be really helpful as
well
the next thing we looked at was payment
there's a little bit of wonkiness with
how girl scout
rewards works that means we can't just
like automatically send them to
a payment page um so we were having a
little bit of trouble with that but the
solution that we came to
was we will be creating paypal invoices
closer to the event for the remainder of
the balance
and then that invoice will direct them
to paypal's website where they can
pay the invoice with a card again
paypal has pci figured out they have
security in place they know their stuff
last thing is the pii
we can't get around needing all of that
information because
running a huge event like that we need
information
but what we can do is avoid storing it
on with the website
so if we figured out that if we collect
just the name and the girl scout id we
can actually cross-reference that with
the information that we get from our
council office
get the data that we need like the
birthdays the grade level stuff like
that
and then we can actually store that
offline so
just by addressing the scope of the site
we were able to eliminate
almost everything that i was worried
about still have a lot of information
we still have a lot of input to sanitize
but at least we're now at a point that
i'm not having nightmares about being
the cause of a hipaa or pci breach and
pii is no longer stored someplace that's
easily accessible
online so girl scouts again along with
those
issues i do have to worry about how much
is being shared
girl scout sites they're not necessarily
hidden they're not like password
protected and stuff like that
but they're also not promoted i don't do
any seo work on them i don't submit them
to google i don't do anything like that
most of these sites they can really only
be found
if you follow the links directly from
the council website or the newsletters
that they only send to registered girls
and adults we are very careful about
what information we share about the
event
and the only photos of girls if there
are any i have done several events
but there are no photos of girls shared
on the website
are ones that we know have signed photo
release forms and the parents are okay
with it
um last names never shared and often
we use camp names or nicknames instead
of the first names so it's again
a little bit yeah um
this is an instance that honestly i feel
like just the mere existence
of having a website makes a risk and so
we can't be perfect but what we can do
is just absolutely everything we
possibly can to protect the girls and
their data
so ultimately what my professor said it
indicated to me as a student
a level of animosity between the web
development and security industries but
i've never actually encountered that
some of the web developers that i've
worked with have actually been some of
the most security conscious people i've
met outside of the security industry
which going off what my professor was
saying would be a big surprise
at some level all of us as web
developers are very aware of the fact
that
honestly of all the i.t positions we're
one of the ones with the most public
facing contact
but everything that i've seen and all of
the web developers i've met indicates to
me that we want to help you
we don't want to make your job harder we
just don't know how to help and that's
really where you can come in as a
security professional work with your
developers to assess what's actually
needed for functionality of the site
help your developers understand why
something might be a risk because you
might see a risk that we are like why is
that a problem
um also another thing that i've noticed
is we're often all
not up to date on the latest security
news
so i'm subscribed to a couple of cyber
security newsletters i've got several
friends in the cyber security community
i often receive news about security
risks from
them instead of the web development
newsletters that i'm subscribed to
that's news about urgent security
updates for a content management system
like
wordpress or drupal or joomla
hosting platform breaches other website
web related security news
that can come from my security contacts
as much as two days before my web
industry sources
so really just letting your developer
know as soon as you hear about something
can really be helpful because if you're
frustrated that they're not jumping on
something that was just announced
they might not even know about it yet um
so i've been told that then this is an
actual quote i can't remember who said
it but
i've been told i know more about cyber
security than any web developer has a
right to know
honestly i don't think that should be a
bad thing um because a security
conscious
developer is actually going to make your
life as a security professional much
easier
so and that is
what i have
let me just move this over here so i can
actually speak again
so far do we have any there are um
questions uh hang on
mute unmuting myself on zoom would be a
really good idea
uh yes there are some questions uh what
are your thoughts on website builders
such as wordpress and do they ship with
good and or bad security out of the box
i would say that if you don't really
know what you're doing something out of
the box like that
is better than trying to figure it out
it's a little bit easier
security wise wordpress is always
always in the news for something
some sort of attack some sort of
security issue that they have so
if you are going to use something like
that just make sure you are as
absolutely up to date on
all patches as possible
and considering how frequently they
release them ain't that the truth
yeah it seems like almost daily
sometimes it really does it really does
um one of my jobs is a webmaster and i
it's wordpress based and i see them all
the time
here's an update he's not that he's an
update yeah
uh another question do you think cyber
security concepts ought to be taught
or required uh more for developers
either formally or as part of continuing
education
i honestly i think it's important for
everyone um not just developers
even just you know anyone going through
anything i think security is really
really important um
but yeah as a developer i do think that
it's something that
should at least have concepts talked
about in class in
um whatever training you're going to
because it's right now it's such a
drastic there's such a divide between
the worlds like
when i was in school we never talked
about security stuff
except for because i knew people in the
industry
um and i i really do think that that's
something that should be
brought in more and addressed for
everyone but yes for
developers included i tend to agree with
that one
uh that looks like it for questions
so that's uh that's gonna be us
uh thank you for your time that's
appreciated and i
gotta click this button over here