all right
three two one and go
good evening i hope everyone's had a
pleasant day and learned as much as i
have from besides
idaho 2020 i'm steve kirby and i'm a
security engineer with bright spring
health services in louisville kentucky
i want to talk about a subject that's
near and dear to my heart today which is
i.t certifications and security
certifications in particular
before we get started i want to mention
that if you notice down at the bottom
there is a
tiny url address you might want to jot
that down or
make a screenshot that will get you a
link to where you can download the
slides because people seem to
like to do that and it was just easier
to do it this way than to
worry about shuffling them back and
forth so
if you want to come back and get that uh
after the session's over
it it'll it'll be there for you to see
i might tell you a little bit about
myself i'm a former graduate student in
history
uh many many years ago i worked for
almost 10 years as a reference librarian
and kind of fell
into it work started off running a small
artist off lantastic network
sharing cd-rom databases back in the
late 1980s and that
moved and moved on to nobel netware and
then discovered unix
and spent 26 years of my life as a
unix systems administrator i've worked
with some
really old crusty stuff so uh i won't
bore you with the details but
it a lot of it now is museum grade stuff
uh along the way i picked up an interest
in
security work as i tell people mostly as
a means of preserving paycheck
continuity
because a lot of the systems i worked on
were
high profile to somebody
from somebody's perspective and having a
security breach would not have been a
good thing
i have earned a dozen security
certifications in the last few years
and that's important especially for talk
like this because you know somebody who
has certifications obviously is well
informed
and knows what they're talking about
i've got some of mine listed there
uh there are others but those those will
give you some idea of what i'm what i'm
about
i should open with a disclaimer that uh
the views
the next opinions that are expressed
here are entirely my own my employer
hasn't screened them hasn't approved
them in fact most of the people i work
with don't even know that i'm doing a
presentation today
so this is this is entirely me
and my employer should be held blameless
and all that good stuff
the question we're going to ask is are
you certifiable and people have been
telling me for years that i
am and i thought i thought it was a
compliment i thought they would were
saying that it would be easy for me to
get
certified in it's things i don't think
that's what they meant
but uh the question we need to ask is
can you do it and
the answer is of course yes it's not all
that difficult
uh certifications have a lot of
advantages over formal education for
example
uh a university degree or
maybe some specialized study and i say
that
speaking is from the perspective of
someone who spent 25 years
in higher education i believe in it but
there are advantages that certifications
offer over
conventional higher education number one
and possibly the most obvious is that
it's faster
a four-year degree takes four years uh
once you get started i guess you could
possibly knock out some certifications
in a matter of weeks uh it's also
cheaper higher ed
is not as not the value it was people i
work with
are stunned to find out that when i've
graduated from
college excuse me
sorry about that the
lights are apparently on a timer when i
graduated from college
back in the late 1970s uh
tuition was about 15 a credit hour
it's gone up considerably since then and
of course the other advantage
that certifications have are that they
are more focused on job skills
so it makes it easier to apply what
you've learned
to any positions you might be trying to
obtain
now it helps to have a framework if
you're trying to decide
what certifications you want to perceive
the one that i settled on
was the department of defense's 8570 or
8140 regulations
originally it was 8570 8140 is the
updated version
and there's a link there at the top of
the page
uh it's a little bit more complicated
than what i've got displayed here but
basically
uh these regulations divide
it certifications into two groups one
the iet group which would be for
technical people who do hands-on work
and the other for managers labeled iam
there are there's a little bit of
overlap between them uh some
certifications could be used for either
category
but uh by and large it it separates out
two different
distinct paths depending on what sort of
positions that you think you might want
to apply for
now or in the future
it's going to do a little bit of what i
call exception exception handling
we're going to go back and talk about
some of those certifications
from the dod in a moment but i want to
mention
first of all microsoft's mta
certifications which are not
part which are not included on that list
they don't have the department of
defense's blessing
there are quite a few of them they're
entry-level certifications that are
geared towards
high school students or college students
or
people are looking to change jobs like
for example
someone who's been working on a help
desk and
is looking to make a transition into
something a little bit more advanced
they offer three that i would recommend
highly
one for network fundamentals that would
be introduce you to
basically windows networking and some
tcp
security fundamentals and then windows
servers fundamental
server fundamentals because those are
the network fundamentals and server
fundamentals
certifications talk about assets those
are the things that the security
professionals were trying to
protect and so it helps to have an
understanding of what those are
about hey steve steve can you hear me
[Music]
yes um you're uh you're
you're not advancing the slides for the
uh for the viewer
hmm
where do we get to yeah steve we're on
the first slide
you might have to kill your share and
then re-share possibly yep
looks like it thank you sorry that's all
right
how's that perfect thanks good deal
okay and there's the the dod 8570 list
that i mentioned
uh that could be that's a very useful
framework for
selecting certifications that you might
want to pursue
i mentioned microsoft's mta those are
the ones that i would recommend
most but there are others in addition
for example you wanted to learn about
sql server databases or other microsoft
technologies
that would be one avenue to pursue and
we'll talk about that a little bit later
and when we talk about
uh strategies for pursuing certification
i also want to mention cisco they have
recently revamped
a lot of their certification program
a lot of the certificates that were
listed on the
department of defense site
no longer exist or have had the names
changed
one that has had the name changed is the
cyberops certification and that one's
still around
uh but it is an entry-level
certification
that would be really useful if you're
looking for
a career in network security it's it's
designed to
uh obviously provide that sort of
background
one that has kind of gone by the wayside
there used to be
separate uh certifications for separate
ccna their
middle level uh network associate
certifications for security and other
other tools those have all been combined
into one
ccna exam so you don't have that option
available to you anymore
but it's it's not useful to note that
those do exist on the
department of defense site but you won't
be able to actually take the take those
starts any longer
which leads us to some certification
bodies
there are several that are that bear
special attention
one would be comptia the computing
technology industry association
and they are a very common very popular
uh
supplier of certification services
ranging from
lower level certs like a plus or network
plus here
which would be comparable to the
microsoft
network fundamentals certification that
i mentioned
security plus which is probably the best
known entry-level certification
available and then other more more
advanced certifications like cloud plus
which obviously deals
with cloud solutions their cysa
which is a blue team cyber security
analyst i believe is what stands for
uh certification that teaches you how to
deal with computer incidents
and how to protect assets pen test plus
the name
is reasonably descriptive uh it is
to teach people who are interested in
penetration testing
and offensive security and then last but
not least
is the casp plus which is their top
level uh certification
uh for people with about 10 years of
experience
it is a hands-on technic techie
certification as opposed to some others
that we'll talk about
here in a minute it's designed for
it's not designed necessarily for people
who want to be managers
but it's designed for people who want to
be doers
and actually uh
be involved in day-to-day
uh technical operations and i i possess
that one
and value it very highly
one neat thing that comptia started
doing a couple of years ago is what they
call
stackable certifications and what that
allows you to do is combine
one or two or more uh certifications
together and derive a third an a third
certification
for example security plus and their
cloud plus certification gets you
secure cloud professional so it's a way
of validating that you have
uh a skill set that transcends
one particular the the confines of one
particular search
isc squared or the international
information systems security
uh certification consortium is another
popular certification body
and they produce two certifications that
we'd want to talk about
one is the sscp the system security
certified
practitioner that is an entry to
intermediate level certification
and it may be one of the best values on
the certification market
you could take this test for about 250
dollars
as opposed to over 300 i think is the
standard asking price for most of
comptia certs some are even more
expensive than that
ise squared awful also offers the cissp
or certified information system security
professional
and that is probably the gold standard
for advanced
security certifications a lot of people
i know
have that is that that's on their
professional bucket list they they want
to achieve that certification
once they have done that they they they
feel like they will have
gone as far in their profession as they
as they need to go
a possible alternative alternative to
isc squared
is isaca which formerly had a long name
and decided sensibly
to change it to just isaca and they
offer three certifications i'd like to
mention the first is a relatively new
one
the csx cybersecurity fundamentals which
is
an entry-level certification but it's
not as basic
in its approach as say security plus or
the microsoft search
uh it's a little i thought it was a
little bit more difficult when i look at
the sample questions
uh the nice thing about this is that as
opposed to
some other certification bodies you
don't have to
there's no continuing education
requirement
so in addition to getting the isaca name
behind it
you don't have to go go through conti
and have continuing education
in order to keep the certifications
current virtually all comptia
certifications and all
of the ise squared uh certs do have that
requirement
uh the one the high level cert from
most common high level search from isaka
would be the cism or cism the certified
information security manager and that's
another popular one that would be a
counterpart to the cissp i know a lot of
people who have both
uh apparently there's a lot of overlap
in the study so
if the folks i know have gotten one and
immediately launched into prepare for
the other because it cut down on the
amount of study time
and then last but not least is the cisa
or
certified information systems auditor
and that name is pretty much
uh self-explanatory it's designed for
auditors or
people who want to take charge of
insurance compliance and systems
management
so there we've got a very brief outline
of a possible
set of security uh certification path
uh you might want to begin with
something like the microsoft mta
or cisco cyber ops or some of the lower
level comptia
certifications and spend the first two
to five years of your career
built building out a foundation
based on those certs and as you get a
little bit more experience you could
then start to look at things like the
cisa cysa plus or
pentest plus even cloud plus or uh
the sscp and as a capstone
when you once you've got to maybe the 10
to 12 year
experience mark you might want to look
at something like cast
plus or the cissp or
cism if you decide the latter two would
be if you
perhaps wanted to go into management
i should make a little bit of a mention
about potential online training
providers because
some of these certifications can be
quite expensive to prepare for
unless you do it yourself or
do something other than the vendor
supply training uh
there's a nice market in vendor supply
training
and the market can be quite substantial
one source for training that i would
recommend would be pluralsight
uh very popular and a good source of
videos on
individual topics if you notice there
they've got uh the cissp and the cism
and security plus so
in most in most cases they're going to
have one course for certification
it will be very in-depth and very very
very well done i've been
a loyal pluralsight customer for a long
time
in addition to certification training
pluralsight i should mention also offers
training
in security tools things like splunk
for a seam or vulnerability scanning or
things like security frameworks
that could be useful for learning job
skills or
for continuing education as you move
along in your career
linkedin learning is another potential
source of training it's very similar
in a lot of ways to pluralsight it used
to be known as lynda.com and one p
one reason people like it
linkedin learning or lynda.com as a
source is it's often possible to get a
uh get free access to it from your local
public library
microsoft bought lynda.com about 18
months ago
i don't know how long they're going to
continue that policy
but i've talked to people that have done
it recently so
the program hasn't been revoked yet
again you're going to have
one one course per certificate one set
of courses
for certification uh
and they're also for the most part quite
good
one of my favorites is udemy udemy is
kind of a contrast to pluralsight and
linkedin learning you will they do offer
online
video courses and they're some of them
are quite good
some of them are not so it's kind of a
hit or miss proposition
but in this case you're going to have
possibly
a half dozen or so courses possibly even
more i guess
dealing with the same certification but
they're provided by different
uh individuals or different groups some
of them are better than others
some of them are a lot better than
others so it's important that when you
evaluate udemy
you look at things like the star rating
over here on the right hand side
it gives you some idea of what people
who have taken the course think of it
you also want to evaluate
not again
you also want to evaluate the
last update because some of these
courses can take several
several years to develop and
they go out of date uh from time to time
sometimes they get left out on udemy for
purchase
even though they're dealing with an
older version of the certification
pack publishing is one of my personal
favorites
in addition to their relatively
inexpensive
uh subscription price you can actually
buy a lot of courses that are available
through udemy
and download them and take them with you
on your laptop
with pluralsight and linkedin learning
you can download to mobile devices
i don't recall if they have applications
for
pcs and macs or not but with linked with
pact you can get you can get a
subscription that would cover
uh a subset of what's on udemy anyhow
and in addition to that you get access
to
print with the electronic books uh
to go along with the videos
i will mention a few uh
instructors and publishers that i'm fond
of these folks
are both unpacked and on udemy
uh jason dion would be one
mike myers in total seminars would be
another and thor peterson
who specializes in the advanced level
certifications like cissp and schism
would be a third
cybrary is one a lot of folks are
familiar with
they've recently changed their business
model and i don't recommend them as
highly as i used to they've got some
good material
but it can get a little pricey these
days but it used to be no
it used to be well known because the
training was free and you paid for
certificates of completion but that has
changed
and last but not least i want to mention
professor messer
uh who offers courses through his own
website and then on youtube
free of charge he makes his money from
selling course notes
and other study materials printed study
materials
uh i haven't actually taken any of his
courses but i know several people who
have
who swear that they're quite good so i
recommend them very
recommending very highly
so to wrap up and summarize what we
talked about
credibility as a security professional
comes from a combination of experience
and credentials
the two are not con are not competing
they're complimentary lower level certs
like
credentials complement experience but
they don't replace it and vice versa
i think systems and networking
experience is essential for security
work
because they're a large part of the
assets we are protecting so it's
important to have a good
fundamental background in both systems
and networking
if you want to be a security
professional
things like passion hardening and
configuration skills can be reinforced
with security certifications
and of course as we mentioned even after
your career is launched
you'll need to earn continuing education
credits to keep most of your
certifications
and that means that learning never stops
hopefully this brief chat has provided a
a
overview of a potential framework for
chasing security certifications and a
reminder some of the
excellent low-cost means of learning i
think we have a few minutes left
i'll be glad to field any questions
yeah sure thanks steve thank you very
good information great resources there
there are
uh there is a question that we do have
i've transcribed it in there
okay also i noticed uh yeah you need to
tell your company to pay the power bill
there and it was
no i didn't lights went out a couple
times we were thinking maybe like put a
roomba and put a
uh maybe a broomstick uh with a witch
writing it or something
around in the back that's i think it
would take something like that i wasn't
prepared for that because
this we we moved out i moved out of this
building for a year
and when i left the lights would stay on
in perpetuity if i turned them on they
stayed on
apparently that has changed in the well
i was gone
well maybe we can hack into the light
system well but better
so let's get to the questions uh
question here so you mentioned a lot of
learning resources are there
is there a starting place for any
particular learning resources you would
recommend for somebody just starting out
like one of those you mentioned maybe
the starting place
i i would default towards pluralsight uh
in all likelihood uh it's not terribly
expensive if you want to buy a monthly
account for it it's about thirty dollars
i think linkedin learning is about
25 and if you want to gamble on one of
the udemy courses
you can often find them on sale for 10
to 15
and the nice thing about you to me is
that once you have access
to the course you've got it for life it
never expires
whereas pluralsight and lynda or
linkedin
are subscriptions that require an
ongoing commitment
but i would probably start with one of
those three that's a good point you
could buy them a la carte depending on
what you're interested in or if you want
a subscription model you could do that
as well and just kind of
go for the whole thing whichever works
best for you
all right uh also relating to that if
you're really interested in
just certification say you're interested
in cissp
is there a particular one of those
learning resources that might be better
than
another uh well the fellow who
wrote the cia wrote the cissp
training for ise squared as the one who
does
the cissp preparation course for
pluralsight
that would probably be a good one to
start with um
for security plus i enjoy but jason
dion's is quite good the one that
mike myers you has produced is quite
good i would recommend either of those
for folks who are looking for an entry
level um
peter thor peterson i mentioned who's on
udemy
and available through pac publishing
does a great job for cissp and cism
but doesn't do any of the entry-level
certifications so
and and professor messer uh for security
plus
and or network plus would be hard to
beat because those are those
resources are available for free for no
charge
all right excellent very good good
resources um
any last words in summary
no i think that's all i've got for
tonight i need to probably need to get
out of here before the lights go out
again
good call all right with that uh thank
you very much steve
uh excellent information thank you thank
you