longer earlier
and i'm refreshing too
this yeah it did take about this long
there it goes in three two
one you're live and i'm ready all right
well hi everybody i'm uh i'm josh stemp
i'm
a security engineer with the idaho
transportation department
i'm also floating around today as one of
the staff members
so thanks eric and uh sin ming for
getting us going and getting us running
so today i plan on presenting on getting
started in digital forensics and
incident response or dfir
and this is a topic that's kind of near
and dear to me
that i've kind of worked my way into a
little bit of luck but we'll talk about
how someone might be able to get into
this same type of career field and the
same path
if you're interested and want to kind of
steer into that you decide that that's
kind of your slice of
a slice of cyber that you want to do
so talking about my background uh like i
said i'm currently with the with itd
um in the past i've worked with super
value albertsons
uh a fortune 100 retailer working
endpoint security
and then i did some stuff with ocio or
its is
the organization keith tresh is with
from our keynote today
so that was some number of years ago
i've got about
coming up on 10 years of experience
doing
cyber security and i've spent the last
about five or six of it doing
um incident response and digital
forensics
so um these are of course you know that
i'm doing this presentation
independently
uh separate from the organizations that
i've formally been a part of so these
are my opinions
um but we'll uh we'll jump into
what we what the plan is to cover for
the next 20 minutes
um we're going to cover what is dfir
we're going to talk about some of the
different tools and skills that you
might have
that you might be able to implement in
what i find valuable and have
been able to leverage in my career how
someone might kind of
steer into that get into it if it's
something that they find themselves
interested in
and then finally once the presentation's
over i have a kind of a slick sheet
of some different free resources and
paid resources as well
that if you're interested in doing more
in this field
that you will be able to kind of
leverage and
and uh and work off of
so i kind of felt it was important to
kind of talk about how i
started in in forensics and
or dfir and kind of just so you
understand
where i came from i
had the first case that i
that i worked on um was
years and years ago my manager at the
time came to me who handled all of the
the forensics work and she was going to
be out the next week
and so she said hey you know we might
have something come up next week
um there you know i need you to kind of
take care of something for me
and uh there's kind of three things to
keep in mind
that first of all you know we've got
this write block kit use that
uh use use dd to image the hard drive
and um also take down the details of the
hard drive
so not having done it before just kind
of took her word for it
i uh you know she had talked it up a lot
about how difficult it was
how detail-oriented it was so i went out
to uh to barnes and noble of all places
and uh you know back when they actually
sold computer books and i got myself my
first
digital forensics book um which was the
hacking exposed digital forensics
computer forensics book
big yellow book i still have it it's um
well well used but i uh read through
some of that over the weekend
just to prime myself on some of the the
ins and outs of what i was going to be
potentially asked to do the next week
i got the call later than or
in the next week past weekend and uh
off i went someone got fired it was
potentially that they were going to sue
we needed to do forensics on that
computer
so i ran off and i collected the
brought it back to my desk brought over
the right blocking kit hooked everything
up pulled my book out
uh did dd on the hard drive
um over to blank media and
i looked at the hard drive not having
like ever really paid that much
attention to the number of details on
the hard drive i didn't really know what
details i needed at the time
so i thought well there's like a
thousand words here and a picture's
worth a thousand words so i just flopped
that hard drive onto a photocopy machine
a xerox machine
next to my desk and hit go stored
the paper copy with uh with the hard
drive
copy where i was supposed to store it
and i remember getting back to my desk
and saying you know
digital forensics is boring um
i can't do this like this is this is uh
there's no way that i could do this as a
daily job thank goodness
i'm doing cyber security instead
and the world kind of has funny ways in
which it works
and uh and now i do so what i didn't
know then is really what digital
forensics and incident response was all
about
so figure let's cover that um
dfir split up into digital forensics and
incident response
uh incident response really we're
focusing on
actually dealing with an active threat
there's a very high presentation there's
a lot of nuances
but i just wanted to kind of break this
down so
we're focusing on an active threat to
the organization
and stopping that containing it
boxing it in and eliminating it and then
on the digital forensics side we're more
going in and trying to find the
we're processing the digital evidence to
actually find the answers
uh that we're seeking in our
investigation
uh the incident response i kind of find
akin to
um like a paramedic who arrives on like
a crime scene
um they will often
just stabilize the patient and
will provide certain medical
interventions just to get things going
in the right direction for them
uh whereas a detective will come in and
kind of do you know
something like digital forensics where
they're going to look into
what this specific issue is they're
going to find out who was at fault what
weapon was used what tool was used was
it forced or not forced
so on and so forth so that's kind of an
easy way i tend to differentiate the two
forensics also it tends to be it's it's
forensics
was uh was its root it's a latin root
um back from roman era when we would
have kind of
public court and so it's it's a you know
in a forum in front of forum so
[Music]
a lot of times uh forensics will still
be tied
to uh legal process there's lots of
arguments about that
and this that's outside the scope of
this presentation
so let's talk about now that you kind of
know what it is a little bit or a little
bit more about it
maybe you're like hey this is
interesting i'm curious
i've seen this on tv and maybe i want to
do this myself
so let's talk about a couple common
career paths
uh that you can take into this uh the
two most common that i see
are and there are others but the two
most common are law enforcement
coming up with a legal background going
through a detective into a crime lab
something like that
or the other side is that incident
response mentality
of defending networks and investigating
intrusions
usually like military dod federal
networks things like that
those the two most common like
experiences
i see uh when i look at forensic
practitioners
um that you know i follow and things
so i did neither of those
i went a different route and so i kind
of wanted to talk about how
i did this route and how you might do
that route as well
so really if we're looking at at law
enforcement and military kind of having
this like fat
they they get a leg up with a lot of the
ex the hard earned experience that they
get
up front a lot of the the the things
they encounter that just
we don't deal with in everyday life
so we have to kind of compensate for
that and
a part of that is being in the right
place
at the right time with the right tools
and i found that this is kind of
a algorithm that is at the heart of
every
every major change that i've done in my
career
is i've been in the right place at the
right time with the right tools
but being the right place and the right
time are
largely luck-based so we really can't
influence those
as much as we want to uh so we really
need to focus in on the right tools
and in tools i don't necessarily mean
tools as in like
hardware or kit though will
that is a part of it we'll get into that
eventually i'm thinking more the soft
skills the
the attributes um things like that so
let's
let's take that and let's separate that
off and let's see what we can do
about actually influencing those right
tools
section so really
i've broken it into four pieces here we
have education experience
attributes and equipment um education
this is you know something hotly
contested keith even
um even talked about this in his in his
presentation working with the colleges
degrees while i don't have a degree and
degrees
aren't what i would consider absolutely
necessary um
there are a lot of doors that are opened
by having a degree
as opposed to not having one
instead i kind of go down the path of
certifications
i'm fortunate to have to have been able
to take
several uh well a majority of the sans
forensics
and incident response pro portfolio
classes and i have
a number of certifications from them um
there's endless debates about
certifications as well
and uh my viewpoint on this for the
purposes of this
discussion is you need something to
differentiate you
to say that in the mind of joe public
that you know what you're doing um and
that you can demonstrate that
and at the end of the day having a
certification
uh on your resume that says i am you
know a certified ethical hacker or a
cissp
or you know a certified forensic analyst
um
leads joe public to think that you know
more about that topic than the average
person
um so that's that's really kind of what
matters there
when we get to experience this is
everything that's not education this is
your
your i.t background uh this is you know
you're likely a cyber professional
who has worked their way up through the
ranks or
is in a cyber position that you
came from somewhere maybe you came from
the help desk maybe you came from
network or server background i came from
a sysadmin background myself
that shapes uh kind of the tools that
you have in your toolbox
and in regards to experience uh also
some things
might be like investigative experience
in a lot of ways you know you kind of
have the scientific method that you rely
on as a technician for a lot of things
but the actual investigative process to
go through and
and you know kind of
suss out an investigation in a nice
unbiased way without jumping to
conclusions
is not necessarily something that
everybody has
so that's something you might that might
also get you a leg up or something you
might look to
invest in also in here is is
something that i think kind of really
well ties in so
uh leslie carhart um on twitter is
someone who i i follow and she recently
put out a tweet at the beginning of this
month
a thread of tweets kind of talking about
her
thoughts on people starting in dfir
and i thought it was it really
summarized a lot of the points that i
wanted to hit on well
um i encourage you to go check out her
twitter
her profile and those tweets back from
october 8th
i didn't want to include them here but
they talk about a lot of these kinds of
things a lot of the diverse background
that is needed for these types of
activities
finally get into attributes and
attributes are
you as a person but also your
happenstance so
uh when when we're hiring um
at my current position at my current
place of employment
one of the things that we look for is
drive and motivation that's not
something that is
easy to grow or build in a person
um if they don't choose to do it
themselves
so we look for somebody who wants to do
the home labs who wants to do those ctfs
who wants to go self-study who wants to
you know grow and grow and grow we want
somebody with strong ethics because
everything we deal with is highly
sensitive
um or has some some sort of you know
issue to it
uh you know there's there's something
i've actually left off this slide which
is kind of grit
dfir professionals often deal with um
you know not the most upstanding people
and
uh we deal with a lot of material that
you know people don't want to deal with
so that flexibility i know that
i don't get to choose my cases if i did
there would be a lot less of them at
friday
friday afternoon at 4 30 and i wouldn't
be going on as many car trips and plane
trips on saturday morning
um to edges of the state
to to kind of you know do my deal
um that if i did that and i had
say kids and things like that you know
or a rigid home life or
a very strict schedule that would be
very difficult for me to do
and uh and so flexibility isn't just a
it's not just a be
flexible it's also making sure that you
know you as a
person and where you are in your life
can can be flexible to the
the often unpredictable schedule that is
dfire works
and then finally we get to that tools
the traditional tools
uh the hardware the software um so let's
let's jump into a couple of those uh
this here
is a list of all open source and free
software
um and tools and resources um
this is not the slick sheet slick sheets
separate um
but i use every single case i work on
will involve at least one of these tools
um
so i encourage that if you are
interested in getting into this and
you're like how do i get started where
do i go
how do i uh how do i get to the next
level
um i think that going and being familiar
with these tools downloading them using
them there's tutorials all over the
place
will get you in a position to better be
able to do
this type of work it'll be it'll make
you ready these are tools that are used
in the industry
and there's nothing wrong with them um
you don't need you know a big
expensive end case license or a big
expensive suite license
um to to do forensics so uh
get familiar with these uh as far as
scripting
i'm i'm on the python powershell camp
uh i there's so many things for that now
that it's such a pat those two are so
powerful languages
that uh i that's that's what i spend
most of my time doing i know there's
holy wars
over this type of stuff but
um and then we i often get asked what's
my go bag
all about um what
what do i take with me when i go you
know fly or drive or whatever
and so i took a picture of this and uh
kind of all the contents spilled out all
over the place
and well you know there's things missing
from this picture there's no laptop i
usually have a
usually a high-powered dell precision
workstation that i use
um that's a that's a laptop i also have
a desktop in my lab
there's there's not a lot of tech here
in this pile
and it's because when i'm out doing
things when i'm doing collections
uh to then bring back and process in in
my in my environment
the it's it's not necessarily all about
the tech
um a lot of times i'm collecting things
preserving it for later i'm taking it
and bringing it back
um you know i'm not gonna sit in an
office in rigby
for you know however many hours sitting
there trying to chew through something
when i could
just as easily pick it up and bring it
back
[Music]
so it's a lot of process oriented stuff
i got i have you know different office
supplies here
some of the most important part that i i
have in this
is extra log books and blank forms um
we log all of our cases case notes
uh in a one notebook per uh per case
format
and each one of those log books then
gets stored with a case folder with all
the paperwork in it
that's really really important to us
also we've got some evidence bags some
anti-static
i have an anti-static mat and some
people might think
why on earth would i have that am i
tearing apart phones in the field
um honestly there's times where just
someone you know i work in an
engineering organization itd's an
engineering organization
you walk in and someone's desk is just
absolutely coated with stacks and stacks
of paper
so it might be easier if i need to
photograph things which i'm
photographing all the time my phone's
not in this picture but
i'm photographing the scene all the time
um to lay out a mat or something that i
don't
compromise you know data that might be
on those papers and i'm disturbing the
scene as little
as possible
other things will be supplemented into
this kit as
as time goes on depending on the case
depending on what i need to do i might
take extra write blockers extra hard
drives i might do other stuff but
this is the this is the kit that usually
goes everywhere on every single case
so that we've kind of talked about the
tools and uh and that
kind of what the right tools are
and uh kind of talking about
how how we can cut you know just some
different ideas and things you might be
able to exploit or kind of work on
um then let's kind of talk about this
come back to this equation thing so
again we're trying to get a leg up on
well not a leg up but we're trying to
make up the gap
between um us and and and law
enforcement
military dod and so we're getting that
right place right time and right tools
well the the key to remember is that
these are not guaranteeing
success they are putting you in a
position to take advantage of
opportunities
and those opportunities an example of
that for me
was uh when i uh one of the cases i
worked on
um we found some suspicious stuff on
a workstation and we needed to figure
out what was going on with it
and so we went to management and
notified them
management gave us three directives uh
one
be quiet about it keep it keep it under
wraps
two this is your highest priority
and three uh keep investigating we're
not
really sure that we want to do anything
about it yet but keep investigating
and uh let us know what you find
so we kept digging over the course of a
couple days
my you know a couple people and i
started
riffling through things we kept hitting
brick walls answering one question
is this malicious and while it was
suspicious
and it was it was kind of strange we
couldn't
say it was actually malicious so
what i did is um one evening
we uh we kind of you know after another
defeated evening
i grabbed a copy of it i came home
spun it up in a virtual environment i
had a book that i had
on malware analysis that i picked up a
year ago i'm not a malware analyst
uh i know i've done some basic static
analysis but nothing super major
so instead i spent six and a half hours
walking through labs
and going through that book and pushing
through and trying to kind of teach
myself
to do some super super basic malware
analysis to just
answer the question is this malicious or
not
and we found the answer i found that it
had no business being on the network or
the systems that it was on
and uh i wrote up my findings and
i sent off that email at like 6 30 in
the morning
and when i went to bed
got a call about an hour later from my
manager saying hey
we have a phone call in an hour
where we're going to present we need you
to present your your findings
uh so make your way to the office and
i showed up and we did the conference
call
and we got that green light to get in
extra help and get extra resources which
is what we've been
the nut we've been trying to crack and
we were also
all right we also were given a war room
to continue to work out of
um this of course it gained priority and
uh and i promptly found the war room and
uh
laid along the wall and slept for a few
hours um
with management's permission of course
but uh
the point was i was presented an
opportunity to try and
answer a question to learn something to
to figure out the problem and
you know we couldn't escalate there was
that barrier that until we got enough
information we couldn't escalate
so um you know we break that barrier
and spend that effort to turn that
opportunity
into into a success where we can move
that ball forward
and that's really kind of what this is
about is
find putting yourself in the right place
at the right time with the right tools
to be able to get that opportunity and
be ready to actually exploit it and turn
it into something
that you can then grow from
and you can expand on just time and time
and time again
so with that um
thanks for for sitting through this and
uh
thanks eric and xin ming for for hosting
this and i'm
happy to answer any questions the last
couple minutes here hey josh yes thank
you we do have a couple of questions
here
in the chat so yeah thank you great
presentation i enjoyed the cat
in the background too so that was a good
audience with you right there
um first question in the channel
is you referred in the slides earlier
to one really important part how
important is attitude
so the attitude it it's really kind of
up to you to make it what you will if
you choose to just say
you know if you choose to have a
defeatist attitude where you're like uh
you know whatever then that's probably
what your outcome's going to be
you really kind of have to be you know
looking up and looking out
and you know you kind of i mean it some
of it's like you got to like your job
um i if you don't like this line of work
you know you're not well it's true with
everything if you don't really like
doing it then you're not gonna be your
best
and so having that positive attitude
having that positive outlook and really
reaching
for um whatever it is that you're
you know whatever you're facing as a
challenge
is is vitally important
that's really good advice in information
security it's not always
all roses right um another question
another question here is you mentioned
quite a bit about some
really good tools some different tooling
i guess for the novice what tools would
you start out with
if you are new to security tooling
um so so dfir specifically i mean i'm
i'm
primarily focused on the forensic side
i do i mean of course i do ir as well
i'm proficient in it but
um most of my time is spent in the
investigation phase
uh so for a lot of that it
like i do a lot of content review and so
throwing something into autopsy which is
a windows-based application and doing
doing content review is kind of a good
way to sort of get your feet wet
and realize just how much data how much
volume there is to data
um that's that's kind of how i sort of
uh got started i guess you know when
when we had stuff going on
and management was like we need this to
happen and i was like well
i got this tool i guess we can give it a
whirl um
that was you know before i really had
any formal training that's kind of how
we
how we went about it so it is sort of a
push button
more so than a lot of people would
approve of and i think
when you start out that's kind of okay
right until you can get some training
and get some experience or find a mentor
who can really
guide you into the depths of forensics
to where you're not
looking for a push button solution
you're really looking at understanding
all of the artifacts and and what they
truly mean at kind of the most
raw levels all right
excellent yeah very good very good with
the tooling i think we got
time for one last question and this is a
really good question
and it is do you find yourself
experiencing any burnout
in this field of cyber security uh
absolutely um yeah i deal with burnout a
lot unfortunately
i wanted to watch the presentation just
before mine here in track two
it sounded like a fantastic presentation
but uh you know prepping for this as
well as
um you know kind of doing some of the
the the back end work
um here i couldn't i couldn't pay as
much attention as i wanted to
uh yeah burnouts burn it's a very real
deal
um especially in this arena there's kind
of a
i don't want to call it a joke but
there's kind of this uh
stigma that um you once you get into
like
hardcore doing forensics like you're
gonna do it for like two or three years
and either you'll make it or you won't
um and it's it's not that you know
you'll fail it's just you'll probably
just decide it's not for you
um it can be very procedural it can be
very boring at times
um you know it's i when i had first
experienced it was just collection
and i did no analysis i just sat there
and stared at a hard drive copying for
four hours it was like wow
um now it's you know it's different
there's a lot more to it
and the the hours can also wear on you
the content can wear
on you um you know you just
you just kind of you have all the
pressures that you do with cyber
security
but you don't get any control about
deciding what it is you decide what you
want to work on for the day
as much it's it's your schedule is
dictated by
the actions of others largely yeah i
guess that's a good point so
just one related part to that question
do you find
that you then maybe
volunteer for some other projects kind
of for some a little
different thing to do yeah
it's it's kind of important to break it
up a little bit
um i still do even in my team where i'm
specialized
i still step out and do some security
consulting in general for projects or
work on some compliance things every now
and again just to kind of keep my
skills up in other areas it's it's
important to be well-rounded when you're
when you even though you specialize it's
important to be well-rounded
so um i think that's you know that's
it's important
so like b-sides i'm involved in b-sides
i'm involved in some other groups in
regard i'm president for infragard
for this year and it's important that
you find
other things to to help disperse and
help deal with some of that burnout
absolutely all right very good well
thank you again josh
excellent presentation thank you thank
you eric