besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success so
that that is what we were told to do to
say when we are going to get started so
good morning thank you for coming to the
first session of track number three my
name is Kathleen Smith and this is
community-based Career Development and
one of the reasons why we wanted to talk
about this is most of the conference's
that happen within the information
security information assurance
cybersecurity community all are
volunteer run and it's interesting that
as an industry we really rely on
volunteers to get a lot of things done
but many people are not looking at their
volunteering through a career
development lens and a lot of companies
are not looking at community
volunteering as a way to recruit people
coming into their community coming into
their companies so I've been
volunteering in the community anywhere
from 7 to 10 years and my background is
in recruitment marketing my name is
Kathleen Smith and I am the chief
marketing officer of a company called
clear jobs net and cybersex jobs comm
and in my volunteering I've had the
great honor of meeting with so many
people who devote so many hours to
putting on amazing conferences like this
besides or like Def Con or hacker halted
or a variety of conferences throughout
the community but no one has actually
talked about how this helps you with
your career so I've asked two really
great volunteers to step forward and
sort of share their story but then we
also have one of our volunteers Doug
Munro who is also a recruiter who has
been in this community and how he would
recommend people look at their
volunteering for career development so
our volunteers are Cindy Jones and Doug
Munro and I'm going to have them
introduce themselves Cindy go it's
halfway mention my name is Cindy Jones I
am a principal security consultant with
rapid7
I have been in the information security
field for about
thirteen years now and in an IT for a
much longer period of time
Mike volunteer career paths has been
interesting it was definitely an
evolution and we'll get into some
details behind that in a little bit but
oh my god okay so here we go let's go
through all the lists of the annual
conferences I I volunteer at b-sides
event in Texas I live in San Antonio
currently so a lot of besides events in
Texas
I run registration for B sighs Las Vegas
it's about a I don't know it's a half
time job through most of the year
through the conference run second in
charge for workshops for Def Con I am
called upon staff for Derby con Def Con
shine I forgot about Def Con shine oh my
gosh yeah so I worked Def Con China for
the beta this past year and have every
intention of going back this year
there's a lot of a lot of things
happening and luckily I'm very fortunate
in regards to how I'm able to support
this desire for myself to maintain
constant integration with the community
through volunteerism so we'll talk about
that later too
I am Doug Monroe I am the director of
talent acquisition from mag aerospace
humble brag for us we are the fastest
growing aerospace company in the world
we focus primarily on intelligence
surveillance and reconnaissance but as
you can imagine cyber is a big component
of that as well as some of the other
operations that we do prior to this I
was in similar roles with coal fire and
the former verus group and I've been
fortunate through Kathleen primarily to
be able to attend a number of events
like this and one of the really exciting
things from a recruitment standpoint is
that I don't think that there is enough
conversation that goes on like this
between jobseekers candidates even just
employees trying to further their career
and recruiters and management as to how
the things that they do have the things
that you do in can impact your career in
a positive way so this is it's an
absolute pleasure for me I've been here
a number of times
number of other events nationally and
locally and it's just it's a kick I love
talking to people here so what are we
going to be talking about today so one
is community involvement why do it a lot
of people are saying you know all I hear
about is volunteering as folding
t-shirts or doing a bake sale or doing a
you know a car wash or something like
that but as you look at large
conferences like this there is so much
that goes on behind the scenes there's a
lot of things that you see during the
day people running around with their
bunny ears or their t-shirts but there's
a lot that goes on this is a year-long
conference in the making so what we're
going to talk about in specific today is
conference management presenting and
competitions and we're also going to
have Doug share with us sort of what
does a recruiter look at when he's
looking at that experience when he's
talking to you in an interview or
looking at your resume we're also going
to have Cindy and Doug touch on how
would you engage your employer when
you're talking about community
volunteering some of the things that you
may learn skills wise you may think that
you know I don't need to know how to run
registration but there are other skills
that you can learn specifically
communication program management finance
there's a lot of different things to
think about and finally how to handle
stress a lot of people think that this
is easygoing and it is not it is an
entirely new level of stress and if
you've seen any of the studies that are
done out there now Jack Daniel variety
of other people big in the community we
all have stress and then on top of it we
volunteer and we add to the stress and
throughout the presentation I'm actually
going to be sharing some results that we
have found I just completed a national
global study on community volunteering
and what people have learned to help
their career and some of the things that
they've found to lower their stress so
one of the things that came through from
the survey that we did was the different
kind of skills people felt that they
learned by doing community volunteering
I remember these are all technical
people who are looking for other skills
too
so collaboration and teamwork really
important in this day and age a lot of
you know lone guns is is not what we're
looking at we're looking at people who
can collaborate with strangers
communication skills how do I translate
what I need to someone who has not the
same experience I do organizational
skills there are 1800 people here today
that is a lot to organize and figure out
how to get it going
networking networking is going to be the
number one way you're going to find a
job and it is interesting people like
well I know people that I you know know
through D&D or I know people who I've
met at the beer hall or something like
that being able to expand your network
through volunteering in the community is
a really great way to find your next job
other things time management delegation
commitment management leadership all
these different skills that people are
learning by volunteering what was
interesting to me is employer support so
a lot of times people don't even share
with their employer that they're doing
this volunteering they just know that
you're distracted at work rather than
being able to say hey I'm doing this
other thing
so 62 percent of the people in this
survey were actually provide paid time
to volunteer so this is a real big cute
engage your employer in these
discussions fifty-nine percent said that
they stayed with their employer because
of this support so if you're an employer
and you're looking for retention being
sure that your employees understand that
you will pay them to volunteer and be
ambassadors within the community and
volunteer support is one thing that
people look at when they're looking for
a new job or if you're not it is
something that you might want to look at
so since we're here at this very large
conference we're going to turn it over
to Cindy otherwise known as registration
goddess as far as her conference
management your sort of career track how
you started how you engaged your
employer how you handled your paid time
off and you know I'll prime you with
you missed absolutely so as I mentioned
before I run the registration team for
besides Las Vegas and if any of you have
attended beef sized Las Vegas you've
seen probably I think we have about 15
different badge types running around
each one of these has a separate way to
register a separate potential donation
value for their badges it's insane
so a lot of things go into running that
prior to that I also ran besides San
Antonio small conference it was great
you know as a I mean we've probably had
300 people but through engaging in these
efforts the skills that I learned that
I've been able to translate back to you
know day-to-day business use have been
innumerable for example managing people
I've always had small teams working for
me probably for the past I don't know 15
years or so
you know teams of like six or seven and
it wasn't necessarily at the level of
dealing with their pay grade but you
know just you'll managing people making
sure tasks were getting done on time
that all changed when all of a sudden
I've got a crew of 40 volunteers that I
need to go ahead and have you know
taking care of things and you know
entering all the tasks getting done so
that was challenging but it's something
that I didn't have the opportunity to
dive into until I was in a volunteer
environment
nobody's gonna trust me was 40 something
people because I've never done it before
well now I have and being able to
express this to my employer was it was
amazing it was it's spectacular they
were so excited to hear about it and
they said well it's only for one day I'm
like no no no let me tell you about my
path through the course of the year in
getting this conference going so well
managing people was a huge skill
managing a budget I was treasurer for my
Girl Scout Troop I think I was like 14
at the time that doesn't count you know
you're talking about literally bake sale
money then this in this case I'm dealing
with this it was a relatively small
budget it was only $20,000 but I dealt
with this on an annual basis and I
always came in within 300 dollars of
that budget that's a skill I never knew
I had that skill I could barely balance
my own checkbook but when it comes to
somebody else's money I got this so that
was fun learning that being able to
translate that into
spending for other events and now
expanding upon that to larger events as
well
besides Las Vegas this year is going to
be expanding how we're handling things
internal the organization so that's
going to be a challenging thing so I
don't know that was another area where I
wouldn't have the opportunity you know I
to manage money like that that to manage
how things were spent and I always
wanted everything to be perfect so
that's a that's a fault there yeah big
stressful since we're here in the DoD
Center when you started beside San
Antonio how did you explain that to your
employer and how did you engage them so
besides being basically the grouse
grassroots you know effort that it is
throughout every almost every arena my
goal is to bring community to San
Antonio I hadn't seen a lot of that at
the time I was a DoD contractor I my
bosses were all here they had no idea
what was going on in San Antonio they
didn't really care from a an employer
support perspective I didn't get any it
was out of sight out of mind it wasn't
gonna benefit them in any way shape or
form as far as they were concerned they
didn't know what skills I was gonna be
gaining when I could bring back to my
position because of those skills they
didn't have a clue I used up all my
leave time used up all my sick time
going to conferences organizing the
conference when in the red from leave
time actually I had my paycheck docked
within one contract roll into the next
one because I didn't have any leave time
left so that happened there huge
transition went from doing DoD
contracting to working for a pin 7 which
is a position that I got because of
community involvement they came to me
recruited me which was awesome
that's a very huge ego boost by the way
but and they were like no we want you
because of your community involvement so
I said ok so what does this mean what is
this gonna mean to me and they said well
we'll pay for you to go to conferences
and they do
about every conference I want to go to
unless it's something I don't want them
necessarily to be involved with they
support me in all my volunteer efforts
obviously I still have a job to get done
so I get my job done but then it's my
times mine so Doug explained to us if
Cindy came to you as a job seeker as a
candidate and she didn't have any of her
volunteering on her resume but you heard
about it during the discussion how would
you recommend she would put conference
management on her resume and how would
you want to hear about it in an
interview well it's two different things
and obviously a little plug for later
this afternoon we are going to be doing
resume reviews and different people will
say different things but I would tend to
say it should be on your resume within
the bounds of reason if you are a very
active volunteer you might not want to
have a full page of it or you might want
to have a link on your resume that would
take us to a different page but it
should definitely be listed and then
it's gonna be incumbent upon you to
notice when the opportunity is to begin
to speak about it if we're asking you if
you let a team and if so what was the
project well besides any professional
experience you have in that regard you
can bring up the volunteering to the
point that Kathleen made and what
Cindy's alluded to all of those skills
translate if you are speaking at a
conference if you're on a panel it if
you're organizing if you're doing
registration all of these things require
skills to translate into any other part
of the job that you're doing and I want
to know about it because it's gonna be
the same questions that I ask if you
tell me about some pentesting effort
that you led I'm gonna ask you specific
questions about what you did what were
the obstacles that you faced how did you
overcome them I'm gonna do the same
thing with the volunteerism because
those skills are just as vital and I
think something that often gets lost in
technical fields and certainly cyber is
absolutely that is that your audience is
not always technical they're going to
need to hear things at multiple levels
of understanding so your ability to
speak to a broad
audience and convey the information that
you have that they need is vital and all
of this sort of experience both the
organization but also that the
presentation of ideas and information is
vital to your career path and it does
translate so I would say again make sure
it's on the resume I tend to recommend
you put it at the end but there will be
opportunities where you can make the
connection hey they're asking me about
this I did this with besides DC and
we'll talk about it so what's
interesting is it's not necessarily just
listing the conference's on your resume
or on your social media profile but it's
actually listing the role that you
played and then if it is a major role
like what Cindy's been doing conference
management finance securing sponsorship
handling volunteers those are different
things that you're going to want to list
I mean a lot of people think volunteer
management is very easy and it is one of
the hardest things to do because you
don't have a carrot or stick with the
people who are supposed to show up I
mean I don't know if you saw my Twitter
feed over the last few days but there
were a lot of volunteers who were
supposed to show up for tomorrow's event
to help out here and they all bailed
okay how do you as a manager how do you
as someone who you know you can't
penalize them for not showing up but you
have to scramble and you have to find
people to show up well what's
interesting is being able to translate
that on your resume as people manage
being able to say that you're a leader
that people do show up when you ask them
to show up and you can held them
accountable but Doug can you touch a
little bit on if you see someone is
listing and me if you saw Cindy's
conference schedule which DEF CON Shana
DEFCON be Stein's Las Vegas Derby con
hacker halted b-side Santonio b-side to
Nashville all of the different ones
wouldn't you think that you're just
paying for her to go to all these
conferences I do have a different
perspective because of course I've known
enough people that do volunteer at that
level that I would tend to look at it
differently but there are recruiters and
managers hiring managers who might look
at it in that way so again
I would say if you've got a full page of
these things you might want to
cherry-pick the ones that are really
significant and where your role is
significant and where your role can
translate into other things that you do
but as a recruiter personally I look at
it as the involvement I will assume that
rapid7 is happy with the work that Cindy
puts out or else you wouldn't be working
there anymore so you're dead so it again
becomes a strength you're able to manage
a full time job with full time
responsibilities full time expectations
and yet you are still active in the
community and broadening your skills all
of that is a positive so another aspect
of community involvement not necessarily
community volunteering is competitions
and I will have lots of students there
people who are looking to get into the
industry say I have no experience but
they'll say that they've been part of
lots of competitions and I think this is
a very big overlooked not looked at very
clearly area where people don't realize
that they can gain experience but some
of the things that they don't realize is
you know when you go in to a competition
you have a time constraint you have a
resource constraint you are meeting new
people that you don't know and you're
trying to communicate with them in a
stressful situation I don't know about
you but that sounds like my everyday
work day at you know my nine-to-five job
so if you're able to relate those same
skills those same challenges that you
have in a competition on your resume you
may not have the work experience but you
actually have the community experience
so be sure that whenever you're part of
a competition you actually take a few
moments after the competition and say
okay what was the challenge what did I
learn what did I mess up and what was
the overall situation because you're
going to go into an interview or a phone
interview and you're going to be asked
what was the situation that you messed
up on and you may not remember that but
you may remember something in a
competition that you didn't remember
it's also an opportunity to expand your
network you're sitting across the table
from somebody and the person at the
other cross the table you guys click
I hope that rather than after the
competition and high-fiving and grabbing
a beer you guys are actually talking
about hey what company do you work with
do they support you being part of here
realize that your overall competition
network is one that's going to help you
in your skill set so Doug you've done
some recruiting through competitions you
want to talk a little bit more about
your how you look at competitions on a
resume or in a social media profile well
you took everything I had Kathleen I'm
sorry so and those couple and those
couple of folks that are leaving have no
idea what they're about to miss what
having said that Kathleen is absolutely
right and and not only those softer
skills that she's relating to that we've
already touched on but this is specific
this is industry specific you are
performing tasks that you could perform
in a professional setting it's vital I'm
gonna ask every single question that she
just asked what was your role what were
the challenges what went right what went
wrong so gathering your notes afterwards
is significant because all of those
questions are going to come up but I
look at it again as it is community
involvement more importantly it's an
ongoing effort to broaden your skills
try new things and honestly doesn't
matter if you come in first or 30th
you're typically gonna be part of a team
it's what you did within that role and
very often in these competitions you'll
start out with a team of three or four
and somebody's going to drop out that's
a key moment what did you do to overcome
so you don't have to win everything you
just have to play the game and all of
those things are very important to us
when we evaluate and particularly if you
don't necessarily have as much
professional experiences somebody else
who might be doing this but I can't
emphasize enough goes for IT in general
but it really goes to cyber it is such a
fluid industry it's a constant
back-and-forth adversaries and good guys
and because it's so ever-changing if
you're just gonna get your degree and
get a couple of certifications and kind
of glide through your career you may do
okay but you're gonna fall behind the
people that are going out competing
broadening their skills though
the ones we want they have a passion for
it because that's ultimately
cybersecurity is every bit as vital as
the well the floating platforms that my
company employs it is the defense of
everything we hold dear so if you don't
have a passion for it and aren't trying
to push yourself forward you're probably
not going to be as successful and you're
probably not the person that we want and
when apples-to-apples everything else is
about the same between you and someone
else that's going to win every single
time we had a really interesting
question at a previous presentation when
someone said well I can't get to all of
the competitions how can our and I can't
get to you know B sites DC to be able to
volunteer well there is this thing
called the Internet and there is this
thing about doing it online so Cindy and
I both volunteer for B sites Las Vegas
everything is done through slack email
and phone calls we only see each other
ass at the actual conference so if you
want to be a volunteer to any of these
conferences or if you want to compete
realize that a lot of this is already
done online you can be gaining your
experience online without even having to
be face to face the other thing is if
you're looking to switch industries this
is also a really great way to build
experience and expand your network
there's a cyber policy T CTF there is
the car hacking there are energy CTF so
I mean there is an a CTF for almost
every single industry so if you're
looking to poke your head into switching
industries you might want to look at one
of the online CTS so Cindy we're gonna
have you switch gears and talk a little
bit more about presenting okay so
everyone thinks that oh it's just the
cool kids club that gets picked to stand
up here and get a speaker badge
Cindy you want to explain what it takes
to present it Derby or Grace Hopper or
[Laughter]
yeah that's a little bit of an inside
joke yeah we weren't diverse enough
which is a totally different thing
anyways and being able so one of the
things you
have to be willing to do is accept some
rejection that's all there is to it
you're gonna get knows you're gonna get
knows I know some people who every
single conference they've submitted to
they've been accepted like what is your
magic sauce I don't understand this
you're gonna get rejected from a lot of
conferences you're get rejected from
conferences that you volunteer out that
you think well they know who I am don't
they want to pick me yeah it's not about
the cool kids people there's a lot of
conspiracy theories that there's a huge
amount of nepotism and you'll see the
cool kids speaking a lot of the time
because they know how to work the system
they know how to present their ideas in
a manner that the CFP Review Board is
gonna say this sounds like a logical
flow a logical talk topic and the people
will be interested in this they've been
doing it enough to where it automatic
Ida by-road happens automatically for
them as they're writing these things out
that takes practice if you don't get the
practice in and get rejected it's just
no it's okay you can move forward and
continue again if you can ask for
feedback for those rejections a lot of
times they'll give you feedback Grace
Hopper said we weren't diverse enough
okay I saw the I saw the submission it
looked pretty darn good to me but that's
cool so you know ask for the feedback
take the feedback they're not saying
anything to be mean to you they're just
telling you how you might improve your
submission yeah that's okay so another
perspective that you need to go ahead
and consider so once you've gotten
accepted right you've got went ahead and
you've drawn up this outline they may
have asked you for your slides in
advance
you're probably gonna alter your slides
in advance or at least at least get a
very solid detailed outline now you're
you have and you've been accepted so now
you know in two months three months
whenever the case might be you've got to
basically write this talk you only have
to write this talk you have to be able
to present this talk in order to present
this talk you need to practice you need
to practice practice practice if you're
putting this off for too long and some
of us might be really good at
procrastinating not oh my gosh because
all of a sudden it's two weeks before
the event you haven't written the slide
yet oh my gosh so this is something else
you need to work on and build from
practicing speaking in front of people
can be challenging for a lot of us I
mean we
an industry I think primarily I mean if
we were to do the research I think it
shows a lot of us are introverts getting
up and speaking on a stage in front of a
group of people especially your peers
that's terrifying for a lot of folks
it's really not that bad
they're there to hear what you have to
say because they're interested in what
your opinion is
so that's brilliant that's a great
opportunity for you to be able to expand
outside of your comfort zone and build
as a human being so the other thing
about presentations is knowing the CFP
timeline I mean I just finished doing
all of my presentations proposals for
you know besides San Francisco and RSA
which are next March so if you're not
doing the research and the time
management of being able to think of a
year from now what topic do I want to
talk about you're not going to be able
to figure out sort of the timeline of
submitting your proposals and as Cindy
said you have to be able to write what
you're speaking about in six different
ways you have to be able to do a short
abstract you have to do a long abstract
you then have to convince the CFP review
board as to why this is important those
are the three things I had to do for
besides San Francisco and then also what
are some of the objectives that you want
the audience to get through there are
many many different platforms I wish I
could say that there was one way to
submit a CFP but there isn't so you have
to keep in mind okay I really like this
conference next June is that con or
Circle City con being keeping an eye on
either their Twitter handle or their
website when they say a call for a call
for papers is out and then actually take
down the form of what you're going to
have to fill out because sometimes it's
a Google Form sometimes it's a
conference management software sometimes
it is something that's completely you
know just an Excel spreadsheet
a lot of times in the industry the
proposals are stripped of who is
presenting their their social media
profile everything it is just based on
your content so it isn't just hey I did
this really great patch and I want to
share it with the world it is being
articulate enough to be
able to convey your thoughts in 200
words or 500 words and then being able
to spend time on google images and
figure out what image you want for your
presentation I am you know horrible I
will spend my procrastination is being
on Google Images and trying to figure
out what sort of image is out there so I
change that all the time
and as Cindy said it's a lot of
rejection and it's understanding that
you might have your your feelings
constantly hurt because you think that
they don't like you you are not
conveying your ideas in a way that your
industry peers can understand it that is
a learning opportunity
so Doug let's talk a little bit about
someone who's a big presenter you know
we had Megan who is on our panel before
talk about how she submits for all of
these different conferences what do you
what do you want to see what do you want
to hear from a candidate that says I
present every where do you want to hear
about you know what a great speaker they
are or do you want to go a little bit
deeper to be honest I would assume if
they're getting the call that many times
they are a good speaker it's more
significant to me that it's the
preparation its it is that content
preparation it is creating something as
I spoke about a moment ago that a broad
audience can understand and grasp and
that when I say broad not just that
dummies like me that don't understand
the technical aspects of it but peers so
if you're able to put together that
content in a constructive way that you
can convey to people that's significant
to me I'm gonna ask you how you did it
what was the reaction how did the
audience take it what sort of questions
were they asking but then also going
back to the things that didn't work what
did you learn from them how did you
become a better presenter because at the
end of the day and that's something that
run into all the time because it is such
a technical field there are folks who
are brilliant can do extraordinary
things back into things that they really
shouldn't just for sport none of it
matters if you can't put it into a
format
that somebody else has to can take value
from and at the end of the day with coal
fire we were the leading FedRAMP
Assessor anyway yeah so you had to have
the technical skills to be able to
conduct the assessment but it didn't
matter because the deliverable the thing
that gets paid for the thing that keeps
all of the lights on keeps us paid goes
to a customer who may or may not have
the level of expertise that's a key
element so if you're presenting you're
creating content you're creating
something that others can take in and
get value from that is very similar to
the deliverables that you ultimately
have to produce for customers and so
those those are the areas that I'm
probably going to ask you about and
that's where the presentation skills
come in handy not to mention when you're
trying to get business when you're the
SME that's standing next to the sales
guy and you're trying to explain why
your company your team is the best one
to give them what they need you're gonna
have to present you're gonna maybe it's
a small room with a half a half-dozen
executives maybe it's a huge room
whatever it is if you've done it that's
significant to us the other thing to
think about when you're doing
presentations is understanding if you're
representing your employer or not and
that is a big question that you have to
make the internal decision on and maybe
speak to some of your co-workers or your
manager if you're presenting at a
conference and if you're expressing
their views or not that's very
interesting in this industry a lot of
people choose not to let everyone know
where they work they choose not to use
their business handle or anything like
that but it's also going back to your
company and saying I have something that
I want to present about and start
negotiating the process within your
company if they're going to support you
in your presentations or not you are an
ambassador for them if you're talking
about the work that you're doing and if
it's non-cleared work you might be you
know surprised they might want to
support you in doing this when we were
doing this presentation at Derby con we
had someone who is on the panel who
learned her skills through competitions
she works for a large financial
institution it took nine months to get
approval for her
present at Derby con so I actually
submitted the proposal to her last year
to go up her chain to management so you
need to understand who needs to have
approval within your company to be able
to present and then ask them you know
what kind of support not only or will
they pay for your travel or pay for your
conference are they going to help you
create the competitive presentation are
they gonna help you with the practicing
you might be surprised at how much
support you would get within the company
when I did a workshop two years ago to
get more women into the community
presenting one of the people who was in
that workshop was a woman who said I
have all of these ideas but I have never
put them down in an abstract she went
home from the workshop and put together
six abstracts and then make made a goal
for 2017 to present 12 times and she
actually did and her company a very very
large commercial integrator paid for her
to go to Brazil to Spain all over the
world because she was brilliant but she
was such an introvert and didn't want to
get out there and realize that this was
a huge growth opportunity for her and it
actually led to her you know being able
to find another job so you know of all
of the kinds of community volunteering
or being involved in the community
presentations I would say would be one
of the hardest but it is also something
that pushes you out of your comfort zone
and gives you opportunities to learn
presentation skills being able to write
your thoughts being able to convey to
non-technical people so let's talk about
the other aspect of volunteering stress
so what's interesting is when I did this
survey 98 percent of the people said
that they found community involvement
very fulfilling but at the same time
more than half of them also shared it
stressed them out
ninety-four percent of them actually
believed that it had a positive impact
on the community and I found that this
was really very enlightening to me
cuz we hear so much negativity about our
community we hear so many bad things out
there yet we are the one community that
is most driven by community involvement
and volunteering and I think it's great
that most of the community feels even
though they're stressed out with
volunteering even though they're
stressed out by you know having managing
different time lines and if volunteers
are going to show up people still
volunteer they still want to go out into
the community whoops sorry
but I find it very interesting that
there is actually nothing out there that
helps us with our stress a lot of people
talk about the stress that they feel is
psychological anxiety depression these
are all the things the people you see
running around here who are so happy are
actually some of the people who are the
most depressed or have the most anxiety
but they're out there all the time yes
yeah we realize getting out into the
community is a way to overcome a lot of
that but Cindy you want to touch on some
of the stressful points that you have
felt with besides San Antonio or even
going to DEFCON China yeah and you know
that was a whole different ball how did
you handle your personal development of
going from being miss perfectionist to
letting things go so when I first joined
the information security hacker
community whatever you want to call it I
was very much I'd go to a talk at DEFCON
and I go back to my room the people were
not something I want to interact with
necessarily I didn't want to be involved
with the thing I wanted to learn and I
did then I took and I took and I took
and it was wonderful I did well when
they started doing the streaming I did
start watching with streaming so I
didn't even have to go to the rooms
which was great
I realized that that is not a healthy
you know a little epiphany happened it's
not necessarily a healthy way to live
your life is taking all the time so I
decided to give back and the easiest way
for me to give back were just say hey do
you guys need any help it also put me in
a position where I was putting myself in
groups of people that normally would not
interact with in any way shape or form
these are people that just were you know
they weren't my stand
but folks not a big deal but it was
taking a risk in that regard and it was
a success successful risk wow that was
hard I met my tribe you know all through
college people say oh you finally meet
your people well I never met my people I
met my people at def con I met my people
you know volunteering for besides Austin
the first year that was there I met my
people at places like this rooms like
this with people like you which was
awesome so I started giving back and
that I am a type-a personality so if I
start doing something I really do
something so I jumped in with both feet
so it started off I was just gonna go
ahead and work with besides Austin I'll
volunteer level
hey Cindy you know we'd really like to
have a b-side sound San Antonio would
you be interested in doing that no no no
no okay
yeah let's do this so it became this
thing and I became an obsessive
volunteer I was already working for
besides Las Vegas said that by that
point and I just took on beside San
Antonio ahead spectacular support
network
had I not I would have crashed and
burned chillin with personnel issues
there I took everything on myself
because the people that I had requested
help from we're not able to step up and
do how do things the way I would
anticipate them being done because I
have a perfectionist so that was another
skill that I learned just have like
those things but yeah I became a little
bit obsessive with that and taking
things on when I continued to do so I
have a hard time saying no yeah I I
think that is one of our biggest
challenges within the community is
saying no and thinking that we need to
do it all and I think that that is a lot
of times that people you know become
siloed because they believe that they
need to do it all and they need to do
the job perfectly and what you find when
you're in a community engagement when
you're in the community you realize
there are other people you can lean on
especially if they are strangers so
what's interesting that I always ask
people when they come to volunteer with
me
is what are the other things that you're
looking for what are the growth
opportunities that you're looking for
and one of the things that is not taught
in our careers in any careers is
succession planning how do you move on
from this particular role
Cindy is no longer part of b-side San
Antonio but she had to think I had at
the time who is going to take over the
organization two years two years I mean
and why don't you talk a little bit more
about how you handled succession
planning him I mean did they teach you
that at rapids oh no that was actually
pre rapid7 so no absolutely not
but I did learn it through my volunteer
work and creating this little this I
call it I called it my baby it was my
baby I was the one doing all the work
for beside San Antonio like I said 300
person conference not a big deal not a
huge budget but still something I had
put my heart and soul into as well as
all my pto so when i realized that it
was becoming a little bit much for me
and with the understanding that i was
having a difficult time delegating
aspects of it I decided to start
planning for handing the tour trio
basically passing the baton along that
made it easier for me to help delegate
it helped me delegate a little bit more
knowing that this is gonna be a
responsibility of somebody else coming
down the line so that was additional
that was very helpful and I was super
fortunate to select for my successor a
great guy who has taken this conference
and as I mentioned it took two years to
do this but he has taken this conference
from you know a little 300 person
conference to about 500 people we've got
villages we've got I mean so much
wonderful is going on there and to see
it grow and I can say I started this and
it's so much better now and that's so
satisfying I mean my whole goal in life
is to help people and to make things
better and when I see something that
actually has gotten better because of
something I started super satisfying
from a personal perspective so Doug do
you want to touch on you know just sort
of these management skills and how do
you want those convey
in an interview or on a resume well I
think we've touched on it on a number of
ways during this conversation everything
that you do translates so just as
Kathleen mentioned think about it not
just the competitions you do but the
volunteerism that you might participate
in what did you do what was the outcome
what were the challenges what was your
role how did you fit in and write it all
down think about it
when we're talking about it it's a great
opportunity for you to relate those very
real management skills to what you can
do in your profession in the cyber world
so it seems it seems like you can just
do it and you know it and you can talk
about it but the act of writing it down
organizing your thoughts and really
looking at analyzing what was your role
what did you do what did you take from
it that's going to be key to your
ability to convey something in an
interview and present yourself as
someone who can take on a larger role
and it's not only in your job search but
it is also you know in your current
employment I mean we're not all looking
for our next job but you may be looking
to stay with your employer but you're
looking for a bigger role you're looking
for a bigger opportunity you want to
have a different career strategy one
thing that is not taught in companies is
for managers or hiring managers or
recruiters how they coach and counsel
the people that are working inside the
company to stay with the company and
move on in different roles they don't
want to lose you and you don't want to
go out and try to find a new job so
using all of these skills all of these
tips that we have shared during this
presentation take that to your current
employer and say I want to build a
career strategy within this company and
these are the things that I have been
doing in the community that can help
this company so some of my final
thoughts in community volunteering is is
a really great way to stretch your mind
and I always look at community
volunteering as a way to work on some
development challenge
our professional development challenges
that I don't have any other opportunity
to work on my best example and there's
only one person in the room who
understand this example is I had someone
on one of my groups that I was always
butting heads with and no matter what
phone conversation we were in or face to
face conversation and we butt heads like
there was nobody's business and we would
always walk out of the room really mad
and I realized well I couldn't try that
sort of work situation in my personal
life with my husband or I would have had
a divorce I couldn't really work on that
situation in my professional development
or in my profession because my staff
would leave me so I used this community
volunteering board opportunity to sort
of examine okay this is a challenge that
I have in my life I butt heads with
people and I realized time and time
again the reason why they were butting
heads with me is because I wasn't
listening I wasn't giving them the
opportunity to say their piece and I
needed to just shut up and once I
stopped trying to talk all the time and
listen to the people who were on my
board I actually was able to lower the
stress and tension level within that
organization and I always look at
community volunteering as personal
development in addition to professional
development it's a lot cheaper than
paying for a lot of therapy
so Doug Cindy some final thoughts on
community volunteering Cindy go first
and then done so one of the things I
found when I was working for the DoD and
I mean I was able to present to the
chief of staff for the Air Force for Air
Force personnel that was kind of
exciting but I had the ability to
present to them based upon a very clear
set of rules which at the time was I
think we saw it was a die cap at the
time so I was able to say this is what
is happening and this is how it's going
I can point directly back to a very
clear set of rules that they were
required to follow volunteering and
being able to express myself in
different formats has given me the
ability to now become
a little more articulate when it comes
to less I guess prescriptive levels of
security now I'm presenting the boards
of directors think this is what you need
to do and it's a little bit more
ambiguous as far as why you need to do
it and have that ability to be able to
express that those thoughts that
everything in a clearer format because
I'm having two on CFP what I'm doing
CFPs be able to articulate two different
types of group of people volunteer
organization when I'm going in and I'm
talking to the caterers who have no clue
what we're doing to the lighting guys
who kind of have an idea of what they're
doing but they don't know when we're
trying to get across and being able to
spread this communication ability across
all these different areas that has
helped me out tremendously another real
quick story when Kathleen and I were
preparing to do the first iteration of
this panel I went to my leadership and
his rapid evidence very involved the
community and I said so you know I'm
doing this on community involvement and
you know what what do you you know what
got rapid7 involved they probably the
story about you know Metasploit coming
into the community being community
involved because of Metasploit and it
just evolved from there and I said well
you guys know I'm really involved with
lots of aspects of the community I said
what do you guys have do we have any
resources in place that would help if I
find myself like over-committing
and the feet this is the VP of HR says
you know we don't that's a great idea
would you like to help lead that guess
what so yeah so once again over
committing to yourself over committing
your time volunteering for things you
never knew we're going to be a part of
that's something to be aware of and to
try to manage the best year availability
and be a little bit particular on what
you're going to go ahead and select your
efforts your energy but did we put into
not my strong suit but I'll try to be
concise two things that I wanted to say
one if you are an employer or if you are
in the process of trying to sell the
idea of the volunteerism to your
employer using a specific example of
various group we had hard data
people in the company who were active in
that their professional communities had
higher personnel evaluations and this
was consistent and by a significant
enough margin that it was it was a
noteworthy figure we had an elite
pentesting team at varus group rose to
about almost 30 people we during one
calendar year
at zero attrition ask any recruiter ask
any HR person that will never happen on
a team of 30
they were so active in the community so
networked with people outside of the
company it was clear that there was a
connection so if you're trying to sell
it as an employer or to an employer this
is it's hard data and then about
networking we talk about it a lot I
don't know if we really delve into it as
deeply as we should it's not just
showing up meeting some people talking
about things that's awesome get their
names get their contact information
follow up see if there's anything out
there that you can participate in
through those new connections and
maintain them seems like a daunting task
you know a bunch of people it takes a
lot of time but it doesn't necessarily
take as much as you might think but if
you just meet them at an event and then
walk away it's not going to do you
nearly the good that ongoing contact and
to give a personal example that is
outside of cyber but I'm fortunate to
have done some things with a local
recruiting group first panel I ever did
shout out Matt - Matt Duren a tenable
it's a recruiting organization and the
last two jobs that I've taken both
coming in situations where I was in an
employment situation that I knew I
needed to get out of reached out to
people that I had met through recruiting
organizations and the jobs came to me
and it's a small thing but it's huge the
last two jobs I've gotten I've loved and
the reason for it is because I didn't
just I didn't have to go out and just
throw my resume and everything under the
Sun I had people out there who knew of
opportunities they knew me well enough
to know what might be a good opportunity
for me and they helped get me into the
right place so I cannot emphasize enough
networking is an active commitment but
it is it pays off the dividends are
miserable so we're out of time we
actually ran over does anyone have any
questions or if you don't have any
questions we'll be around we have
another panel so was this an okay
presentation
[Applause]