besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success all
right thanks everybody everybody have a
good time this weekend
let's start off with crypt kids Jenny
are you gonna come up short
[Music]
all right so while Jenny is coming up
here congratulations to Jenny David mr.
Darcy name is Ella Andrew the whole team
congratulations to our black badge
winners and the the new trash in
challenge was super popular I even got
some complaints on Twitter from adults
who are like why don't we get one why do
the kids always like the messiest stuff
[Music]
there was some talk there was some talk
earlier that maybe one year we'll just
have a kids con and let you adults have
a room let me let me well let me do kids
first real fast as he said we did add a
trash in tillage and for those who
aren't familiar with what we did there
we basically had lots of bags of fake
clean trash because you know I'm not
going to do that to the parents but they
got to dig through all the trash to look
for seeds and flags and if they found
the entire list of flags then they got a
prize so the nice thing was that all the
kids that did that and then went to the
escape room immediately found the first
lock combo because it was in the trash
we had a amazing keynote this year for
the very first year we had a kid keynote
our kid Khan and she was amazing if you
get a chance
well she can come up in come on up so if
you get its chance she had wish you can
have a specially-designed stool so she
can see over the thing and if you get a
chance to watch her talk later she
teaches kids how to program notes to
make peanut butter and jelly sandwiches
it was awesome thank you so much we also
had instead of last year I got yelled
out last year apparently the adults
wanted escape rooms too so I added an
adult escape room this year and then I
was yelled at again because apparently I
needed to next year because not enough
people got a chance to go through we're
thinking no promises made let me see
what I can do
we'll talk next year but apparently
those are a big hit and people enjoyed
those and then yeah I know it's like if
we just like fill up the whole room
block I'll have as many as you want and
then of course anyone who came our
cookies and milk party was an awesome
success last night we had games we got
cookies we had milk and we had cake so
there was cake there too I think I'm
gonna let someone else talk about the
kids versus adult challenge and then
we'll go to the do you want to do that
well so this is actually kind of part of
the kids thing cuz it was it was her
idea so she also in addition to
keynoting ran an entire W CTF village
and contests for the kids that she
created herself and she asked him cuz
she kinda knows a guy low they decided
to hit at the end of the day a kids
foxhunt team versus an adult foxhunting
so let me let him know how you with that
so we just had took the two fastest
times and had them go against an adult
and the first time we found it in like
50 like very like the adults couldn't
even go it was 30 seconds the adults
didn't even leave the room yet and then
the second time we sort of won but we
didn't really so they found the Fox but
the instructions given to the Fox was a
little off so the Fox was like it's not
me and the kids came up and like yes it
is can we have it and they gave it to us
and what was the technicality well so
the adults found it first but we brought
it up and the rules say that you have to
give it to the person to get the points
so we basically won both so it pays to
read the directions because the adults
thought they'd won and she went over and
went giving our points and so they
actually won since they followed the
directions and I think that's all I got
for the kids we're going to crypto
contest now apparently people enjoy the
crypto challenge books so far I've
gotten a lot of great feedback for those
not familiar with night Vale we did a
b-sides a night Vale this year visa our
night Vale now has its own b-sides and
our crypto contest winners are team BLT
the white bread of info suck and I need
Daniel Burnside James loving and Alan
Taylor to come up to get their black
badges
gee
that was three years ago I don't care
where you do it we're all tired
so the so I wanted to tell a little bit
like how this works so don't get
discouraged like if you feel like people
are in front of you the people that
solved the like the next part the people
I thought we're gonna win unfortunately
they got passed so don't assume if
someone else is ahead of you that you're
not you can't do it you know what I mean
and if you're struggling with one don't
assume you're not gonna get it cuz you
like we talked right but what was funny
was the final the actual ticket to get
their black badge was hidden in a book
called you meddling kids and it was in
one of the libraries upstairs on the
meeting room level so they managed to
find this and bring it to me after a
tussle with 12 flamingos that occurred
multiple times so thank you gentlemen
for playing and we're already working on
the one for next year so we hope you
play next year as well can I say one
more thing so a lot of people come up to
me I'm gonna try not to cry but I'm
gonna do it anyway a lot of people come
up to me and tell me oh you did such
amazing work you did such a great job I
can't believe you know this absolute not
have happened this year without my
daughter who has double-checked
triple-checked
quadruple checked by Krypto and she's
helped with every escape room with the
walkthroughs troubleshooting you know I
don't think that's gonna work
checking locks for me helping pack gear
and I will tell you this right now
that running crip kids is huge it takes
a lot I takes my attention I've got a
lot of things going on I've got keynotes
she sat in the crypto booth the whole
two days and she just took charge she
ran everything for me and I just check
in and be as like everything cool she
ran this contest this year and it would
not have happened if she had not been
here to help so give her a big NER
you forgot the other stuff and ER she
made oh and while we're waiting for him
to walk up I do post all my crypto and
my escape room stuff on my patreon for
anyone to use for free in the community
if you want to do it at your own besides
or your own event it'll all be out there
take it use it you know teach the kids
alright well to turn that back on okay
so the kids crypto this year ended up
having some helpers that were is going
to help out go tsunami got done and
probably in about three days put
together as usual I will probably have
it put up on SlideShare and share it out
and tweet it out but this year it was
women in stem they were given their
first clue which was the Caesar cipher
and had to go from there and find
different ciphers hidden around the kids
con area our winners Denis with staples
and Cameron Cole came in did it in about
an hour and a half and solved all the
puzzles and worthy winners this year for
the black badges
okay so the kids wife is kids my fine I
got these slides slightly out of order
sorry we just wha Vlad and Catherine you
can't got the black badges for the kid
Khan adult for the fastest Suffolk sign
all right so that is good for you guys
thank you oh my god next year sorry
moving on to more crisis of the wireless
village winners Rick and park up here
yeah I said they could leave Mike yeah
listen I'm gonna make you say that team
name cuz I want to yeah satellite go
firefighter what do you guys call your
team are you here how are you what do
you call your team
I don't like jackass from now on is the
new name of your team this could go in a
lot of bad direction yeah those
interesting year so how many are you
announcing how many people were here or
is that later yes that's okay so I don't
know what the total number is but we had
over a hundred people play the wireless
capture-the-flag this year that's silly
a lot of people now we were offering the
badge which Alex was wearing to anyone
that scored points and this is the badge
that we made for Def Con so that was
kind of cool we changed things around a
little bit and had a couple hiccups we
over exerted ourselves a little which
may not ever happen again
but that being said the teams that won I
think you guys was your second time
playing is that right they played out at
Def Con they came back here team
blunderbuss was was new I think weren't
you
they played DEFCON 2 and then that other
team that's you know kind of local or
something Crimson agents but we're gonna
start penalizing them because those
sokka's on the team so it's just
it's just the way things go she no Sokka
not to pick on her again but the fact
that she was using a wireless mouse
during the wireless CTF and maybe her
radio went off a couple of times because
we were in the wireless village I don't
know might have something to do with
them not doing so well first place got a
$250 or $150 gift card Amazon second
place got $100 and third place got 50
they got our challenge point in first
place did get black badge so again thank
you very much b-side
[Applause]
yeah please keep them up sorry Brandon
has something for you by the way this is
the adult team that was playing against
the kids team all right so IOT village
is the next one that will go over the
the winner there was first place was an
OP researcher they have 37 thousand
points that team Waldo had 23 thousand
points and team meat bunny had 22
thousand points that was as of about 315
so this could have changed a little bit
but if if there's anyone from team not
researcher I feel like it was a small
team or maybe one come on up and get
your badge as well
over to her all right opens ah kayo ran
their blue team CTF on Friday night and
there was a team of to the embroidering
echidnas which is kind of strange name I
know one of them is not here then might
still be here so we're gonna contact
them outside first and second place
they'll finish all of the challenges
they got through everything
yes oh you're both here wait you're here
okay come on
[Applause]
all right and then pros vs. joes also
happened and the the winning team there
was team Raiders of the Lost Ark of
great name I think there was names were
chosen for them all right
given how many people were here this
morning I imagine some people went to
the hecto professed party that was put
on by Altis consulting anyone here
that's still alive from that okay how's
gonna say no everyone died okay all
right
hiring happy hour was another another
excellent event this year did anybody go
to that yesterday I went and checked it
out for a little bit it was a really
good time Kathleen and everyone from
flavor jobs does a great job for us
every year they I think doubled the
amount of resume reviewers and they said
they never stopped working the entire
time so it's definitely a great
opportunity to get some
new event that was added this year
packets in policy that started right
after the clear jobs fair that was
definitely a very interesting event for
me especially bob was the the one who
kind of came up with the idea with bow
from from i am the cavalry kind of close
to the khan it seemed to go fairly well
bob did you feel it went pretty well
yeah i saw lots of people in there
discussing it's kind of an idea to to
get some outreach from our community to
the policymaking community so that we
can share our expertise with them they
can share what their understanding is
with us and we can kind of cross
pollinate those ideas and to help the
policy makers make better decisions
after consulting with us rather than
making decisions before and us going so
it's definitely a good outreach that we
want to do more of in the future relax a
con you're welcome josh it relaxed the
condos are second year we had a great
time we played board games we eat
cookies we drink we drank milk we stayed
up way too late so next year we did so
we did we did ambush Quadling because
it's his birthday
well yeah something that we're expanding
every year applause for getting older
somebody on Twitter dubbed it relax akan
and I kind of like this so I think we'll
keep it again a lot of this is covered
by sponsors love the sponsors help us to
have this space to have everything all
of the equipment all the volunteers all
the t-shirts everything else so running
through those really quickly again our
engage the audience sponsors these are
our top-line sponsors that kind of carry
the bulk of the event for us and above
and beyond our game sponsor or our party
sponsor all just consulting our lanyard
sponsor antietam know that our core
supporters up incoming sponsors and then
additional gear people who give us gear
suffice for the wireless and for the
wireless networks for the actual con
tool for coming out and supporting the
to the wireless village ISE for doing
the IOT village Iron Horse for for
giving us way too much fun on a Saturday
night all right
so networks one point and this is some
network stats that we we ran 1.1
terabytes of data over the course of the
con so stop downloading movies or os or
ISOs apparently there 155 clients
connected to one of our ApS at one time
and at some point we at some point on
Friday what's that or it could have been
the wireless village and at some point
we hit 425 out of 500 megabits on their
pipe which disturbs me a little bit
apparently was on Friday right when the
con started that giant spike
firmware yeah okay update your OS attack
on it's good ideas
I'm sorry yeah I know thanks though I
need to get those Donovan putting off so
final attendance numbers for this year
and he guesses no not two thousand two
thousand ninety three which
which is insane I understand that I mean
send them to what send the extra people
to Delaware
yes extra people move move east last
year's a tense I think was like at 1700
something like that and 16 16 25
honestly the first to give you kind of a
perspective there were six six years old
now our first year we're like 300 and
something and it was it's kind of crazy
looking back actually because you know
the first year we will you come and get
the child she weighs 40 pounds one
moments
never work with children or parents our
parents our children will you pick up
the child yeah so in the middle of that
but seriously you know six years ago we
we had been working for like a year and
a half on this idea besides DC you know
the old story that Mark and build it to
original founders of besides DC called
Jack and said hey why isn't there
besides DC and Jack said there is you're
it and they went what so you know we all
put it together I remember meeting in in
one of the pubs in Chinatown and talking
about this idea and putting it together
and then we all stood in a stood in the
hotel ballroom about this size which was
our entire thing and we all went what
have we done is anyone gonna show up and
then like five people showed up and then
ten people showed up and then 50 people
showed up and then eventually 300 people
showed up when we went oh my god people
came that's cool but you know now six
years later we're over 2000 people which
is just kind of insane to me it's it's
been a process for sure so you know with
that thanks to everyone on our team you
know there's there's Bob doing
co-directing with me Duran dealing with
finances and chasing us all around Jenny
doing doing kids con Angela wrangling
sponsors Jim doing Network stuff and and
reg baat which is awesome
Cory helping with networks Mick helping
with tool now but he also helps with
with some other stuff behind the scenes
Romero doing all the video stuff and
Thor doing video on buying super bright
lights to blind me cuz I think I see him
waving in the back but I can't tell
because there's a spotlight Jojo and get
there doing volunteer wrangling managing
all the all
friendly smashing people Justin Janice
Khan siblings helping us out
Jim chatting and helping us with
networks and reg Seth Feldman he runs
our CFP stuff Jack for keeping us in
lined and boosts and then of course all
the volunteers I mean everyone there's
it takes over a hundred and twenty
people to run this thing so it you know
there's there's a few of us up at the
top who kind of bring all this together
but then there's a ton of people that
make it go so that's that's really
what's going going on there and I just
took some pictures of the various things
shenanigans going on and I think Josh's
hat appears in there twice he keeps
losing it and we keep having fun with it
okay official announcement there to
Josh's hat has a Twitter account
Quadling hat feel it follow it it has
adventures my hat has a Twitter account
my child is a Twitter account my voice
is
and it makes Josh upset which is fun so
with that I'll say thank you again to
everyone for coming thanks for hanging
around for to listen to us blab about
about looking back and then see you next
year the next year's dates to the 25th
to 27th same place follow Twitter and
check the website for any updates
[Applause]