besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success so
the topic today was about DevOps and
security and DevOps and so I my name is
Tish Lutra and before we kind of start I
wanted to provide a little bit of a
disclaimer from what little there's a
little bit of feedback okay all right so
I just came out from a really bad cold
and I'm still kind of running through it
so I'm gonna try not to yell or loud
would be too loud otherwise that's gonna
be the end of me but anyhow this is just
to kind of talk about that there's some
of the things that we are doing in our
development shop and there are some
forward-looking statements also and
we're also talking about some you know
there's not much confidential
information in this deck as such as all
private and wherever the sources are
I've actually labeled where the sources
for those information and and
documentation is but if you if there is
any future or any forward-looking
statement I'll probably pointed out but
just to kind of keep that in perspective
so my name is stage I worked in Berlin
and Merl International is is a good 21
plus year old company and prior to that
they had a different part of the
business so in eight years that did a
lot of web development and over the
years Marlin has had different today but
they wore different hats we built a lot
of software for many major companies and
that business sort of car divested about
maybe 10 some years ago and then
morpho reseller and solutioning business
but overall for the last 21 plus years
it's been predominantly cybersecurity so
and our market has been federal as well
so many of the agencies we've had
working with every working with they are
we've had some really good relations
with them over 15 16 years and running
and we are also moving a lot more into
into the commercial space and last year
we we changed a little bit of direction
it wasn't been a massive shift again but
we retained our reseller and the
distributor business that we have but
then we also took on product development
and this was again after probably a
lapse of a few years we went back into
pearl of them the main reason was to to
provide IP our own IP because we felt we
could solve a lot of these problems that
we come across in a day to day to day
basis in a very different form and start
a different yet in the market so not
being as a as a reseller of anymore but
not this becomes much more bigger when
we go to our customers we not only
stitching them a solution that's
important to them to solve their
problems or aligned with the mission but
we also look in that ways to kind of
solve security problems with our own
with our own product as well join with
me here is Devesh Arora over here and he
runs the engineering pardon we have a
available since it's a young shock
we kind of broke a lot of norm in terms
of how we wanted to set up the shop and
it's very young to like many of our
developers they are roughly at is 6-7
months old as when we started you know
stacking up the shop and then we have a
team about maybe 25 people now so we
really grew very quickly so he leads the
micro services and web development you
know
of our engineering division so today
we're going to talk a little bit about
DevOps we're gonna lay the foundation
and then talk a little bit about what
security means in DevOps
and kind of translate that into some of
the requirements that we see come in
what are the challenges set of guidance
that might be relevant to many of you or
if you come across situations maybe
these you know guidance can actually
play a huge role but fundamentally what
I really wanted to do was kind of open
up as a broader discussion and kind of
give you examples as much as possible
and also talk about some of the
practical experiences that we had over
the years my past experience came from
Netflix where we really ventured into
dev also we really built it out from the
ground up and then I went to IBM it was
totally flipped completely different but
then we could see how we could apply the
same devoir principles to this massive
company and try and bring the same you
know efficiencies that we wanted to
bring so I've had that kind of passive
experience I want to bring some of that
back to you guys and then you know kind
of talk in broad sense also go a little
bit technical where I can but also leave
at a policy level upfront so you guys
can actually see from a broader sense
where it makes sense and kind of give
you some you know anecdotal examples as
well so I wanted to start with this
slide and it's it's kind of good to
understand where the market is going and
and what industries and companies are
really looking into and if you are in a
certain industry it's always good to
keep track of what your industries
moving towards and what they're trying
to achieve so what this chart actually
shows is it's predominantly for adoption
of security in DevOps and this was
published by Gartner I think in earlier
this year I can remember movies for 2018
or 2008 2017 report but it's pretty
evident that
there is a shift of bringing security
into DevOps
and with that there are tons of
opportunities and benefits and I wanted
to start with talking about you know
laying the foundation let's say we know
and understand what DevOps really is and
we implemented some level of that
framework an organization the
opportunity that you know security and
DevOps presents is about continuous
assurance and providing continuous
information assurance to the way we
deliver software and this has been
pretty much you know it's been more and
more evident with cloud native
technologies with adoption of cloud by
moving into you know you know
infrastructure as a code if you if you
look at these different paradigms that
we've started to adopt within the
organization you start to see that
that's actually been you know feeding
into this requirement of information
assurance and that's where the big
opportunity really lies and DevOps so
fundamentally I mean if you kind of look
at the adoption rate within a year or
two like I mean what garden kind of
talks about on the on the top that will
pull it over there from mere 15% to they
see about 80 percent adoption and
incorporating of these capabilities
within you know the existing devops
pipeline and there are tons of
challenges to I mean it's not that it's
you know here's a tool just implemented
and here it goes there is there's a
massive undertaking and understanding of
why we need to incorporate these
physical aspects into you know all the
processes that we do or the tools that
we that we utilize even the mindset of
the people who are implementing their
ops I mean that becomes a big factor as
well but if you guys are looking into
you know building a startup I think this
is a great area to kind of focus into
because the market is fresh there's not
too many standards out there and there's
a lot of requirements coming in but the
growth is phenomenal I mean that's
pretty much what it is and it kind of
boils down to so you know along the
course of this this presentation I'm
gonna
the components of DevOps as well and you
know you'll probably you probably you've
already used some of this or maybe you
know it but soon you will realize that
it's not actually a tool that's really a
practice it's a methodology that we want
to implement and we want to leverage the
best of what it provides so you'll see
you know things like continuous
integration continuous delivery
continuous deployment those kind of
artifacts become really important in a
DevOps environment and that those are
again the key components of how you know
a DevOps organization succeeds in a way
to be able to provide what they need to
provide to their customers and we'll
talk a little bit more about that as
well
benefits are huge I mean you know
predominantly it's about staying closer
to your customers being able to deliver
your software to your customer in a
short period of time and it's all about
being competitive and have that
competitive edge so the whole idea of
DevOps is not just about you know here's
a new process and take it over and
that's about it it's really about
providing that content to your customers
and being closer to them and being able
to deliver these features and in smaller
components rather than these large
monolithic applications or large
features that we are traditionally you
know used to kind of delivering it kind
of breaks that norm down into smaller
chunks smaller manageable chunks and
then provide that as a feature set back
to your customer base so it's really
about you know going back and then you
know the benefits of bringing security
inside this are phenomenal because as
we're getting into this new mode of
continuous delivery and being able to
you know shorten the time of providing
this content back to your customer base
or into your production application it
also brings a lot of risks because
you're kind of running at a very fast
mode you do not want to overlook a lot
of these components about security about
code quality about you know
you know just common sense that you
would normally use in any core
development process so there are you
know lots of benefits of doing bringing
security back into DevOps because it can
reduce your risk it can reduce your cost
quite a bit and I mean as we all know
that if there is a bug fix that needs to
happen in production it's probably 10
times or 20 times more expensive than
actually fixing the bug you know you
know much earlier and in the in the
cycle like you know in the development
cycle so kind of wanted to start with
that but there is there is phenomenal
opportunity that we see so let's spend a
little bit of little bit time about what
DevOps I kind of talked a little bit
about this I don't know how much of a
jalloo you know but DevOps to me is you
know agile on steroids I mean this is
how I see this I mean agile kind of took
this huge paradigm of waterfall and took
you know these massive projects and then
waterfall was literally about you know
following step by step by step see but
then it took a very long time so agile
what that does is it starts the
formation of smaller teams more
collaborative more functional teams in a
way so we talk about a lot of a
full-stack teams coming together
providing a feature delivery so the
mindset kind of changes from a project
delivery to a product delivery that's
really what agile really did and when
you get into a product delivery mode
what you start to see is that you're
more in tune with features that are
going out to the customer you kind of
less worried about infrastructure you
kind of less worried about the mechanics
of how things are actually functional I
mean it's important but you started
liver based off of a business
requirement that's out there so if
certain feature requires it needs it's
maybe there's a requirement going into
the business function then you would
spend time on it otherwise you put it on
the backlog so what DevOps allow you to
do is implement of implement a
methodology to deliver software using
agile methodology so and really the the
focus here is to accelerate the product
delivery for customers I mean that's the
basic goal of it and there are many
other you know
components of why you would want to do
that and there are some conversations
about I'm sorry I'm trying to figure out
where the mouse goes yeah so the core
components of DevOps that we talked
about it brings a lot of continuous
components to it which is continuous
integration which is a principle of
implementing code changes or deploying
code in a pipeline and a pipeline is
radically different from you know siloed
applications because pipeline become
part of a functional operation and they
all kind of deliver an end product at
the you know at the end of completion so
continuous integration provides the code
into that pipeline what continuous
delivery and deployment is about taking
that piece of code and cycling it
through different phases of code
promotion and deployment and you know
getting into the state where it needs to
be and what you should also see is a lot
of components around continuous testing
about continuous quality governance all
these become part of the you know how a
DevOps organization really is formed and
those are the core tenants of any DevOps
component the question becomes you know
why DevOps you know why do we need it
and it's fundamentally really you know
the basic requirement of DevOps why it
came around was the business need to
accelerate product development and in
the way they can accelerate delivery and
it was really a business function for it
so the the focus of DevOps has been how
to move new features to the customers as
soon as possible but then
then there's a there's a radical change
of culture that we talk about and the
change is really on providing the
developers the keys to the kingdom
because now they are much more closer to
your customer because they are not only
developing their code but they are now
responsible for deploying the code into
production and also managing it and
that's where operations and DevOps comes
into play because your development team
is also know your operations team so you
kind of take that whole paradigm and you
squeeze it into one you give them the
freedom you give them the responsibility
but then they have the ownership of
fixing things if they were to go wrong
so there's a lot of ownership that comes
into the team on delivering that piece
of component and the basic functionality
of all the basic you know requirement
for for DevOps is that it tears down the
traditional silos of IT especially
around development and operations excuse
me
you do I just emptied my hyper Cola I
was thinking of calling in sick today I
had a perfect reason to do that let's
see how it goes I'm gonna talk less and
skip some of the advantages that we've
seen across the board from puppet labs
from Bank of America and others is
really about delivery and reduction in
the bugs that they are actually seen by
implementing this process so it's really
it's beneficial I mean when you when you
go across seeing what companies have
done and what they have achieved
there is phenomenal growth but the
journey you know to that point is really
it's something that everyone has to
undergo like you can't just plug in
devops and say I'm DevOps and you're
good to go it's really a journey and
it's not a destination that's how I kind
of see this but once you kind of
incorporate that journey in your process
there is huge increments I mean guilt
for example had this IV for 4.5 guilt is
an online shopping app basically I mean
you can go in and you can choose your
you know what kind of clothing you want
and stuff like that they implemented
DevOps and the use of micro services
based application delivery methodology
and for about two years it was really
about building the core components
building the platform you know getting
things set up so the number of features
that they delivered was probably you
know relatively ok I mean not too many
but once the platform was kind of set up
they had an exponential growth of
delivery of each feature set so that's
what happens when DevOps goes right
because you get phenomenal growth in
terms of delivery in terms of providing
more features to the customer without
adding the cost of additional
development to your organization
so there are phenomenal advantages of
implementing your application using a
DevOps process or methodology and it's
also you know something you have to get
realize
whether you know how your current
development processes are how do you
support your current applications it's
really easy to do this in a Greenfield
way if you have you know nothing you're
starting from scratch this is perfect
this is great but if you already have a
process and you have to maintain all
applications or you have to refactor
something then those are kind of things
that you can probably have to think
about you know why you would like to
implement or why would you even wanna
you know you know embrace DevOps in a
way so just like any other you know
process or tool or a method there's
always you know pros and cons and here
are some of the challenges you know when
we get into this DevOps kind of mode
getting an understanding of what kind of
auditing is is required what standards
that standardization is required how
much reporting do you have to do how
much oversight you have to do all those
things in implementation of controls you
know constantly changing assets in the
delivery in delivery of those components
of the features is really important and
I'll talk a little bit more about these
changing assets because you're moving
into a cloud based methodology you're
virtualizing everything you're straining
out servers on and off so it becomes
really difficult to kind of understand
you know what is changing what's not
changing where your configuration store
because you don't have a physical asset
anymore you're kind of moving everything
into code and when that becomes another
challenge on segregation of duties like
how do you you know provide compliance
when your development is a guy who's
building but is also making bug fixes in
production and things like that or the
operation team is so much more closer to
your development team so you want to be
able to understand the segregation of
duties the other thing is around you
know this virtual acid that we talked
about you know what kind of
authentication schemes are they leverage
the use what kind of cloud provider are
using are you building everything
yourself are you
you know leveraging some capability
provided by someone so you have to kind
of decide and understand what do they
give you and how do you adapt your
requirements to or your processes and
your standards to what they are
providing so it becomes a little bit of
a challenge kind of kind of starting out
with so because you kind of relinquish
in control as well you know you're kind
of giving away of control when you move
to a public cloud so you have to sort of
come to an understanding of whether it
really aligns with what your ultimate
goal is but there are opportunities
because you're constantly improving
there's a lot of automation you kind of
bring in you break down these you know
siloed processes of you know not only
code development but all the way to the
end so when this happens when this kind
of automation and you're kind of
crossing across between teams you start
to see a lot more collaboration in many
you know companies that have been you
start to see a lot of buzz and you know
lots of small team Huddle's because
they're constantly people from different
you know parts of the business and they
could be the line of business it could
be the security team they could be the
DevOps team or the developers and the
architects they're all kind of coming
together and this is a very healthy
thing that happens because traditionally
if you see in a waterfall model you are
typically designing something throwing
over the fence does the next person
takes on something produces an artifact
you know throws it over the fence to
somebody else and then so on so forth
goes I mean there's very little
interaction that's happening so those
are some of the opportunities where
teams start to come together they
understand you know there's much more
communication and it also avoids these
last-minute manual audits that we kind
of look into because you're continuously
developing and implementing standards as
you're building the process or as you're
building the application so there's much
more oversight into how you are actually
deploying quality and if there are some
audit requirement that are coming in
those become continuously deployed we
talked a little bit about threat and
vulnerability management as well so
there's this is where you know lots of
opportunities do exist the whole
paradigm of DevOps is really about
shifting left and security is no
different you start taking all your
processes whether you are
you know designing or you are probably
doing you know security checks or you
are getting together with your business
you start to bring them early on into
the development phase you start with
shift left a little bit and you know so
so that's another big change that starts
to happen quite a bit but then it also
provides you standardized configurations
for example things and frameworks that
you have that code frameworks that you
might have to use across the board you
know you start to see everybody kind of
leveraging the same kind of framework so
if if your container izing all the
applications everybody decides on what
kind of container applications you would
be using or if you're using a certain
framework for java then you know
everybody kind of comes in consensus
that yes this is a right way to kind of
go so you start to see a lot of these
things happen early on and it makes the
team's actually much more productive in
a way so I really wanted to quickly
touch on this end-to-end product life
cycle because the rest of the that kind
of talks a little bit about these
different components and how security
kind of plays a role but I've kind of
broken the zone into three different
sections that develop and integration
and then you have production and we
talked about DevOps it was really about
development coming together with
production and kind of breaking the
silos a little bit but there has to be a
handshake
between them it just doesn't happen
overnight that you're not build
something a built in artifact and then
it's gone and then it's the operations
guys in a turn or when it goes into
production that's when I'm gonna start
looking into it so to be able to provide
you know quality code it has to sort of
process follow some sort of a sensible
process but many of the tooling that are
available to today like the C sed
processes given by Jenkins for example
or others they all do incorporate many
of these components within so the tools
are kind of getting mature in the way to
provide this kind of automation but if
you kind of start from left to right we
look at the development portion kind of
starting first where the relevance get
together developers get together and
they produce some sort of an artifact
and it's typically is a form of a code
maybe a Java file or a class or
something or maybe you know a package
that's available and that package is
then tested it could be the developer
who's testing maybe it's a unit test
test but then it could also be a
dedicated testing team who's actually
applying a lot of tests to it and
there's that's where security scans
could also happen once that is done it's
validated to for certain you know KPIs
that you were trying to measure for
those particular tests so that's when
the business validation component comes
into play and then once a component is
is produced then the security checks
need to happen at the same time because
what you're trying to do is not wait for
the application to go to production to
do the test or the checks but you want
to do them early on so you provide
guidance in terms of what kind of tests
what kind of checks you want to do
whether it's you know checking for hard
codes or bad vulnerabilities in the code
or you know cross-site scripting or any
kind of other tests that you would want
to get done you would want to do them
early on in the development phase and
that's where all this kind of sticks so
once that is done what you have is a
secure package that is ready to be
shipped or deployed and the integration
component really talks about you know
how do I take components that I've built
during my build phase and transfer it to
the next phase which is either it could
be a staging environment or it could be
a load test environment or I'm ready to
kind of take it to a certain level and
it's almost production ready right so I
want to be able to get to that point so
that's what you see the integration come
into play where you have those packages
and you start building platforms
specific delivery artifacts and platform
specific is as we kind of you know
getting into this multi cloud
environment you want to be able to
create your code once and deploy it into
any any kind of cloud environment if you
want to and that's where it becomes
really important for the platform to be
agnostic to what kind of cloud you will
be deploying your application into or it
should be aligned with what is your
target environment so if you are if you
are using containers makes it so much
easier because you built a container and
you basically ship it off to you know
wherever the container orchestration
engine might be whether it's you know at
Linux or if it's a kubernetes based or
wherever it is you know newer
technologies going to make it easier but
then if you're looking at
other applications which are you know
kind of running as virtualized in VMware
or KB M's so you have to kind of think
about how you're going to deploy it but
the platform becomes really important
for that now when the platform is
created when you have the images that
are created the journey doesn't end
there because you have to constantly go
and check and make sure that those
images or the packages that you've
created they are still clean and there
are no vulnerabilities in this so
constantly scanning them for CVEs or
known vulnerabilities or patches that
need to be applied let's say you have a
version of Java running in there which
is you know known to be wonderful so you
need to be able to go and scan those
images constantly over time to be able
to find when they are susceptible or one
river before somebody comes in exploits
there so you want to be able to do all
that in the integration environment and
those applications validated ones are
the ones that run in production so you
can see that the ownership is really on
the left hand side and not really on the
production should still be very light it
should be running as designed because
that's where your user experience really
gets your user should not be you know
the one suffering because you were
trying to deliver features faster it's
really our own ownership on the
left-hand side to be able to produce
quality product you know and and so that
this kind of explains quite a bit about
the whole journey that is typically in
any kind of an agile shop and in a
continuous delivery environment as well
so going into a little bit of you know
these different components we have CI CD
so we've touched on a few of them and
this is something that we've implemented
in our environment as well but it's kind
of just kind of giving you a very
high-level view in the continuous
integration you really have the build
phase that you're trying to build code
and you kind of see the whole process
around the code combined which is really
where the developer comes in and you're
kind of committing the code
it goes through quality scans it goes
through a building unit test and then
you know you want to sort of package it
somehow whether it's a container or
somehow whether it's a jar file and once
that packages could be
it's ready for the next step so you
basically have a compiler code at the
end of CI at this frame that's really
what it is but what it allows you to do
is frequent code checks and check-ins
you can check into a master you know you
don't have to have multiple branches so
it kind of keeps your codebase very lean
but it also brings a little bit of you
know complexity if you have to do that
but these are things that your team can
actually sit down and identify and feel
whether you know this is the right
process for us how do we put make pull
requests how do we deploy into a branch
how many branches we should keep because
now you're looking into multiple teams
providing multiple features and they're
all running in parallel so if you have
too many branches after one year you
might have a really hard time
understanding how many branches you have
and how many of these features are kind
of growing you kind of break away from
the norm of keeping things nimble and
you start to complicate things so those
are some of the decision decisions one
will have to make in the CI phase itself
on how one has to manage the code and
deploy them so this is where you know
some of these processes become really
important now the delivery phase is
really when you've created a package
which is really you know a piece of
compiled code it could be an image it
could be you know some artifact that you
have and you put it into a central
repository and this repository kind of
advertised not advertisers but this is a
place where everybody kind of subscribes
to to pull the final piece of
information that they need for
deployment so if you have built you know
a UI component the you know the image
for the UI component would be in this in
this artifactory well this artifact
repository and from here you will the
the continuous delivery process whether
it's built on champ Jenkins or bamboo or
whoever that is whatever their program
might be they will pick it up from there
and
droid into a target environment which is
your test or the staging environment it
doesn't go into production because
you're not doing continuous deployment
right you continuous deployment you kind
of break the norm and you're touching
production right away in this case
you're only going up to staging but
you're doing full functional integration
security checks up to that point before
releasing the code into production so
that becomes a big part of you know how
you manage code and how you start with
deliver code within the organization and
the next one is Bart continues to
premiere see it's kind of more or less
the same but what you're trying to do is
now you're breaking the barrier and
you're going directly into your final
production environment and this is where
you have either you've enabled live
updates in your tool chain or you're
considering you know building a plan a
deployment plan that goes directly into
your production server so some companies
do that
you know many apps that you actually use
today on your phone they typically go do
work on this philosophy but the whole
idea is that we've tested the code
enough that it's now ready to go into
production and it's it's faster delivery
in a way but the whole idea is that this
the article decode promotion actually
happens all the way to production at
that point so so let's talk a little bit
about you know security intervals and
why would that be really important first
of all you know security is everyone's
business and we as application
developers as applications users we all
have the responsibility of making sure
that the enterprise is secure typically
we talk about secure DevOps from an
application development standpoint but
then the question becomes like what if
an applicant what if an organization
does not build an application what if
they you know don't have any development
shops
it doesn't still apply to them
fundamentally the process of security
applies to everyone it's just that
everyone has to define the process and
procedures and flows and workflows
because what they define will be
applicable to how the applications are
consumed in
organization so it's important because
at the end of the day we have hackers
and chemical criminals who are literally
coming in to find these vulnerabilities
in your application and basically try
and breach in and then you know exploit
and then once they are in they try to go
laterally elsewhere to find you know
critical assets and essentially
basically take control so having
security not only in the DevOps but
overall as an application in a sense in
the organization is is fundamentally
very very important and it should be
part of a security strategy that you
have and the security strategy is driven
by many many different reasons it could
be because of compliance it could be
because of regulation it could be
because of the industry you're in or the
kind of application that you're building
they all mandate certain requirements
around security so before getting into
any kind of development whether it's for
an application or is it if it is for
delivery or whatever it is it's very
important to spend time before the first
piece of piece of code is written before
the first dollar is even spent to find
to define what the security strategy is
going to be and when we apply security
and DevOps these strategies need to be
transferred back to the PMO office who
is going to be putting together the
plans for development because that
communication needs to be transferred
and shifted left in the right form and
in the right expected
otherwise they will never get done if we
say that we will build the policies and
we'll do something afterwards we just
need to deliver software to the customer
and let's just get going with with our
application development that would be
probably a recipe for really you know a
lot of pain at the end so you want to be
able to provide what the you know
processes and protocols are up front
kind of give it give it you know to the
relevant teams up front so some of the
challenges you know people say that here
we are trying to run at the speed of
light and now we have these processes
that we have to take care of and it all
goes down to cost the cost of fixing
about cost of a breach cost of you know
defame a brand situation where you know
company has been breached
those costs outweigh any of these other
things so as you know as an organization
one has to obey the risks and it all
comes down to how much risk am I ready
to take and how much risk I'm not
willing to forgo so it's not that you
know it's not binding anymore you know
so you use the security themes since
they are working much closer with the
development teams they have you know
policies and procedures provided to them
but they're also constantly Valarie
evaluating the risk and if it turns out
that there are certain features that are
going into production that do not form
or conform to the policies then it's
important for them to convey the risk
back to the business owners because then
a proper decision can be made to let the
feature go with a known set of risks or
maybe with a known set of roadmap that
yes this will be fixed in certain amount
of time you know what is the valid date
around it a lot of times the challenges
come out that you know the team say hey
listen we're behind the firewall we're
in a private cloud so we probably don't
need all this stuff which is probably
the really wrong thing to think about
because all the hackers or you know what
they need is really one you know one
vulnerability and once they are in it
doesn't matter whether it's a private or
public cloud I mean there's a lot of
conversation about blockchain and
you know here we have you know appear to
be a validated Network and if it's a
private blockchain then it's you know
really really close but you know
security security I mean and once you're
breached it's you know the same security
principles they will apply so so how
what I mean kind of you know I even
talked about the considerations but
that's really the you know understanding
what the methodology we are leveraging
what kind of physical infrastructure are
we using so and so forth what kind of
testing methodology is being used I mean
all those things can away into interment
understanding what's the router security
and DevOps so let's talk a little bit
about the lifecycle I mean we talked you
know this in the larger sense but if you
look at the chart this is where you know
all the development is happening and the
developers are checking in code into the
build process so during all these steps
where we are we are providing you know
code as a delivery pipeline right we're
providing features in a pipeline rather
than a silo we this is this is all the
pipeline and we are soliciting feedback
directly from the customers so if things
break we're getting understood we
getting an understanding of why it's
breaking people can actually you know
hop on a chat and they are literally
connected to the developer who wrote
that application nowadays so there's
this constant feedback loop that's
coming in so we in this kind of paradigm
where we're connected to the customer or
to the in application and you have you
know very few kind of you know hops in
between from the developer to the
concept consumer the lifecycle becomes
really complicated because you want to
be able to provide all those
capabilities upfront so common things
that you can do up front is a you know
provide static dynamic testing for
example or vulnerability testing which
is you know if a code smells or if a
code is you know not written correctly
like your left API keys and they're
something I mean those are kind of
things that you know we gotta be able to
scan we also need to be able to scan the
images as such you know the baseline the
operating system what kind of
you know ports are open on those
baseline images and and what are we
using to kind of secure them you know
because if we go through a stake process
it's very very evident what they really
want the systems to be and how they want
to operate on those systems so all these
security policies and requirements they
need to be provided early on and the
feedback going back to the cease or to
the security application and security
team is in the form of reports because
they need to understand how these tests
are coming out so if somebody is running
a pen test on the development systems or
on the image the outcome of those pen
tests are really important to see
because it tells how those
vulnerabilities can be exploited what
methodology was used because at the end
of the day the pen testers are really
thinking like hackers they want to
exploit the system just like any hacker
could do and they formulate a process
saying hey this is how I'm going to come
into your system and these are the steps
I'm going to follow to come into your
system and do a certain preacher attempt
to do a breach so getting an
understanding of the kill chain and
understanding the process that the
hackers use that's really what comes out
from all these different tests so
getting all this information back to the
security teams is really important so
these are some of the common
requirements that come about again it
goes back to design there are three
major components to this we look at the
architecture we look at continuous
monitoring and then the documentation at
the end and on the right-hand side you
see some of the key aspects of what the
common requirements are whether you know
somebody's trying to log into the system
how do you do log management what kind
of configuration management do you do
you know what kind of physical and
personal security data security are
there data retention and also you know
disposition of the data is also really
important because in the cloud form you
kind of use the potty floor you know
persistent environment where data is
kind of stored in different kind of
stores and they are really built for
purpose so you could have a time series
drive you can have an object store you
can have so many other things so having
a consistent policy across the board is
really important
goes back to what kind of architecture
you put together and architecture is
really a non your compliance
requirements you know what services are
being used are the sources trusted were
you getting the data from for example
you know are we leveraging cloud native
applications you know all those kind of
decisions need to be made in during the
architecture phase and then the
continuous monitoring is really about
governance about you know what kind of
tools we leverage what information do we
get from them what processes are being
used so and so forth and even the
artifacts in the SLA that are being
defined they're all part of the second
pillar and the last one is about
documentation so you know we have a
security plan you execute it and then
you want to see the outcome and you want
to be able to log those and they
eventually become a backlog because if
you're using an agile process all these
pieces of information they get a score
and they become a backlog because they
have to be resolved during the lifecycle
of the product development so there are
some guidance I don't know how much time
I have but I might have to skip through
some of the guidance but you'll have
them all in the deck there are these are
sets of guidance you know they are kind
of broken down predominantly into how
security objectives are adopted how do
you integrate security across the tool
chain for example you know how do you
bring a code in how do you automate the
process how do you deploy it how do you
test it how do you go back and we do you
know the the the entire lifecycle again
and again so in the next few sections
I'm going to try cover most of these but
I'll try to run through them the first
important thing about you know
implementing security in the
organization is about understanding what
the known vulnerabilities are right so
not go hunt for something that you
that's an unknown unknown because it
could probably you know be a widening
shades at times but knowing a known
vulnerability and knowing a way to kind
of address it is really important so in
today's development paradigm also we
started leveraging a lot more frameworks
and these are standardized frameworks so
your actual custom code that's written
has dropped drastically to about maybe
10 15 percent depending on what can I
in your building but predominantly since
you're using a framework it's easy to
kind of go scan those frameworks for
known vulnerabilities and you know so
it's it's kind of tricky because some of
these frameworks also come from open
source and knowing what the open source
component is and what kind of
vulnerabilities exist I mean that's
important decision that you probably
have to make but setting up a process
along the way to address many of these
normal abilities is always a good way to
kind of start I mean using this I mean
majority time so you can address all the
major flaws that are you know probably
in the application up front
the next important component is about
hardware and software now this becomes
really important because what we are
delivering back to the customer is
infrastructure as a code and software as
a service right so you've kind of taken
away or abstracted a lot of the
fundamental physical you know aspects of
application development so you're going
directly into a more coded way of
deploying infrastructure so where does
that where is that stored it's all in
configurations so it's important to
understand what those configurations are
because what's going to happen at the
end is if you have a cloud provider they
will be spending up machines and giving
to you without any tracking possible so
you can't really understand whether you
know let's say there's a problem that
occurred on system a you the remediation
is destroy the system let's move on
let's deploy the code to a new system
let's bring it up and running and we
just basically destroy the old system in
a cloud environment when we're trying to
scale we do the same thing you know we
want from one web server to maybe a
thousand web servers we quickly scale up
and down so we get all these virtual
ephemeral machines which have no
traceability at the end we kind of you
know lose them as soon as we lose the
machine so knowing all those
configurations upfront understanding the
baseline OS images that are being
leveraged to deploy on those machines is
really important because you're
supplying all the security construct
constructs to that image using code
using configurations using manifests so
all those things are really important to
understand
in the tool chain itself in the in
configured CI CD tool and that we talk
about so all those aspects are actually
included now if you kind of go through
CIS website they actually do provide a
lot of benchmarks out of processes so
and that's a really good place to kind
of go look for these resources and many
of the tool chains that exist today for
example chef you know ansible jenkins
and salt and tuffet you know all they
have they've simplified the process of
rolling this out so you will probably
see a lot more capability in these tools
you not have to you probably don't have
to write everything from scratch so next
kind of comes about you know if you have
orchestrated this continuous delivery
methodology using configurations and
infrastructure as a code then how do you
go and make sure that these are being
deployed properly so there are certain
testing methodologies that are out there
which is one is called the blue-green
deployment your prime model might have
also heard about a/b testing but
Bluegreen is really about you have your
existing system that's running and then
you stand up a new infrastructure and
you know so you have a green
infrastructure that's a new one so you
start to you know direct a little bit of
lower into the new one and you keep the
old one running as well and you test it
out and make sure everything is fine and
then you do a final cut over so in that
situation you are basically you know
providing new feature sets with
literally no downtime so there is no you
know the application doesn't even know
that you know it's basically being cut
over to this new system because
everything is now running in parallel
and then you sort of gracefully switch
over to this new system it's also great
for open to early adopter scenarios for
example where you have maybe tons of
agencies or departments and each
department has their own requirements
around you know certain features that
you want to release so instead of doing
a company-wide release you could
actually you know compartmentalize that
release only focus for that particular
department or agency or for that mission
so you then you can gracefully roll out
to all the other divisions as well so
this methodology becomes much more
kind of useful in in that respect as
well the continuous one durability
assessment and mediation this again is
really important because you know every
so many CVS actually get released off
and on every time and and you want to
make sure that is the CD applicable to
what we are doing is the CPE applicable
to me is there a risk control that is
getting impacted because of the CBE
you know what kind of container so if
you are following regulated industries
it all boils down to what kind of
regulation is being impacted by that
particular vulnerability and is that
vulnerability in your system so having
this automation framework constantly
scan the images based off of those
vulnerabilities and how it impacts your
organization and providing your risk
assessment a business identifiable risk
assessment is really important so that's
again where a be testing and blue queen
kind of become really helpful and all
these scans the more you can shift to
the left during the development process
it makes it much more easier because you
don't have to kind of deal with this as
an after-the-fact because apps act
typically is a different organization
and development is a very different
organization so they won't they don't
necessarily talk to each other but it is
you know if you embrace that wathcing
organization it's very important for
these two teams to start coming together
and even have a champion you know
deployed from security into development
so they can actually you know provide
those that guidance early on into the
development cycle application software
security is again really something that
is important and most of these tools
they are able to provide I'll talk a
little bit about this tooling as well
but they can provide security
assessments and and multiple you know
code checks that you can do and you can
run through these apps fairly you know
on a constant basis it's just a matter
of how much noise are you willing to
take because every scan you do through
an application is going to result into
an action that some developer has to
kind of go and answer or remediate so
you want to make sure that there's a
good balance between what kind of scans
you do to how much information is really
relevant
and our most important to kind of fix
you know and typically in a developed
environment you're delivering smaller
pieces of code there's often a notion of
maybe quality can be kind of you know
reduced a little bit but that really
goes back to the development team and
the principles of the development team
kind of follows on still providing
quality code so it's not saying that you
know you have to relax your coding
standards but it's about being more
cognizant that you would be tracking and
capturing these errors of fun and there
should be a way to kind of handle those
upfront as well so the charts actually
kind of show you like you know somebody
leaves an access key in their code base
the scanners will actually go and pick
that up pretty quickly so this is really
important and what happens in
infrastructure the code in the
fundamental nature of DevOps is that you
have probably handing the keys or the
King keys of the kingdom to one person
or a process for example infrastructure
is a code you know the process that's
deploying the server is the admin also
it has a lot of privileges to actually
do stuff if you look at the DevOps
paradigm for a developer that developer
is fixing code in production so that
person actually has the ability to go
and fix something in production as well
and we all know from regulation that it
becomes really hard to kind of manage
that if the same person is kind of doing
the both things so controlling those
credentials becomes really important so
figuring out how to manage that how to
secure it is really important so many of
these newer tools that are come in they
do leverage keys and certificates and
there is a process of generating the
surge and then rotating the keys and
delivering the keys as and when the
requirement is there so having those
processes inbuilt into your development
process makes it much more easier to
develop infrastructure as a code and be
able to implement all these automation
components that you want to do because
if you don't do that then essentially
you are publishing
username/password out in the open or
there is some methodology that is
probably not validated and it's not
we're going to leave a lot of
vulnerabilities into how you know any
hacker could probably come in and start
using your system so things like hashing
core vault and conjurer SSH management
so those are good examples of where they
actually let you manage keys
they provide rotation capabilities as
well they give you one time access as
well so if you know somebody just needs
access to deploy a certain piece of code
during deployment is just that key that
expires after the first use so makes you
know much more harder to kind of you
know hack into those systems or leave
keys around quite a bit and also kind of
helps not designing a rocket ship like
you see on the top that the carton kind
of talked about a little bit so this is
I kind of came across these guidelines
and I think these are really good
guidelines in terms of implementing
security in your application environment
and they talk about pretty much all the
fundamental things regardless of it as
DevOps
whether it's anything it's really good
sense that any application development
shop should be taken care of so
understanding you know what sequel
injection is and what the processes are
understanding you know security
misconfigurations foundational security
hygiene is really important hygiene
really doesn't come with a with a piece
of code it is really again a practice
it's something that you know we clean
our house we clean our house because
it's a practice and it you know we
instill that practice security hygiene
for an organization is again something
of that you know you constantly have to
make sure that you're high valued assets
are secure and you're doing the right
things to protect your company so there
are some tooling that I came across I
mean this is not an endorsement for any
one of them but I would probably you
know say encourage you guys to kind of
go take a check out these tools they all
kind of do one thing great and the other
thing now some have great UIs and great
logging techniques but then the others
you know don't do stuff that you really
want them to do so take a look at you
know
these are open sores as well as you know
that's available through these big
vendors like IBM and HP and others but
they all have their pros and cons so
overall you know recommendation is you
know one thing that happens with
infrastructure Zak or did you start
treating your end deliverable as an
immutable you know component and the
immutable component is that once you
validate it once you've figured
everything out that it's clean and great
it goes out and it's published out in
the open for consumption if things have
to change you can't change that one you
can't change that artifact anymore you
have to create a new and immutable
artifact and then replace the one that
you had published you have to destroy
the one that's out there so that's where
the immutable concept kind of comes into
play again we talked a lot about
integration and security compliance
testing into your DevOps pipeline that's
important scanning is important scaling
is really important because it can get
really you know busy if you have a pen
testing machine and an info SEC team
that's sitting with development and
you're doing a whole bunch of code
checks the application code checks
there's other security checks in your
code it could actually amount to a lot
of things but you know all these
recommendations are important in terms
of automation about how users are
accessing and so and so forth and most
importantly it's also about the culture
you know having an understanding of how
your application delivery is going to
change or what you are taking on as an
organization is really important so in
closing all that probably want to say is
you know security first it's never an
afterthought it's I think it's the older
dodge we should never stay away from it
and it's again about the culture it's a
lot about the culture you know all these
policies and frameworks are available a
great way to start is you know look at
the NIST framework and you know those
policies can be converted into
checklists and those checklists can be
provided to your PMO office for
implementation in the court you know if
that's a really great way to start if
you don't know how to start a where to
start
you know it's also about what we talked
about was how to bring security into the
vault and that's where it's important
for the security teams to adapt to this
new culture of DevOps as well so it's
not just about DevOps getting more
control and they're free but then
security teams need to come back in as
well and the develops teams need to
understand regulated environments too
they can't relax that you know because
in our case as well I mean although we
are very new shabi of building stuff but
our end consumer is a federal agency and
we know how cruel they are in terms of
adapt you know accepting any piece of
software so ownership is really on all
of us to kind of do a good job and test
all the tools that are out there and
there is a need for best practices
although we do see a lot more coming out
but using those and making applicable to
your company in enterprise is really
important all right so with that I want
to thank you for the time and I really
want to thank you because
so any questions yes please
[Music]
why
so so I have to be honest about those
companies I mean that's not where we
deploy DevOps as Marlon we are actually
managing their hosts and intrusion
prevention so we architected and we also
manage their large all the endpoint
management systems actually we manage
them as well so we deployed them we
stood them up but then none of these
organizations actually have a DevOps
component that goes in with it
the only one that we are actually
working with right now is the homeland
security and it's in the very early
stages but in that case we are so early
in the game we are defining the
application so we are defining all the
security requirements during the design
phase of the application and we're
bringing all those constructs up front
on how we want to leverage their valves
what the PMO office is supposed to do
when we put the tickets together for the
roles that people have I mean we made
sure that the testers part of the the
development team a product owner is
available during the development phase
as well the security analyst is
available during the you know so we had
head counts for each of those roles to
come in so I think it kind of starts
building that culture upfront so in a
Greenfield we were able to do that many
of these are the deployments that we've
done they were already existent or you
know so we didn't have much leverage and
we just kind of adopted what they had
actually done right yes
[Music]
yes I have to yeah I'm really bad at
powerpoints although this looks really
pretty but I hate PowerPoint and most of
my stuff is on confluence I will
actually remove confidential and I'm
going to produce a PDF and then pass it
on yeah oh thank you yeah
any other questions it isn't
so do you so the question is like what
if the security teams are very far away
from the development teams how do we
kind of still kind of bring them
together it's a question I have is like
this development team that you talked
about I mean are they already using
agile methodology and they've already
set up that way okay so I think it's
important for the stakeholders to have a
conversation and make sure that the the
risk of not doing something is exposed
across I think that making getting that
awareness is first thing is really
important I always start with it because
that is process you know but if I don't
have a standard I can put a process I
can't put a procedure together so
showing how this would be important even
providing requirements that you know hey
we need to know what standards to
operate against we need that
understanding I'm pretty sure Caesar
would be all years I mean they would
want to know that hey this is something
that he 7 CIO and C so I think they
should definitely be very close and most
in most organizations we kind of see the
kind of channeling up to the CEO
so they're both their objectives is
really to keep the company safe and
operational although their functional
requirements change you know after that
point because one's on security others
are an application of time so but you
know they still have the same you know
channel to kind of go up to so I would
say escalate it up and and try and get
buy-in from leadership yeah ok yes
please
company
not me it is really hard no it's because
it's a culture you know because oh sorry
so the question is like piggybacking on
this question around silo teams like
who's the ultimate responsibility on the
top I mean I always go back to the
business owner right to me a business
owner is spending the money and they
have an objective in terms of revenue
attainment at the end and if they see
that you know teams are working in
isolation and I've seen that happen in
North Face as well I've kind of seen
that that every company every team is
given their own funding and they go and
do stuff on their own but at the end you
know the mission ends and nobody knows
whether there was it was fruitful or not
so getting that you know focus from the
business owners is really important
getting an understanding from the
development team owners of the
development team not the developers
itself but the ownership of the of that
whole stack and getting those people to
talk about that this is how we are
changing the company or this is how we
are moving forward because we want to
align with these deliverables that the
business has it's always a business
conversation in my mind I mean most of
the time that I'm spending today is
really making sure and making the case
that I'm in alignment with the with the
sales and the marketing and and those
teams and the security team so you know
we are always delivering a product that
sells you know so I thank you very much
for for the time again and hope it was
useful
[Applause]