besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success
hello everybody thank you all for coming
out to my talk I appreciate it I like
talking about this stuff
I'm Isaiah Sarju and today I'll be
talking about how threat modeling made
me better at online dating it's really
focused on threat modeling which i think
is a great skill for folks in security
to have I think we we sometimes get
caught up in like the sexy stuff you
know the exploits and all that but in
the end why we're doing all this is to
make this world more secure and protect
people that we care about and so I
thought that online dating would be a
nice modern kind of context in which to
talk about threat modeling and to learn
what are some of the skill sets that we
need to do or have to do throughout
modeling effectively
so first Who am I I'm a security
consultant Kohner at Revit solutions I'm
a red teamer I do penetration testing I
also teach information security I teach
penetration testing I have certain
worldviews that kind of lead me to do
led me to do this talk
the first being kind of what I'm against
so I'm against nihilism I'm against
security theater I'm against waste of
time I'm very much Pro risk-based
security and it's completely unrelated
to this talk but I love chocolate chip
cookies so if you enjoy the talk you can
buy me a cookie if you hate the talk and
you see me eating a cookie just like
slap it out of my hand
it'll be infinitely devastating for me
and it will let me know that you did not
like what you saw so some good things to
know so who is this talk for um it's for
folks who want to learn about threat
modeling I'm by no means a professional
edit I do use it on my day to day job I
help developers do threat modeling I'm
don't consider myself the best person at
threat modeling so this is for talk I
did this talk to also help myself become
better at it get back to the core
principles so to learn what threat
modeling is learn the basic steps for
modeling and then how can we as
developers as product owners and as in
users use threat modeling so this talk
is for both sides of the coin so folks
who are are building these applications
or any application has privacy concerns
and folks who are using any application
where P is involved and then hopefully
you'll walk away with some tips on how
to do online dating better around
security I can't help you with your
dating game
I can barely help myself so let's just
curb expectations right now I can't help
you be better at it the dating part
itself so in the end you should have a
basic understanding of data flow
diagrams stride attack trees and the
principles of nimittai and Link ability
so these are the core principles around
threat modeling and specifically
throughout modeling for privacy and
it'll be a good good place to get
started and to do continuing research if
it's something that you're interested in
and bring into your own organization or
doing in aspects of your life so I don't
need to beat kind of the the the horse
of why online dating is important to
talk about because growing in popularity
there's any number of graphs that that
show that what I found humorous and and
and lighting was when you search dating
software google recommends tinder bumble
Grindr you know the regular ones and
they also recommend post nuke and my
sequel so so Google like wait dating
software you must want my sequel which
just demonstrates how much our dating
lives are getting put into databases and
the intersection of Technology and are
in our personal lives so why bring
threat modeling to online dating because
I want to avoid promote build and
protect certain things I want to avoid
security nihilism it's very easy in our
industry to go oh my gosh the sky is
always falling there's no hope or as an
end user you know you hear breach after
breach after breach after breach you
like
here's if I give my information at this
new company they're gonna lose it anyway
they're gonna mishandle it and we're all
pwned all the time that's just the what
why even care I don't believe it has to
be that way I think that we can't
promote safe interactions I believe that
folks can can engage in these online
communities engage in these and in these
platforms and be able to do so feeling
safe and in the end I want developers
and folks who own these products to
build more privacy and security centric
applications to build that into the
process and not just bolt it on it'll
build user trust I believe it's also you
know if you aren't getting sued it's a
good way to hold on to the money that
you've made and then in the end all this
is pointless like I said I'm against
doing security for Security's sake I
think a lot of times it's fun to point
the finger catch people with their pants
down say AHA you're doing this wrong but
that's that's pointless that's just an
exercise and like kind of propping
yourself up what do you mean ah no
comment on either of this I'll just
avoid that one all together but yeah so
in the end we have to have a point to
what we do it without that it's it's
just security for security sake so we
want to protect users there any number
of groups you don't feel safe engaging
in online dating because there hasn't
been a space created for them to do that
safely and feel like their privacy is is
is being thought of but still allowed to
engage with the platform so that's the
point of doing all this and there are
consequences of doing bad threat
modeling there are many we've read about
them we've heard the horror stories I'm
only going to focus on two I'm going to
talk about the checks marks research
that some of you were probably familiar
with or check marks research research
from earlier this year
and then this idea of data linking and
demonstrating kind of how easy it is to
link data and and reduce nimma T of a
given target so the first step to doing
throughout modeling is you know the
boring part the least sexy part is data
flow diagrams
so this is one that I put together for
online dating it's simple it's
definitely missing a lot of things but I
want you to keep this in mind as I
describe it and I'll hop back and forth
so keep that in mind as we describe what
a DFT is so you want to first decompose
the application process and you want to
understand how data is flowing then we
can apply stride which some of you are
probably familiar with I'll get into it
for those of you who don't know what
that is and we can apply stride to each
step of that data flow diagram and
that's gonna help us start to think
about actual threads so again what
opting for so we decompose the
application we see its indistinct its
indistinct areas right there we have the
dating application the social media that
might get tied into it we have end users
that's using it we have third parties
that get all this data sold to them
because why not monetize your customers
you know in addition to how you're just
monetizing them directly so we we
decompose that we see how it's all
connected we understand how data is
flowing some data floating mana
directionally sums bidirectionally and
then what we can do is we can look at
each step and we can fly stride to it so
stride is a great acronym it's spoofing
tampering repeat agent information
disclosure denial service and elevation
of privilege so this is how we can start
to it gives a way of thinking about it
in a in a systematic way of coming up
with potential risk to our application
and to our environments and this doesn't
just have to happen in in a data flow
diagram you can do this when you're on
an off of your offensive team you're
trying to think about what could be some
vulnerabilities in this application
they're usually going to fall under
stride and it gives you a good way to
brainstorm so just some examples so
spoofing you could falsely claim to be
Isaiah Sarju on your tinder profile and
wouldn't recommend that your your your
success rates would probably go down a
lot
but there is no way of necessary
verifying folks tinder is known for
having a lot of BOTS a lot of people
spoofing Bumble does offer a level of
verification it's an OP end not a
requirement then there's tampering such
as changing the presented profile photo
changing a swipe let's say there's
someone acting as a man-in-the-middle at
a coffee shop or something like that
being able to change the interaction
that somebody's having on that platform
repudiation being able to say I didn't
swipe right on that person without the
application being able to say you
absolutely did you absolutely did it so
there's no like signing of a swipe like
some type of digital signing of it it's
not being put into anything that has has
some level of non-repudiation
information disclosure so disclosing who
you're swiping on disclosing your
matches disclosing who you're chatting
with after a match that's one thing I
want to focus on information disclosure
it relates to the two examples that I'm
going to talk about in a bit then
there's something like denial of service
so not being able to have the front-end
talk to the clients this could be you
know not being able to access tinder on
a Friday or Saturday night that could
mess up a lot of people's plans and you
know if you're not able to connect you
kind of be screwed and not in the way
that we like for online dating but like
you you don't if you have if there's now
service on against your application then
they're going to go somewhere else and
that's not ideal
there's also elevation of privileges and
I didn't really think about elevation of
privilege until the recent Facebook
breach where folks were able to
impersonate a user and then use that to
authenticate to third-party applications
and I should have thought about that
just looking at this data flow diagram
like this was on me just thought about
it look at the data flow diagram I see
social media has a direct connection
with user data with potentially
authentication systems and I didn't even
think about this and then the Facebook
breach happened I was like oh my
goodness yes I should have thought about
how those two can interplay with each
other and so being able to do something
like a lateral lateral elevation of
privilege across one context
of the user profile to that user profile
in another context social media to the
dating application so let's look at an
actual example and what we'll do is in
threat modeling when you're using data
flow diagrams you want to pick one of
those those those intersections that's
where you want to start where data is
crossing context that's where you going
to get the most risk there's definitely
risk internally within each one of these
internal boxes its internal context but
for example the end user context they're
my phone or my computer I can pretty
well control that nobody's going to kind
of access that if I have physical
security around that I'm carrying it on
my person I have a strong passcode using
a fingerprint whatever it might be I can
pretty much prevent people from
accessing that stuff on that device but
when it's crossing that boundary that's
when I get exposed to risk and so this
is where you want to start looking while
you're doing threat modeling is where
data is crossing context and that's
that's the best place to start so if we
look here where you have these different
potential clients connecting to the
front end the folks at checks marks
checkmarks I keep adding an S there
excuse me folks that check marks were
able to show that the images that were
getting loaded on the device for someone
to be presented with the swipe left or
right were sent unencrypted and so
they're able to see the images and then
once the person made a decision the
response they got so that's the top
right hand corner image response they
got differed in size based on if it was
a no a yes or match and so that was
tender disclosing information on the
decision that person made so you know
we're sufficiently scared there's no
hope
yada-yada I don't believe that we can
always manage risk and we have some
choices so for those of you who do risk
management these terms are pretty
remedial you're used to seeing them for
those of you who don't they're good to
understand kind of what are our options
for managing risk we can accept it okay
it's gonna be that way we can avoid it
remove ourselves from that context
we can transfer it you know give
somebody else responsibility by
insurance hire security guard whatever
might be we're transferring that risk or
we can mitigate it and sometimes folks
break up mitigation and reduction I like
to put them together because you're
either mitigating it partially or
mitigating it fully so you're taking a
step to kind of reduce that risk where
you're taking a step to get completely
rid of it so I like to combine those
together I see them as similar similar
things there's a matter of how much how
much you're handling the risk in its
entirety great so let's apply this to to
that specific case of check marks so
like I said I want to approach this from
the app developer side and from the user
side because I think there's
responsibility for both parties so at
the app developer they could have just
put HTTP on everything like there's no
reason why you shouldn't have HTTPS
across every every single data
interaction between a client and your
infrastructure just put HTTPS just I
don't know I'm not going to keep going
but like it blows my mind that they
don't do that because they do another
parts of their application we know it
doesn't slow things down just do it okay
so they could standardize the response
size that would prevent the information
disclosure of the decision the person
made so I'd be mitigating that risk or
they could just don't they just don't
care they just accept it and that's
currently the route they've chosen to go
there's also steps the user can take the
user could use a VPN so they can still
exist in that environment they can still
swipe at a coffee shop but they're
mitigating that risk with a VPN they
could avoid that risk and only do it at
home so that it only be exposed to
potentially their their ISP or they just
don't care kind of the security nihilism
around which I really don't like I think
there are steps we can be taking so this
has been an example of using a data flow
diagram applying stride to it and then
thinking about how we can handle the
risk there's another thing that I want
to talk about which was attack trees and
this is a great tool
I use this in my offensive work when I
have a target that I want to compromise
I'm going to create an attack tree and
I'm going to come up with the different
routes I think I could get there I have
when I make actual attack trees for my
red teaming engagements they're much
more complex and they're much longer
left to right because they intersect you
know if I get caught in one area but I
was able to get data before that I could
potentially use that for a different
path
so the paths can intersect and overlap
and this is just a simple attack tree so
let's say you wanted to stock somebody I
don't Rick I don't advocate for stocking
anybody actually you could also say
let's say you don't want to be stopped
you can create an attack tree against
yourself and say how would somebody
stalk me if they wanted to so it's on
both sides of the defense and the
offense so let's say this lets say an
attackers goal was to stalk someone and
they wanted to learn where they live
let's say they match with them on a
dating application if their opening
message was hi I really like your
profile where do you live
you know maybe ninety six ninety seven
percent success rate with that they
could get the location that way just by
asking for it let's look down at learn
where they work that has some examples
that I really want to get into so some
folks just put their company name right
on their profile they put their company
they put where they work or they could
put you know you could ask for it as an
attacker sometimes folks disclose their
profession they disclose their real name
and then they also have some type of
location data associated with it that
can be used you know Monday through
Friday nine to five having a relatively
good idea of where somebody is you can
also spoof your location as attacker
fairly easy easily and move yourself
around and get overlapping distance
circles distance radiuses so you can
overlap those and get an idea of where
somebody is real time and that brings me
to this idea of nimma D and link ability
so using those three to two
to execute on the objective of learning
where they work and let's talk about
that so nimma D is just the amount of
information that's disclosed in an
interaction so anonymity we're all
familiar with it's the lack of nimma T
so nimma T is that information that we
put out and Link ability is the ability
to bring one or more records into a
single record and so I call this a super
record or virtual record or virtual
drawing for database folks in the
audience that would be like a key you'd
have a key such as an email or phone
number that you could find in multiple
data breaches and you could use that to
link someone so if you saw their their
phone number and their email associated
in one breach you saw their email and
their real name associated another
breach you can link on that email and
you have the phone number email and full
name of that person and so that's a
super record or virtual record and so
this is an example of someone's profile
I was able to just with their real name
and you can't really tell but in their
profile they say at some tech company
that's like the only part I didn't blow
her out
they say at some tech company so they
obviously were aware of the privacy
concern of disclosing their actual
employer but just with their real name
and a description of what they did I was
able to find them across their LinkedIn
and across their other social media
profiles across their twitter across
their Instagram and create a super
record on this person learning about
basically around where they live based
on their Instagram photos they took a
lot of them learning about where they
worked because they explicit I found
their explicit LinkedIn and so able to
join from these disparate records based
on single piece of information that
overlap and so you'll notice that I've
lured out a lot and that's because even
with this person school and just their
job title you'd be able to find this
person
and it's very important to remember that
disclosure does not equal consent you
know a lot of times you see this in
private research where they aren't going
through a FX board or research board
where they'll just disclose this
information and they'll say well they
put it out there on their online dating
so they deserve to have it out in the
world this person is choosing to share
their information with folks within a
specific geographical region so just
because they put it out there doesn't
mean that they want random folks at a
conference in DC to see it so it's
important you know as we're doing this
it's just me taking a second on my
soapbox to say we do need to care about
these privacy concerns when we're
talking about research that handles real
people in in the actual world so again
we're not sufficiently depressed and
despairing that there's no hope I want
to fight against that and say there
absolutely is so we can handle this risk
as the app developer we could allow
users to choose which information they
disclose and they do this right now it's
risk transference we could as an app
developer not disclose their Instagram
handle Bumble made that decision to not
disclose Instagram handles while tinder
discloses the full Instagram handle so
bumble has choose to do some level of
mitigation its reduction down so the
Instagram photos that are displayed in
somebody's profile or only like the last
five or last ten or whatever while
tender you can actually go back and find
that person's actual Instagram and look
at years of photos if they have a public
profile and so that's different levels
of reduction that could be there
there's fuzzier delayed location sharing
this I really like this idea and I wish
dating apps would use it we see OkCupid
doing this they won't say like a mile
away they'll say like five miles 10
miles etc and so it's it's fuzzy so it's
hard to triangulate somebody's position
with with just with such a broad
distance categorization so that would be
nice well bumble on the other hand goes
down to the tenth of a mile it's a lot
easier if you're spoofing your location
to hop around different locations and
identify where somebody is if they're
saying their 1.7 miles away it's a lot
easier to do that so and that could be a
way of reducing risk in this situation
and then or they could give the user the
ability to hide their distance
tinder does this but the problem is is
if you do that
folks think that you're a bot and so the
I I really opted for that kind of
gradient where folks can have more fuzzy
or delayed locations as the user we can
also take steps we can avoid this
Wriston just not date but online dating
is it is a modern way of doing dating
and it's what a lot of people are
starting to do and so instead of saying
you know screw that we should just leave
it behind don't do it let's find a way
to do it more safely in a way that
protects the privacy and safety of the
users so you can use a fake name it
makes it harder to do link ability if
you do that don't disclose your employer
I don't connect your Instagram you can
prevent so one thing that I think this
this part really should demonstrates
well when we get to preventing real-time
location sharing is if we go back to
this diagram here and we look at the
lower left when you're looking at that
and we say okay the context of the
end-user and the context of the
application are separated what is that
app is the end-user
client actually doing it is there to
present you with photos and to share
your real-time location so the real-time
location is coming from the end-users
client device so theoretically the end
user should be responsible and have
ownership over that location and so we
can start to think about how do we use
this application if it's not if we
prevent it from running in the
background so it's not sharing our
real-time location if we choose when we
want to use the application so that
we're only you know using the
application when we're travelling
between home and work so that's never
being tied to our actual place of
employment or our place of living where
we are more static in our lives so if we
think about that then we can talk about
how can phone to be designed better for
not just dating applications but any
application that uses locations and
iPhone is taking the step to say only
use only share location when you are
using this app or when it's running in
the background or never and I really
appreciate that because it puts that
power in the users hand if when they
want to disclose their location to that
pick application Android on the other
hand just like y'all know we're just
gonna scarf it up because God forbid
Google doesn't pull information out of
our pockets every you know three seconds
so what is that oh yeah its fact I just
didn't want people to be any more
despaired like let's just be the spirit
about online dating we can be despaired
about other things in other talks so but
yeah there is hope I think so
we can also spoof our locations and or
we can just be nihilistic and be like we
don't care cool
so from this talk hopefully you've had
some tools of data flow data flow
diagrams and attack trees and
understanding you know new MIDI and Link
ability so these are kind of the core
principles that I use on a day-to-day
when I'm doing threat modeling modeling
especially around privacy centric
applications and so in the end I want
developers and to be able to build
better applications I want us who are
acting as defenders to think about the
stuff intentionally so when we do things
like create data flow diagrams if not so
much about the end product of having the
pretty Visio diagram because they're so
beautiful
it's not about that it's about the
process and and the intentionality of
having to create that as an attacker if
you're doing offensive simulations these
are also great tools whenever I'm doing
red teaming engagements if I can get my
hand on network diagrams of any sort
that's gonna help me further my
objective or if you're doing something
like a web application penetration test
and you can get an understanding of how
the data the backend databases are
connected where connections are
encrypted where they aren't where data
is at rest all of that can be helpful
when simulating offensive attacks or
doing penetration testing type activity
and in the end
Isis users can use these applications
more safely and so I want everybody to
be more intentional about the decisions
they make when they're designing
applications and when they're using
these applications so that's all I got
if there are any questions I know I was
scheduled for 15 minutes but I don't I
don't
thirty minutes that I have that much
material but I'm happy to stick around
and answer questions if anybody has them
yes location what they did what they did
encrypted coming back they was your foes
clients go ahead yeah I remember that so
I focus on the major applications but in
the research that I came across there
let me see I don't remember if I have so
okay so some applications use HTTP HTTP
consistently across the application
across sending it between the client and
the front end I specifically talking
about tinder in that case there have
also been situations where like you said
they're they're sending their fording
the therefore ting the location to the
phone of the of the potential suitor and
they're in the phone itself is
calculating the distance we saw this
with Grindr than disclosing HIV status
directly over that application or
actually I believe those two third
parties but they're like packaging a bit
but it's coming directly off the client
and there was lack of anonymization and
again the link ability issue it was a
whole net I don't remember if they had a
problem with encryption also somebody
else remembers that please feel free to
shout it out I don't remember that what
exactly happened with that but I
remember that was a problem with Grindr
in the last year or so any other
questions
right appreciate it thank you
[Applause]