besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success
good afternoon everybody I am Daniel
Orlando and this is a delight Mecca and
we're presenting a talk on encrypted
network traffic and detecting malicious
activity in encrypted traffic so we we
are from Fidelis cybersecurity so first
of all network traffic is sequential
it's it's a sequence of sessions one
after the other some of these sessions
may be encrypted and so for example
first you may be as an example of
malicious activity first you may be
referred by a hidden iframe you may
visit a landing page malware may be
downloaded over TLS paying for
connectivity and then steal data over
TLS so notice that a lot of these
sessions are encrypted and in fact a lot
of the critical sessions where important
malicious stuff is happening is
encrypted in this example so but but
also there there are some of these
things that are in the clear
so when it thinks for connectivity
that's that's in the clear the hidden
iframe may be a HTTP page and the idea
is to use the structure of how the
sessions flow to understand whether this
is actually malicious traffic or not
[Music]
so first we're going to talk about some
of the data we use to to train this
model some of the features we extracted
which features are a numeric way of
describing data that the algorithm uses
and then some models so once we actually
have these features how can we use these
features to train the models and then
we're going to look at some results
we're actually going to peer inside from
feature extraction all the way to
inference model inference exactly what
is going on at each step of the process
and then finally we'll give an
illustrative example for how this is
working so first the data the malicious
data we have our suspicious files that
are submitted to the Fidelis sandbox
appliance and these files are run
through a sensor and generate pcaps and
that our internal start research also
researchers also finds files and submit
them as well they have feeds that they
can see latest files and and submit them
to the sandbox that we have pcaps from
from customer submission and threat and
we another issue is labels so with
supervised learning there's a
fundamental question which is what are
the labels this is this data an example
of a cat or a dog or or a horse for
example so we need to know which which
these samples are are are these
malicious are these benign right because
we're taking submissions and going
through well in addition to the feeds
where everything's obviously labeled as
malicious we take submission so we have
to label them first and then we can use
them for our algorithmic trading yes so
this is um this is primarily from a
and our own rules developed by the
threat researchers and we use samples
which are highly confident that these
are indeed malware so for example on
something like VT there are a lot of
different high scores from from the
vendors to confirm that they are indeed
malware and that that comes to around
36,000 samples that we used in the
training for this particular exercise
here yes and as for the benign data we
could use submissions labeled as benign
but the issue is that these submissions
to the sandbox are not in general
representative of general network
traffic so what does this mean if if you
are a user who is using a computer
browsing some stuff on the web that may
look different than the network activity
of say a word document or or an
executable that is being submitted to
this even if the executable is indeed
benign so the idea is if we want to use
this in production with live traffic
then the benign data actually has to
look like live traffic so what we do is
we supplement the benign samples and
sandbox with a DMZ network traffic and
that comes to about 550 1,000 samples
from benign submissions and another
270,000 samples from this general
traffic so you know adding adding it up
that comes to about 320,000 benign
samples
another question is if you look at the
samples that we had for the malicious
yes or the malicious data what we had is
a sample being submitted and then all
the sessions that came from from that
sample detonating in a sandbox so how
does this correspond to live traffic
then the idea is to put a hard limit on
a two-minute continuous sequence of
sessions so there's there's a certain
threshold one session after another and
a requirement that that that's within a
two-minute window because the whole the
whole idea of machine learning is you
have to have if you're doing a
classification problem you have to have
an apples-to-apples comparison so for
example if you were trying to classify
between a picture of a cat and a picture
of a dog it would be it would be
problematic if on one hand you had
photographs of cats and on the other
hand you had drawings of dogs for
example so the idea is you want both of
the classes to be similar and finally
we're going to talk about the features
so again as I was saying you you have
the raw data which are the proxy logs
and we want to extract features we want
to come to vectors which describe the
data so this is this is a really large
problem and n is face image recognition
there are many ways to get vectors from
images text there are many ways to get
vectors from text and in this case we
actually want to use one of these ways
to get vectors from text so what we're
going to use some natural language
processing techniques and talk a little
bit about what that means in this
content but also in cases of encrypted
traffic obviously you can't see the text
so you can't do your standard text
analysis so there we use the certificate
classifier that we presented at last
year's besides as a supplement for the
cases where we don't have direct
national and natural language processing
type features precisely and so the idea
is what we can see what we do have
detailed visibility into we will use and
then what's a little bit more opaque
will
we'll met with the certificate
classifier and we're gonna talk about
this is text how are we going to use NLP
to understand this and convert this to
vectors so a simple way is to use some
technique called bag of words and one
one hunting coming so for example here
this is a document it's a very short
document just one sentence the tuxedo
cat that's afraid is not really a
sentence and it's the document has a
very small vocabulary it only has three
words three unique words in it the
tuxedo and cat so the vectors that we're
going to use to represent the words in
the document are going to be the size of
the vocabulary and each word is going to
be represented by a one hot encoded
vector in this space which means it's
one in one place and zeros and all the
others so me we could arbitrarily
represent with this this vector here one
zero zero tuxedo zero one zero and cats
zero zero and now now that we have this
phrase we want to represent this
document as a vector so each of these
words has a vector associated with it
each of the words in the vocabulary so
we can aggregate them together simply by
taking the sum and get what's called a
document vector so this is a document
vector representing this document the
tuxedo cap and the idea of using this in
the context of sessions is that if each
session we can represent by a vector
using using a technique like this there
are many tokens in a session so we can
aggregate them to get a session document
vector but we actually want to talk
about sequence of sessions not just one
session so the ideas our input data
would be a sequence of document vectors
that's great and in fact that's the
setup we're going to use but the problem
is the
to many dimensions so we can't use this
this bag of words approach where the
dimensionality of the vectors is that is
the size of the vocabulary because of
the vocabulary is huge the English
language already has a huge vocabulary
French Spanish huge vocabulary but if
you take something like cybersecurity
there's just a whole world out there and
a very large vocabulary so a solution is
word to back and work to back is a very
popular approach these days for doing
representation of text so for example
even something like Google Translate
uses a sequence the sequence neural
network with with word embeddings so
with word tobacker and possibly some
other kind of impelling they invented
word to vet for google yes lee yes so
yeah for Google Translate yeah I'm
pretty sure well but yes they did they
did invent work to back and idea is if
we go back here notice that the vectors
in the space are very sparse it's it's a
high dimensional but sparse space and by
sparse I mean it has it has very few
values that it can take in this space so
you know there are very few vectors in
in this space there they only have the
values in the component 0 and 1 and
actually why not have a lower
dimensional space where the vectors are
more dense in the space which is to say
that the components of the vectors can
take all real values so instead of going
0 to 1 integers between 0 & 1 inclusive
those are those are only two integers
you could have the uncountable set of
all real numbers in each of the
components which allows a massive
dimensionality reduction exactly and and
more get more capability of expressing
all these different words in
lower dimension so the idea of your
Tyvek is you train it on a corpus of
data and it's trained to recognize
possible context from a word and it
actually uses a shallow neural network
to do this but the interesting thing is
once you do this it recovers some very
interesting semantic information so the
dimensions in the basically you're using
the word to back model to transform your
very sparse representation into a dense
representation and the dimensions in
your dense representation are these
semantically meaningful dimensions yes
it turns out to be the case yes and so
like as we see in these examples the
dimension that the in the the dimension
of like grammatical gender for example
the word King is in one place and where
Queen is in another the word man is in
one place the word woman is another or
in the semantic dimension of present
tense - past tense the present tense are
all on this side the past tense are all
on that side and so you end up with you
end up that the model basic the neural
network in the worked effect model
actually learns the semantics in furs
the semantic variation within your
training set so back back to the title
of the presentation actually this is a
this is a good point to mention it
that's the whole idea of network traffic
is an open book because we are using
natural language processing techniques
so the ideas visibility into encrypted
traffic but also using using these
natural language processing technologies
so now that we've talked about the
features we can talk about building
models using these features so one
possibility is random forests this is
very this is a very popular algorithm to
use but a limitation of random forests
is as we talked about we have these each
stamp one way to
aggregate these these vectors together
to in order feed it to random forests is
to just take the mean and and so so yes
so now we can use random force but for
those of you who don't know what random
forest is I have a small example here a
random forest is an it's what's called
an ensemble classifier of decision trees
and a decision tree is this float it's
sort of like this flow chart over here
with with this with this root so it's a
flow chart with a root and as it
branches off it it makes different
decisions so this this flow chart over
here is representing if somebody died in
the Titanic or not this is the canonical
textbook example of a decision tree yes
it's slightly morbid but but and so you
know one of the first questions you
might ask is are they male or not and
right off the bat if they're not male
there's a high probability that they
survive women and children first on the
exact so that's so that's what this
whole thing is representing actually
women and children first and a decision
tree you go by sex is the the way they
essentially the way a decision tree gets
trained is it looks through all the
features you have and it figures out
which one has the most predictive
validity for the set of data that still
exists at this stage of the flowchart
and so you start off you have everything
at which point the women mostly survived
is a pretty easy prediction to make but
then within the men you have to look I
mean the old ones mostly died and then
the children it actually turns out
interestingly to be depending on how
many adults were accompanying the
children whether they survived so and
this this actually is a great decision
tree but if we have on the order of
several hundred features which is what
we're looking at if we have hundred
dimensional vectors then what happens is
if you train a decision tree on these
features it has a tendency to over fit
which means that it'll have difficulty
generalizing
new data so one one way to offset that
overfitting is to use what a most
ensemble yes this ensemble classifier
random forest so it's like having
multiple experts in a room and they each
have a random subset of the features
they each know they each have different
strengths but together they can come to
a very well-informed decision so the
wisdom of crowds as applied to these
machine learning algorithms yes and and
so that actually did pretty well very
well ninety ninety eight point nine
percent accuracy with a high AUC of
point nine nine seven six but we could
actually do better than this so the next
step is to use a recurrent neural
network which takes into account this
information of of this sequence of
vectors so it uses the information about
ordering of the sessions and the idea
the idea of how a girl recurrent neural
networks is through each example you
have multiple vectors and the feeding in
vector after vector and these these
horizontal lines are the weights that
keep getting updated as you feed in each
next vector so it turns out that the
most important feature when we use a
recurrent neural network ends up being
the certificate classifier score when we
train the random forests we use the
certificate classifier score and it had
an AUC of 0.99 seven six and then when
we train the recurrent neural network
without the cert classifier score the
accuracy went up but the AUC went down
and the AUC is the measure of general
quality of the model as you vary the
predictive threshold so maybe you decide
you really want
really want to make your false positives
as low meaning that you only predict a
positive if you have a higher threshold
so AUC is a way of measuring aside from
of the standard cutoff of 0.5 how it
does over many different carry it's a
it's about it does it refers to the ROC
curve which area under curve yeah and so
the the curve itself is it's a
characteristic it's a characterization
of the model and it's a standard signal
processing metric that we use but in any
rate I think the main point is so using
the better model drives up the accuracy
quite a bit well or rather cuts down the
inaccuracy quite a bit I mean once once
you're approaching the plateau is a
little incremental mentioning returns
but as far as it goes you can see that
actually the search score makes a
difference but at any rate it's really
the switching from basic sequence lists
traffic to characterization to the
sequence aware characterization of the
features that really gives you the in
actually classifying traffic so now that
we've talked about data the features the
modeling we want to show some concrete
results of actually what this looks like
from beginning to start and actually
peer inside the model so first off what
you're going to see are are several 2d
visualizations but keep in mind that
we're actually visualizing 150
dimensional data and more so what we're
going to be using to reduce the
dimensions to show you because at least
I can't view 150 dimensional spaces but
is tease me
so TC is
is an award-winning dimensional
dimensionality reduction technique that
essentially builds a probability
distribution between the similarity of
every two points in this high
dimensional space and and has some some
it projects down to two dimensions or
three dimensions or whatever dimension
you you choose to reduce to and make
sure that that that probability
distribution is preserved so here here
are the five stages that we're going to
visualize this on one one one stage is
the transaction level word embeddings
because within each session are the
transactions so these are the various
network operations that the HTTP
operations for example in an HTTP
session yes and and then you assemble
these transactions and you you get
sessions and there are certain things
that are constant now across sessions
but are not constant across transaction
so these these are the tokens that are
at the session level so we have to word
embeddings going on and we assemble them
together to get the document vector
which represents those sessions as a
whole so remember that each sample is
actually a sequence of sessions so once
once you have a sequence of these
document vectors then you actually hand
it off to the RN n so the RN n is seeing
the recurrent neural net so the Arnon is
seeing a sequence of vectors and we're
going to look at the activations in the
first layer and then we're going to look
at the activations in the second layer
and okay so these are the transaction
level token embeddings and the this is
the same plot if you look at the shapes
it's really the same plot but we're
actually looking at looking at it across
these two different dimensions of
malicious and benign so malicious is
the nine is blue on the Left chart there
and on the right we are actually looking
at these different kinds of kinds of
tokens so there's a - suya
tokens from url's tokens from hosts
different different things and these are
the different fields in the proxy log
that give us token quantity in the
different so each of these points is a
session and the color corresponds to
what sorts of tokens so what's
interesting here we got so much the
picture on the left because since we're
in a very low level we're not seeing a
lot of separation between malicious and
benign samples they sort of have similar
tokens they're their clusters of blue
tokens they're little pieces that are
predominantly red but overall it's it's
really muddled what is interesting
though is that the word embedding does
learn very distinct things about types
of tokens on its own so keep in mind
that I'm not telling it some additional
information about what kinds of tokens
these are just like if I was training a
word embedding I wouldn't be telling it
that this is a verb that this is a noun
it just automatically figures that out
on its own from contact right so the
basically the the different colorations
of these different regions correspond to
the word embedding having learned
different semantic properties of the
different classes of tokens in the proxy
logs so a word on axis if you're
confused about that of pi-1 and pi2
recall that we are visualizing a
two-dimensional projection so pi is just
a mathematical lowercased pi is just
mathematical notation for the first
projection and the second product
projection remember that this is active
these are sort of contrived dimensions
here for the visualization purposes
and then it actually gets a lot more
interesting with TC with sorry with
session level tokens so here again we
have predominantly a component with
predominantly D port on the left on the
right and other stuff on the left which
others use other things it's primarily s
and I actually and there's a lot more
variety on the tail of that over there
but if we look at the figure on the left
again the the deport the D ports are
very muddled there's some some benign
some malicious looks like yeah the main
point here is that by the second in the
session level tokens you can see we got
quite a quite a bit more structure in
terms of exactly the semantics of
whatever between the semantics that was
perched on the edge of the table
whatever anyway so basically you can see
that we got we got substantially more
clean structural understanding of the
semantic meaning of different types of
tokens at the session because because it
is higher than transit rights but again
so these these semantic tokens don't
really court the presence or absence of
these tokens doesn't really correspond
to a label because I mean you're going
to have destination ports in malicious
traffic and benign traffic right so yes
so moving on to now we're actually yes
so this is this is by the time you you
aggregate all be total all the vectors
all the word vectors from the session
tokens all the word vectors in the
transaction level tokens and you
assemble them into the document vector
one for each session and this is this is
this was very exciting when I first saw
it because it it goes along with your
intuition that some sessions will
definitely be malicious and you will
only see malicious traffic some sessions
are benign and you probably all be seen
benign traffic and but there's a lot
where you see it's mixed so I don't know
if it's the beer model here you have a
bit of a muddle here you little model
here even in places where it's
relatively clean you still it's still a
little bit muddled yes but there are
some reasons where it's pretty
relatively clear and some regions where
it's sort of isolated so but but the
idea is that since we've gone up a level
we've gone up from transactions to
sessions and now our transaction our
session tokens to now a whole
representation an aggregated
representation of that whole session we
really start to see some significant
separating out between what really looks
like malicious and what really looks
like benign and so this is now we can
look into the sort of knowing on the
Left what the labels are for the
different regions of this contrived
projection space we can look and see
what are some different features that
correspond to different locations of
that space yes so that that orange down
there for example that's from the UK
yeah that green up there is from Russia
well there's some China there's some
traffic that goes to China from here
there's some traffic that goes to China
over here but in general you can see
that actually the traffic going to
different countries is relatively I mean
there's some muddled in the middle but
there are some regions where it's quite
clearly defined that the traffic in this
area is bound for one destination
country versus another destination
country yes
and then the greyed out blobs there
which as you see it's not really in the
color-coding our unknown country so
that's like DNS requests that we may not
well not just done mostly unknown but
also I mean we're not we're only
coloring five of the countries yes but I
mean there are other countries in the
world obviously and so but yeah so
moving on this is a different coloration
of the so as you see the region there's
a lot of DNS requests you know this this
piece of a fear are DNS requests that
we're only seeing malicious data mainly
there's a little bit of blue specks in
there right but a lot of that is is
malicious DNS requests and these ovals
are you know some makes seven to nine
DNS and for for our purposes the engine
the most interesting piece over here is
this right here you have this big
malicious blob in here particularly
which corresponds to this which is I
mean there's DNS but then this is where
you see HTTP and TLS trial yes so so TLS
tell us and and focus on that remember
that TLS on these this rightness you
have this center blob the bottom is not
so interesting but the top you have the
right side that's the TLS so watch that
so now that we get the file type we
actually see that a lot of the file
types in that TLS section are actually
certificates and in and the rest is text
because I mean once it's encrypted it
just looks like binary ASCII text yes
and and then as for HTTP there's there's
really a lot of JavaScript binaries
JPEGs things like this which is exactly
what we'd expect and then how much so
what what's the session size
and we see this is this is kind of
interesting on the outside remember
there was a lot of DNS and we see that a
variety of DNS sizes in the malicious
but the interesting thing is that Green
appears to be more prevalent so there
there seems to be made too high in DNS
and then HTTP and these are all these
are all mostly zero because the size
didn't get it's not a well-defined
property in those sorts of cases based
on the definition of the feature we're
using here so if you remember what I was
what all I was going to show you there
was the document the transaction level
word embeddings the session level word
embeddings the document vector level
aggregation and now we're actually going
to start to look inside the model so
before before we actually go into the
model I want to talk a little bit about
machine learning theory so you
understand these visualizations first
there's this concept of a decision
boundary if you have two sets of points
for simplicity that you're trying to
differentiate between and you have the
feature space or two two or more
numerical ways of measuring the
differences between that space then what
a machine learning algorithm is actually
doing is it's it's doing some kind of
regression problem so it's it's learning
this boundary between these two classes
these salmon and sea bass along these
two different dimensions width and
lightness so for example right off the
bat you see that lighter fishes tend to
be the sea bass and the idea is that
when you have really good features the
decision boundary is going to be more
clear and another another thing is that
why is there so much hype about
all networks so the hyper about neural
networks is actually the neural networks
generate their own features in the sense
that the layer before the last layer is
creating features for the layer after it
right so the input to each layer is the
features that that layer is using and
then the output becomes the the input to
the next layer and so it's the features
that the next layer is using and then
the output of that layer becomes the
input to the next layer which are
essentially the features that it's using
so after each layer you're transforming
your feature space which gives you new
features that are hopefully more clear
or that hopefully provide a more clear
illustration and separation of the
different classes yes so this this is
what the first layer looks like and then
by the second layer we we see that it's
it's very well separated out yes and
this is the process of right so you go
from here to here this is the
transformation from one layer to the
next yes and just to illustrate how
useful the Search score wasn't this this
is the same recurrent neural network
train without the cert score so you see
that by the time you get to the second
layer there there still is quite a bit
of separation but was not the same type
of improve like this this looks this is
you can you could by hand just write out
the function that goes here as like a
piecewise linear function and then just
by looking at this you could get almost
great results yes so so great now that
we've looked inside the the neural
network understand how all the features
works what what is a concrete example of
how this classifier is actually run with
with an actual piece of data so I went
into some of the data that I was using
and picked out one one example here so
here here's an example where the
probability coming from the classifier
was that it was malicious is very high
and this is actually a known malicious
sample so it's fitting that it has a
very high probability
just because it is in fact malicious and
the search score is is also on the high
side for one of these sessions yeah for
it yeah looks like so yes so here for
the sequence we're taking the highest
the highest score for the certificates
for all the different certificates that
comprise the session and so here's here
you can see the this is the sequence of
sessions
it starts off if you want to well yeah
it starts off with a couple HTTP web web
pages one with Google api's then it goes
to vid seven comm and it it does a lot
of stuff in the US but it has one
session HTTP with Russia fast picked out
are you and there were some there were
some pornographic web pages in this data
it's sketchy stuff you know but at any
rate once it redirects to this XO click
site you end up with a very suspicious
certificate yes oh and actually I plug
and don't don't go to that website it's
you know Google search easy list cloud
then the first first result was how do I
get rid of easy list Club virus on my PC
or something like this so say yeah and
so each of these sessions gets
represented by a document vector and
these are actually where those document
vectors landed so you see there's one
that's smack dab in the middle of
that red zone right there some on the
periphery means I guess our DNS requests
and so here's here's where it landed in
the recurrent neural net in the first
layer it was in this red piece over here
and by the by the time it got to the
second layer it's it's well towards the
it's deep into the malicious tandoori
right now my problem this is a clear
example of malicious traffic so it's
fitting that it ends up very very far
from our sort of visual decision bank a
rule of thumb decision boundary here yes
so so let's sum up we've we've analyzed
sequences of network
traffic's network traffic and use word
embeddings to extract our features so to
turn the raw proxy logs into numeric
quantities then we've trained an ml
model to identify these malicious
sequences of sessions and we've
leveraged the cert classifier the
certificate classifier this knowledge of
this this may be a suspicious cert or
not and and finally the results are very
encouraging so some next steps would be
to investigate possibly mislabeled
training data so if you look back here
you can see that we have some of these
labeled benign samples that are
sometimes very far into the malicious
territory and so he we've started
investigating them some of them look a
little suspicious but we haven't
concluded that investigation yes but
certainly there are some suggestive
results that actually maybe are labeled
so right off the bat is that I don't
know you guys can see but there's a
little blue dot next to my star over
here
so there's actually one sample that I
can start by investigating that should
actually be very structurally similar to
this malicious sample that I just showed
you guys so that would be very
interesting to look at
and and yeah so this is all with I mean
we we got a small ish training data with
only a few hundred thousand examples so
we'd like to going forward maybe redo
this exercise with about 10 times or 20
times 50 times 100 times as much data
see how that affects the results I mean
already with the hundreds of thousands
you're probably in your statistical
limit there but you know it's good to
check and then you know once once we've
done all that then we want to put this
in our product so you know
production-wise a ssin so testing
validation integration with the
production code base etcetera etc you
know all the regular stuff and but an
important an important thing here is to
monitor performance set up
infrastructure if they're automatically
monitoring this yeah classifier and
doing periodic training it may be right
because I mean this is all based on the
the thing to know about these if you're
using machine learning and you have a
model that model is trained based on
that model is inferring is making
inferences based on the training data it
had and so you know as threats change as
there are new types of malicious
behavior new patterns of malicious
behavior that are invented the training
set we use has become is going to grow
increasingly obsolete over time and so
the goal is to eventually be in a place
where automatically every month or week
or several months or however long it
turns out to make sense to do part of
the performance monitor right based on
our performance monitoring we would then
want to just have it automatically
retraining or building a new model based
on that newer newer example data great
questions yes
monitoring in this context well I mean
sanity check is is one thing but here
we're talking more in terms of just in
general looking at so this would be in
the context of you know classify
malicious traffic so you know periodic
you know looking at a sample of the
predictions it's making and checking to
see what fraction of them are correct
based on other sources of labeling and
you know comparing the results of our
model to other sources of identification
of malicious traffic and you know doing
that doing that in an automated way so
you know we automatically run all this
traffic through various like you know
antivirus engines and our threat rules
and we have lots of other ways of
figuring out what's malicious and so you
know comparing the results of this to
that over time to make sure that as we
are sort of updating all these things in
tandem that they're sort of continue to
agree with each other going forward
[Music]
so the horsey ho
their classification this this month my
fail that chef in the tense
yeah yeah I mean that yeah right yeah
right yeah and it definitely that's one
of those things like even as we were
saying even in our smallish relatively
small training set we found some things
that look like they're suggestive
suggestive of mislabeling and so
definitely all of whatever
infrastructure we end up building out to
do that investigation more thoroughly is
certainly worth applying to just these
monitoring activities going forward yeah
yeah because I mean definitely the the
goal is that you have multiple different
sources of knowledge and you're
enriching each based on the other and
you're bootstrapping your way up to a
better understanding yeah any other yes
sir
starting this work like this our area
[Music]
yes so potentially explore different
more nuanced way of extracting features
so one one thing for example that's been
done before is waiting using tf-idf the
different vectors so what this would do
is this would emphasize more rare --is--
more significant kind of tokens and the
the weighted sum it would be a weighted
sum instead of an average to get these
document vectors and you would be
emphasizing the more unique yes yeah
[Music]
thank you any other questions yes mr.
Craig
you showed an example
yes yes yeah so I don't I don't know
that we have those numbers no no I don't
I don't have those numbers off the top
of my head but I definitely did look at
directly how the certificate score
correlated with malicious sessions and I
think the issue with that is that
sometimes not the the critical stuff
wasn't happening in the encrypted
sessions it could have the payload could
have been delivered in the clear and you
know just have gone to some refer refer
page over TLS so there there could be
many instances where the certificate
certificate score wouldn't come in handy
but it definitely is useful in the case
that there was is actually critical
stuff that is happening in in TLS yeah
so I like I said I don't remember off
the top of my head but my record
is that it wasn't enough to be
convincing on its own yeah and then
especially like I mean if you look at
our our example here you see that like I
mean some of these like this easy let's
not club which is I mean that that is
that itself is like the that he googled
and don't go there is the score is much
lower than this ad certificate and this
these EXO click certificates are much
more suspicious than the easiest Club
certificate even and so it I mean it's
it's a great feature to have but it's
not
we still gained a lot from knowing that
you had like a sequence of different
different events
right yeah yeah right exactly it's it's
it's the context when you have
everything in context you can see that
together it's very suggestive in a way
that by itself it might not be any other
questions it would it would absolutely
be possible so that that's actually a
important note that I want to are you
familiar with recurrent neural Nets so
so the idea is you have each recurrent
neural that is like I was saying it's a
sequence of feature vectors so one
option is to put the search score in
each of these feature vectors as an
additional component but what I've
decided to do instead is have at the
last layer of the neural network a
linear combination of the max search
score and whatever whatever the vector
coming out of the RN is and so then
there there becomes a weighting between
the maximum search score and whatever is
coming we essentially we have a
staggered input layer yes so so
basically if there's any other features
that we want to tack on like these float
base flow based statistics we could
absolutely do that easily and that would
be an interesting thing to you right
yeah is that it definitely having the
architecture as it is I mean the
recurrent piece picks up we have a
couple of recurrent layers but that's
not the only input so certainly we could
add other things
any any other questions okay well thank
you very much