besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success
dobri autre good morning how are you my
name is Dave Riley and I showed up early
so I could set up in case there were any
mishaps and there were so here we are
like I said my name is Dave Riley I'm
presenting on reverse engineering
vintage systems although I only cover a
sliver of everything that there is to be
covered so there's certainly further
reading to be had and lots to talk about
you're welcome to contact me at any of
those two locations if you want to talk
more so about me I'm a former ish
embedded engineer in in past lives I've
done a hardware software and FPGA work I
still do occasionally but right now I'm
an API programmer I'm also a computer
necromancer I work with a lot of
formerly dead computers and ones that
really just want to take a very long nap
and my preferred architectures generally
to work with I like vintage Mac's a lot
I grew up with them so I'm very fond of
them and they also have a very
interesting architecture I also work
with a lot of pdp-11 s and other Dex
stuff and 8-bit micros 6502 and 68 oh
and I are my favorites
so this presentation is going to be
biased a little bit toward those
categories but there's many others when
it comes to vintage machines definitely
not qualified to instruct on this stuff
who really is it's it's half archaeology
half embedded systems and then the third
half is magic I'm currently employed at
fireEye
but I submitted this talk before I was
hired there and I'm an API developer
there so if you don't like this
presentation do not blame my employer
that's all on me
but I hope you enjoy it anyway so what
kind of vintage computer are we talking
about how vintage specifically there's
religious wars on this subject what
qualifies as vintage when I really
got into the Hobby about ten years ago
the general gist was anything about 15
years old or sell and these days it's a
little bit harder to say there's you
know ten years later there's more
computers that you can consider vintage
and what really qualifies is again up in
the air most people don't really think
old pcs when they think vintage although
they can qualify and more and more
that's that's becoming a thing people
reviving das games and that sort of
thing certainly relevant for this topic
for security but I'll mostly be talking
about systems from the late 70s up
through the early to mid 90s and so that
covers things like late PDP sevens
because the earlier ones usually aren't
in in operation anymore
early 8-bit pcs Apple two Commodore 64
trash eighty all the way up through sort
of the peak zenith of the VAX alpha
spark mips NetWare time period also pre
imac max power pcs before the new world
that sort of thing one easy metric for
whether you could consider a computer
vintages is it old enough to vote that
probably fits unfortunately now that
includes computers made in 2000 and I
don't really want to accept that but
here we are and yes these machines are
absolutely still around they're even
around in places where you would really
care about them failing and if any of
you are ICS people probably about 80% of
this presentation is going to be pretty
familiar to you because almost all ICS
stuff involves a lot of vintage
machinery so agenda for this talk
why vintage systems going to talk about
why we care about them why we should
care about them even if we don't and why
you might want to where to start in
terms of finding out about them getting
into them that sort of thing how do we
break them so for the red team how do
you get into them how do you penetrate
them how do you convince people that
these things need to be fixed or
replaced how do I protect them so for
the blue team what do I do for a machine
that hasn't had an OS patch since 1998
is still controlling some important
giant piece of machinery and then for
the yellow team for lack of a better
term how when do I replace them that
that can be a deep topic it's not just
hey this thing is old it needs to be
replaced because oftentimes if it were
that easy it would already be done so
why do we care
computers are usually still in service
after 20 to 40 years for three main
reasons number one they're very
important maybe they're controlling
something big and dangerous like trains
or nuclear power plants
number two often they're very forgotten
someone has put a server in a closet
somewhere and it's lived there since
1984 and it's still you know delivering
the mail or news groups or whatever and
so as long as it's still running no one
no one bothers with it number three
somewhat important is lazy or cheap or
both because it's easier to replace to
not replace a computer than to replace
it until it breaks down and these really
are the ultimate unpatched systems and
in a lot of cases unpatch Abell unless
you're going to do the patch yourself
which sometimes you have to do in
something that's critical so just how
important are we talking critical
process control is a pretty typical area
you'll see older things again like I
said ICS big area for for vintage
machinery there's a lot of multi bus
systems and vme systems still running
machinery and trains and everything else
out there in fact I think the London
Underground still runs on multi bus or
at least a big part of it does and
there's lots more in industrial like
steel mills our nuclear launch system
still uses a old IBM system with eight
inch floppies which you know is sort of
good news because eight inch floppy
drives are easy to repair but the media
is not so you know not great the
benefits of the replacement may not be
worth the cost and the risk sometimes
just in the someone's opinion sometimes
it doesn't wash out so you know if
you're talking about something like a
giant steel mill if you replace it it's
going to cost a lot to do it right it's
going to cost you know man years it's
going to be mountains of documentation
but you know you also want to weigh that
against what happens if the old
machinery breaks down and we can't
replace it because these things haven't
been made since the 80s and you know
don't generally underestimate the value
to a business of something that's known
working there's the old if it ain't
broke don't fix it you know again with
critical things that's important because
the cost of failure is extremely high
also the original developers and
maintain errs are almost certainly long
gone on a lot of these things so the
ramifications of the replacement or
upgrade may not be particularly unclear
or it may not be particularly clear
because the people who wrote it and
maintained it before aren't around to
give advice so it's a good reason why
those are often not replaced as far as
being forgotten about everyone either
has or has seen server rooms that look
like this this looks actually a lot like
my basement even though it's not my
basement things get forgotten and buried
especially in let's say small to medium
sized businesses that have survived long
enough and these servers get set up they
get put up you know under someone's desk
that person leaves it becomes so the de
facto server corner and you know there's
credible stories of NetWare and VMs
servers being found behind drywall
because someone put a server into a
closet later the workers just patched up
over that closet the machine was still
running and nobody knew about it until
the mail stopped coming one day and I'm
like whoa what server handles that and I
had to trace cables back through drop
ceilings and eventually they found it
behind a wall these things happen
and of course those operating systems
have fantastically long up times so mmm
and of course if no one but facilities
management goes into the wiring closet
at your work you know how would you you
know the third generation employee at
this office necessarily know about the
old backs that's been running about
running the accounting system that
everyone has pretty much forgotten about
so finding those can be a bit of
sleuthing work and of course the third
reason laziness or incompetence
sometimes things don't get replaced for
really dumb reasons especially in
government because once you add
bureaucracy to things it just takes a
lot of time in
effort to to replace things because
everyone's afraid of getting fired no
one wants to lose a government job
because they well they'll always pay
well but they're they're at least pretty
static you know for example the
Department of Defense will still pay big
dollars for a particular micro VAX model
or vac station because it's on the
checklist for a mission-critical app and
so on eBay you know all the other
members of that family are going for a
hundred bucks and this one goes for
three thousand because the DoD will
still pay that for it and no one wants
to get fired for purchasing the wrong
thing or moving it to some emulation
solution which will probably work but
might not and then of course sometimes
management just won't replace a system
that's still working usually because
technical debt is really poorly
understood effect in a lot of circles
you know the the understanding that it
takes twice as much effort to replace
something farther down the line is a
little bit alien to folks and it's
difficult to explain that's why these
things stick around and the places
you'll find them so where do we start
well if you want to start finding them
again safety critical systems power
plants heavy industry lots of ICS stuff
trains anything nuclear basically
anywhere you see computers controlling
really big expensive machinery it's
likely also long-lived inexpensive
systems that have custom interfaces so a
lot of hospitals you know are famously
still running like Windows 3.1 for
running their MRI machines a lot of
electron microscopes have interfaces
that were only available for old Max or
pdp-11 or whatever and they still work
and unless you're going to build your
own interface you're not going to be
able to use your electron microscope so
unless you're in the mood to buy a new
one you keep things running lots of
other big lab systems lab equipment is
notorious for just kind of having hacked
together interfaces to computers that
may not be replaced very often less
often you'll see them in everyday use so
old servers that never migrated like you
know your old mail or news group server
that's still been chugging along until
one day it doesn't
everyone's gone to an autoparts store
and you see them still clunking around
on a VT 222 check out your brake pads or
whatever they're still running an
ancient POS system that works absolutely
well enough for them so there's not much
reason for them to change at least as
far as management's concerned old
computer labs also you know universities
frequently just don't clear out the room
until they actually need the rooms so my
my alma mater actually advertised that
it was still running onix's SGI onyx is
up until about two or three years ago
when they revised the course catalog
although I'm not sure they still were so
often these things are physically
obscured so like an old computer lab no
one uses or a wiring closet or something
that gets patched over they get
forgotten because the people who
maintain them leave and no one's
cataloging them anymore so it's chalk
another one up for asset inventories
very important before you get into
things always be cognizant of legal
things so there's the standard potential
legal disclaimers even vintage software
mace may still have licenses that are
still in effect for bidding reverse
engineering that may or may not matter
depending on what you're trying to do
with it it has the same legal hazards as
reverse engineering modern software and
hardware because people do get sued for
that but it may be hard to find out who
actually owns the IP now some of these
companies have been bought and sold
three times and you'll find that the
company that that actually owns it now
says well we don't have any record of
that but we will still sue you if you
try to take it apart and you know so
some companies especially defunct ones
because they can't won't sue you if if
you're not harming their commercial
interest but of course some do anyway
because they're jerks and some also have
a funny idea of what might harm their
commercial interests sometimes they're
also right but a lot of times it's the
lawyers told us to do it there's also
physical risks of course and again we're
talking about things controlling large
industrial systems be careful when
poking at things that you might break
because you know you don't want to be
destroying a ten million dollar piece of
machinery because you brought something
down to the ports can older HOF Hardware
often didn't have as many safeguards on
it so you could configure things in ways
that could actually damage the hardware
that's true of new hardware - but it's
less common and of course it's just old
I mean you know old hard drive platters
are just spinning rust
they've been spinning for forty years
maybe sometimes they just stop working
and if you're really exercising them
they may stop working quicker so with
that said how do we break them how do we
get into them this is this is actually
the most reverse engineering part of
this talk but we'll we'll get to it so
what are we trying to do with these old
systems if why would you need to know
this as a red team member let's say
standard red team's stuff you want to
get into a system you want to gain
access you want to dump critical data
you want to see if you could potentially
break it and cause a lot of financial
damage and so you'll want to try
networks a lot of these things are
networked some of them art many of them
aren't some of them were pretty standard
networking so there's lots of different
interesting Network protocols that don't
really exist anymore they may be
physically isolated and that can still
be important you know again if we're
talking about things like ICS having
physical accesses sometimes just
something you have to assume an attacker
has had and you want to be able to make
sure they're at least not easily able to
get in and break things you might want
to manipulate data if it's an accounting
system you might want to be able to pay
someone extra something like that or do
s important things anything that you
would want to do with the modern system
it's pretty likely that you would want
to do with a vintage system except maybe
distribute malware over the web that's
probably not going to happen
short of that you know nothing changes
under the Sun how do we get in so we
talked about networks physical access RC
ease abound there's lots of them because
you know while a lot of these things
went under code review a lot of them
didn't and the you know
hacking community was not as distributed
back in the day there are a lot of
things that were never found
privilege escalation on multi-user
systems can be a big one so for example
in VMs now called open VMs just in 2017
there was a privileged escalation the
system found that went all the way back
to VAX VMS 4 which was released in 1984
so that's a 33 year latent bug in a
safety and security critical system that
the Department of Defense and Guinness
and other people use still so there's
there are still lots of things to be
found and lots of things that were never
found
that you know you can drop a zero-day on
a 33 year old system if you want
there are Hardware firmware bugs so
we're we're coming back again full
circle to this now where we're finding
out things like our network cards are
actually just tiny computers that can
also be hijacked well this was also true
in the 80s for a different reason well
the same and different reason the the
host computers weren't as powerful the
buses weren't very fast so for example a
pdp-11 Ethernet card is a 68,000
computer that does the job of sending
and receiving the data over Ethernet and
then one that's got a bunch of stuff it
dnase it into the hosts memory you can
exploit that if you find a bug in that
68,000 computer's program and overwrite
it so and nothing nothing really changes
but these these things are out there and
the nice thing is those are a little bit
easier to disassemble than some custom
weird microcontroller from Intel also
lack of good access control and
certainly especially if we go back to
the 80s especially if we go back to
early micros there may not have been any
access control so if you have physical
access game's over you can pretty much
control it other ones especially early
ones were very limited like very limited
password length RS X 11 M on the PDP 11
I think it's an eight character password
max a hint I'm not even sure the
case-sensitive because the entire OS is
in case sensitive
lots of old backdoors left around lots
of default configs certainly a lot of
earlier versions of VMs had default
passwords for field service which was
basically a system
config' so and there's hardware debug
options so a lot of them made it really
easy to get any debug the hardware
because if you were assembling a
computer like this you probably needed
to do some of that so those things are
still left open it's just like leaving
an open and unprotected jtag port on a
modern router something like that
a lot of ways to get into the older
systems also there's not much encryption
the older Hardware just didn't really
have the horsepower to encrypt much and
do anything else at the same time you
could you can do a YES on an Apple 2 if
you want you just need to come back to
it next Tuesday
most networking also assumed fairly
benign host networks obviously not all
of it but if it was built at a time you
know let's say it was in a university AI
lab and it was only ever gonna be AI
students accessing it they may not have
really ever expected much to happen to
it but the things change the again ICS
has the same problem you know that's why
they keep those networks separate at TLS
also was not a standard till the 90s
when it was invented by Netscape so
everything earlier is custom and a lot
of places just either didn't do it or if
they did do their own custom crypto it
had the usual effects you would expect
from custom hand-rolled crypto from
people who didn't know what they were
doing
so encryption is usually not something
you have to worry about overly much
there's also of course weird networking
protocols and hardware that you may not
have heard of before that you may have
hard times getting equipment for unusual
hardware like arc net token ring isn't
that unusual because I think IBM still
uses it but it can be harder to get on a
newer machine local talk for for older
Mac's Dec DD CMP which is just serial
SDLC x.25 that's just a tiny sliver of
the things that might be out there you
may find yourself needing to cobble
things together fortunately that's
actually easier now than it used to be
because it's easy to get things like
FPGA evaluation boards that you can do
with that or beaglebones that sort of
thing there's also lots of protocols and
Linux actually still supports a lot of
the older ones which is nice and TCP
dump understands even more of them so
appletalk decnet and related
px' those are still supported by Linux
they're still supported by some of the
BSD s
and you can still listen to them with
TCP dump or Wireshark that sort of thing
there are quite a lot especially if you
get into the IBM world that are a little
unusual but IBM actually keeps them
maintained so you will if you're trying
to go into a vintage network you may
have to do some deep digging on a lot of
these protocols to figure out how to
actually talk them so without all all
said what's already available for
vintage research and reversing so the
nice thing is the vintage computers and
systems are often really well-documented
compared to the modern systems so if you
go and look up manuals on PDP 11
processors they will tell you exactly
how every block of it works and part of
that was because every block of it was
on a separate you know card about this
big that you put into a rack for the
early ones so if you had a broken one
you needed to know how to fix it but
'men sever ething down to a bit level
and there are a number of archiving
organizations that are dedicated to
preserving all this history so bit
savers is a big one archive.org also
serves up bit savers information but
does its own archiving as well so a lot
of service and operation manuals for
these older machines are still around
and available if you look for them
unless they were incredibly proprietary
and even then sometimes they are because
people just had them lying around in a
binder that they took home from work one
day sometimes even schematics and
diagnostic guides especially if you get
into service manuals and if you're lucky
things like theory of operation guides
and assembly listings so how this really
works with comments which if you're
trying to find a hole in something can
be a Holy Grail because oh you didn't
check the bounds on that great
unfortunately of course it was a long
time ago and it was a time that not
everyone was really concerned about
preserving history so a lot of documents
were lost to accidents or careless
storage HP just lost a huge trove of
documents that were waiting to be
scanned because of a warehouse fire I
think also lawyers again
a lot of lawyers don't want things
getting out if they don't have a reason
to be out and we'll just forbid it and
then the documentation disappears which
is a shame but usually there's something
available so if you're trying to get in
do your homework up front do a thorough
search to see if the thing you're trying
to find is documented somewhere I talked
about archive.org and bit savers a lot
of that stuff is ocr'd so if you do
searches for things that you're looking
for it'll pop up on Google a lot of the
time because it's ocr'd actually well
enough for Google to understand it which
is good and you can find it there's no
need to rediscover the wheel if it's
already documented unless you really
want to if you really want to find out
how these things work the best way is to
dive right in if you're just trying to
do your job it's not going to be the
fastest way and it might not be the most
effective way someone else also might
have solved your problem so you don't
need to write a custom appletalk
listener because tcp dump still
understands it
someone might already have written a
program to route decnet over the
internet in fact they have it's called
heck net and you can use that to your
advantage if you need to break into
things remotely there's lots of old
tricks still out there Usenet archives
are full of them because that was what
people communicated on before the
mailing lists and that lasts forever
there's also now modern vintage computer
group forums and mailing lists which if
you're interested in this I highly
suggest you join because you can ask
questions of the people who actually use
it at a time or the people who've been
researching it in the mean time and have
learned all the fun tricks you know
worst case buy an old sysadmin who knows
a thing or two about what you're looking
for a beer and ask about their tricks
and they will probably still remember it
unless you've had too many beers
so for example talk about do your
homework up front part of what you want
to do is get familiar with what you're
looking at so this is a scan of not
actually mine but the same model of my
pdp-11 scuzzy card
it's a scuzzy card but it's also an 8086
computer that runs a specially formatted
dos executable I found all this out
because my scuzzy card broke because of
a dumb thing I did and I needed to fix
it and it turned out to be a bug in the
firmware but taking just a look at the
card if you're familiar with the older
computers you can already see a couple
things like you have what's clearly
under these stickers a CPU and a pair of
eeproms which means it's a 16-bit
computer and if you look at a couple of
the surrounding chips which you
certainly cannot see from the back you
can see things that only ever existed on
Intel 8086
unless someone was crazy so that was
enough of an you know an intro to say
well I can just pull those eeproms and
dump them and I can probably disassemble
them with any standard dos disassembler
and figure out what's going on and I
could and it did and it worked but you
might not be able to spot it that quick
if you hadn't already been looking at a
lot of older computers so getting to
know the context in which you're going
to be operating can be incredibly
valuable if for no other reason then you
can just say hey I've seen that so other
things that might help lots of old
systems were reconfigured by building
from source so you know I'll actually
still BSD UNIX like net BSD OpenBSD
FreeBSD you can still install and
uninstall drivers by rebuilding from
source Linux is similar the whole system
comes with commented C code even
commercial systems like VMS and RS x11 M
they they reconfigured by rebuilding
themselves and they basically came with
stripped and obfuscated assembly code or
other code for for rebuilding when you
changed your configuration that's a
little bit easier to reverse engineer
from then trying to take a memory dump
and and move outward from there of
course anything based on UNIX really set
the bar high on that because the whole
operating system came with its or
code obviously the proprietary unix's
were slightly different but still
compilers and CPUs also we're
comparatively simple back then so
there's not a lot of optimization in
anything that's compiled so you're not
going to have to be you know trying to
wrap your head around stupid compiler
tricks like you know declaring two
variables in a single register that sort
of thing because the CPUs didn't have
multiple execution units for the most
part pipelines were non-existent all and
optimizer did was get rid of you know
garbage collected references things like
that and so the code is usually very
easy to follow unless it's intentionally
obfuscated especially handwritten
assembly because it was written by a
human who needed to read it again and
often the OS facilities were written
with assembly programming ease of use in
mind because they assumed everyone would
be writing the programs and assembly so
the way you interacted with it was based
on that rather than a bunch of C
function calls so it can make it a lot
easier to read what's actually going on
there more things that might help the
hardware is generally a lot easier to
physically probe if you need to then
then modern hardware if you need a
dumper ROM you don't have to desolder a
BGA package you can just pop it out of a
socket a lot of the time or if it's
soldered on it's easier to desolder
number one but there's also clips that
might work that that could override the
signals while it's powered on and read
it out dip packages are really easy to
clip scope and logic analyzer probes on
too much more than than surface mount
packages
there's also custom clips that exist for
popular families like 68 oh 30 in QFP
package you can get a clip that just
sits right on that chip and you can plug
it right into an logic analyzer and see
what's going on on the bus and then also
the buses are usually narrow and slow
enough to attach logic analyzers to so
you get an HP 16700 family logic
analyzer which you can get on eBay
although the shipping is going to be a
lot because they're heavy they're
amazing and you can bypass the license
manager on it to get the licenses for
the inverse assemblers which will
basically disassemble what's going
across those buses live so if if your
of options and you just really need to
see what the processors are doing right
now it's a great option the code sizes
are also often very small so for example
the pdp-11 s they only add a 16-bit
virtual address space and same with
8-bit micros
UNIX on PDP 11 for the earlier machines
which didn't have split instruction and
data space those you know UNIX programs
could only be 64 K in instruction and
data doesn't leave a lot of room but it
also means if you're trying to
disassemble it you're not going to have
to go too far for more advanced
operating systems for systems of that
area like RS x11 M there were complex
overlay mechanisms that can make it
harder to read but it's comparatively
rare things to watch out for
so even ancient code from the 80s still
employed anti reverse engineering
techniques because reverse engineering
was still going on certainly there was a
lot of espionage back then I know
digital put some fun things in the in
the die for some of their chips so that
they could see if they were being copied
by the Soviets and they were I think one
of the VAX dyes had when you care enough
to steal the absolute best and it popped
up in the Soviet clones so and sometimes
there's clever techniques that that make
reverse engineering harder to so
unconventional branching methods like
branching to the indirect target of some
register can make it hard for
disassembler to follow the flow
especially if it's an older disassembler
meant for that particular target
branching into the middle of existing
instructions sometimes that's for
obfuscation sometimes it's just because
you needed to cram something into a very
tiny space and that was your only option
one of the boot roms for for pdp-11 does
that because it only had I think 128
words of space for a very long boot
process and it actually branches into
the middle of an instruction because it
was able to reuse that particular value
as another instruction that's very hard
to disassemble self-modifying code was
actually fairly popular back then
because number one it didn't break any
kind of emulation or JIT compilers so no
one really cared but
number two you could do some things to
save a few cycles or some space or
confuse your competitors when they were
trying to disassemble it and so unless
you have some really fancy plugin for
Ida or something those are hard to do
disassemble automatically packing into
data sections same thing malware another
pack word packers do now done a lot for
compression two virtual machines and
bytecode interpretation that's also used
for compression the Apple two at one
point had a 16-bit virtual machine
interpreter in there that was incredibly
slow but also was incredibly compact
code and so you could use that but
you'll see that in older code a lot I
think actually all the original
Microsoft Office programs for the
Macintosh ran on a virtual machine as
well and of course you'll see encrypted
and encoded in compressed strings just
like you do now so as far as how you get
in there are standard system tools so a
lot of vintage machines have built in
debug mode Zoar monitors hit a key
combination or send a serial break
condition or something like that and
you'll pop into the monitor so on spark
machines there's open prom which is the
same as open firmware on the Macintosh
on newer pdp-11 there's ODT which is
basically just a serial version of the
front panel console switches you can
just go directly into memory and do
whatever you want there VAX alpha system
console was basically the next iteration
on that you can get full access to
everything if you have physical access
to the machine and in some cases like I
said just a serial break sequence will
dump you into those things sometimes
especially if that was never turned off
by the person who is setting up the
system and since lots of vintage systems
were written in assembler there are
extensive machine code level debugging
solutions in a lot of the operating
systems meant to run on these things
because that was the only way to debug
them there weren't a lot of source level
disassemblers back then and often they
were very expensive and didn't come with
the system for offline work of course
there are lots of reversing tools some
of them you probably know pretty well
some of them you probably don't
there are a lot of interactive
disassemblers there are more these days
than ever because people keep writing
new ones which is nice because it means
Ida keeps getting cheaper but they all
have benefits and drawbacks over each
other especially when it comes to weird
CPUs and vintage ones so I know of
course is the big one it has a very long
history in reverse engineering and as a
result it also has a huge selection of
CPUs and binary formats so it includes
things like pdp-11 alpha 6502 especially
if you have the pro version lots more
doesn't have VAX for some reason but but
it chances are 80 90 percent of the time
you'll be able to find whatever target
you're trying to disassembler a
disassemble in Ida the only problem is
of course it's expensive if you're
working for a company and you're part of
the red team that may not be a big deal
but if you're an independent consultant
or a hobbyist it's maybe not so great
and they have a free tier but it's x86
only so radar - which I never know how
to pronounce properly newer open-source
disassembler it is free it's not bad
it's not spectacular a lot of times
especially for non x86 architectures
it's not bad for arm I found it pretty
much unworkable in its current state for
PowerPC but your mileage may vary it
doesn't have as many CPUs supported as
Ida but part of that's just it's newer
and people are writing new ones all the
time you can always write your own just
like you can for Ida and everything else
so if if you have the time to devote to
it you can always write a module and
that may make your job easier and of
course again it's free and it is
improving rapidly it is getting better
at a very nice pace if you're looking
specifically for classic max stuff this
is the definitive solution it runs on
the classic Mac Steve jazz expose II
which is the disassembler and the
debugger which is the system level
debugger it it gives you the the
capabilities to go a lot deeper than
Apple's development tools go and it is
an interactive debugger very much in the
vein of IDA it works very well
it
has a very funky interface because he
pretty much just wrote it however he
wanted not keeping to the interface
guidelines from Apple but it is the way
to go if you're trying to get classic
Mac stuff or really even any 68k stuff
done because it does such a good job
with it and it does things with classic
Mac idiosyncrasy idiosyncrasies like
resource forks that Ida really can't
handle and radar and everything else
doesn't work under the classic
environment in OS 10 the debugger
doesn't anyway Mac nosey does but it
will work under emulators like sheep
shaver other PowerPC emulators so if you
find yourself needing to disassemble any
of these for whatever reason they're
excellent tools and if you need a real
machine find a vintage computer group
you will get more than you want binary
ninja it's a new kid on the block pretty
good actually it's commercial it does a
neat thing where it basically lifts
things to a higher level intermediate
language so you can examine the higher
level program flow better which is nice
and it's also fairly extensible it's
cheaper than Ida Pro and actually it's
more expensive than this now I think oh
maybe it's not maybe maybe that's
actually still correct but that is still
cheaper than Ida for either version it's
very scriptable it's a lot more friendly
to modern you eyes if that's your thing
it doesn't have nearly as many
processors and binary formats supported
but it does support a lot of things that
you'd need to see in a typical I see
yeah yeah ICS environment like arm
PowerPC that sort of thing and again you
can always write more and there are
community developed plugins that have
more support as well it does support
6502 which is nice hopper is a new one
it's Mac and Linux specific I haven't
used it but people really seem to like
it supports the things that that I would
want to see in sort of a basic
disassembler especially for for ICS
stuff it's not a great candidate for
vintage stuff but and again there are
plugins for things like 6502 and TI DSPs
and that sort of thing and it is
actually a lot cheaper
binary em is another one I haven't even
looked at yet but it looks like it has a
very similar feature set that you might
like so that's about it for getting in
and I promise the rest of these slides
that go quickly there will be a little
bit of a question time before we're
actually it's time to get out so we're
going to talk about how we protect them
so now this actually this slide is out
of order
this was supposed to be in the red teen
side so how do I protect or protect
against these systems number one of
course replace them or upgrade where
it's possible we've already gone over
the reasons why that doesn't happen
there are lots of good reasons lots of
bad reasons for that but when you can
and wear it where it's feasible replace
them if you can't isolate them as much
as possible
you know these systems you should treat
them as fundamentally unpatch Abul so
the trick is to put as many things in
the way of them being exploited as you
possibly can
so sandboxing is an obvious one there is
no reason you should be running you know
a vintage Mac or something on Windows
3.1 on the same network as your
production servers don't do it and you
know you may have to do things to route
those protocols over whatever your
gateway is but it will be worth it from
a safety standpoint you know decnet
doesn't route over modern IPs but Cisco
routers often have ways still of routing
that so place gateways firewalls what
have you in the way of these things so
that people can't just get full access
to them also audit them you need to have
a good inventory as with everything in
security know what your computers are
know where they connect you don't want
someone saying oh yeah that Ethernet
cable that just threads directly through
the drywall there no one really knows
where that goes it know where it all
goes and you know listen make sure that
you have some sort of monitoring
solution that is actually monitoring for
non IP networking protocols you should
be doing this anyway because in in an IP
only network if someone starts doing
that it's a sign that they're probably
up to no good but definitely if you have
any machines you need to be listening
for them and logging and know
what to look for and yeah what if it
just won't die if if it's
mission-critical and irreplaceable try
to find a way to replace it again you
can accomplish a lot with sandboxing you
might have to do custom code to route
stuff and firewall it and all that you
may even need unusual hardware like
cisco routers again can still route some
of those old protocols you may need to
get an older router and older interface
cards for them but it can work you
should hire the cranky old people who
have big opinions and pay them well
enough that they will stay because they
will actually know the pitfalls that you
should be looking for on these networks
better than you know someone just out of
college who wasn't born when the
computer was built which doesn't mean
they can't know it it's a likelihood
thing and again make sure you have
visibility you may have to write your
own logging and monitoring code using
you know BPF and and other things to
find custom or unusual protocols and
make sure that your seam knows what to
look for what to flag and that your your
sock also knows what to be looking for
coming from the seam you don't want lots
of false alarms but you also don't want
total ignorance so the last part how and
when do I replace them so how to replace
these things you need to fully examine
the cost and risks of replacement so
obvious again for big ones like ICS if
you're talking about replacing something
that controls a steel mill that could
kill people if it goes wrong that's a
big cost and you need to absolutely make
sure that the thing that you're
replacing works correctly before you do
it which means a lot of time a lot of
documentation and a lot of research some
of the subtle things can be easy to miss
you know what if there's this really
subtle race condition that causes some
terrible cascading chain that ends up
blowing something up it happens do you
really remember everything that this was
connected to is there some modem Bank
running somewhere that some system
maintenance thing out in Peoria needs to
connect to or it's going to you know
stop billing your important customers
and don't forget OSI layer eight which
is politics there's always going to be
someone attached to the existing system
and there's always gonna be someone who
wants to get rid of it so figure out how
to
correctly leverage those things and
satisfy those players and you'll get a
lot farther than just fighting make
backup plans for if something doesn't
work like you expected these
replacements aren't easy things break
and consider partial solutions emulation
is very popular a lot of nuclear power
plants are still running on pdp-11 code
but not physical pdp-11 machines because
they're not very maintainable emulation
works well I think parts of our traffic
control system work on emulated HP minis
as well
and a lot of them can even interface
with old hardware be very wary of
off-the-shelf silver-bullet something it
says oh you got an old backs put this
box in your network and it'll replace it
sometimes they work a lot of times
they're snake-oil so you have to be
super careful about what you trust with
those things when do you replace these
things well if they're well-maintained
they should evolve naturally because you
should be replacing things when there
are a couple years old and starting to
get a o L rather than 20 years old and
oh my god we have no idea how to replace
it which happens a lot addressing
long-held technical debt is always a
difficult sell to management because it
costs more the longer you wait and
they're even less likely to want to do
it the if it ain't broke mentality is
pervasive but it doesn't consider
whether it's going to be a catastrophe
if it does break like you know a bridge
the bridge breaks it's bad news and you
should have fixed it beforehand you it
can help to account for the long term
financial benefits of upgrading and
replacing compared to the cost so like
lower power consumption longer uptime
lower breach risk lower risk of
catastrophic failure etc if the system
is officially EOL you should be trying
to find a good replacement you shouldn't
be trying to hang on to it unless you
have an extremely good reason that
concludes my talk we have like three
minutes for for questions if anyone has
any but if you want to contact me
there's the info if you want to learn
more about vintage computers there's
some resources to connect to I've seen
at least one VCF member already here so
questions yes speak loudly
I know many III have a long time ago I
meant know many people who do you mean
the tablet right yeah yeah we have VCF
members who actually have whole
collections good machines you almost
certainly it's not in my domain but I'm
sure you could get easy pointers on any
of these lists for it though
other questions so 3b one yep it never
goes away I didn't even touch IBM
mainframes which are still running code
from the 60s in some cases but iBM has
made a significant investment in making
sure that stuff still works right so yes
any other questions nope
thank you for coming to my talk I
appreciate it