besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success
hello everybody I'm Wally Prather my
talk today is the unforeseen
consequences of data hacking and
breaching I am the senior intelligence
analyst for McAfee x' advanced programs
group were a cell that's dedicated to
providing intelligence products instead
of reversing malware the same-old
same-old we actually have intelligence
professionals on the entire team and we
take data and we turn it into something
that you're probably not used to what
we're going to talk about today we're
gonna break break this down into three
different sections first a methodology
how we do things how we look at
intelligence our cycles of intelligence
we're also gonna use show you our case
study which is a look that people don't
usually take when you get hacked what
actually happens is particularly with
foreign intelligence services and then
our final part of this talk is basically
how we take all these intelligence
methodologies from Special Forces from
the Marine Corps from clandestine
services and how do we apply that to
cyber security so as a disclaimer with
like especially the dnc hack and the
Clinton emails and the Podesta emails
there's a lot of personnel information
we've redacted everything in here so
there's actually all the phone numbers
or 867-5309 and all the way down so we
took out actual individuals personal
data because that wouldn't be proper to
throw people under the bus I didn't
that being said second point is none of
the none of the data in here is meant to
be political at all and so think of it
this way you know political hacking is
nothing new but the largest hack that
ever happened was the DNC hack during
the 60s the Russians had multiple
campaigns against the Kennedy
administration when Kennedy was running
for office they set up NGOs they had
propaganda nowadays the propaganda is
digital instead of physical
so we're going to talk about data some
of the doctrine what do what do foreign
intelligence analysts look for what
makes you a target in a good target for
them some network analysis we're going
to talk about vulnerabilities and
specifically if they can't find a
vulnerability on you how do they create
a vulnerability and then also the human
toll and some other applications for the
methodology so what if foreign
governments look for it's called human
intelligence it's one of the oldest
professions in the world if you have
ever read about American history you'll
know that George Washington spoke very
highly of his spies it was most of the
intelligence back then obviously was
human intelligence so what is foreign
intelligence services look for they look
for adversary intelligence people they
look for heads of state heads of
municipalities teachers university
professors they look for tribal leaders
they don't just look for everybody on
the top they also look for the middlemen
guys and also people at the bottom of
the food chain per se they need people
who can plug thumb drives nowadays into
servers they need people who can pick up
trash from companies organizations
once they find people who they think
could be a plausible target or somebody
who might commit espionage against their
country they look into three key factors
PAA placement access and accessibility
that's that individuals placement access
and accessibility to that data set or to
that issue or to that human so with that
being said what I usually ask the crowd
is if you were looking into the Iranian
nuclear program who do you think would
have the best placement access and
accessibility to that information any
guesses throw out a name anybody how
about Mahmoud Ahmadinejad so obviously
Mahmoud Ahmadinejad would have placement
access accessibility to literally
anything you wanted to know about that
program he helped modernize it and start
it up
but there's other factors involved so
what's his level of cooperation going to
be do you think that he's going to
cooperate with the Americans probably
not you know is he does he have a
vulnerability that we can exploit not
likely and would even if he did give us
information would it be reliable no if
the information you want is already at
the top probably the place to start to
go get it is not the top so what we did
was there every intelligence agency in
the world has an intelligence cycle when
I came on board with McAfee what we what
we knew we had to do immediately was
start a cycle and a methodology taking
our many many combined years of
deployments and intelligence community
experience and put that on papers so for
us every in every agency shines in
different places for us it's collection
and utilization utilization we'll talk
about in a little bit but collection we
have an incredible ability to do what we
call persistent stare once we start
looking at something at my section we
never stop looking at it we know that
sometimes the threats wait 18 months and
they reuse information later and they
will use the domain for one attack then
they let it sit on the shelf for two
years then they'll pick that back up and
use it again so when that happens if
you're always looking and you're always
able to collect you're able to
capitalize on mistakes
in addition to that it's important from
an intelligence perspective to have a
covert communications network we have a
very advanced one where we have you know
we're across the dark web or across the
normal web and we have personas to boot
for every operation that we do with
utilization that'll come a parent here
in the next couple slides but every time
we build a network for anything we keep
that Network and then we're able to see
the evolution of malware the viruses
ransomware any type of remote access
tool kit and we're able to compare that
to other samples worldwide so with our
methodology on the left is this special
operations methodology in Vietnam when
you see things in the news especially
during the Vietnam era as large-scale
raids it was bringing people to the
table to have discussions the Green
Berets knew that that's not where you
attack that everything that is allowing
that to happen
is under the surface of the iceberg so
for us it's the same we know that
there's a shared common infrastructure
when you see the news you see the large
scale ransomware attacks you see the
hospitals getting shut down
you see people hacking you know
children's oncology departments in Ohio
you see the Netflix hack but what we
understand is that's that is the
endpoint that is the what everybody
looks at the bright shiny object under
the surface there are a lot of things
that allow those attacks to take place
specifically things like shared common
infrastructure of EPs networks
bulletproof servers that's where we
intend to exploit fully
and so throughout this talk I'm going to
talk about you're gonna hear the term
merging quite a bit and so I wanted to
explain that to you what that actually
looks like this is adwin remote access
tool kit on the top left is the IP
addresses on the top right is the
domains so when I say merging it's
taking two or multiple pieces of data
putting them together and then at the
bottom that's what that network looks
like so we're gonna get into the to the
dnc hacks the dnc hack and the data that
was pulled from there also the Clinton
emails and the Podesta emails so like
any organization they had personnel data
and it looks like a lot of different
forms you know they also obviously had
financial data this is Hillary Clinton's
Travel traveled by plane in the dollar
amounts and the time when she traveled
and this data I mean I have tons of
slides on this it's everything that you
would have at your corporation or your
place of work who works there first of
all obviously as a corporation you know
that obviously if you have a financial
department HR all that data is kept and
stored if you know what you're doing
it's a goldmine
especially for a foreign intelligence
service and so what if where would a
Foreign Intelligence Service start so I
started where when I used to do that for
a living where would I start I look at
the personnel within the organization so
let's say I'm Russia and my goal is to
infiltrate the DNC where would you start
you have to know who works for it so
this is a simple macro to micro of what
that looks like so for this slide its
constituent services who's in could
stick you in services what's their phone
numbers what's their emails real simple
here's another example party Affairs
what is the what is the DNC going to do
next what is their future planning
the Democratic policy committee if you
wanted to know what their policies are
going to be in the future and this is
just phase one this is just taking the
data they have and not enriching it at
this point just taking a look to maybe
start start planning on a targeted F or
elsewhere with our methodology once you
have data you're able to look at things
by location so for this example of New
York let's say the example from an
intelligence perspective would be you're
a Russian case officer and you're
talking to your assets and you would say
hey listen what's it like working in DC
and the agents come back to you and they
say well it's not a good place to work
second we leave the embassy or our safe
house we're follow the 100 percent time
real-time and we can't get anything done
well house New York well New York we can
work there so with the methodology you
take all these location data and like
all your donor data and so what we see
as analysts is like in New York will see
a skyscraper of residential apartment
complex and we see hey okay well the
32nd floor you know 60% of the people
donated to the DNC or at least submitted
on some level for more information or a
flyer or sticker what you can do then is
you can start changing ideology through
propaganda so you know that that floor
60% 80% of the people on that floor in
that building for say subscribe to this
ideology you can start swinging that
ideology if you already know where the
bases
credit cards so financially it was when
I got ahold of this data I was shocked
so if you have your company and you have
company credit cards please don't put
all the cards on one excel spreadsheet
and then the people who own them and
then a picture of the front in the back
and all the information and then the
card owner's personal identification
number all the pedigree information
including mother's maiden name
don't put that all in the same excel and
don't please password protect it if you
do so when I got that I was like oh my
goodness it's like oh now I got humid
Dean's credit card and her personal
cellphone so you know with just that
amount of data I mean even if if you're
a foreign intelligence service you don't
care about the credit cards but what you
can do with that is you can start a
harassment campaign you can keep that
ongoing and ongoing and ongoing once you
raise the stress people start making
mistakes if you have an organization and
it's probably not a good idea to make a
list of your friends and a list of your
enemies because that can be used against
you phishing campaigns for say will
cover that more in just a little bit
amongst the emails and amongst the DNC
data we found basically all huge
thousand personal list of friends and
thousand person list of enemies or do
not contact this person underneath any
circumstances preferred press lists etc
with this list also that was included he
will cover that a little bit in just
another slide is this person donated a
lot so they have preferential treatment
at this dinner or this meeting or this
event so donor specific money works the
same way as personnel networks so what
we did was we took all the DNC donor
information took it by it basically the
individual Excel spreadsheet are the
text documents and we took all that data
and we merged together and you see here
quite a large volume of data so what do
you do with that why is that important I
mentioned phishing campaign so let's say
you want to start targeting people why
not go after the five to ten million
dollar donors that would be great they
obviously have money to donate five to
ten million so good chance that in some
way you can start rolling what I would
do
but my legal department shut me down was
I was planning on going in and emailing
all these people about 1.25 million and
I was gonna offer him free 18 months
credit monitoring because the heck gonna
spoof the email and then once they click
on the button just it goes to website
shows us a clicker
but our legal department said absolutely
not no way so here's another example
this is the 10 to 25 million and you can
segregate this type of data any way you
want and then you can focus targeting on
that because this is just a this has
been dubbed down there's more
information behind all this data the
addresses the account numbers in a lot
of cases the credit card information or
the checking information but the banking
information is already there also all
their personal information and so we
what we did was we had names to money
and we have people to places and then we
merge those together and right now
you're already looking at about a
million individual entities on the
screen and this is a micro view you can
take the micro into macro so the Clinton
emails so I have a security clearance I
couldn't go into the emails but what I
did was we figured out we had them all
on a zip file and we gave each email an
individual unique identifier and then we
had sender and receiver and the program
we're using by the way to do all this is
called analyst notebook it's owned by
IBM I too and so we have a color okay I
forgot to mention it green is money we
have a color coding blue is
communications so this is when we
enriched it and took a look at it so
what does this tell us what is this it's
the communication network this is
actually a better representation so you
see how there's clusters of people and
those are those are people and the
communications going out what we do is
we do social network analysis and the
Pareto distribution which we'll talk
about in just a little bit but once you
take out the clutter what's left in the
middle is the people who talk the most
now sometimes there's false positives
here those false positives can be people
like executive assistant who sends out
email HR who sends out group and mass
emails those are pretty easy to identify
outside of that once you're looking at
communications once you identify that
people who talk to you have a target
this guy talks a lot he has a lot of
influence within the network he's easy
to spot
he might be easy to turn and so here's
what a cross-section looks like taking
it from macro to micro so this is just
in the middle cluster there's that's
just one gentleman how he talks and how
that information spreads elsewhere
and once combined with the previous
merge you see it's a rather large
network and this is just the what we
call cluster this is the large cluster
because everything else is too big to
put on the screen essentially okay so
here's something that people don't think
about quite a bit is if you're if you're
within it if you're with the political
organization like the DNC and you get
hacked they had quite a bit of
information on the LGBT community so if
you were on the extreme end of
ideological difference with the DNC you
could take all this information you can
start a campaign against the LGBT
community I was really surprised the
LGBT stuff within the DNC was very
detailed and it wasn't
password-protected it wasn't encrypted
they had everything in there like male
LGBT focused parties and who was the
attendees who were the people's dates
what was on the menu I mean all these
little details that there's no reason to
keep but they did keep them and then we
merge them together so I want you to
focus on the red star because if you're
an intelligence agency you have to pick
targets and so what we did was we found
somebody in the DC area
who is unnamed and we took a phase one
look at phase one exploitation of a
human so what does that look like in
reality
it's if we get your hands on you you're
already screwed there's nothing you can
do but for this you see two huge
networks top and bottom and then you see
the star in the middle that's social
network analysis that's connectivity
that's AG and vector centrality and
there's a lot of other factors to go
involved with choosing targets so meet
Steve I chose Steve he was in the middle
of centrality but I saw the name of his
company and I was like oh that's a
pretty cool name for your company I'll
see what this guy is doing if this guy
you probably remember about two years
ago
the DNC had some issues about emails
coming out talking about what works
after the lawyer was killed in DC he was
one of the people emailing Podesta about
I didn't know the DNC still did what
works
so everything you see here on the bottom
is from one of his websites and we'll
move on to the next this is what the
first phase of exploitation of a human
looks like from a network analysis
perspective so where can you find data
obviously social networks so you see
that little blip in the middle between
the two large clusters that's what it
looks like when you protect yourself on
Twitter on the left and the right that's
Facebook and another Twitter that's what
it looks like when you don't
that's why privacy settings are so good
without breaking the box you can get
very little information outside of that
he's a lobbyist he gets paid by a
political organization all that is on
file with the Library of Congress so
every financial transaction that's ever
been made to him or his companies is
publicly available that tells you a lot
we also looked at his employment data
everywhere he worked from start to
finish he's been on TV quite a bit so we
got copies of everything that he ever
did
pertaining to media and press we also
look at his his education and then we
had emails so we knew who he was talking
to on a regular basis and we know who he
wasn't talking to so when you look at
his companies you wouldn't go straight
to Steve what you would do is you would
find people who know Steve and you would
start there so if you were going to look
at his companies he owns two companies
he's a co-founder of one the founder of
the other so you see right here in the
middle they put all their pictures of
all their employees online so with those
employees you would obviously go to the
people who are involved with both
companies they would have information
you would have to double up your
resources to try to exploit two people
to get into both companies with clients
so this comes into the vulnerabilities
let's think about it realistically if
you're a politician if you're a sports
figure or you're an actor and you simply
get accused of something like sexual
harassment whether it's founded or not
what happens to your sponsorship it goes
away immediately
every time so the same thing applies
when you're trying to create a
vulnerability for an intelligence target
somebody who can answer questions for
you you have all its clients
what happens if you pick one client and
you start spreading falsehoods about the
person and start creating stress and you
start messing with their wallet once you
start messing with people's money the
chances of them flipping to tell you
what you want to know increases
drastically okay so what we're gonna do
now is we're gonna show you how we took
like the basically the human factors in
the human intelligence something you
would do if you were developing sources
and looking at human networks now we're
gonna take a look at how that applies to
malware ransomware viruses anything that
affects you guys as an industry and what
we try to do is we try to do both we
look at the cyber infrastructure and we
know that there's humans behind that so
once they make a mistake we're able to
capitalize them we build what you just
saw on the first section so this is just
like a human network this is a PT 10
this is a PT 10 from 2016 you see big
clusters in little clusters what that
probably is is you have the main c2
infrastructure and then after that you
have likely the toolkits involved things
like credential harvesting you know
brute force tools typically the Chinese
make their own tools they do use some
off-the-shelf and they also share some
infrastructure wherever they're
attacking this is what a PT 10 looks
like as of 4 months ago
so you see quite a big difference
between the two any state actor and many
of the very squared away groups 18-man
b-team you can watch the evolution as
they as they start hacking places and
then they get busted they change up the
toolkits they change up their
infrastructure
and so when I started this job I thought
it was really curious that Chinese and
Russian and Iranian and activist groups
out of North America Canadian groups
they all had infrastructure that touches
in the middle and I was like why would
they do that is that an agreement
between countries
probably not but they need the same
services like VPS servers and they need
bulletproof servers and just things that
people aren't going to touch and so this
is what we call a master merge we take
each one of these color-coded is an
individual family of malware and we put
them on into the same chart and if the
IP address is the same they
automatically merge together and this is
kind of the result of what you get as
I've been doing this now for three years
I can see some really interesting things
so the top two clusters there those are
Chinese related IOC infrastructures and
you can see that it's allowed to touch
this but not touch that essentially so
what does that tell me
lawyers lawyers are involved just like
many attacks when we attack people you
know you can do this but you can't do
that they have the same type of thing
going on and you see that there's a big
difference between the the red and the
blue on the top right compared to some
of the yellow where it's all over the
place it's connected to things that
that's spread so taking a closer view of
this will do a b28 first so a bt 28
Russian GRU really super advanced
network it evolves daily essentially but
this is the most recent most recent view
of that it also shares infrastructure
with the rest of the world
so the top of to south 2016
six of the top ten ransomware is touched
now this is not false positives
obviously if his location Russia is a
big place China is a big place we took
out all those and this is unenriched one
thing we do is once we get IOC s we
enrich them with McAfee data and
community data gives us a better picture
of what's on that hash the domain what
is it what's on the IP what is it
resolved to etc but this is without
false positives the first step and so
this is very important because that's
really odd like I don't know if maybe
I'm just the only one who didn't know
but yeah six of the top ten touch now
this is what it looks like when you
enrich it and close in a little bit so
we know there's common infrastructure
but we never knew that it would share
with other people no does that indicate
that it's the same group with three or
four different types of TAC possibly
more than likely those groups just have
the same insight into protecting their
selves and they work together and this
is what a micro view of those
connections look like between type A and
type B for this Tesla Krypton crypto
wall PHP it's you know database links to
get data to the database the same shared
common infrastructure also applies to
cryptocurrency a lot of people think
cryptology and privacy privacy is
secured with cryptology which isn't the
case so one of my first jobs I was
looking at DD for BC they're attacking a
bank in the UK and we were able to get
the P and GS and the emails and wherever
look at the Bitcoin and then we exploit
that in from start to finish and at the
finish they made a mistake and then we
were able to alert law enforcement but
then we keep that data part of the
utilization we never get rid of anything
and we always keep it and we always
watch it in case it pops back up again
so about a year later the Ashley Madison
hack happened and we grabbed all those
bitcoins
sure enough the Bitcoin wallets from the
Ashley Madison exploitation hit the DD
for PC so you have a Malaysian centric
das for Bitcoin group and a North
American hacktivists organization shared
Bitcoin wallets
that's not intentional the one group
probably doesn't even know the other not
likely what it is is they're both had
they both have a common goal it's what
you would consider the mobs new coin
laundry service and but it's crypto
logical and so with always taking a look
at something whenever they make a
mistake able to capitalize on it and so
for this this is this has to do with
wanna cry so when we want to cry the
whole purpose of committing some of
these crimes and these cyber threats is
to get paid so if you're always watching
the Bitcoin the blockchain
at once they make a mistake they made it
and then you can take that and you can
enrich it and then you can watch it and
then something's on your list so this is
an example of what that looks like
basically what we think was one of the
attackers made a transaction from their
Bitcoin wallet on their computer and
they probably forgot to turn on their
security settings maybe they forgot
their VPN or something and they got an
IP address and then what's how what's
housed off that IP address and what
files what hashes okay so this is really
cool
if you're a total nerd like me but the
Pareto distribution it's an 8020 factor
it's typically used with to explain
differences in societal sociology but it
also applies to basically everything in
the universe 20% of the stars have 80%
of the mass the same uh same with trees
that break the canopy same with Heights
of mountains that go over a mile or two
or something like that
but it also applies to cybersecurity so
what does that actually look like so
this is adwin another edwin when the
Pareto distribution is fly so we apply
social network analysis and we look at
the clusters the center of the cluster
is what essentially allows the cluster
and everything to work so it's kind of
like cutting the head off the snake the
body fails so what you are identifying
is basically the multiple head pariah
that's in here
and then once you get this you simplify
basically a huge giant network into a
really simple infrastructure and this is
where you want to spend most of your
time and most of your dedication you
want to if this is part of a threat this
is what you blacklist first or this is
any way you can exploit it this is where
you start
okay so in closing I hope you got
something out of this talk I've been
wanting to talk of besides DC for quite
some time but as you're doing things the
artifacts of your life they're all over
the internet those will be used against
you if you're up against a government
absolutely they know how to collect it
they know how to control it they know
how to maintain it and they know how to
find it
the DNC hack tells us one thing that you
need to adequately protect yourself you
need to password protect your personal
and private PII information you need to
encrypt files that you don't want
anybody to have and one thing that if
anybody has insight I'd love to talk to
you about the shared common
infrastructure and shared with hacker
groups but in reality if there's
probably 12 organizations that are
controlling 90% of the threat traffic
and so if you take those out you
significantly reduce the threat to
America in the world and go vote so are
there any questions
not at all yeah there we go
so I did this let me give you a little
example I did this I spent three weeks
on it and then I updated it as I went
and had some different ideas for it if
you with that data set that I did this
with if you were a government and you
had a team like a fusion cell where you
had a collection manager probably so
many sick and imagery HUMINT you would
be this whole project would have been
done times ten in a week tops it
wouldn't take them off but yeah if
you're a civilian and you're in this
situation against the government your
host time to move back to your parents
live a simple life you know well yes so
that's the one thing are you a target or
not that's where placement access and
accessibility comes in so if you're at a
if you're at a senior level of something
or you're like a systems they go for
systems administrators quite a bit an IT
staff you may not think you're important
but you have the keys to the to the door
right but it is it don't think you're
not at the way to think is that don't
think that you're not a target because
of who you are because you don't know
that your adversaries goals essentially
you might be a target because you're a
millennial and they may think that
you're lazy so they may think that you
didn't do what you needed to do to
protect yourself so they may target you
to get what you know to get to something
else you may just be a stepping stone
super non-board yeah
nobody that's right
that's a tough question if I was them I
mean I would just rebel to rework the
entire organization I would move people
from one division to the other so
everything that they did know that could
be exploited then is no longer valid its
I would definitely change the
department's around I would change the
whole communication infrastructure
around and I would also obviously the
financial stuff I would set basically a
standard operating procedure that
everything will not be stored in a in
the same place
everything will be protected via these
methods here's here's an eye-opener for
you - I didn't cover this before with
all the financial information we also
got their budget for everything and they
spent something like thirty six thousand
dollars on antivirus and no hacking
protections and dlp 36 thousand dollars
is nothing you know that's that's
something that a high schooler can break
and now obviously they're they've taken
steps to mitigate any further issues cuz
this one was a doozy you know I that's
what I would do sir in the back
very
well you could start with google arts
for your social and your personal
information that would be a simple
simple way and if somebody starts
looking for you on X Y & Z you'll get a
notification I would get rid of
unnecessary social social networks if
you just have them to have them because
you think they're cool and you don't
really do anything with them delete him
something else obviously if you start
getting contact by people with accents
you start getting emails that are stuff
that's outside your your normal pattern
of life starts happening to you start
seeing the same cars the same people
sometimes that's okay because you live
in a place you have neighbors you have
people live down the street
but basically think of think of your
life and your patterns as different
islands so you live in DC but you work
in Alexandria but you like to go down to
rest in for dinner every two weeks so if
you start seeing somebody in DC a lot or
a car and then you see that same thing
in Alexandria and then you go to a gas
station here and they happen to pull up
next to you those should be serious red
flags so if you see one person on one
Island all the time that's fine if you
start seeing that same person place or
thing in your other islands that you
travel to then that's bad and then you
need to change up your change up your
patterns of life and let somebody know
that's one of the first things if you
have a clearance or a security officer
and you think something's wrong it most
certainly is and you need to let
somebody know and they can help mitigate
that yes sir
nope nope it wasn't McAfee I've been
asked that almost every time I was
waiting for it but knowing it wasn't
McAfee the judging by the indicators
that compromised if they would have had
McAfee and it would have been updated it
would have catch caught everything that
needed to be caught to not have the DLP
kick so anybody else any crazy questions
anything well I'm gonna be here for the
remainder of the day if anybody doesn't
want to speak up now I'm more than happy
to answer your questions I have cards if
you ever like to come and visit us in
Columbia Maryland we're more than happy
to have you this is the one thing that I
like to tell people this is really about
5% of what we've had the pleasure of
exploiting since my time in McAfee so
but I think thanks everybody for your
time really appreciate you come in and
thanks for coming to besides DC