besides DC would like to thank all of
our sponsors and a special thank you to
all of our speakers volunteers and
organizers for making 2018 a success
yes I'm Alex Norman I'm one of the
co-directors besides DC my the
co-director Bob Weiss is sitting down
here in the front row we're going to go
through just a couple of quick
housekeeping notes and just kind of give
you a lay of the land of what's going to
happen over the next couple of days and
what's going to where you where
everything is
so first of all housekeeping please
silence your awesome ringtone we know
it's awesome
respect speakers organizers volunteers
and fellow participants I know you know
we can all get very excited about our
various areas but you know the main
thing here is to to share what we know
and learn from other people so that's
that's kind of the main idea adhere to
our principles those are posted on our
website and participate you know if
there's something that you see that
you're curious about jump in and give it
a shot you know I know my favorite joke
every year is to say we lose people
unlock the lock pick village all the
time because they go in there in about
thirty minutes and we never see them
again
until they come out with like 27 pounds
of locks and picks and tools all right
who's who orange badges those are
organizers that's the kind of core group
that puts everything together spends
nights weekends evenings we're all
volunteers you know no one is an
employee besides DC Gold there are
volunteers these are people who are
coming in to try to help get you in the
right place you know they may not always
know the answers to everything but
they're you know doing their best to
help you guys have a good weekend have a
good time they're over a hundred and
twenty of them this weekend just to give
you an idea
white speakers really speakers thank
them you know they're coming here to
share their knowledge with us they put
together CFPs they've worked on their
slides maybe they still are sponsors so
the green badges there are the people
who really you know pay the bills put
the light and keep the lights on allow
us to have this really great space allow
us to have all sorts of other cool
things like our shirts and our badges
and everything else and blue that's you
guys attendees thank you for coming
really that's why we put this on all
right about this year we have first of
all we have more escape rooms because
last year the kids had escape rooms and
the adults got kind of mad that they
didn't get to go have fun so now we have
three escape rooms this year we have a
third hiring happy hour that will be
happening from 3 to 6 right here over
there Kathleen is over there jumping up
and down Thank You Kathleen we have a
third track added this year so after
after mr. gear gives his presentation we
will split this room into three so it'll
be track 1 track 2 track 3 we're in our
fourth crypt kids con is still crazy
popular every year Jenny I am not sure
where she is probably running around
getting getting ready but crypt kids
come and be starting after this the crib
kids keynote will be in the center room
here and then crypt kids will be going
all day and then this is the sixth year
of besides DC all right a quick tour so
we have the IOT village that will be
straight across in congressional Hall a
was first created for Def Con it's all
Internet of Things that type of stuff we
lose people in there every year as well
that is a black badge contest so you can
try to win a black badge which gets you
a lifetime entry all right lock sport
village that is in the same room it will
be somewhat crowded so if you want to
get in there get in there quick all
right Wireless CTF that starts at 10:00
or 10 ish it's located in congressional
Hall B which is also straight across but
slightly to the the north direction
south direction got turned around
indoors again follow their instructions
keep an eye on the leaderboard it can
change very quickly
I've played Wireless the wireless CTF
quite a few times and if you can find
the Fox that can get you a ton of points
and make a huge difference hack their
stuff not ours please or we'll hunt you
down
yes
oh yes lock sport if you're getting your
new lock picks they're very exciting but
please don't try to hack in or try to
lockpick anything of the hotels as well
we won't want them to invite us back
all right creep kid starts at 10 a.m.
it's located in congressional Hall see
that's their basically straight across
there's a hallway down to the corner and
in there to get into crip kids you do
need to have a child chaperone so if you
are an adult you must have a child with
you and again if you know something
share it if you want to learn something
ask somebody so you know there's
definitely a lot to learn in there and I
know there's a trash village so that'll
be interesting
all right schedule there's a bit of an
issue with the schedule on the website
the link has kind of an extra bit of of
code on the end that's messing it up so
if you just delete back to either the
word mobile or the word schedule that'll
allow you to go back to the days we
still need to get that fixed but the
schedule from BCC is that besides the DC
org has a mobile version all right thank
yous we're gonna run through the
sponsors quick so engage the audience
these are our top-line sponsors so clear
jobs net perspective
fireEye and then critical snack above
and beyond sponsors endgame is back
again Palantir is new this year all just
consulting they're also sponsoring the
Saturday night's party at the Iron Horse
Antietam technologies they're also our
lanyard sponsor global tech tenable
defense points Lockheed Martin Northrop
Grumman scope group nets Parker
Sony Booz Allen Hamilton polarity cyber
Vista recorded future digital cloak 0.3
system one Trimark BAE and our core
supporters anchor technologies in
coutelle war collar and proactive and
our up-and-coming sponsors Connexus and
secure sets and other thank yous that we
have so folks they lend us gear every
year to run the wireless network and
our various networking the wireless
villages they have been with us since
year one putting together a really great
event for us it's it's a really great
opportunity to get to play with what Def
Con has it's the DEF CON Wireless CTF so
you're getting the same the same abuse
from them the Iron Horse Tap Room
they've been great to us every year this
year there's not a caps game so you'll
have a little more space it's a no way
game was that Nathaniel Marriott an
independent security evaluators alright
the hiring happy hour is back this year
it's in Grand Ballroom North begins at
3:00 p.m. there are drink tickets free
as in beer resume reviews so take
advantage of that and then of course
people who are looking also there are
the wristbands there's the you know
orange for I am looking in blue for I am
hiring so go grab one of those alright
packets in policy that's a new event
this year Bob put that together for us
the Grand Ballroom North it begins at
6:00 p.m. it's the I am the cavalry
group so it's basically going to be you
know us and then congressional staffers
are coming in you actually don't have to
have a ticket for besides DC to attend
this event
we're kind of opening it up so that we
can get as much discussion as possible
and the idea is to get technical people
together with non-technical but policy
people so that we can kind of express
them and explain to them what's going on
in our world and kind of reach out so
that we can hopefully get things get
them to be thinking in the right way
when they're creating policy all right
the fest in October what you all been
waiting for
Oktoberfest that's at the Iron Horse Tap
Room begins at 7:30 p.m. there will be
drink tickets they're generally DC beers
it's basically just straight down a
couple of blocks so just one block over
and a few blocks down and thank you
again to Jacob Porter and Altaf Altis
consulting for putting this party on I
don't think we've ever run out of drink
tickets right Bob okay not yet yes so no
worries the party will continue all
right coming back this year is the
cookies milk and games party so if
ours are not your thing which totally
understanding congressional holla see we
all get together we literally do have
cookies and they'll and board games so
we hang out in there and it's more of a
low-key type thing kids are welcome and
like I said we'll start going at about
7:00 until we get tired which is like
8:30 9:00 and finally the team this is
kind of our core team mentioned Bob
Duran is running around somewhere Jenny
works on the on crip kids
Angelo's our sponsorship lead Jim Gilson
and Cory are networks guys so there they
will be running around and they've been
up all night for the last two days Mick
is working on the lockpick Village David
is in the kids destruction village Alex
Romero and Thor are running around here
somewhere in the back doing our AV stuff
Seth does our CFP process so if you
submitted a talk Seth someone who
handles that Cynthia Josh Janice our or
just kind of support mortal support for
us through the year and then of course
thanks to Jack Daniel who is always
helping us out and always giving us good
guidance what oh yeah I did that guy
over there thanks to to Jo Jo and
Nathaniel I don't know how you guys are
not in there jo Jo and Nathaniel are our
volunteer Wranglers and they wrangle a
ton of people now like 200 or something
and sometimes their angle us angle me
because I forget things Thank You
Nathaniel like that yeesh
directors what are you gonna do now I'll
hand it off to Bob to introduce our
keynote
so I'll be very brief I'm very excited
about the keynote today mr. dan gear has
been a thought leader and a bomb thrower
in our community since before most of us
were involved in it he's been a real
leader and not afraid to come out with
strong opinions that may that may be
controversial so it's a welcome give a
big round of applause
mr. dan gear
[Applause]