cool good afternoon
besides Belfast how's everyone doing
good excellent cool so apologies for the
clickbait title first of all I needed to
have something to fill up the room and
it looks like a few of you of born the
bait but I'm going to switch things up
from a lot of the talks we've heard
today and speak a bit less technically
about cybersecurity and a bit more about
some of the natural human biases that go
into some of the poor decisions we make
and know broadly consumers make when it
comes to security put simply why we can
make stupid decisions so I'm only going
to show you an introduction to the whole
field of what is deemed behavioural
economics but it should give you a good
platform to start understanding why some
of the most common things that
News seen and observed in wild
so a bit about me so first of all I'm
not a psychologist I'm not an economist
I don't have any formal training in the
field however I have built and worked
for various companies in roles where
I've built products and in that time
I've had lots of failures it's a product
that haven't worked or have had big
gaping security flaws but also a few
that have been pretty successful as well
and I currently work for a company
called anomaly which deals in threat
intelligence and we're currently hiring
at the moment if anyone is interested
but I'm not gonna speak too much about
the product pitch
now before we begin what we're going to
cover today is lots of academic
experiments and you're probably going to
go away
a feeling of wanting to test everything
so wondering why you're making the
decision why you chose to buy a certain
drink why you chose to come here today
and but hopefully you'll come away
shaping those decisions to positively
influence your own behaviors and those
of others in the future when it comes to
cybersecurity now a lot of what I talk
about today involves academic studies so
I give it a woman up front a lot of
these studies are unethical for some
part so don't necessarily replicate them
in your everyday work but it's academic
research so they're allowed to be
unethical right
and I'm gonna ask a few people to
volunteer so if you don't want to
volunteer just don't volunteer and if I
pick you out of the audience I'm looking
at a few people I know don't feel you
need to answer a question so there's a
lot of fields that have started to study
the way in which we make decisions so
there's a field of consumer psychology
behavioral economics social psychology
they're just a few right and their aim
is to try and understand why we act the
way we do
and the interest in the fields are
increasing over time so either we're
becoming more irrational or people are
realizing that we have inherent
cognitive weaknesses in our
decision-making abilities more and more
people like me are jumping on the
bandwagon right I'm not in itself is a
bias right there's something called the
bandwagon effect where people will
follow a crowd people will do what a
crowd are doing simply because a crowd
is doing it and there's two key concepts
as we go through that I want to touch
and there might be new too they might
not be but the first being a heuristic
so these are really important and we use
these almost every single second of the
day
this will mental shortcuts that help us
make decisions quickly so when we open
up the fridge and we see a bit of
rotting food we don't need to spend 10
minutes figuring out why it's rotting or
whether we should eat it we just don't
eat it because we instinctively know
it's probably going to make us ill but
it happens with all types of things
there's one heuristic the availability
heuristic
which essentially means we heavily
weight the first piece of information
that comes to mind when we make a
decision right so if we've been primed
with something and it comes to our
memory we're probably going to use that
heavily in whatever we choose to do so
for example if I have read a lot of
Business Studies on starting a
successful business I might have read
the Steve Jobs biography I might have
done some reading up on Bill Gates I
might remember all the successes those
guys have had and because that comes to
my mind first I might think it's easy to
start a business or I might think I'm
pretty successful at starting a business
and it happens a lot with the
restaurants right so there's a stat out
there that 90% of restaurants in New
York City will fail every single year
yet every other chef wants to open a
restaurant in New York City right it's a
dream and they think they'll be
different to the rest because they've
got something different and because they
think they
learnt a bit more and that information
that they've been researching and
learning comes to their mind first over
all the other failures and the errors
that other people have had and seen in
the past which of course their business
is to shut down
and that falls into what we would be
cognitive biases in behavioral economics
or consumer psychology right so when a
heuristic that ability to make a
decision quickly fails us and leads us
to draw an incorrect conclusion from
what's in front of us it forms a
cognitive bias and we all suffer them
right there little quirks that make us
human and we're all susceptible to them
in fact they're pretty useful and
they're probably one of the reasons why
you're here listening to either this
talk today or just a b-side in general
right we're going to talk about
something called the confirmation bias
which essentially means that we seek
information or seek opinions that match
our own right so we come to conferences
we come to talks based on information
that we're interested in or know
something about we don't necessarily
come to talks that challenge our own
beliefs or a different to what we
believe in right
because of the natural human tendencies
we suffer a lot of people fall victim to
them in a security context right so when
we're talking technically about security
we talk about probabilities right we
talk about mathematics right if I do
something how much better is it going to
be than doing something else what is the
risk of change and we look at this very
very closely and we might have automated
cadres raid which tell us where we need
to fix things and where we don't it's
either it's a binary option is here can
we do something or we don't do something
but security is also about feelings
right
we don't necessarily act always
rationally when it comes to security so
I went on holiday recently and it was in
the middle of nowhere we booked a
cottage up in Scotland and there was no
one about for miles and miles yet every
single day we lock the front door
there was no one that was gonna Berglas
right we're used to doing it I live in
London right so we used to lock in the
door but yet we still did it even though
there was no need to write
we're just not very good at judging the
probabilities of risk and this is really
really key to security right so we hear
all the time in the news about security
incidents happening and the whole
security teams will start to focus on
these things right and this is because
it's right at the front of our mind it's
a new risk and we want to take it on
board now some risks will exaggerate
like those that have just been in the
news
others will tend to downplay right so
imagine you're standing there and you're
being offered two glasses of clear
liquid and one of those glasses is being
offered by a chemical company and one is
being offered by the Queen
which one of those two do you think you
would choose
you might not use either of them right
but ultimately
you're probably not going to go with
that chemical company right because you
might inherently think that there's
something bad in the water right and the
fact is it might just be water another
good example is do you feel safer
driving or do you feel safer being
driven right there's an element of
control if we feel in control then we
don't feel scared of the risk of
crashing whereas if your partner or your
friend is driving you might have that
uncontrolled element and you may judge
the risk of crashing to be a little bit
higher
and it happens again with all types of
things
so now that you've been primed of how we
consider risks and how we judge risks
I'm going to talk about four biases and
so those cognitive biases we touched on
at the start and how they actually fit
in to a cybersecurity context so the
first mental shortcoming we're going to
look at is the confirmation bias so we
talked a bit about this but essentially
we seek out information that confirms to
our beliefs right and it happens with
news stories it happens with politics
it happens with their friendship groups
we choose to associate it with
so I'm gonna do a bit of audience
participation and if anyone wants to
volunteer for
a quick little experiment and it would
be much appreciated
no no takers okay we can go ahead
without doing that so a sequence of
numbers here right
two four six can anyone guess the next
number in fact let's do it a bit
differently right so looking at those
sequences of numbers I will give you the
opportunity to shout out what you think
the next three numbers in that sequence
and I will simply tell you whether it
confirms to the rule that I have written
down here on the slide deck or whether
it doesn't confirm to the rule and then
when someone thinks they're confident
with what the rule is then they can
shout it out all right if no one shouts
out I can just tell you what the rule is
and we can skip this entirely so there
anyone one have a guess as to what the
next three numbers are in that sequence
so a sequence of three numbers
so 10
sixteen
yep they confirm to the world
any other guesses
well yep conforms to the road
can anyone guess what the rule is from
that
our grater as usual
yeah exactly that so the rule is that
the numbers must be in ascending order
right so any combination of numbers five
ten five hundred one seven nine all in
ascending order anything in descending
order wouldn't have mapped to the rule
right so that was a good guess
and actually it bucked the trend of an
experiment that was actually done
considering that exact scenario right so
participants were given the opportunity
to submit the next three sequence of
numbers and submit as many consecutive
three sequences of numbers as they
wanted before they were confident that
they knew the rule right and when they
were confident that they knew the rule
they gave it to the researcher who would
either tell them they were right or
wrong similar to what we've just done
now a lot of people followed what we
call positive test patterns so one of
the sequences I think shouted out was
eight ten twelve right so in that case
you might think the rule is increasing
intervals of two or plus two every time
another group so one of the most common
answers that their researcher saw was
multiples of the first number so you
would essentially times the first number
by a value to get the next number
but the researcher source almost all the
participants tried the move that they
had in their mind each time when they
submitted a number so that is if they
thought it was increasing intervals of
two they would submit six eight ten then
twelve fourteen sixteen they didn't try
a negative test strategy whereby they
went against what they thought the rule
was right so instead of saying six eight
turn they might have said something that
I didn't think confronted a rule which
might have been ten eight six and if
they would have done that they would
have got the correct rule and you can
see in the chart there right so what the
incorrect the 75% on that chart is
pointing to is it I'm the first instance
when someone called out what they
thought the rule was they were incorrect
because they were positively testing
what they believe to be the correct rule
they were conforming to their own
beliefs and they thought they were right
when in fact if they would have just
done a simple test to try and challenge
their beliefs they would have realized
that their positive strategy wasn't a
very good one
and this happens in mainstream media
right so I'm not going to get political
but when we start hearing news stories
about Donald Trump you get two sides you
get the right wing in the left wing and
everyone says oh everyone on the right
wing they just listen to Fox News
they're wrong and then everyone on the
left wing says we listen to whatever NBC
the BBC we must be right right
ultimately these people are going to new
sources that they trust that deliver
information that conforms to their
beliefs right that's the reason why
they're going to those sites in 2008
during the election with where Obama was
running there a group of researchers
looked at Amazon book trends right so
what people had on their Amazon wish
lists and they found that people who
supported a bomber we're looking at
books that painted Obama in a good light
whereas those who didn't support him
actually putting books on their wish
list where Obama was in a negative light
they weren't buying the books for the
information they were buying the books
for the confirmation right
and another experiment done so this is
one where people were looking at support
for various issues like gun ownership or
abortion so pretty strong moral issues
and what happened was they were shown a
variety of news articles so for news
articles in total two supporting their
beliefs two opposing their beliefs and
what the researchers found was
participants spent 36% longer looking at
articles that conform to their beliefs
so supported what they already knew then
knows that challenged their own beliefs
now this is really important right
because we all have very strong views
about what we're doing whether it be in
a security context or a wider general
everyday context right we do this
because we don't like to be proved wrong
we like positives test strategies
because it doesn't make us look silly or
stupid right and if we can tell
ourselves we're doing it right it feels
good and it's dangerous because even in
examples where data is used to validate
arguments even quality even quantitative
measures can be proved wrong right ma'am
and what people will do is they will
read charts how they want to read them
and not necessarily pick up the chart
the way it should be read and you see
there's a lot of journalism actually the
way various journalists or build graphs
that don't quite look right or
are shifted towards looking to support
the view in which they want to share
with the audience
and this is why especially from an
analyst point of view you want to try
and prove yourself wrong during
investigations right just because you
think you're right first of all doesn't
necessarily mean you're right right can
you get a colleague to challenge your
views or when hiring can you build a
team that doesn't necessarily say yes to
everything you're doing that comes on
board and actually challenges what you
think is right whether that's right or
wrong and look beyond the usual sources
right
so again if you're just looking going
back to the news example that sources of
information of learning that is
potentially biased again you may be
missing a whole host of things which are
proving your current beliefs wrong
so now we look at the future so we look
at our inherent optimism
so we always think the future is going
to be good right we think we're going to
get better jobs as we grow older we
think we're gonna have no money we think
our kids are going to grow up to be
successful there's not many people that
have kids and think they're not going to
do very well or they're going to live
bad lives or they going to get ill as
they grow up right then the reality is
that those things might and they have a
very good chance of happening
I mean who thinks they'll come to
b-sides and be worse off after the
experience right you think you're gonna
come here to learn and you probably will
but equally something particularly bad
might happen to you whilst you're here
and I'm going to be a bit morbid again
talking about the health situation
because this is a big one and a lot of
health body struggle with it in trying
to educate people towards healthy eating
or living better lifestyles so 50% so
one side of this room and I'm not
pointing to the left side necessarily
here are probably going to get cancer
during their lives right and that's
pretty high but most people you are
probably don't have cancer on their
radar aren't preparing for it which is
fine it's not something you should be
preparing for
but it's interesting when you start
looking at it in how stubborn or how it
can influence the way we actually look
at things so here's an experiment
another experiment run so there was a
particular type of cancer and I forget
exactly what type of cancer it was but
people were asked to predict their
likelihood of getting it they weren't
medical health experts they were just
regular guys and with no particular
medical training and there's two
participants here but this is
representative of a much wider study
participant a on the left the first
destination of getting cancer was 40% so
pretty
no optimism for their own lives there
they were pretty pretty ranking their
chance of getting cancer highly the
other person so part is him and being
this example thought he was much more
robust much stronger that chance of
getting cancer was just 10 percent right
which is we've already seen is way below
what the reality is now this particular
type of cancer in the type of person
they were using for the study the actual
likelihood of them getting it was 30
percent so three in ten people were
likely to get cancer and they were told
this once they submitted their original
estimation and then they were asked
again so what are your chances of
getting this particular cancer right do
you think having just been told your
actual probability of getting cancer you
would probably line it up to that base
estimate or at least put it pretty close
participant a did exactly that right so
there's second estimation they said okay
yeah I 40% me okay that's fine a bit
better than what I estimated they've got
a better chance of longevity and I now
arrest made it to be 31%
participant B was a lot more stubborn
right having being told his chances were
30% he thought he was a bit more likely
to get cancer but only 4% more right
he was really stubborn in changing his
belief and he was still thinking yeah
it's probably not going to happen to me
in my lifetime even though all the
research would suggest otherwise and as
I say that's widely represented across a
study of a thousand people right and
these are the similar results to what we
are seeing across that whole experiment
and here's another good example and it's
not necessarily the best in example in a
group of security focused people however
when you ask the general public what
their own risk of being phished or what
their own risk of falling victim to a
hack is they often will tell you it's
pretty low right they'll tell you oh I
have pretty good internet security
practices or I don't go to sites that
are potentially going to affect me or
vulnerable I just look at Google and the
news and browse Facebook right that's
all I do on the Internet but then they
might have a friend who's very similar
in their social situation but they'll
say yeah if you look at John he's
probably gonna get fished he's probably
gonna click some silly link on Facebook
and get hacked or he's going to give her
the bank details over the phone when
someone calls him up right
even though their lives are pretty
similar and again that sort of outcome
has been represented in a number of
studies so one on online privacy in this
example right essentially participants
were given a list of questions about
online privacy and security and what
they thought and they were asked to rank
these various behaviors on a 1 to 7
ranking so one I'm not going to fall
victim to it to 7 I'm probably going to
fall victim to it right and when they
looked at well during the experiment
they had to rank their own risk as well
as a peer risk and the peer was someone
very close to their own social standing
in their own employment right there was
almost a mirror image they were asked to
imagine and you can see here right the
the self risk so the actual risk of
falling victim to any of those privacy
problems was lower than that they
believed of the their peer so there they
were optimistic about themselves but
actually we've got an optimism bias for
our own situation but we're not so
optimistic for others as that study
shows there
and this is something that can be
avoided quite easily right people have a
sense of invincibility and as I say
people always think the future for
themselves is going to be better we have
a desired and positive state another
negative state and one of the reasons
for that is we have more information
about ourselves right we know our own
preferences we know and behaviors we
don't necessarily know our next-door
neighbors preferences as well and it
will even our best friends so we need to
take away that feeling of invincibility
we need to introduce negative events and
the consequences of negative events and
a lot of companies do this at the moment
right so what they do is they want to
make bad events more retrievable from
someone's mind so instead of
them being overly optimistic you bring
them back down to earth right so if
Facebook's a good example if you click a
link moving away from the site it might
be a completely genuine link but there's
a second step there that says are you
sure you want to move away have you
considered the risks of going to a
third-party site right even that's not
perfect because a lot of people are
going to ignore it but it's that extra
step that's making people think well
should I be so positive about where I'm
going next do I need to think about it
twice and you really want to highlight
the losses that may occur from someone
doing a bad thing right or someone doing
a bad event that they don't necessarily
know will be
bad event such as navigating away from a
secure environment so phishing emails
are a really good example in that
instance but another really interesting
one actually is in Germany so what they
have in Germany is something called piss
screens so they have these in bars and
clubs and when you go drinking and after
maybe three or four beers or half a beer
of yummy you need to go to the toilet
there's a little screen in front of the
here I know so is for men I think it's
only for men I don't know if there's a
woman's one but the men will stand there
and little game will appear on the
screen and essentially I've got a
controller a little car around the track
whilst they're pissing right and it'll
actually monitor the speed at which
they're reacting to turning the car on
the track to avoid the obstacles and
their reactions are slow which is
obviously an indication that they might
be drunk at the end of the game it'll
flash up when the number for the local
taxi firm or uber or whoever to say we
think you're a little bit drunk do you
want to get a taxi instead of driving
and the drink-drive rates plummeted
after that campaign right just by
bringing that negative event of getting
in your car and driving and potentially
crashing and which would happen on a
game if they would perceive to be drunk
to their mind so that they then didn't
go and engage in that action going
forward so we've looked at the past and
we've looked at the future let's look at
the present and how much we love the
current state of affairs how much we
love to do the same things over and over
that it causes us to miss great
opportunities and in a cybersecurity
cent stick with negative outcomes so
just have a think about some of these
things here right so how many times you
change your utilities provider or how
many times you change your I don't know
favorite brand of cereal or toothpaste
or cosmetic product
it's very likely once you've found
something good or something you believe
is pretty good for your situation you're
not going to change and again this isn't
always a bad thing if you've got a
favorite brand of toothpaste and it's
cleaning your teeth what's the point of
changing right
but in some situations the status quo is
not always the best option this is a
really interesting story from some of
the research that I was looking at for
this presentation right and one of the
things that got the researchers looking
at the status quo bias is they had a
colleague and for I think it was five or
six years this colleague at board in the
same lunch every single day to work
right it was a ham and cheese sandwich
and then there was a particular day it
was a Thursday they remember it
perfectly and I've got a date here March
3rd 1968 was when the research was
conducted and he changed to a chicken
salad sandwich on that day and then for
the next five and six years he had that
exact same lunch right he just stuck
with the status quo didn't want to
change even though there was plenty of
great lunch options out there
again another experiment looking at the
status probe right a group of
participants were told that they were
putting themselves down for
a brand new car so they had found a new
car at a dealership that they really
liked and they were told there was no
none currently in stock but they had an
option between four colors so they could
choose any of the four colors now a week
before they went to pick the car up
they were then told three various
situations so the groups are essentially
split into three groups so a week before
they were called again and said by the
dealership you can have any current car
color you want what color do you want do
you want the red ones you want the blue
ones you want the white one or do you
want the green one in that case 22%
opted for the red car
now the next group so they were first
told when they got that phone call
actually we've only got the red car
available do you want it and they said
you know we will have any car we wanted
any kind of color and that's fine and
then
they got to the dealership and actually
every car was available and the
dealership so do you want to change your
mind well actually most of them didn't
want to change their mind 53% stuck with
the red car so way above the 22% right
that we would expect and the same thing
happened but the other way around so
they were offered the blue white or tan
one not green one sorry and the ones who
selected that when they got the first
phone call because the red car wasn't
available again decided to stick with
that decision this time only 15% went
with the red car when they were given
the opportunity when it became available
to the dealership so moving this into
sort of real-life situations this has
big impacts right to the organ donation
rate in Austria is 99% in Denmark it's
4% does anyone know the reason why
exactly right
so just by making it physical um doubt
where a person's got to say look I don't
want to donate my organs they rarely
ever do that one percent of the people
do it right whereas full percent will
actually decide in Denmark to opt in to
donate organs and for anyone wondering
in Scotland and Wales its opt-out in
England and Northern Ireland
it's opt in and I'm not sure the exact
rates but you can be pretty sure they're
probably quite similar to that and this
is pretty important when we start
talking about privacy in some respects
because for a long time companies could
just opt you into things or they would
have a default opt-in button checked
when you signed up for a product or
service right then you get a ton of
emails or letters through the post and
you've opted in because you didn't see
the little checkbox hidden right at the
corner of the page that says yes I
agreed to consent the EU is kind of
brought in a lot of laws against that
but it still exists in some places and
the reason why we do this is because of
the fear of
anticipated regret right we know now is
stable we know now is good even if will
offered a 1% increase in security or
let's say a five percent increase in
security there's a lot of risks
associated with that whether that be
choosing a new bit of software or
choosing a new way to do things right
because it could go wrong it might take
more effort right that there's a whole
host of things in that process that
might not keep things going as well as
they are even though they're probably
pretty low in reality so you really got
to set the status quo in people's minds
to get them to start thinking about
changing their behavior so that might be
and I've seen a lot of companies now
doing what they call security reviews or
benchmarking right letting people know
where they fit in the wider world so you
are better than 99% of companies or you
are worse than 99% of companies right
and when someone hears such big changes
or or sees they're so far away from the
status quo it gives them the incentive
to change you need to make the fear of
staying the same higher than the fear of
change right so you need to make it more
compelling for them to change their
current behaviors and Toyota's a good
example to test look at examples of this
actually when it comes to electric cars
so instead of Toyota going all out with
electric they kind of went with hybrid
and electric for a while I think they
still make the Priuses right which was a
hugely successful car at a time because
people knew petrol cars they wanted to
stick with the status quo of petrol but
they also liked their green credentials
of the Prius so it was a nice easy shift
into the electric or green market if you
will where a testament said
we we're just not going to have petrol
engines right we're going to go all in
on electric and well they're starting to
see a change now as electric becomes a
status quo it's taking them a long time
to get their right to Tesla what a 15
year old company now or something like
that
and they're now starting to see good
market traction but even now it is still
tough
so finally I got five minutes for this
but it's fine I've got enough time so
we're looking at anchoring right so I'm
going to talk about why we're really
lazy when we make decisions and when I
weigh too much on the first bit of
information that we're total right so
I'm gonna look at invite anyone to stage
because I don't think anyone would
nominate themselves but if you have a
think in your head what the answer to
this question is
anyone know the answer and I knew I want
to shout out an answer
a hundred thousand course the answer is
forty thousand three hundred and twenty
right no many people can do a math
question like that very quickly unless
they've been a pre one then it's coming
but an experiment was done with two
similar questions one where the numbers
were descending one whether numbers were
ascending right and these are two
different groups and they were asked to
predict the likely predict neuron so
sorry Group one where the numbers were
descending so eight seven six five four
predicting the answer to be 2,200 2,250
where as ascending they predicted to be
512 so there was one two three four five
the reason for the difference we'll
think about how we read the question
we'll read it from left to right so what
the participants were doing we were
reading eight seven six producing the
answer to that and then trying to figure
out what the final answer might be based
on that first bit of information the
other group of doing it the other way
one two three okay this is a lower
number I'm now going to predict the
answer from that and as such they come
up with a
example Social Security numbers so again
I was just doing a google image search
to look for something good on this slide
and it comes up with way too many people
have posted it on Twitter but an
interesting option was done around
social security numbers right to
students was shown a list of items that
they were asked to bid on in auction but
before they fit on the items they were
asked to write the last two digits of
their social security number next to
each one of the items so the last digits
of my social security number edit away
11 I would write down 11 dollars so as a
price next to each one of those items
they were then asked to bid on the
actual item so an auction was then held
and they were allowed to bid whatever
they wanted for the items now this is
insane right if you look at this so
people on the top there that's the last
two digits of their social security
numbers people who have lower social
security numbers it's significantly less
than those who had higher social
security numbers right it was in some
cases 346 percent higher
now that doesn't happen in everyday
auctions and that type of examples
pretty far-fetched but it highlights the
process of anchoring they have taken
that first number that first price had
written on the page and they had been
anchored it to their next decision right
so they had moved away from their anchor
to decide what they were going to bid
for the item right so they say $11 I can
go a bit higher
I'm only gonna go X amount higher it
happens when we buy a car right we know
the price we're going to haggle based on
the initial price we're told we're not
going to come in with something way
lower or if we do we're probably going
to be rebuffed pretty quickly as it
being a stupid offer and it happens
again insecurities with loads of
different things but passwords are a
great example when you sign up for
service in this as your password must be
12 characters it says your password must
have 10 digits to numbers whatever right
what you really want to be doing in
these situations to influence behavior
change is really start to influence by
anchor right so you can see the top
example a good password is 12 characters
I set the anchor 12 password a 12
character sorry whereas if you say your
password must be between 6 and 20
characters I have no real anchor to go
on so I'm probably just gonna choose the
lowest number I'm gonna go as 6
characters just because it's again the
easiest I mean though there's no idea of
in this case a status quote but also an
anchor and again we see this across
loads of different things and it happens
in all types of marketing so it's all
about improving behavior change
cool so that about wraps it up actually
quite nicely
there's hundreds of cognitive biases
that we fall victim to right and it
happens across all types of things and
security could really do with
investigating the field a lot more in my
opinion and especially in my role is
building cybersecurity products I think
there's a lot of ways in which we can
positively influence people to change
their behaviors rather than build
products that force them to change their
behaviors and this was really aimed to
be a primer so you can start to
understand how we're predictably
irrational but how you can use those
predict abilities in our natural
behavior to actually take control right
and even in that so I show you a big
list like that there's biases that a
result and I was a bit nervous of
showing that so there's something called
the choice paradox where if you offer
someone too much choice they just simply
are paralyzed and they won't take action
so by showing you a list of hundreds of
biases you might just think what there's
too many out there I'm not going to do
anything right so I've kind of cut the
list down so hopefully you can go on
Wikipedia and start having a look
but there's tons of information online
that distills this information down and
gives you great sources to start looking
at Security Investigations and as tons
of books out there as well
but as I say this is only aim to be a
primer today and just to get you a
feeling of some of the ways we can be
inherently stupid but also how we can
use that stupidity to make positive
changes in our lives specifically around
cybersecurity
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]