outstanding outstanding those really
nice-size audience here kind of
impressed with that I've done a lot of
b-sides and seeing turnouts like this
aren't always always there I've been in
rooms where I had five people show up so
nice turnout
really appreciate it so a couple quick
questions just to gauge the audience so
how many people here are IT security
management people so we have a few so
and I guess the rest of you are
practitioners do we have any pin testers
here a couple pen testers good so it
gives me an idea of the audience well
today's presentation is called out go
the lights and an enlightening you like
that play words enlightening discussion
of automated technology or automated
security so this talk is going to be
around IOT technology so let's go ahead
and start with me my name is Darryl
Hyland I work for rapid7
I hope you don't mind if I walk around I
really really hate standing behind
podiums I find that horribly boring so I
work for rapid7 I'm the research lead
and my job is to research IOT based
technology so this has been really
challenging a real challenge when I was
given this job one of the first things
they asked me was you know so now that
you're in charge of research in IOT what
is IOT and also you don't have a budget
so so I've been doing that for about
I've been an IT for about 25 years I've
been in security for about 15 and I was
working as a pen tester for last 8 or 9
years before taking the role as the
research lead for rapid7 so let's kind
of move on so our agenda today is give
you an idea or understanding of IOT at
least from my view my vision of IOT may
not be everyone's vision of IOT but it's
mine and we're to talk about IOT
migration into the enterprise we're also
going to be talking about lighting
automation exploitation I did some
research recently on Io T based lighting
so you know you can say hey I seen a guy
today with a light bulb in his pocket
and we can also talk about securing IOT
best best practices how do you approach
IOT within the workplace how do you take
care of it how do you manage the
security risk implications associated
with IOT within the workplace so let's
start with the Internet of Things
there's a couple couple interesting
things here when talking about IOT how
do we define IOT so there's a couple key
areas interrelated devices IOT
technology has interrelated devices they
collect and share data between them they
do this over a network this typically
can involve Ethernet Wi-Fi ZigBee z-wave
some kind of communication they're going
to communicate and then also we get into
a bed electronics they all contain bed
electronics so this is the base of all
definitions when trying to define what
IOT is so this is what I was challenged
with doing defining what IOT is so me as
a research lead can figure out what kind
of research we're going to do in the
area of IOT and the only way to do that
is to properly define what IOT is but
see this wasn't sufficient enough in my
opinion what we needed to do is look at
it from a bigger picture kind of an
ecosystem so in an ecosystem of course
we have the network communications but
when we're dealing with IOT technology
there's three other core pieces that
make this up this actually includes
mobile applications and includes the
embedded technology and it also includes
the web api's and within each one of
these we actually have code running on
each one of these that make up the
overall IOT structure and we also have
data that's actually exchanged over the
network communications the east of each
of these three pieces so why are we
looking at it from this ecosystem type
concept the ultimate goal is is is to
understand the potential risks of
security vulnerabilities that could
apply within the IOT environment or
ecosystem and the only way to do that is
look at each segment of that the mobile
the Web API and the embedded part of
this and how all of them affect each
other because we're
the security breakdown on any one of
these pieces is obviously going to lead
to a failure of the overall system the
biggest problem I've seen with most IOT
research that I've encountered it all
seems to focus on the actual embedded
technology so everyone's going oh I'm
looking at a hardware device I'm looking
at an appliance you know they look at
this this happens to be a light a five
for a home this is a home automation for
lighting systems so they look at this
and they go this is IOT
the fact is this is not a OT this is one
piece of IOT this device here is control
with the mobile applications on your
phone that's part of IOT to do that it
communicates to cloud applications cloud
API is out on the Internet
this will communicate to those cloud EP
is the mobile app communicate to those
cloud EP is and that's used to control
this device another piece of IOT and all
of those pieces make up the ecosystem so
the failure at any one of these pieces
could somebody compromise a light bulb
that could lead to actually compromise
in your home network
can someone compromise this that could
lead to compromising the cloud a api's
could someone compromise the cloud API
is the effect could compromise your
phone to gain access to your network the
answer is yes unless we look at that
whole ecosystem there's no way we could
effectively secure IOT technology so we
have to look at it from that standpoint
does that make sense to everyone says
we're going through this I think we got
enough time if anyone has any questions
while we're moving through this please
ask don't hesitate to ask that so make
this much more fun and exciting if we
have some good questions that come out
of this whole presentation so moving
from there let's talk about each one of
these pieces in the potential risk or
attack vectors that need to be
considered
so when we're looking at mobile mobile
applications obviously we have the
application we also have the
communication that's associated with it
that's going to communicate to the
cloud they may communicate across your
network through your Wi-Fi network
directly to the device so we need to
look at that type of structure we got to
look at actually what's being stored on
your phone what kind of information
relate it to the IOT ecosystem is being
stored on that phone that creates a
security issue a security vulnerability
and last we got to think about
authentication how do we attend ik eight
to that application on your phone is it
strong is it we can it be compromised
moving from there we have the cloud
aspect this is very much similar when we
talk about the cloud EAP is most of the
time this is actually going to be web a
web service it's available on the
Internet and again we have the similar
type of stuff we have to deal with
authentication how is the thin ocation
so you can buy IOT based technology you
could deploy it in your home in your
workplace but if the authentication
mechanism is totally flawed within the
cloud API what's the impact of that for
your home security or your enterprise
security it could be quite significant
if I can compromise that cloud API I
assume that I can gain access to PII
information critical information about
you your business or potentially tunnel
through that application into your
internal network and that has to be
considered we also have to think about
encryption is the data flowing from your
phone to the cloud API or from the
embedded device to the cloud API
properly encrypted is it passing
confidential information passwords
information PII information if it's not
encrypted what's the potential risk
there I just finished up a research
project I wish I could share you the
details about it but we're waiting for
the vendors to actually fix the problem
and this turned out that the mobile
application that we were looking at when
it communicated to the to the cloud it
wasn't properly authenticated in a cloud
there was really no good indication at a
cloud so all I had to do was be able to
capture a piece of data any piece of
data about that communication and was
able to use that data to access all the
information about this device you the
person the PII information from the
cloud because of poor authentication
mechanism and then of course we got to
deal with
I'm sorry poor
encryption then we got to deal with data
storage how is your data actually being
stored in the cloud is it being stored
properly securely those need to be
considered and last don't but not least
web attacks within the cloud API since
they are typically web applications are
they vulnerable to the common web
attacks can you do cross-site scripting
cross-site request forgery sequel
injection or a number of other type of
attacks that are available door to web
stuff and then we want to get into
network communication all these three
pieces the the cloud the mobile app and
the actual embedded device all
communicate via network so from a
research standpoint ecosystem standpoint
we need to consider all the
communication that happens to go over
the network what about the protocols I
mean like I said this is the number of
different protocols we're all used to
Ethernet that's pretty common or Wi-Fi
but now we're seeing communication
protocols between devices or you know
the example would be like the light bulb
on the network that are using other
protocols this particular light bulb
uses a ZigBee protocol we need to look
at all of those communication protocols
between the sensors the embedded devices
the clouds the other embedded devices on
your network and all these pieces in the
mobile applications and that
communication is it proper is it secure
is it encrypted and can we attack that I
mean we have a number attacks like the
home automation there's attack against
the ZigBee protocol the home automation
version of the protocol because it never
raqi's plus someone cracked the key and
it's available on the Internet so even
though the authentication between this
light bulb and that device there is
encrypted it can be replayed because it
uses the same key or it could be
decrypted because everyone knows what
key is because it's easily available on
the Internet and you go oh my gosh it's
a light bulb who cares well the truth is
that's fine if it's in your home if your
neighbor just wants to torment the
daylights out of you by turning your
lights on and off all day that's
perfectly fine no harm done but if you
were actually sitting in this room and
this whole
room is controlled via this technology
which is now hitting hitting the market
and being implemented what's the impact
of lights in this room going off we're
going on off I mean it you say oh I
would just leave well that's fine but
what about the business what's the
impact of the business what if you're in
a retail business and you can't keep
your lights on what if you happen to be
in your place of work trying to do your
job and you can't keep the lights on I
mean most of us are probably like
sitting there hovered over a computer
wearing a black hoodie anyways but in
Jenna and Jenna in general the truth is
you can't function without lights okay
so if you're security your lights are
bad at a bare minimum you got a denial
service that needs to be considered so
it's kind of fascinating area to think
about was that yes could you say that
again adhere oh wow I never even thought
about that so he's basically said that
that there was a scam where they would
actually call in a bomb scare well
they're elite riding on coats or
whatever in the bomb scared everyone run
out the door and they stole all the
coats in this case they just turned off
all the lights walked out the door so
yeah that's that's the reality it's
there's a bunch I never even thought
about that but yeah I guess that's a
scam we don't necessarily see in the
u.s. they just walk out the door they
don't bother to care yes sir yes
so hit what he was saying there if you
didn't hear it was basically by turning
lights on and off at ten Hertz it
affects epileptics and I know there's
been a number of attacks like that the
horrible thing someone did that to the
epileptic website and made it flash at
that frequency so yeah I have so yeah
you've done it is that from experience
and what was your name excellent thank
you very much thank you very much
so yeah you you have replay attacks
spoofing attacks against a number of
these protocols and even though it's
something simple the lights there's a
number of possible risk and
vulnerabilities that exist there and
again this is a piece of the overall
ecosystem that we need to think about
when we're examining IOT technology that
we're not just examining a small piece
of it and the last one is the hardware
this is the part everyone kind finds
fascinating so you want you want to be
able to look at the detail of the actual
devices so the circuit board you see up
there I actually cut that out of one of
these light bulbs so that's actually a
picture of it and just so you can get a
closer look
I ask that you return it here's here and
pass it around so pass it around the
National circuit board it was cut out of
one of these light bulbs so we like to
examine things at this level here and
look at the possible security
implications we want to download the
firmware code off these devices this one
here the actual firmware code was
actually brought down encrypted and was
actually stored encrypted too which was
kind of crazy on there technology all
this company's technology on this case
here
it's actually a ZigBee processor that's
on the device and the interesting thing
if you look close at that board you
actually see where the I think the three
black wires that I have on there those
actually connect to your UART a serial
connection so you can actually hook that
up to a computer and watch the device
boot up so so it gives you a different
perspective of what a lightbulb is very
different than what we're used to seeing
in the past it's a piece of technology
it's a computer it has code on it that
code can be manipulated there was a talk
at blackhat that I missed but I was told
that it based on mostly on theoretical
concept in the theoretic attacks against
lights and actually being able to create
a worm that could spread through like
light bulbs I think it's doable it would
only take someone a little bit of time
to figure out a piece of code that they
could put on one of these light bulbs
screw it in when it's incorporated into
the ecosystem of that technology spread
through all the lights potentially doing
some of these other nasty attacks that
we heard here at will or at random so
it's something to consider so let's move
on
IOT migration into the enterprise don't
have a lot of slides here but I have a
lot to say about it so let's start off
with yes they are here I don't know if
people remember the movie apparently not
okay so so IOT technology is in our
workplace I talked to you professionals
all the time I go to a lot of
conferences and I ask the question do
you have IOT in your workplace and most
of the time is two things I don't know
or no the answer is more likely you do
so let's think about this remember we're
looking at it as a as an ecosystem so
we're not looking at it as just some
small piece of Technology we're looking
at the whole ecosystem and how it
connects up so example your employee has
a Fitbit strapped on to his arm or some
other type of wearable technology okay
that wearable technology connects the
Bluetooth Low Energy typically to his
cell phone okay and his cell phone has
applications on it mobile apps it's part
of the ecosystem those mobile apps and a
lot of times will also connect out to
cloud technology okay so it ties into
the cloud so we have those three people
pieces we have the embedded technology
we have the mobile technology and then
we have the cloud api's then he walks
into your workplace and he attaches to
your internal Wi-Fi because you have the
whole bring your own device policy okay
so now even though you don't believe it
or not that Fitbit or that wearable
technology is part of your network
because he has it on this wrist hooked
to your phone connected to your internal
Wi-Fi network connected to the cloud now
all those three pieces are now part of
your network what's the security
implications of that the scary thing is
we don't know yet we're still so young
in this field of understanding what the
security implications is such things are
of wearable technology and how somebody
could abuse those two compromised you so
then we get into lighting now think
about this okay you you're in a business
your company your managers decide
they're gonna cut costs and they're
gonna put in lighting automation
solutions to make the lighting all
better okay say hired contractor and
they put the Lighting's in they hook
everything up they connect it into your
network you know what I bet you it's
probably about a 75% chance they never
bothered to tell the IT department that
they were actually going to tap into
their network I've come across as more
times than not that IT is often the last
people to know with some of these core
based technologies such as lighting
implementations coming into the network
the other ones heating ventilation and
air conditioning so when you implement
heating ventilation air conditioning
automation the IOT based stuff within
your environment a lot of times this is
used to manage power consumption within
the organization to keep cost down this
may tie back to a corporate
quarters it made a it's more likely
going to do this to the cloud more
likely you're going to have mobile based
technology involved in this I've seen
these like iPad type things mounted at
various locations in a building that are
used to control this type of technology
within your environment and that's what
gets implemented into your environment
but yet they don't necessarily tell your
IT department that's not part of the
process IT department does computers
right they do servers they do laptops
they do desktops they do router switches
in firewalls they don't necessarily get
involved in the process around lighting
or heating ventilation and air
conditioning systems am I correct
am I wrong does anyone go to challenge
me such silence in here so how many
people have IOT in your workplace now
now would you raise your hand before I
mention some of those things
okay good some of you some of you said
yes and that's perfectly good so we need
to be thinking about these things within
your environment this technology is
coming in every day now me when it comes
to the definition of IOT I do not
consider router switches and firewalls
part of IOT I know you'll run into a
number of definitions of IOT that
involve anything it touches the internet
it is the Internet of Things so if it
touches the Internet it must be IOT if
that's the case we've been at using IOT
since the 90s at least now and I don't
necessarily agree with that I think it's
part of that ecosystem that I mentioned
that actually makes up the IOT based
technology so power management is
another thing that's another one of
those things that I'm just recently
getting involved in I had I had a
company I did some work for had just
implemented this type of technology
power management to actually attract
empower in their organization in their
case the IT department vet at the entire
technology before it's plugged into the
network which is really good you don't
often see that that's what I challenge
most organizations to do get your
security people and your IT people
involved in some of these type of
technologies to make sure it's done
right they actually tested all of the
products that they implemented with an
organization and I was up there doing
some work for him had a big discussion
about this and they go yeah we
implemented a company a B and C's
technology it's in all of our store
locations all over the United States
what it does is it manages power what it
tells us how much power consumption is
being used it communicates this to the
cloud we could use various applications
or mobile applications to interact with
it to get this type of information and
we add yes we did consider all the
security things they actually with an
Ethernet version of it which was kind of
neat and then instead of the Wi-Fi
because the Wi-Fi gives you the remote
attack capability and you will actually
talk about that in a few minutes on some
products so they went with the Ethernet
and then they also isolated it into a
subnet which toured in we're gonna talk
about some of these best practices the
nice thing was they go yeah Darrell and
we actually have a whole spare unit that
you can have and they gave it to me so
that's sitting at my lab at home
actually busted open with a bunch of
probes connected to the circuit board as
I'm analyzing the technology but again
that's one another one of those
technologies that may not be
incorporated or me I team may not be
involved in the thinking process around
deploying that type of technology and we
need to do that now this is the one that
always gets me audio/video system so you
go in an organization you go do you have
i oh t technology in your environment
and they're like no we don't I pull my
cell phone up I turn on my bluetooth low
energy sniffer and it lights up like a
Christmas tree and everything says
Samsung Samsung Samsung go into every
one of the conference rooms they got
these big TVs on the wall there and I I
imagine a lot of you have those in your
home too right big the big Smart TVs
they're kind of neat my wife actually
forbids me from putting one in the house
she doesn't even like going into my
office cuz it's kind of there's so much
IOT stuff plugged in she doesn't trust
anything that goes on in that room she's
not putting one of those in her house
and I'm like why she goes well I don't
want the thing watching us so you know
and all these TVs actually have
our cameras built into them they
actually watch you and send this stuff
off to people not all of them but a lot
of them do if you connect it to the
internet they definitely listen to your
audio okay and that's also transferred
off onto the Internet if you have the TV
connected to the Internet I know a
number of people had these TVs that have
turned that technology off I know other
people that the technology on certain
TVs they couldn't turn off and it would
continue alerting on the screen that
they couldn't connect until they plug
the thing into the Ethernet so connected
to the Internet so I'm not sure what TVs
you have or what TVs you have in your
organization but let's think about that
so you have a TV it's sitting in a
conference room where you have
confidential talks and discussions okay
is that TV connected to the Internet if
it is connected to your network it's
connected to the Internet because I'm
sure it will find its way there unless
you've set it up specifically not be
able to route but I know I've been into
offices where they go yeah they fire up
their laptop and they connect to this
Wi-Fi service and in the how and the
building and they're connected to the TV
and they display anything they want on
that TV because it's on their network so
it's on their network it's on the
Internet
now it's communicating audio/video out
to the Internet actually one of the
vendors and I think it was Samsung
actually came out with a statement it
says don't do anything in front of our
TV you wouldn't do in public so think
about that when you're when you're at
home from your TV it's watching you or
it could potentially be watching you
says something to think about but it's
nothing to be scared about it's a thing
to understand okay you don't want to
panic over stuff like that but if I
assure you I'm getting ready to buy TV
if it has a camera on it there's gonna
be a little piece of tape probably over
the camera because I don't want I won't
go buy one those little slide things
I'll just put black tape or something
over it so I look weird but it's
something to consider and something to
consider in your corporation so if you
implement these technologies look to see
if they are communicating out to the
Internet
because if they are the last thing you
want to be going out
the Internet are potentially going out
over the internet is all the
conversation that takes place inside
your conference rooms obviously that's
typically important meetings
confidential information
now these TV manufacturers are not using
that data for anything
unscrupulous they're not doing anything
illegal
they're not harvesting your data and
selling it to people they're not doing
none of this type of stuff it's all part
of this move to be able to market to you
better so they can consume your
communications and deliver you
commercials seriously in the future that
are based on your conversations that you
had in front of the TV I don't like that
but that's kind of one of the goals I
see them moving forward to but the
reality is is if somebody wants to
compromise your network or somebody
wants to eavesdrop on you somebody wants
to break in and steal your corporate
secrets how are we gonna do that I know
what I would do I would probably tap
into all these TVs you have setting into
conference rooms if they happen to have
video capability to happen have audio
capability why can't I record that
information and excellent rate it off
the network out to wherever I'm at and
watch you and record you with what
you're doing I think that would probably
be the most interesting attack vector I
can think of if I was just wanting to
monitor to you does that make sense so
is everyone gonna go home and everyone's
gonna get out the black tape and I cut
the wires the audio on their TV and do
crazy things don't do that don't don't
do anything crazy the whole idea is
awareness if you're aware of something
you can make the right decisions for
yourself personally and for your company
and that's what it's all about it's one
of the reasons why I do IOT research
it's never about fear and certainty and
despair it's about knowledge if we have
the right knowledge we can make the
right decisions
so they're going to get into lighting
automation exploits how much time we got
okay good you got 10 more minutes okay
so let's kind of move through this so
automated exploits we're gonna talk
about mobile applications embedded web
communication protocols local Direct
Connect services so we're talk about
some of the attacks that I was doing so
let's start with this one mobile
applications where I had mentioned that
you need to look at the data stored on
your mobile applications when you're
looking at the ecosystem here's a prime
example here happens to be a iPad and
the plist file actually contains my
password and my SSID for my home network
so if I lost my phone and I go get a new
phone truthfully this data is
compromised another example and this is
fairly straightforward and simple but it
turns out like with an iPad you know
when you hit the one button shut the
application down it takes a screenshot
of that page and you know how it shrinks
you see the page the way they simulate
that is by taking a screenshot and
shrinking the screenshot and that's
actually stored on your machine so if
you happen to be on the configuration
page setting a password and you're done
you hit that button you just made a
screenshot now the screenshots will
overwrite each other over time but I
mean if you're on doing banking I'm
doing banking on my iPad putting all the
stuff critical information I shut it
down and then I lose my iPad I leave in
a cab
hey the person all I have to do is pull
up this screenshot folder and actually
can see what the last page is you looked
at before you shut down and actually
could leak information prime examples
the password they're embedded web
attacks cross-site scripting let's just
do a demo it's a lot much much more fun
but we're dealing with in embedded
technology and you're dealing with and
you're dealing with IOT technology most
corporate enterprise IOT technologies
just like most corporate enterprise
devices on your network have web servers
they all have web servers
well we haven't have a lighting system
here this is a this is a lie defy
enterprise level lighting system
this one hasn't been patched yet so what
I'm going to show you has actually been
patched
so let's go ahead and log on to this
device I'm not sure how well this will
you'll be able to see this this is a
configuration page for AWS roms lighting
system like I said they've patched this
do not consider this any kind of
negative against asraam they actually
patch this stuff I work directly with
them helping them behind these issues so
these are actually good things this is a
good company they do things right they
take their security right they create
patches quickly automatically update the
patches on the system I just prevent it
this one from doing updates that's the
only reason why it's still vulnerable so
we come down here under management and
we look at security logs in this case
you can see where you've logged on and I
logged off that's how the security logs
are it's kind of small but this is a
page of security logs okay
this case here see if it's words
let's come over here real quick here's
the actually pricing this any better
this is the Oswald configuration page
you look over here when you go the
security logs we can view the security
logs here see them a little better you
see is really nothing there simple
security logs what we'd expect well what
we're going to do is we're going to
actually log on but we're gonna pay a
log on so we're gonna send it a failed
log on this failed log on is actually
going to contain HTML source code this
case here which is basically a
cross-site scripting so we log on and it
fails so then if we come over here
refresh this so now his logs are a
little more unique we're actually able
to plant stuff in there so there's a
number of attacks that can be carried
out this way you can carry out
cross-site request forgeries it caused
them to reconfigure the device so this
happens to be one vector that we found
which is not necessarily an uncommon
vector it's easy enough to inject
cross-site scripting via logs very
common method but we have another one I
have a video for this one here is an
attack vector very similar it's a video
it's easier to do with the video but in
this case here instead of a failed logon
attempt we're actually going to start up
our own Wi-Fi hotspot and for the SSID
we're actually going to put attack code
into it in this case it's just going to
be a flash file we're not going to do
any real attacks with it but we're gonna
show how it's delivered and it's a
similar attack as the other one we carry
out cross-site scripting so any device
that actually displays SSID structure we
could actually potentially inject
cross-site scripting cross-site request
forgery in so again we go to the Lyta
Phi system here we're going to come down
to the
Wi-Fi configuration we're going to go to
the wireless client mode it's going to
come up here in a second and we can see
we have 2 SS IDs that one happens to be
going home that one's my neighbors but
what we're gonna do is we're gonna fire
up our own SSID in this case we're
actually going to call a flash file and
we can call JavaScript files from a
third third party site to do attacks but
this is what we're gonna do so when this
product actually enumerates the wireless
spots nearby we'll scan it again so it
shows up this case something different
happens and again again it's it's a fun
entertaining way of actually
demonstrated in a potential
vulnerability in a product but the
reality this type of attack thing never
gonna quit there we go
so this is just one way to demonstrate
the attack but the reality is this
attack vector is pretty serious I did a
get blackhat you're up here three years
ago on this exact topic where we demoed
enterprise level products and one of the
examples we actually use this attack to
create a administrative ID on a
enterprise level wireless control and
controller with root level privileges
used in this attack and also had the
device offload all of its configurations
to us to a third party website so these
same attacks can be carried out any
other way so if you happen to be
implementing a technology or using a an
embedded IOT based technology where it
can see Wi-Fi around you and it's
monitored via that anytime someone would
see those SS IDs the potential for an
attack vector existing there does exist
and again this is kind of an
entertaining way of demonstrating that
attack vector but it's a quite serious
attack vector so let's jump back to
slides real quick
so on the last one I'd mentioned is
communication protocols
ZigBee Ethernet z-wave Wi-Fi the whole
list goes on and on and on but the truth
is and and we mentioned it earlier these
type of protocols can be used to do
replay attacks and various things like
that and they exist across the number of
these different protocols that needs to
be considered on the the Wi-Fi
communication on these devices and some
other ones we've been finding a lot of
the WPA pre-shared keys that exist on
these technologies by default and you
know they give them wpa2 out of the box
setup they seem to be complex but
they're not complex it turns out that we
typically are able to crack most of
these keys in two to six hours so if you
using these technologies and use them
their defaults that come with their
products you need to reconsider that
because we're found in the key spaces
are using to generate those keys are
insufficient and they're brutal and we
can easily crack them and like I said
two to five hours and if you happen to
have one of these devices connected to
your network via ethernet and Wi-Fi and
I'm sitting in a parking lot and I can
crack your WPA pre-shared keys on these
devices I am now on your network it
turns it into an access point so we can
easily pivot into your internal network
so that's something to consider
also local connect one things I found
out with most iot technologies
especially the home stuff is when the
cloud goes down does your whole product
quit working no it does not quit working
it goes into what we refer to as local
mode so your mobile app will connect
straight to the device but typically the
whole thin occation mechanism was your
device with indicating to the cloud to
get information down your mobile app
connecting to the cloud to get stuff
down but when the cloud fails that
communication drops the local mode and
instantly there's no longer any
authentication and it happened to be the
case with this particular device right
here so the code you see up there I mean
it's a simple piece of code snippet
and what we're doing there is literally
we can pass an SSID and our own
pre-shared key directly to the device
without Afeni keishon and it will do
from your network andrey off to ours
without any authentication and this is
not this is not common or uncommon it's
quite common i've seen a lot of
technologies that are built that way so
instantly i mean your home networks
typically going to be secure it's
probably not going to be a problem but
as you see more of these technologies
and move into the enterprise environment
those need to be considered your network
becomes a lot bigger a lot more people
in it you could have people unfriendlies
on it people break into your network if
i can compromise your network and find
some technology that i can set up a
permanent backdoor by routing your
system out through my system I'm going
to do it it creates a way for us to move
data back and forth without properly not
getting detected so an attacker is
definitely going to do that now we want
to get into security IOT best practices
and we've kind of covered a couple of
these so stopping right here the stuff
I've showed you guys do we have any
questions yes sir
although we haven't looked into it so
the question the question was have you
seen any lighting systems used to
exfiltrate data often network was that
we were saying basically so and no I
have not seen anything in the wild but
we were talking about that with my
manager just recently but because when I
was at Def Con I was in an IOT village
talk and they were talking about
lighting specifically and in that case
there they it actually took a building a
lighting control system and turned the
whole front of a building into a video
game by using the office Lighting's so
it actually played out like a video game
using all the office Lighting's so so
that brought up the subject with my
manager going hey you know someone could
use that to actually send data out of a
company Network you know that 40 storey
building and you have a light on you
know the 40th floor that goes on and off
at a certain rate is anyone going to
notice maybe maybe not or have lights
come on in various places at different
times to actually communicate data out
through a building and so yeah it is
possible I'm not sure I'm sure someone
will eventually try it let's be real you
know so that is a possible attack vector
yeah okay let's kind of move on to this
right here best practices and this is
this these are real simple this is not
rocket science identification you want
to go through make methods to identify
IOT technology it's currently in your
workplace how do you do that this is
something I'm currently challenged with
trying to figure out from for rapid7 is
how how can we help our customers
identify IOT if we don't know what they
got if you don't know anything about
what's there is there ways for us to
identify IOT it's something you need to
do because you can't protect it if you
can't identify it business needs you
always need to make business decisions
that's what everything's about it's not
about
security it's about business decisions
the business has to make those decisions
are we gonna embrace IOT and do it
correctly or are we going to wait until
we wake up one day and something happens
and we go huh I didn't know I had I owe
t technology in the workplace which is
basically what happened the phones I
mean did cell phones sneak up on us and
sort of most companies would don't have
any cell phone policies until they find
out that half their employees cell
phones are connected to their network
and then they go oh my gosh maybe we
should have a policy so let's think
ahead of that from an IOT perspective
and think about what's acceptable what
isn't acceptable from a standpoint of
IOT within your corporate environment
isolate segmentation the best thing you
can do if you're implementing heating
ventilation air conditioning power
management lighting systems don't put
those on the core network put those on
some kind of backbone network so that if
it is compromised they do not compromise
your internal network to me that's the
best way to go keep it isolated patch
management anytime you go to purchase an
IOT technology the first thing you need
to ask them how do i patch it what's the
method for patching it how easy it does
it patch the truth is if I have a
technology and and the asraam was
probably one of the best examples that
homelite if I system every time a patch
comes out I fire up my cell phone or my
mobile app to look at my lights to turn
them on and off it alerts me that
there's a patch all I have to do is go
patch
a minute later everything's patched it
does it over the wire does it over the
protocols it patches all my lightbulbs
does it all that's the type of
technology we want if a vendor goes oh
yeah yeah you'll have to have an outage
and you'll have to take the device and
you have to do a B or C to get it
patched in but we never patch anyway so
it shouldn't be a problem you don't want
that product you want a company takes
patching serious and they're patching
method around upgrading the devices
firmware is simple and not complex if
not it's not the case you don't want the
product
and any questions yes sir right
yeah with with IOT the IOT technologies
I see that I've just started working
with myself for like Bluetooth Low
Energy so there is still number tools
that are coming out for monitoring
Bluetooth Low Energy there's some
hardware like Adafruit puts out a
sniffer that you can actually get within
the middle of a Bluetooth low-energy
communication there's the uber tooth
device for sniffing Bluetooth technology
those are some of the tools for sniffing
there's also RZ USB device which killer
B which is basically attack tools but it
gives you the ability to sniff ZigBee
and capture though protocols just
recently there's been stuff come out
with z-wave but I've not looked into it
typically z-wave you're gonna use some
kind of RF RF hacker tool or something
like that to catch those RF
communications but yeah unfortunately
unfortunately there's not a lot of tools
readily available typically the
technologies are with us longer than
I've liked before people start producing
valid tools for capturing that data but
from Bluetooth Bluetooth Low Energy
there's some good tools out there the
ZigBee like I said the R and I have one
of the devices here if you want to
actually see it devices for the ZigBee
stuff that you can use to capture replay
dump do peak apps and stuff like that so
you can actually analyze the data
available and most of these you can also
input the data into Wireshark the
Bluetooth Adafruit sniffer will actually
output all the data into Wireshark for
further analysis also in same way with
the uber tooth any other questions
what's that
the work that no that's not necessarily
long with vulnerability you want it you
want things to update but you want them
to be signed also so packets firmware
package should be signed that means you
just can't drop a firmware on the device
automatically that's important but the
automatic updates they don't
automatically update what happens is is
your mobile application plays the pivot
point and when you say update it pulls
those firmware packages down and then
serves them up to the actual Gateway and
then the Gateway deploys them to the
light bulbs can you hack the phone in
this kit and this in this case here all
of the packets were encrypted all the
firmware packets were encrypted I did
not know the decryption form so you
would you would have to know their
encryption mechanism their signing
mechanism to be able to create a packet
to do that but you got a good point
there just because the device is
automatically update just mean it's
secure you can easily update it with
your own firmware then it's not secure a
company has to have good encrypted
firmware and the packets need to be
signed if they don't meet those
qualifications they should not be able
to be deployed onto the device so a good
point yes sir no no I mean I mean let's
think about that you think the
application community operating system
community have a problem with bugs
I mean Microsoft has a crapload it comes
out every month bugs aren't gonna go
away so so how did how did Microsoft
solve the problem they solved the
problem by putting a good program in to
patch so and I think that's the case now
I agree with some of the bugs are just
like you got to be kidding me did you
even try and you're gonna run into that
in some cases and it's kind of a new
field and you got to remember a number
of these companies aren't software
companies they've never done software
before so they don't understand security
they've always produced some kind of
product and now they're in they decided
we're in IOT
so yeah they're a little bit behind the
eight ball but there's something
companies out there build it secure
secure securely build it securely which
is the website if you look that up that
is a company or that's an open sore a
non-profit basically focus on helping
vendors build security models around the
creating and deploying their products so
think about time