the level of their expert about their
coffee and coming in to have a look the
presentation it's got a bit of an of
choose title Louis because but really
that's actually well they can't make a
title because so a policeman sniper cry
and I used in their feet of information
act and I'll just talk you through why I
asked what I asked and some the results
know also some interesting insights into
the information okay so this is marginal
medication so they can get you this
actually made over here so my name is
Ron restarts manager and logic so
Houston headquarters our security
company but we have a research
development so I did an image in
electrical and electronic engineering
McQueen's little tango hold on all the
PhD thesis and
previously presented in across the world
that's relevant when they specifically
asked about it deep inside the
presentation are the print sensor
applications so agenda agenda and then
information about the cyber protection
that we have the minute or just some
contacts with talker talk about my
requests the results of analysis there's
some abuse of Defense and if I doesn't
take away some discussion so I a little
bit rate so I'll look to the organizer
to tell me whatever race weekend off and
then if whenever I need to get all the
makers storm for a couple of nights just
to make sure in love unduly effective
investigate two experiments ever protect
review so and you can't handle
protecting itself whatever where the
other type of threats okay so that means
the whole of the UK right everybody K
yeah but is our real is our cyber
protection realistically covering all
those different things I mean whenever
you hear my breeches maybe hear about
the money one of the things where we
hear quite government initiatives it's
usually who big company it's been act
all yen pien somebody doesn't left some
vulnerability website and somebody's not
right but realistic that we're talking
about hope UK showing that should be
very yard where we are really at also
protection shoot increase with us but he
protects the public so we are the we're
under Louisville essentially right there
for the UK like they okay they consist
of the entirety of the UK so no I it's
actually I'll talk you through where the
thought process that I went through in
order gets you to do an exact where
every bus so say the average person s
let's say that person let's say the
people in this river race right this
presumes everybody here is a separ
professional so it's fine they're not
opposed to each other what would you
think you might say your brace you
probably go when you've been a academic
or technical in chess tonight you would
go when you were median and do whatever
it is doesn't need to do in reflective
done so that's how your friend is
breached right nice maybe in front of if
it's not me you would care a little bit
last thing you would if it was you
probably kind of fix it
but without me deeper he probably to say
dispatch it the answer they say the
general public is breached right and
they don't have us to call PETA for the
person they didn't have the call other
soaps cupcake you know why he's doing
that
what are those guys do what do they do
no I would imagine and this is where
this goes through difficult police
because generally speaking the average
general public would say okay I told to
replace say that person does with the
local police what happens right what
happens so that was essentially the the
mechanisms to be watching right here
this happened 2012 and as a result I
asked for information for more 2011 to
2012 yeah
and I didn't really know a lot of them
you cannot remember from here so we did
some digging in terms of well what I we
got to my eternal surprise apple pie
as far as I'm aware it was the first
time you have to see there's a level
never it was called the UK cyber
securities company protecting them from
putting the UK there there's the world
and November 2011 okay that's a really
great but the central break done before
things are worthwhile they had four high
level objectives and they said okay
we're gonna secure UK cyberspace are
we're going to these more things one way
to make the UK will secure place to do
business business you can't be able to
resist attacks in national
infrastructure opens people rely on
cyberspace yeah right it's not about
protection good sir you can't necessary
knowledge to Exhale cybersecurity it
will lap my covers for the local police
all right that's kinda science education
but it's gonna fit anywhere today so my
thought about each of those in each of
those internal if I do reflect upon
either the public or small to medium
businesses right to expire but we could
say your state or government departments
some people care if you're rich right if
you are a local co-op or you know four
shops are going to say everybody cares
about you if they're targeting cats
right small name is like they should be
covered under this to do business
enemies right like SUVs are
disproportionately targeted and the
reason they're disproportionately
targeted but I hope not saying this to
anybody who doesn't know this it's
because they have less resources before
he applied cybersecurity there's many
more of them so generally speaking if
you get some sort of scout or you're
doing some sort of whatever you're
likely to find just opening the
addresses that have some graphical or at
least no clue me as any because I don't
actually have the resources to have
these things so say you're an SME need
to get briefs and they report their
local place to class but that was
essentially when I got like they also
said the issue you can actually battery
with resist our attacks against national
infrastructure we all hate conversations
now our robot we all have that in our
hallways that's however many cans of
millions is that not protect right same
employees go home also professionals
right say the city HR person was hope or
the exact for whatever the apartment
goes home and then they get breaks at
home through their own Baba because
there's some vulnerability and some nap
here blah blah blah that's ten years old
okay you didn't say you know did they go
to the Danielle September's you get open
stable on the vibrant Cypress piece I
didn't really have anyone that I could
say I don't really know
she doesn't like we're here with you
then you can't have a necessary
knowledge ticket sales are secured again
surely opal is fallen so not having a
food room for me to request right joke
they're like and this time I was opposed
talking points and I got I read right
around and their thoughts nobody likes
to do something about this because
post-op McQueen's next to a power belt
so then she can't be moved from you not
know this gives people that right to
access report information health back
public sector organizations so that's
the purpose so it's actually one of
those few times whatever you take
elements it we're going to be more
transparent and it actually work for
that regalo generally speaking to you
arbitrarily pogroms for some dirty
laundry you'll find it all across the
newspapers that's how they call it
primary mission but it can be some for
us that's what the outcome for this is
it if you want to find out things about
cybersecurity it's applied in practice
at government this is what way you can
do where else did you actually so some
temples of some favor information
requests have been put through to police
because again this is requested the
place mark normal these people dividers
and check them out that's what reported
super I would be surprised another one
how many bolts I face in this tool in
the last five years that's twelve super
went to your chocolate over multi traced
alone that's a work factor how many
apples items in the cold it has to do
with the police with the reformer how
many crimes in the world clogs one he
was a big movie
I call that justice so fy2008
send any public one in the UK I gave the
context to this police salaries but you
can't send a Daniel okay it has to be
broken test information can't ask for my
right matters of people most guillotine
from existing systems they kind of have
to go widely find information that's
already there
we're not gonna get you know where some
administrative effort to acquire yeah
these are all limits will be important
elections these so those are the rules
that I said right come up with a couple
of questions so I can take right since
which separate dressing to each of the
fifty one policeman stories the UK oh we
got a sponsor from 37 the purpose of it
was to determine how public Council or
businesses means war crimes in the local
policeman I II do think so
all stop for hunt that I talk about this
opposition I believe that that's
teachers at the Amazon so Harley handle
if they are reported and what is the
library level of cyber expertise again
the reporting period was November 2011
to there whoever 2012 this is important
as a novice date so my request details
tested earlier I hope everyone in the
back to read this little bit about
everyone so one how many reports were
from a public would be the business
community for dnews reported offenses
agreement of the computer misuse act
like there are many acts of things could
conceivably be covered on there plus I
shall see you later in terms the results
I got it was at least relevant and again
if we go back to the 18 hours and if I
say please give it to me from all these
9x well then that take something kind of
law and michael mattos a tasty love
we're not gonna answer so there's been a
scoping there all these reports
essentially how many were deemed worthy
of further investigation
so trying to fill the time to cheat if I
make a report it only if you actually go
out and the third one
how many of these were passed to the CPS
prosecution service for consideration of
qualification at that stage that's how
more of an optimal talking CPS to fight
back okay what actually happened okay so
that's that stage is a white sentence
cope with this and that was the point
ministry questions to see how money as
it goes through those kids again I'm
referring back to the UK cybersecurity
sponsor 2011 which I mentioned at the
start reason I mentioned that is it a
specific require in 4.31 that the UK
local police forces recruit cyber
specials again service references
intentions of course
let's kill affiliate investigation cyber
crimes so okay we're a union how many
well the reports in question one not
gonna read through this we'll talk about
later essentially split it up into
different categories
I made crimes were a court of a social
media all these how many were further
investigated in this 2011 all the
reports in question one where any of
them use in an online reporting method
never mind associated somebody said
alien who those are the requests sent
news to 51 second race with a timetable
tape he's giving all these answers
November 2011 the property visible trial
and this is what I'll give you each one
so 51 requests
37 responses so that's my quick response
trip I have given additional information
by forces are so good that they just
wants to know walk you to McDonald
there's additional stuff that we never
even ask for what we think will be
useful 14 said the done was not
organized I'll be referencing this
constantly they know many volunteers Ola
however make not tell me how many crimes
were reported under cyber or this
particular cyber legislation that's
suspicious
now every state is to respond is 33 so
that average day to respond
particular one algorithm all to do
that's the finding it out to do probably
means are just really busy
I can't on the right-hand side me coming
back to these game as well
sex said that there were four national
security tactics exceptions so they said
no possum I don't I feel security we're
not going to answer any of your
questions for me at sex and there were
37 let's you know actually information
very specific there were nine and I'm
Marshall
so again there were over ten questions
within that someone said well we can
give you the answers to one side of the
sex that's right
again why other people are going to be
this little answer but wait at least you
numbers once without was thank you so
the percentage of course responded was
only 34 percent it's not a great number
however the reason they wouldn't know is
that this is not there's enough this is
useful in terms of point examples it's a
relatively small sample set we have to
take it with rigorous statistics and
then the cost these requests in theory
as a maximum there's twenty seven five
horrible pipes and we'll come back to
that way and yeah this is a essentially
the average request responses to each of
the questions again weren't relevant
will call the spot guy but we'll do the
impression he's glad to be shared and
then people walk down there the notice
is a question for the sanction zero if
you're paying attention question for us
is pointing and then the key fibers was
broken up into different so question one
and one average horses experience twice
as many reports with people is for
businesses okay so that's essentially
what this again if to take your
prisoners had often to be here okay
enough to be any so good
however if we if we project that light
when we could say okay so however many
are protected however many are reported
for businesses we could expect twice as
many to be effective public okay now
that's addressing us you so that's not
great enough to try to do something so
one of the more helpful Kansai queries
they saying took it make sure lungset
have access to another even that's what
the doubt was essentially they give me
older 14 2005 up to 2000 as well which
show is essentially a linear expose pick
you up from 20 actually on showing an
Oprah trainer so not only are we saying
that there are twice as many to the
public were supposed to businesses we're
also seeing there's moved on but so yes
we're demonstrating there it's actually
going on people are recording more
year-on-year to local police forces to
say you know what I have a crime visual
unit is some sort of cyber event okay
that's a little take people are doing a
more but just that a couple people are
getting it and it's not going on yeah
yeah question taken many except the
report a political force that have
enough information to work further
investigation okay that's good to the
things that people are reporting for the
police the police take on board then
saying okay ninety percent of the time
that's worthwhile do the will 10 percent
Rocking
but they never sent a big number however
once you ask once you then talk about
how many were passed or propagation of
not offend 2% so all of the people that
are presenting hey I have experienced a
crime and upset but then when 50% of
those or worthwhile actually say yes so
50% yes so again - um because I've heard
one because that would represent that
when usually helpful additional details
and they broke a time exactly how the
reports were presented them a result so
we have fortune charged
we've reprimanded restorative resolution
on the technical crime resolution but
yeah they're working to remember there
is a number they're in their pocket and
then they're 46 in there well the safe
for sex with the pie charts but
important are there from the crime right
so that's interesting that our whole
order of over or no pride wonder why
people reporting things that protect
this one particular time again it's
important that there's no crime in it
like wonder why that might be and
generally speaking the way this is
between the public is whenever was legal
in real life there's also illegal
cyberspace right does not really hold up
it's not about the books this hold
forever isn't actually a crime there so
yeah some of these are going to be
they're going to have analogies in
online they're not gonna have a more
line so for example one would be they'll
all find a girl with malware right
sometimes old boxing watch your house it
says my back I don't easily make sure I
can he actually described underclothing
appropriately this is actually a crime
in cyberspace
this might not actually have an
equivalent in real life because I have
to
or something you rather than just
Baptists actresses but the tech
consultant interesting kind of great so
we have a loose crime so that evidence
was not treated to do suspect again you
can make estimations of that list of
whether or not we're actually kind of
writing about for formation we we should
have got any more information and then
we should be using that more at these
crimes know this she was who can request
a little place and if interaction result
or not oh yes yeah so because some more
amount of details here so policeman
subgroups were super helpful give me
exactly samples of some crimes were
reported from oh yeah more connected
sesame or so I think about when in the
back can really get but well really like
to snail tails so the first one there is
retailer states to someone access or
computer software website change putting
the holes of the price appear pointers
essentially bring the guy for to pay or
pay we Guzman eldest class so when that
wasn't since the attack was not
successful violence of committed his
hate crime he knows all detected the
second one retail victim were his
website for where the chase 91 P turns
like this was actually a Fault in world
pay and I'm not actually in regional
recommends health again they weren't
this item have fewer but not still a
crime as still some means attempted
unsuccessful there another ependymoma
index employers computer only from hope
a hormone at the hard drive number for a
fan directed the near systems at the
company
attention to disrupt their business
operations they got some ones right that
guy just got in evidently someone think
I can believe it all the data I'm gonna
fan her number five as excess that
greets basic America changing pasture
poultry councilmember Alsip again
caution you'll notice as well that's
social media how insulated then number
sex is better being a schoolboy during
the lesson of work let's go use your
school computer to access the skilled
network deleted files arrived trying to
get access to things we couldn't
compromise
blessing spares no those are examples
there were actual examples of things
that report to the local place so like
so one of two or sixty programming
interface but it not hopefully well it
was really well but we have examples in
the magento shopify right for people who
remember what that is that's essentially
a very similar like this is evidently
being used against what we do business
we have so this is never that we have
made in school can be visited
that's important to know right these
people are actively being targeted by
these things no to the victim number two
was a victim by proxy they were number
one of their suppliers horrible okay
rule patches whatever else but anybody
think of another fake company that was
attacked target again by proxy these
people are also vulnerable these
vulnerabilities all exist within this
whole media business environment music
or they're dispatched
final six were interesting to use social
media note that the report crimes what's
the basis in question six social media
with zero so there are crimes occurring
in social media in 2012 well nobody
reported that way
we're 2016 most year probably get the
friends
yes and I are and as a result we'll
never they're much more active on that
night 2011 we would also be hardened to
opossum our school systems enough
national instructor as well of course I
mean this is all publicly funded stuff
that sits in you know hundreds of
buildings across the country
I wonder how much money those guys got
from the cyber protection initiative in
order to secure those things gas and
everybody said this not deliver the
virus like cyber specialist was all this
year 11s and that's for specialists Saul
a yearly intern answer from everybody
the answer back was no that's not again
you're doing over the course of a year
extrapolating across they're only three
seven replied I've never done the
national expertise to be able is
important there is a national level
stuff so say Starbucks guessed it right
there's going to be a national level
organization there in order to protect
those people no that's fine but the
whole point of money difference between
a national level or the local level of
protection is that they actually gave
the things along that level so the
answer to national protection they can
probably don't care about this more
locally stuff local police are supposed
to handle that stuff and yet where is
that set the priority but even if it
wasn't working them I'm sure they're
super primary Asian they say okay this
worlds they preach any we're at the top
okay and then question five is actually
pregnant dying by the type that was
reported there was nothing terribly
shocking under this Paris but there are
actually seeing results in these areas
so broken time by malware that's a
personal details one authorized computer
access
expressive children really cyber for
anything to you with Wi-Fi and there's
something older it's other relevant
Americas but now you have things like
malware class whatever
there are things fall into those
categories are being reported within
that computer nice computer
mississippi's fact counter they are
actually being avid against the public
at small businesses these people need
protection there are no signs of the
categories is essentially just a pair of
numbers pie chart access its large
number so one day exclusions meant that
the UK government contributes to the DPI
our report and as a result mrs. or
businesses rugby blue and then it's okay
here's the secretary Rachel's the world
good absolutely good to contribute
without that kind of information is the
kind of stuff I have massive war so
we're gonna have on the might snap make
that public through this vehicle for
your information point we're gonna
tactic that information is you have to
the samisen stuff I'm asking for so
that's a little bit so is it chess we've
seen therefore the lease a floor is one
is considered the least some of their
information was protected either by some
sort of police force information
exclusion or since our national security
yeah oh there's no no when we give me
okay Thursday actually handed me big
shovels of extra data because they're
being super help so so I broke that like
into across the UK this is the
reasonable night again we're breaking
this time in furious so the places where
you should go live with the blue board
on the reports yes if you track that
plane nobody has actually been bracing
or portlet is pull it there and then
under your rules protect their we're
least likely attack there and then there
are areas where we did not receive
reports that's large nice cobblers hold
on Scotland a scholarship here and
Northern Ireland as well yes the recipe
you can write to you that the black
areas are no information then TV to get
back to me right don't ask for my
testicle little packet and then you can
also have faces like Durham the radwells
for security exemptions so you want to
show her what's going on in there that's
to do with national security as to
whether or not a particular member of
the public authorities so yeah this is
essentially a description of across the
UK
how are your resources reporting with a
reacting to reports of threats against
the public and enemies so if they're not
reporting in if they're not putting
together a kind of a circuit Alice
number bonsai trees for the domain of
the public over crimes so that's
essentially the information that I got
to have from the resolution requests but
there is a little bit extra that I went
into coming back to the post request
which is 27 5 400 so long to stop the
resented possible feeder information
requested by 30 pound an hour like
probably more long didn't all the nasse
house places but let's ignore it because
it's the information and again give a
maximum 10 of 18 hours that would then
be 40 in this case a 50 local cemeteries
preservative all of them used all the
time even if they do 27 540 that's why
visa over that was a maximum like that
in theory so when you take element by
sending the same request all I have to
do this in a relatively generate a to
one email addresses
necessarily to be a very devious mind
you were kind of we dig there so this is
Walter thought process here as we go
along these does that very accept
submissions by email any email any
utility you know have to be correspond
well sometimes they ask questions bike
that's all clear whatever else so they
need to actually be able to contract you
again
otherwise my hope is kept entirely
neither the identity of the requester
than the ordination of the requester is
considered or necessary so I pretty much
like the wealth education right there so
this is like the intentional the whole
point of the people comedian/actor it's
still a lot of people go and find what
find out about information but that's
alright noble but it also the exhibit so
really only you need to do is write a
very short script mutator basic template
variant robbers in there send out the
seriously series of emails to whatever
audio feedback gossip then I phoned
police for some berries but it can't be
anyone yeah it's not 51 that's the
maximum of hospitals social service
departments educational boards whenever
it is that you want anything at all so
let's put this together in the process
look so you select some sort of classic
template generate some sort of identity
probably going to me to tell your them
that leaves an actual effect right so
you put together starting to four names
right as you see fit you've got a couple
of email addresses you're going to need
a couple of temporary email addresses do
generate some sort of topic a Generac
topic I would like to know the number
all right on the top of primary mental
social possibly the impact of it you
know what's the cause with stopping this
expertise was exciting this
that's encountered up to your
imagination with applause it's all sort
of offset the current date you can ask
for every six months individual requests
for every six months for last five years
they will consider every single one of
the cleaner accent the one individual
request fourth in fact because it's
broken dyed by guillotine hours if you
sent it further further gone
in theory I couldn't hire guys who said
no I'll take too long
say method at the end of the six months
three months whatever and then the
easier for those guys were actually
produce results and again nothing uses
up the time that's like your target
emails they sources Hospital Russell's
everyone's Oh
and then Sam all right I'll have to get
this together four months of rejected
I've had fine but for all of these
things we're gonna 70 large networking
and then that's gonna consume on
resources like there are two conditions
you have to be within here right this is
not entirely two conditions they have to
fall off one of these two things you
know the information requested is exempt
from excluder we'll talk about whether
requested this introducing some
reasonable repeated has to be so for
something to be exempt from disclosure
it has to be at least partially compiled
and actually have to get to the reason
for this is them form I think all the
harm tests where they say okay well
we've got the down we're kind of looking
at here the positives to tell you what
here the negatives are telling you about
it we're gonna sign with the negative on
this sorry right and whenever some of
the votes that did give me answers to
tend over of information gave the rape
part of this hard tax right so you know
this is a girl in this instance we don't
get the data but if we're going to carry
out this particular kind of resource
consumption attack a maximum care we
don't care mentality or whatever
wherever you want what we want is for
people to expand to kind of like doing
things and that's it so as long as it
isn't immediately rejected from being
exempt and some damage to the dog might
not be the maximum kid in the matter but
it'll be something that's greater this
year similar are various
boy don't make it to an individual will
reject a mixture it is national security
or police force we kept asking like
things of that nature just don't know
about tell you about so the three ones
that are more interesting for us right
if it's repeated there's a nuisance
unreasonable repeated so we're heated to
describe at least essentially he's in a
public communal ready you can't make
repeated requests to the same thing well
you can change the timeframe commentary
that would be different but you have
absolutely everything difficult script
that there is a specific site you can go
to you find a list of all you have
parsed out maybe hope you care about
isn't unreasonable ie is going to exceed
the 18 hours but even in that instance
they have to do some sort of assessment
of the data to begin with and as I said
you can segment that's doing to promote
leadership what you see this now it uses
a dignity over to know everything should
be rejected by that but are you gonna
categorize something as an using
specific no any individual police force
might be able to work like this is
suspicious and again I said to the fifty
one individual once right so it has to
be each request sending individual body
then as a result each individual body
but have to independently a ten percent
there's a pattern here I go hang on the
minute that seems like it's scripted I'm
not gonna answer my question that seems
to be something that's all the other job
description of the people you're
assessing figure information request but
do you know the skills we have this
wonderful but this still has to happen
fifty one individual titles and I only
did the police again however many you
know that you find out hundreds symbol
there's missing Cuban style so what
things in the could because you live in
for similarities requests worst email or
IP the use of a template I reputation of
certain key text time interval between
submissions this is essentially spot
alright but what there is no spinal
filter or work the site it's a person
sitting there going I think this was in
fact it's father stole the thing
indicates of people number
now why would somebody do this in Paris
why does anybody do anything with you
that will main control things or just to
see if it works
you can also different activism
important remember is that this will go
to anyone anywhere in order to you don't
have to be a member to you can't reach
have to say something to you can doesn't
for this will give them the answer
someone in wherever you want just
constantly have the FOI request system
with garbage stuff to assess the whole
thing not consumes you can actual
resources can theory depends it's
entirely up to you how many you say
whatever it sounds so if there you can
do all these things like a new trend
against it so we have a net boy system
that's intentional authenticated the
whole point that's in lecture that for
whatever they wanted already keep it
going with a chat or one most way to
talk about very long this appears to be
a better access to data but any defense
rates is more near rooftop
so essentially let's talk about these in
any great detail essentially have the
current system which is probably easiest
access you can imagine right well
actually just making everything look
like all the time
this is the easiest way to do not
anything other than that to get to be
more secure without additional cost
Howell actually will make more attack
but more difficult access so if we talk
about making requests to Anthony has one
thing detection software essential six
five of the second and then we've got
central organization as laughable so
companies what you could do is make to
something as simple as P expect right
like you could generate multiple
character constants and make more
difficult today we do still do it moving
at harbors or you tiny unofficially
Anthony like many times whenever you're
looking into the government systems you
kind of actually go in that and
authenticate using here whenever you
want to pass what you essentially gonna
on this idea in that when you can make
it with that not already existed
something could be implemented however
that's gonna cost money nothing costs
nothing in fact
or they call so ridiculous in our family
in order to do that we also request you
can also require a response before the
request in actions again you can still
script that before you so applying
counseling help more spa the terms of
whether or not we're going to pick that
logic and it's at some level of the
national level depends who you get to
then finally the sample at my request
office which is probably the best way to
do there are actually general generally
benefits did to me as a public
requesting information for this as well
so the idea would be that you couldn't
be a central fYI request system to be
essentially a triage step this tree I
person would look at of metal that's in
suspicious ie
we both response filter worth it was
passive it was not perfectly well
trained to spot these things plus it
actually gives you the benefit of being
able to say please house all the
political stories this question rather
than medium it will dig around will find
fifty one individual email addresses
some of which were definitely role in
the internet and then the Senate each of
them communicate with individually you
can actually just send one class that
this man guys that would be better for
me as a person if you request it also
protected but of course cost that system
essentially that's the end but a couple
of just the primary benefit of this talk
in general is to demonstrate that
actually you could use free permission
request to find the useful information
myself security right I asked a couple
questions whatever you think is worth
qualifying might development just went
out the community the class system would
require our right there in the public in
the business public a small medium
businesses are indeed reporting crimes
would look at this type of race again
that was a theory then I propose it's
smart it's definitely happening you've
got twice as much from the public that's
businesses based on this time here can
speak your statistical the technical
questions consult you know appear to
have been very well resourced and to
investigate cyber crimes a zero people
with specific cybercrime knowledge which
was something was not yet in the
strategy so that it as a result you can
do resource consumption attack against
them you have to put in your mind is
exactly why so the way to do this thing
but remember as well person does not
have to be you can remember the UK
presently you get some used to be in
somebody whatever they want to just as a
final addendum is actually finished so
that time expiry trying to get 2011
finished and coincidentally took place
in 16 others look you've got the similar
you probably results reporting my
Wellington there the significant
progress with toward reaching these
goals they say this is the screenshot
you'll notice certain wasn't local and
we were actively building our cyber
schools knowledge I'd like to find out
how many experimenter specials over and
that's essentially it
[Applause]
considering instead few years like you
know it moves on you concern it will
have in yeah I think they'll be
interesting I think just something that
all began and see anything else it's
very different would be worthwhile like
to be such an expert anything how do we
gonna find the time I promise we'll be
able to it's probably just attending it
[Music]
[Applause]