all right
good morning offensive con my name is
Jason I'm a security consultant at MWR
and what I want to be showing you guys
today is how we can files 3d
acceleration and eventually opponent
with some self-imposed restrictions to
make it a bit more interesting the idea
with this talk is to cover a lot of
bread so I'm asking you to really stick
by me with us so first off what is 3d
acceleration as it pertains to
VirtualBox
so VirtualBox makes use of technology
called chromium which is essentially
just an abstraction layer over OpenGL
and this accepts chromium messages which
they which define graphical operations
and it's within the parsing of those
messages that the actual bug set now
chromium can be can be used as a
standalone
TCP server or as in the case of
VirtualBox and embedded software
components now guest additions can
essentially be thought of as a
collection of services where 3d
acceleration is just one of them and the
way that you interact with these
services is by speaking the HT cm
protocol and this protocol can be spoken
to the hosts from the guest via device
files within the guest and this is all
accessible to unprivileged guest users
now one of the main interface is exposed
by these services is a function called
SV sequel so you'll find them in all of
these various guest additions services
and they essentially receive the HT same
messages take out some parameters and do
something with that so a chromium
message will be one of these parameters
so quick look at how we can fuzz
VirtualBox or 3d acceleration
essentially there's not a whole lot that
we need to actually interact with
chromium if we want to basically we just
need to initialize the chromium server
which there's a convenient export for
from the shed see our OpenGL module we
need to be able to connect disconnect
and send chromium messages to basically
simulate everything that a guest
operating system would do when
interacting with 3d acceleration now
looking at what I Chrome
message looks like how to craft these on
the Left you'll see to chromium messages
and one of the biggest things here in
this message is the CR message ah Kurds
message type so this prompt chromium to
execute an opcode handler so you specify
op codes in this message and there's a
one-to-one relationship between opcodes
and opcode handlers so CR unpack or CR
unpack extend will receive these op
codes and call the appropriate occurred
handler which will read some input from
our chromium message and pass that on to
the relevant dispatch method now all of
the bugs associated with chromium are
usually within these awkward handlers or
within these dispatch methods now
basically we're generating a bunch of
input because we want to first read the
acceleration so the main things to take
away from figuring out what to do with
that input basically adjusting as some
of the input making sure that our
message type is set to see our message
up codes basically it can get quite
complex when specifying multiple up
codes so maybe you're interested in
doing something more one dimensional so
fixing the number of occurs to one when
looking at your awkward so three and
four we want to make sure that there was
in range specifying a dead opcode
doesn't mean anything to us we won't be
hitting any code paths and if you want
to get really smart with this you can
look at the input parameters or input
values that you're giving for that
opcode maybe look at the data types
there's a relatively easy to follow
convention within opcode handlers for
what various the various values or
variables are used for and eventually
what we're going to do is we're taking
that chromium message and sticking it
into client rights and maybe the bugs
fall out so ideas regarding a developing
a puzzle like this take into
consideration that there's little more
than 550 op codes which i think is a
relatively big attack surface looking at
it from an unpublished guest perspective
and essentially what all of these
messages do is they manipulate the state
of chromium all right up to this point
most of the bugs that have been
identified have been one-dimensional so
single op code results in an awkward
hand
dispatch method being called bug gets
triggered but I do think that some of
these are dying while these are dying
out fairly quickly and we're definitely
going to have to start thinking about
some of the more intricate things about
the state of the chromium server for
example bug that still needs to be
mitigated basically was this convoluted
process of forcing chromium into the
state to trust the Pointer supplies by a
guest operating system so that happens
too now I'm a fairly novice
vulnerability researcher in terms of
fuzzing so for me I just kind of used
standard AFL to see where that takes me
and what I can say is that
initialization of the chromium server
takes a whole lot of time 65
milliseconds which I mean if you're
working with in-memory fuzzing this this
problem can be overcome but despite that
if you're really interested in building
an AFL phaser for 3d acceleration it's
as simple as pointing configure two AFL
GCC and AFL C++ so something I will say
is that definitely do this comment out
RTO log create in that source file so
chromium on upon initialization creates
a log file rights to it so if you're
fuzzing 3d acceleration you're going to
fill up your disk space or you can be
this idiot and create a bunch of cron
jobs that run every 20 seconds to clear
a folder it took me a while to find out
that this was the problem all right
so debugging VirtualBox is very tedious
there's this weird thing where if you if
you're focused on a virtual machine and
you hit a breakpoint the keyboard and
the clipboard just break and that really
sucks testing production also sucks
because of debugger checks so VirtualBox
just says no and I wanted to come and
get around this to really facilitate
making my my exploit efforts a lot
easier and the idea that I came up with
is basically creating this little
standard interface that consists of
connecting disconnecting and making HDC
M calls now how that how that interface
is implemented on the host that library
well that library will load the relevant
dll's
read the export results or get the
export myth exported methods and use SV
sequel to simulate connecting
disconnecting and making HTC M calls now
SVC call isn't exported but if you
initialize chromium at a higher level
you can kind of smuggle out that pointer
which is great you can do this for debug
and prod and on the guest operating
system this interface is essentially
implemented as a set of driver calls
right and what I ended up with after
making this is basically this workflow I
exploit the debug libraries I mean I can
debug the symbols that's great
then I update my exploit to target the
prod libraries just update offsets I can
still debug this because I'm not running
in VirtualBox and then I turn my VM on
for the first time we just sped up the
process quite a lot now a lot of the
code related to the until this library
that I wrote and also some example
fuzzing harnesses I'm planning to
release all of these on github so soon
TM alright so burning VirtualBox and
looking at these two bugs now throughout
the next few sections it's going to be a
couple of interesting exploit primitives
that we can use to facilitate our
exploitation for example we've got this
amazing feature in chromium where we can
buffer chromium messages and we can make
those buffers arbitrary sizes meaning
that we can perform arbitrary size
allocations we can write to those
allocations to a byte of granularity and
when we execute those buffers as
chromium messages they get freed all
right so we can free and allocate and
all of these buffered chromium messages
are backed by an object which I'll refer
to as a service buffer and service
buffer objects hold a pointer to the
chromium message through P dot o now
more in if this is research that you're
looking into you're bound to come across
methods like SVC get buffer and SVC call
to better understand how these buffers
are used so let's first look at our info
leak so 20 19 25 25
I reported this but Nicholas
unfortunately beat me to it this is an
out of bounds read in CR unpack extent
get a drop location and
you can see on the right is top right as
I chromium message and we have this
value that we're providing called packet
length all right packet length in it the
awkward handler is used in set return
pointer and set right back pointer in
those macros now what does matter is
translate to use a call to CRM copy
which is just a mem copy wrapper and the
offset is added to see our unpacked Auto
which is a pointer to our chromium
message and at this specific instance si
are in fact Auto is actually pointing to
packet length now the destination for
this copy is our two global variables in
this case return pointer and right back
pointer and after the message is
executed return point and right back
pointer will be returned to the guest
basically meaning if we can make packet
lengths very very large we can read into
adjoining memory and in total because
all both of these two variables or
objects are 16 to 8 bytes in size each
we get to leak 16 bytes now the target
for our info leaker is AC our client
object which represents an active
connection to chromium and one of its
members called current context info is
initialized to point to see our server
dot main context info which is which is
a global variable Co serve as a global
variable so if we can leak that object
or leak that member in that object we've
got a pointer in the shade CR OpenGL
module so subtract some offset and we've
defeated a SLR so calculating our value
for packet length is fairly
straightforward we're targeting see our
current objects we can abuse our ability
to either make arbitrary size
allocations to target that low
fragmentation heat pocket and the idea
is to make numerous connections so
you're kind of limited to 64 but that's
not a problem and then we're just going
to keep on sending our malicious message
if it doesn't work the first time just
mash X and the way we're going to
calculate this is fairly straightforward
start of our chromium message to start
off see our client that's m18 hex
into our chromium message
the tacit length is 10x and into the CR
client object that's 20x do the maths we
see packet length is a 3-1 hex so how do
we execute code or what what will be our
code execution primitive so 20 1925 48
this was and well this was an integer
overflow and that one you can actually
see the patch that was introduced
earlier so that entire check that didn't
exist which was which is very convenient
at the time and two we can see that
messagelen' gets calculated by taking a
size of RP which is 38 hex and then
adding multiplication between Whitesboro
and height both attacker controlled from
the VM and the three message Len is used
to allocate memory so basically if we
can craft bytes per row and height in
such a way that the allocation is
smaller than the object size we can
write into adjoining memory when the
object gets initialized and something
that you'll see soon is that the object
gets entirely initialized by values
obtained from the guest operating system
so quickly looking at our restrictions
Whitesboro is not supposed to be it's
supposed to be smaller than 1/8 of
unsigned int max greater than 0 height
smaller than 8 of an unsigned int so
let's choose messagelen' to be 20 hex
meaning that will be writing 1/8 x in
two adjoining memory if this works and
just choose an arbitrary value well for
height as 8 and we can see that the math
says it we've kind of meeting or the
criteria that the patch forces us so our
target object for this is that same is
the service buffer object surprise
surprise we've already did the math for
targeting 20 hex allocations and and the
reason we're interested in this object
is because it can give us out of bounds
and arbitrary right primitives if
targeted correctly now the interesting
members of this object is an ID that is
a reference that we hold to that object
the size basically when you update
this buffer the sizes Mei is used to
make sure that you're not riding out of
bounds so if we can somehow increase
that to some massive size we can write
in to adjoining memory and obviously if
you can somehow control P dot L then we
can update into arbitrary memory
locations so just to give you an idea of
what we're working with on the Left we
have like a hypothetical empty piece of
memory followed by a service buffer and
on the right is not really that
important just to give you an idea of
everything that gets initialized with
our P now everything inside that
initialization is controlled by us
except for the message type or the
header type and after initial
initialization it looks something like
this all right what we've done is we've
overflowed this the integer we've
allocated less memory than it's
necessary for the object and skip pixels
Roland's
format and type all corrupt the heap
header of our service buffer that we're
targeting and pixels which is an 8 byte
value will corrupt you ID and UI size
okay and this is great because we
corrupted UID with dead beef so that's
something that we know we can use that
as a reference to reference that buffer
and we've created to make UI science be
largest that it can be and that
basically means that the service bar for
a service buffer within our new buffer
chromium message range we can write into
it so what we can do is carefully write
into various offsets that we've
calculated that will typically be the
place where a UID would be so we can
keep on doing that and maybe just write
like beef dead and we can keep on
checking that so we can do all right we
can check if that buffer exists now
eventually what will happen is if we
manage to trick get one of these then we
can fully control it by now we have a we
right into its ID we override P dot R we
have an arbitrary write primitive so
this is typically what our configuration
looks like at this stage we have a
partial control control buffer which is
sufficient to control another buffer
fully control another
so we modify partial buffer to write
into SVC full we adjust SVC fulls UI
size and P dot through our partially
controlled service buffer and then
finally what we can do is we can write
well or update as we see full - to write
whatever we want wherever we want now
we've got two bugs let's see what we can
do in terms of exploiting them now we
have we have defeated SLR with our first
bug and we've obtained an arbitrary
write primitive I want to try two things
because virtualbox uses very old
compiler technology it's it's very
boring just trying to do well it's very
boring just trying to bypass some of the
exploit mitigations because it has a
lack thereof now we want to try and
break up with our shellcode and we want
to avoid requiring any kernel32 offsets
and for this we're going to need an
arbitrary read and a command execution
primitive so in this scenario we're
attacking a Windows host from a Linux
guest now what I mean by shellcode list
is that we can target the actual
dispatch table that gets called an
opcode Hendricks now the signatures for
the functions in that dispatch table
look awfully similar to the things we
want to end up executing anyway so in
this case I'm showing you an example of
one exec how that might typically look
is we're sending a window create extend
opcode we've overwritten ER unpacked
dispatch window create at points to when
exact now and in our message we can
specify parameters that will get passed
out in the OP code handler and
eventually passed to window create which
is now pointing to an exec and we can
use this for quite a few things as well
see now next we want to create an
arbitrary primitive using the shell
catalyst technique for this we're going
to target a CR client object again just
because there's a really nice member
called con which is a CR connection
object so certain chromium messages
after execution the responses are
buffered and the response is pointed to
by PS buffer and C and the size they're
all kept in CB host puffer within
Khanh again so if we can leaks your
connection or con with an SEO client
object and use our arbitrary right
against that we can basically fake
buffered responses eventually leading to
reading arbitrary memory now a really
interesting function that we're going to
use for this is server try and get so
this method takes a client ID and a
pointer or second order pointer for this
and it basically retrieves a pointer
associated with the client ID that was
provided and takes that pointer and
write it to pp client now what makes
this interesting is that when chromium
messages get modified in transit so
during that whole transaction you will
get the modified version so if we can
somehow have PP client point to our
chromium message then we can leak
arbitrary C our client objects the way
we're going to do this is by attacking
the delete fences env function in the
dispatch table it accepts an integer and
it sets a pointer an intent pointer
which kind of looks like a CR client
object to me so what we can do is we can
now specify a client ID and in the in
the opcode handler they're basically
going to they're basically going to use
data pointer to retrieve a pointer to
our chromium message so when the lead
princess gets called
we're actually passing server client get
our client ID and a pointer to our
message after execution it gets returned
back to us now what we're going to do
now to actually leak a connection or the
current member here is we're going to
fake a chromium message and basically
have it stretch over across ACR client
object
the idea is to point our fully
controlled service buffer to a couple of
allocations before the targets your
client object and then just write an
awkward message to it and have it
execute and we'll receive the content of
that message which will contain the
entirety of that CR client object
containing pointer to the CR connection
object now there's a little problem of
this and that it's not as elegant
because we don't know what that memory
is used for
just right to it so my idea here is to
get an initial see our client objects
address make a bunch of see our client
allocations get add and then get those
addresses and kind of like work until I
have an address that's within for
allocations and disconnect that client
and then point our chromium message
buffer to that client we know that that
memory is free now and we're just going
to point it there so our full a fully
controlled service buffer will then
point to that earlier a location you my
size will extends to pass this your
client object and then we have and then
we write our NOC code message execute we
now have a pointer to a CR connection
object now there's a couple of drawbacks
to this as we see full when the message
get executed P daughter gets freed
meaning that we've got a double free
condition we've disconnected to this
your client object and then executed a
chromium message but for for that
purpose I basically just spray the heap
again and hope for the best we also lose
our arbitrary right because we kind of
like used SVC phone now and it will be
freed but the thing is we can basically
reuse our partial buffer to do this
exact same thing and regain our fully
controlled SVC buffer so using the
address of that CR connection object we
can now basically manipulate POS buffer
and CB host buffer as long as we never
disconnect that that client so we can
manipulate PS buffering CB s buffer to
now read arbitrary memory so as for a
command execution command execution
primitive there's this convenient
function called CR spawn it is within
the same module as CR mem copy which is
used by shirt's your opengl meaning that
just through our arbitrary read and
attacking the import address table will
eventually end up with a pointer to see
our spawn and this does on Windows it
does create process on other systems
that uses exec VP and we're going to use
bounce info CR in the dispatch table to
point to this function
now what this does is it basically
receives basically what's going to
happen here the CR spawn method bounce
info see R is going to accept some value
and it's going to be interpreted as a
pointer or it's good to give a pointer
to a chromium message to see our spawn
and see our spawn is going to
dereference that pointer as another
pointer so and then that is eventually
going to be our command line so that is
you create a CR client object
disconnected we're okay off the CR spawn
that memory is not going to get freed so
we'll just write all of our arguments to
that see our client old see our client
objects memory and then add that to our
chromium message and when we call this
dispatch method through they're using
the relevant op codes will be executing
OS commands so we managed to convert our
arbitrary write and info leak into an
arbitrary read through attacking the
dispatch table and creating fake service
buffers you obtain the address of CO
spawn using our arbitrary read and we
haven't executed shell code or used
kernel32 alright mandatory
[Music]
I'm hoping calc will spawn on the screen
all right I'd worked thinking about is
that I'm running it still so okay now
all right and any questions
I'm sorry
entirely depends on chromium s have you
tried this on other software this that
relies on chromium I was build upon
chromium so the thing is I only know 3d
acceleration in VirtualBox that makes
use of chromium but what I will say
something to take out of this is that a
lot of the stuff regarding fuzzing and
so on that carries over to other
components of VirtualBox itself so
because the other guest Edition services
exposed the same interfaces and there
might be a similar strategy that you can
actually take with the vise simulation
in VirtualBox but as for other products
that use chromium I'm not sure any more
questions
okay then I think that's it thank you
[Applause]