all right
hello everyone hear me we're good all
right can't really see any one cent but
I can see this yeah started about that I
flew in late last night and didn't
av-test so we exported this straight to
PowerPoint we'll see if it works but
yeah so I'm here today to talk about
fuzzing and I guess the last couple
years I've just kind of been exploring
how to take like this whole idea of
coverage guided fuzzing that was kind of
pioneered by AFL and just like coming
from a more auditing bug hunting
background like how can we use AFL kind
of augment that or live fuzzer you know
whatever kind of fuzzing engine and so
in this talk I'll start by going over a
little bit about what FL in the pleasure
are in case you don't know and then I'll
talk about something that I call the API
problem and how to address it with
fuzzing and then you know once you know
how to fuzz some kind of weird code and
it's not working how do you make
progress and try to get the bugs to come
out and then we'll look at once you have
a way of testing things well you know
how do you decide what to prioritize and
then I'll have a couple real-world
examples and then I was thinking of
doing some kind of like live demo at the
end of the but I guess I can't so you
know I killed 15 minutes anyways so
here's the bug hunting tower success and
it's kind of meaningless but I thought
you know it'd be kind of entertaining
but I guess when I look at you know the
tools you have available to look for
bugs as a researcher you can kind of
come at the same problem with different
ways and you might be able to find the
same bug in different ways and the idea
is just like looking at all the
different techniques you know how can we
combine them well to make finding bugs
as efficient as as painless as possible
and so the last couple years I've been
focusing on this table area
until recently there wasn't very good
static analysis tools available as far
as I'm you know having like a compiler
pass to LLVM or something is like very
heavyweight and it doesn't catch very
deep bugs but from what I've heard from
some other researchers is that this new
some old stuff is really good so I think
static analysis will be getting a lot
better soon but for now we'll focus in
on coverage credit fuzzing and kind of
how do we combine this with auditing so
just as some background information
about AFL and Lim fuzzer these are kind
of two of the more popular variants of a
specific fuzzing technique called
coverage credit fuzzing and the idea
here is you have something that you want
to fuzz you have some corpus of input
data and the way that you make progress
is by picking a random corpus input
doing a random mutation and feeding this
into the input program and you see if
new coverage was uncovered and if so you
keep this test case as a special one if
not you discard it so it's a very simple
idea but it just turns out that when you
do this very quickly it actually does a
great job at exploring code so you know
this has been around since like 2014 so
it's not really news but you know just a
little background so because I'll be
giving some kind of specific examples
with Lib Huzur I should go a little more
detail about that Lib buzzer is LLVM
projects version of coverage guided
fuzzing and this is essentially this
exact same design of keeping a corpus
and growing it with new inputs as they
find a new coverage but it doesn't do
any forking like AFL it just keeps all
these test cases in memory and it picks
one it tries to flip a bit and run it
through again and it just this kind of
self-contained feedback loop and then as
it's finding new coverage is writing
files out to disk you know this this
does really matter but just a little
detail but the important kind of
difference with lib fuzzer which i think
is important is that it's a little bit
more work to set up versus AFL but it
kind of forces you to interact with an
API and make sure that as you're fuzzing
in this loop in the same process that
you don't accumulate state so for that
reason you have to kind of have some
more awareness about the API or the API
you're interacting with and how to make
sure that you can clean up and reset to
original state and it I just found that
by playing with this I realized that
this tool kind of encourages you to
think about the API you're interacting
with and kind of it kind of brings this
kind of auditing mindset of like you're
looking into API how it works some of
the semantics of it and stuff and it
just you know once you get it working
the fuzzing seems to go a little bit
better so I'll talk a little bit about I
guess how to use this so it's actually
very simple there's basically two parts
there's the writing your fuzz target and
then there's how you actually build your
fuzzer and you know this is just
documentation so I won't spend too much
time but you know you just implement a
function that will do something
interesting with your code that you want
to fuzz given an input file string of
bytes and then you pass these special
flags to play and it will include the
fuzzer for you so this is like the most
recent way to do this it's very easy it
works on like Mac OS and Windows Linux
so it's pretty easy to extend any
project that can you can build with
claimed with this kind of fuzzing and so
as a simple example say you have some
image parsing API that has this same you
know takes the data and the size of the
data you know you would just do some
very trivial kind of integration here to
use your API and then you just build
with these flags and then run it and
starts buzzing and
sanitizer will print the bugs out for
you so you know this is okay this is a
really simple thing that like a lot of
people are already doing but how do we
find these like sandbox escapes with
like Network you know the some kind of
weird network interaction or some like
timing of packets or something like it
just seems like such a huge jump and so
like this is the problem I've been
exploring and it turns out it's actually
not too hard to deal with this and so
the issue here like I was just saying
you know basically when you have when
you're trying to attacks line coming
from the network I'd be CDMA you've all
these kind of weird tack surfaces that
are not just string parsers and you know
you want a way to basically expand the
scope of of these fuzzing campaigns to
kind of incorporate the type of
interaction that could actually happen
within a you know from kind of an
auditing perspective you think like oh
how can I interact with this API to
trigger a bug you know you kind of want
to have a way to fuzz that so you know
to boil it down basically when people
are using coverage guide fuzzing it
looks like they're always attacking
these things on the left and then what
we really want to do is be able to kind
of extend it to focus on fuzzing things
on the right and so if you can just
learn how to make this jump from fussing
some string parser thing to fuzzing an
API this actually opens up a tremendous
amount of attack surface and you know
for example like all of the Chrome
browser IPC for sandbox escaping so I
think like you know it's useful to kind
of explore how to do this so kind of the
existing ways that people deal with this
problem is through either generative
fuzzing or mutational fuzzing and a
traditional sense so what this means is
in the first case people might write it
like a Python script that will generate
some random IPC calls or
you know they might think well I don't
really know what to generate because it
won't really be a real interaction so
let me flip bits to try to you know
tease out any shallow bugs that might be
in a more legitimate interaction but
what's nice about coverage guided
fuzzing is it's doing this second thing
for you and it's you know essentially
helping you find the interesting kind of
interaction already so all you have to
do is be able to figure out a way to
interact with this API deterministically
so okay how does this look so I thought
about it and I thought okay well you
know we can you know ideally fuzz these
things you know with with generative
fuzzing you're not getting coverage
feedback and it's slow with bit flipping
mutations you know you're not getting
much coverage but you know there's no
reason we can't just combine these
things and you can just make a
generative coverage guide fuzzer so
that's kind of how this works so I think
it's pretty clear like that okay you can
write a generative buzzer in C++ and
then had this covered stuff and it
should work but how to kind of actually
do this in practice is where it's a
little interesting so I have talked you
know before about kind of the fuzzer I
was writing there's a couple open source
buzzers I put on the chrome repo to find
these hanboks escapes but like here's
kind of the truth about how they came
about so okay it's a little messed up
because of the PDF thing but basically
the the idea is before you're hooking
lib buzzer directly into this library
under test and now we're going to
introduce a little simple parser in
between we'll just make up kind of a
floor mat that represents an interaction
with an API and then interact with the
API so you know that sounds kind of
weird but it's actually really simple
so the idea here is you take your input
string of bytes and you wrap it with
some kind of object that lets you
consume the stream one chunk at a time
and then you just treat this stream of
bytes like this random number generator
and you just write a generative buzzer
but the insight here is that coverage
guided fuzzing can explore for you
because you're not just randomly
flipping a coin you're actually you know
taking this random data from the fuzzer
input so yep so and then you know
basically I noticed that the same kind
of pattern keeps appearing where you
just try to set up whatever kind of
objects you want to test in the C++ and
you try to set them up as randomly as
possible so if they have some
configuration options you just try to
think about like as an auditor you're
always thinking like okay how much of
this do I control this same kind of
insight comes into writing the fuzzer
so you know here's this very simple
example so let's say we have some kind
of database class that we want to fuzz
so you know this could be something in
like a web api like in JavaScript or you
know in the Dom or something or this
could be in the in the chrome sandbox
here from the renderer process this
could be something that's in a
hypervisor and you have some way of
hitting this API through some path and
you know the idea is like there's a text
service everywhere and you know when it
pulls down to it it's just they're just
C++ you know they're just some interface
just play with it and find the bugs so
the idea is essentially we take our
input string and we have this API and we
say okay well we know we can control any
of the arguments to the API so we just
take our input string and consume you
know a byte there and like in the
beginning of the switch and say okay
give me a random integer from zero zero
two inclusive and you know this is going
to give us which API to call and you
know then we just consume a little bit
more to get the arguments and you know
this is just kind of a really simple
thing but incredibly no one is doing
this and you know it's just kind of
milking this for like a year or two on
the chrome sandbox and so if you look at
this you know this is like actually a
very familiar pattern this is what
everyone does for generative fuzzing as
I said the insight here is you're just
finding a way to make that deterministic
by using this kind of helper object and
so yep so what's the key thing here
that's making this interesting is
because things are deterministic and you
know we're calling any API and you order
if there's any if there's anything weird
that happens after a chain of calls the
coverage guided fuzzing will tend to
uncover that and funnily enough this
exact API was what I you know I found a
couple bugs in Chrome's network
component in the HTTP caching layer and
it turned out that these were two
critical bugs that were like user after
freeze where you didn't need JavaScript
code execution it was just outside the
sandbox from JavaScript so that was just
because I saw okay here's this API like
deep in the sandbox somewhere it turns
out I actually can hit it all the way up
from the render from JavaScript without
having RC either and it just turned out
that this when I looked at
implementation was really complex they
had some kind of cache eviction thing
going on so when the database got too
big I think I might have yeah so I kind
of like allude to that here but I
started this database with a random size
and it turned out that by default the
database was like 2 gigabytes in size
but I made a 512 byte database and then
I was just testing this cash eviction
stuff very thoroughly and found these
bugs so the kind of the point I want to
get across is like how simple this stuff
is how under-applied it is and how
important some of the bugs are that we
can find a fit so yep that's it you know
we picked API call stuff and then wait
for the bugs
well not really right so you know this
looks good on paper but in reality
things almost always fall apart
instantly and so you know generally like
you forget to call some API you've got
some setup wrong something's hard to
reach because the fuzzer just bit
flipping is not smart enough to get you
there you were not a memory and the
buzzer dies you know like things go
wrong all the time so the idea is we
need this process that not only you know
starts from this idea but actually lets
us kind of get to very thorough coverage
and so this is this kind of next part
how do we deal with failure so I keep
thinking about this it might be kind of
crazy doing this too much but after
looking at these no coverage reports of
fuzzing a lot I got this sense that like
you start at the top of this API and
it's like you're pouring water over and
you just see like where the water you
know flows to like coverage gutted
fuzzing will explore very quickly like
as far as a can naturally go and then it
will just get to a point where it's like
you know one in a billion chance of
making progress and so the idea is
you're like okay let's just look at
where it's getting stuck at some point
where it's hard to make progress and how
do we undo it by hand and so you know I
kind of got ahead of myself here but you
know basically just setting up fuzzing
in this kind of like I basically used to
think okay well I'll make some huge
fuzzy idea like write it all on paper
have this huge design and it'll work and
it never did and it quickly learned that
doing very small rapid experiments was
the right way and so yeah and like you
know just a tidbit so I think the the
the metric that I focused on most was
just how many lines of coverage was I
getting and I've been pretty surprised
to find but like you know out of all the
chrome sandbox escapes I found which
it's on the order about ten or so these
are were all found with only about a
quarter of the code that I was even
trying to cover covered so you know
there's probably still bugs there I just
got bored and moved on but yeah so
there's gonna be more for you guys and
you know this kind of what I'm trying to
encourage you to do so here's the meta
you want to use this thing called claim
coverage basically I've been using this
like the last month or so and it's
really great and been helping me a lot
on some weird projects like xnu
which I'll get to but the idea here is
you get these yep you get these reports
where you have hit counts per line for
your current corpus and then you try to
cover as much as you can obviously but
as uniformly as possible so here is
something I took straight from Chrome's
like unit test coverage thing so they're
using claim coverage reports and you can
see that in the unit test they're
hitting you know some function you know
eight thousand times but then they
actually only have one test case
covering one iteration of this loop and
so when you see this just from a unit
test perspective this already looks
suspicious I don't think that there's a
book here or anything but essentially
you'll realize that you know just
coverage is I mean coverage is enough
but looking a little bit deeper at line
counts and trying to think about how to
structure your fuzzer so that you're
hitting things uniformly kind of at
random
like that's where you know you'll get
bugs quickly so okay so now you know
it's pretty simple still you know we use
this thing called claim coverage we just
build with some flags and it's in the
docs we have some HTML report and now
how do we move forward so there's
basically three ways to deal with
coverage gaps and they all have
trade-offs Argus there's four but
basically you can either for example
here this is not a perfect example but
you could like let's say this was a you
know md5 track or something or you know
you have some other unlikely condition
happening you can add a patch right here
into code under test itself to kind of
get further and so the problem here is
you know you might introduce a bug or
hide one that's there but in practice
this is just like a very useful tool to
make progress quickly and I actually did
use it for sandbox escape which I'll
show later the second thing we can do is
try to edit that top level function
that's interacting with the API and this
is the best way because it's completely
sound so any modification you make there
as long as you're not doing something
weird with API that is somehow
impossible you know your test cases will
be you know accurately reflect what you
can do and you know you won't have fake
bugs introduced but the problem with
this is it's actually very
labor-intensive sometimes to actually
make these changes and then the third
way is to add a test case directly to
reach something which I personally never
do because that's just so much work but
you know if you're looking at like a PNG
parser or something that's that's
relevant but for a custom API fuzzer
we're kind of constantly iterating it's
not worth the time investment
and then I guess the last way is say
you're covering things fine but there's
just too much to cover one thing you can
do is knock things out and this sounds
kind of weird but you know coverage
guide advising doesn't know what to look
for it just goes for everything so
there's a kind of an auditing thing but
if you think like okay that was probably
a bug over here oh there's like three
distinct interesting things happening if
you can help make sure that you're
fuzzing these things independently this
is another way that yeah you can improve
the performance so I guess I kind of
already covered this but basically the
two main ways that I do this are by
hacking the code under test or by
changing the harness and so usually I
will edit the code under test first just
to make progress quickly and then later
revert it or if there's a bug try to get
rid of the hack but then keep the bug
intact and so yep that's pretty much it
and so there's one kind of other trick
which is if you're finding that your
fuzzer is slow or you're hitting some
bosses whatever you know it makes sense
to just kind of patch around things that
are boring so like say say you you find
some malloc that will now look like I've
controlled you enter something so you
keep allocating like four gigabytes you
know you don't really want to do this
you want to just like oftentimes I'll
add actually more constraints in the
code under test so that if I might try
to parse something that's too big I just
bail out early and this kind of keeps
things moving really quickly and you
know just I didn't know these things all
sound like trivial tricks but it's just
like they've helped me so much that I
feel like it's worth mentioning so
what's the extension from this stream
based buzzer so say we have this kind of
stream based buzzer that is working
really well and we want to go to kind of
the next level well
there's a thing called protobuf based
api fuzzing so I've talked about this
before but yeah I'll go over that again
just recycle this talk and you know
again this looks all messed out but the
idea is rather than making this byte
based parser which the fuzzing engine
doesn't know how to deal with you know
so we're doing this kind of stream based
thing you're not making like the the
fuzzer still has to go through your
little parser so even if it's simple
it's still doing that extra work and it
doesn't know really what to mutate and
so you lose some performance and this
idea of protobuf mutaters is if we
actually write down a simple grammar for
you know that we kind of implicitly
defined when we wrote that initial
stream based buzzer and then we hook
this into the fuzzing engine then it can
understand oh this is the grammar for
this thing that we're fuzzing and so
we'll make mutations on the tree based
level and so because we're not fuzzing
file parsers we're fuzzing an API
there's no sense in finding bugs in that
partial that we wrote so this is a huge
benefit and so yeah basically the
advantage here is you get much more
performance in terms of mutations if you
extend your your harness to cover more
api's for example your existing corpus
will be backwards compatible so you'll
just start introducing new new api's but
the old ones will still be called
correctly and you know it's just kind of
better performance but the trade-off is
protobuf is kind of annoying to deal
with for one-off
fuzzing projects it's kind of not worth
the effort and it's very easy to kind of
pepper these byte stream things all over
the place rather than just writing a
spec and like you know plumbing that all
the way through somewhere and so and
yeah not to mention part of buff it's
like generating some code Lincoln and
stuff and it's just kind of a hassle but
when they're at the point where you're
kind of finding bugs and you're
like ready to do better it makes sense
to introduce it so now we have kind of
the two parts to implement protobuf
specification and the C++ glue that's
linking your you know how do we give in
one instance of this kind of grammar
that was generated how do we call the
api's so here's an example for this
database thing we were just looking at
and I've added another evict command
just for fun but the idea here is we
have this high-level top a node in our
tree called a fuzz session and what do
we want to do in this fuzz session well
we need to define the size of the
database and then we also want to
repeatedly call a bunch of commands and
then what does it command well it's one
of one of these API is what is one of
these API message types well we get to
the bottom and we see okay you know add
is adding a key and a value and we'll
just put those literal types there and
then evict for example it doesn't take
any arguments so you know it's just kind
of a void type but you can see here how
that if the this part above mutator is
this mutator that knows how to take one
of these specifications and it knows how
to mutate in 32s the same way that live
fuzzer already does but it also
understands that okay we have the
sequence of commands and let's inject an
update somewhere with valid key and
value rather than kind of just blindly
figuring out how to fuzz this with a
stream so here's how this actually looks
you know this is just kind of how you
use protobuf but it'll generate this
header file file for you and those
parser and stuff so you know you can
Google how to do this not worth talking
about but the interesting part here is
this LVM fuzzer input that used to take
in a data in a size now takes this kind
of root node type called a session so we
put the session there and live
we'll see that and it says oh okay I
realize that you're trying to fuzz this
specific type and so then it will
recursively kind of fuzz the you know
parts of this tree and then we just call
into these different you know functions
like we did before but we're parsing it
out of the protobuf so you know that's
just kind of like the exact thing that
I'm doing not too interesting maybe but
you know that's just like kind of where
coverage guide fuzzing is today and so
that's that's useful but you know like I
said I want to kind of really emphasize
what is it that you actually do in
practice you know when you sit down
you're like okay I'm just gonna fuzz
this thing like what is what does it
look like well so you just start by
taking whatever C or C++ files that are
interesting you try to keep as few as
possible and make this into a
self-contained library then yeah you
make this you know consumable byte
stream fuzzer and then you kind of play
with it until your coverage is looking
really good and stuff and then at a
certain point you decide either I'm
finding bugs or I'm not or I need better
mutations or something and you just kind
of play it by ear and figure out you
know up front you invest a little bit of
time and then you figure out like should
I abandon this or should I keep going
and basically being able to realize when
things are going badly and bailing for
the right reasons is important so this
is really my stuff this is the most
complicated one but you know this is
kind of my my approach at a very high
level is basically just what I do when I
sit down to test something and so we
start at that top left corner and we say
okay let's attack the app cache let's
attack this database thing you know
whatever it looks interesting
you know container right this byte
stream fuzzer then play with that for a
couple days and then keep inspecting
this coverage report
and then you know once things start to
look promising then you port it to
protobuf mutator if not you move on and
you know you just kind of have this loop
going on and so yeah this is pretty much
it it works really well and I think this
is an underutilized approach so even
though it's somewhat simple it's still
effective so now that we've seen this
approach let's talk about how I found
this bug last year that was used for an
actual full train exploit and so this
was like a two bug chain I didn't find
the RCE but I found the sandbox bug and
actually right after this talk Nicolas
will be discussing like how the exploit
worked but what I haven't ever talked
about is like literally what happens in
terms of I found this thing you know if
shown like the final product and another
talk but you know here's how it fit into
this process that I had whoops okay yeah
what is it doesn't matter all that
matters is that it's a packable right so
this is pretty corrupted I'm sorry about
this but you know the idea is this is
the interface that's just in the chrome
source repo and I was hoping to kind of
show you how I found this but you know
my laptop isn't here
but you know basically this is the API
we're attacking like before it's you
know like six things they take these
primitive types as like a host which is
an int you know like the stuff isn't
rocket science you know then if you
click around it's not hard to find that
here's the actual C++ implementation
that could be vulnerable and would let
us escape the sandbox if we found a bug
in it and so we say okay now that we
know where the code is we saw that it
was part of the attack service let's
compile a tiny library containing this
object and anything it depends on and
try to play with it in and see what
happens and so yeah so stage one is just
calling the API so I just did the same
thing I described in the beginning I
just made this byte stream thing and I
just called api's
in any order you know I instantiate
AddThis object the appcache dispatcher
host and I think like I even put a null
pointer in for the service because like
I'm just lazy you know let's just see
what happens where does it fall over and
then so you know you start to fuzz it
and you see oh there's an old ER f okay
it's trying to use the service somewhere
and then I'll by hand to implement like
piece by piece the functionality that I
don't really care about but will let me
make progress on this thing that's
actually interesting so yeah so
basically you know I just played with a
little bit and then suddenly there was
some crash like it was trying to make a
network request and died and through
auditing and looking at previous bug
reports I understood that weird things
happening with network request timings
was what I was actually looking for so I
was pretty excited and I said okay you
know like I'm done for this week you
know you know took a day off whatever I
was like okay we're ready to come back
at it deal with this network problem so
basically then like I said with this
null pointer thing just plugged in some
fake network object it turns out that
there actually was one already in the
Chrome sources that could be used for
testing so I you know let some requests
happen using fuzzed input bites
where basically whenever a request would
come in I would just return some of that
input byte stream just as my you know
server response but then the problem
with that is you know do you want the
fuzzer to like generate a full HTTP
interaction for you like this isn't
really going to work especially not on
like my own fork or machine yeah so I
realized that you know I could write
this whole thing that would generate all
these valid HTTP sessions and make it
grammar something like this is what I
thought I should have done when I
started but what I know now is that you
just hack things in so let me go way
back actually this might be annoying but
oh man it's actually really far but
I'm sorry yeah this thing right so this
isn't the exact snippet of code but it's
the same concept so this sounds crazy
but what I did was like I just exposed
this byte stream thing within the
library like at this point like line 153
I made sure that I could you know use
some global pointer and like get a hold
of this this input stream of bytes and
what I did was I just randomly I didn't
even do any parsing at all I just
randomly created these app cache
manifests which was this thing that was
it was trying to parse through HTTP and
I just said let's skip all this HTTP
interaction and just like create these
like so for example yeah actually this
is kind of the same the right code so I
would just like say okay
picking it from 0 to 4 and then decide
ok going to loop and then add like three
or four random entries into this
database and just from looking the code
is pretty obvious that this is something
I could do if I wanted to and then if a
bug comes out of this you know I'll be
really motivated to go and actually make
the real input to reach it so I did this
kind of everywhere and I ended up having
this kind of fake header object so
whenever would try to read HTTP headers
it would you know it's I made this kind
of fake HTTP header API that reads from
the stream input so you would say like
okay did they give us a cache header and
then I would just flip a coin and take
it from the fuzzed input and say yes or
no like yes there is a cache header
again I would try to read from it and
then you know I just kind of really
hacked through this thing to death but
then at the same time I was knowing like
okay all this stuff that I'm hacking
around like I could get it to work if I
had to later and so I'll go all the way
back to where it was let's see here yes
okay yeah and so basically playing with
caching and these HTTP responses and
like
reading stuff that it was trying to
parse out of this network request was
enough to find a bug somewhere and so I
had like a couple fake bugs where I
would like try to revert my hacks and
reach it and it turned out it wasn't
possible but in the end I finally did
get this one bug where it was real and
slowly and surely I would just kind of
revert a hack and add support at the
harness level and you know finally I had
this thing where I had an untouched
library and I was triggering a bug and
that was the thing that I submitted to
the chrome repo so if you saw that and
thought like oh you know how did you
think like how to you know weave this
needle through the code like yeah I had
no idea it just did it like based on
what ended up finding the bug when I
hacked around so yeah so basically at
the end I was like okay I have this
stream based buzzer that will find a bug
let me port it to protobuf so that it's
easier to kind of minimize the test case
I can play with this more and do better
mutations now that I know this is a
buggy pattern and so yeah and then at
this point you know I had this one input
that would trigger the bug and then
created a second build of Chrome and you
know added a bunch of prints and just
kind of by hand reconstructed what was
going on with the Python server and then
that was the you know use after free PSC
that we started from and then Nicolas
will talk about in five minutes
so yeah so you know this is like a
really important bug there's not too
many people finding sandbox escapes from
what I can tell it's kind of secretive
industry but you know I would say that
you know this isn't something that's
happening very frequently like around
the world maybe every couple weeks or a
month someone's finding one of these
things but the important thing is that
this actually wasn't a lot of time to do
and it wasn't actually a lot of insane
ingenuity or effort or anything it was
just like a process that is novel and
you know leverages this great coverage
guiding technique but in some really
weird way that no one had done before
and it was able to uncover a bug and so
the reason I'm kind of emphasizing this
is I think like among all of the
techniques that that people can use to
find bugs like this is one of the really
one of the easier ones
it's about as hard as writing unit tests
so like this is like that interns get
assigned to do when they join a company
and yet here it's like finding sandbox
escapes and I just think like you know
they should bridge this gap either the
bug should go away or you know more
people should be able to do it so you
know I encourage you guys to try this
technique so I only have three minutes
but let's talk about xnu real quick so
this is my new project I've just started
and same exact technique very different
attack surface and I kind of keep trying
to discover like okay how far can I take
this thing and where does it stop
working and so I wanted to test xnu
networking and so what I did was I just
took the whole network subsystem of xnu
compiled it with the instrumentation for
like live buzzer and stuff and then
tried to make this little self-contained
library in user space and then of course
when you go to link it there's all the
rest of the kernel missing and so it
says like you know a thousand functions
are missing so what I did was I just
stubbed all those functions out to
assert false and just crash when I
called them so that way I could start
running and working with this thing and
as it would hit code that it actually
needed to work I would either put that
real implementation in or stub it out or
put my own mocked implementation or
whatever but basically I had this kind
of very quickly had to set up to start
fuzzing and so what I realized was once
I saw which API is needed to be
implemented this kind of boiled down to
you know obviously memory allocation so
Zi look M cache
not look like these all these api's are
in the kernel so I implemented all of
them by just kind of translating them to
the user space equivalent so for Malik
that's trivial you just call forward it
to the user space Malik but for Z
outlook you actually have this kind of
custom like zone that gets set up and
stuff and you know I just kind of had to
develop that myself by looking at the
API
same thing with M buffs so packets are
kind of stored in this like slab he
thing that's custom in X in you so I
just reimplemented that using the normal
heap you know it took like a week or
something of just randomly doing stuff
and threading and stuff I just turned
off I said okay I'll just I won't look
for race conditions right now just
looking for parsing bugs so okay so
those are things I had to implement so
how do we actually interact with this
thing now so the same way that user
space already interacts with the kernel
is through insist calls and so what I do
is I just call this just calls with
random arguments and then whenever it
goes to copy data in from user land it
calls this copying function so I have
this thing hooked up to my you know
fuzzed input stream and so then with
some more hacks to like just skip over
file descriptors and stuff because it's
not really relevant
I finally had this fuzzer working so I
would I have this thing that creates a
socket and interacts with the socket and
then as part of this fuzzer loop I'm
also sending random packets in to that
socket and so this pretty much
encompasses networking and so I leave 20
seconds so yeah basically just got
something working did around stuff tried
to avoid spending too much time before I
knew it was necessary and then there's a
first bug and reporting more soon I've
reported one actually already like last
week two seconds I want to do this on
binaries to work hard live demo and I
guess I want but yeah sorry yeah so I
don't know I guess we have a break now
but yeah if anyone has questions like
I'm happy to talk to you up here or
something
yeah
hi thank you delay to talk and was
having a wish now how is this technique
how applicable is destiny against groups
or stuff especially yes no I totally
agree so it does the thing that I was
trying to address here so I'll just
cover quickly getting fuzzing coverage
feedback and writing the harness is
doable very doable I have a private
project that does this
the problem is hacking around things and
like making quick progress when you
don't want to like I was saying like
make some random type in place like you
can't really do that so I haven't fully
explored this yet but I think that's the
kind of next step after xnu
yeah I think we will talk I have two
short questions both concerning time the
first one I read a classical for fuzzing
yeah because you mentioned it at the end
of your talk yeah do you decide when
it's time to move on to your next target
how long do you usually fast until you
get your first crash dangerous yeah yeah
so I think at this point it's about two
weeks per project and so generally
following this exact kind of pattern you
know by the end of the week I'll see
like okay I'm making progress here and
either I'm getting random nobody refs
that kind of look legit and stuff and
like you get some kind of feedback that
this is worth pursuing or like I mean
generally I try to fully cover some
self-contained thing and usually by the
end of a couple weeks I'll have like
fully explored it and so it just looks
like it's time to move on but that takes
experience I guess so and your second
question quick and technical real quick
you move to X and you yeah how much time
did it take you to get acquainted with
the ecosystem
you because it's rather big yeah yeah so
it's kind of funny like I I I don't
really know anything about xnu but the
reason I went for networking was because
it's very in line with stuff I already
know which is like you know huh I mean
syscalls houses calls work and how like
packets work like I need that but you
know I'm trying to order books on how to
actually interact with the real
ecosystem which I have no idea yet and
you know so you know there are all these
bugs recently with this mock port stuff
like these mock port use after freeze
there were a couple of bugs like that
and when I looked at them it seems like
this technique can be extended trivially
to that so you know I think this is
applicable it's just I have to get
acquainted but yeah as far as the the
first prototype took me about a month to
write for this fuzzer where I was
finding bugs and then or bug you know
and then I haven't really worked on this
for a month or two but I'm gonna resume
but yeah cool thank you so any more
questions come on pester him and give me
some exercise
no okay see ya thanks everybody and yeah
feel free to come
[Applause]