[Applause]
okay
yeah thanks everyone for coming to my
talk I hope you all had a great
conference so far I definitely have and
here's another talk on fuzzing this time
about JavaScript engines so let's get
right to it
start with some motivation on this slide
you can see two proof of concepts for
fairly common JavaScript engine bugs
it's not really important what the bug
here is in particular so you have to see
the numbers we can look it up but this
is just to give you an idea what the
kind of code is that we are trying to
find through fuzzing and so let's think
about how we could write a fuzzer that
generates like code something like this
I guess the first yeah the question is
how do we fast JavaScript engine so I
guess the first the simplest approach to
fuzzing as well you do dumb fuzzing you
just throw random by itself your target
yeah now as you can maybe imagine for a
javascript interpreter this is not going
to be that effective but I think it's
still important to to understand exactly
what's the problem here so what's going
to happen is that the parser the thing
that consumes JavaScript and converts it
to like an internal bytecode saying it
rejects this because it's not valid
JavaScript syntax and so nothing ever
gets executed it stops in the parser and
the parser is may be interesting for
fuzzing but it's only about two or three
percent maybe of the engine source code
and probably the least interesting once
so we have to do something better this
brings us to our first requirement which
is all the the samples we generate they
have to at least have valid JavaScript
syntax so requirement one out of a few
now so it's in tactical correctness now
how can we achieve this one possible way
to do this is with a grammar based
fuzzer
that's also a very common approach
example here is tomato and many others
the idea is you take the JavaScript
syntax you formulate it as as a
context-free grammar and then what your
father does is it takes random
production rules so it decides to
produce a expression statement maybe and
then for the expression it decides to
take a to use an addition expression and
then and so on
and yeah so then you could come up with
something like this maybe so this this
is what a generative grammar based
father couldn't can produce for you
another problem here is in this
particular sample here that it's calling
a method on something that's that's a
number which doesn't work it's going to
throw a runtime exception and the
problem with that is that once the first
runtime exception occurred occurs then
the code following that is never going
to be executed so it's not yeah it's not
very helpful and so the the common
solution for this is you put everything
in frycade if you look at some of the
the common JavaScript or browser
father's you will see pretty much
everything as in triquet and then it's
okay every every statement executes if
it throws an exception it's fine it's
getting caught and then the next code
still gets executed the problem here is
if you think back about these samples
that we try to find at least one of them
was a jib bug
so the bark in a JIT compiler as we
heard yesterday from Bruno and so for a
JIT compiler these two here are really
really different right
so there's completely different control
flow between the sample on the left side
and one on the right with all the
trycatch so for a JIT this doesn't
really work and so this brings us to our
second requirement which is that we need
a fairly high degree of semantic
correctness as well right so not only
syntactic correctness also semantics
this is harder quite a bit and there are
a few options that you can achieve this
one option is you can try to do fairly
precise type track
remember this example from from from the
generative father you could try to trace
that this variable head type integer and
then you wouldn't try to to call a
method on it other ideas that I want to
play with is to to maybe generate
JavaScript called step by step so you
generated a few lines and then you run
that and if that doesn't throw an
exception you continue and if it's
Rosanne exception you go back and so on
but the approach that I decided to use
here is mutation based and again this
picture is a bit messed up I don't
really know why but I guess you can
still follow so with the mutation based
approach the idea is that in your corpus
which you take your samples from you
always have semantically valid samples
in your corpus and so then for the
mutation you pick a sample it's it's
valid you to do some small mutations to
it and these small mutations they have a
small chance of making it invalid right
and so with that you get a fairly high
degree of semantic correctness and then
depending if you do any kind of guided
fuzzing also you you put samples back
into the corpus if they are interesting
but you only do this if the sample
doesn't throw an exception this is
really important so everything in your
corpus must not throw runtime exceptions
and then this works so then then the
final question you know the final
requirement is here
we need mutations for JavaScript code so
mutation is present need some kind of
way of mutating inputs bit flipping
probably not super effective then we run
into the syntactic correctness problem
so let's try to figure out sensible
mutations to to JavaScript code or
source code in general now this is also
not a lot of new research topic people
are already mutating source code in my
opinion there's three different levels
on which you can mutate code so that's
what you see on the right side here the
the top level is like the source code
itself that text string you can flip
bits and bytes on there probably not
very effective again
syntactic correctness is a problem the
next level and this is what people are
already implementing and fussing with is
the syntax tree the abstract syntax tree
so it's a tree representation of
JavaScript source code you can change
like literal it's also in it or you can
perform tree mutations like take this
this one here put it somewhere else or
copy copy sub trees from another sample
etcetera but the observation here is
that for the engine itself the the
syntactic representation is really
irrelevant it doesn't care what it cares
about is stuff like control and data
flow and so what the engine internally
does is is it first takes this syntax
tree and it converts it to byte code and
despite code is then what captures
control and data flow and so for the
same Biko there's many different
representations in the syntax tree but
the byte code is important thing so what
I try to do I wanted to do something
different what I try to do is to mutate
more on a byte code level on a lower
level and so things we can do there's
you can like mess with instructions
change registers or you can copy
instructions from one sample put it in
into the other and so on it will see
some mutations later so if we want to do
pass or mutate byte code we can either
pick an existing byte code or we can
make our own I made my own I called it
fast il just because it sounds cool I
guess and it it's yeah I guess it's
optimized for fasting right so it's an
intermediate language it looks kind of
like the byte code you see but it it's
easy to mutate that and here's an
example how it looks like it's I guess
it's fairly self-explanatory the it has
these registers or variables v-0 v1 and
so on and then there's operations each
instruction has this operation load in
or begin for our binary operation and
they can potentially have these
parameters which is the blue things so
load in here the first one has the
parameter 0 so it's loading
the value 0 into v-0 I guess okay so
that's how it looks like the important
next step here is of course this is
technically a JavaScript engine doesn't
understand this so we first have to
translate that into JavaScript so let's
talk about that
it's called lifting again this is the
same sample on the left side let's see
how we can make it turn it into
JavaScript there's multiple ways you can
do this there's a trivial way in which
you pretty much convert one instruction
into one statement so these loadings
they become assignments of constants the
begin for starts starts a for loop etc
so this is very easy to do if you want
nicer looking code you can actually also
do it so there's another way to lift
this at the bottom right here this one
uses expression inlining so you can see
it has inline all these constants zero
and ten and so on and and like chained
together the method calls et cetera but
the important idea here is that both of
these syntactic representations they do
the exact same thing right so for an
engine it doesn't really matter the the
top the bottom right one might be nicer
for you to look at but for an engine it
shouldn't really make a difference okay
so that's lifting but let's talk about
mutating which is the real important
part so here's an a simple simpler
facile program and I'm going to show a
few kind of fundamental mutations for
that so the first one is called input
mutator it's a dataflow mutation it's
really simple it takes an input value of
some instruction and replace a set with
a different one so in this case the call
function operation the the second input
to that was previously v1 and now it's
me zero and now we have changed the data
flow of the program another mutation his
operation rotator which changes these
blue
parameters so before that it would loads
a global print function and after that
we made it low to encode your i/o
function and left the rest in place then
there's the insertion mutator which is
how new code gets inserted into the
programs it generates new code following
a bunch of like hundreds or so of
predefined code generator functions and
this one it maybe generates a property
load so there's a load property
operation and it just randomly generates
that and this one has currently the
highest probability of producing
semantically invalid code right it might
produce a proper method call on
something that's again an integer so but
it still has like a 60 or so percent
success chance of success
quite quite okay because it's only doing
small changes every time and then the
final one is the splice mutator I called
it that way what it does it it inserts
existing code and it only inserts part
of existing code so in this case it's
copying code from the same sample but of
course normally it takes code from a
completely unrelated sample and puts it
in the current one and here it copied
one instruction only the first but it
could also copy ten or so depending on
yeah I guess randomness
okay so here's for quiet fundamental
mutations and there's a few more that I
have there's one other problem which is
minimization or one other thing that I'm
doing which is minimization the problem
here that this is solving is that with
these mutaters programs can only grow
right if you insert code of you like
take home from another program and put
it into the current one it can only grow
and so eventually the programs would get
way way way too big like thousands of
lines and then the performance secrets
but the easy solution is to minimize
those programs after when they are put
into the corpus and minimization is
actually simple at least the basic
algorithm
what you do is you you go over the
program you take out like every
instruction after taking out an
instruction you read random program and
then you check if the behavior changed
so if you do coverage guided fighting
for example and you trigger the new edge
then you keep removing all the
instructions while still that so that
the same edge is still being triggered
and for a crash we do the same thing so
while the program said crashes you
remove all these instructions so
conceptually it's really simple but it's
quite expensive in terms of executions
right so if your program has 200
instructions and minimizing it costs
about 200 X X okay now this talk is also
about guided fuzzing the nice thing is
at this point we have the mutation based
buzzer so all that's left to do to make
it guided is to plug in some kind of
feedback system that can say well this
sample is this good that's interesting
let's keep it or this one is maybe not
interesting let's make a new one what I
currently have is edge coverage more or
less exactly what a of others important
to notice for the JIT compiler only
measures coverage in the compiler and
not the generated code which is still
pretty useful so we can still like fine
code that figures interesting behavior
in the compiler itself so it does work
for kids but I guess this is an
interesting research question can we get
like coverage on the Jade code itself or
so and I guess there's also other
potentially interesting metrics matrices
that could be used again maybe an
interesting topic so then look the core
basic fuzzer algorithm looks like this
in each iteration it takes a sample from
the corpus executes it checks if it got
a crash if yes then if minimizes a crash
and then goes continues if it did not
crash then it checks if it's exceeded
succeeding meaning it doesn't throw an
exception if it did throw an exception
then go back
to the next one but if it didn't throw
an exception then check if it triggered
new behavior new patches for example and
if it did forget new behavior then again
minimize put it back into the corpus and
then go back okay
here's what it what architecture looks
like we've seen most of the components
now so the main father here or one
father instance is made up of one corpus
and the mutator the lifter thing the
evaluation the coverage guidance and
minimization yeah right now there's one
instance per target process which
simplifies quite a few things and then
the whole thing can see many instances
can synchronize over IPC or the network
will see this on the next slide and then
so there's what I also have is a bunch
of optional optional modules so the
thing is kind of modular for example the
synchronization which we'll see next is
one module it's not necessarily required
but it's optional okay so and then the
main primitive for synchronization is
importing one instance can pretty much
send a program to another instance which
would be imported there and then yeah
let's see how that works so
synchronization works in kind of a
master worker scheme and between a
master in the worker there has to be
some kind of communication link maybe
IPC or TCP sockets whatever then it
works roughly like this this worker here
finds an interesting program says hey I
found this this program it's maybe
interesting for you
so what the master does is it executes
it on its own instance and again checks
if it did trigger new edges now in this
case it might have triggered new edges
and so then yeah it is indeed
interesting also for the master and so
that master is gonna send it to all its
workers and so the the new simple
spreads through the global corpus and
the workers do the same thing they we
execute that sample and check if it's
also interesting for them
yeah now this is kind of kind of
expensive right one sample is executed
multiple times there's ways to make it
faster I guess we could like just export
the bits or the edges that it's
triggering also this sample of this this
algorithm here is very simple to
implement that's why I have it right now
it has the nice side benefit that non
deterministic samples get kind of
filtered so if the worker triggered a
sample that's not deterministic and like
only triggers this edge one out of
hundred times then the sampler probably
doesn't spread further so it's a nice
side effect and so I didn't really
bother making it better yet the same
happens for crashes but of course
crashes are only sent upstream right the
the crash isn't sent back to the worker
or anything because it's not needed okay
so then talking about scaling this is
roughly the architecture that I have
running right now the potential problem
is if there's way too many workers for
one master then since the master has to
execute all the interesting samples it
might just get completely overloaded so
I have these intermediate masters and
then a central one which collects all
the crashes synchronization works over
very simple TCP protocol and the whole
thing is really really easy to set up
with for example Google Cloud engine and
docker you just make a docker container
for one instance say like write some
scripts and to start 100 instances or
whatever synchronize them maybe human
eaters might be a nice nice thing to try
I heard it's cool I haven't tried it but
let's see yeah so that's pretty much it
now I've wrote this thing for my master
Caesars last year where I had been
running it on one server more or less it
did find some stuff back then but yeah
so currently supported this
javascriptcore SpiderMonkey in v8
corresponding to WebKit Firefox and
Chrome so if you do fuzzing I guess any
kind of trace
engine fuzzing there's tons of
assertions and crashes you'll get so I
haven't kept track of them
but you will see a lot of assertion
failures in debug its some of them are
interesting but many are not you'll see
like nine point ID revs you you actually
sometimes or not not to us yeah I guess
kind of regularly you'll find samples
that trigger observable misbehavior
where the engine output something
different but it's not actually a
security problem and so lots and lots of
these analysis is also kind of tedious
some of these assertions you have to
first figure out what's going on to say
if that's a security problem it did find
last year to see VG's in WebKit and one
pretty cool spider monkey register
allocation bug now it's running on more
than one server so let's see they did
already find some crashes I reported but
yeah so what is my roadmap for this
right now I want to do some more
cleaning up now since I'm at Google I
have to put it into revenue before open
sourcing it probably I should also wait
for the current set of bugs to get fixed
which I reported in the last weeks but
then I want to open source it I'm aiming
for like in a month or so but this
roughly let's see and then afterwards I
have a lot of things on my mind that I
want to try so for example right now the
sink and even import existing JavaScript
code it just starts from like one
hard-coded sample and keeps mutating
there so probably starting from an
existing corpus it's a good idea let's
see
and then the the FA's il Singh doesn't
cover all the language features yet
another thing I would as I mention
briefly I would like to try this this
kind of hybrid approach where I generate
a sample in multiple steps and see what
happens I definitely need better time
tracking my custom instrumentations
probably right yeah so that's already it
so what have we seen guided fuzzing
approach by mutating a custom
intermediate language right now this
thing is fairly I would say fairly
generic code mutation engine so probably
it would also work for other languages
at least as long as they're dynamically
types
then it probably works watch this space
for the open source release again I
can't really say when it's gonna happen
but hopefully very soon and I'm
definitely looking for collaborators if
anyone is interested in running this
playing this very very welcome
ping me write me an email or ping me on
Twitter if you have any questions if
anything's not working and with that
thanks for attention and I'm open for
questions any questions anyone okay so
this is pretty cool when doing
minimization have you considered doing
any sort of analysis on the il before
trying to minimize it and do something
like you Steph chains so that you can
kind of figure out easier what's not
being actually affecting the program so
not really know what I what I do is I
have on in the fancier language there's
this restraint that like every variable
has to be defined before it's used so
this minimization for some of the
instruction that I remove I can directly
say it's important because the output is
new used somewhere so that does reduce
the number of executions by a lot but
otherwise it's really dumb it's really
just like removing everything from the
bottom up and see what if something
changes thank you for the talk I think
it's very interesting idea
implementation but can you please go to
the slide where you showed yes this one
this one yes for last year so can you
please clarify I mean you found like
more than 50 in one engine and 100 sets
150 bucks and free CV but what was scale
of fuzzing like how many like it you
fast for one year or what very much
throughout one year unlike like eight
cores or something like that okay yeah
it's pretty hard to tell like I was
fuzzing it during development right so I
would like develop something then start
the Father then see okay it doesn't
reach as much coverage as before so it's
up probably I should maybe go back
exactly and it's a matrix okay have you
considered or what do you think about
fuzzing the actual bytecode of a
specific engine jet engine so the main
problem with that is that the buyer code
is assumed to be trusted so if the buyer
code if you like flip any bits or so if
you increment indices it's gonna crash
all over the place because the engine
assumes the biker is president doesn't
do any of a kind of verification on it
so it wouldn't really I don't think it
would work like naively just taking
bytecode and feed it to the later stage
of the engine thank you hello thank you
for your talk so one of the things that
I've been interested in is figuring out
how to apply coverage to browsers you
mentioned that you're doing coverage
over the jet engine itself so you're
using something like a sine curve or
some compiler instrumentation one of the
things that we did for my class was to
convert D'Amato into a self-hosted
service and then do coverage over the
actual types and the grammar tree so
just as we can talk about this later but
just as a suggestion for anybody working
in this space you know we have two types
of coverage that we're trying to
choo-choo one is execution and one is
data space coverage and so it may be
possible for you to import the BNF
grammar that's available through D'Amato
which expresses these type relationships
in the data that we need to generate and
use that in a way that correlates I
guess with your ability to do coverage
tracking and the jet engine but really I
think the efficient search of the object
relationships and the properties is an
interesting space you mentioned you were
using like a static list of a hundred
different functions or so to do your
injections
so maybe there is a way to enumerate
type tree effectively of the properties
and functions that should be operating
on each other and efficiently search
that in combination with the feedback
yeah thanks I think we should definitely
check yeah I have coverage that's right
now it's the easiest thing to implement
it is just F sanitized coverage equals
something PC trace right now I also have
it as more or less a workaround for for
this this year that the problem that I
don't actually can import any existing
code because then through coverage it
will find like at least some interesting
samples so it's more it is to some
degree also work around for this
restriction at this point but I'm sure
there are other matrices and ways to
measure I get feedback that probably we
produce more interesting results all
right so a big round of applause for Sam
Oh
[Applause]