[Applause]
welcome everybody so we're going to
continue this talk and talk about fault
injection the same as the last talk but
the target is going to be different so
in this case we're going to talk about
hardware wallets and what we can do with
fault injection on these devices so
first let's start with what is a
hardware wallet and some time ago when
cryptocurrencies became popular a number
of manufacturers realized that there is
a need for secure device and it is your
PC is most likely compromised and you
need some kind of secure device which
can be very limited in the api's have
very limited attack surface and then you
keep your keys there and you generate
the keys on the device and the keys
never leave the device so you plug it
into your PC or connect to your
smartphone and use signed transactions
but the key is always tell the device
and that's the whole idea to make these
devices secure and here on the slide you
can see three most popular Hardware
wallets so it is a ledger keep key and
treasure not all of the hardware wallets
have the same architecture ledger quite
different but keep key and treasure in
this case they are quite similar because
initially there was treasure and it is
open source so anyone can make their own
clone and keep key has the same chip and
very similar firmware as the treasure
but today we're going to focus on the
keep key so that's how it looks and all
it has is the screen one physical button
for the user to improve operations and
USB connection to the PC and all the
communication is done over the USB so
the screen is not touched so it just can
only press the button
so why keep key well when you make a
secure device you have to make a number
of claims how securities and for example
here you can see from the website of the
manufacturer it says that if you lose
your device the pin protection renders
the device useless even it falls in the
wrong hands so what happens when it
falls in their own hands that's what
happens so someone builds a setup and
they try to use physical attacks for
example another thing you can see for
example on the Amazon description it
says there's been great security that is
simple and that's something you want to
put to the test and see how secure
actually it is also something to mention
I didn't research the previous
publications on this when I started the
tests but at some moment I found the
presentation at Def Con on tracer so it
was 2 years ago or year and a half and
the they presented the attack on tracer
and as I mentioned they have very
similar hardware so the physical attacks
on Frazer might also work on keep key so
what they tried to do is to use voltage
fault injection on the device and their
conclusion was that it is inconclusive
because they didn't manage to glitch
using voltage there unmodified tracer
device so what they did is they build
their own clone and they had more
control over it and then they managed to
get some results but not on the
real-life device and of course there was
this comment on one of the slides and of
course challenge accepted
something about features of the keep key
it has stm32 and this is another reason
to try physical attacks because this is
just MCU it's not a secured ship it has
internal flash and so you cannot do some
simple attacks just without the keys
with a physical access it has quite a
few commands you can send over USB so
there are 22 commands you can send beam
protection it is fully open source so
you can have the boot ordered firmware
the source code and so on and it has
verification of the firmware it has
flash protection and it verifies the
images running on the device using 3 it
has 5 keys and it uses 3 of them to
verify an image so every image signed
with 3 keys and actually for our type of
physical attack it is quite painful
because we need to reset the device
quite often it does 3 elliptic curve
signature verification which takes a
while and the device boots two and a
half seconds so it slows down what may
be even could be considered con to
measure how how does it work so
initially when you have a device you
have something like that you plug it in
and you need to initialize it and it
generates the keys on the device and it
got these twelve words which correspond
to the master key on the device and this
is used for the backup so you have your
twelve words you write on the paper and
keep somewhere safe
and if you lose your device you restore
using these twelve words and when you
use the wallet you plug it in if you
need to do something security sensitive
if you need to enter the pin and they
show you this matrix on the screen since
there are no buttons on the device you
need to type your PIN on the PC but as
we said that we see could be compromised
so there has to be some kind of solution
and what they do for that they bring
these metrics on the device well hence
the
I told this presentation and they
scrambled every time with a random
combination and then you need just to
press corresponding buttons on your
laptop or PC to enter the pin so every
time you enter random digits and
something about hardware so it has stm32
205 and it has one megabyte of internal
flash and there are a number of
different partitions of the flash so
there is a some secure storage here for
storing the pin and the user data there
is bootloader and there is a firmware
itself which has the applications for
their cryptocurrencies and it supports a
lot of them but it's just one monolithic
firmware and finally why I would go into
the hardware attack and as I said it is
quite popular open source project so a
lot of loop people looked at the code a
lot of issues were fixed the current
version is five point ten point two or
something that so there were a lot of
new releases and a lot of issues were
fixed but on the other hand the use
general purpose MCU and there is a
chance to use fault attacks because this
general purpose MC use are not designed
to withstand such attacks and well
initially I brought this device to do
because I thought I have a vulnerability
in the code I found and I wanted to make
proof of concept but when I got the
device it was already fixed because
there was new version and then I had no
possibility to exploit it using software
but then you can still try to do some
hardware attacks and that's what we're
going to do now so something about fault
injection just few words I will not talk
a lot there are some papers and a lot of
research in this area but the idea is
that there are some specified conditions
in which you supposed to use your chip
and some in which you not for example
chip
expects to have a stable clock and to
have stable voltage so this device
powered by USB power or it expects that
there is no yum process around it and no
one shoots lasers at it and no one
freezes it or no one heats it up too
much
so all these restrictions are there but
if you mess with this you can try to
affect the chip in a specific way and
well the common results of fault
injection that you can corrupt data at
some moment of execution so you can
corrupt it to zeros you can corrupt the
two ffs you can corrupt it to some
random value or just do a few simple bit
flips so you just leave one bit at some
place in the byte and so on you can also
corrupt instructions when they execute
instead of one instruction another one
is going to be executed or you can as a
edge case you can skip a struction if
you corrupt something - nope or
something like that so these are most
common outcomes of a fault injection and
we'll try to use that to actually
exploit the device well first what I
have to do is of course open the device
here on on the table it has no case just
one PCB first of course not always you
have to open it I tried it without open
any opening the device but it has
aluminum case on the backside so it's
not possible to glitch through and on
the front side it has PCB and the screen
in front of the chip so it's not always
also very easy that's why you have to
crack the case and well that is a setup
on my desk some time ago as you can see
it's a very precise and scientific and
you have to be careful with this you can
see I use x-rays at table there on the
back of the picture there is no X why's
that here because I couldn't fit it in
on the airplane with me so I have to
leave it there and just bring the rest
and just try to put it by hand carefully
close enough
to do the glitching well we have the
setup we need to try to test and see if
we can affect the chip in some way and
for that we can normally do in the lab
characterization of the chip ideally you
would like to run your own code and
execute it and put nice triggers like
erase the pin up just before the
operation do something simple like
copying and raise the pin down and you
know when it exactly happens and then
you glitch there in this case as I said
the flash is protected so it's like real
life case I had one device on which I
tried that and I couldn't execute
arbitrary code so I had to use what I
had there in the framework and that is
the simplest command I could find there
available over USB and it just did ping
command so you send some data up to 256
bytes and you get this data back just to
test that the communication works and
what it does there it does the mem copy
of the message back to you and that is
it well that's we want to do one a
glitch here we want to bleach the mem
copy and try to see if I can corrupt
some data and it should be easily
visible because because we get the data
back from the device and we can see if
affected mem copy the way we expected
and as I said no code execution so it is
really painful to find a place where to
bleach you can see this is the data line
of the USB communication and that's the
command with San here and the response
we get and there is one millisecond in
between and the Chi branch at 120
megahertz so there is quite a lot of
stuff could be happening and you could
try to be smart and find the way using
the power consumption of the chip but
you can also try to boot for us just to
glitch everywhere in this region and see
when you affect it of course it will
take longer but it also requires less
thinking so I just put first and that's
what I get so I said you have X Y Z
table it is quite precise you can move
the probe just few micrometers at a time
and you scan the full chip again and
again with different power and different
timings and you get such kind of picture
I gotta have the layout of the chip
what's underneath so I only know on the
outside you can see there is a block
which really affected a lot by the
glitching and just explained so the
green ones the green dots is when we
tried to bleach but we got no corruption
so we send the hello world message in
the ping command would get it back and
that is green yellow ones is well we do
the same we send the message and we'd
get no response back so we just glitched
too far and we corrupt it too much and
it doesn't respond anymore then we reset
and it works again but we got no
response from the commander sent and of
course the most important are the red
dots and these are the dots when we send
something in the message and we get the
response back but it's not what we send
it's something different and that's what
we mark red because we are actually
interested in these in these dots and
well that's the moment to do the demo I
started it in the beginning of the
previous talk just to have a bit no time
to do the glitching you can see here
this is the setup running here on stage
and well to the best of my knowledge
it's the first demo life of my fault
injection on a real target and we got a
few glitches here you can see we've got
four glitches success rate is quite low
yesterday in my room in the hotel I
managed to get two percent success rate
with the same tests but really depends
on the place where you put it and I
cannot be precise because the table
really shakes a lot if I move around you
can see if I move away from the tip it
doesn't bleach anymore because it really
has to be very close to the probe to the
coil so that's the glitch and what kind
of results do we get
we can see here maybe I don't know if
it's really visible so this is the
current running test and that's quite
sad actually what we got we just
corrupted to one letter instead of
sending ten back
we glitch the mem copy and get only one
back only one message only one letter
but of course you can imagine that yeah
if we just corrupt them somehow doesn't
work anymore if we corrupt just one
character we can get better results so
that's the demo I've done before I will
not show it because we had some glitches
here but these are the results I got
before and you can see that in this case
we corrupt the length of the memo P
quite a lot and we can set it to some
value and quite often it's less so we
send ten characters and we get less and
one time or two times we've got 11
characters and you can also imagine if
you corrupt it to something big like 200
400 or megabyte we can get more memory
well if you have two megabyte we're not
going to get anything but if a corrupt
is something reasonable we can get more
data from the device and get basically a
buffer overflow using the fault
injection so this is more results I got
before when I just first run this
characterization on the device you can
see that in the different parts of the
chip I was still scanning the full chip
and try to glitch and I got a lot of
different results here you can see often
we corrupt the length and we get just
less characters back sometimes we
corrupt four characters and they set to
zero oh we can corrupt it like these
bald ones they have one bit flip in the
character so the capital D and lowercase
D they in ASCII just one bit flip from
which other 32 in decimal so we corrupt
one bit and we get these kind of results
and you can see the last one on the
bottom is quite interesting because
ghost
something we didn't expect at all it
says settings applied we send how the
world and we send ping command and we
get back
settings applied and that's quite
unexpected it's hard to tell because
it's a black box we don't see what's
happening we just glitch there and
corrupt something one explanation could
be is that when we copied we corrupted
the source to the string which says
settings applied which is present in the
firmware which is not very likely
because it's difficult to corrupt it
exactly to the beginning of the string
and it could be but another explanation
could be is that corrupted the PC
register and just jump to another
instruction and this is one of the
commands you can send a command which
applies settings so if we corrupted the
PC to the place where this instruction
is executing and in the end what it does
it brings settings applied and it
returns the message back to the user via
USB so that could also happen here other
interesting results so this is the
screen on the table here you can see I
have no screen
I had one device and I was glitching it
for in total maybe four or five million
attempts over this past half a year and
well I killed the screen and one of the
LEDs they do not work anymore but the
chip still works it boots and it runs
the firmware and USB works so for the
rest it's still fine and it has still
keys and pins so I can still use it but
you can see what you could see on the
screen when you glitch sometimes you get
error detected and the boot device
message that happens at some moment they
check CRC on some data copied and with
which somewhere there and it brings this
message because it detected that
seriously doesn't match anymore other
one it says that cloak instability
detected and you need to reboot device
and we'll talk about this what it means
a bit later just a few more screens of
the glitching so you can see we corrupt
the start of the screen and we print
just from the random place and we get
this messages they don't really matter
like you not gonna exploit it like that
but it just nice nice picture
so why clock instability detected this
is the source code what it says in the
firmware so the manufacturers of the
hardware wallet they actually cared
about fault injection and they added
this check and what it does it checks
some registers and it is used to prevent
clock glitching as we talked in the
beginning you can use not only voltage
or a.m. like in this case you can use
clock and if you give fault o'clock we
skip cycles or change this frequency you
can try to affect the execution and
that's what they try to prevent here and
as far as I know this is the only fault
injection measure control measure
present in the device at that moment and
we see we trigger it sometimes but
that's not our idea we don't want to
trigger this content measure we try to
avoid it and corrupt something different
without triggering the the check so that
is nice we can corrupt mem copy we can
corrupt the screen output we can get
some nice pictures but is there actually
exploitable bleach something we can use
in an attack on the device well that's
something we're gonna try next this is
the first command I tried it says change
pin and of course that something we want
to do a pin is one of the quanta
measures security features on the device
and another one is passphrase but
passphrase is not recommended for
average user only for advanced ones
because if you forget your password it's
going to be a lost forever a cannot
restore advice that's why on the side of
the manufacturer they say you better not
use it unless you really sure you want
to use it so on most of the users
Hardware wallets I can imagine that they
just have been and nothing else so if we
can change the pin to something we
choose then there's no protection left
on the device that sounds nice and
that's what we try the change ping
command
it's as if pin protect and at this
moment it asks you to provide the pin if
you didn't it asked you to provide
in every time and you have to enter the
pin on the PC and send it and it shows
you the scrambled metrics and so on and
then if it is correct
then you can modify to another pin you
choose so we want to glitch this if
statement and hopefully skip it entirely
so do not do this check arrow and
continue and right after that we can
enter new pin and we're done well it
wasn't that easy it was a fail I started
glitch in English English in and I spend
maybe a few weeks or week of collation
and I got no results at all like I never
skipped this if statement and then I
looked a bit closer what's what's
happening so I sent the command and as I
said we have no trigger when this
execution starts so all I do is I
trigger on the USB packet I sent and
then I just wait for some time English
so I try to be to reduce junior as much
as possible but you can see here you
have to press the button and it's like a
security feature to ensure that user
actually wants to change the pin you
have to press the physical button say
yes I do want to change the pin so of
course in the beginning implement in
some relay board which does the clicking
I need to hold the pin for the button
for one second exactly and I had some
FPGA which does exactly that so to would
know jitter almost no trigger it presses
the button it releases it so I know
exactly when I release the button but
the execution itself the what the
firmware doesn't this loop it's not
deterministic it's it has quite a bit of
jitter in this execution so after I
release the button it doesn't execute
right away this or after some fixed
delay this next part and I have a lot of
a lot of jitter in this part and having
this random delays before the if
statement this is actually a
countermeasure common for devices which
try to protect the gas fault injection
so you add random delays here and it's
very difficult to hit this if statement
so this attack could be still possible
but maybe it would take me
for you to run non-stop in the lab and
then I would hit at one time or I need
to come up with better ways to find the
exact place on the trace my when this if
statement happens so of course it was
too much work to continue here and I
just moved on to another command
econsent and this is the reset device
device command we send some parameters
on the to the device and it is supposed
to be used first time when it just plug
in your device first and you initialize
it with a label and language and the pin
protection if you want to use pin you
can even disable pin on this device it's
one of the possibilities for the user
not to use pin at all but if you use pin
protection and set it to true then you
can set a new pin and so on
and you can see here in the beginning it
checks if the storage is initialized so
if the user already put the pin if he
has his own keys and he used this wallet
before when you send it you got the wipe
device first message and we want to do
the same as before we want to skip this
if we do not do this check we go right
away to reset in it and we update the
pin here so all it does it updates the
pin it doesn't wipe the device it does
not affect the keys all the rest stays
in place all all your changes like label
language and pin and you can choose even
if you want to change them or not so you
can just choose pin protection and
change the pin so that's what we would
wish here in the if statement and it was
successful quite fast and what we
managed to do is we send the command
reset device we glitch there it skips
the if statement and it ask us a new pin
and then I change the pin and then I
recited the device and then I couldn't
enter the pin when I entered the pin was
wrong so actually the attack didn't work
but then I had to figure it out and it
seems that in the reset device what it
does it changes the pinion in RAM so
when you boot the device it does Shadow
Copy of the flash storage
and when you do reset device it changes
pin and RAM so that's good so far but
would be nice to have persistent one
bleach and then persistent change and
that's all you can do so you do if you
do it in a sequence you just need still
one glitch you send the reset device
command you glitch here one time and you
change pin on RAM and then you send
change pin command the one we used
before but this time we don't need to
bleach anymore because we have our pin
already in RAM which we just corrupted
when we done the glitch underside device
so we have our own pin and RAM with send
change pin and change pin is going to
change checker against the pin and RAM
and we can set another piano or whatever
one now and it's going to be written to
flash and it also writes only pin the
keys are not affected by this and
combining these two calls in just one
single glitch we could bypass them DEP
in check so that's the full attack how
it works also on the next slide how it
looks so you get the device somehow you
do this you bleach it there user already
should have initialized the device and
have the pin set and tokens on the
device the keys for the cryptocurrencies
and then you do change ping command you
glitch you change it to another
something else and it's written to flash
and from there
you have the user device and nothing
else else changed but the pin which you
know now and you have the full access to
all of the features which the user had
of course as I said for advanced users
who actually use the passphrase you not
gonna get everything right away so you
need to combine the glitch with with
something else and then to get the
stored stored secrets on the device and
then boot force it offline so it's a bit
more hustle but as I said since the
manufacturer does not recommend average
users to use this most likely most of
the devices will not have this enabled
and then it can just do this simple
glitch attack something about results
that was in the lab so when I had a nice
setup when I could find the sweet spot
when I can glitch easily
I got success rate of 1.2 percent and
this is success rate not for the whole
attic but for every attempt every time I
tried to glitch every time i reboot the
device and send the command and the send
the glitch on average I would get like
one point two percent so an attempt
right is zero point three so I need to
wait five minutes send few hundred
glitches and then I skip the pin and
that is it well something about
conclusions well that's what it can do
if you have MCU on your device any
quality security device and you have no
quantum matters in software or they are
very limited to some specific type of
fault injection for example clock
bleaching that it's not going to prevent
an attacker from using other kinds of
physical attacks to try to bypass your
security features and finally if there
are no vulnerabilities in the source
code of your device in the firmware it
doesn't mean that this device is secure
there could be still some attacks on the
device well that is it the last picture
I wanted to show is that I got it one
moment at glitching I was corrupting the
screen output a lot at this particular
delay and what I think happened is that
instead of printed this string I expect
so it should have said something like do
you want to really change the pin it
corrupted the string pointer to
something else place in memory and you
can see if you ask characters and all
the rest is unprintable on the screen if
you have any questions I would be happy
to answer
thank you very presentation I may have
missed it but I don't think you
mentioned which hardware to use to
inject fault how much it costs and where
does what are the practical problems
with say setting up the lab and stuff
like that yeah
so that is something I really didn't
mention I used the proprietary tools
from whisker I'm from whisker and of
course I have the lab next to me so it's
quite easy to get all the tools it is
not very cheap to use this equipment
I don't know exact prices but you cannot
just buy this and for a hobby project
and use it at home unless you want to
invest quite a bit but as you've seen
for example in the lab we always use
x-rays at table for this glitch I don't
use x-rays that anymore
you'll lose a bit in the quality but you
still can do some glitching so you can
remove quite a few parts from here it
will take more time to set it up but
with the investment in time you can
replace quite a few parts there is also
open other solutions like cheaper ones
for example chip shoulder or something
like that or you can use live versus
you've seen from the last presentation
you can create Enfield using simple
lighter maybe it also works but yeah you
can reduce the cost quite a lot and
that's the question can the attacker do
that or not thank you for the
presentation I might have missed the
point in if the information is already
in flash and you're already doing
hardware voodoo why exactly are you not
just changing the the flash well you
were reading out of the flash what you
are interested in yeah exactly so if you
can't flash that is it you can just read
the contents it's plain text but as I
said they have
boot loader and boot loader verify
signatures so you cannot try it anything
there on the device like any code you
want so you cannot read it from the
software from the hardware the flesh is
internal on the chip so I have this
stm32 205 as one megabyte of internal
flash
you cannot just connect something and
read it directly and also they have
flash without protection disabled so it
said to the so you cannot just read the
flash with external tools connecting to
the device
you you didn't mention also how he chose
the point where you inject the fault you
did present the heat map of where it
default were but what made you chose a
particular point or which which one did
you choose
well in the when I was doing the test
I was just scanning the chip and see
where I get better results and then I
stopped there but now when I do the
glitch answer I do it somewhere here in
this area but of course by hand you
cannot be that precise and it's like
maybe half the chip and the problem is
quite big so it's like one quarter of
the chip and I most likely affect these
parts here and do the corruption but you
just have to scan and to find the place
finds like the best for you if you have
used X Y Z or keep fiddling by hand and
trying to find it if you use setup like
this and also I try to find a place for
the bleach and now on the stage to have
like half yellow half greens and then
you affect you have a higher chance of
affecting you if you are in the spot
where you get all the greens it's very
unlikely because you just don't affect
the chip at all
I maybe have two questions so well first
one why did you choose EMF I over like
VCC glitching for example or and second
one how many what frequencies are that
you can send multiple glitches with EMF
I do you have to wait in between why I
chose amfi because voltage didn't work
for me I didn't want to try too much but
I try to this holder the capacitors it's
powered over USB so it has a bunch of
capacitors there I tried to remove all
of them and then it stops working if I
keep few of them it doesn't glitch I
could dissolve the chip and do more
soldering work but it's like not
something very interesting for me so I
moved on to MFI because you have to
change the PCB less and just to try
affect the chip and also you can get
better results because you just affect
some parts of the chip not the whole
chip and it also has USB on the chip
within the sock so if you use voltage
you will affect the whole chip and
affect USB and affect the CPU and then
most very likely will just crash the USB
and you will not get any response even
if you had a successful bitch on the CPU
you will not see the response and you
will not know if you did something and
for the second question what was the
second question so
how long do we have to wait or to do
multiple bleaches with Jennifer so you
can shoot a few glitches at the same
time right after another like few
microseconds in between if you really
want to but for me I really want to
effect one spot there's like one check
or one instruction so I just do one
which at a time and whenever you want to
do next attempt I need to wait if I get
the green ones normally I don't reset so
I can try right away so it's like maybe
one second in between and if I got
yellow so the device was mute I had to
reset the device and then it takes 34
seconds to reset and then continue again
thank you