Mic Check okay all right well hello
everyone welcome to my top it's called a
height of your tax in this direction
like redacted right off the bat let's
play let's talk about some general
disclaimers here all content on the
slide is going to be available for you
to download you know please review share
whatever and views that I'm expressing
here are my own and are not
representative my employer so don't hold
them accountable for what I say so
during this talk what we're gonna be
doing is we're gonna be taking a look at
techniques and methodologies applied by
advanced persistent threat groups and
then how we as penetration testers
hackers and whatever you are Ken
utilizes methodologies to you know
basically become more effective and have
your campaign be more effective so some
of these groups you know you may know
the you may heard of the NSA you may
heard of GCHQ the PLA electronic warfare
division those kinds of groups and we're
going to take a quick look at what they
do so if you are interested in a good
image of what these people look like
that's probably not it but let's get
representation so a little background on
who I am I work as an IT security
engineer / research or like west well I
phones company based in Tampa we do a
lot of IT security related things so
contest we also provide managed security
services and so you know hey if you need
someone to watch your logs for you you
can do that among other things I mean
university student and I love security
man I you know breaking things and so
much fun I securing things isn't as much
fun but hey whatever
alright a quick shout outs let's give a
round of applause or be sized Orlando
organizers because those guys have been
awesome quick hello to my co-workers
because you guys are awesome hello to
anyone from Def Con 813 you guys are
awesome I don't see any white Hatter's
but if there are any people from wait
headers hello hack Miami crew and the
two NSA agents in here you guys about
your heads or whatever but just give me
a little wave right off the bat let's
talk about government capabilities and
capabilities of these apt groups I don't
care who you are the government is going
to have more money than you they're
going to have more access you could ever
possibly hope to get and they're going
to have a lot more leverage and you
could ever possibly hope to get so don't
get it in your head that you're ever
going to be as good as then because
unless you're rich and really really
really really really rich which you're
not you're not going to um but on the
other hand advanced persistent threat
groups don't necessarily have to be tied
to government um you know by the
standard definition advanced persistent
threats or just hackers that are better
than your regular script kiddies so yeah
all right so as a little forewarning I'm
gonna we're gonna be going to school
right now I'm going to give you a little
history on these you know advanced apt
groups or whatever you want to call them
just bear with me but at the same time
what we're doing this kind of take note
of you know the evolution of their
methodologies and their tactics and how
it's changed over time starting in
nineteen ninety eight we'll take a look
at this campaign called moonlight maze
basically what happened was the US was
parsing logs whatever and they found
notice some electronic probing of you
know
Pentagon systems DOD systems department
of energy and other like research labs
something interesting and something to
take note of is that humans are the
weakest link security we all notice we
have an intrinsic flaw built into our
systems and basically we love routine
and we hate change because of this fact
that enables blue teens to leverage
things like pattern analysis and just
help collect better intelligence against
people so with moonlight maze you know
some of the log patterns that they found
were that hey these people are working
in an office that kind of matches up in
you know that all the activity that
we're seeing is between eight to five
moscow time now we're chasing these logs
and we trace the back to a server in
Moscow I wonder who did that in 2003
there was another campaign called Titan
ring these attacks focused on defense
contractors and DOD and the attack
vectors for these was social engineering
emails it's important to highlight the
fact this fact because they did an
extensive amount of reconnaissance
before performing their initial attacks
recon is key to the success of these
campaigns better recon leads to better
social engineering attacks all the
all the communications actually ended up
getting traced back to China now that
wasn't the chats not say that was a
Chinese government but it got traced
back to China in 2006 there was psyche
pas this was a really really
sophisticated campaign that targeted key
us industries such as telecommunications
harbor manufacturers defense contractors
and aerospace organizations unlike a lot
of bots at the time psyche block clients
didn't talk back to the command control
server at regular intervals so it was a
lot difficult especially for the tools
that exist at a time to notice that
initially you know you know most botnets
they'll communicate every 30 minutes
back to the C&C server just to do a
check back if you just say hey check in
15 minutes and then next check in 30
minutes of the next check in 32 min
that really throws off and just manual
analysis at humans there because you're
looking for patterns right there was
some other really interesting
characteristics from the malware
utilized in this campaign they hid their
their DLLs that they use for
exploitation as Microsoft dll's that's
really really easy stuff to do take a
resource editor right flick say hey
let's change it from saying oh my god I
run an evil corporation LLC to microsoft
corporation that actually hides a lot
better than you think that mean you may
consider exactly exactly um it also had
some other characteristics that would
time soph itself to match the timestamp
of svchost so you know if you're looking
for like time patterns it kind of hides
itself and then it's at this really
really cool technique to perform
persistence which was kind of cutting
edge at the time so we can actually you
know see the actual the important part
is what it does is it deletes its
dropper task most I exe that launches
itself from from the startup folder to
remove any traces of resistance e1 Ram
so when you when you put up the computer
you can't see it being when it's
executed a new thread is created that
detects the ending of a window session
only when windows exits does it relocate
itself to the startup folder to survive
reboot since it only exists in startup
folder when required live analysis
techniques probably miss it when startup
entries are inspected and again you know
this is for the kind of analysts that
are quickly looking through things
automated schools and just you know not
paying a lot of attention and that is
just easy ways to hide from them
in 2009 there was a campaign named ghost
am very very extensive and it's
interesting because you can kind of tell
a lot about you know the Mauer operators
about who's controlling and who's
performing these campaigns by their
targets you'll see here that it's had a
pretty good list of targets in Taiwan
India Thailand Germany Iran and Tibetan
exiles centers um when you combine that
with location analysis like the fact the
C&C servers were posted from the same
region as a signals intelligence
facility in China you kind of learn a
lot about what you can tell from the
group and that's some other features you
know included the ability to utilize
audio and video recording from devices
that would find in the network but it
also had a really really really massive
OPSEC failure and op SEC is another key
thing to always be aware of essentially
some of the seed some of the CTU servers
that talked back had similar records in
the end a host and the movers they're
both survived lost half 33 @ hotmail.com
you do a little bit of Google magic and
that leads you to a blog post on Windows
hacking which is on the left hand side
here if you do a quick look at the
profile you can see that this guy's
handle is lost 33 get his date of birth
place of residence and his personal
motto the board soldier swing on an
empty battlefield the trail would
normally go cold here because this guy
never posted again but you know kind of
going back to the intrinsic flaw of
security and how humans are stupid let's
do a google search for this motto and
ooh you come up to a new blog title the
board soldiers blog space at this point
you know assuming that they're the same
person he changes his handle from lost
33 to damn foot nine but I know you're
probably thinking Jonathan this is just
speculation I mean this isn't concrete
evidence to you I must say you just
activated my check
basically the fact of the matter is it's
somehow these two personas share the
same motto the same birthplace in the
same birth place of residence I mean
that kind of indicates that they're
probably the same person but in all
seriousness don't cross contaminate your
handles you can have a public handle you
can have a private handle make new
handles for each campaign be random ops
X key but not enough apparently in 2010
there was another one called Operation
Aurora now this one was kind of
interesting just because of who they
were targeting right they're looking for
developers and development companies
large organizations that hosted you know
software code base management Google was
one of the people that were targeted and
whenever they realized that hey these
people were probably Chinese they
actually left a Chinese market because
of it ultimately the goal of this miss
campaign was to put malicious code in
pro in the code base of solutions before
they even left the market you're
downloading trusted programs and now
they're packed with mauer that no one
even knows about that's the ultimate win
at that point um the commander control
servers were also hosted on rackspace
accounts so they could post these up
anywhere and it was a lot harder to you
know determine where these were coming
from although looking at the source of
the phishing emails you could see that
they were coming out of smtp server from
city in china which just so happened a
host and intelligence facility huh
and then there's 2010 with one of my
favorite campaigns Stuxnet these
targeted the Iranians and their nuclear
control facilities it was amazing it's a
very very sophisticated campaign that
supposedly has some origins of American
and/or Israeli you know characteristics
it's a self-cleaning malware and by
exploiting 40 days it would cause really
it would cause I you know nuclear
centrifuges to spend really really fast
and pretty much explode it had three
modules one that was the worm that
executes routines related to the main
payload a link file that automatically
execute the propagated copies of the
worm and a rootkit component responsible
for hiding malicious files and processes
preventing the detection and presence of
sucks on it the other really cool thing
about this is that scared the bejesus
out ever going was the fact that it
infiltrated an air-gapped network you're
not gonna put your you're not going to
network your uranium enrichment
facilities that's just probably not
smart when you're running up structured
that scared a lot of people and you know
initially most people thought the
initial attack vector must have a no
they found some guy that had access to a
USB and that was able to drop us be in
there what people don't normally talk
about the Stuxnet was how did that USD
manage to get infected that leads us to
talking about the supply chain attack
vector which is just beautiful so
essentially let's see here you have this
organization called foolin Technic
international what they do is they
create automated systems for industrial
Iranian industrial facilities next month
the group called neta international
group who is a component supplier for
industrial systems specifically Iranian
industrial systems and they also make
products for with potential military
applications and then the month after
that control gostar jahed company who's
an industrial control systems vendor who
sells to iran was hit with an
another was hit with sucks in it as well
most people think that net and ghosts
are were used as like
intelligence-gathering hubs which makes
sense you know the entire time that
you're in there you're kind of seeing
who are these guys telling to and
essentially these guys also the Iranians
they all are in the same space so you
kind of think they're all talking to
each other and when you have a foot hole
in all of them that really really helps
the amount of reconnaissance that you
can do and you are able to collect much
more effective and actionable
intelligence finally a year year
afterwards it hits Cal electric who's
the developer of the centrifuges that
were used that we're targeting Stuxnet
so going back to the code based attacks
it's like it really kind of makes sense
as to how all this happen you know
they're good they're going to send a
developer to update firmware on these
centrifuges at some point right USB key
infected code base goes in Stuxnet worm
destroys the Center for you just deletes
itself boom everyone's happy well so
with the nuclear facilities are gaps the
attacks were conducted in the
assumptions the firm's own exchange
information with clients thereby
facilitating the attack on Iran's
nuclear program and then in 2012 there
is another one called flame this one was
actually discovered by the Iranian cert
team and some interesting changes took
place here there was some hints from
ghost you know taking some it's from
ghost net flame had the ability to
collect information via bluetooth
devices around compromised house so if
your computer had bluetooth on it and
you had bluetooth enabled on your phone
I'm now able to pull info off of your
phone bids we it's Bluetooth let's
assume for a second that the creators of
Stuxnet we're American and due to the
fact that flame shares some code was
Stuxnet it's really interesting to see
that the location of C 2 servers were
not for once and they're presumed
location of origin another really
interesting feature of the c2 panel for
flame was it the way it was disguised
it's made to look completely benign to
you know any passerby so if these are
hosted on VPS or you know like Rackspace
account somewhere and then they're going
to say oh this server seems to be doing
something funky as the rack spaces
administrator I'm going to pierce
through her to see if I see anything on
returning looking at this panel you see
things like you know it doesn't use bot
bot net oh my god ultimate botnet 3000
uses common words like data upload
download client news blog ads it just
disguises it makes it look not
threatening this was likely done to
deceive those guys in 2013 there was
another campaign called rain awesome
really really incredibly sophisticated
malware ever get a chance read the
analysis paper on it because it's really
cool you know very highly modular uses
the same technique to mimic Microsoft
drivers and it had a pretty wide target
specifically a lot of those targets just
happen to be in telecommunications so
you're kind of attacking infrastructure
at that point it employed a lot of stuff
and a lot of antique forensics and it
also used a custom-built virtual file
system and even alternative encryption
just encryption types that weren't
commonly used or just slightly modified
the encryption that was being used
another key thing to look at is the fact
that it used multiple means of protocols
talk back to the CNC server so it's not
just talking back over IRC or PGP or
whatever it's using ICMP cookies IRC p2p
it's just using a multitude of protocols
so that it's a lot harder to figure out
how data is feeding exfiltrated
it remained undetected for a long time
because of you know they try to hide it
as much as they cook we're going to give
a special mention to the belt rom hack
2013 that was unofficially done by GCHQ
um they're using a little bit more
interesting attack vector basically what
happened is they can't assume that they
compromised the backbone of the internet
right or whatever in front of Bel jicama
they pretty much just man in the middle
of everything so they were looking at
system administrators and they said hey
I see you're going to LinkedIn before
you go to LinkedIn I'm going to
intersect your request upload a little
bit of you know execute code that's
going to execute and then pass you
through the LinkedIn oh and now I have a
shell in your box sorry um you can
literally inject code in transit
transparently by intercepting the
requests and all you got to do is
control network infrastructure another
key point is the fact that they
performed really really extensive
reconnaissance reconnaissance leads to
success that's a fact use reconnaissance
yeah all right history lessons done you
guys can wake up now let's take a quick
peek at some of the methodologies and
just properties of these of these
attacks and then how we can use them to
hack all the things rule number one it's
the location have you seen see to server
don't put it where you're attacking from
that's retarded you know even if you're
using junk boxes and but I'm my see two
servers right next to me in Florida is
that really the smartest thing to do
just like imagine if the u.s. launched
their attacks from an IP address located
in fort meade gee I wonder who did that
so for penetration testers that means
don't call don't use the host name of
your botnet as c2 dot your company name
com that's not very smart and for
governments host that out of the country
you have multiple partners why don't you
host your attack from Sweden or host
your attack from I don't know a server
you probably owned in China and for
malware operators you guys are black
hats hack people China many many
vulnerable systems own them and use them
VPS operators have been doing this for
years takings from them for extra kudos
and this is really cool you guys can
take a line from the NSA it's a tailored
up access operations group they use a
technique that they it's called a fourth
party collection called the pliant
warrior and essentially they penetrate
while you penetrate while you're getting
penetrator right they'll take a look at
existing botnet servers and see two
servers you know there's plenty out
there people are running snooze button
lets people earning pony soul or
whatever they hack into those hi there
botnet inside of it and now attribution
gets shifted right say you're the Bata
that you're running gets compromised or
somehow it gets discovered there's
already someone else running another
botnet on that c2 server they're going
to take the blame for it because oh
you're running a public you know you're
running a publicly known botnet
obviously our data is being communicated
back to you you must be be at fault that
will really really hinder the
investigation process don't get me wrong
there's ee service associated with this
technique like the fact that your
campaign might not last as long Oh like
the fact your campaign might not last as
long
but it really helps out in the long run
especially if they're really hot on your
tail they're going to get very
distracted just by looking at the
existing button mask more comprehensive
forms of penetration over someone else's
performer penetration again going back
to this very important key recon matters
intelligence and war is just the same as
intelligence cybersecurity extensive
reconnaissance will raise the
effectiveness of your operations and
this is especially true for fishing
campaigns you can't just send people hey
click me and you're good to go the more
tailored and more normally you make
something look the more effective it's
going to be recon should be also be
something that you perform constantly
throughout your operation it shouldn't
you shouldn't be doing recon at the very
beginning and say okay spearfishing is
done now will launch an attack when you
own a box start performing recon at that
from that vantage point start performing
recon from the next vantage point and
just really build a solid database of
information and it allows you to execute
attacks much more effectively another
key characteristic of these campaigns
has been patience let's look at the
sucks net group they waited an entire
year before commencing the final part of
their their attack there's a lot of
reasons reasons that the there's a
reason that many of these penetrations
were able to last as long as they were
and it wasn't just from viagra slow and
methodical movements tend to be much
more pleasurable for an attacker in the
long run so tread lightly
and anti forensics one of my favorites
so there's some common anti forensic
techniques shared across all of these
you know different different campaigns
they utilize secure secure delete shred
overwrite a file with zero and it's
suddenly nearly impossible to recover
for the rain see two servers the way
that they were discovered they were at
they were actually able to recover an
image from the the VPS is that they were
hosting from the you know VPS provider
because they were like hey we noticed
that these were being used in a malware
campaign can you provide us with an
image of the boss and they said sure
what the sea two operators actually
ended up doing initially was they
disabled all the logs including web
server logs so there was no logs
whatsoever located on the box you know
you might think but they have the image
and they can sink hole de campagne
whatever that won't give them a history
of previous clients so say for example
you deleted you know pots that you
compromised there earlier you're not
going to be able to trace that back and
that really hinders help center the
investigation masquerade DLLs masquerade
the names or functions and injects
drivers as something more legitimate
than oh hi ma'am our operator LLC hide
your panel in plain sight take it from
ring you know Google Google dorks are
awesome start looking for box and you'll
pretty much find a botnet panel don't
make it about don't make it so obvious
if it says ultimate uber leet botnet
you're just as bad as the people who you
overuse cloud also it's a lot easier to
hide from web crawlers
now we're going to talk about encryption
and encapsulation just we'll take a
quick look at fashion cleft which is
probably one of the coolest things that
has ever come out of NSA's tale about
access operations which is there you
know infiltrate penetration group
basically what this protocol does is it
takes a copy or a clone of a host packet
appends metadata and redirects copy
packets to a listening post or another
host hiding normal traffic still goes
out from the host but at the same time
it splits off you know at another hop
could obviously outside of the you know
of your target organization and then it
splits off and sends the data to to the
sea to server at that point the
investigators can't do anything if
you're if they start splitting splitting
information in transit there's not a
whole lot that can be done because the
device that's splitting the information
is no longer in control of you know your
target so they can't pulling the logs
off of it and analysis stops it also had
a keeper it also had a way to
authenticate the data copy packets and
help ensure integrity now I'm sure
there's not a lot of us a lot here that
can take a bit to make something like
that but it's definitely something cool
and cool to think about kind of CCB ever
be able to apply similar techniques
the key thing is don't get frustrated
tap select your data HTTP communications
should always be encrypted with at least
ssl no matter what even if you can't x
fill it over for 43 x fill it over 80
it'll help hide your attack no matter
what you know if if an analyst is going
to be looking at the say that all he's
going to see is oh there's junk you know
random packets going over over port 80
sure that might raise a red flag but
it's better than saying oh this is
obviously malware data going over port
80 DNS exfiltration is sometimes easier
to detect is sometimes easy to detect
and you know you'll typically see a lot
of invalid request to a single domain
Jesse's multiple domains split split it
and always use the bright protocol for
the right target so if you see as a say
its traffic coming off a windows box
that's probably not normal or looking at
a marketing user right they're never
going to use SSH they're probably never
going to use IRC so don't use IRC or SSH
as a communication protocol and you know
how you find that out by doing your
reconnaissance if you want to get a
little more advanced you can use you
know other special techniques split data
exfiltration across multiple protocols
on one on one hand you'll you'll send it
out over HTTP cookies on the other hand
you'll split a file send the other half
of the file out over IRC that puts it
makes a lot harder for an analyst to you
know put the pack put the information
back together and say here's what they
stole it's a lot easier to do whenever
you can provide a unique session
identifier but you have to be able to
hide the fact that its unique session
identifiers that make sense at that
point on your seats who served you'll
just be able to rebuild them by joining
the session identifiers you can even
send both information to two different
servers and then reassemble it on
another and then get the most out of
your etsy hose
change your CT server two points of
Facebook I mean as the data gets sent
over information let's get it's going to
be see seen as you know request sent to
facebook com not request sent to evil
see to server calm it's it's not one
hundred percent effective and you know
some automated tools might catch at some
not but humans make errors a lot of
times they're just going to see hostname
facebook com okay that's legitimate and
continue scanning on utilize the
weaknesses in humans right another key
is to aim higher expand its scope of
your targets cheap key targets that
these apt groups or tow rating is
infrastructure stop looking just that
you know clients and servers look at
routers switches firewalls if you own
those you own everything because you can
completely control the flow of
communication between your target hit
him where it hurts source control
management I mean looking at you know
are they using any applications that
they've developed for internal usage are
the system administrators hosting an
hour an internal get server and it the
scripts that are using you should be
attacking everything in your pen des
don't just focus on that you'll just
focus on one thing and then watering
hole attacks this isn't as applicable
penetration testers but you know look it
because you're restricted by anything
that's in scope so you want to look at
internal services being used internet
portals helpdesk portals file shares
edit those you know hide your malware
within those four black hats attack
whatever do your recon figure out what
slice and services they're using figure
out if any of them are vulnerable own it
oh no in the story and finally get
really creative with some supply chain
attacks there was a story a few years
ago about a guy that targeted the system
administrator during a penetration test
by sending him a US
keyboard that had a keylogger hidden
inside of it and it was one of the
state-of-the-art logitech once Ellison
mechanical keyboard thank you for being
a valued logitech customer as as a we've
decided to send you this gift as a
promotion soon administrators everyone
loves free stuff they're going to take
use of it take advantage of it and now
all his key strokes are being sent out
that's awesome utilize that another key
characteristic of these government
groups is that they're intercepting
routers and delivery to tart locations
and in planning mauer before they arrive
nope tampering with mail is illegal but
who cares also aim lower firmware based
attacks hard drive attacks rootkits
their way harder to do but they're
really incredibly awesome and they allow
for much much longer persistence so we
take a look at a program like NSA's i r8
monk it's used by their tailored access
operations groups and it you know
provides application persistence by
targeting the MBR at that point even if
you wipe the OS it doesn't matter it the
computers still owned so the next key
point is to throw the trail on your tail
there's a lot of power and based
analysis that goes into you know
identifying who an operator is writing
style gives a lot away there's an
application called the if you go to the
Hemingway Act where you can do is you
can take a block of text pasted into it
and it'll say you should probably change
these it essentially hemingway out looks
at your writing style and says this is
way too advanced for 5th graders you can
dump the sentence down eliminate the Sun
and stun this down done this down change
that around and suddenly it doesn't look
like you wrote it anymore change your
identity use multiple handles for
multiple campaigns don't use your one
handle for everything that can be traced
back to you
it's easy fake name generator calm click
generate click randomized and now you're
a whole new person and don't cross
contaminate your handles if you can have
a public handle that you do for IT
research right to security research
whatever you know hey you'll release
your your advisories that you discover
over that but if you're hacking stuff on
your night job don't use the same handle
for that so if you guys have any
questions I there's the best place
contact me or over jabber or Twitter um
you know it would be after the top but
you guys have any questions now I will
put that on my blog but that's a great
point
because they post think that that's like
a huge red flag the dns server result
even better be dns server so because
that's rarely ever detected even better
even better that that goes back to the
point i was saying expand your targets
control infrastructure and you control
everything right questions even there so
yeah thanks for sending my top and this
has been enjoy b-sides
you