test 123
test test test
you what
hopefully everybody it can hear me
if I'm around here present a little talk
on in this cybersecurity framework
mostly guys will be something new
probably learn to me from this when I
put either this talk it kind of made the
assumption that while there were
technical background with matrix pretty
some of the things that deal with
frameworks and controls or what you
probably have not been exposed to so I
kind of assumed a lack of knowledge in
these were areas are going to make sure
that everyone has brought a kind of a
good decent level so if you do you know
if you're the things I talk about it's
not meant to be an insult it just meant
that i'm not sure what the audience
experience and knowledge is someone
trying to cover cover it for everyone
blogspot it's kind of an occasional flaw
be a fight have something I want to talk
about or see what kind of bothers me a
blog about it so it's not a regular blog
when they are do try to talk about us in
the upcoming events let us see in the
area they important i plan to sort of
blog about today's event I kind of keep
my impression terms of what i thought
the event was it like myself will
quickly I come from a technical
background and a lot of people that you
work in my area was not called
governance risk and compliance too often
come from when our auditing or an
accountant tight background i come from
a technical background kind of had a
very bright career and I sort off going
to be a certain software engineer it
went into system administration and then
into the security one thing is that I
was actually part of a 90 or addiction
that was assessed at CMM level three and
you know what that means that we don't
i'll point out what why that's important
later on i do have experience or a lot
of different these frameworks without
them very very popular whether its
regulatory firm I swear I k HIPAA think
of like pci iso 27001 and two and now
with the new substrate framework that
just kind of fits in with what i've been
working
I'm awful acted in the I say some other
organization as well there's kind of a
background of what we're gonna cover it
can I give you a background
understanding of what we're talking
about in terms of what our frameworks
and what our controls and so we're going
to the Miss cybersecurity framework kind
of talk about what that is so you've a
better understanding of it going to talk
about some resources that you can make
use of he's gotten more and more popular
and I think it's going to increase so
background I actually started this whole
process of creating this was actually
back in February of 2013 when president
obama signed an executive order called 1
36 36 improving critical infrastructure
cybersecurity it was all about you know
let's create a substrate framework that
companies and organizations can follow
to reduce cyber risks if you're into the
X he can get this document and take a
look at it NIST which was the group that
was to be to develop this they had a
bunch of workshop that they called him
in 2013 these were workshops that
brought together people from the private
industry from the public industry to get
some feedback and understanding of what
they thought was important they actually
released the first version in February
of 2014 which means that this this
framework is less in a little over a
year old
that didn't had a six workshop in
October of last year to kind of get a
feedback in terms of the people who had
initially started using it what what
they like with it didn't liked and kind
of been laying the groundwork for
possible improvements they didn't reach
the report in December of 2014 about
what they got out of this workshop now
one thing they talk about here they talk
about these is critical infrastructure
it's like what the heck does that mean
this is what they mean by the critical
infrastructure all these different
industries and quite honestly most of
you here are probably in some of these
industries if you're working in
government you're working in healthcare
so for you probably fall into one of
these critical infrastructures what is
the big push of a federal government if
you not IP services and whatnot for
companies that are in these critical
services will you follow their
information technology but you probably
might be working for coming that are in
these different areas I know for what
the work we do
there they fall under some of these
areas missed if you're not familiar with
what NIST it's the National Institute of
Standards and Technology the part of the
Department of Commerce while their main
focus or the original focus with
standards and measurements they've
actually gotten into a lot of technology
stuff nothing something down technology
standards by and large it's been the
government that's been using their NIST
standards but you know these are
available for everyone to make use of
one that you may have heard about is
what's known as the NIST special
publications 800 series these are a
series of publications over almost
getting PI over 150 now various top you
know some were are more fundamental
someone were broader I know there's one
for like you know cloud computing
there's two three there about malware
risk assessments and so forth and all of
them are free if you want to make use of
you go to the website and there they are
as PDFs we can download them some of
them are more active in terms of
updating there's someone now they've got
into like a third or fourth revision or
some they wrote in 15-20 years ago and
haven't updated a sentence so this is a
group that with that the government said
hey you're going to put the other the
cybersecurity framework I don't think
that anything that happened was a couple
months ago the White House had what was
called the cybersecurity summit or full
and some cyber security and consumer
protection held its Stanford actually if
you're curious about what they cover it
cuz they covered a lot of different
topics including cyber security you can
actually go to the White House website
whitehouse.gov and you can get a report
of what they talked about and when they
was interesting was they talked about
the status the cybersecurity framework
and its use and so forth and I've
actually pulled the other from different
sources center where it's going right
now and it's actually it's convincing
how widely has become you know put to
use already so this is something just
from this from the private industry area
you have lots of companies are already
adopting the cybersecurity framework you
have Intel you have apple yeah bank of
america and what a lot of what these
other companies are also doing is not
only they're adapting it for their own
use but they're telling their vendors ie
companies that they deal with and either
get goods or services from to say we
want you to use this as well so it's
kind of its rapidly being adapted or
being put to use by a lot of different
industries some other ones are kind of
interesting is a IG is using it in how
they write cybersecurity insurance
that's the biggest one thing I hear a
lot is that people are like oh we had
the cyber security issue oh let's just
go get insurance to cover ourselves but
what they're going to do is going to use
the framework as a way to assess
companies to see how good they're doing
in their security because if they're not
doing too well then they should probably
be charging more for cybersecurity
insurance for them and the legal
community apparently is looking at it as
a way to set down a standard of care
again using it to take a look at company
to say are they following good practices
or not and if they're not then they're
not going due diligence you know good
care and which means that they probably
might be penalized for that that's just
private industry and pump in the
government side is the same thing a lot
of government agencies are now using it
DoD doee department homeland security is
using it
one thing is the federal gun is also
incentivizing it to use IE encouraging
more people to use it so they're doing
things like we're building it into
grants and such like oh if you get a
grant from the VOE or FEMA they're going
to say and we want you to use this as
well to assess yourself several state
governments are using it those the ones
that i have seen reference and some of
these sources and what i think is really
kind of insane foreign governments are
looking at it I mean we created this
opportunity framing for our use within
the US but it's funny that the UK is
looking at it the European unity is
looking at it the SEC again when these
things were is they're looking at it as
a way to tell financial organizations
that are hegler heavy regulated you need
to be following this so depending on
where you're at you may actually be in a
company or an industry were there
already starting to push it so you need
to be kind of aware of what the
cybersecurity framework is because it's
probably comes through the letter we've
already dealing with with our clients we
tech science coming up and say like hey
we need to be assessed against this we
need your help to look at our practices
and see where we stand ok but we kept
probably the framework what is a
framework and this is a term that
actually i'll be honest when I got into
IT security what I never heard the term
framework that's something that I've
only seen kind of in the last few years
with some of these concepts so I want to
make sure people are saying what we mean
by a framework I think so there's some
there's some misunderstandings and
whatnot and there's a lot of them which
makes it worse basically it's based on
an abstraction assessed on basic
controls things that you should be doing
in your organization but it's meant to
be in a very high level i saw one
article that talked about the cypress
tree framework and he kind of the person
kind of complaining about oh it wasn't
detailed enough
it's not supposed to be detailed that's
the whole idea of a framework it's meant
to be a high level you know basics of
how you set things up not getting down
into an indie gritty to tell you what
you need to be doing because then it's
not a framework it's kind of a
misunderstanding about that again it
doesn't specify technical solutions so a
framework might say hey you need
antivirus but it's not going to tell you
how to implement that or what's best for
you because some people I say well we're
going to use white listing and we're
going to use you know these are our
antivirus products here and there that's
great a framework is not going to tell
you that that's what you need to
understand about your needs in your
organization to define that these are
some of the frameworks that are out
there too maybe you might have heard
about these the one the copper rule
familiar the lobby was the 27,000 lon
infinite 7002 which sets down was for do
as information security management
systems this is an international
standard a lot of companies are
following this another one it's cobit
five which comes from eye sockets that's
not what's called IT governance ITIL is
one of the people might have heard of co
so if you're from the financial side you
might have heard of co so this has the
100 which is more of federal control so
if you're not in the federal government
you're probably not worried about 853
another one that probably a lot of
people heard about why you're a year
will improve the sands top 20 which is
portos the critical security controls
yes
well kind of will get what you'll see
you know how it ties in and it actually
kind of interesting way how it does that
I pull this off the internet kind of
show you what we've been by some of that
is that framework this is just kind of
one we're kind of talks about the
different elements need to advertise
like scoping system model and so forth
controls of the term if you hear a lot
about and I don't and I think a lot of
really don't really fully on here what
control is I know if you'd asked me a
few years ago I would have stumbled
through it because I never use that term
before even though to be honest i've
used controls my whole career basically
there are just a specific activities
performed by persons designed to ensure
that business objectives are met basis
meant to be you need to be doing this
you know to make sure things are being
done right and we have a lot of examples
and probably guys probably use a lot
easier change management system that's
the control sutton out of standard for
password that's the control you've all
over control we probably have these were
in your organization access control and
so forth but i know for a lot of us i
mean i always tell these are just
policies but they're actually controls
that's the fun of a thats a control can
be a policy it can be a procedure can be
a guidance I've had people talk to me
about what's my experience with the
controls after I told them I've been
writing policies were treated for years
and I sent much wonder do they really in
10 what a control is because those
policies are controls now ideally if you
have a control alexia patchwork you know
policy the hey patchers must be in a
certain form and so forth you'd like to
implement that control into the system
what most of us do is we put in into the
system where it forces you to adhere to
the standard when you create a password
and that's great to implement that
control but it can well could be as
simple as a as a as a written document
that says hey patchers we've been
created this way and I create a kind of
example I said pathak have a crashing
against malware that's the control and
the thing is this control oxys this is
the lobbies frame which I want to pull
them up and it kind of funny when you
look at these different frameworks how
much time they spend on it I the
cybersecurity framework only has we've
seen one statement that matches up to it
where is with the critical security
controls they have a whole section which
goes into like about a dozen sub items
all about malware so kind of varies in
terms of how much these different
controls deal with different topics some
it's like one-liner a do this others
will go into like three or four or five
or six more in-depth I'd integers how
much they think is important with I so
they have a basic control but then they
go and they spend like a page or two of
other information kind of you
information and background lights
important and some advice and so forth
so it all kind of varies upon the
controller by the framework that you
make use of where your company is making
use of so the cybersecurity framework
this is actually the true name of it is
framework for improving critical
infrastructure cyber security as
currently version one it came out in
February of 2014 it's meant to be
voluntary at this point there is no
government regulations that require
anyone to follow it I think that's going
to be the case everything I seem to get
an indication in terms of things I'm
hearing from the government what is they
really don't want to put it into our
regulatory requirements so it's not
going to be like a hippo requirement
where you're required to do it and be
assessed against it and so forth they're
more trying to put it out there and
encourage it
doing kind of incentivize it as opposed
to forcing you to use it it's also meant
to be a one size fit all and that's a
problem with the again with people
thinking of frameworks that everyone has
to do the same thing the idea is that
each organization needs to take an
assessment of them themselves what is
important for them what is their risk to
them to focus on what's important for
them and that's going to really big go
for a lot of people because we kind of
have this mindset Oh everyone needs to
do the exact same thing without realize
that no every organization is a little
different you know the threats for
different ordinations are different so
some more to defeat your focus in
different areas and so forth it's also
meant to be a living document they're
going to be updating it based upon an
input and usage and so forth so we'll
see how that goes it's just again it's
busted it is little over a year out so
we'll see how that goes the framework is
basically has recommended three major
parts there's the core there's the
profiles and there's the tears I think
for most people we're focusing on the
core that's the that's the kind of the
heart of it the core is broken been
defined functions those are broken up
into categories and the further going
into subcategories and then what's
really interesting is the subject
remember then cross matches those
subcategories to other frameworks that
kind of goes into your question in terms
of like how they match up that's what
they did they've actually gone through
and said hey this control method up to
these controls which is kind of
interesting
it's not meant to be replacement you
know they did these crossovers because
if your are using it then you can kind
of match them up and using the
conjunction right right yeah so sorry
you can you can cross mattress you don't
have to go and toss out what you're
using it can use this in conjunction
with what you're using you know what to
think of what the thing is good and
there's the profiles of tier that's a
little trickier I'll get into that and
this is how its laid out you have the
five functions and they color code them
then there's about you cook divided into
categories would you go into
subcategories and they have the
information reaver references this is
actually how its laid out in the
document if you take a look at it and
this is actually that's the five
function they use these color coding
really so I protect attack respond color
identify is laying out the groundwork
for what we call in information security
management system ie and it's broken you
can't see it but a thing such as setting
down your governance for IT and IT
security doing a risk assessment
understanding what your risks card for
your organization you know understanding
your strategy to how to manage risk
things such as knowing what your assets
are and assets are not just you know
your computer but also your software new
systems and so forth and understanding
your business environments what kind of
like lays down how things are and then
it takes the next step is you're putting
in protection methods you know access
control and training and so forth and
then detect well that's all about you
know monitoring and auditing and know
what the heck's going on with your
system or who's going to access your
system and then if something does happen
you have response yeah whether it's an
incident response whether you have a
disaster recovery had to respond to it
and then once you've responded to you
how to get back and running on your
business that's recovery what I do like
is something
that aren't ways and other friend works
is if you see the response to require
you having IV improvements you have an
incident did you do a lessons learned
have you figured out what went wrong or
what you can do to prove it and then go
back and improve how your act how you
responding and how you're doing things a
lot of people don't always do that they
don't do that post-mortem reviewed how
they improve things but the subject
rimac actually puts it as very explicit
they want you to be improving things and
getting doing a better job I think
that's me is real important because you
know as we see things going on as
professional as we see hey you know
target got hit what do they do right or
wrong so that you can do better in your
organization that's sort of improvements
is really really critical so I kind of
pulled this example out to kind of help
you guys understand what it looks like
so we have access control which is under
protection and this is what they have in
the sub-q framework it's you know access
to assets are going to authorize user
processes or devices and to authorize
activities and transactions so that's
that's the function which is here put
any other protect the category is access
control and then it breaks it up into
four sub categories number one is about
identifications and credentials for
authorized devices you know number two
is about physical access you know that
means things such as hey you have it in
a secure room or you've got it in a
secure data center three if you have
remote access controlled your people
dialing into your system and for that
you have access permissions that are
managed and you're dealing with least
privilege and separation of duties and
that is as far as it goes in the sub
security framework it doesn't go any
deeper and turns explanation which you
know I think for some people frozen
lawfully figure they're going to go into
a lot of depth and whatnot but that's
why I like the fact that they do they do
the matching up to other frameworks
because then you can go to the other
frameworks and see what they say what
they expose upon and the TV go actually
go deeper 45 is about a network integra
you having segregating the accelerated
networks there's another example again
taken from the cemetery or framework
this one is from identifying has asset
management bastard laughing six
different steps but this is how they
laid out the framework in the document
they talked about a function that had a
cavalry they had a subcategory you see
visual references with a new the actual
map check the specific area in those
different frameworks I realize that some
effects don't voice match up so you have
an ISO 27001 and the same if your
organization is already using ISO 27001
as your standard you can then match up
and know what you're already doing in in
the cybersecurity framework and then
take a look at what is different or
unique because there are things that are
different and unique in the subject
framer from others these the information
reference to the exit there's this code
five there's the critical security
controls or sans top 20 there's these
next two ones which are more people who
are dealing with scatta i surf I 701 and
then of course the the NIST 853 which is
more for federal government so these the
match up to do and I've also heard of
people who have done matchups with PCI
DSS the secretary framework with gun
matches up for HIPAA sub security
framework and so far we've not seen
those but they're out there i also have
i don't i don't think i might have
enough for everyone i also was able to
get from sands they did this poster last
year with Maricopa the critter critter
controls but what it also does is also
includes then this opportunity framework
in a matchup matrix between critical
screen controls I so 20 said that wasn't
to DC I you know secretary framework so
I'll pass these out toward the end
the next element is the profile which is
kind of its more you use more for when
you're implementing the subject to do
framework and what it does is it kind of
figured okay where do we stand and where
do we want to go so they talked about
the current profile which is okay where
are you for each two categories and
subcategories on with this control and
this one you know not too well and
here's where you stand and then again
you have to assess your organization and
what is important for you you then set
down the future profile where do you
want to be for each of those categories
and obviously there's going to be a
difference mean where you're at where
you want to be so you do a gap
identification and now you know what you
need to focus on without him from that
within you within see what's more
important and spend your resources on
and this is kind of how it's done then
you have a current profile your target
and read well no need to focus on based
upon where you where you're at where you
want to be
tears is really weird second I and I
don't know how everyone really fully
understand it I know I don't fully
understand it so I'm not you know it's
almost like why and people were heard it
was basically a maturity model it's not
a maturity model and I'm not sure how
many people know what we mean by a
maturity model i'll talk about that
shortly but i think it's really kind of
important but it's poorly understood i
think a lot of people are like I know
just skimming over this point they have
four tiers as partial risk inform
repeatable and adapt and they assess
these tears based on the maturity the
organization in risk management and the
integration which men into the
organization and then an external
participation that means how the
organization is participating with other
organizations and so forth in terms of
information you know passing on
information of getting information so
forth that's become a big thing nowadays
hey we need to be sharing information
that we see so we can prove in six years
improve security so what is the maturity
model again I don't know if how many
people heard the term before and know
what it is but basically it's about a
degree of formality or basically how
good your processes are in your
organization
ad hoc or what I've seen with IT
organizations it's the ones that were
during what we call firefighter mode you
know doing everything by the seat of the
pants you know if you for is to be your
building systems you build systems ad
hoc and just kind of like do it
differently so every system is not quite
the same and then when you go to any
support work it's a pain in the butt
because they're all different or you
have it clearly documented and followed
procedure to build every system that's
repeatable so every system is the same
and then when it comes time to support
them ahead of having a dozen or two
dozen or several hundred systems that
are all not quite the same you got all
these just litter saying that all
managed you can easily do it dr. team
that's the difference in having an ad
hoc yeah low maturity or no maturity for
a very mature organization and that
could be really really important because
you know I know from my experience is it
if you're you know in an immature
organization you know your be very
costly for your for your company or the
coming to get really tired of your
organization
get rid of you and I for if you're not
doing the job that you're you're
supposed to be doing some maturity
models can be what we call process
oriented and some are what we would be
call process technology oriented one
that you may or may not have heard of
it's called CMM capability maturity
model which is a rigid crated for
software but then we started using for
other areas and that's what I'm familiar
with you know personally because I have
I was involved with the orientation that
had to be CNN assess there are others
out there made her attorney with an
older model or save your growth model
which is more people process technology
oriented we don't think for IT security
I think that's a better and some
proceeded to be more people process
technology oriented come to their
maturity this is CM m for those who've
not seen it before it's a five stage
level and the idea is sort of level one
with your ad hoc initial but if you
wanted
requires management product line and so
forth you need to do all those processes
well before you can be go to say it's
too if you want to go to 63 you need to
be doing everything it doubles two and a
total three and so forth with the
ultimate goal let's try to get yourself
to level 5 which is really really really
difficult I know we got level 3 it was
for us it was a lot of time a lot of
energy a lot of money to get to level 3
but it was worth it because we didn't
get out sourced like other IT group to
our company this is the other time which
basically has their columns here through
our policy formation and so for and the
assessment level
how are you
which is kind of interesting is that in
a CMM type model the goal of the top
level whereas in the CSF model the other
one well that's not necessarily the goal
harsha would be after ad hoc or risk
informing you have a better honey what's
going on you have things under here a
little bit better under control then you
keep improving yourself for eatable and
adaptive and this is what's going to
need about the tears I think is that
they do encourage you if you're at tier
1 to get to tier 2 but here's what I
think that find is interesting is that
going to a higher level isn't something
that you have to do it depends in your
organization because in a biscuit it
becomes costly in time and money to go
to 23 you go to 4 and maybe for your
organization it's not worth it so I'm to
be staying it too is where you need to
be
so unlike with CMM where the ultimate
goal for almost everyone who does CMM is
a hey we get 25 that's the big goal in
the subframe were getting 24 isn't it
isn't the big goal and this well thought
was kind of interesting is that they say
that getting to your target profile I
get into where you want to be for all
the different categories and
subcategories is more important than
getting to a higher tier level so again
I mean the tears is kind of that to me
is kind of a strange part of the sucker
for your framework I don't know if it's
everyone fully understands it because
it's not a whole lot of information and
even the document so
well that's house music it's all it's
all based upon your risk college new
risk exposure is you might have a set of
you to the time yourself and that isn't
it our frustration when you look at it
because I mean it's not a fairly
freaking big document you know they
don't give you a whole lot of guidance I
think you're trying to like it's kind of
a balance between do we tell you tell me
what to do and then I restrict your
decisions or we made a high level enough
that everyone's that are free to come up
to what's best for you it's kind of a
balancing act and maybe in future
version they'll have it those who look
better will come out with lessons
guidance and some suggestion and so
forth because again the only thing is
like you need your organization you know
you have your own issues important to
Eurovision what the risks are or another
word addiction gives it took a risk and
so by understanding what is that
affected a lot of work or they should do
a poor job of that that drives what is
important to focus your activities I
think it's kind of like it trying to be
I think not trying to be a one size fit
all it's going to be a make it flexible
enough to fit different organizations
it's one of the things we're like here
is it too loose or croissant yeah so it
is and I think one thing also i think
what's going to happen is is you might
see people where they're going to come
out of her life you know hey if you're
the financial industry peers may be
suggested you know profile for you who
are in financial world
you know oh hey you're in manufacturing
this may be what you need to look at oh
you're in healthcare and maybe this is
what you need or something like that I
think that that's something I would hear
in it that you may have see that where
people are hard working with it and
coming up or something my page you will
samples and guys into one after that
might help
a little bit
and then you seeking that crossover and
what not even dhss i mean i'll mention
about this supports to the gotta come
back and over some of their stuff and
cemetery framework so i think we can see
more and more of that stuff it's just
not there yet but i think we'll see
something like the next year or two as
more more hard ization views and more
puzzling more or anything about our
partner to push it yeah they needed have
provided premium support it's not quite
there but i think it's coming this is
actually coming acting from how you
implement it and their day was
prioritizing scope it you want to poker
pro by ear where you currently at and
how do you be you know the framework and
again it's why I kind of like the
matchups with the other framework so if
you're like an ISO 27001 or two
organization you know when you want a
bit of sustenance that and sort of like
okay what matches up oh we're doing this
we do with this
things we're not doing is that important
for us you want to have your risk
assessment I wondering what are the
risks that face your organization then
drive where you need to be and then once
you have that you have your ally to
acquire the apps and the implement
and they also have this chart from the
subcommittee framework booklet or its
again about your ongoing improvement is
it really worth it was ongoing
improvement and everybody involved with
it I think for a lot of us were probably
down here imitation of maybe more here
but it has to be memorable it has to
come from a senior level say we're going
to do this the business processes
ongoing improvements and so forth and
that's and that's a real difficult thing
for a lot of organizations who don't do
if you will are not really mature in
terms of how they are handling their
security I said I do assessment with
organizations I go in the air one per
table hey you know let's say your
policies and procedures you know we
don't have this
okay so it's like started turning it
that step 1 so some of the resources out
there I think more coming again it's
moving out a little over here so we're
going to be that we have some stuff but
a lot of things isn't there and I'm not
really sure if we can see some of these
things but it might be a lot so we're
training there is no official training
on this you know I don't think there
ever will be the only 20 about half
pound is a soccer at a two-day course on
some of your affirmative report because
they're behind code of five it's all
cope with five oriented so that's this
is the only one you get a certificate
complete exam that's not a certification
that's just a certificate of completion
well that's going to be interesting i'm
not sure haven't seen this is i saw that
if you're not aware is doing its cyber
security conference in DC and october
and i want to look at the preliminary
information they have and they talk
about how oh where have these tracks and
guess what they call the tracks oh let
me i'm good at each track and then
protract track and a detective track and
am I thinking yeah where did you get
those terms from me so it's gonna be
insane when we see the list of the
workshops or the presentations at their
conference to see how oriented it is to
secretary framework
but soccer seem to be the only group
that seemed to be kind of behind getting
one cream too kind of getting behind it
in terms of pushing it certifications no
there's no certifications whether it's
whether it's good or bad other
frameworks do have those I mean with
cooked with cobit with a high too with
ISO 27001 and two you can get
certifications like you can be certified
in terms of a base knowledge you can be
sort of quite an implementer of it you
can be a certified in assessing it
nothing for cybersecurity framework and
don't expect that to change because it
would probably have to come from with
missed approval yes
no totally different it's yeah the side
of you know yugatech separate the
Submariner this subsidy framework from
the very book you know right into the
800 series they're totally separate this
meant to me to overall all-encompassing
cybersecurity framework in the 800
series the only one that said it's a
close match is 853 but that's only focus
on the federal government and it doesn't
have a total match
yeah but that's again things more
tightly to miss the mist 800 special
publication which is for federal
government whereas the Secretary's
framework is very very new and it's also
you know meant to be for everyone not
just federal government in sort of
private industry and everyone else so
now a lot of people do can get confused
especially when they're kind of familiar
with the 800 series about like oh oh
well isn't that the same it's not really
I mean there is some matchups to it but
its focus on a different area well
actually I would say that the summer
period actually meant to be a broader
focus and because it's so broad it can't
be is real specific versus the other one
which is more federal government
computing in terms of books and
resources at this point there's not a
whole lot either you get the framework
itself from this it's a PDF or the
website they have actually a section on
their webpage for it and they have some
other other documents that you can
download or other things that work with
it the only person other group ended up
in Britain a book on it is aisaka and
it's in putting this under pretty
framework using coba five big surprise
there if you're a number you get that
for free if you're not it's going to
cost you quite a bit I think if I want
to get the print version as a member it
can cost me 35 bucks if you're not a
member i think it's like 80 bucks but
there's nothing else I've done it I've
got an amazon and search down side of
your framework no one else has written
any books I don't know what we're going
to see one
there are other item on Terra if our
mother free Intel had written a white
people on a used piece of it you
downloaded for free price waterhouse
cooper has created a white paper I'll
adopt exceptionally framework this is a
resource page tied to it which they're
putting some stuff there the power of
Homeland Security Network all the c3
site so it has resources there and I'm
hoping that we'll see more and more of
these resources popping up but hey I
said it's only been a little over a year
so we'll see as we get more and more
stuff out there version 2 oh I don't
know I will point out that ISO 27001 it
took about five years between versions
like that we've only had it out for a
year so I'm not you know I expected
version 2 for another four or five years
I think more people need to use it beat
it up you know see what works what
doesn't work and we'll see where that
goes these going to make conclusions I
really think we'll see more and more
people using it more uncertain more more
organizations using it what I do like
especially since they did the matchups
is that people don't have to see it as
an either/or proposition they don't have
to you know if there are using
there are using ISO 27001 they going to
use the substring along with it one of
our clients that was the case there are
financial organization they already had
built their information security
infrastructure around ISO 27001 and the
came to watch because there are
financial institution the SEC comes
along and says you need to be assessed
to get by against the cybersecurity
framework you know so for us we just did
the matchups okay you know you're doing
actually twist I'm the one I pay it
matches up to you know these items in
the subsidy framework how will you doing
it you know and the few ones that like
don't match up because there are some
that don't we assess them and say hey
how we do on this one how you doing that
point and so it wasn't they had to go
and throw out what they have done it was
just going to like will layer it on top
or add to what you're already doing
you think we're seeing increase are they
using it especially with various other
large companies now telling there's
their vendors or suppliers however you
want to call it until this financial
institution they actually are a a vendor
to bank of america and whomever haven't
yet come to my cell hey we wanted you to
do this also but you know that could
happen so you could be an arrow religion
of where you're not using it now but
maybe in six months or a year you're
gonna be expected it to put it to use in
some manner depending on your industry
logging said i'm seeing a lot in
financial in the financial industry you
know other areas i know i think with
health care everyone's running around a
bit worried about HIPAA so i don't
really expect to see it there but i
think the ones that are more heavily
regulated whether it's a pci or from the
government are more likely to use it if
you're not don't follow in that area
maybe a little bit farther down the road
before you're gonna have to worry about
it so any questions
like that I had a few of these hand out
here I've heard it from sands and what I
like he hasn't had a poster on it you
can get this as a PDF but I asked and
send me a whole bunch of these don't
want to be able to pass them out to you
guys don't never have enough for
everyone
don't really need it someone who can use
it get it from the air but I think it's
a really good tool whatnot so any other
questions yes it's called the suckage
called implement yo and put inside
credit for instance that's the actual
official and if you if you search on the
disk CSF it'll take you to this website
and you can download the PDF it's kind
of really it's suffer from the 800 here
exponent so it's a holy totally separate
page on the Smiths I'm three framework
and you can go and get PDF there and
you'd like two or three other documents
I'd like an Excel spreadsheet that you
can help it'll help you out with some
stuff but if you look on the back of the
poster there's a the whole listing of
the matchup of iso with pci in the
critical security with 73 framework
that's what i find that that's why i
like that poster
I had all the ones i had a head you can
also get that out there the PDF from
their website I actually asked them
saying they send me a whole bunch so you
can probably you know drop the massive
gift if you're not in the stands mailing
list you dropped it in email
inconvenience in your hardcopy but you
can do as a PDF from the website that
some is actually a poster that you can
get an able to get them to send me some
for this session okay thank you