couple beers and now you're ready to
listen to some threat Intel we're
already alright going to start off to
make sure you guys are awake how many
people in here use threat Intel within
your organization right now thread and
tell any type of threat intelligence at
your office and one passion or the other
one two three couple oh look at all
those people great how many you pay for
the service okay is it worthwhile
okay we'll talk about that hearing a
little bit so I do I'm a manager for a
large company I do cyber forensics every
team of quite a few people that are
spread around the world and part of what
we use is threat intelligence to
determine things that may happen to us
or is happening right now and when
people talk about threat intelligence in
this venue we're going to talk about
cyber threat intelligence but it's
really not the only piece that we deal
with I deal with a lot of companies part
of it is cyber focused summit is focused
at maybe physical threats discussions
that happen on blogs web pages things
like that but primarily a lot of the
groups here that I work with they ingest
cyber intelligence through a number of
different vendors and open source
intelligence when we talk about thread
cyber threat intelligence a lot of
people use missed as you know what is a
threat possible danger it really did
generate threat intelligence you don't
have to have a threat and we'll talk
about some of the thread actors that are
out there that are trying to look at
your company's investigate what you have
and maybe explore your perimeters and
what they can get into and the
intelligence there maybe maybe some of
that or maybe not
in short threat bad guys intelligence
predicting the future are predicting
what's happening now what may happen in
six months from now nine months around
and putting those two things together to
understand what's out there in the world
that may impact you today or tomorrow
let's see you care now let's talk about
who generates threat intelligence or
threat data there's a lot of people here
and out there that are researchers and
intentionally good bad indifferent there
are out there maybe they're looking
through their logs they're looking at
activity on some blog whatever maybe
they're doing research out there and as
they're doing that research they're
developing activity that is observable
by someone somewhere they're crossing
the internet and we're collecting that
data so some of your researchers some
review our security people innocent or
not also we're seeing quite a bit of
Prelude to conflict Syria all the
different events in the world of probe
in the network I work for a lot of
different power companies and we routine
routinely see the Chinese the Russians
and Syrians and everybody there looking
at the security of
the infrastructure or these different
power generation companies because in
case something happens in the world they
want to know how to shut down our power
grid well the commercial customers tons
of organized crime activity I have a
large customer we have one in I think
for Social Security numbers in one in
seven p I records tons of data
especially medical data before people
would steal credit card information now
there's so much about a market it went
from just be a dollar fifty a record
think it's down to about ten cents are
recognized for credit card number it's
worth noting healthcare records anywhere
from 25 to 100 dollars on the market so
very valuable very useful information so
they're hitting the databases i also
have a lot of private investigators that
are going after large companies they're
paid to when a divorce case and they
will get that data one way the other
once again they leave their home or
their office they transit the network
somebody's watching that and of course
we have the hacktivists there is so much
that activity right now banks are a
great target
you make a statement that is not going
to regret they will come after you and I
think we've seen that in the news quite
often so when we talk about why these
people are generated besides money I
have a at a large retail customer forty
thousand stores tons of cash registers
all over the place I ever cash registers
so slow can't hardly do a transaction
she said well you're here doing some
other work can you look at her cash
register itss is fine well we go on
there they have a botnet on they're
doing bitcoin generations so we have
40,000 patrick stewart interview
bitcoins and there so that data right
now what was funny ton of money they're
making kind of money that way nations
say if you saw what the White House
yesterday they figured out G with the
Russians again and according to the
intellectual property so all of that
activity goes across the internet so
what's looking at that besides in the
same
now anybody seen or spiking their cool
little dog yeah it's pretty right
there's about ten vendors that put that
I can be out there cause I had customers
that put the heat on her side even
though Scott hours it's awesome a
customer Zulu so we have that in two
other vendors upon the soft wall is
awesome so remember those little points
Norris has when they say like eight
million centers wherever maybe all over
the world and they come in they pitch
their deal since we look at everything
everywhere where every major goes to
pursue it around the world and very
intelligent is original which means
they're finding it they're not going out
and OEM it from someplace else they're
generating that data there are seeing
that guy trying to go over there and do
something to them and they're recording
that and their package that and we're
going to sell it to their customers then
your other customers that are like
that's expensive eight million endpoints
we got to manage all that date in this
gigantic database we can't do it what
we'll do is harvest data from what's
available on the internet package all
this stuff up and want for service to
our customers I said ok mr. healthcare
company we're gonna watch data focus
right on you and it works so it doesn't
work for some people but so this is an
example of some of the people
non-governmental that collecting this
data and we're going to talk about how
well we do things
so threat Intel cyber threat Intel if
you're familiar with this this is a
sample of data that we see we see an IP
address okay great this IP address
you're in law enforcement you should
track known associates you're committing
a crime we're going to watch you you
talk to him and you talk to him you call
him you email that guy and we tie it all
together known associates we do the same
thing with IP addresses this IP is tied
to that useful not you know we could
tell that DG a type of infection Pat
otherwise it's like it could be the same
if we get into something a little bit
more useful okay we've got an IP slot on
that day oh the givers the kill chain
face that's kind of neat for a crack to
look great that's why I can watch this
so break you better know we saw this I
be talking to US government host it is
associated used to make so what how
helpful is that
you can have your analytical track that
down you know many things I get or used
to get my customers like let's go puck
it's nothing you only have a finite
number of antlers to follow up on this
stuff but common threat intelligence
kind of raw a little bit process not
much value your buddy that has a
security company there's all the raw
data and you're like well how many of
these records are you kidding I would a
thousand some of your large
organizations are getting think we're
getting close to a terabyte of logs per
day so lots of stuff this is an hour
snapshot you she likes 100,000 k of
ingestion threat intelligence raw data
logs what is that two million something
like that the last hour magic just
feeding that to your sock analyst now
they would go nuts so he's pulling in
millions of ioc of analyses but
indicated everyday tax dental text any
food is rachel bionicle too well so what
this exploit dad clears hijack that
files all kinds of neat stuff
take that data and categorize it so if
you're interested in something like that
you get a feat of that data and you can
work with it you can manipulate it you
can crash ingest it into something
useful so this is just kind of a sample
inja straight from one vendor two
million hits and using all some sensors
but could you imagine something that has
eight million sensors what kind of data
that they're seeing you saw the earlier
thread and tall with that IP address and
that domain and if your handlers can
hate these there's also threat
intelligence from the form of this is
realm I think this is hi trust so we
give you the everyday and you have to
deal with this you know what a waste of
time this is because somebody has to go
in here and pull out now we have here
this one patient somebody uploaded 2
million credentials to taste it so if
you do that manually and I have with
puffiness 250,000 voice and you've got
to go through there and notify all
200,000 people that the credentials are
posted out on a sprint it's a headache
so this is right if you're in a low
balling environment but in a high volume
intelligent package okay do you want to
be able to take this and process it
ingestion and automate it because
otherwise we're gonna get killed this is
useful to let threat posed for
speculative research training or rolled
on or you have an unlimited budget with
tons of analysts that can sit there and
go through this
that will this thread entails is the
same everybody's thinking I'll seize
malware indicators domains actors email
addresses well yes but there's a lot of
companies that are harvesting data a one
company that they want to know what
every single competitor employee is
doing it on Facebook Twitter they're
scraping all the data off of that and
ingesting these articles into a threat
intelligence database or its process and
we have certain strains that says you
know if it's that name and mentioning
this and this and this is popping up to
balis and it could be pictures which is
hard so when you think threat
intelligence pictures places total
context
so it's a real headache a lot of data
but once you have something like this
working it actually works really well
this was set up to parse almost every
news agency in the world that has a
public feed so large database large
amounts of data now I'll mention if you
look farther down but when you're
spending someone you've had you guys
were paying for pay service right 50
grand Hunter Graham who's paying like
half a million a year 100,000 hundred
thousand right does your boss make you
go through and prove a metric okay so I
got customers that routinely spend over
between 1 to 10 million dollars they go
threat until better there's Patsy Duff
go pay for it and they pay for it and
let's go week on time for this and they
paid two hundred two thousand years
renewals for this one you got 10 of
those also you've got millions of
dollars well crazy absolutely insane
if ya you want to keep your job and you
want to show value to the organization
which is what we should do and keep the
service you want to be able to produce
some type of metric you know you've got
all this data coming in and talk about
how to do that but all this beat is
coming to come on your feeds you're
seeing all this computer we've got a
nice report we have my glasses on but we
have tactical intelligence we're being
dated for maybe some vendor five years
ago we want to make sure it's active
inactive and we have pending where it
has the process for an answer yet you
want to deal with it do we want to do
the work or do we want somebody else to
analysis before we get it most
importantly all positive most of the
data that you're should get is false
positive you're going to see tons of
stuff you're going to see this guy went
to there and what do you do with it is
attachable does it mean anything no can
you qualify know a lot of times you have
false data being reported to the threat
intelligence under it's all so different
so many diverse stuff that comes in Wow
I got
let's say 20 million pieces of raw data
coming in per day most of this as well I
want to act probably not but probably
want to focus on on this chunk here can
be able to say management says six
thousand pieces of high value high
threat intelligence coming in affecting
us and they paid for that so you want to
be able to say yes it took if we can
children we correlated it we matched it
nothing affects us and we're watching it
as much good metric one of that you know
this is kinda where I look I taken 45 50
different vendors I put them all in here
and go what am i eating my data from I
get some better one minute I pay four
hundred thousand dollars Bureau but this
is hardly anything they're just taking
the cash money just keep coming in
they're loving it so when I get that
metric when the renewals come up next
year because it absolute them bye-bye
all right you saw some data you want
some threat intelligence if you don't
have any right you know you want to go
ahead I can't tell you that we can talk
later if you guys have questions offline
unofficial that public we can have a
discussion just based on my experience
opinion of where your money should go
and not go I don't want to get sued but
I tell you what I've dealt with a lot of
them and you can draw your own
conclusions where do you get a chance
sometime before you're like teachers
over could you provide this generically
speaking the handful of threat
intelligence vendors that we could
research from cone up that's coming up I
want to talk about what's happening in
this industry i I've been in this
industry for 25 years I've done sim work
I've done so the largest implementations
in the world for many many customers and
the most exciting thing right now is
actually being able to use threat
intelligence because before collecting
this data and processing and analyzing
it and doing it in such a fashion where
I didn't have to have 300 people now
there's enough brains computing power
and smart people that can automate this
and consume it and display it in an
actual fashion what's worthwhile and
this is why you're seeing such a big
boom a multi-billion dollar boom and
threaten telligence right now you're
excited threaten tell how do you get it
right
I deal with federal international I get
threat intelligence from everybody and
their brother VOD do dia tells not bad
however do you and you're not give it I
mean they've got some great stuff I
worked over in released and every day or
a couple days you get that whole Bolton
that comes down and says you will do
this to these people in this data boom
beautiful loved it some analysts had
already process it and had an action
taken so we just went out there and it
did it it it done can't get that out FBI
how many get the FBI alerts do they suck
or what you go out there and you get
these FBI alerts and you're like FBI
they got to be right on the ball well
they're not giving it to us you're
giving us crap the stuff that they give
you has been out on an open source
community for three or four months and
when they give you a list ALCS Google
Yahoo excited you're like okay what do
we do with this nothing we trash it but
I tell you what in every organization
i've been at any time i get an FBI alert
everything stops everybody searches for
those ioc's and we write up a paper it
says we found nothing same thing I
Newark there's these Newark alerts
there's all these different alert set
they come from certain sources and from
a political standpoint you have to drop
what you're doing especially health care
and say yes we search for that I
remember the sony one
the / marijuana we had some internet
site information on that and guess what
we spent weeks digging through every
single one of these acquired entities
that we owned around the world making
sure that none of that stuff was there
but political standpoint they could say
we look for it now we just look for it I
said great let's automate it let's do
all this work we put in an automated
fashion so tomorrow if it happens we're
gonna lord I we don't need to do that
politically they cover the butt and that
was it the one thing that bothers me
about the federal state intelligent hold
by the way fake anybody anything from
the state I worked in so many different
stage couple of them are not too bad
most of them there's nothing there is
nothing available for you so much you
know thank you and i know i think lord I
talk to them there's not that big of a
group that i know i mean i speak at the
new york state cyber security conference
they have a big program they have all
kinds of stuff they bring people in and
i'm trying to get florida to do that
where they bring in all that businesses
and share but they keep tell them idiot
liver so m
when we look at the breach right we have
the FBI we had tons of happy billions of
dollars in losses is anybody doing it
you know where's the national initiative
of putting something together not just
internally but from all the people that
are coming after us in 1993 after work
at the free company and they had gates
guards lock down and they couldn't
figure out why the French Israelis we're
stealing their stuff and coming out to
the market six months at a time boy they
were just pissed can they spend all that
money so I said well let me go look I
walk into a great cameras got guards
you've got a great physical control and
I look I go you put these eunuchs
missions let's see where they go well
you follow all these eunuchs consumer
the deal the development on they connect
it to the rest of the corporate network
well the corporate network was
compromised by French Chinese what kind
of Israelis in French of that
so all that security is worthless but
that's 1393 long time ago but now it
happens daily I can't tell you how many
foreign nation states are going to have
to stuff that i have i not anything from
the FBI that's telling me i don't get a
federal or state response that's helping
me out and i know they have the data and
I know nothing secret they gather stuff
too soon we do and we wouldn't do I
don't know it bothers the hell out of me
anyway okay so we can't get it from the
fatima can't get it from the state go to
your vendors and we love benders right
big vendors big box as well as big BS
this is a very large vendor if you have
this tool at your office or corporation
you would probably recognize this it's
the same story from every few hundred we
have the latest threat theta we do this
we do that no they don't they're one
company they're either buying their
intelligence from someplace else or they
have a subset of what the community
would have talked about
but just it's a bit time short tell me a
story so i'll buy it from you and what
happens is unfortunately you go through
the company's you go in now and you say
you know what don't mind us cuz you can
get it politically they'll spend 250
thousand dollars on the latest let's see
arcsight package or RS a pact with your
XYZ package I mean it drives me crazy
big business right let's talk about that
earlier here's some little good vendors
as we kind of we've dealt with and when
I say good they're only good if you hold
their feet to the fire most of these
contracts are terrible I can give it
Dell SecureWorks we did they which the
customer I said you know what we're
spending eight hundred thousand dollars
a year we have so many consulting hours
in so many analysts hours we want to
understand where the value is so that's
a quick let's take this latest threat
thing that's kind of scary to us and
let's let our control for analysts
through the research on that's time them
engage the quality of your analysis and
let's send it out to I was SecureWorks
cross right I defense we should not go
eight hours later no response so they is
four hours so pick up the phone call but
where's the damn oh we're working on
more all the other animals were done in
about two and a half three hours wrote
up some nice papers have lots of data in
there and they said this is what's going
on these guys come back going
secureworks looks like than just google
but impose too much crap in there that
we already had and they probably the
best job probably did a great job
speculator over your kind of animals
that's a lot of money if they can't
provide me more in-depth analysis that
my on-site analyst to know that they're
pulling from open source intelligence in
their own sources why they spend at you
had a thousand dollars a year and I've
told many a company I sense of comedy
ftes or contractors are preferably fts
can you get three hundred thousand
dollars a year that's sit there and do
threat intelligence analysis all day
long and they go but you say that word
FTE is there like we don't have to use
anyone have to use anyway so these all
pay all goods alone
agree or the other there's some more
experience I guess you want to have a
slightly brunch people but it really
depends on what your focus is on threat
intelligence what are you going to do
with that data and we'll talk about that
a little bit later because your use of
threat intelligence isn't it be
completely different from yours and
yours and yours so that's why you guys
figure out when you put these vendors
and what data feeds you're going to get
from them oh and the fun one yeah this
one's paying 2.1 none other analysts
used the service and all none of them
one of them one of them has a p.i on
staff and all he did was like Trachsel
girlfriend stone it's all he had it's
awesome I mean worked out for him all
right I got a lot of companies and they
said you know I television said 800 400
100 nobody else budget or they can't get
it they can't justify it or two euro and
I still be what sanirim all that kind of
thing from wherever they are but I under
budget well you have a ton of threat
intelligence data within your
organization time and people understand
that they're like we need threat
intelligence well no one tax your
company
your employees are doing stupid things
you don't have security controls really
I beg to differ I know all of you that
firewall what form or the other if you
have like some cool ones like Palo Alto
or the new checkpoints or the 40 net
you're going to get some cool stuff
you're going to get geographical data
you're going to get some domains you're
going to get some intrusion detection
signatures you're going to get a lot of
cool stuff from that firewall allowed or
denied that's great Tretton called a DNS
queries nothing is awesome people do you
ask when you look at the NS board have
you guys ever had a DNS telling attack
are they sucking out terabytes of data
through DNS towels or somebody using
your company as a DNS amplification tack
and you're blown somebody off the
network every week and you get a
subpoena just appear in court if you
keep blowing another company off the
network haha we're gonna Deena great
data until I guess I guess those about
saying but nobody takes that data it
seems nobody has an idea of what threat
management means they don't take all of
this data that you're collecting and
they don't put the profile they don't
understand who why or what people are
after they don't know the type of
attacks are being targeted with their
own vulnerabilities or the risk so
there's no threat profile of what the
enterprise looks like day is there
with this data we go who's attacking you
how they're attacking you and usually
with what tools no one's taking that
date and put it together going oh it's
the Chinese again it's you know mr. Wang
over there he's firing up this XYZ to
land now instead of going after these
five IPS he's going after in the mail
server today you kill them off their you
block his IP address oh look he's like a
place in Texas mouth because we have a
strict profile you blocked China now
he's in texas but we know this signature
you know how he attacks we know what he
does he's going to make a living just
like us this this is awesome this whole
space i guess only how many have anybody
have invincea you think cool like that
or nobody has it huh how about Siberia
nothing cool like that I tell you what
look at the two products you may put
yourself out of business but I tell you
said the corporation a lot um semantics
trendmicro mcafee really got that right
you don't think that generates a ton of
logs awesome long I think people like
how can you figure out where my lab will
attack your coming or going to
like a look have mcafee grabs magic I'm
getting a firewall data I I could win
that I go oh look you've got a lateral
you this machine is infected this
machine this is that like open to that
look at they break up no visibility
there we're collecting that threat data
oh all right damn Bella lash line great
data point email people don't follow
your email i start i get i forgot how
many millions of emails we get every day
it's just one customer like so i think
it's like five million if we was finally
on its time smile there's no 97 points
something is blocked like oh what'd you
do with that data oh not it are you
crazy if you pull that this is just a
cool friend rich new one on some of
these products we take all the email
blocks you know the fish you one click
here to say hi to Grandma and Centrify
box or click here for your American
Express of your fact those links are
gold mine you take those legs we tied it
at fireeye fire right goes up crawls all
those links what does the fire I'm as do
you're familiar with it fire egg mass
will take all of that information feed
it up to fire our cloud and I guess
where it goes goes right to your fire I
appliance at the perimeter although 0
days symantec math if you will never
know low guess who's gonna stop him fire
right and you got that data that
why I don't know about but again as well
as heroes ever block and think about all
the executables that you're gay times
the executables yours go through it
depends I mean the first one goes
through we know that it went through and
usually pick it up when there was one
that went out last week who's a two-hour
delay right that two-hour delay depend
on your corporate policy if it's an
executable I know a lot of corporations
they say if there is an embedded
executable we're not taking it if it's a
zip if we can expect that zip we're not
taking it why would you bring that risk
and organization I tell cooperate okay
you want to send password types of stuff
great but my IES staff the security guys
give them that password because it's
going to be unencrypted and inspected
before it goes into the organization
that took eight months to get that
approved but they're so phishing attacks
are like the number one most awesome
thing I can pen testing and I don't even
bother doing peste des anymore because
everybody's dumb enough to click on
email that I'll craft and i'll send them
something and
I tell you I get the sea so I get all
these people every single time and they
get it they finally get it when I like
doing funny stuff to them they get it
until this stuff happen to your users
they don't get it seeing is believing so
on your point first one gets through if
it's an executable goes down to a
workstation hopefully if it's a zero-day
in fact semantics useless maccabees
useless all those ABS stuff is useless
they'll tell you we're dirty forty
percent effective look up there's been
useless for years that's why I mentioned
things like invincea Siberia there's a
big defense contractor that was getting
nailed all the time and they were told
by the government said one more time
you're gone no more business with the
federal government they put in invincea
across the organization their incidents
went down to zero everyone is starting
to virtualize their applications
application whitelisting with bit9 okay
so what we're using carbon black with
that so what you better start
virtualizing your outlook your browser's
these different applications otherwise
you can still get nailed time after time
after time
in the activity pull that data in number
of viruses types of viruses proxy
activity or people you're trying to go
up to the plaques ninety-nine thousand
times to a member Flocka man that's good
threat intelligence to know this thing
here this is awesome how many you have
honeypot couple right you use with
mutter honey that are you doing your own
okay i'm lazy right greg martin those
guys over at threat stream put together
the modern hunting that you load it up
you toss it out there it's awesome it's
i go to hate yes i go to all these free
web hosting services i have honey pots
all over the world free it's awesome and
they feed me of all kinds of data
whether it's the chinese food forces the
chinese malware the spammers the fisher
all that data you're being fed in here I
take these I've got a bunch of old IT
resources I toss them all the way around
my perimeter they're like wool woods say
i would call because what's our attack
situation awareness I stopped dice as
well
I know you know what that sucks doesn't
it we put that out there because we knew
the attacks that were going out against
the assets that we're logging but we
didn't have a complete picture of all
the attacks that were occurring against
all of our subnets throughout the world
we have a ton of dead machines times IP
address base load it up there we have a
couple honey pots sitting on the
perimeter all of a sudden now our
situational awareness just exploded we
started seeing stuff we never thought
about we should start grabbing malware x
20 days and all that data is fed into
our collective intelligence framework
awesome don't forget your perimeter
routers and switches they're sitting
outside the firewall tons of stuff good
actual intelligence that you can use
later on down the road and
just saying here I found this little
thing on the internet if you're in
health care to some step and energy you
have groups I get on these calls with
all the energy companies in the United
States and we're starting to collaborate
however a lot of them are deathly afraid
tell anything would happen getting
people to talk about incidents at their
company there's frameworks for to allow
a limited amount of information if
anything else just say you know what we
observe this type of activity but let
people know hey there's this malware
there's this type of activity and share
it collaborate talk to other people at
wherever you can talk share that
information absolutely vital that you do
because if I'm getting attacked with it
pretty much you are going to get the
same thing and I see data from many many
different types of entities a lot of its
example written by the same people that
are very interested in us all right so
you had what's in your wallet
open source I love open source
intelligence to a point last night look
there is a hundred and seventy-six open
source intelligence data sources that's
a lot of data there's a lot of people
that are very interested and a dedicated
ton of resources to collect information
and share it on the screen here this is
the modern honeynet sample if you load
it up it comes with a nice gooey you let
it run on your home router for less than
two minutes you will start seeing people
bounce against you and all that game is
like you can do your own stuff with it
but 176 open source data feeds grab it
music it's there it's free but you have
to do some work
okay so you've got the data that's in
your wallet right in organization you've
got all that data being sucked in you
hooked up to 176 open source data fees
and you're getting blasted I hope with
data well we did Nike address how many
people are analyst work okay don't you
love getting oh this is bad he still
went to a bad site you get a ticket on
that you're like you go to that thing
you do your research find out there's
three and 67,000 domains on there what's
the point there's nothing else you have
an IP address there you go okay that
Gator splicing don't care there's three
and sixty-seven Chinese origami sites
less blocking
awesome the one that I'd be like a group
the investor with my type is a saint a
business partner their interim pen
testers who are awesome they once who
scanned a country italy and had the Thai
government call us what are you doing
they decided to scan our internal
corporate network not realizing that
there was a nap between us and a large
financial client they're scanning away
their get their stuff you're going with
pen testing Oh call from the FBI and the
big bank one you guys attack well you
know what the bank block their IP
address you only need millions of
dollars of transactions that they not
below for those two days so we got to
think about that it's part of the whole
quality thing say thing the email
addresses
email addresses are very valuable if you
how many people use multi go multi goes
awesome right you throw an IP address in
there and you throw it in error you'll
see that that guy on 450 domains and the
more shitty said now I got a bad guy and
I got a list of all 450 a bit she
demands an item why no problem so don't
overlook that email address fishing take
all those down but make sure the
qualities they're going to validate that
this IP address staying here this is
another thing we have 22,000 clients
we're going to a website on port 8443 we
know is that website but we know that
the analyst can't hand it off to the
sock much less to the organization for
fishing off the network because they
can't tell you typically organization
your job is to say this machine is
compromised we can prove it this is Miss
and then we'll take it and they'll
actually do something with it
trying here but this thing is going up
40 80 or four three so now you get pcap
you're looking at porn is both got no
problem 443 how many people are doing
SSL decryption yet I have one thing a
lot of my customers now after in the US
they've had if their customers are not
in the US they're blocking the rest of
the world they don't care we don't do
this channel and Kazakhstan blah blah
blah whatever it is they're blocking
everything anyone deal with it it's
costing them way too much time I got one
of those a lot of business in China we
see 300 machines going to try on for 42
44 3 you know how it's going we're not
doing SSL decryption it says it's bad we
look at threat intelligence a base well
5050 I can't go up cold two two three
four machines off the network figure out
that their listen to music it's tough it
is really tough but as a solid
decryption is coming to most
corporations because let's never wait an
extra chilled raita well it's nice dns
says these display okay are you pen test
first angle most these cupcakes are so
sloppy you go in there and you're
sucking all the data out and you back
absolutely
and then I need to monitoring that their
baseline for three traffic should be
like this right there just like this and
then much less than two o'clock and
saturday or sunday works like this they
don't have that threatened toast said
they don't they're not pulling that
floated in about trending porch about
trending through the traffic that's
actually fail now our indicators we left
dealing with those but the actual now
when you run through we took a shower we
ran through Joe sandbox and so there's
other ones and we got three different
cells to headache so you want to get
down to it is an actual or false
positives in the floor only champagne
and orange salad ate the source reporter
all right so as you go through here and
kind of try to build this and ports
value source necessary support so what
source destination for an activity keep
building up to get the value you kind of
build the context of the threat I tell
intellect initi and activity and the
history
things that are out there imagine it to
what's going on in your corporation
you're starting to get something there
with the Dale all right so what do you
do with it if you're not using you
better does it tell you away is use
daily indicator to compromise threat
intelligence is post later decided the
problem is most companies don't have
time and you're authorized to do
anything with threat intelligence with
your company or share that clean plate
and the most important question is I do
it all this stuff's out there free to do
it except your ability to execute how do
you process it how do you ingest it
analyzed for late respond and report on
it how do you prove that's worth
anything you do this show management
that you save them a breach worth X
dollars stuff and then how do you react
to it you get the threat intelligence
data now because you're against the
response program to deal with some of
the stuff that you're finding that's
always fun people run around with their
heads off screaming you're getting the
feeds there are you can drop by threat
intelligence that you can just are
excited and tell our say has first
launched a law you gotta pay up baby
it's not cheap not keep it all some of
you may have play around
Collective Intelligence framework on
google great learning about cozy years
ago during the commercial ventricle
treachery most of things now are going
into the Duke we can just a lot of data
into do we can query it a good website
three hours Purdue 15 seconds but you
have something else how to implement it
how to congestion how to protect the
data there's a lot stuff in turn to see
these members aren't scared of this
because people are going for free
biggest problem is suggestion two
million we've got very about 2.3 million
an hour I'll pass you suck that into
your database can you normalize it so
you can search it you got it the
immobilization is the toughest thing you
can deal with new poll is up there how
can you consume it and how can you feel
it I'm going fast as I don't have a
couple minutes left quiet 15 don't give
me that five okay tenor all right so
this is kind of an example this is the
collective intelligence framework and up
here
have corn your feet your firewalls your
routers or switches all that Gators come
in it's going to collect intelligence
favorite server you got your public face
while you're hosting sources you can
presenting the data is there so what I'm
on a private right now I am logging we
have to get like 15 petabytes of data to
deal with their law did your water what
do you do it then you get like free now
the price tag on is millions but they
wanted me to quiet actually do log they
forgot that water monitor part so you
get down to here may collect
intelligence trailer now you can query
it you see something happen here now
this machine is talking with that boom
type it in it BAM here's all the
strength how is the stuff the whole
history about someone you've got that
but that's not what you really want you
can't afford to have a ton of analyst
sitting around with manual looking
things up doesn't work get on the model
here we got some collectors we're
pulling in from facebook paceman reddit
Twitter blah blah blah a lot all over
their net or second that stuff then
we're going to do and we're actually
doing something thing we're logging
massive amounts of data French some data
but we push a lot of that data we
developed a used a solution what's he
using plus when would we want to go
about and one of those data elements
that when you need so we'll pull in that
game
goes into HAARP site and I get the red
correlation rules that says if this
happens yeah this is a very common
framework that you're starting to see
being developed because no one wants to
spend three billion dollars on
commercial salmon in most commercial
Sims when I start talking 300,000 to
500,000 events per second you know they
have to go use the restroom it scares
them it really scares them all right so
now we collected it we've ingested it we
don't sound cool one of the things that
we're seeing out here now and if you're
a federal government or you're on a
cutting edge one of your shared data now
magically through a common format sticks
cybot actually which is free you can
upload all kinds of cool stuff Bishop
your emails indicators I PSP caps we're
taking tons of data put it into this
bridge sultra has like a vm you can
download and play with you can suckle
this day to end this now we got this guy
is tied to all these things and I like
to take this data and say share this to
all my people my health / share this to
all my people in the feds sharing data
collaboration is going to save your
bacon hey that right now it's free
this is magic by the way
if you have a sim developer that can
write very great correlation rules where
your side people aren't pissed off
because there's so many false father
very good people anybody great piece of
Intel it says I'm going there you know
that if you're going there is bad no
question by your type you're right duel
and says this business we know it's bad
it's like we know there's no magic take
a little piece of magic pure magic is
turning around and taking multiple
pieces of intelligence and activity and
time that all together where you at 2.3
million events per hour your son can't
handle that you need a sip filter
kool-aid get down to the point where you
give them very actual direct and
interesting intelligence but they could
have done otherwise going to be in
trouble one of the things I kind of
skipped over remember target they all
got the fire I learns does it happen
they weren't looking at the laws we can
ask me do their liability do not collect
data that you're just going to sit there
and do nothing with
think about that yeah we at the data
yeah we saw we were breach we didn't
feel like looking at do anything with it
attorney about that see how that
works out anyway threaten tell you not
do no harm remember the UPS hack is it
last year this organization said our
policy is that organizations hacked we
block their whole domain if I QPS calm
Paulette hurt leather with me so when
you do it please validate a trip common
sense that we're eight members of
understanding with senior management
says this is what we're going to do when
we see this really bad stuff they go
deal good sign here so we have a block
ups type of activity anyone approach
this that's what we've redone that is
our standard operating procedure so all
that data not only to feed that to the
sample we have one ton of money but take
that data feature-rich send to your iron
for your proximus with bad domains bad
eye peas bad stuff and it goes to a lot
though you can publish a list and
palatal grab that say how this bad stuff
we pulled back so populate the firewall
to say pocket take the night Jessica
tree I read cuz my distance repel all
the time based on threat intelligence
and I'm that's understand where I push
up or great intelligence of do semantics
you can't find anything you push it back
down it pushes to all the clients in a
first it's a way to help them help
themselves and were completed active
with us and streaming lynxes of energy
wow we know that people an RSA likes to
be on our side but we're stuck with that
five minutes left any questions done
you want to tell you what I've seen I've
worked with kind of the new stuff like
Burma me by Kenneth bromium yeah cool
stuff I looked at it last year was it
quite ready it might be ready now very
promising sigh Berra Palo Alto just lost
I ver deployed it at some extremely
large banks after three months does what
they did they didn't renew their AV they
took AV off of 186,000 pcs same thing
with invincea they're not to the point
where they trust well this one DoD
customer they don't have a TV they have
invincea they did the painstaking task
of application whitelisting virtualizing
all the apps that they're running I tell
you all the guys that are doing all the
response or doing something else it will
save your bacon because if baby doesn't
cut it
you know like they bought one of my
favorite a boss clarinet works they got
some cool stuff there I don't know what
anybody a four I couldn't tell you ok
let's go twice to thank their much hope
you enjoy the rest of the conference