all right good morning sir so I'm going
to be talking today about why we serve
our boxing resource management anyone to
back you guys in here we're good awesome
all right so my name is Vikram i'm a
developer i also work in the barn
dramatics live right upstairs and i do a
lot of tech stuff and this was our
research they got funded by the National
Science Foundation on doing some crazy
stuff that I was actually surprised at
how sane so the research focuses on
decentralized resource management so you
know on your kind of laptops and
computers TF but as you see the whole
control all belief go to task manager
you see resource management we're trying
to apply something like that to a much
broader context where we can see what's
going on where devices that are not
connected to one another in the same
physical place oh what the applications
are but I people to start off by saying
thanks to John and Jeff for like having
me around and the awkward program yup
we're actually gonna just really really
teaches you how to commercialize
research so that just ended yesterday
that was a good 10 11 weeks of solid
colors it was crazy obviously not
visa for having duck here so let's see
so here's how the talk is structured
initially but is that watching and if I
would be here these are going to short I
don't want to spend too much time on
them is the opportunities in bak chair
and that's not just opportunities for
technology lets opportunities for
application and commercialization half
the girls after that I'm going to launch
an application start and finally the my
contribution they depended logical
access units I think I should kind of
make a point here but what I'm not going
to cover this probably more productive
because bitcoin is way that you brah I'm
not gonna cover my name I can get a
whole talk on mining but I chose not to
you know my name is very kind of
exhaustive day and I'm not going to
cover kind of a whole trip to political
landscape of at all that it's very
heated and unproductive and finally I'm
not going to cover kind of the really
technical aspects like and when you for
talking's what goes on at that time how
do you pick the longest elective chain
I'm not going to cover those topics cuz
they are getting very kind of
technically this is everything is going
to get there too but in kind of
difference low so what do I want you
guys to kind of kick out of this no
that's kind of why I chose this time so
there are kind of three main takeaways
there are one and probably the most
important one is that the corn may or
may not be around 50 60 70 years down
the line philomena the CEO of ever know
he likes to say build companies that
last 100 years so can you build a
product company that last that long
bitcoin may or may not be around but
blockchain will definitely by far be
around it's kind of subtle she's funny
seeing what will make the soy but
fascinating we'll get into that in a
quick moment um the secondly so in early
1900's there was a guy he broke into a
big win so naturally right embracing
life and there's no security I didn't
get interested today asked like you know
why did you break into a bank is that
I'm just you know pretty miracle money
right so you go where the money is and
investors right now are looking really
really really carefully I mean I'm
talking about big firms like inducing
Horowitz who will throw a library a
couple of hundred thousand like five
five hundred thousand six hundred
thousand and seed money to dust into
Bitcoin and block chain based artist and
I'll talk about that environment in a
moment kind of weird you know believing
that between talking about the
importance of the talk and so on and so
lastly the last thing I want to talk
about is going to be the logical units
so um if you guys know the whole inner I
see research is constructions in
architecture for the processors the way
they started off ages ago was those
vacuum tubes itself in the vacuum tubes
one of the things they could do was very
basic but definitive logical operations
so in a kind of going back to the roots
are computing I'm trying to my research
mostly focused on how can we do the same
stuff that was done ages ago with vacuum
tubes bring me to the blockchain all
right so let's get started
so what is the deep option huh as you
guys already marvelous no bitcoin has a
public letter public ledger public
registrar anything it's called a block
chaining basically the public record at
all the transactions that are taking
place over the time it does a few things
very very very well and one of those is
verification so a lot of people graphics
schemes focus on the idea of being able
to verify one one thing works at another
XO public and private keys in PGP kind
of follow that um blockchain it doesn't
do PGP per se but a lot of the kind of
ideas per se still translate over which
is you have a lot of nodes that
independently verify transactions and
that's one of the things that are
hitting a huge advantage in the
blockchain over so you can't do what's
called double spin and I'll get to that
shortly because I that's a kind of a
critical part of what I'm going to talk
about any bit um watch it is so is
nothing more than a recording tool and
that's my angle you know kind of my
focus on the restore exterior the
picture you see here kind of really
more than box really strung together in
a sequential order so one going to the
next one going to the next one go to the
one after and they're done in a very
much manage so let me click any block
and I can verify up and that I can
verify which one which kinds actually
happened on and this has allowed in the
Bitcoin blockchain kind of stores
everything to imagine it gets very very
very good in every to be here that's
accessing here needs to have all of it
downloaded you're talking about almost
gigabytes of data build up but you know
there's especially in Bitcoin there's
other pick up mike wallace so like
electronic i think is the name of a kind
of like a man named now which is a light
wallet so it doesn't actually require
the entire block chain requires some n
number of operations that you can do on
the blocks and like that verified uh I'm
a big delivery came on the original
units philosophies that came out
one very very popular kind and the idea
is that you make one tool that does one
thing right that's it so if you're kind
of like on mailing lists and stuff your
problem using and he may look like like
much it does one thing and it allows you
to read email but my god it's so
expensive there are so many options so
many things you can do with it and
there's something really really well
only because it is true to that original
philosophy which is one tool at one time
um eventually we want to do is you want
to string them together so one tool does
one thing right you put it another one
like proc map so folders another one
which is the mail sorter and you've got
a pretty nice million system then you
can use with a lot of those conectes up
going back to the launch in it I try to
think about can you give kind of one
tool one job right kind of functionality
as a blockchain it's difficult we could
watch changes a lot of things but like
if you kind of go back even if you strip
away everything that's not essential the
block chain in the end gives you a tool
to record and that's kind of cool power
a feature more than power w exploit this
takes us to Canada core idea can admire
research we just I tried to find a way
that could we use the blockchain to
record events on you speedily and so the
point is that if you have transactions
see the advantages if there's money
involved people are going to do that
stuff product you can just inherent you
cannot bank on that because if there's
money involved there's a lot of people
who are capitalizing on it as a result
people are going to
tools that are more reliable so we can
use that well I can use up to my right I
can I can kind of blindly revise the
blockchain to be one thing right and
that's undisputedly tell me which events
are happening and by the address been a
transaction I'll make the more
generalized assumptions later on um I'm
in neutral or 14 but I'll vary due to
mixing something so one thing that's
really really really powerful what the
block chain is error correction so when
it transaction happens the interactive
you kind of run through a lot of
unsorted entries and make sure is
anything not to be useful if they are
you will say no this is already expect
so if I have hundred bucks a nice
counter and then before the tins
actually can i get to clarify i spend up
again because you can do that and the
budget will just say no like you'll be
spending money you're done you're
spending an extra hundred that's kind of
a basic idea of the double spending
power we're all that actually and it's
actually airport to in the broader sense
where it will allow you to kind of build
applications on top and that's kind of
weird
I was correct the part of the reason the
answer liked our idea was just because
we were doing something like this that
hasn't kind of been done before oh so
kind of going back to UM algorithms data
structures per se you can view the
blockchain if you go back to the awana
just mentioned earlier which is the core
idea one to one job and here you have a
recording tool so you can kind of view
this recording as a data structure I'm
very complicated one but Silla data
structure that can record things in a
way that you want once you have that
kind of mindset what you can do is you
take an instructor and you can kind of
build layers upon layers of application
and an even access level applications
all that I ask the person that can you
take transactions which is what
generally happens on the Bitcoin
blockchain can you generalize that two
events so transaction documents but it
makes me more general they're not
limited to just money kodikara you can
do other things there now I understand
that you know good point to one you know
what all that kind of stuff in color
claims you can already assign monetary
value to taste we're talking about
something more
the mental but it can I take any event
so you know reading security covers a
living example of that in very
intriguing detection so you have a lot
of kind of you guys come in here can you
look at those events can i record them
and filter out what's right and what's
not work till the 22 defender advance
which ones you don't can the Boche can I
do something like that and not the
blotches can i hear you need for money
so to speak but can you can still bring
those ideas over and I spent by your
roughly give or take on on this idea so
let me take a step back and talk about
blogging for watching why why is this
even there you know why do we just need
to pick up inside internet money myself
near email if you look at gmail now it's
got a little doll but my father you can
send money to each other I don't trying
to know how to affect it they have
worked or not but you know what I do
that whatever there-there things that
about this debauchery is coming that was
something called the three Byzantine
problem it's the picture shows very
narrow dinner one general for two and
three other sources vary so
the idea is a customer service team
appears next one but there's a few
generals we're going to attack a
territory the problem is you can't trust
what I generals because monitors are
pretty so he's going to send it
corrupted message or take message to one
of the girls go attack and the enemies
already you prepare for the target he's
crushed so how can you still do the
whole passing the message across from
each other and remove the trust that is
kind of what so fundamentally important
up but Bitcoin the reason you could
experimental different from the
currencies like you know fear is that
there is no inherent need for us so
totally in hand until the block in
a manner that like almost zero trust is
required in the whole process because
you can get public birthday so it solves
the core problem in the basically in
generals which is it doesn't matter
whoever says what is it is the messages
block it's going to get checked because
a lot of public nodes are identifying
which messages are wrong in kind of mix
and match that this was kind of probably
one of the biggest problems this has
been an open problem for about 30-40
years before so till she came around and
put the tools together to solve it
that's kind of why this is his huge
legacy going back to a little bit of the
history of why so half this has been
around actually
19 496 when these order i haff factors
used early on to kind of work with a
standby then came the idea of proof of
work that was also part of Hashcash
which is also again for sparing out
lastly there is a teacher knows it was a
very open no no problem in distributing
message passing so these are like any
team verticals or you can pass messages
from one class to another on a processor
model and a very fundamental systems
level these two little bit existing so
this is not something like completely
you know kind of out of the blue an
ordinary that came out what's assoc is
absolute genius was putting my kind of
order by konami had proof required proof
of stake even proof of bandwidth which
I'll talk about in da enjoy a really
cool ideas but initially we all had kind
of been the work for designing they've
been around 94 96 and then eventually
reach out of one these were all very
well known believers that's what makes
be recording in ticularly the block
change so exciting and things for me is
the relation
decentralized consensus and that's the
idea of having independent verifiable
notes which can connect and verified one
event each of these communities the
community yes but these nodes can
obviously taking some time verify all
those events in nashua so nothing in the
village street stays unmatched code
occur and this really allows for fur for
something that was impossible for which
is trying to be currency because the
reason believe there's but there's a lot
easy but one of the fundamental reasons
we need that is because there needs to
be acceptable authority that can be
dispute in case transactions go wrong
but while very generalized but it's one
of the reasons we need them the block
chain eliminates that were money to be
tracks with it's not money really
disappointed assets so as it can be
transferred from one entity to another
without the need for a mediator who will
also take part of their cut it will slow
down the process varies you know maybe
very sluggish that came out of this
which is a whole idea of Bitcoin to
point where you're not trying to be
money anymore you're stronger
transferred assets and in these assets
and I'll talk about those assets kind of
are at least now in like another 25 /
here but that's a very very part time
think about it like 30 years ago 20
years ago you could not ever think about
transferring money from one place to
another kind of having it done in you
know five minutes what is it the
transaction verification times about 5
minutes 5 5 10 maybe yeah so you
couldn't have it generac it in that time
period especially it being verified and
made a bell so in I was just learning
about Bitcoin of this is by the way when
I had already missed the Bitcoin i
initially learn a mushroom told me this
is never gonna work I'm not gonna buy
this that was good like I got it
thousand or five big points for ten
bucks or something super cheap and I
regret that I would probably be hella me
right now not good so my friends told me
I think about if there's a kinase and
remote village in Africa just has
internet access they have like a an ATM
to record their kind of common now
camera from what I've here but you can
transfer money that kind of almost
instantaneously 5-10 minutes the other
person in that kind of a remote place
has that money taking step further when
you transfer assets now you're talking
about a very powerful parachute wow you
know gets up gets us excited um kind of
going to the further tell the
interfacing hub so started thinking
about the blockchain as as confident
to which multiple devices connect right
so you have a kind of thing that sits
somewhere virtually and millions of
devices interest in keep in mind this is
not limited to just computers I could
connect to in a block chain transfer
money from my laptop I can do it from my
phone that's probably the best things
are you can charge money very off your
phone to the box shape so millions of
these devices are connected and the
block she kind of evolves from the core
idea of just the way to transfer money
to avoid to interface device it's very
very tough and I'm sure a lot of people
in the room kind of make a living doing
this is connecting like pink their
features i have online desktop at home
to this laptop and then on to this
device it's inherently tough doing that
right so enjoyed you can transfer step
off your rocker to the android for a
pretty easily anybody yes okay so dog
chain is kind of moving in that
direction now where you can actually
really use you
the features are they already built into
the budget right so I'm not making
anything to connect my laptop to the
block chain or connect my wallet to the
block chain the ladders allow the
interface that what has not been done is
kind of take it to the next level
where's ok well can we take the
interfacing and keep invalid if the
devices are connected can be kind of
push to next one we're so devices to
block chain to be chemical to reverse
that if you could do that then you know
we're looking at something quite
powerful um seamless integration is
having a huge deal lately especially
with the buzz words between to another
place you can get everywhere millions
and millions of dollars in imported by
companies like Heidi and so on what is
it coming back we don't know to to about
this game so the whole kind of funding
cycle takes about eight to ten years so
ten your report card Katy Gallagher all
the money to run into irt bigger garbage
another huge buzz word intended you can
evaluate how well they perform below the
money that I'm a you know last time that
happened we just was called plenty time
whole bunch of us kind of money money
nothing about huge successor but we hope
that doesn't happen here because I
probably custom outdoors oh yes so
mobile also be a big deal solar has one
I think
whether all of coins also have mobile
odds mobile locks kind of first started
taking a step further where you can do
the whole seamless integration so very
briefly and I'll come back to this my
research focused on how to create an
enterprise-level cloud for a blockchain
that an organization can use amongst
themselves to create a whole internet
stays sober relying on just deploying
kind of a cloud container with the block
chain and you can interface back and
forth for a lot of devices so moving on
from here I'm going to kind of take a
short detour of why do we really you
know really care and we're really
excited about Bitcoin this is a brief am
hoping you guys can see of the virtual
cameras going yet so around or 4 2014
about 45 million minute and only 15
deals so that means venture cap match
capitalist and something biggest one
says invalid made about 14 beers and
portal 40 million you can just divide
that just think about how much what each
deal does it huge sum of money that
they've got coindesk one of the plumbing
best like sort of recordings and stuff
they got a huge chunk of money from
inducing horrors they're actually only
investors very very interest in this so
going back to the idea of the guy who
broke into your bag go every monies this
is camera the money is right now super
exciting the whole bit point to point is
this service sort of I wish king out
basically this is going to become a
netflix oh you can be patient
occurrences in he'll take basically
stream data off kind of a decentralized
storage which is lucky to your asset can
be stored elsewhere and you don't
if you kind of princess walk you to your
your office of being cute building or
something and you kind of have like a
steward incredible plowing keep walking
anything our message you pull out your
phone in but it'll screw dry off believe
I could have a message of something any
of your you have documents basically
file storage tanks but it also allows
music streaming videos and all that and
it does everything we've had it look the
blockchain idea and I'll talk about why
do we need to do this to block chain
manager supervisor so what kind of gives
you advice what are the basic reasons
you can do that is because it allows for
smart contracts and that's been a huge
huge deal that we took advantage of as
well smart contracts basically allowing
to do to kind of automate a task so if
you use an application called if this
than that it's kind of a shame on you
get smart contract that executes at one
time doing one thing I hear the sum of
the asset I was talking about earlier on
what is the Star Trek so a lot of kind
of companies are starting off it may or
may not be a bad tactic but they're kind
of started off with an idea so it's very
huge you know made strides in this
direction where they've started off
selling a couple of million worth of a
turning point and obviously they're
doing some really amazing things so
kudos to them but a lot of competition
sorry most stars of the currency is uh
is one of them and lastly
oh you know going to rent a car and like
you kind of just take your phone out and
put it next to the car and the cops got
into a Bitcoin blockchain access that
have been verified you've transferred
money automatically you're smart
contracts stuff for eight hours you get
into character I whatever you don't have
to go see a person who can fill all the
people work out because it's our DB TT
pair and mashed and FBI reduce my
country to expire you get mssa it's
expired George in your car in next hour
or you can even finally I don't know
that kind of stuff another thing that's
been interesting especially there to
talk about it he's a developer Christ I
encouraged people who are like kind of
Bitcoin developers interesting typically
the whole like start-up ideas and stuff
kind of see me kind of afterwards
there's a few things that are coming up
that easy so true you're here let's kind
of talk after the day and some of us
that's basically offering money to
developers from one to ten thousand i
think is the kind of upper limit our
groups of two or three people you can
apply if you have a good idea you know
good a technical background applied to
get drugs that we've gotten guarding the
answer not for material but same idea
you get somebody in something worth
nearly some money to kind of go through
once in lesbian you just an all my time
doing that doing the kind of research so
these are just popping up google had one
like this to that i'll i'll talk about
in here in a quick moment if your name
is doing something quite interesting
that i want to talk about so this is
something Satoshi had considered if you
look in the email archives but I Tyrion
is really trying to make something else
previously really tight impossible you
try to make what's called cheering
complete bust
live in the block chain so what happens
is is the way products especially the
supplies products caroline is you have
the pigs another core and on top of the
key build test you want to leave the
core kind of strict minimum another
solution philosophy to like keep the
blockchain as minimal as possible going
back to the Holy no UNIX philosophy the
reason is it will work very well would
track who's kind of a core developer for
a career um actually buy the kind of
against the traditional thinking he's
like no I'm going to incorporate blood
cured a complete test and what that
basically means is you have logical
access to the blockchain so you can
actually create a program like a skirt
that runs whatever you actually the
script on the blockchain so using the
blocks the transaction the transaction
entities as a function can you create a
strip that integrates those in a
meaningful way to do something and
that's the whole idea of smart contracts
where you can integrate it blocks to
integrate transactions place of origin
all those kind of things in the Creator
like a really cool new smart contract
that uniquely identifies you as the
person pushing the contract or culture
the contract
then getting a service as a result of
really really poor idea the reason
Satoshi didn't consider was because this
was not scriptural everywhere literally
done server security you know how that
like when it is stripped it's in and
that's something that you don't want to
do I mean you're looking at like a lot
of crappy gotta clean up afterwards so
totally did not want to even touch this
topic simply because I'm talking they're
blocked you to get too bloated and more
importantly the blockchain would have
too many issues it would get sluggish
with it you know not just sluggish it is
security issues come up which are huge
the bottom doesn't really good job it
actually more secure that HIPAA which is
the compliance more like medical records
which is kind of awesome and this is
open source and hit but require you did
thousands of bucks I don't know huge
interconnect can overhead out costs but
this will actually open up kind of a
whole endorse box that you don't
necessarily what because skip something
everywhere running walls but definitely
no no
these are two Swan started what was
absolutely incredible which incorrectly
so companies are amazing money do
something where they give up part of
their company so in the hope that their
company will be part of millions of
dollars they say to an investor here
take ten percent of our company and give
us a whole bunch of money so we can like
start building this company right smart
actually a lot of people to do that to
cryptocurrencies so on Kickstarter when
you give someone money all you're
getting ready to deploy a ball in return
now you're actually maybe still hungry
so if your company becomes a
multi-billion dollar company one day
you're going to become a decentralized
if you invest it in that time
interestingly if you follow the Kendrick
White House landscape what's going on
there the jobs are I kept asking 2012 is
going to allow people to do that with
fear and we are like incredibly excited
because I think in the second quarter of
2015 you might announce like what's
going to come out so people would kind
of certain income level and level acid
can be going invest in startups for
equity and the whole idea being Jobs Act
was kind of put startups back on the
scene and kind of either bring them up w
have to be very exciting for us oh by
the way there is a picture of the Google
grand party we actually found out
did not get it but only like seven teams
out of 200 something got the customer
all so I'm not too surprised but their
proposal when all their transition to my
research by contributions to the work
there is a focus on postal open up of
things they wanted to create the whole
Internet of Things idea and then when
people to work on protocols we were one
of the only proposals that are talking
about a lot of changes to the cloud up
and here I'm going to go a little slow
but the whole idea behind little
different logical access is that you can
do a set of things right and you need
them so like that like you can in
tomorrow another side here but i'll
explain that you basically you're you're
taking advantage of properties that are
inherent to a data structure bitcoin as
a recruiting tool does one thing very
very well it will not let you double
spending and the whole idea is with
double spending if i have x amount of
money i spend X amount of oil in the
time that is being verified I can use a
specially crafted let you know script or
code to spend a hundred hours a day
because they haven't been verified so
they've really haven't been taken out of
my account so to speak but if I spend
them again so you know I sent twice as
double spending the block chain will
reject the second transaction because it
can figure out that like that it's not
working my proposal was well why don't
we take advantage of this why don't we
force a connected device to double span
which we know is going to get rejected
and use that as a basis to do yes or no
operations so I'm streaming a video all
right and I have paper access which is
not painful to you for four minutes I'm
really really like my smart contracts
that my money is going to keep going
down when 12 minutes you going on but I
indication that much the mighty muscles
gonna say okay here amor well I don't
have any more money but we're going to
force her to spend money in there we do
that because this kind of simplify the
development side of things so you for
something that you know for a fact that
blockchains gonna turn in their contract
it is the function identify the yes or
no answers that you can tell you okay
this resort like this is kind of your
distinct money you don't have anymore
resourced so i can t show you in the
next 12 minutes or next whatever setting
we took advantage of that i try to build
an enterprise cloud out there and i'll
walk into in a walk you guys through
that so the approach
there are clear across is that the way
this can accept the way I approached it
if you find problems that are resolved
and use them as a basis to make a
decision so going back to the whole out
of unity I say instruction set
architecture you can do a few cable you
can be the very very well which is add
subtract divide X or and all those
logical gate functions you can do a very
small set of time to think about keeping
them but it could be them variable and
you know that the answer is always going
to be flogged the probably the block she
was a you're afraid that the answer
might not be reliable if you use it to
do something kind of enterprise grade
right it might not work out the way you
want it to be so you want to run other
things that you know are kind of work
out very well never spending we know
it's going to always give us enough no
matter what question I put if I double
spin in addition to that question I'm
always going to get a no as an answer so
we use that as a basis to build logical
operations on top T so if I know I'm
always going to get it no can I forget
the question such that the question is
meaningful so then the no extra means
something in terms of my application so
we're screaming no
that doesn't make any sense right your
screen forever but you asked the
question is my contractor update your
monday babies running out by the time
you kick in and you start to pee but you
don't really have the money for well you
can use that to terminate so basically
you can kind of see an upper limit that
you can never kind of cross using this
idea in offer but why that kind of
matters down the line here's the Bitcoin
applications time in five years so this
is kind of going to be what will be
happening out of most good coin startup
companies because the whole idea of a
full stack startup is that you don't
just go to powder when you build the
services around the product that give up
experience the move the way for the
future is going to be a concept of
experience experience economies where
people are actually paying for the
experience so there's a college impact
anybody here is it so it can recently
came out and they got funding from
another box instead of accelerated year
the idea is they're not doing anything
you well basically doing is creating
these kind of gym places the call
studios you can just go there with
friends and you have a mobile app that
kind of links all you with one pack and
you go there and rescan your attorney
and unless you're good and you can do
whatever you want so nobody tells you
what you need to do but basically the
idea is that are capitalizing in the
fact that you can have that experience
all four of you from
or whatever go to the same place and I
thought that's what they're capitalizing
on and that's when I wear good clothes I
too so that we won't hear a bottom up
into the other share here that's kind of
very very fundamental access for
everyone dials to block chain on how is
the block chain itself think so good
luck she uses that data in a logical
manner connecting one bed to a picture i
presented early long after that I'm
properties was coming over the network
that's kind of a network of notes so
publicly verification and all those that
have will next level that's this year
here at work on this is the layer that
share all the data across all those
computers that are connected to the
block today the same is a sugar bowl
there the protocol here actually is what
allows rules to get passed down so the
whole idea of double standing always
giving no answer is a rule that I can
almost always certainly believe it so
taxing there are two notable
applications is going to be curse or
separate from from the data which
connects the block chain together
this any interpret currency so I kind of
put them as you know k one group but it
could literally anything there on the
next year and that's Carol beginning the
some of the most exciting things
happening distorted that I their company
I represent early-round are creating a
commercial idea to kind of do street
screaming and hosting using a blockchain
you can see growing up the ladder you're
reaching already the shooting protocol
there there's mostly does the last clear
that's going to come out very very soon
he's actually being able to be
operations on the block chain so if you
use like empty amazon release that thing
it's gotta do buddy or that but I'm use
presses you can order one thing and
you're going to keep order in their game
so the idea basically reduce one
function to just kind of pressing the
button right so surely that we're going
to see the blockchain we're gonna see
Apple the issue is created on top of the
block block chain using four elements
first one is the transactions second one
is it blocks struggle together in an
order the third one is detectors actions
and last one is the amount so to speak
it could be token or whatever but the
amount being a transport so we're going
to see those four components people are
going to get really creative commander
in an interesting manner to make
applications
you can kind of think about like in app
games so what if they did to gimme block
cheese or the apps you can I do to the
Bitcoin block chain and by the way I
should really mention here it's not the
Bitcoin block chain / say at this point
it could be a blockchain because they
generalize infrastructure is present
across almost every cryptocurrency
basically okay the whole idea behind
different about relaxes is you have
certain known fundamental truths truth
is more philosophical but really the
same idea then you can build something
on top but so so do you know that
something is always going to go a
certain way and Kevin take advantage of
it and exploit it to build higher level
functions and I'm talking about for
entire countries in a moment I'm
probably more understandable idea is the
idea of preemption and that's when you
know on the processor church a task so
in in creation perhaps give a test it on
the run queue so this is kind of like
processes running on the processor
itself until then what a keyword is
going to put on the processor but the
processor determines something else
order for take it off put it in the wake
you something he doesn't go on this
whole room full of task is called
friendship the scandal we're trying to
do where it go back to the example of
streaming right so something stops that
so if one device was screaming for its
12 minutes that device texting enough
not another device get put out there so
imagine someone watching a security
videotape or something and then we need
to have access to X a moderate so one
when that hard thing is done their
advice loses act and someone else gets
axis which is who's Gary box or
something like that um so this is kind
of a move that their price Club this is
part of proposal opportunity of SF to
get he finally called young
entrepreneurs in scholars and so another
handler kind of the enterprise cloud
that we proposed to create a spa the
first one is obviously the server so
you're taking the idea of blockchain
running for everybody to close it off
and blockchain running just for my
organization not now Davi attitude this
is that the organization has their
infrastructure and they can run a kind
of private block chain which really was
not the initial intended use right so so
totally didn't envision that down the
line people would start to use boxing
for assets he thought that it would
really be
way to get a hit across below with money
but so the first 50 servers so you have
to have your own servers to run it
started obviously which is the induction
itself acting your story storage
component you guys and these are
not just events per se like you're
recording the whole thing but the events
are you stored elsewhere all your
recording is metadata on top of it would
say X event have in relation to why that
is the whole idea of contextual
knowledge which is really going to be
pushed forward by a lot of leaders in
superior or images you don't need
introducing about an event that's
happening in the next cement that's
happening what do you need is the
information about how these relate
future so a thousand events happen but
like you really need a thousand events
know they can probably go store in any
hair is what it need more importantly
right now is how those other effects
related to figure out what's important
so in the context we really figure out
some things so the nodes are obviously
kind of a few you know publicly verified
and those I say but in organization
they'll have to be private servers that
I need to be part of that um and so
moving on I don't want to spend like too
much time on your will be proposed but
so are you
really kind of novel about about this is
that we can take advantage of a lot of
features that are present in the
blockchain for doing your things that
are really new in the sense that save
any vending machines right so we have
any issues all over here someone
actually has to come by fire calls it
come by see like how much money this
machine you know kind of got taken out
really well and so on and so forth
imagine kind of paint network that you
use vending machines to get kind of
property that lasts so this machine only
have access to this area for X number of
time when that one's out that machine
needs you cannot pay to kind of be ready
to let the place there you're talking
about now the implementation of smart
contracts but logical operations where
you can cut it this is the air at the
most basic level this is the idea of
taking a theorems Turing completeness
and breaking it down into problems that
are already on departure so instead of
me proud to say okay well during the
disc let me but one who's that little a
block chain I am targeting more
fundamentally can we do something that
is already present on the block check
and he built logical operation is not
talkative right so imagine imitating
someone would just use the scripting
language inviting application in arguing
work you don't need a scripting language
all your reaction ended up doing is
framing your problem in framing your
whole idea in sequence of problems to
all of which the answer's no until you
reach the stage where you know is the
right answer I think I talked about most
of this I apologize last one cut off but
i already mentioned that the streaming
stops when the contract is nullified so
um yeah here is that with different
logical axis will you but it works on
your next I'll take my work to is sort
of property in resource allocation where
can we defend
like this prop this asset can be
allocated to this entity for X amount of
time and you can kind of do autonomous
property allocation and then turning it
back on track like all automatically
there's going for a person to do this
and this could apply to carry you know
you're screening devices could I I he's
gonna fly to random machines which is
kind of an interesting example because
that's not so many of them actually
obviously Ivan just because I agree so
what did I learn it there was a lot that
when I in the project s event I was not
that I was running and is kind of really
putting a proposal together I was here
about 55 60 hours a week so it's gonna
kind of tough but uh yeah he's probably
hard to do it logical logical access to
particular doctor do so I had committed
the ATM folks were really creating
something so powerful that allows me for
a lot more than just logical level axis
so they do a lot more than what i
propose to this of next year is things
like darker enterprise cloud deployment
software is really really hard get up
top five years
to learn those technologies and another
thing I learned just I guess kinda
obvious retrospect is a block chin is
amazing for recording device it can do
that I mean if we really pushed it to
its limit reveal yourself just how
amazing it got like I could do the whole
streaming example on my phone you know
indeed kind of damn we did and it was
really amazing like a blockchain could
record against especially what I mention
area which is relational so it could
record contextual information in
absolute phenomenon that that's it thank
you so much