hello everyone my name is your huang i
will present
our study on end users information
sharing behaviors and preferences within
a multi-user smart home
lte devices are commonly adopted at
homes by sharing the devices multiple
users can access the information
associated with the device
for example by sharing a smart speaker
multiple users can access the
information
associated with the speaker such as the
contact list
reminder calendar and to-do list when
there are many devices adopted at home
various types of information associated
with the device
could be accessed by users who live in
the same household
in this study we aim to answer the
following detailed research questions
so far our preliminary findings reveal
that
primary users usually lead the
purchasing process of the smart devices
and major rules of sharing the devices
also most
participants have a limited
understanding of how their smart devices
are being shared
you