hello
i'm eric an undergraduate student at the
university of maryland i'll be
introducing our research on cyber
security learning
our work shows that online exercises
including capture the flag competitions
and more games are useful educational
tools
however much of this research is lacking
as they consider very few exercises and
only
focus on a few measures of learning we
centered our research around analyzing
multiple
online hacking exercises evaluating them
off of a set of pedagogical principles
as a follow-up we also interviewed
organizers of these exercises to
understand challenges they may face in
development
in creating our framework we found five
core dimensions shown here encoded each
exercise to see which principles it
applied
no exercise implemented every principle
but most principles were implemented by
at least one of the exercises
overall we found that support and online
communities were common while structure
feedback and metacognition were lacking
these results may be able to help
organizers improve their exercises to
support better learning outcomes
you