our collaborative team
from unc charlotte and bank of america
proposed the user interface security
assessment method
usa to allow application designers
and developers to assess the security
risks
that result from user interaction with a
particular application interface
inspired from human reliability
assessment methods
the usa process involves five steps
to identify possible human errors in an
interface
everything from unintentional sleeps to
intentional lack of use
and their potential security
consequences
guided by a handbook the method helps
evaluators
identify design triggers for those
errors
allowing stakeholders to discuss compare
and improve interface designs based on
security concerns
you