digitalization seems inevitable
he certainly has lots of obvious
advantages such as improved productivity
improved quality of life but also it
spells out new security threats as well
as significant social changes what is
more important preserving privacy or
improving services as positive hackers
we certainly are interested in
information security that's why in this
roundtable we are going to discuss the
current state of things effectiveness of
attacks effectiveness of defenses major
thrusts for improving quality of life
particularly those spelled out in the
national program for digital economy and
finally we'll fantasize a little bit
about things we can expect from this
trends actually in our plenum here we
have a number of dignitaries that I
would like to introduce we have our
elective VP of informs ashita stanislav
Bartok head of a products office of for
information security at Ross telecom
Dimitri Volkov he's got a very special
positioning head of Investigation and
he's actually a co-founder of group ID
Vladimir punish Caen his the years of
social matrix technology center console
see Omer and Ilya graphs are from IBM
security Russia good morning
please note now we've got mics in this
room and you're more than welcome to
grab the mics and ask questions to any
of the speakers pretty much any time the
moment I see you blowing around the mic
I'll try to accommodate your question so
let's talk about the current state so
lay of the land in terms of attacks and
overall information and security now
various state authorities keep telling
us the number of attacks mounted against
individual industries keeps growing just
like you know the number of attacks
performed against the public sector
keeps growing at the Sun Tom as we well
know the old attacks are still valid and
they're often reused or a leveraged in
use scenarios new attack factors keep
arising Wando it's sort of fashionable
to attack SCADA systems the other day
they're out of fashion but something
else gets attack that experts say the
number of targeted attacks keeps growing
just like the total number of attacks
really we are going to hear it now from
a number of experts from different
industries and tries to come up with a
comprehensive picture
it would be great to first hear from
stanislav from Lawson Ross Telecom after
all
Ross telecom 'is the largest provider in
this country oh stop that
no all we say is that the number of
attacks against information isto
providers in fact against the
information infrastructure in fact keeps
growing and keeps growing at a pretty
fast pace
Luce attack from so many sources not go
for example thing that matter to us
recently was the attacks during
elections well the Central Election
Committee other related websites we're
in the subject about fifty attacks some
of them were DDoS attacks that were
application level of X bar is Jiri
Operations Center a pretty good job well
the key attack vectors were DDoS or
attack types rather
the kiddos
dd-does does deserve a separate they're
actually trying to attack quite a wide
array of different assets using a
relatively small number of assets on
their own what about the defenders what
CeraVe point
those are trying to grab the attackers
by their tails
let's go PT occupation area is device 30
we actually have two sources of data in
the world like we got our own equipment
tells us that certain attacks are mainly
for second source Edina for us is the
incident responses with foam capes
growing it doesn't really mean the
number of attacks keeps growing
necessarily but so they are getting more
sophisticated responses required a more
sophisticated as well I think it's a
pretty fashionable show to say that
number of Doc's keeps growing well
that's true but I'm sure this science
honest number of simple attacks keeps
growing that's right but on the other
hand for the simpler attacks naturally
their efficiency effectiveness will go
down over time so the attackers will try
to focus their efforts the number of
their attacks will therefore go down
however the effectiveness of their
attacks can go up at the same time
faster it's a total number of attacks
keeps going up however most of the new
attack
but most of the Delta so to speak he's
actually futile nobody cares about them
because the technologies involved in
defending assets are pretty good in
terms of protecting get simpler attacks
not a single mic seems to be on will
agree with the previous speakers was
much certainly we would love to know the
total volume of attacks with phones but
I don't think we'll ever gathers numbers
after all we're talking about relatively
delicate subjects and reputation Ares
and after all we all know the fear alone
187 we are talking here about batteries
of national secrecy and importance at
the same time all we see is our general
awareness keeps going up
and you know as young stirs acquire new
talents and competitors they see a way
to self-actualize
by attacking certain resources the sheer
number of this people is growing and
this low caliber attacks there indeed oh
the rise
she's in there right circle you know
right now so what normality morrow board
so these are pretty much jack house
trying to attack a wounded animal this
is good because they're training us so
the effectiveness of what they're doing
keeps going down because well thanks to
the hill we are getting better day by
day well the statistics sometimes going
show is the point is there's a big
target attacks it makes me think of
Bonnie and Clyde you know this Bonnie
and Clyde's style attacks they won't get
mentioned much and we won't hear a lot
about them is a single a laser sharp
attacks presents the biggest strategy
well it's good that people are
practicing in the next room somebody's
attacking others are defending great you
sure we have just the requested starts
on the attacks we have registered so
what we are saying is about 800 DDoS
attacks every day against us on our
clients and about 100 the various
anomalous DDoS such as unauthorized
access attempts about 22 week
information security policy violations
about 25 per week denial-of-service
about the statistical stupid move over
10 per week
if you
which probably means that you don't
really see any anomaly as a potential
attack sure the total number of
anomalous is advanced for thousands for
per day currently oh good so this is
important data for us can we hear it
from the sociologists now please I'm a
psychologist by education and for me
it's certainly a privilege to be invited
to such a professional gathering I guess
in order to approach better
understanding of this situation we could
to compare what we see here to the world
ok ology like many but Syrian diseases
do we know how many can we diagnose how
many are out there in the world that we
can know diagnose that and how many can
we actually treat again I don't see
myself as very professional in this
field but I think it's only natural that
the number of attacks has to grow the
clear-cut evolutionary rules for that at
the same time we can also be expected to
grow and mature in terms of our ability
to which will defend ourselves
so I guess we'll soon reach the stage
where most attacks will be pretty easy
to deal with and the next interesting
question is how do we define the
organism we are trying to defend so in
biology that would be simple that would
be each and every one of us here and an
epidemic would be say a community that's
exposed particular
in the most open it's like here I
understand we're not really talking
about individuals these seas right would
rather be compared to cells and bodies
right the cursor on the end you can use
a company where workers good things much
more please would ye like eyes tears
yeah please do comment to that
well we at IBM talked about our
strategies we often talk about immune
systems so we talk about information
security year as if it were akin to an
immune system because it's a collection
of diverse systems that you'll employ
and you should employ them in a
particular concert so that you actually
get some holistic see protection for the
other thank you actually I'm to measure
abilities cabinets it you moon Lister
that we actually have a great biological
kind of agreement here the weights
through the court coupon is latest again
okay would you like to share more stats
with us rose nice of him
present at so many societies to Thomas
Thomas machinist we shall resist come on
shaft
okay here I represent a global American
corporation and we have a team called
x-force within IBM security and these
guys do regular research they collect
analytics collect details really no we
don't claim that we have some you know
comprehensive and we understand
everything is happening in the world but
we do work with a number of global
accounts around so many countries baby
em cook Minister security service
provider is a managed security services
provider IBM is actually one of the
largest operators in the world so we're
talking about several thousand large
corporate accounts and there are some
interesting in facts we discovered in
2017 and this is what mitri and all like
have already mentioned the number of
attacks in our top industries has gone
down reached incidentally and the number
of incidents has guns out as well about
18 and 22 percent respectively
this is our first conservation the
second one is how the financial industry
is still in the lead in terms of being
the subject of attacks the object rather
of attacks is any different followed by
ICT manufacturing retail and others this
teaching man thank you
focus needed Ichiro and this was named
it's done listen it is which wasn't easy
lovely this attacks is becoming an
increasingly more difficult endeavor
because of growing and bolstering
defenses so which means that instead of
quickly becoming a sort of a you lead
kind of profession with the
cryptocurrencies naturally were a trend
in 2017 for a very obvious reason it
became so hyped that lots of people
flowed into it naturally manufacturers
which means English we're all interested
in it so criminals don't understand a
lot of protections that most I didn't do
a blog change projects with master
pretty love show their budding
entrepreneurs you don't put it with
incidentally brilliance again well y'all
know the incidence in Korea we're up to
two attacks an exchange just what bust
anywhere others as well when you're in
Chalmers debate about our expectations
for 2018 this heart before that says
supplied by our us doesn't want such an
persimmons tears so children's are
expected to become the tool of a leaf
cyber criminal groups and syndicates we
believe we shall see more encryption
attacks 2017 was a very successful year
for that cyber criminals will continue
to focus on large businesses the carpet
cetera because there is a larger push
that
well the smaller groups will focus on
the retail Maori through mobile channels
there will be more targeted attacks
against banking systems until we expect
growth of theft through mobile channels
and particularly through Android
children we also expect more attacks
against cryptocurrencies and critics
changes Belinda is for yesterday it was
clearly stated that there are
vulnerabilities pretty much pretty much
everywhere in software and hardware and
firmware and very often vendors well
sort of three terms are they've taken
care of this owner abilities but we
heard it from several speakers at least
but there are practical vulnerabilities
that can be very luxurious they
exploited quite intensive objectivity
what's the general charge German
demetri demetri would you like to start
that
because readiness it can be just to it
I'm just discussing trades with your
permission I'd rather stand too many
people in the room so it's okay he asked
me questions don't be afraid to
interrupt me and do not be Russian still
here to talk about the effectiveness of
attacks and obviously it's not enough to
simply say that effectiveness is of the
right let's start out by segmenting the
attacker sheer fact that somebody has
discovered a vulnerability has been able
to exploit a vulnerability it doesn't
really mean that it's commercially
attractive attacks and different actress
will have different motivations such as
espionage financial motivation protests
energetic acid ester or even sabotage
sabotage and espionage usually are
state-sponsored while cybercrime usually
cares about financial motivations and
also protesters because that's what
justify resistance yes exactly
we always are certain activists such as
the anonymous for this guy's for example
it's a clearly against their interest to
increase the total number of attacks
well because the more you do the less
will be the media impacts of each and
every attack these people usually do is
defacement attacks little interest in
people like this and very often they are
incapable of mounting serious attacks
although the number of attacks they try
to perform keeps growing now most of
those activists are usually low
qualified so what they can do is grab
existing tools do math scans and break
what they can physically break sometimes
they do hits on a governmental research
- they do wanna deface but it doesn't
happen very often
another important subgroup is the cyber
criminals so financially motivated this
is actually the largest group of
attackers because everybody wants to
benefit from the unique knowledge well
in Russia for example people start
making less money if even if the number
of attacks keeps growing all this
probably means that effectiveness is
going down I will share with you some
data later about so how much they are
making so it's actually pretty rosy
trend there's a number of effective
attacks is going down and the total
amount of money
produced in the course of such attacks
is also on a decline although there will
be variations from country to country or
industry to industry
yes this ludicrous espionage it's much
more interesting to look at the state
sponsorships 2017 was the year of
sabotage Joe we're talking about not be
a bad rabbit wanna cry here another a
less publicized attacks it is in this
field that effectiveness a is growing
with sabotage usually all these cases
are relatively public with espionage
it's very difficult assassin in most
cases is spiash cases will go unnoticed
ikkyu lurid company has been heck
doesn't really mean that their
information was stolen umber of attacks
is on the rise and in defensibility
service these are the Rises this slide
is designed to show there has been a
shift in innovation because
state-sponsored groups used to watch
cyber criminals and learn from them
there has been a major shift now now we
have cyber criminals watching
state-sponsored groups and learning from
them well in most cases actually learned
from security vendors reports warn
state-sponsored or apt attacks all the
interesting things are happening now for
the first time in the attacks performed
by state-sponsored groups but this
doesn't mean that you should stop
watching cyber criminals you know
they're still active
so sacred criminals will now learn from
18 I think it's pretty clear why this is
happening on big teams that move this
attacks become more mature and countries
and customers start training it more
seriously you know they start treating
it as arms you know arms that need
development and improvement and can be
exported there's growing demand for that
is becoming at ran out to demonstrate
the capabilities of your cyber arms and
there is a lot of interest in this stuff
from mass media pretty much every
publication would love to talk about
things like this which means sorry has a
contagious a first row is this positive
hair day so it needs to be positive from
time to time so we publish this report
all the Russian market primarily all the
russian-speaking markets and this one
shows the amount of money made by
russian-speaking hackers in various
yellow signifies phishing and blue
stands for laundering Wow orange shows
targeted a gay attacks against banks
which shows actually the total volume of
money defrauded from thanks keeps going
down
on androids they have been lots and lots
of very successful and all the other
channels it's actually pretty good you
shouldn't really think that so the
banking section is much better protected
now it's not so most of this improvement
is due to the activities of the law
enforcement agencies you know despite
all the criticism a Levitan them now
they're actually doing the good things
and they are apprehending the bad guys
so you will see that in 2016 2017 the
majority of successful attacks they
actually represent targeted attacks
well the criminals now what do you want
rather than attacking hundreds of
companies they take a single company but
with spectacular results there is this
decrease here compared to 2016 Greece is
not because Russian banks a better
protected but because the same attackers
you know they've acquired useful
experience in taking Russian banks and
now they're attacking banks else Bank
children's so shown in black the
children's available in 2016
shown in red the children's that are on
their way out and the green on the new
ones so you'll see that there were no
new developments in Russia well in other
countries we see when you thank
children's ABC children's
this is all glaze but please note the
effectiveness of this Trojans is going
down because in fact things becomes more
difficult anti-fraud systems are working
better a laundering has becoming more
complicated when people are looking for
the criminals and resting them are
actually doing pretty good jobs vote
rock for example is out because a
sorceress has been caught you also
notice that the size of the average tag
has gone up Sakura sir choose a company
that is more vulnerable and the company
that's at the same time be a more
profitable target there is this paradox
how we encounter every year that
information security budgets keep
growing information security solutions
become increasingly smarter you know if
you trust marketing claims and we have
artificial intelligence pretty much
everywhere they don't seem to work
organizations who were vulnerable and
they stay vulnerable there is more
height waste more money and still
attacks are successful difficult to
defend yourself from attackers
specializing on a particular group of
companies who are on a particular
industry but they give no - there are
various potential reasons for failures
in defensive
some of the obvious was so that's a
misconception for example if you don't
see an attack it means there is no
attacker all the Hilton no attacks now
very often we're told we don't need
services because we're never attacked
you know what you're a large company he
should be a juicy targets are the
companies in your industry are attacked
why do you think here enough and we're
told usually well our occurrence
information security systems do not give
us any warrants we ask him what are we
using and say well we have a s I am
ordeal B or no antivirus system
congratulations your systems are no
design to discover it develops threats
what alone attacks this is a very
popular misconception on fighting this
misconception is actually very difficult
usually the week is not educating a
company like this they were really hard
white well sometimes they just hire any
information security officer and he
educates the customers another
explanation is there are no rules for
information security because after all
for the previous several years we've all
been trying to become compliant and
vaporize you know document in the
documentary world we all seem to be very
well protected
unfortunately our attackers did not read
this piece of work that's still
successful with all this compliance
spending we don't really have any money
left
for realsies disease or a security
of course concepción effective in the
machine mister I'm sorry switch stop we
often we try to beef up our stuff
maintain this systems but we don't
really have money for new systems that
can be good in terms of discovery but we
also hear in many companies we're told
whoa we want to have a sock with an S I
am system running is sure you need a
seam system he's actually a log
management solution he will not enable
you to discover anything oh you can come
up with some correlational set name
Bower you to discover some anomalies but
if we're talking about advanced rats and
I mentioned previously of the number of
advanced attacks keeps growing not a
single seam system will tell about silk
people have this misconception that you
need a softness with a CMS later on you
get actually install a threat
intelligence and they're great logic
alpha Daisy well we already have a cm
systems just doesn't work put in a sock
and if we bolts own thread intelligence
in a will we also see sometimes
particularly in the public sector is at
a new a newly hired SCI sir he's often
hostage in a given situation he doesn't
help our teammates bullying issue well
we also meet new customers we tell them
or would you like us to show how the
your systems can be compromised
or if you're the subject of attacks and
if he has sent us particular files that
she consider weird you know we can
analyze someone tell them tell you if we
can associated with particular apt and
you know after this meeting you know
Willie for the CIA so we'll go the
routes will go through an administrative
Wardell of getting the approvals
eventually find himself in a pretty ugly
position because he will know for sure
now the the risks that he was with
previously so aware of have become real
he hasn't got the tools to address them
no he knows that he is the object of
successful attacks he cannot do anything
for at least a year before he can
actually send her for the solutions he
needs automation and I'm not talking
about bones or PowerShell scripts but
what I mean here is that there are
certain steps that can be semi automated
I guess there are some professionals
here you probably do that as well right
if you see yourself in an environment
that you know that you've experienced
before you will probably get form the
same sequence of stuff what I liked
about notes we said after launch she
sings to me and kept doing it launched
meaning cuts doing the point and mimic
us naturally takes logins and passwords
from the working memory
there everybody knows me me me me Cass
was used in a most he forgot logins
passwords I was started using W my and
PS exact system cause he's not a normal
six even see if it happens on muscle yes
it is anybody is detected no third thing
is it it also tried to exploit the
well-known vulnerability of the turn o
blue it was so well known right after
water crunch even Microsoft that
published the patch in the big
corporations in the bank's suffered from
their you don't really need to keep a
low profile
simply because defense is so poor you
should and rather your carpet bombing
Nicktoons to mutant box to try and enjoy
box Catriona for the it's not new
computer oh very often we see public
disclosures of new children's US
children speaking Trojans or Android
malware at the moment we shoot their
scripts in public reach recipe is there
will be more more parents of them
spreading around the internet sector
darling it's a Couture EKG data crucial
after I think it's possible I miss
Puccini per system
she misses him a takuji Bijlee no is
good to a substance any more attacking
an abundant oh we research this a group
that was attacking banks they had his
children that would infect the whole
Bank network and as long as at least one
computer was running you know
interestingly you know it wasn't very
persistent I know it wouldn't write
anything in into the register so once
you restarted the whole thing the the
virus will be gone but it's required
disconnecting or rather restarting
switching up all the can be remote and I
guess this persistence routine will be
on the rise as well Oh Bank and POS
Trojans currently showing steady
increase by searching for the right
machines on the network they will
actually become more effective GDP is a
great new innovation hopefully Russian
legislation will change as well
Ethier first successfully hacked
subsystem do you remember the miscue
percent of potential fines as VP of this
machine oh wow
it starts at 20 million u.s. dollars and
it's yesterday it's 2% of your turnovers
pretty neat isn't it so you take a
public corporation you look at their
turnover dimension simple and you know
in factors and you ask the company to
pay just a little bit less than it was
have to pay okay so fine that's actually
a lot of money isn't it
so yeah that was a question that's it I
hope I haven't taken long thank you that
was very interesting to me well in your
slides you showed all sorts of reasons
for the poorest state of information
security I guess it will trigger all
sorts of questions like what should read
in it should we net do now the humans
the growing effectiveness of
sophisticated attacks and he also said
that nobody would learn about some
successful attacks no does that also
apply to you say if you are attacked
successfully you will not tell the other
members of the industry well the answer
is both yes sir any response agreements
that we saw as a confidentiality clause
we're bound by emotional tools we sell
about to tell anybody else about our
customers so we cannot really disclose
anything about our customers or a
particular successful attack against
them but if we learn about a particular
attack vector or tool or children that
was here we are prepared we actually
exchange indicator information
so that's companies that are Nord our
customers but can be attacked by the
same parties could defend themselves I
think this is normal practice everybody
follows donate get it fast
what's the window of opportunity
seriously no I don't think that
attackers will be able to cover the
whole market there is this opinion that
you gotta be very fast the antivirus
industry told us that whoever updates is
database faster is a better provider
performing an attack say it's time in
the banking industry it takes several
days to several months so I don't really
see a reason to rush leaders oh you
prefer is to first study the throughout
in more detail learn more about the type
of extra so that detection in the future
happens faster now what happens very
often it a company share indicator
information simply by dumping a number
of IP addresses but what do they mean
which logs do you read what are these IP
addresses used for this is a useful
information which unfortunately isn't
often shared this is stuff that some we
would want to read in other companies
indicator the Ross telecom for example
it works very closely with insert and
central bankers and when the riot acts
against banks
we naturally inform banking community
hall bacons the same applies to a number
of other industries such as the powerset
red naturally we also tell the law
enforcement agencies and group IB
exchanges data with us and we exchange
data with them so the professional
community does it there is no doubt we
gotta do it as a professional community
and I understand it is done at the
governmental level after all that was
one of the objectives of having Kasatka
which is a state committee for discovery
prevention and response to computer
attacks now the chance is still there
it's a increased trend is but we also
believe that defenders are awful always
trying to catch up with the attackers so
Tuckers are always in the lead
when you data warehouses and data lakes
are established by corporations now they
can be attractive targets for attackers
do we expect businesses to be better
protected would you recommend that
businesses don't go so fast implementing
data waiting for telecom additional oh
yes indeed the tag technologies
developed faster as a defense routine at
the same time we have a pretty large
group of analysts who study the trends
do all sorts of research variable we
need business and we try to stay in the
good side of the the requirements of a
business pocket provide for their
security but we certainly need to do if
we see the risks as high we'll recommend
that our business partners do not rush
their implementation otherwise miracle
oil will try to secure what they do okay
does your risk based assessment work and
how would you go about coming up with
the right felis that it does work and no
business bothers to listen to us there
are different methodologies you know
sometimes you know you start with
financial data sometimes with
geopolitical considerations let me argue
with you a little bit go first I do not
agree that the industry is sort of in
the ketchup mouths
so terrific and we ran with the Ganesha
is rubbish
regular cybercrime is easy to detect
well I'm not talking about ABC's April's
these are separately even targeted cyber
criminal attacks can all be detected as
long as he is as the right solutions
properly do not buy a magic box that
claims to include all the solutions you
need and all you gotta do is simply
switch it on now I'm not talking about
boxes here but apparently from your slaw
it's it follows batching souls 99% of
troubles this is not a solution is just
a hygienic consideration isn't it now we
keep talking about hardware and
technologists but indeed most attacks
evil the human factor 90% of attacks
particularly successful attacks involve
social engineering so improving the
internal hygiene prerequisite but
nothing will completely solve your
problem what I'm saying is that
technologically the industry is in a
good position we no longer need to catch
up with cyber crime you still need to
choose the right solution and to use it
properly the market itself seems
relatively slowly well if everybody used
the most advanced solutions in the
number of attacks would go down even
further it's great we have this question
so this question has energized the
panelists but we will get it out
discussion a bit later well you guys who
won't have ads anything about the
effectiveness of attacks
if no so I suggest we start talking
about the effectiveness of Defense's
unless we I'm sorry
practices I people no I got any sense
jobs he needs a look for new methods and
Demetrius is a noted on the hair tie
fighters impossible to argue with him we
should know but personally coached know
what namu is clear it or some waves
while you're watching Egypt but we see
in our word to store the British install
voltage attack Ebert's refactor it cheap
is a personal Kapoor is a shed company
is a shell Sheba and I should but you
push symptom Patriot NASA natural
silicone mini a pieman he didn't finish
the sentence you a tissue
it was I think 2005 dealing GUI system
comedians that an operator was
implementing a particular billing
systems program they actually had an
internal rom no with a the software
developers sure three days later the
billing system just disappears
probably three years ago the company
there was this issue company big holders
hackers and children's
there were lots of interesting things
they had they look at their firewall and
it turns out that means so the firewall
as a city search you know they just
plugged it into a socket but they didn't
set it up
you know they didn't update it they did
nothing so hackers are indeed an
important source of risk for sellers but
I actually believe is it much more
important with furniture the choice you
up you can I fully agree with the
guys saying that human factors if you
have a strong team you will be protected
as possible if you haven't if you do not
provide the right environment for people
to get better with twelve levels every
magorium veneers new veneers mean little
schreeten we keep talking about
exogenously thanks for some reasons
though what about internal guys take
WikiLeaks that was primarily internal
work right well Russian hacker is a
neighborly hexans mrs. Clinton reunion
however she apparently did not follow
even common-sense security protocols or
even disciplina as monitoring you poor
so actually we certainly need to our
great the disappointment of our users in
compliance buffoon and the objective of
compliance is to make sure that you have
the right processor at least and again
you can have different approaches to do
you know you can you can develop the
right process it will look protection
against wanna cry or you can have it so
you know on paper alone then you will
suffer from wanna cry or not special
well by the way we do
with payment hours to equity umbrella
process it's a double-edged sword is
because commando meteoroids come on
disseminating partisans leader abu talib
really first thing I developed the right
policies but Don he needs motivate
people to follow them absolutely is a
made of hydrogen air of corporate
culture with Legion historian Tomatoes
cuisine nebula in cleavage ravaging I
guess this motivation thing is arguably
one of the most difficult things in what
we do
now that we are talking about
effectiveness of defenses there should
be some global factors we need to
consider such as rules of the game
imposed by the state Russian government
has adopted this program for
digitalization of the economy
let's discuss the car rules of the game
Oh
no when I was invited to participate in
this event because I was seriously
tima it would mean 15 was the of a
Pierrot analog you brush brush life yet
upon meeting requirement the wine not
the first time TVC of a beeline
sufficient for my presentation is about
effectiveness of defenses sufficiency of
regulation of organizational measures
hardware solutions allow a Ministry of
Economy usually uses money as a
yardstick a mighty market in billions of
rubles what information security is not
shown as a sub-element of this data
[Music]
debris no politics America what can
actually assessing the consequences of
these so the political snap is always
loved the approach of the Ministry of
Economic Development FST C or other
agencies propose new measures Minister
of Economic Development say well that
will cost a lot whatever there is he
always wondering how they actually bring
out those judgments
would my cousin it was a recently cross
standardization ages in the Russian
Federation introduced national agency
classification IDs fortunately there was
a similar decree published by another
agency so everything is in a state of
confusion what happens is the
information security spending for
budgetary purposes can be classified in
exactly 193 well this means you are it -
ransom it was pretty difficult if you
liked the site we need in terms of money
spent on information security premium
polity secretion into easy political
decisions can be based on foreign
dangers orientation even better database
and Economic Analysis Ponemah besides a
political influence or a political
regulation the opportunity exists the
state implicates information security
companies sorry very fragile Asian
sensational regulation import
substitution some protective measures at
our foods do some other images
I should be principal principal history
coverage as a commodity boudoir it's
about our saloons I will not talk about
industrial regulation too many laws
their Ministry of emergencies publishing
[Music]
what matters to me is three kilos rolled
in a federal law talks about
governmental institutions usually
involved in maintaining or protecting
our datum another law deals with the
operators of personal data we're talking
about two hundred thousand companies to
Roskam the door machine communication
sir the infamous 187 security of
critical information infrastructure its
relevance both for a governmental and
private institutions this is serious fSV
see you know will regulate security
gives us an opportunity to improve our
well base
not only money impression what this
inertia pharmacy a category to it in
pharmacy the information are much
showing it here is relevant for these
subjects very laws 200 NT school 47
sorry 4400 to 3 in 2017 that's the size
of the information security market in
Russia 56 billion we predict you'll be
rotating
what this parity Mears know Jesus
testing what you know so that 24.9 are
the organizations please by chance a
bite even Couture booster Bharat say he
misses the first muchas him state-owned
corporations parka seaweed is 2 percent
of account for about 70 percent seems
present fighting no differently what
accounts for about 70% of IT spending an
information security represents four
percent actually these proportions you
see over there
44 44 percent they not changed much over
the previous three years
Otacon valle de la semana dylan nida
german company tried shisha did
Priscilla of coop with whitey
relationship the present of dr. cooks
cavity with amber food Tigre me asana
doclet
what it would eat what russian not years
them yes my personal issues like what it
would give the PDA restate that we have
blue IT spending apparently no it's
growth in percentages but apparently is
growth of spending it's not shown
anywhere in this but blue stands for IT
in yellow stands for information
security in the bottom i'm showing
various orders of SS dec number 17 21 31
and 2017 so the adoption of the federal
law one or eighty seven and I understand
the FST see orders to 30 439 will bring
fruit its next year nor in 2018 maybe
even in 2020 I do not expect them to
have any measurable impact on the vodka
in 2018 2018 will benefit from federal
law 187 I actually expect the
information security market to go to
much juicier starting from twenty to
twenty somethings in this country do
have a relatively faster say in 2017
they spent three hundred million rubles
on gossip
although back then you know they mature
no documents underpinning is about
sixteen different customers initiated
their own Gasol can Rogers so this is
our whole base is warming into
regulation and I'm showing here in
technical standardization committees I
certainly have lots of respect for
regulators there's the Bank of Russia F
is TC and FSB because they've stepped up
there to save it as significantly
recently tomorrow there will be another
amazing of the Technical Committee ffs
TC and they're going to see to the
approval of new goes so what tripped me
when I analyze this data besides these
three technical committees they're
actually lots of other committees such
as technical committee 22 TC terms
telecommunications committees the old
dog it's not a parameter ETA 3 knots
trees to treat speech
PRP capital so take ghost 13 three three
five volumes five it's actually based on
iso standard well actually iso standard
that was abolished ten years ago I don't
have many ghosts like this he does
happen from time to time committees are
not so directly exposed to a particular
industry or what for some reason try to
regulated watching Berkshire chest which
in Berkshire chest
probably not mentioning all that because
development of Goss is an important
element in the development of digital
economy TC 22 Committee on ITU the state
is not even represented there TC 159
software and hardware elements of DLT in
boxing's again regulators are not
present there at all maybe that's why we
don't have our own operating systems
although they do say that Ross Telecom
has this plan of installing their own
operating system on smartphones with all
we have TC 7700 braking systems
compatibility that's idea society's not
represented there and serious concern
serious company that was expected to
represent say their bag actually it's
out of business for five years with a
proscenium I said three of the ship and
it's in zero booty licensing does it
work three percent of group ownership
exact as a boon from Sony bizarre past
mistake
it listens you thirty percent of those
who be fooled no statistic important
Lucius alright these are the licensees
of F SDC shown in yellow or the license
companies are shown in blue are those
that are no license within twenty four
twenty first a number of companies while
fifty-six is billions of rubles or size
of the market which is an interesting
situation isn't
understand if to share terrain change to
those on immediate release in Seattle in
changing the Quad Cities contract is
current a concourse a man called upon a
booty boom and competitions scratch for
is service often in decades and that's a
contender for should be licensed by F
STC or FSB so in this respect I don't
see any particular threats thirteen
billion dollars were spent on antivirus
very rarely misses out of state total
number of F STC MSDE licensees well we
hold an eternal or unlimited license to
hold there are two hundred twenty one
hundred new 2200 licenses for technical
information protection companies while
at the same time there are only 700
companies active in this market what are
the other companies doing I'm not sure
you need me at practically Robert
catalysis EMU their license but they
don't really have plans momentum do
another a common requirement is that the
contender shoot employ at least several
I ask professionals holding such and
such certificates well if they don't
work
they barely don't work in this 1,400
companies they quickly will see their
skills deteriorate we expect this market
to grow yes we should expect higher
demand for people like this for five
years we've been saying without in terms
of information security little is being
done by the state in terms of educating
future I as professionals okay this is
the data from the ministry 4,200
graduates he in 2017 in the field of
information security 4,800 in 2018 and
we should have some like 80 hundred by
20 or in 2023 this is a number of
graduates I'm a shudder to call them
specialists these are people currently
studying you know greenhorns first-year
students clearly not all of them will
graduate 15% will no graduate for sure
and many of those who will graduate will
gather will find jobs elsewhere compare
it to the number of economists this
country produces 130,000 versus 4.2 why
do we need any economists 1.2 million
graduates every year almost half of them
for one year
consisted of economist managers and
liberal arts professionals
this for Putin and Medvedev have been
complaining about so much we don't have
enough engineers you know we're training
managers and economist and liberal arts
our artists if you like maybe European
countries will eventually start singing
Kalinka malinka and we will probably
occupy managerial positions everywhere
and the engineers will come from some
other countries things are changing
we go from 4,000 to 8,000 but still
eight and eighty-five year education
actually gives a chance to training
centuries and it also gives a chance to
outsourcing service providers I'm sorry
we're strapped for time what brings
people nationalist procedure here Prince
appear who everybody if it was actually
a serious was there okay well we show
here is the eeriest where Russian
products are actually any good for in
months are shown in blue in terms of
protection from unauthorized access and
antivirus protection what we have is
actually very very good place the deal
be say three years ago there was such
trends customers will get to antivirus
solutions in 2017
will occupy Stanley pop factory and
Tversky the trend was to buy to Russian
and Tyler's and one for in antivirus ISA
being the leader in this respect however
in terms of the performance of our
hardware and in terms of the
functionality of software we are losing
two or four incubators in terms of
discovery of targets at attacks
Olek yeah well I'm not sure we need web
security some we do dislike spicy but
it's really this is the most interesting
sly thank you very much
we also need to hear a very unusual
viewpoint on matters of digitalization
next presentation please
it was remix but they're very punish
kitten I'm with a societal mattress
technologists Center all trying to be
concise in two years and I hope you will
find my meditation interests let me pray
oust my speech by us yield theories been
weird question
so what looks like here do you think of
the word a Lucifer he's a good thing or
a bad thing that's a good idioms people
I guess did you tell the Christian
tradition cool associates the word
Lucifer with something bars a little
cappuccinos little severe abuse to you
but the saint of Lucifer means bringing
the light right what's northern guys
each other Iannetta philosophical
efficient let me simply state that many
things in this words are not as
self-evident as they may seem
I'm not a software developer I'm not a
professional in your industry I'm a
psychologist my trade you something
meniscus is but I'm also going to claim
all more information security solutions
are all dated I have no doubt that your
great analysts and programmers you know
the hardware very well you can see della
position the best production system how
they're possible but none of you as
commands of the key elements you see the
system is ninety
that is you're not really now the
psychology of the other size does not
know
always behind the other screen you know
his interests his habits his fears were
the objectives
he was traffic York City oh you might
say it's useless to know whether he
drinks coffee on say every morning
also you can claim that it's unrealistic
because we're talking about thousands or
maybe even millions of people actually
you can learn and I believe it's the the
later office of our case humans will be
the company that will learn how to work
with humans you know the results of
their words you gotta play against the
other chess player of the chess boards
we have developed a new technology
technology that can assess the emotional
state
this technology is pretty good at
assessing what's happening in life
generally - now this all we call it
social metrics and you seen in the
screen let me show you several social
metrics of several banks so we have
central bank alpha Bank and in res Bank
central bank is obviously the regulator
alpha bank is a large bank the largest
private bank in this country and
interests make it a small private bank
so you can look at simply the number of
right thoughts there also where it
clouds there we also have some
interesting charts here
with that show that things like hybrid
wars are absolutely specific they not
Astrid at all well this is the research
we did it cross a range of mass media
radio support a radio freedom their main
message is that of fear well they don't
talk they don't use the word very much
but they play the card of fear a lot
well Russian mass media actually is
totally different messaging well good
hackers don't leave traces on the
machines they attack but they do leave
traces of their own machines we work
with consciousness and consciousness is
like molding clay so sciama
degrees emotions if you tell us which
resources a particular hacker is
interested in will tell you what he
wants if we have just a single cookie
from his computer
we'll be able to glean this information
for you well so Shyama today works a
number of interesting areas for example
we have a partner that is Iraqi Russian
Association corporations in information
security security cetera we've been
supporting a number of our
cryptocurrency projects as well we are
open to new partnerships Wow thank you
very much unfortunately we've exhausted
all the time we had for this session we
have heard various views about the
nature of digitization well I still
don't have a clear-cut view on whether
digitalization is a risk or aperture is
a threat or an opportunity but less