good posture webshops opinion okay we
have three reports and three speakers
okay I'm not going to make a report but
then I am on the vendor side and you
know sometimes vendors want to learn
what it is that the customers want what
the integrators want sometimes you want
to know what the initiators of MSSP
program spawns the plan is as follows
there will be three imports one by an
MSP another by an integrator and by
customer talk about Angora be tlk okay
they also develop their own software but
they are primarily an integrator and
that is also solar security there is
surah security and they actually have
their own MSSP and they provide
high-quality MSSP to a number of they
companies so they have three species
about 15 to 20 minutes along and the
rest of the time is for you to ask
questions and please whenever you ask a
question indicate who you want to take
this question
passionate
hi brother stop wasting your time and I
invite the first speaker to take the
floor this is Sir garrison from GT okay
hi everybody i'm sergey riesen advisor
on security to the CEO of GTL K which
stands for state transport leasing
company and I have a speech about the
winding alleys that bring people to
introduce a Sosa's we've got a small
team doing information security ok let's
start it's a pretty fashionable now to
discuss information security
technologies because many companies are
now being attacked and they have to
defend themselves and marketing people
try to sell their software and analysts
are happy to tell about breakthrough
technologists that nobody seems to be
using CMS are also a sort of a mix thing
because some people I heard about it
others say it's an expensive tool yet
others say it's a useless thing but on
the slide the actually you see us so our
plan is to share with you our experience
in building a private SOC that serves a
local business no my plan is not to say
that you know we are great and we can't
catch everything just a we're sharing
experience here well previously that was
the network topology that was very
prevalent he would have a firewall
protects your external perimeter after
you would have liked an anti-virus that
was pretty much it right Tommy is flying
fast flying fast I'm sorry many
companies started themselves kimura so
if they need a cm well naturally there's
nothing to protect here that would be a
waste of money
okay now we start asking ourselves so
what if we need suddenly be on sister
may be more smart production is right or
maybe next generation firewall is the
solution maybe and G firewall will
protect us about against zero day
attacks or SSL traffic inspection or
other will help us perform as a cell
traffic inspection and will help us
prevent intrusions and do deep packet
inspection that's something at this
stage cm or SOC are not required because
systems like this come in with handy
monitoring and management solutions they
don't need really anything on top of
them if you deploy an SEM on top of it
it will be like having a fifth wheel
chair call okay at the moment so we're
running a fully fledged SOC that serves
our needs okay we've got AV protection
we have protection against have data
leak protection and we also have
protection I gaze on authorized access
we also have very sure virtual data room
that he navels us to minimize risks of
unauthorized data transfer let's move on
well this is what our networks look cool
what our network looks like at the
moment we have external perimeter
protection clusters next we have
next-generation firewalls and there's
some redundancy there we have
anti-malware protection we have VTR's
privileged user controls privileged
access access management systems
vulnerability management patch
management in a situation like this he
certainly need to have better analytics
and better control it's easy to manage
one system but not such a zoo this is
where sock comes in handy a sock should
help us minimize our risks and develop a
system that will support business
continuity after all this is a
fundamentally important objective before
implementation we need to decide what
kind of objectives we have and also
decide why we are trying to implement
sock whether we want it to be external
or internal whether IT divisions are
prepared to collaborate as they do it
because it can easily be a stumbling
block do we have people inside the
company are good enough to build such a
sock do we have an infrastructure that's
mature enough for such a sock
implementation if you look at the old
schema you will see that in order to
protect us against the malware and do
firewall event correlation we certainly
didn't need it that would be ludicrous
really what's the benefit for the
company from building a sock what's the
mileage what are the results what kind
of information can we get
next we need to decide what will be
important for a business partners if
indeed we build such a sock
well the toaster gives you this is a
data integrity access control and
business continuity as you go about
building your sock
please remember to consider what the
market has to offer look at all the
trends consider the mentality of the bad
guys because because of game theory
really also we got a do vulnerability
management because we'll need to control
for the vulnerabilities and patch
management to patch out for the
vulnerabilities who discovers that it's
a continuous into iterative process this
is how you make sure that your private
sock is actually up to scratch guys from
angora and solar they do it as a service
and they've got I guess lots of their
own am pleased you know what they're
doing if you've got a private soft well
this should be your personal area of
responsibility and the offices of your
attention thank you very much
focus heritage I'm sorry
throughout the conference they keep
using this magical words so I understand
what it means that security operations
center but what's your definition of a
shock if you don't want to you shouldn't
tell me where it appears but say your
corporate definition would be great
thing to have we have over 10 different
information security systems managing
and monitoring the stealth systems
manually is quite a task
it's useless in a way because there are
too many logs to read it's so much
better to collect them all and to start
running correlations it's so much better
to look in one window as opposed to 10
windows that I understand what's your
definition of a sock his mic is off
Wow it has a button last two years I'm
trying to help the speaker last two
years even in conferences such as Sauk
forum people try to run away from
definitions
what's this conference about three years
ago what he actually had this discussion
and you know what he was a bloody battle
so I'll be able to say this is people
process and technologies and then people
say okay let's this was this I which
processing technology does a Kaspersky
antivirus a virus amount to suck I've
got a good person actually reads it it's
a technology and there is a process this
is a sock that's why the industry
decided to actually avoid arguments like
this we can ask everybody this question
but you know what that would be a waste
of about an hour and a half that we have
for this session maybe everybody has his
own song actually I should have given
you more details about gdlk usually when
we talk about something large like Salk
who we invite big carbon accounts people
who have hundreds of people working in
information security divisions and they
usually design something huge
now Sergey has a small information
security team these guys work 24 by 7
I'm sorry this guy works 24 by 7 and you
see him in front of you so he is the
person discovering incidents and doing
vulnerability management so his story is
about a sock that you can run on your
own now I personally know Sarah I know
that 90% of his time he spends on
automation because he is the only person
to information security
I've been allowed to automate everything
because they say we cannot hire more
people but what a mansion is okay when
our assets grow when we implement near
tools well for example if somebody
[Music]
connects to a socket without
authorization
everything can be blocked like the whole
building so that security paper will be
alerted where if you have an
unauthorized connection to Wi-Fi natori
the whole network segment will be
blocked or if you copy data to a USB
Drive people will be notified via text
and they will respond is this a sock in
a sense it is but I am trying to rubber
ties it in a way because I'm trying to
take the humans out of it incident has
happened incidents
please be monitors incident has been
delegated for response we have a
clear-cut line drawn between me and the
Security Division there is the IT
division as well the I see people will
respond to some of the incidents I've
got another question if that's okay
when you build a sock what often happens
is that no things are automated
you only need sometimes to close
incidents and reaction when everything
has been automated what you do let me
disagree with you actually sock
developing sock evolution is a
continuous process because new things
keep happening like every day like as
you updates your software you need to
normalize new types of events let me
give you an example we changed our
access control systems and we had to
normalize this segment of our sock so
you have to keep tuning your sock there
are also new Crips and minors and new
viruses hitting the market since
February we have seen a whole influx of
children minors and we have to deal with
them as well
hi Siva substernal corporals is I guess
I'm Alexander from STS media in your
opinion what's the right approach to
building socks
should we do it in-house or should we
delegate it to a service provider it all
depends on the business needs doesn't it
in our case we are partially owned
company partially owned by the state but
this means that we have to store and
process all the incidents internally
that's why we decided to launch our own
saw but we could have invited Solar
security or anger or any other company
in the market because there are service
providers like this but we wanted to
have our own system well if he could ask
a vendor for any technology what would
you ask for something else doesn't exist
today simplify event normalization June
as a service oach you don't touch it at
all now it's an interesting like there
are this business applications for
example there are not covered by CMS and
[Music]
I would love to monitor them this could
be electronic document interchange
system more than one ass or other
accounting software okay if the
objective is to connect a new
application with minimum effort why
would you want to do it on your own well
want to keep it all in the family so to
speak we want to maintain mobility
service me do you know a lego mindstorm
is
[Music]
now this is a solution that helps
children program Roberts having a
solution like that for socks will be
great so that you wouldn't have to be a
technical expert to arcattack a sock
very often it's former military people
who are doing security so making a user
friendlier for them would be great idea
hi i'm carol from IT Park in cousin
companies that deploy CMS or other
protection systems they often ensure
their risks well you guys providing such
services how do you ensure your own
risks that is of failing to discover an
attack very often it's even difficult to
prove that an attack did happen what do
you do when you don't have a role when
you don't have a spelled out in the
contract well as a customer as a builder
of my own sock I can tell you the
following we had attacks there were some
virus attacks versus our mail servers
there were attacks against our
infrastructure
so far they haven't been successful
after all we need sock in order to
assure business continuity this is the
mantra for information security that's
it okay what if you've discovered an
event say that your server has been
hacked or say your cm tells you that cm
has blocked an attack this means that
your system works well but you won't
learn an attack if C of an attack you've
seen fails to register it well we're
being monitored by IT as well as
security people well we cannot rule out
that somebody's in our network we don't
know that okay what about the companies
our outsourced security
how do they make sure they don't buy
this stuff blindly well I don't have an
answer to this question because we know
it's in the market for such services
German would you like to comment I don't
want to but I have to the purser feels
it's a big problem not sure it's pretty
difficult to control the providers of
the commercial sock there are some
organizations that actually make money
like that as well as a customer I can
only recommend drafting our bulletproof
contracts you can actually run audits of
your sock well that may actually cost
you more but certainty often Casas in
order to do the audit properly you have
to be an expert you very often we go for
outsourcing because we don't want to
have this expertise on board that
depends on what you want to have if you
have the understanding we don't have the
time you can do the audit if you don't
have the understanding then you will
have to retain the services of an
external auditor an NZ ace alone will
not cut it we don't have other questions
I suggest we turn to the next speaker so
that way we'll have more time for a Q&A
later
I'll example crumbly Alexander and it's
a sukham leading from solar security is
their chief expert chief analyst I'm
sorry
hi I'm Alexandra sue calmly Network for
a solar security solar jsoc we are going
to talk about main content issues at
sock are usually lots of processes at
sock besides a street and saying threat
hunting I'm sorry machine learning that
are older age now also those old lures
or alerts that are still triggered by
decayed old events
present events that have a long history
so you need to know how to interpret
them and how to read logs let's look at
the key problems related to content so
default content from vendors as is most
vendors will give us threats of I'm
sorry attack discovery scenarios and its
raw formats
and it's a very difficult to read or to
process like 1 or 70,000 alerts per day
it would be great to have reliable data
coming from the vendors but that's not
what really happens after five to ten
attempts of discovering events you know
you'll start simply switching them off
I'm sorry so the default content usually
works like this now we try to minimize
the number of triggers and maximize the
value another problem we have is that we
don't know how to interpret events
[Music]
very often we don't know how to
interpret events Oh
take for example 46:24 we see here the
name of the host initiator and it's a
incorrectly mentioned
incorrectly show or if we look at non
logon type train is possible without the
AP address there is another event with a
reconnect of an RDP session we see the
data is handed over correctly but if cm
does convey the host name information as
in logon type here will it be able to
read properly or not and that really
depends on the correlations and
scenarios you have said are before
[Music]
or alternatively usage of Metasploit sir
should also be detected sir maybe it's a
correlation engine that has how to
discover it so we'll check the source by
AP address we'll look at the whole
series legit
it hasn't been you know blacklisted
before how can we interpret that we see
different random host names with the
same IP and naturally names of the
workstations don't seem to tell us
anything now this data that should come
from our scanner the question here is
can you your first line of defense is
probably interpreters
another issue one every when we sort of
a launch everything one by one system
after system sometimes it's because we
don't really assess the state of a
particular source we can be running on a
package of different scenarios looking
for different axes but our sources do
not report events in this case the
efficiency in the effectiveness Houston
air is close to zero correlations can
give us all sorts of false positives or
imagine we're running a default content
with a scary scenario names but our
managers love it business partners love
it then we will ignore the response
process status we haven't really
executed a playbooks and we have noted
upsets our salaries either for
investigation or for response well wiki
is the default so guidelines such as
look in the donor surroundings what this
means is that the performers there won't
have an understanding of what has
actually happened and how they should
react how should we execute scenarios
before you execute a scenario can ask
yourself two questions one why would you
do that and what's next the first
question should help you decide on the
applicability of this scenario to your
company in the second one should help
you understand how to best run it
[Music]
how to select Mexicans Sedaris ok bed
rabbits he's attacking everybody there
was a storm about it and that's media
not sure you got a detected right
question arises do you really need to
develop a separate scenario for this
particular sort of activity or not only
you really have any Content that would
look for a new service installations
which is so we should be able to see ok
what if a task with the name from the
game of Thrones is created
do we actually parse the task scheduler
log do we see information on file
creation and see windows tasks are there
any rules for das creation actually
scenarios like this should exist should
come from the Box really next one is a
grades file cincy windows well first
we'll get a check if we have ordered for
changes in this particular folder do we
actually notice that files get created
as see windows is this in a running the
internal scanning is one of the basic
scenarios ok next stop is either in
numerous requests via SMB do we have
scenarios for us for a network scanning
please no there is nothing radical in
you here do we really need to come up
with a separate scenario for activity
like this because we're actually dealing
with standardized stuff here which
should enable us to discover a better of
it right away
okay we want to launch a scenario and we
need to decide how shall we do that most
vendors and analysts suggest that we'll
look at blocks of network connections so
let's look at a particular situation
here we did our analysis and we have our
Kouros and generate an alert and we have
two hosts in the top here that
collectively account for 37% of all
blocked connections the first thing we
do is naturally to analyze the hosts
well we see it's an Amazon Cloud well
some connected PDF but that's not scary
next thing we need to learn which
particular process initiated this
particular connection many people say
that you got actually look at see small
and Windows filtering platform so see
you for some reason Kaspersky is
requesting it if we drill further if we
look at the host events we will see that
Kaspersky processes are actually being
tunneled by some of the process and see
that the adds a 1 to the port here port
number so
it's very important to understand how
even a fancy technology is going to be
deployed and your existing
infrastructure so I wonder if your first
line of support will react properly to
an event like this will they register it
as false positive or not next situation
with a lack of content structure ization
what we see very often these are a sock
will try developing separate roles
separately therefore IP md5 and so on if
you have more than one person in the
first line of a support you know it can
easily happen that two people will be
investigating the same events
differently ideally that's what it
should look like we should have three
levels fundamental and profiling real
scenarios and workflow like we don't
really need rules for each and every
type of IARC
because after all they're all
standardized IP md5 and so on we Adam to
list profit if we have a new source of
Ti we parse event to assign categories
we clean them
we have profit again we see what's in
this vid on the scenario level incidents
will be generated by relative sorry the
respective criteria and we also collect
incident statistics so they can be
addressed later the workflow level we
will develop a battle cases so to speak
will filter pigs by events and will need
this statistics later for analysis and
this is what gets integrated with
external service desks so instead of so
many different events we should see a
single incident that will be responded
to by a single employee
or I say yeah is to use Cal abilities of
CMS well as other systems a typical
example is say a company wants to
control edition editions of users or
inclusions of users to privilege trips
you actually have to work around this
right say you see that a user has been
added to a group check with the IT the
ID says it's legit but there is a
different approach in the service desk
you can have a supper field that will
parse a list of users and list of groups
so you can parse this field and you can
use it in scenarios well that way you
can either talk to I see all the time or
automated the choice is yours next one
is information protection systems you
can take Kaspersky Security Center in
Kaspersky Security Center you can
actually develop internal rules for
automated workplaces and you will then
trigger events like a failure to update
software a key is same information later
on correlations the same applies to IBS
why would you want to develop scenarios
on and show on external scans in your
IBS if you can actually add a couple of
signatures to IDs and I use them for
correlations another big problem is when
you actually don't have a process for
checking your scenarios
so it may easily happen that's a
particular rule or particular scenario
will fail to work or will never start
working so you need to actualize them
you can automate scripts we can generate
events so you can do pentest rule
control also needs to be performed
whenever you change roles many CMS will
actually log change just like this so
this is good and also it needs a this
data to be delivered to the - Boris of
the analysts that's it thank you very
much a question from the charts where do
we stop like I have nothing
give me a step-by-step description of
how to develop the right song I guess
many of your customers ask you this
question what are customers who don't
even ask you this question but you see
that you have nothing well our first
recommendation is that you try
describing a process from A to Z do a
serve inventory of what you have it's
important to have a clear list of your
assets and your pain points you describe
them and next you know you can list your
people your response teams your
information production assistants next
question there was a slide about window
log artists and you said that you would
with Parsi windows right
Nalini what you do with a false event in
Big Sisters the big infrastructures
where lots of changes happen well sock
should not be look at the correlations
alone right usually we try to develop
the right process for the customer no
but the question is it is about buckling
false positives in this case we have a
joint process for reacting to incidents
won't really inform that only incidents
okay what if it's so good you say
thinking a year you know by the time of
you stole new patches new ones are
available
well usually our customers need to
change their patch management process
well change our doubts
my Seba
do we have questions from the room from
the for those nights of snotty
Kovach magista ccs least so quickly
under okay how do you interact with the
customer stock i always the only
Socrates menu what's your interaction
like we actually have customers like
this
scuri operation center is a process
rights the effectiveness of a stock is
driven the Sox ability to resolve
specific issues right what happens but
often I thought they for example they
don't really have enough human resources
because you do have did a forensics
after the response and so on so we will
undertake some of this functions and the
customer will be responsible for
development effectively customers always
need to make the decision whether to do
things in-house or invite great people
who know what they do like you what's
the right logic like how do we make this
decision Rockaway Sox are effective when
they're gonna address your local needs
and for the customer you know it means
having at least one person managing it
managing the MSSP process and by the way
we can also be a knowledge database on
network attacks because after all we
served many customers so there is this
uh cross-pollination with cases
happening here
duskie not as what tell me differently
when the company shouldn't call you well
if you believe that having MSSP is a
panacea don't pose no that's a different
question in round three when should a
company build a sock in house I
understand you can sell your company
right
maybe Maxim can help us he's rarely done
to don't need to call MSS B's all the
time what I'm trying to say is that some
customers believe that having an MSSP
contract is tantamount to having a song
that's not true you need to have some
functionality internally do they really
need MSSP why don't they do everything
in-house well sir companies really want
to develop their own stock and they are
invested in this idea
now the best situation for us is when a
customer has concepts as all the right
processes you just say strapped for
resources human resources to us
okay barely the answer is that you
should always call an MSS be
particularly if you have the money but I
saw in your presentation seems to be
based on some basic technologies such as
filtration normalization correlation no
fancy words there no machine learning no
AI no behavior analysis which wise out
what do you think about fancy terms you
know you can try automating cows you
will have automated cows smart systems
can be good if you have a perfect
understanding of your network and the
reality of your users like I said in my
presentation without knowing the basic
things about how we are going to react
to alerts coming from you ABA thank you
do we have questions from the floor okay
this is it so let's sing the second
speaker Dmitri is a billion from angora
[Applause]
hi I've been introduced already I'm
actually in charge of a risk management
practice that I'm gurram and I'm going
to tell you about the target model and
I'll try to sort of tell you everything
you need to know about uh so could you
please raise your hand if you believe
that your song doesn't work the way
okay what about those who think they
know what should be running in a song I
actually thought it would be different I
thought the number of people who would
be able to say what they think should be
working at a song
well this is what we usually see that
sucks the things don't work it's usually
unclear why when they do it's even more
of a mystery now try to talk about those
complex things in boring terms let's
starts by agreeing on what should work
at a good song and will call this
understanding the target model of a sock
it's useful if we can formalize it
because I way you will be able to
measure deviation from your initial
design in order to develop a motor like
this we need to add lots of art effects
and words where do we take him from
where to find them my understanding a
sock is a division that has operations
that are formalized very pitiable
luckily it fits our information security
right
if we go about creating such a division
what sort of requirements showing
thousands I think all companies in the
world fall into two categories
who is marker that actually tries to
make profit so there is another group
that is funded by taxpayers well there
is a business division that usually puts
bread on the table and there is
information security division which
usually doesn't so in order to be able
to spend money you gotta ask the people
who make money what they want those
who've tried doing it in practice
usually know the business people don't
want to talk or they will say things
like I want to feel secure but I don't
want to think about it it's your job and
they often cite well you know you are
professionals
don't ask me very smart questions
because that's not my field of expertise
but we want to be secure okay we need to
find this detailed requirements
somewhere so that's we can you know sort
of - for more a detailed criteria of
success I'm going to risk management in
detail some people believe you shouldn't
do that some say you shouldn't do it to
them although Level II should only do it
at a level of say-so
now if we don't talk about I saw the
2705 we're a hobbyist and race or
what-have-you but simply if you have
information security education you
certainly know what threat modeling is
right so the easiest way of risk
identification is to model threats okay
you will need to choose some problems
and you will need to find
countermeasures some of them can be
admin the some you will want to put up
defenses and some you will simply want
to accept if it's difficult to do from
scratch you can grab some basic threat
model oh you must have heard about
federal law winery foods - it does
contain a threat models and there are
also threat models for other industries
and you can look out PCI DSS if you're a
bank and there is a the eve for like the
for legendary bags for those interested
in SCADA throt models
so these are the things that should
under law your work or this on the sock
let's look at the artifice now
[Music]
that's all we need to know about people
in a single picture we've analysts so
she should have been a target model and
we need three types of analysts so we
need some simple analysts complicated
lists and forensic analyst maybe you
don't want to put them on your payroll
so you need to decide what kind of
people you want to have if you badly
need this people you have money for it
well it's a good idea to have them in
word it's also important to decide on
the roles the number of people because
eventually you know you will have to
talk to your managers and ask for the
payroll
well it's clear that an analyst cannot
process more than 100 incidents in a
shift
even if we're talking about trivial
trivial incidents he can easily read to
the analytical reports from headhunter
and you can share them with your manager
so they know how much you budget you'll
probably need to review this model in
the future well you gotta start
somewhere so we have engineers here that
will set up defenses only you know
sometimes now you also on to DevOps here
but there are also researchers and
hunters remember we see them we
understand that these people will
actually need a lab and a separate set
of tools and the ultimate solution is
when you have a red team a blue team and
a purple team that car donates the
actions of the red and the blue team I'm
talking of the manager is to actually
observe vacillates on all these services
at some stage you may need an architect
also please remember that besides the
people actually working inside the
division that will be people working
side-by-side with them well for example
if you have to do Cornish court
appearances he will need lawyers it
makes no sense to employ them in sauk
well you may want to read same
professional lawyers from outside or
your own in-house lawyers have to be
relatively good in IES matters also you
need public relations experts
also it's important to have system I
understand there's been showing them
there are many things have Ottomans
showing here is such as KPIs at 24 by 7
or nodes having or not having first line
of support well people often talk of
processes but I'd rather talk about them
as services ok this is just an example
but please knows that here we're also
showing the Gestapo Corporate Center
analysis again
well you can say that this is some basic
things and you would possibly want to
store with some like this if you need to
start somewhere
this is artifact about tools so we've
talked about people and processes and I
understand that you would want to split
it into processes right you certainly
will need I def email if you're going to
use this kinetic it's better to execute
it as a flowchart okay this is a very
technical picture full there's show them
what I'm trying to show here is what can
it be you're in relatively small company
we're not talking about Elon Musk's
collaborations well there is the
augments stuff here this is what she can
bring into sock to increase his capacity
to increases throughput power well
naturally you can add what is it a video
no deity so threat intelligence but
imagine now you're an organization that
has a terabyte of logs per day a box
solution will it work for you it's
easier to fire everybody and it's so
expensive hide up is great what about
Hortonworks well somebody has to
configure it for you and maybe one day
you will have Natron but what you know
you already have one terabyte per day
already in death paths cognitive
technology should also help you and I
should also be shown a approaches model
because having one terabyte per day is a
killing
please know that here at the core level
we are showing a p.m. this is a p.m. if
your objective is to have a sock the
believes is mature there is no going
away from the notion from the
realization that you're monitoring the
business processes that help the company
make money they're only like five chains
they're the help the company make money
the company after all was created to
make money so if you start saying well
this is a very expensive story won't be
able to understand it or you can for
example say that's well this particular
turbine you know if it breaks down will
lead to total destruction of a big city
downstream oh this is something that
business people to understand
so IPM should help you develop service
resource models it's easy to find them
on Google if you happen not to know them
well there is to say that you cannot
manage something you haven't measured
metrics should certainly help if your
objective is to reach a certain stage in
the maturity model actually there are
some proprietary maturity model so it's
a cost a lot of money and I don't think
you are prepared to pay millions
hundreds of millions of rubles sometimes
to the blue giant before some like labs
begin you suck seven it's actually an
Excel spreadsheet easy and it will give
you the asterisk that you will be
interested in while the business
partners will know it's they don't care
about metrics but it's important to you
because you will want to jump step from
from one step to another a road map
I must have unfortunately
because the road map shows how you're
going to go from one step to another and
how long it's going to take so a Gantt
chart will be part of your target model
to make sure from the very beginning
that your suck will work this all the
stuff that you will need but if you have
a target model and nothing works then
you gotta ask a service provider they
may be able to help that's it
[Applause]
Oh chica question from there you've been
talking here about big data there's a
terabyte per day the Hadoop are there
any specific things that's our wiki is
well we have customers who would tell us
we have terabyte Burdine of data of
traffic and we want to track it and
monitor if we are talking about this
mode of data now there is no technology
today that I know of at least that can
be used like that
cm will not do that for you
correlations automated correlations done
to run on a terabyte of data
so I guess machine learning can do that
eventually
oh very often people say let's train
models what's do a Y I was dude
applauding nobody says why we should do
that well the why he said this cognitive
technologists are designed to replace or
augment human capabilities well
my proposal is to use big data and
machine learning
I'm sorry big data to gathers data and
machine learning to avoid hiring 1,000
analysts replace like 900 of them with a
robot well some incidents cannot be
algorithm oyster well we could have
discussed playbooks
now playbooks are very important because
you know they tell you what to do with
an incident and machine learning can
actually be very useful for the area
said she cannot algorithm or as a vendor
I can say that a terabyte per day is not
a lot like okay do you have a price tag
for that can you at least tell us the
number of zeros in your price tag you
you don't have enough numbers no all
mine all my fingers they're enough
[Music]
okay I can give you customer details I'm
his son a matter of technology because
everybody's using big data if I
understand the question correctly and
I'm going to build on it which I
understand it's cheaper to develop your
own Big Data solution as opposed to
buying a box Lucia this what people
actually believe many of them before
they try it some are actually successful
I know people like this but I do have a
question regarding machine learning and
this cognitive technologist can you give
us a particular use case where machine
learning is and aids useful I'm sorry
can you please be more specific sounds
like you're asking me why should we
collect a lot of data no that that's
easy a lot of data can easily be
connected with cm and you can call cm
big data and you can use your Hadoop to
collect a lot of data it's just a matter
of price so then you mentioned cognitive
technologies and machine learning and
all other fancy words and Isis question
couple of times before and you get this
question again give us a particular case
where it will be useful what are the
mechanisms that will enable us to
automatically discover is incidence any
particular example preferably from life
incidents are nothing new we are not
really looking for some sort of
deviations it's not a behavior analysis
for God's sake
now this is the first city Shui will
help we'll be able to replace people
with machines more importantly there are
things that people simply you will not
find I'll take IBM Watson a bad example
that works rather good example for our
commercial sock we'll look into the
Internet through a small beep hole while
Watson is using millions of people's
like this and they will probably be able
to find more stuff which is good for
paranoia
it will answer your question well do we
have questions from the room from the
floor no questions from your beers ok
and let me continue you may take a seat
let's thank the speaker Dimitri you
still get my question he knew your slide
you mentioned a lawyer for a song what
are those he is a sock that would
require having a lawyer whoa data leak
or data theft has been proved you have
an employee haven't been able to come to
an amicable settlement you need a lawyer
so you've collected ciub proof through
forensics of what have you will it be
your engineer your forensic expert or a
manager representing the company in
court do you know many socks that
actually employ lawyers not a single
sock that I know and that would be
seated my suggestion is to use the
lawyer such a company usually uses they
corporations often employ lawyers do we
have any statistics on how many legal
suits our bro
from soft well I think that Group IB
will tell the l-word everybody else will
say no many now the question is about
machine learning you know it say you've
mentioned IB do we have successful cases
in Russia well Alexander borken and his
friends in my sock will be happy to
share this examples with you I'm sorry I
didn't work for the commercial sock so
I'm not able chance this question ok for
all the panelists are you prepared to
share your rules such as correlation
rules or instant and discovery rules
upload themselves sure no problem on the
website within a week I will hand them
over to you if you come just come to me
and talk to me while we're trying to
develop a community here Alexander where
he is no we won't
that was at least honest Thank You
Alexander a question - Alexander No
do you also write commands particular
countermeasures when you discover an
incident yeah whenever we execute a
scenario together with the customer we
discuss what needs to be done next so as
part of the alert we also supply some
generic recommendations ok thank you
do we have other questions for some
reason telegram is working they
apparently being blocked again when you
visit it if we haven't answered some of
your questions yeah
please repeater and you can also use the
mics to ask more questions to the
speakers if any one correlational show
so do i hunger ah has promised there at
correlations can we actually ask you to
publish them somewhere what you support
you can say I want to have your peril
Asia have you have you ever set up
correlations in max petrol CMS yes and
you still want it yeah I don't really
understand your question it's really
tough sucks talking about a particular
broaden bean max petrol are exciting to
IBM it doesn't matter what matters we
want to discover new chains and we
believe that somebody has got a silver
bullet there to share their expertise or
not yeah that I understand I'm just
saying won't help you suddenly gotta
understand when you start working
through the user case never implemented
see yet this will end in flames because
people usually try generating lots of
use cases if you're interested I can
shout you the difference between detect
only use cases and investigate tabouli
use cases well you see for example that
somebody's trying to brute force
password what you want to do about it
you want to learn who was doing it why
and where are they proud he could be the
user himself who forgot his password
maybe it's somebody from from her far
or maybe somebody's IT companies doing
it and still trying to brute forces okay
let me reformulate the question and the
latest SOT forum Alexandra's beer talks
about solar approach and he had a sir
slide where he said they had some self
weights
chandi didn't share them I understand
how exaggerated I go into the other but
yeah I think it was something had this
standardized SATs that they give to
their customers when they first meet so
they have this interesting Excel screen
AF categories and what-have-you
it's actually it's beautiful in a nerdy
way so I understand solar says they
cannot share do you have some basic
scenarios by the way she you start or do
you start with building a unique mortals
basic scenarios are part of every cm and
they make no sense well this will prove
they works that's what it does I can
give you a particular example now some
of our peers worked with that particular
customer before us so they gave of this
like twenty use cases we started talking
turn out a thirty percent the customer
didn't know what we were talking about
the I a thirty percent of this year's
cases the customer told us he could not
really provide data for them and they
have Alex in Oracle as the anchor of
their assistance
in order to do proper work on say five
use cases here go into spent so much
time what if we give you 90 use cases
one or a 240 I think this is a very
important subject we've been talking for
several years about creating community
you've been creating chats and telegram
you know within having those arguments
about having or not having socks and
people would say well we want to have
this new source of information maybe you
know they will read say 100 scenarios
you know there is a website called let
me google it for you and you can easily
find lots of use cases there there is a
for example data on soar manufacturers
or RB manufacturers you know the upload
there are use cases there if they don't
have a problem with up because you can
easily find this information elsewhere
when you grab an existing use case say
I'm gonna be tracking in my
infrastructure imagine Advanta it comes
in and says I've got this great
defensive system would you like to buy
hey you to say well it sounds relevant I
should have it and they may easily
happen that you do have this problem but
it's number 100 in a prioritized list of
problems yc1 so I suggest you first do
an inventory exercise this basic set
really is useless how are you going to
work with it well you may have say 500
rules for different activities the value
of that is close to zero I believe you
need a clear-cut quotient structure
he also needs to use basic scenario
doesn't float oh there is a question for
the customers but the list of incidents
he discovers they said nonlinear
incidents I'm sorry I found the right
questions what was the main application
of song it's a one-man sock right well
the word pretty long attacks where the
attackers were effectively starting us
and I know we're Russian company but we
have the rap offices abroad so they were
starting us for a three months with the
hell or a sock we're able to discover
them trace it back and limited to a
particular company Oh see you you're
able to identify the actual originated
from ok what's the original mode model
of anger a sock well it's a unique
proprietary model ok well we're all time
loves kbase brushwood
Dustin cannot see yet I have a question
shoot
hi
I can also answer the question regarding
when to buy and when to build a sock but
I actually have a question myself what's
your assessment of whether it's
technologists or people that bring
success in a song as a vendor I should
tell it's technology but you know what
I've been looking at the operations of
our sock and I'm gonna look at the stand
off here and I can tell you people be
technology hands down well this is
actually the answer to your earlier
question well if you have an
infrastructure where the right people
are lacking you would want to buy sock
as a service I actually have several
products see and the problem I had was
that I had about three and thousands
born of feeding events in cm so they
were not false positives they actually
had to be responded and I'm not even
talking about web attacks and other
things that also required response
another solution helped us identify 55
various threats children's targeted
attacks you name it I hope that over
time vendors will learn and will also
learn how to be more independent and how
to effectively have access to things
that are real Bonavita threats and not
false positives but technologies are
becoming increasingly more complex with
every passing year
yes the smart right now where'd you find
the right people for that well if you
look at Gardiner reports
you know I guess neutrons would appear
every year a year and a half but then
you got no reports for assigning watts
they say stop chasing trance make sure
you get a fundamentals right and I'm a
true believer in that I hold that one
day when you will stop selling
complicated technologists they're
impossible to explain that's why they
seem sexy and will start selling
technologies that actually work well
every automation system is a high-tech
harvester that requires a good mechanic
a good engineer if all you can do is
shovel with a spade and you don't have
an engineer or a good operator pun
harvester is not gonna help you where
are you going to hire these people well
look at Sergei he's alone you came up
with a list of systems it's a long ways
this is just a firewall or an anti-virus
or just a simple scene he's hello I
really love this case they actually have
the system summoning security guards
whenever people connect devices to power
sockets that were not designed for this
sort of connection anybody else has it
here well by Oh a lot store IT division
this guy certainly know what they do
they started building their not work at
a high quality level
business processes are designed in a
proper manner one of the problems was
are they wouldn't really think enough
about security and then they summoned me
then we started working together now
thanks to high quality interaction we
were able to build a system that enables
us together to drive down business
continuity risks yesterday geo to
storage failure we minimize the downtime
on mail servers to 30 minutes although a
storage system actually died physically
sure I think you are lucky I'm lucky to
work with the kind of people I work with
but he has to be a comprehensive
approach in more than one company
actually IT and security people should
work together both our support functions
designed to help business to his job
that's clear but do you see loss of
companies like this certainly not and
that's an issue is there a solution more
conferences more communication do you
think we can actually develop new talent
here at the conference maybe we can call
IT people to PhD next year or like an
open-air event
he can do it in the red square and no
more than five people can assemble in
the red square now guys we need to wrap
it up okay I've heard three different
presentations the customer wouldn't talk
about technologists or trans or target
models oh you did talk a bit about
processes but he talked most about cases
particular issues they were able to
resolve given their significance stuff
constraints from solar knows for sure
the his system is good at detection the
problem they have is they have a lot of
content and that's why his whole
presentation was about structuring its
ordering it making sure you properly
manage this wealth of data on incidents
so the guys are mostly interested not
know how to best cell with it's a rather
in how to best manage body hair and the
integrator perspective to make sure will
correct me if I get anything wrong gave
us an audit review we start by
developing an target model the needs of
the customer now this is a more
personalized approach
I like the difference the great divide
between the three presentations for the
majority of people here in the panel
except for Dmitry new trance and
technologists so sexy
you know it as a vendor I'm not asked
for machine learning but I'm asked for a
more user friendly way of normalizing
data or alternatively I'm invited to
integrate with Watson would you like to
help me guys in terms of wrapping it up
anybody wants to make a closing
statement do we have other questions
from the floor maybe ok that we actually
need to call it today thank you very
much for coming thank you very much for
your questions and thank you very much
for your presentations