everybody must race today mom to tell
you well gee my general manager the
beginnings let us watch video
[Music]
excellent you need to bring more action
what's about thank you that this shows
the next slide
[Music]
now hello young man young Elysium
apostle interdisciplinary very clearly
about not new layer things
what is the system nonnamous monitoring
and management of certain functions that
it into so it's for during some
iterations it works independently from
the two interesting things like
[Music]
connection of remote virtual media give
him over a be your most and sole support
base your support by just one will VLAN
support monitoring of temperature
cooling system and other interface for
racial human soul and ipmi vendors what
are the vendors most common supermicro
answers IBM HP ILO is also quite common
but across a bit less Intel RM Dell
higher-level they're more expensive and
it's my less common but borderline yes
dell idrac are the simplest and cheapest
in the market and others how they look
like as web interface that's the one
that's I love HP I dragged Super Micro
IBM let's focus our attention on some
server settings where we can see some
parameters but the server configuration
we can configure some things from IBM I
like change passwords or users console
so a mode where we can manage our
ipmi itself and different things which
makes no sense to mention right now it
looks like components let's talk about
components main component that systems
are based on are the BMC module as base
both management controller that's this
small computer which allows to implement
the IPMI standard IPMI itself it's
intelligent platform management
interface I map IBM cipm be I'll tell
you about it a bit later and a few words
about BMC module as said before it's
base board management controller small
computer which is made on the
and that are switching to regular land
with the network interface into my face
of connection of IBM I seem to have
several modules and connect them that
question before I'll be my IPMI so what
is IP my lecture intelligent platform
management interface very something
using which you can upgrade the server
and among other things not the only one
but one of the several things it's
operated through the web interface
remotely through network through the C's
23 to disappear you did p-put or through
the maybe my tools a network I noise IPM
I can work the operator three modes
first dedicated traffic goes only
through the dedicated network interface
and IPMI port I peer my traffic goes
through the any network interface of the
system abort failover when there's no
connection on the dedicated interface
traffic goes to through one-one
how it looks like in a picture we have
by PMI port and two common ports I saw a
PMI is a separate segment of the network
is the operation what it's fine some
common use ports to connect some things
network whatever let's talk about
general vulnerabilities vulnerabilities
in dedicated mode we mentioned here in
different IP addresses it will be there
but it can not know about it you know
you don't know that is that it's miss
connected it appears in the industrial
segment Packer comes and broke your
server at the end access hecka comes and
they can easily come to the segment of
the network in case if we reload of ipmi
and this could be done remotely secure
things and settings in particular change
of passwords go to default this problem
could be in dedicated roles
let me explain with the picture how to
setup there are connected service in
Japan is correctly connected
directly connected or me he may have
been connected properly and then
something went wrong we make an idea
here VLAN service is running in IPMI
mode B might a cosmic national promotion
secure and that way IP my is Ronnie you
know production environment I hope it's
sort of clear from this let's look at
vulnerabilities in shared or failover
modes like I mentioned phthalo remote is
pretty much the same as shirt win
situations we don't have the right link
control interface that can be seen in
the IBM I can be seen in all the
segments of the network the situation
will naturally change every time you
reboot the device or in other situations
as well so if you break essi you should
be in one VLAN you can get access to you
another one like I showed previously you
can have several segments of veal on
between this VLANs you can actually kind
of migration IPMI will serve a function
of a kind of a bridge between them what
you see here is a screenshot service
VLAN 3 and service VLAN 1 and that's no
the right approach so you got to choose
one network mode
this transmission of passwords employee
intelligence even unknown man authorized
user who follows this particular quill
see some like this so he will download a
file and in this fall you will see the
passwords in plain text such as my main
admin or maybe the real usernames and
passwords from well-known from devices
from well-known manufacturers after all
most about it a very interesting
vulnerability was recently discovered
called our AKB the key feature you
actually generator let's say killer H
mark which will serve as a key a key is
it to restore real passwords to IBM I so
we got authorization request and this is
the command that we use now we get a
response we get session request and we
can write PP a response containing our
mag that's Eddie that's what the package
looks like what does it contain it can
see some data well we're interested in
its the mass word and the staff required
to recover
rapido por el gato right Pisan whatever
your grandmother's power now we can
follow the algorithm in RFC to restore
the password and we will compare it to
the password I be my actually brings us
this so we can easily brute-force my
site for zero serious my technique is
interesting why to disconnect from
authentication new completely if you
show if you implicate the sign for zero
this actually means that you know we
don't need of the decays you know we
should be a largest like that into if
you study the package in more detail you
will see this actually - max at the
beginning that's exactly what no
authentication requires as a result you
will be able to produce a user list the
only difference here is that you have
successful authentication with empty
login and password for reasons not
entirely aware it's actually pretty
weird actually do not indicate walking
are passwords the user like this doesn't
exist but you still get authorize next
one it's miss configuration files record
here either
and what you see here is light a
screenshot the I pay my shell enables
you to make screenshots and store them
in your file system so you can have
access to them you can also get access
to the config folder which happens to
store your password this is how you get
access to I pay mine yeah right it's in
plain text for sure other supermicro
adorableness i just decided to give you
a list of CDs here but I'm not going to
repeat it and most of these are memory
leaks and buffer overflow vs 84 possible
right I pee myself seems okay but it
often comes with the DRC deviancy year
DMS what have you and when you change
your IDM a passport for some reason it
stays the same on VLC if you have a VNC
server next so IBM i you may have
defended security right a hacker can
easily use the same login and password
on VNC which is actually a very
widespread phenomenon this obvious man
what's interesting about it here is @ws
man mode which is often thought of a
partial mode numbers you can actually
address the pages out password file here
and get the credentials for WS man
Michigan later he is in order to
remember the highest rank my boss Logan
have very interesting and a very simple
adventure that's
every sponsor with a password which is
one is the person I drag her go
I dragged or pushing interest or even a
what attitude i drugged
relative I Drive that I could build you
man
or some daylight BMI over oh sorry you
an eye drop so they just love the show
and if you log in as root soon you will
be able to interests this is not a hack
of the admin system now that was part of
the firmware I'm not sure it was
designed by mistake but it is there's
also a share of IBM I on idrac and
that's what it's usually call to be Miya
something hydride share it will store
all the images that were using in this
particular IBM I all those who were
using in our server management system so
all we can do is actually write it
because we have the rights replace the
image and the admin comes and he will
use this image to actually stole the
system the system main simply may happen
to have backdoor it Super Micro ipmi
UPnP vulnerability well for us it's a
memory leak or ability it was a
discovery masses they be in 2013
UPnP you can't be i was integrated at 9
p.m. i inherited so what I'm able to do
is to completely change your firmware so
there you can install a backdoor and
read the data it's a particular example
and Metasploit so everything has already
been pre-configured for your enjoyment
the controller Brad we're done with the
tag so let's talk about post
exploitation upload a bullet Furler
supermicro might be mine this
functionality for firmware updates
it's everywhere I Drive so many other
systems what's nice here you can
actually replace the forward without any
signature with an older version you get
easily updated with older firmware a
running some malware on top of it and
again the system will be absolutely fine
with that
and this is a particular form you won't
see if you fire them ok next one is
traffic interception function on super
bitch Martinez studies something started
as well
I don't expect everybody abusing the MC
itself isn't IRR it's a small device you
should truly expect a lot from it even
in terms of traffic it can go through
however it's quite comparable to a
regular router as this chart shows 90
megabytes per second he can easily do no
problems it does support IP forwarding
so that is possible as well SSH
tunneling ipmi has its own SSH where you
can log in and this is something we'll
discuss in more detail probably you
would want to access other segments of
the NAP room through IBM i we have on
IBM I probably doesn't know that because
it has dropped the air well I can I can
all payloads because you know don't
grate in SSH what do we do the first
problem we need to address is scarce
Otzi of physical space first we need to
create a partition well we can virtually
add a hard disk create a partition and
there will we'll be able to set up our
own SSH for example Debian arm now we've
tested it we know it works also we'll
need to attach a new IP address are you
doing over there are two MAC address
well next we do reporting
that's what it looks like naturally this
is just a list of commands he will tell
us discuss Supermicro they actually have
their own implementation of SSH
interestingly you can use the same
credentials admin admin and you will end
up in a show like oh just like in the
web you can study the walks you can
remotely not hid my servers and do other
things that's what it looks like usually
so we see this quasi SSH which is
running naturally we want to escape this
show into beam bash beam SH so that we
can actually do things in a pretty old
native researcher which a show there was
a hidden capability and I be my shell
command it was for some reason our
documented tomorrow so if you do shell
ash with him actually
well they fixed it in version 1 they
completely switched off the command
apparently I started starting it and I
noticed that smash and chilli he enables
you to create some sort of targets like
this and every target he's actually a
suffer file
and if you address a file like mr.
theoretically you can actually end up in
Sh I proceeded on that hypothesis and it
turn out that smash actually would work
with variables and the shell variable
was reserved and they would actually
point to the root of smash itself right
okay this is but naturally you can
actually put a different target there
after all this variable if you do that
that should bring you to say Sh right
that's what it looks like in code
fortunately this is unfinished research
because that requires real choice so
which I usually don't have maybe if we
do privileged escalation it will work I
was also able to find some keywords such
as passwords shell and such so this has
been smashing sell for let me also
whatever one more thing there is ET c WD
i chose which shell isn't by which user
and there are users i will actually take
us to for using sis or be a jiffy not
slash
so we see for example test 1 and test 2
users that are allowed into smash which
is not robots
if we use admin account please know that
I've been with name capitalized and had
different users that will take us to SH
we didn't add anything this is default
you see possibly e to see this is small
table that gives me R is IP my versions
there shall say you'll see super Mike
Earth CC box which makes astray to later
versions interesting why la has their
own implementation how do you look for
ID like this is very interesting as well
deport 623 w depdc means sometimes
blocked
maybe it's blocked with firewall juice
where maybe doesn't respond for other
reasons so good reasons can be different
but how can he actually detect same Oh
first you get lunar before SSL
Certificates and sip of micro will
actually disclose itself a super micros
my demo you can bar cerise most
different web servers easy to detect
I mean server headers if you have s him
I'm sorry I am IBM I share that also is
quite telling
this approach does return some false
positives but rarely or you can look up
the DNS name some ipmi devices
supporting those names
so you can try simply checking I'm in my
dog's ordination company years shows
this must be a microcontroller if you're
not clearly using them and you're a
company should be careful with them well
we we simply found a couple of
microcontrollers like this search for
markup like I am
I'd be mine Super Micro sort of parsing
words like a charm SSL Certificates I
covered this already
now if we find the word I feel like this
is pretty telling
the first rewrite called IPA is
computable that's what it looks like
things I mentioned and all you got to do
simply execute it with this we also
desire this script multi the exact
linear audience I will detect it all you
will look for the right plugins default
logins
also you can find IPMI incenses it's
interesting I found very few of this you
want shot on one senses I indicated IP
mine I found for you no no you know what
I won't give you the exact number you
don't need this information
okay but you can use showdown as well
491 shorter significantly fewer and many
of them are actually the false positives
many of them are actually falsely
indexed let's talk about automation a
little bit they've been around for might
be my version in order to ascertain the
version of IP why because we have I'd
made my wine the one I pay my - that's
enjoy so what it does these sub packets
depending on the response it will person
reach her but this only worsen for 6:23
okay this particular scripture will only
try admin admin ok I pay my cipher 0
that's the entire time previously
described on you this is the one that
actually switches encryption or other
authentication Supermicro might be Mike
Connor he's actually to the sake gain
support 49 152 where you actually
address for download there's no there
you finally passwords in plain text but
in my sky
interesting development because it does
find the advice it also gives you BMC
config file the brute force is account
details and also looks for the
vulnerabilities I described there also
Metasploit module what's interesting
here is the last one I show that way you
can check IP my because I naturally
wanted to automate everything I've
described so far which are dead so what
it does is I mentioned it also has
certain the version of IBM I am I
and also checks form possibility of
escaping smash it brute force his
passwords and it checks against the
whole CDs that's what the interface
looks like that's how it works that's it
Sokka nuts protection why is it
important to regularly scared IP and
eyes like a bad shellfish the port might
be mine he's a beast
that often comes with the goalie chief
ER where you send your request once you
don't get a response so you forget about
it with a second or third scan you will
be able to get a different result
could have been you know an issue IBM I
rebooted he would turn on
also who we see we recommend using
dedicated Network modes all the commands
I mentioned previously can be used to
change the mode and please please do
remember to observe commutation or
switching girls I PA CL be very very
serious about ICL
all the author's recommendation is to
change to my sweet all additional
accounts add main admin user Karen who a
user at Kelvin naturally this accounts
need to be deleted and naturally issues
block site for 0 ok let's cover the
hatchery being a king you know nuns as
well honey folks I was feeling bored
since I decided to check how many
hackers are interested in entrance so I
created to make Hawaii my page I expose
it to the web I use the admins admins
those words I set up a service that
would return the word IBM I on for 6:23
so that it could be detected with
different scanners
I'm on a date so there is it looks like
zipper Mike you have this console it's a
java application connects somewhere he
does something what I did was to come up
with a blank of my own now what's a
simply tell me via DNS that somebody has
launched the application that would die
yes there are several mouths here such
as HTML baby if he doesn't want to use
Java you'll see the console is blocked
so you're invited East Java sees a
browser will tell him you shouldn't
really downloads after all he hasn't
been officially signed so 39 people
tried it in two weeks so this is how you
can actually find hackers with honey
boxes um thank you very much for your
attention
Oh Rose I'm sorry gotta Delia mini to
default me parboil the take away these
are naturally to change default
passwords but that's not the policy help
to have a more comprehensive approaches
makes me feel so lost without you baby
my okay how do we actually get access to
the operating system eight Linux of
ywhere or Windows once we have control
over IBM I actually have a console there
well in the IBM I interface from here
you'll watch the console's words with a
server operating system
won't it be locked you can do concern a
bit of so people solution by the console
operating system should be right as they
usually Yahoo servers other additional
ways well you'll have to hack sorry
about out this yeah but you can connect
your ISO right I have not really
researched answer I was only looking at
ways of hacking I pay my server hacking
is a different profession you know
thanks to you mention SMB share it's not
inside the IBM I itself right not the
one running castrated learn Linux or
circumscribes latex
it's actually irani of the BMC control
and there a loss of aya cells their
whole do they fit it's on for 6:23 no
they share it south and the BMC
controller do they actually react to
this for example you know many rows
would not be fixable different oh the
latest version of IBM I lost based I
feel so far I fail t scape completely
from smash and cipher zero attacks are
already blocked in the new version of
IBM i firmware
[Applause]
how probable is it that you get access
to a system like this
and in order to send out alerts you know
the ads mainly know what's a keep his uh
his data there would be able to take it
out of the system well that's a feature
of EMI or BMC rather so we after the
webinar we look up the configuration
falls and we try applying them to the
server that's exactly what you're the
first
foscar mentioned that's a been test
already this is a more comprehensive
approach really because you need to find
the passwords and try to reconnect to
the system using these passwords but
that's not difficult I have another
question are there any services such as
xenix that would connect to IBM i we use
IBM i for certain functions and i can we
actually intercept the authentication
details services that's address I'd be
my only role I'm not sure about that but
shouldn't be an issue that's what I
think
is there a network interface between IBM
I and the server can I actually like a
jumping around yeah babies actually the
implementation of my be my weapons your
face is just freaking for your
convenience being it all say is a be my
you tail and ap I pay my tools that were
specifically developed in order to the
protocol level and what I mean if there
is a dedicated to network interface for
management and for server versus if I
gain control over a management function
can I actually no you cannot gain
control over the network function as
well by default you shouldn't let me
this is the industry award ceremony and
I think this is this was the best
question so you get a t-shirt sir I also
like me this question about the network
interface were you the asking person the
Oscar that he is a Mike so the question
was completely notable bobeat
alright so that's a github address I
should have shown it it should be there
maybe I haven't opened access to the
repository yet it should be there