brings me to
uh blake here uh i i feel like we are
uh kindred spirits uh uh blake
reagan reagan i should have asked regan
regan ah
man yes pronunciation is hard uh works
as a senior security engineer for westco
international
where he focuses on blue team improving
enterprise security posture and
automating active directive related
business processes with powershell
uh i this is what the moment in reading
your bio that i felt the kindred
spiritness
i came from an admin world as well lots
of active directory lots of powershell
and excellent all right uh prior to
westco blake worked at motorola
solutions as an engineer securing
government and public safety land mobile
radio systems uh
itt technical institute in oakbrook
illinois where you graduate with
bachelors in information system security
you have a lot of letters after your
name i heard this
giac is this like it's
from this yeah it's this
hi everybody jeff mcjuggern uh sense
instructor and author as well by the way
so you hold the gcwn sand security 505
securing windows
gcih which is from sand security 504
uh hackier hacker techniques
ethical hacking security plus network
plus and project plus
priority starting in infosec 10 years
ago blake worked in building
trades and ran his own remodeling
business he lives with a wife and
daughter in illinois sorry
his wife his one and only wife didn't
mean to imply otherwise
and blake's talk today is on limiting
admin user risk in a windows environment
and other tips to avoid making the news
right to avoid appearing
like hey we are breached and i know
because i read uh krebs on security
today
right that's a bad way to wake up so
this is a
this ties in nicely to our last talk as
well on
turns out admin users are users as well
it's right there in the name
they just can result in a breach more
quickly if they are compromised so
uh blake any uh questions for us are you
ready to
uh have us drop off audio and video and
take it away
so thanks for the great intro that's a
great um
i you know feel overwhelmed there i do
have a link for
um the slides i'd like to share with
folks so if you
want me to share it now um yeah i'll
click on any link you provide me
i'll send it to you real quick um okay
i will be your relay point as well thank
you
thank you oh my goodness posting your
slides on github just before the talk
i am swooning over here
all right so yeah if you don't need
anything else any other info
i'm ready to get started excellent all
right
uh lee and i will sorry wesley and i
will drop off
and take it away blake thank you very
much
okay hi my name is blake regan and my
talk is
limiting admin user risk in a windows
environment
and other tips to avoid making the news
thanks jeff for the great intro
we can probably cut some time out of the
presentation now
two of the things that were covered in
there automation enthusiast
i love automating things with powershell
um
many years back a manager challenged me
said hey
you know i'd like you to get into
automation so here's a project
make an automated usb scanner out of a
raspberry pi
and so uh we got a raspberry pi i i did
the work on it that is up on my github
but that was a really fun experience
that kind of really opened some doors
for me
new challenges so and also a serial
learner
right we all have to continue our
education in this field
threats are changing every day new
technologies are coming out
and in order to stay relevant
i found it to be important to continue
your education
right and that comes into training i do
have a couple certifications
um i've got those through that that
constant learning right so what are we
going to talk about today
we're going to talk about unauthorized
local administrator privileges
we're going to talk about managing local
administrator credentials at scale
we're also going to talk about
protecting administrative account hashes
and credentials as best we can
right we're talking about limiting that
risk we're also going to talk about weak
password policies
for administrative accounts and how to
fix that and then
we're also going to talk about how to
limit your risk from efs ransomware
so just a disclaimer here i am going to
reference
a couple scripts that i these were
things that i came up with to solve a
problem
um in my day-to-day job and i thought
that they'd be beneficial
for others to at least start that idea
of how to accomplish it right so
please run these scripts in a test
environment before running them in
production
there's no dangerous actions being taken
by these but that's just best practice
right there's a lot of information
great information on github it's just
always important to vet that information
before putting it into your production
environment
so unauthorized local administrator
privileges
it's like breaking through a wall right
it's unexpected you don't want it
it can cause problems so let's talk
about some of those problems
so we have unapproved and dangerous
software installation right
a lot of software requires access to
um areas of the windows operating system
that only an administrator
can can have right so that's one of the
things that you want to limit
in a production environment
we're also going to talk about user
compromise turns to instant privilege
escalation if that user that is an
administrator
is compromised that eliminates one step
from
you know that kill chain that the
attacker has to take
in order to get to their objective right
they got local admin right away
so we're also going to talk about uh
just this improve
configuration changes um you know
maintaining a baseline in an environment
is very important and when
an unauthorized user gets administrative
privileges they can make changes that
may deviate from your
you know your your acceptable risk
baseline or just cause production issues
right and those are that's a bad day for
everybody
and then insider threat um unfortunately
there are those situations where
someone who is trusted has elevated
access and
does take advantage of that many
instances
in the past you could just check the
news and there's many many
more this isn't an all-encompassing list
of of risks right
so how do we detect this how do we
detect this
unauthorized local administrator access
so one of the ways that we can do this
is by keeping a
a management system a records management
you put in a request
the request gets approved you either get
the access
for the consultant for the project for
yourself
or it gets denied right but the the idea
behind that is it's all
it's recorded and now there's a baseline
that if there
is an incident you can go back and check
hey did we actually
like what were we thinking when we said
that this was okay or no we have no
record
right that can kind of help fill in some
of those those blanks
in the event of an incident and it's
important to have that information at
the very start
right kind of track down how did
something happen we can also use our
our sign our security information event
manager
by creating an alert for event 4732
windows event id
that's a member was added to a security
enabled group
so now across if you have a domain
wherever you have
50 servers or you have 50 000 servers
now you're letting that that sign do
that work for you instead of checking
each server every day
that's not a task anybody wants to do
now you can get alerted when that
that privilege escalation happens you
can get tipped off and you can either go
check your record system
and say do i have a record for this and
i just didn't know about it
or is this something that is not
expected
right a lot of environments do not have
a sign
and that's okay there's powershell to
the rescue um i created a script that
can go out and query
members of a domain servers workstations
and using wmi
that accounts for older powershell
versions or older operating systems
to query the members of the groups that
you specify
right so now we can have this baseline
we can identify
what's going on in our environment and
the other step that comes with this is
holding people accountable right in
in your whether you're an enterprise
environment or a standalone environment
trying to understand what was the
reasoning why an account or a user was
granted administrative access
if it's just so that someone can log on
to a server and giving them admin access
that's not the best way to do it right
um so it's just
it's creating that culture of
accountability and security
um you know from the sysadmin from the
administrator level domain admin
and then all the way up through
leadership right and that that'll create
that bond
that's very important um you know when
maintaining defenses for an environment
so um you will find that if you start
generating events on an
account was added to a security-enabled
group and you start
asking people why this is happening you
may get some pushback
right but that's part of building that
culture of accountability and
understanding
the risk that that comes from it right
so let's use a little scenario here um
this is referencing my
uh get local membership domain script
so we see that when we run this this is
just a test environment so we have
two servers here but we can see we have
a whole bunch of
accounts that are local administrators
um
some of these may be known we even have
the domain controller
as a local admin on the server that's
not a good thing but this helps us get
that baseline
right you can't protect what you don't
know so
using this baseline you now have a
foundation to do cleanup
to use for incident response and then
also for audits
right a lot of times if if your
organization is subject to audits you
may need to prove
um principle of least privilege right
using this baseline can help with that
so let's look at example scenario now
this
i believe is a bug in the windows
operating system
right where if a user is named dollar
sign
you know if you see here we we said show
me the net users
right and you can see that dollar sign
does not appear
on this list and so that's right here
sorry
so that may be something that would get
missed a lot of times administrators do
things via command line because it's
it's faster it's easier but as we can
see here that if we view
local users and groups via the gui we
can
see that dollar sign account right and
if we check
the local administrators group on that
host we see that dollar sign
is a local admin on this host along with
other accounts here
and so
and so now when we run this script again
and we compare against our baseline we
see that we have a deviation
right so we need to look into this and
that's where coming back to our
our crm or our security request form
management
can say hey do we have a record for this
no we don't okay
did you add this do we have a sime alert
for this well
luckily if we set up the sim alert we
will have one
and we can see the actual time we can
start to get some of that
that telemetry data right the time the
the account that was used to add that
dollar signed account
to local administrators and other
information right but now we have that
that chronicled over time where even if
this wasn't
uh a malicious incident
we now have this pattern that we can
establish right instead of
trying to remember oh i think i saw this
account here but i don't remember if
it's supposed to be there
um so
one of the ways that we can remediate
this is to use
restricted groups in a domain
environment
now this is a good solution to
maintain a baseline of approved
accounts that are supposed to be um
enabled
on a particular set of servers um or
organizational unit or even workstations
and every policy enforcement what
happens is
this restricted group will refresh
the list of members that are supposed to
be there so if we go back to our
incident where we had
um get added that wasn't supposed to be
that isn't a member restricted groups
policy
that'll get cleaned up at policy
enforcement okay
and mouse died here so we're gonna
we're gonna offer out a bit
so how do we remediate this we talked
about our policy so in the last slide we
created our
our restricted group policy and you can
see that before we apply the policy
we still have dollar sign we have um
some other accounts we have bob
tech9 controllers with the domain
controller
when we run that policy enforcement now
we're cleaning up that list
now we're only having the local
administrator that will always be there
and then we will have domain
administrators which
um there's different theories on that
being in local admin but
now you can see we've we've cleaned up
our baseline right
so uh just going back over remediation
you can also do this for remote desktop
users
very often a user gets added to local
administrators
just so that they can log on to the
machine or check some things out
that's dangerous right you can add those
people to
those accounts to remote desktop users
using
the restricted group policy again and
that allows you that if you have to
remove that access
whether we have 50 or 50 000 servers
that if we're doing it through group
policy we now don't have to touch
every single server to do that we can do
this at scale
using our policies here and so we can
see here that
remote desktop users has no members
before we apply our policy and then
afterwards we now have our limited
access group
uh and then to remove it like i
mentioned you remove it from the policy
policy updates no more access on the
server
right so and this is just coming back to
our
our get local membership domain i
configured it to look for local
administrators
and local remote desktop user
rights so that's just showing here the
remote desktop
if you like this idea you can go modify
this look for any group that you want to
the script also does have powershell
commandlets to look for users but a lot
of times in environments
the powershell versions may not be up to
date so wmi may be
a better way to do that so
um so let's say you like this idea of
restricted groups
there are some no no's for restricted
groups
do not apply restricted group
administrators to domain controllers and
the reason for this is
the administrator on a domain controller
the built-in administrator
is de facto uh domain
administrator it also runs a system when
you connect to other hosts
so it makes it very hard to detect what
actions were taken by
a user
running that way and so just showing
here this instant privilege escalation
so just be careful with this and do this
in a test environment
if this is something that looks that
could be very helpful to you
test it out in your test environment
the other thing to think about is that
if you
if you modify here you can add users in
this section here
and it will not overwrite the currently
enabled users in that group
if you use this option up here
this will wipe out everything that is in
that group
and apply what's in here so again be
careful with it
it's a great way to limit that risk
but you need to check it out in your
test environment first
so now we're going to talk about
managing local administrator
account credentials at scale also known
as lap
now lapse does have its shortcomings but
it is better than having the same
account password on every single host as
administrator
in your environment there's also another
way to do this
jason fawson um has documented
a way to do this with powershell protect
cms message
and the benefit of this method is that
it can be used
in a non-domain environment so that's
one of the caveats of lapse
is that it requires a domain and so that
kind of leaves
um that leaves out a large scope of
systems
you know that that can have this feature
applied to it so
um some of the risks of having the same
credential on all the hosts in your
environment for local administrator are
if that hash is compromised um popular
tools like responder
using llmr or netbios relay
um can get that hash can actually get
authentication to happen and send to the
attacker
and get that hash okay and now
that we have that hash we can either
pass that hash
or we can crack the hash a great tool
um by marcelo salvati is crack map exec
it's very common way to pass the hash
there's also some powershell versions
out there invoke the hash
but again that's that danger right and
we want to we want to eliminate that so
and what does lapse do um lapse differs
that credential on all of the hosts and
the environment that it's applied to so
there's a unique password for every host
because windows does not salt the hashes
for passwords if i have the same
password that you have our hashes are
identical but if it's in a linux
operating system
they have a assault and that makes the
same password hash different
for as long as you don't get a hold of
the salt for different users so
um a couple things that you can do here
right is deploying the laps in the
domain environment that's going to help
to solve that issue
uh lapse has some built-in functions
that can help you for delegating
permissions or building that into your
role-based
access controls right so different
different levels of access need
can be applied to different to different
um
organizational units of servers based on
sensitivity level
so i know that sounded like a bunch of
complex words but really
you can grant access to the people that
need access to those credentials
and then denying access to the
to those individuals who do not right
um
so tips and tricks for laps
um i struggled with this last year
and a couple of things that i came up
with and
successfully um completing that struggle
were
to rename the local administrator
account via group policy
that that lapse is going to manage now
that doesn't
it just makes things more difficult for
an attacker to enumerate
right the the rid will stay the same but
the
the name will be different right and so
then we're looking about
uh to assign laps to manage that new
account name that's what we're talking
about there
renaming the local guest account via
group policy if you're going to
take the time and invest in deploying
laps to your environment
also take the time to make sure that the
guest account is renamed and then also
disable that account if it's not already
disabled via group policy right
this was something that was a little
puzzling to me
so deployed laps in the environment all
of the servers were reporting values
but when you went to go use that
password it wouldn't authenticate
and so going back checking over all the
settings
everything was good i found a post um
i believe it was on stack overflow
where someone said when they force reset
the password for the lapse
client that the password synced and then
the password was able to authenticate
and so that ended up being the case and
if you see here on this
this screenshot here if you deploy laps
or you have in the past and it didn't
work for you
you saw this timestamp here this means
that
there's no password expiration set
because those values haven't synced up
on the host yet and
authentication will not be possible so
to fix that for
at scale right i came up with a simple
script to
you know target the organizational unit
where my servers existed
and then using the command to um with
the appropriate permissions
to force reset the password i was able
to force reset the password on
all of the host and then all the
credentials
synced and started working again this
was a huge relief
we had a red time red team exercise
coming up laughs wasn't working
um but by persevering and
reaching out into the community and
looking for information
it was very hard to find this i don't
think it was because people weren't
sharing it
it's just very obscure and you know
surprise surprise
is not documented in any microsoft
documentation
but i digress and so
are there some downfalls to lapse uh it
can be viewed that way
all right the lapse values are encrypted
in transit but not at rest
so when the admin password dll
is communicating between the domain
controller and the host
that communication is encrypted
but at rest those values are in clear
text
with the caveat that the account has the
been delegated the privileges to view
those values
okay so there are some controls in there
there's some active directory magic
that's going on to
to manage those extended rights um
but if you're viewing information
through a third-party ldap viewer tool
that attribute will be shown in clear
text because it's not being encrypted in
transit between
communication between the dll so that
could be
inadvertent information disclosure so
how can we solve that
well we can use packet encryption in in
windows
domain environment we can use ipsec with
no encapsulation
which i know that sounds complicated but
basically
it's just using kerberos and ipsec
to generate a secure um
connection between the client
and the the target right
and so um is there a better way to do
this
possibly definitely for environments
that are not
on a domain
jason fawson uh documented this so the
credentials are stored
um in a certificate encrypted file on
the host
and that certificate can come from a ca
or a self-signed cert
the password gets encrypted with a
public key on the host
or network share so the attacker gets
that public key that's not the end of
the world because it's the private key
that matters
um and then those passwords get
decrypted with a private key that can be
stored on a smart card
you and then you use a scheduled task
that handles the cadence of the password
update
um running the script to do this and
then archiving it on a network share
i realize i'm running a little behind on
time so i'm gonna
and the best part is it does not require
a domain to use so for
a lot of ics and ot environments that
are not on a domain or some segments or
not
this may be a solution for you and as
you can see here
just encrypts the um you know it names
with the host
the account name the timestamp and then
the thumbprint certificate so that when
you're going back to uncover this
credential
you know which certificate is is needed
to access this
you can also use our back here if you
have views different certificates to
encrypt
different levels of credentials and then
you you control
the access to those private keys
for your your staff you can then also
kind of balance in some
some role based access control there so
protected users this is really important
protected users
in the windows domain environment has
some major protections
for active directory side for accounts
and then on the client side for accounts
so the main things are restricting the
use of
ntlm authentication so that will break
past the hash for ntlm
also restricts the use of das or rc4 for
kerberos pre-authentication
so a lot of older protocols may not work
when you have an accountant protected
users but the the main benefit is the
restricts the use of kerberos delegation
so um
you know you definitely don't want to
have your domain administrators or your
account
operators be delegated to authenticate
to different services right protected
users kind of
puts the brakes on that and then the
kerberos
tgt ticket granting ticket cannot be
renewed
um you have to request a new ticket
granting ticket so
if you are able to to steal a ticket or
forge a ticket
that ticket can't be renewed it has to
be
created from scratch so that kind of
adds another protection there
and the biggest thing about protected
users is
eliminates the caching of plain text
credentials for cred ssp
and w digest so the downfall to that is
it will break offline sight in
but again you don't want to have your
administrative users be able to sign
in offline on any kind of device
um also ldap and ntlm authentication
will no longer work
so what it's kind of a big deal because
a lot of technologies use ldap and ntlm
authentication so looking at protected
users
you really need to take a approach of a
small test group
and then monitoring and kind of
increasing the scope of that
because there may be some things that
break that you don't know or won't
expect
so definitely uh important to
take small steps there one interesting
thing is
tacx plus for administrative access on
cisco devices
ends up using rc4 for kerberos
pre-authentication now attack x plus is
a
20 plus year old protocol maybe it's
time to move on from that i don't know
that's something to think about there
weak password policies for
administrative accounts and non-admin
accounts so the problem here
is that with lan man authentication
is an older protocol you take the
password clever
and lowercase so what happens is lanman
converts that password to all uppercase
and then it splits that it pads it to 14
characters
and then it splits that password into
two seven character chunks
right so if you anybody that has
password policies where they say well we
have 10
we only require 10 characters
guess what lan man hashes can still be
stored on
devices and they're very easy to crack
the last part about landman um is that
it uses those two chunks
and then uses a des encryption
uh method to bring those hashes together
uh i didn't do the best job explaining
it but that's why i provided the slides
so um and that's the thing i mentioned
before windows hashes lack of salt
so again those that one password hash
for a user is the same
for another user with the same password
so as you can see here using hash cat i
was able to crack this hash
in one second
so it really focuses on the need for
length over complexity
and so the downfalls of a windows domain
default password policy
is that there's some limitations on what
you can enforce and as you see here
here's a screenshot
14 characters i think the default if you
install active directory is seven
characters right now that's still the
default
weak password policies for
administrative accounts the solution
here
is to use fine grain password policies
a lot of people may not know about this
this is accessible
through active directory administration
center which comes with your remote
server administration tools
and then these screenshots here will
show you how to access that but
the benefit of that fine grain password
policy is
we have the option to say if my admin
account
keep it locked out until an
administrator manually unlocks the
account
enforce account lockout policy for admin
accounts you definitely want to have
manual intervention needed
to unlock this account for user accounts
it may be based differently on your
your risk model here but the the minimum
here i would say minimum
is 20 characters for passwords uh for
administrative users
and for your regular users at least 16.
if we remember lan man hashes are 14.
can only compute a hash with 14
characters
if you take it a step further to that 16
um
you're still having that that complexity
right and so um unfortunately i ran over
talking about a couple things so
um just reviewing here
and these are all on the slides folks uh
one of the last things that we can do
is use um password spraying in our
domain
to identify weak passwords right and so
there's a tool by
uh written by bo bullock from black
hills information security
called domain password spray again use
this tool
in a test domain first but this can help
you find passwords like summer 2020
exclamation point
um
just so you know we we have uh 15
minutes of buffer for q a
do not oh you don't have to fly through
these slides you're okay okay i
appreciate it i was going for the 30
minutes so
let me just step back here uh thank you
thank you
so as we see here in the slide um
we have our fine grain password policies
that we created we created one for
administrative users and then we created
one for
just regular users and so you can see
that this tool will pick up those
policies
and looks at our our lockout threshold
the
password length so it's identifying that
we have different password policies
applied
right and by doing this password
spraying right the password was password
this is for example
but it will identify the different
accounts that you have here so we've got
tyler durden
lazarus group sec moto all we're using
the password
of password so now
we either know that we need to change
these passwords
if we're doing this as a blue team
exercise or if we're doing this as a red
team exercise we now know that we have
some
access that we can use right to do
further enumeration
and so that's the power of that it's
great it's one of those things related
to password policies
right now i know the the future
of authentication is going to
passwordless
but until greater strides can be made in
usability and and applicability we'll be
using passwords for some time
right so and passwords are like
underpants
change them often keep them private and
don't share them with anyone
so uh kind of wrapping it up
uh limiting risk from efs ransomware
this is also something that i picked up
in my sec 505 class
and i just thought it was amazing i
thought it was so smart
um so efs our encrypting file system
is built into windows
okay and it uses a certificate
to the private key or sorry the public
key
of a certificate
to encrypt files so only the private key
can decrypt that
so think about that if an attacker was
able to get access
into your environment and escalate to
the domain
or enterprise admin level access
they can now take and use that built-in
efs
function against you and ransom
and lock up your system right it can
even be done with a with a key that's
created
outside of the environment and imported
as a string of characters
once that private key is gone you can't
decrypt those files
unless you have an efs recovery agent
key set up and so what that does is
um
creates in a policy a using a
certificate
that when the efs mechanism
goes to encrypt files that private key
that is used
is encrypted with the public
key of the efs recovery agent
so now if you have the private key
to the efs recovery agent you could have
a recourse
to decrypt your files that an attacker
tried to use efs ransomware that's
something to think about even if you
don't use efs
in your environment it is good to check
and make sure that you have a recovery
agent set up
the caveat to this is you must you must
have that private key
store that offline put it on a smart
card put it in a safe
it may never be used but in the event
that it's needed
i mean how awesome what what a great
feeling and what a great outcome that
would be that
you know you prevented that and so
closing thoughts what do we say to the
god of death we say not today
right uh limiting risk as much as we can
in our environments is very important um
i think we know or or are learning you
can never be
100 secure and even the most elite
um and mature organizations can be
compromised
it happens right the important thing is
to have that
baseline of access that baseline of your
systems
limiting that risk strong password
policies now
i know that it's not the end-all be-all
solution but it really
can help to mitigate that risk on a very
large scale
and these are quick these are
easy wins to say to upper management
and you know infrastructure and say
listen this is what we want this is the
problem we have this is what we want to
do
it takes some some testing and
cooperation to get there
but it's it's such a better place to be
than just having
you know the same password for all local
admin accounts on servers and
password policies under 20 characters
for administrative users
there's so many other things right some
acknowledgements here i'd like to give
acknowledgement to jason fawson
um you can find his information at
blueteampowershell.com
also black hills information security
when i really started getting focused on
info
information security that was a has
has been and is a great resource
for um for people new to information
security
and advanced people also beau ballock
davtec with the domain password spray um
and then also tyrone e wilson from cover
6 solutions
tyrone was my mentor for the
presentation
and really gave me some great feedback
and just given him acknowledgement there
nice to meet another person in the
community
we also both play hockey so that's you
know it's cool to meet another hockey
player
and i'd like to say thank you to graham
and scythe for the opportunity to
present
um i think it's great to create a
community where people can share
information
and share um different ideas in kind of
an open way
and just collaborate this is my first
major talk to a large audience and it's
been a great experience working with
tyrone
and graham and scythe to get prepared if
you want to connect
i have a github linkedin and on twitter
i go by the handle blake
underscore r38 i think the first handle
i went to pick out was taken so i just
used
the next one there so i really
appreciate the time
and i look forward to watching um the
other events and
and hoping that uh 2021 is a is a much
better year for all of us
i know that it's been difficult and just
looking forward to um
to a brighter year next year so thank
you very much
well done blake nicely done uh that was
thank you that was an amazing talk um so
perspective again i came from blue team
ops i'm now
on the red team and literally yesterday
i presented a report to the client
where the in the even up to the
executive summary the example path i
gave
was hi if my attack if the attacker
gains access by a phishing which it
almost always is
almost always they'll have limited user
access unless there's some way to get
local admin that's a significant uh
sync for attackers they don't always
have to get local admin but it's always
useful
and the single fastest path
to failure as a defender is having
sets of computers with the same local
administrative credentials
let me say that again the single
fastest path to failure as a defender
is having the same local administrator
or administrative
credentials across multiple machines
another path i used with that exact same
client the report delivered yesterday
was one random admin machine with
authenticated users in the remote
desktop users group
so anybody across any domain that has
any trust could log into that box
i log in i'm a limited user oh no but
the
local administrator password that was
shared on public file shares
lets me escalate and hey look there's a
domain admin logged in
right that was oh yeah from limited user
to domain admin
in two steps right log in and log in
again with
uh local administrator credentials so
this
happens i love your talk actionable
advice and
this is where a lot of attackers look
both pen testers red teamers and
real world attackers so i cannot give
this a strong enough endorsement i love
laps as well
um i do share a couple extra links of
just setting up laps so it's not
terribly surprising doing a lab
environment first so you know what's
going to happen
um thank you for talking about what
happens with the protected users group
um in terms of like tacx i hadn't seen
that before right most of the
repercussions for admins
they don't care if they can't log into
the domains unavailable because they're
a freaking domain admin they're
there to admin the domain so it's not
usually relevant
um but but yes thank you for showing
that the possible downsides to
protective users
as well uh ghost mentions
abusing trust issues with bad security
practices and responder is my thing yeah
if you want to get into that you can
disable
link local management name resolution
protocol r you can disable
net bios for name resolution both are
default
right before giving up on a dns name
windows will say hey anybody
have you heard of that old sccm server
that's what i'm looking for
responders like i'll respond to that
that's totally me connect to me please
and you can either relay your crack
credentials from there yeah
ah thank you that was it that was
fantastic talk i'm i'm glad to
see you at grimcon and i will happily uh
attend your talks
at future events because this should not
be your your
one and only step into presenting you
did a great job blake
thank you thank you very much thank you
thank you yeah uh
let's see any other questions or
comments wesley
oh man no no the great presentation
um you know something that can be added
on to this as far as just another
another presentation is that you know
for people like jeff you and me this
makes perfect sense
you know this is definitely something
that we can see we can visualize we see
it done
but you know i'll be i'll be interested
to see how we report this to somebody
you know who may not have this type of
uh in-depth knowledge
and everything and like i said this may
be a presentation i did because
this is all great we understand this uh
from this from from that technical level
but hey how do you take this and put it
into a word that hey you know
oh yeah no absolutely somebody somebody
can actually understand like you know
what
i need to fix this right now that's the
biggest thing let's see these are
some talks ideas that can definitely um
come throughout the next grim con
or whatever conference to because these
are very
these are things that people like me
jeff and
anybody who've been in this field
struggle with just trying to communicate
this up
so that they understand like you know
what this is an action this needs to be
fixed
so um definitely something to think
about you know if you have
any ideas and how you how you present
that how you put it in a language or
how you get somebody to how did you
influence somebody to take action on
this
great presentation idea uh so
as an aside on that i i just literally
pulled up the
pen test report and it's nice to start
off with
start off with basic kind of orient your
audience so
my first sentence for the finding about
multiple computers with the same lock
and password
domain credentials are nicely centrally
managed inside of active directory
however each domain join also has its
own local credentials that are
separately managed
because there's a lack of visibility
that's where
security problems fester so
gaining increasing that visibility is a
huge thing so i said
commonly a lack of configuration
management on those local accounts are a
source of security related issues
for example using the same local
administrator password across multiple
machines allows by default
attacker who gains control of any one
computer to control
all other computers with the same
password i'm not hedging my phrasing
there but that's
huge and i go into specifics but uh
keep the make the complex simple and
orient your audience to the
idea quickly um so that you can then
talk into specifics but
start from very general is coming advice
there for a finding itself
um so uh that was awesome blake are you
i
shared your links inside of the noobs
track channel inside of discord uh
you should be judging me on the discord
shows
i'll answer questions if people have
questions you know it's great and i
thanks for the opportunity and i look
forward to um learning from the other
presenters
so yeah absolutely well i'll look
forward to seeing you at uh future
conferences
as well okay thanks jeff huxley
absolutely absolutely
uh powers from you all right get that
local admin back
yeah that's right we're not we're not to
the point of sharing root passwords yet
blake sorry
yes