so
catherine welcome on that positive note
uh that's this is this is our 2020 uh
gloom and doom discussion woohoo
always good to have a little gloom and
doom well that's how we're going to
close that
year we're going to put it all into one
big ship pile we're going to set it on
fire
these recordings will still be available
afterward but we're going to we're going
to have a more positive 20 21.
i agreed absolutely but on that note
what's your prediction for
what you think is going to be a new
trend in 2021
on the threat side
i you know i i don't i don't truly
believe we're gonna see anything
new per se i mean everything old is new
again right
so even with what we've recently seen
um you know most recently with with
fireeye
and solarwinds um
certainly that was uh not a good thing
right that there was a whole lot of
um devastation to an awful lot of
companies and entities
but at the heart of what was done wasn't
super new i mean we've known that that
was a possibility
so i don't know that we're going to see
anything truly new
what i expect is we will see things that
are old
done in slightly different ways that
make them come across
new enough that the media decides to
jump on it and run with it
that's kind of that's my prediction
because that's kind of what we've seen
right when people talk about all of this
stuff
i and they say to me you know oh you've
been in security for you know for how
long and i don't know how you stay on
top of it all i'm like
because it the change is not
radical it's the same problems we've
been encountering for a very long time
and while it's cool because this stuff
does evolve to a certain degree and
there's always new stuff to learn
the the heart of the of what we've seen
has not changed
yeah that sophistication is not as
sophisticated as
it is portrayed no but i am grateful
that at least
when they use the word sophistication
with the solarwinds thing
you know and they used apt they were
actually not just talking about
a business email compromise so you know
yay for using the right word
um because i've certainly seen plenty of
that yeah
it's easy to attribute that
no i was just going to say it's easy to
attribute that uh
and kind of play off your negligence or
your breach
if you call it apt if it was
sophisticated you're not really liable
so it's no big deal
right like that kind of uh playoff blame
game
i get from a liability standpoint a
business standpoint like as a
businessman like yeah i would love to
have someone to blame that
on but we really have to kind of start
to get away from that as
the professional industry that we are
we'll leave that to the cyber insurance
companies and let them
you know play off their liability
however they want but
yeah and i think i think one thing we
will start to see and we're already
seeing
right are those insurance companies
going hmm
no i'm not going to pay for this anymore
no we're going to change the contracts
when you get hit with this thing we
already know about
you're out of luck so
yeah yeah cyber insurance is going to be
a dangerous game to play and again we're
going to end up with more lawyers
because they're going to have to read
through all of that
fine print and we'll be doing some
circular
investing we'll call it
agreed i like how we brought in the
third rail of cyber insurance here
because that's its own
separate problem anyone got solution on
that one
and that ties into the ransomware issue
because ransomware has been
ravishing the the down market right i i
break the world into three categories we
have the haves
which we spend most of our time talking
about have problems
right when we're talking about like you
talk about uefi
i mean you're talking about the top of
the top you know littlest percentage
that can even consider a problem like
that let alone understand what it is
and then you have this other really
small group that's just below those
halves
and then everybody else is a have-not
and those have-nots are
municipalities local communities
water treatment plants small to
medium-sized businesses
and they're the ones that are getting
torched by ransomware and
my prediction from several years ago on
what was going to happen with ransomware
was i considered it the
collateral impact of connectivity which
was no one's going to target a community
bank
right there's nobody sitting there going
like well i really want to go hit peoria
because there's
so much money there but peoria happens
to use a lot of the same systems because
as much as we have all these different
vendors there's still
fundamentally a significant monoculture
and everything's connected right that's
what the internet does
and so what happens is you know insert
large financial bank can protect itself
and that ransomware that's going after
them just happens to sort of slide off
and knock that community bank offline
yeah i would agree i would absolutely
agree and i think too
i mean so i'm in higher ed and and
that's another space
um that has been hit pretty hard and
what we see with some of this stuff
it's really common that the attacker
puts puts something
out right through through email and
once it's downloaded and they get to the
next stage what they're doing at that
next stage is looking around and saying
hey where did i land is this an
interesting place should i keep going
so the target the true targeting nature
of some of this stuff is
is that it isn't it's just what can i
get into and when i get to that next
stage
look at that i'm in a thing and it's and
it might be cool and there might be
useful data here
so yeah that target of opportunity and
target landscape really you're
you're getting to the point where at the
end of the day
criminal enterprises even apt groups are
still business entities they still have
deadlines they still have timelines they
still have budgets they have
objectives and goals that they're trying
to meet and so while they're putting
time into the development
of you know whatever whatever it is
ransomware c2
that target of opportunity then has to
become monetized in order to
keep the lights on pay the bills maybe
they're contractors maybe they're
selling off access to apt groups so
that continual need to
provide money and sustainability at the
end of the day that we're all
capitalists even even the criminals are
capitalists
that capitalism has to pay for itself
and that is where we come down to
that target of opportunity or what can
we get for what we've done
i agreed which sets us up
really well for breaking the bad news uh
which is your talk
that it does
oh i got to make you presenter you do
i got carried i love it then i will
gladly share it
there you go boom all right
all right should be able to see it now i
hope
with our little grim fellow in the
corner
i liked the candy scythe i did too
i did too which is why i sort of crapped
him out of the other image because i
i couldn't cleanly get him otherwise
but uh yeah so we'll talk a little bit
here
about things like ransomware and
breaking the bad news in
the industry um because certainly
as we just discussed this is a huge
topic
so here we go this is this is the agenda
this is going to be a very short version
of a presentation
that i typically spend a little more
time on but i think we can really
hit the highlights and the really
important stuff and spend most of our
time there
so i'll talk briefly about myself and
why this is important if you haven't
already figured that out
and then we'll talk about some strengths
and weaknesses that we see within
infosec
that ultimately play a role
in in all of us being able to
communicate this information
and we'll talk about communicating at
different levels within our organization
and then we'll talk a little bit about
non-verbal communication which is
equally as important and some final
thoughts
so this is me well not really this is my
sloth mini
that i used to um was an adopted sloth
at the zoo locally she unfortunately
passed away a few years ago but
i love sloths this is really more about
me
um i've been with the university at
buffalo for more than 20 years
i'm on staff with some things i do a
bunch of volunteering and talks and i
have some degrees and some
certifications and other
assorted stuff so what's the motivation
behind this
well if you weren't just uh hearing us
talk a moment ago
ransomware and other forms of attacks
are pretty common
so you know the odds of getting hit with
something like that are pretty good
even when we've seen perhaps in some
cases a decrease in breach we've seen an
increase in records
so these are the statistics going
through september of this year
because that information is basically
quarterly so this
this shows you literally what the odds
are and you know if that really isn't
enough
realize that last year alone and of
course we're just coming the end of this
year so i can't wait to see what these
numbers show us
but last year we we lost roughly a
billion records
and a huge chunk of them they may have
you know
been not pii right they're not sensitive
data
but you could wind up with additional
exposure so this really
is something that you're likely to run
into and the reason why that
this talk came about is that i
recognized we seem to spend a lot of
time talking about
ideally how to prevent bad things from
happening and we talk about how to clean
up after bad things do happen but we
don't talk about
communicating while those bad things are
going on so that's really the focus here
today
and if you haven't seen this quote i'd
be very surprised
this idea that there's you know only a
couple of types of company
the ones that have been compromised in
some way and
you know the ones that are going to be
again right
if you don't know that you've been
compromised you probably haven't looked
hard enough
so sorry for the bad news but now let's
talk about this our strengths and
weaknesses
really this problem that we run into and
by this problem i mean sort of the
larger problem of
compromise and the possibility of
needing to do ir
is not a technology problem it really
isn't a lot of this is a people problem
and so if you
think it is maybe you should take a step
back and realize that all the technology
in the world can be incredibly helpful
and it has a role
but people play a huge role as well and
that's the
kind of the point of this particular
quote so what are we really good at in
security and
in i.t in general well we're great at
fixing things there's a problem we get
hyper focused and we want to solve the
problem right
so that's what we do and we are
spectacular at that that's what we are
known for
what we're not always good at and what
we're known for not doing well
is communicating with people so
whether or not you recognize this this
particular image is
from a skit on saturn in it live
where they have this computer guy who
you know kind of behaves like a jerk
and this is the attitude he gives right
it's the computer that's stupid not you
right and we do this and we don't
necessarily do it with
bad intention we're not trying to be
jerks
in most cases but the reality is that we
are
in some cases not so nice and it's
it's very easy to get caught up in
focusing on fixing the thing
and not the bigger picture with the
people
we don't have patience patience is tough
and and i've been there and i've been
in situations where you just want to
scream and tear your hair out right
because the person you're talking to
people they just don't get it or they're
not listening or they don't understand
but realize that that goes both ways
when you get frustrated
and you lose your patience you're not
patient with them either
and we'll talk about why that matters
why does it matter well
there can be a loss of trust and that's
really important if
your goal ultimately you know once once
you're done dealing with this
this incident or even during the
incident is for folks to trust you to do
the right kinds of things
you need to make sure that you're
communicating with them in a way that
that continues that level of trust
you're going to have difficulty
communicating with them in the future
you could have additional conflicts
there certainly could be negative impact
on the reputation of the company
people go out and they talk about things
they probably shouldn't you have a
decrease in
morale and everybody's stress level goes
up
so we're going to use an example here of
ransomware because it's so prevalent but
realistically everything i'm talking
about today
first of all it doesn't matter exactly
what role you are
so if you are you know the i.t person
and you do everything from security to
you know replacing keyboards or you are
one of
uh you know a small security team or a
large security team
this should apply to you when you run
into some situation that you're doing
some form of incident response
so the example i'm using here is
ransomware
so let's imagine that you've had
ransomware but it could be solarwinds it
could be any one of these
things that you know now you have to
deal with and
none of them are fun right none of us
want to go in and deal with this kind of
thing
so now what do we do well we can step
back and go
wow big explosion and walk away not
usually helpful
we can panic and completely freak out
also not terribly helpful
so instead we're going to have to
communicate something about what is
going on and again
depending on your role you're going to
communicate with different people at
different levels
so that's what we're going to spend most
of our time talking about
so we need to do what's called framing
the conversation and the whole idea
behind framing the conversation
is focusing on what's important to your
audience so these are the three levels
we're going to focus on your end user
your mid management and your executive
and you want to think in advance about
what are the kinds of things they might
ask and what is important to
them you also want to think about
how you're going to get this message to
them the channel right so
is the message going to be sent through
an internal website are you going to do
a presentation to somebody is this an
email or is it in person
there's always of course lawyer approved
pigeon carriers
but consider your channel because if you
have an entity that is potentially
inside your organization like
in the case of the solar winds maybe
internal email or communications of that
nature is not your best option
so first we'll talk about the end user
usually they're focused on what impact
it's going to have on their day-to-day
job right
you want to make sure that they know
what happened
and why but only what they really need
to know
if it's something where it's you know
somebody's clicked on something and you
have the opportunity to teach them
something about what happened
and encourage a change in behavior by
all means use that
ultimately we'll see all of these
different
groups whether it's end user mid
management or your executive
you need to use effective and efficient
communication
so what do i mean by that well
what i mean is number one be concise
less is more
absolutely you don't need to tell them a
huge story
you need to tell them something simple
but don't
use things like blaming management to
tell your story
and leave out stuff that's going to be
relevant to them that's why it's
important to focus on what is
important to them and be patient even if
you have to go in the closet
afterwards scream tear your hair out
it's important
make sure that whatever you are saying
without however you're communicating
that it's at a level where these folks
can understand and relate to it
because again there are ramifications if
you don't
this is how we don't want to communicate
with end users right we don't want to
scream at them
we don't want to freak them out we don't
want to give them you know additional
fear
that's not ideal so be upfront
lying to them you know the lies we tell
children right we tell them things to to
make it easier on ourselves
that often winds up biting us in the
butt and we don't want to deal with that
we want to address their fears so if
they're concerned about something you
know be honest about what you know and
what you can tell them
and perception really is reality in all
cases but especially for your end user
if they see or come across something
that they have a concern about even if
you
know it's really nothing make sure you
take a moment
and you listen to what they're saying
because number one it could be something
bigger than you realize
and number two they will really
appreciate that you took that time
to really listen to them all right our
mid-level managers right mid management
is a
really tough place to be everybody who's
in mid-management typically wants to go
up
right they want to be executives and the
people who are below them want to be in
mid management
that's a tough tough place to be they're
focused on
you know their impact to whatever
business process they're involved with
so
it's going to depend on their department
and again you want to speak to them at a
level that they understand
we're going to use effective and
efficient communication we're not going
to use technical terms with folks who
aren't in i.t
and even with those who are in i.t be
careful what terms you're using because
they may or may not understand them
there are groups of people in i.t who
might understand security terminology
that
other folks in iat don't so just be
aware of that
we don't want to be chickens with our
heads cut off right we don't want to
walk in there and be like oh no it's the
end of the world the sky is falling
we need to come to them with a plan
which we'll talk about in a second
so the ideal mid-level manager
what do they look like well they've got
fantastic delegation skills
their interpersonal skills are amazing
they can communicate they can negotiate
they have emotional intelligence
they're influencers and where are
these amazing people well i've given
this talk a few times and i've actually
had people come back to me and say oh
i have an amazing manager and that is
fantastic because
you know we should have more of them but
they are somewhat rare
kind of like pink fluffy unicorns
dancing on rainbows
so we're going to communicate with
regular middle management by being
supportive
again they're in that weird mid space
right so you're going to come with an
action plan
even if you're only presenting maybe a
portion of it because of your particular
job responsibilities
that action plan should include
communications that go up and down
so they're gonna you're gonna have to in
some
way either working with them directly or
yourself communicate
above them and below them and be
empathetic
put yourself in their shoes it is a
tough tough place to be
and whatever you do make them look good
it can only help you in the end
so the plan we're talking about this is
what it really should include
what happened all of your stakeholders
you should have a sense
of all of these different stakeholders
so you know are
are there just internal stakeholders
probably not they're probably external
as well in some capacity what are the
potential
recovery time frames what are our
options um
you know how can we make sure this
doesn't happen again or what what can we
do to
at least limit that possibility and have
an end goal in mind you know and maybe
maybe you have a plan and it's a
short-term plan and then you have
another short-term plan so the end goal
might not be
get to the end and clean up and be done
with everything the end goal might be
all right we need to get through the
next 24 hours and where do you want to
be in that next 24 hours or when do you
want to beat a certain point
be accountable management really needs
to take responsibility for their users
which doesn't mean
that we play the blame game it just
means if
you are dealing with folks you've made
mistakes or
have done something that have caused
problems you need to take responsibility
for that
so these are some things that you should
be thinking about in advance
that that you want to talk about with
these mid-level managers and you want to
have decisions made
well before this sort of thing happened
like how to handle
you know potential ransom payments so
don't be asking the question when the
rants when that happens
ask what are you gonna do before it
happens um you want to maybe
uh you know have that conversation with
legal
and anyone else that needs to be
involved you want to
coach and encourage collaboration so
where in this process are you going to
manage your delegate
are you going to delegate or negotiate
again important things to consider
all right so let's talk about our upper
tier our executives right
our executives look at the big picture
these are the things they're focused on
they're focused on our
the goal the reputation of the company
and the vision and performance you need
to think
30 seconds in an elevator so you walk
into the elevator that's all you have
time to tell
whatever you're going to tell them so
that means you have to do your homework
you need to understand who these people
are because remember we're framing
the questions we're framing this
whatever we're telling them
on them you want to enter and exit
gracefully don't be upset
don't as best you can you don't want to
be agitated
you're going to discuss things
strategically with them and remember
they're people too even if maybe they
don't seem like it because they're so
far removed from you
they really are most of them have you
know a home they go home to
family you know maybe grandkids it's
it's a it's not a an easy place to be
either
so usually this is kind of what they're
going to want to know they're going to
want to know what happened
and when it happened but in a
non-technical sense again think big
picture
best case worst case most likely
scenario and the consequences and
underlying cause
not you know mr smith click this email
and blah blah blah long story
they want to know a compromise occurred
which wound up essentially
making data unavailable right you don't
need to get into the nitty gritty
when you are speaking to executives do
not use geek speak and we've already
kind of covered this with
the other levels too right you don't
want to speak to them in a way that they
don't relate to
and geek speak for the most part is
going to be a no-no
so which executives well make sure that
all of these people
at least have an idea of what's going on
so the leaders of your finance your
operations your marketing your
technology folks
there may be others but at a minimum
make sure that these folks are aware of
what's going on
okay so we have given a message and your
and as you've seen
that message is not going to be the
exact same message for all these three
groups right but the question is
was the message received or did it sort
of fluff off and how do we know
well this is kind of where nonverbal
communications can come into play
if you're able to give this information
to them in person
pay close attention to body language
which includes these things so face your
posture
gestures handshakes breathing all kinds
of of things that have nothing to do
with the words coming out of your mouth
how you interpret those nonverbal cues
is critical so
think about when you see somebody with
raised eyebrows right
we can we can interpret that with
discomfort or maybe it's surprise or
maybe it's doubt
so any one of these cues looking at
somebody excessively
crossing your arms and legs right is it
cold in here
or are they resistant to ideas you can't
necessarily tell
same thing with exaggerated nodding so
what you have to do is synthesize them
any single particular cue might throw
you off
so read the person read the situation
look at all of these things this is just
one example right if you have raised
eyebrows with someone with where their
eyes are moving all over the place
their hard grip is on whatever it is
they're probably uncomfortable
um but you could see something else
again you need to sort of look at that
bigger picture
all right and i'm flying through this
our number one job i have always
believed in security is to educate
we want to educate we want people to
understand
why they should care about what we have
to say we don't want to adjudicate
learn what folks know and trade back
your knowledge with them for a while i
worked with a group
that were actually rocket scientists
and they were brilliant brilliant people
some of whom were really bad with pcs
that's just not what their focus was on
but
they were rocket scientists and so i
would teach them what they needed to
know
about their pcs and their and the
computing and the networking that they
had to do
in order for them to facilitate being
really good at
being rocket scientists right um which
meant using that computer as a tool so i
think it's really important to think
about what you can teach others and what
they can teach you
ultimately we want you to be the change
you wish to see
in the world right if you don't like
what you see
in terms of how it and security
are talking to people then be somebody
who doesn't talk that way and that's
certainly something
i came up through i t doing support and
system administration that was my
background before i started to do
security directly
and i have found that absolutely those
skills
empathy and the things any of the things
that i've learned in any customer
service role that i've had
have been invaluable for me in security
in part because i'm often doing some
translating uh of
it things to non-i t people or even to
i.t
people who don't necessarily grasp
some of the ins and outs of all of this
and now we should have plenty of time
for questions
i went a little faster through that than
i was
ultimately anticipating
yeah so uh first challenge is uh folks
are um only have access to
ask questions on discord discord yep
so now let's see what we've got going on
here
um posting for questions questions
for catherine
so um i i i really
there was a slide where you talked about
uh the responsibility of management and
as a former army officer
the thing that immediately went into my
head is like that's what leadership is
right like taking accountability
for your organization the people that
work there because i think all too often
we get into this blame the user culture
and to me i simplistically look at that
is
we're faulting them for using a computer
the way it was designed
yep agreed and yet we continue to do it
and we hear these anecdotal
stories of employees fired for failing
fishing tests
three times uh and
i see csos grab onto
phishing training metrics example of
progress
and they're like we went from 27 uh
people clicked to 22
people clicked and i'm like it's above
zero
wait going back to the bluetooth talk
any any access in
is it yes and it and it's backwards from
from the way that i think people should
think about those kinds of tests
too right so um i take a very strong
stance
on the subject of phishing when i
haven't when i have a department that
comes to me and says look we want to do
this
because we offer it but we don't
necessarily do it campus wide
i will explain to them the purpose of
this
is to get them better communicating uh
about what they're seeing
the purpose isn't to catch people like
that's not the goal
and i think that's really important so
even the language you use right so you
were just talking about
we went from you know 20 whatever 25
to 22 or whatever uh of people who
clicked
why are we not talking about the people
who didn't click and why aren't we
focusing on the message if we want to
change the behavior to a positive
behavior why are we focusing on the
negative message
additionally like the the people that do
click
and even if they are multiple clickers
those people are
some of your best assets for continual
training and training
the people around them not only at home
but in the work environment like hey
you should double check that email i got
caught doing this like that's going to
be a much better trainer from peers
additionally from a breach standpoint a
ciso that's went through a breach
or a team that's went through a breach
is one of your best assets that's
training and that's hands-on experience
that no one else can get or give so
those people are going to be much more
effective and efficient
have a much more uh broad understanding
of how to handle a breach properly and
the communication that's going to be
necessary from lessons learned
so you definitely don't want to fire
them you want to encourage that
yep absolutely because because if you
can get
somebody to to call out hey this is
weird looking
and then everybody else around them
hears hey this is weird looking hey
you should check you know hey don't
click on the thing you know hey this
thing just came
that is way more valuable than you know
well
so and so click the thing and now you
know we should punish them in some
capacity it should never ever be about
punishment it should be about
behavior change and moving in that
direction and
again negative behavior change um
is is only going to happen if you
continue to give a negative message
right
like that the two are are intimately
related
yeah that communication and really
understanding like us as security
practitioners and
infosec or even technical folks
we really have to understand and change
our mindset of
talking down to people bringing it down
to the level that's 100 percent not the
case we're not business people
our ability to speak at the level of
business speak
is limited to a certain capacity so
we're actually not speaking down to
someone and we have to change our
mindset
and say that we are taking it to their
language and really understand that
we're not above anybody and that
connotation of how we speak down to csos
or executives
really has to has to change otherwise
we'll never adapt we'll never get better
at speaking the business language
they'll never adapt and understand the
technical language that we're bringing
to them
until we're both treating each other as
equal and understanding
uh and trying to make that empathy jump
and make that understanding of
communication jump
yeah exactly and you know and and maybe
we need to understand a little bit more
about that the business language right i
mean that's something that i've had to
do over time
is is be able to speak in that way in
order to facilitate that communication
and what i think of in some ways is
translation and that's really what i
spend a lot of time doing
is in in the awareness role that i play
in my job
it really is just about saying here's
what you should understand
and here's a way for you to understand
it in language that makes sense to you
it doesn't need to have all the bells
and whistles and technical stuff
it needs to have the verbiage that you
can relate to and you can understand
and that that applies across the board
not only from communication but really
understanding the business and the
business functions and needs
the other day their business has to make
money and
allowing them to make business risk
decisions by appropriately
bringing them the information in the
language they can understand is how you
properly do your job that's your job as
an analyst that's your job as a security
practitioner is to bring it to their
language so they can make an informed
decision
for their business and that's something
that you have to learn to apply from not
only a vertical standpoint
uh you have to be able to talk in that
industry or in that particular sect and
at that level
but you have to understand their
business otherwise you're not going to
be able to provide them the information
in
in the means that is going to be
worthwhile
exactly i mean i can give a a formal
example of that
we um i i've had a couple of tickets
recently where
entities wanted to share data outside of
the university
which is fine like we do this all the
time but it was it was the type of data
where we have to be very careful on how
we set this up so instead of you know
either calling them up and saying no
which is what some people will simply do
um or calling up and saying well you
have to do it this way
the first thing i did was call them up
and say what's the goal
what are you trying to accomplish tell
me about the process
that that's involved here i want to
understand what you're trying to do
and then let's work together to figure
out how we
can most safely accomplish that and at
the end of the day
that's what we're doing we are educating
it's called being a good human being
right learning that empathy learning to
understand and communicate
at the end of the day we all just be a
little bit more compassionate a little
more empathetic
and really start to adapt ourselves and
be the best
us that brings a whole 100 percent to
the table where you can have multiple
hundred percent brought you're going to
have a much better
outcome long term in any business
absolutely
i would agree we do have some questions
first one up what training or courses do
you point cyber security people to help
them with communication and dealing with
management
that's a really good question um i can
tell you that
there are a couple of people that i
would look at um
but i don't know that i have particular
course stuff yet i can tell you that i'm
working on something myself
uh that once once it is formally out
there i will i will formally announce
but i i'll give the hint that something
is coming
um but uh it
they're really this is a tough tough
area there are certainly
there's certainly stuff out there for
communication like within businesses
and i think it's applicable but i think
it does take a little more hoop jumping
maybe to see the applicability
so unfortunately i don't have like
specific things i can
i can point people to at this time but
there's something coming
there's there's a ton of books out there
really any of the books on on
understanding business
business leadership i mean look at some
of jocko's books on the dichotomy of
leadership
uh any any of his stuff is is fantastic
of really understanding how teams and
dynamics work how to take responsibility
those all apply to the infosec and being
able to bring that
that kind of uh forward thinking and
forward leadership
to the table when you're talking with a
business or an executive i think that's
a great starting point
yeah i'd agree
okay what do people need to tabletop
first to help non-technical folks learn
about what to improve
i think with a tabletop it's having
those non-technical people at the table
like that's what we often don't do right
we we involve our technical people maybe
in our leadership but we don't involve
those folks um so i think it's
you know maybe take a scenario that's
already happened in your organization or
one that you see
frequently happening and take a step
back from the super high technical stuff
and think about how you want the
non-technical folks to respond to that
like what do you want them to do
and play that out with them get them
involved have
you know have have a scenario bring
one person from five different
departments who's not technical to the
table for the scenario
and see what they think like get their
feedback
see you know see what they would
normally do because
if what they normally would do is useful
and
um could contribute fantastic
if it's either a combination of things
you don't want them to do or just a
bunch of things you don't want them to
do
then obviously that's that's not ideal
and you want to spend some time
working within maybe within that
scenario to guide them in a direction
that you want them to go
so always being able to encourage
positive behavior in that way
is is can be useful
on that one so fast because i looked at
that i was like oh man i feel like i'm
setting her up because that's a that's a
tough question
it is a tough question but i i think
it's an area that um
you know we're just starting to do
insecurity ourselves right we're just
starting to really get serious about
tabletops
um you know the back doors and breaches
the stuff that that black hills has come
out with bryson you've done
you've done these uh choose your own
adventure scenarios right so all of
those kinds of things
are relatively recent um even though
table topping
in a general sense has been around a
really long time i've been in the fire
service for
you know a zillion years what it seems
like and and we have
they literally have table tops with
little cars and things where you can you
can do a scenario
like uh you have a chlorine spill and
the wind is blowing this way and what do
you do
right so that concept has been there a
really long time
um but we're kind of just getting used
to that
and because of that we're only i think
thinking about it
in our security bubble uh at that
top level and because it's so new but
that really is kind of the next step
is you know legal should be involved you
should have a couple of end users about
you really should have
ultimately have somebody from all these
different levels play the game with you
because in real life
they will so if if if you get a better
handle on what they're doing
everybody's better off and and people
like doing stuff like this
i mean my experience is it's a game for
them
even if even if it really is mimicking
like something bad that's happened in
the org already like
it gives them a chance to kind of think
about it not under that pressure
and eventually it's going to happen
again
yeah it also gives them a chance to kind
of shine and show areas
of creativity that they may not even be
related to their job function i mean
really getting people involved getting
the conversation open and then
bringing people and processes into the
whole thing yes there's a technology
aspect yes there's the
mitigations and and reaction but the
the processes and the people involved
and being able to provide some of that
benefit of walking through that
that's when you start to see huge
organizational changes that can
shift cultures and actually make a big
difference
agreed that's why i like the the bruce
schneier quote up front about
the the role in technology or
the over-reliance or confidence that we
have in it
and as a result shows how little we
actually understand it
um the the major criticism that i've
come up with for this industry is
we have a lot of nerds coming up with
nerd solutions to nerd problems
yep yep exactly and
that's just the technical component
which is
a fraction of the problem the surface
area and these things
and we see this manifest in so many
different ways
in the offensive side of the house i
think we are all too fond
of uh being very clever
i think we this is where i've been
giving my talk for a couple of years now
on how that's
conflated with ego uh starting to drive
it versus
still fitting with what the
organizational requirements are
um and and we're doing ourselves a
disservice
and we continue to complain that users
or management
or folks that are not directly within
what we do don't
understand what we're doing but it's
incumbent on us
to speak their language and talk to them
and that's why i love the table tops
that's why
i really liked um inspired by tim
malcolm vetter the choose your own
adventure that i pulled together
um and so many other folks that are
doing so many things and i'll also give
a credit out to uh
bruce potter uh for his work with his oh
noes
uh dungeons dragon style yeah game
um because those are
how we facilitate that conversation
because the end of the day it really
isn't about
the technical depth of it you don't need
to go down to ring zero to have a
conversation over
what would happen with a ring zero
attack on your enterprise
right right i don't even have to know
what ring zero is to be able to have
that conversation
and having a meaningful contribution and
buy-in
to what your organization is doing to
protect me
yep and there's so much in the news
right now too right like
people there was a time when when a lot
of what we did was totally hidden nobody
knew about any of this stuff because
you know the whole computing thing was
like under the table somehow
and now it's mainstream media i mean
for good or for ill right it's out there
so people have heard the words
and they've heard the way the media uses
them but they don't necessarily
use the you know they don't understand
the lingo necessarily right they
understand the media's interpretation of
it
um so i think that that plays a role too
and that really is our job is to take
what is technical and provide it in a
means that is actually
valuable to the business and i think we
need to be the buffer between the media
and a lot of our executives because that
is you know that is where they're having
to get their source and why are they
having to get that source
uh we should be as technology
professionals providing that
kind of buffer and translation for them
so that they can make a better informed
decision that's not coming from a mass
media or
you know misinformation disinformation
whatever you're going to call it
that's happening agreed absolutely
oh we can't hear you bryson
there you are here we go 2020 right like
the the virtual world
you got two different mute buttons your
microphone doesn't know which
is talking to what and yes can you hear
me now yes thank you
so uh catherine so great to see you
again and thank you so much for this
insight
i thought it was a really important
addition to the speaker track because i
think we do not
pay enough attention to the human side
of these problems
well i really appreciate being able to
be here and talk about this subject it's
something i could talk about all day
i will be on discord so for any
questions that didn't get answered i'm
happy to jump in
and spend some time there
nice happy grim cod thank you thanks