how's everybody doing
hey you're doing well thank you for
joining ah man this isn't
like this man segways are working out
nicely because
getting your concept across and hey look
our next presentation
i totally planned that uh is on
asking questions and writing effectively
christopher lopez i'll read your little
bio here
before we uh break it to you so uh
christopher lopez
bio says my name is christopher lopez
obviously i
no wait no that's that wait that way
that's christopher lopez i'm jeff
mcjugger
uh christopher lopez is a father first
and a sock analyst
second if i were to say sorry if
christopher were to say he had a
superpower
it would be the ability to ask questions
thank you alright be
able and willing to ask questions even
if they seem like silly
or stupid questions is in fact a
superpower i wish more people had and
used that superpower
uh this is what uh chris go by
christopher or chris i'm assuming
christopher whatever is easier
honestly but christopher feels our his
work his analysts mainly consist of
asking the best questions to drive our
analysis yes
questions are far more interesting than
answers i think i've been in infosec
field for a few years but a sock analyst
throughout uh chris came from i.t been
very fortunate to have great people
around to learn from oh my goodness
this theme of learning from other people
and sharing that learning
i am happy that uh this track is
emphasizing that through
and our speakers are as well chris
enjoys understanding how an analyst
investigates and jumps down rabbit holes
to learn how things work yes
sometimes rabbit holes are worth further
investigation because there
are answers out there this is why we
have lab environments
this is why we have forensic artifacts
and kind of the
ability to make good questions and
answer them uh that sometimes takes your
own
somewhat original research and that's
fine this is how we advance as a
community in advance as a field
so uh with that said uh unless uh wesley
do you have any uh last comments before
we
break away and give it to christopher no
i'm ready for it i'm ready for this
presentation
i'm excited about this one i'm excited
for this one so
uh christopher will drop off and let you
take it away just so you know
we have 30 minutes allocated for your
talk it does not mean you have to end at
45 after on the dot we have a little bit
of wiggle room for q
a and banter and i stole two minutes
from you
so christopher take it away and thank
you very much
all right perfect so we're going to
cover
asking questions and writing effectively
today as was already mentioned
this is one of my favorite topics um you
know i was very fortunate like i said in
my bio
to have people around to guide me
because i didn't understand anything
about
cyber security or info cycle and
whatever we want to call it
when i first started right so definitely
something i'm passionate to talk about
okay so this was also mentioned a little
bit uh i'm a father
that's kind of my most important role in
life
and i've been a stock analyst an
investigator for
you know all of my career with an
infosec and
all i do is ask questions uh if anyone
would know ask someone that knows me
personally they would say
that yeah uh chris talks a lot and he's
always asking questions about stuff
it just helps me understand things
better so
the agenda what are we going to talk
about uh we're going to talk about
questions there's going to be a lot of
that here we're going to talk about how
to ask questions why they matter
and how that works into the
investigative engine
and then we're going to pivot over to
write ups because this is how
you know value is derived from your
analysis as
an analyst right so it's really
important to be able to translate the
answers to your questions
in the most effective right as possible
for your leadership to make decisions
and of course this is all based on you
know the sock analyst perspective since
that's what i am
so just keep that in mind as we roll
through this
okay so here's the best part the tools
to be an awesome investigator
you don't need that much uh you need
your mind right
your questions that's in bold for a
reason we're gonna keep going through
that
um your biases uh very interesting just
the way that you think about things is
really important to keep that in mind
and be aware of them
your perspective and your experiences it
doesn't have to be an infosec related
experience it can be
you know you learn how to ride a bike i
don't know you can bring that in to be
an awesome investigator
so another thing is somewhere to take
notes right i still use
uh paper and pencil i don't know it just
feels good
instead of typing all day like i usually
do but of course any text editor uh
you know would help you uh a loosely
defined process the reason i emphasize
lucy defined is because i feel that
investigations
really benefit from the creative minds
of analysts
and having a very structured process to
investigate can stifle that creativity
that can come out of an investigation so
just have like
you know a guideline that you follow as
you're investigating
and of course your team members uh lean
on them
that's super important there's always
something to learn from everyone that
you meet
especially people that are investigating
things are in the same team as you
so just lean on them and that will help
you become a better investigator as well
this is the engine that we're gonna
focus on right this is the investigation
engine at least from my perspective this
is how
investigations usually work you have
your questions
and with your questions that you ask
yourself based on an input
right an alert for example uh you
collect artifacts to answer those
questions right that can be logs
that can be no is usually is logs that's
what we
primarily deal with uh rabbit holes come
in
the reason i put them here is because
they can be one of the most enjoyable
experiences that you have during
investigation
but they can also really take away a lot
of your time i spent a lot of time in
raga holes trying to understand things
but they're part of the engine of
investigating compiling your findings
right so after you've analyzed your logs
and you've you know reached out to users
if you need to and you've
spoken to your team members you compile
your findings and then you form a
conclusion
right you try to answer the question
that we are all trying to answer is this
bad you know is this a
true positive is this a false positive
and then you document right
documentation
is super important it's how everyone
learns from each other and it's how you
track
you know what you're doing and uh if if
there was anything that i would say to
take away from this is that
documentation is key to making sure that
everyone keeps getting better as an
analyst
so what does that look like uh the
beauty here is that
this is not recreating the wheel this is
not something new
we've been taught this since elementary
school we are applying the scientific
method to understand how an
investigation works
in order to answer the question that we
need to answer right
which is is this a bad thing that
happened for example and your leadership
may need to understand that to make
decisions that
would protect your company or whoever it
is you're working for
so of course there's an observation
that's your input
that is your alert for example or a
email that's sent to your shared mailbox
from users that
want to contact you about strange
activity and you have your questions
right your then you form a hypothesis
what you think is going to happen
you experiment in this case you pull
logs right or
you figure out some way of getting more
evidence uh you analyze that evidence
and you form a conclusion
it's all the same thing uh and it makes
me really comfortable to know that
you know it aligns with what we've been
taught since elementary school makes it
easier to keep it in mind
these are our questions this is what
we're going to focus on this is the the
meat and potatoes of the conversation
here
uh the what the why when where who and
how
so let's just jump into these questions
the what
i consider this to be the input this is
i've said it a few times this is a
sim detection right this is an alert or
this can be a threat hunt idea
right uh there's been a lot of you know
breaches recently that we all
are aware of uh there may be some really
interesting artifacts within some of
these reports that may
lead to a threat hunt idea to find
evidence of that in your environment
right i mentioned that here
and of course there's always the input
of a new organizational process
many of us are going through this or
have already gone through this
you know with our companies moving to
the cloud you know what does that look
like
should i learn more about this and how
do i use that to create an investigation
around like
what logs do i even have in the first
place to have visibility into this
environment
um this is your input this is where
everything starts from
in the case of this presentation we're
going to focus on
detections and alerts being your input
this is something really important this
took me a very long time to learn
so i'd like to have this right after i
talk about
you know the questions and that is
always question the alert first
this i spend so much time going down
rabbit holes which are fun
of course but they can be very time
consuming trying to understand why this
happened like this alert saying that
this fired or this bad thing happened on
this machine
and it looks super bad especially since
you know i was new and i didn't
understand the context of a lot of
things i was looking at
and i failed to ask this simple question
of
hey does this alert make sense does this
uh
is it actually finding what it was
intended to find
is there documentation which there
should be if you're creating detections
right someone should know who created
this detection so you can reach out to
them you know
or they're not in the company anymore
but at least you have some context
around the thought process of a
detection you need to understand
why this alerted in the first place and
that can help you throughout the context
of an investigation and it can also stop
an investigation
before it even happens by saying this
doesn't make any sense
this did not find what it was intended
to find this is a false positive
and this requires some tuning because at
the end of the day as stock analysts
we're all trying to improve our
investigative practice right we're all
trying to
get better and more effective at
investigating and answering these
questions quickly
so tuning is part of that process so
just always remember
ask that question does this alert even
make sense
the why this is your hypothesis this is
where
you look at an alert and you're like you
know what this looks to me
like a false positive now without
evidence there's no way of actually
answering that question
but it's good to have some idea to drive
your investigation this is really
important
and this is something that i tend to
still write down
somewhere i mean if i'm typing in a
ticketing system for example
i'll write down what i think you know um
just to keep that in mind
and this leads to the questions that you
continue to ask yourself to find answers
right an example
of these would be let's say that it's
related to an av detection antivirus
detection
this detective file does not appear
malicious that would be like a
hypothesis right that would be what i
think about this this is not
this looks benign this looks like
someone downloading something that
just looks to be malicious but it's not
or
the phishing email that we received an
alert about was not clicked
they received it but it wasn't clicked
and then i go
right and you build your hypothesis
based on these three things that i think
really help you create a really good
hypothesis
um and leslie said it perfectly in the
wild west hacking fest this year and i
had to put it in here
uh build your hypothesis based on these
three things is it falsifiable
is it testable and understand the scope
of your hypothesis right is it limited
to one machine
is it you know throughout your whole
environment can you even
pull evidence or logs to test this
hypothesis
right and it's better to prove yourself
wrong it's it's really interesting if
you go through the process of that
i believe that this malicious
potentially malicious executable did not
execute
right it did not actually do what it was
intended to do
on this machine well i'm gonna go look
for logs that
try to prove that it did execute and
that helps me
you know prove to see if something is
falsifiable this builds out
the hypothesis which is incredibly
important to drive everything
and this is an example i talked about
you know the av thing that happens a lot
uh antivirus
you know catches things and um you know
this is an example alert from june
let's say uh i know we're a little bit
past that but that's okay
uh so it detected a potentially
malicious file in a user directory
in my hypothesis i did not execute so
now i'm going to go back and i'm going
to try to find anything that i could
to prove that it did the when
okay so here goes the story so i started
in a sock and i didn't understand how to
do investigations very well
so i would write down questions that i
should ask myself on a piece of paper
um in order to help me like really
understand you know the daunting process
i feel a lot of people feel
when they're starting out in infosec
there's always so much going on
and one of the things that i failed to
understand very early on
was when you work for a global company
and there's end points that you're
receiving logs from
different regions of the world is to
understand the importance of time stamps
um so an example would be i was trying
to investigate a malicious
file there's always there's always that
happening i guess
and um it was on a machine
that was in asia all right that's that's
not the u.s so
it's a completely different time zone
and i was looking for
logs within the sim
that were set to eastern time right i'm
in eastern time and it was set to
eastern time but there were logs that i
had to pull from the machine itself
right and access and you know be able to
analyze
that or from the machine but the
machine's time
is different than the time that i'm
looking at within the sim and that's
something that i didn't
really consider and i ended up looking
hours
away from you know where it was that i
should be looking for that evidence that
i was trying to find to answer the
question of
this did this file actually execute
and the problem with that was i was
wrong so those things happen you make
mistakes right and luckily i had a team
member tell me hey did you
make sure to go back to the right time
on this machine because
the sim is set to eastern time and this
is not eastern time that you're looking
at these logs
so they could be off and that was very
helpful because then i found the
evidence that i needed to prove that
this malicious file did execute now if i
didn't have that i would have been wrong
and that would be not the best way of
ending an investigation
but you learned something from this and
that's why it's super important
to ask yourself the when when did this
take place
right and to if you can set everything
to utc because it just makes sense and
it makes your life easier
and last but not least understand time
conversions if you have to
uh that's something that you know i'll
go to google and
figure out like what time zone something
is and just do the math and just to make
sure that you're on the right
track on the right page the where now
the where is interesting because this
could be
answered with the one right for example
that asset
was in asia right but it's also really
interesting to understand the where
through the context of a user
because this allows you to understand
whether or not
this user is traveling if this is a
laptop if this is a server
that gives you more context as to if
this is a machine based investigation
right
it gives you more context as to like
what the context of this
investigation contains so is this a
server that would tell me something very
different
than if this was a laptop for example
because
there may be a certain amount of uh you
know standards that you
have towards servers that would help you
answer questions as to is this
malicious or is this just something that
we've seen in our environment before
that
just looks malicious to this you know
security
appliance that decided to make it you
know an alert
so aware is really interesting
especially with asset management and
it's a good question to ask
yourself who
all right so we're going to get into a
little bit of attribution here
there's been a lot of talk about threat
intelligence and the power of it and i
i i think it's incredible um but
understanding
the who around an investigation is
really important
and i want to really spend a moment here
to talk about
the abstraction of a user account this
was hard for me to really
you know wrap my head around so just
because
you have a detection that lists a user
account that may have done something
suspicious
it's always really important to
understand that it doesn't mean that it
was really that user that did that
you know user accounts can be
compromised so it's really important to
understand the who
behind something and to be aware of the
abstraction level whenever it is you're
dealing with a user
related uh investigation right
so uh an example would be uh you know
knowing when to reach out to a user
about a specific
investigation right trying to really
understand
who cause you know trying to understand
if this is an outsider or an insider
type threat that you're dealing with
um and it can even be your co-worker um
what i mean by that is
it can be something where you know one
of your
fellow stock analysts was downloading
something because they wanted to
understand something for their
investigation
and we're going to keep going on the
antivirus thing because it happened so
much
antivirus captured a file it doesn't
mean that your
you know team member their account was
compromised and something malicious was
executed on their machine
but what it does mean is that you should
understand the context of the user
account itself
um so this is something that's really
important throughout an investigation
understanding the who how
this is to me one of the most
enjoyable parts of investigation this is
where i spend most of my time
and it's only because there's this
innate
curiosity that i've had and i think it's
helped me
propel my career um you know within
infosec
is that i just want to understand how
things work uh and that is
this is such a great field to have that
like innate
question that you're always asking
yourself like why did this happen and
how does this work
right so this is where you start asking
yourself the question of how did this
get here
and i want to spend a moment talking
about that question because it's so
important
and that is okay so we're going to keep
with the antivirus thing
uh antivirus captures this file
all right it is quarantined and there's
no threat
right so it's really easy to dismiss
that
it's really easy to say okay well
there's no threat so it's gone
but the question that should come up is
how did this get here in the first place
why did this get here right like how is
this possible to have
been detected like how many layers of
security
controls do we have in place that should
have prevented this like a proxy
or whatever that did not
catch this but it's still here and also
how did we detect this was this a user
that reached out to us and said hey my
machine's acting a little bit weird and
sent us a screenshot
and it looks like something's happening
on their machine or was this
a detection that we have created as a
team
based on some behavioral logic that
we've
learned about that's really important
because the goal
of an effective sock as was mentioned
before is to be more effective to keep
building better detections better rules
and to better protect you know the
organization that you're working for
so how do we detect this is a very
important question to ask because if
this was
a user related you know uh inquiry or
something that they reached out to us
maybe there's
the opportunity of creating a rule
around the behavior of this
event so that's just something to keep
in mind and how does this work
that's where i spend most my time like
how does this file work
why does it do this thing and what else
can i learn from it right so that's why
we have sandboxes that's why we have vms
that's why
you know we like to detonate malware you
know in a safe environment to see what
it does because you can also
really derive some great detections
around that type of behavior
and that again goes through the cycle of
improving your suck
the last question with the how is how
impactful is this
right so we haven't talked about the
whole ir
um you know invoking ir and really going
through the process of escalating
an incident uh you know to up the ranks
depending on you know what level it is
that you're on
you know in your in your team but it's
really important to ask this question
even throughout
even throughout your hypothesis creation
is how impactful is this is this enough
to
you know invoke ir is this enough to uh
reach out
let my manager know right like whatever
process you have in place with your
policy
uh you know for an investigation or for
these types of events
it's really important to ask yourself
often like how impactful is this
event okay
so now you spend all this time
answering these questions and writing
this
up in a really rough draft form right or
some ticketing system and now you're
you're ready for the write-up
and uh i just want to stress this a few
times you're going to hear it
probably more than once here and analyst
efforts
is reflected to their documentation and
that's super important
because i've been a victim of this
myself in a way
where yeah i just spend the entire day
investigating this but i
don't know how to communicate this
in the way that the audience is
receptive to it
so yeah i can write something super
technical and say hey this is really
cool the way that this worked
and wow like it did this thing and you
know us analysts are
interesting where we get really excited
when something bad's happening
which is just part of the job because
it's interesting i guess
um it's hard to really communicate
that sometimes in a write-up so this is
just some
uh some things that i've learned from
really
bad write-ups that i've done you know in
my career so far
so some things to keep in mind uh talk
about what actions you took
right the reason this is so important is
because oh i would love to read
someone's write-up and be able to
replicate their actions
right what did you pull where did where
did you pull this log
source from like what did you search in
the sim
to find this evidence to prove this
thing that you're
saying uh i think that's really
important for not only
you know the management to understand
your thought process but also to train
others
um and to help others understand your
investigation
and when did you take these actions so
this is a secondary timestamp right so
not only the timestamps of the events
that may have taken place on the machine
but also when did you pull this log like
create a timeline of the events that you
you know
went through throughout the course of
your investigation right i
reached out to this user at this time
via email
and you have like you know basically you
have the evidence of that
in your inbox or your sent box whatever
um
you know what answers did you obtain
right so
what questions did you ask yourself you
don't have to put the questions
in in the write-up but what did you
learn from this
and of course is escalation required
right did you
find this to be something where you've
already escalated it and it's just
really important to keep that
somewhere in the right of probably
mostly on top that
you did reach out to someone and this
was already escalated and this is the
bottom line right
so what is your conclusion this is
really important
right this is all providing facts this
is all not
necessarily your opinion on this thing
right your leadership
and those that need to make decisions
based on your analysis
uh want to hear what your conclusion is
they don't want to hear the facts and
one of the things that was really hard
for me to understand early on was
sometimes you need to be very honest
about
not knowing you know what happened
let's say that for example you try to
investigate an event and you realize
that you did not have
the visibility into that specific
log that would have told you if this was
a false positive
or a true positive well that's
definitely a huge takeaway
from the investigation and hopefully
there's a way that
you can you know inject that information
into
your visibility improvement process you
know as a sock
so that's just something to keep in mind
as you're creating a conclusion
and this was really hard for me to learn
and that's the bluff
uh i write a lot i talk a lot and i get
really excited about things like this
so it's really important to put a bluff
a bottom line up front
at the very top of your write-up to let
your management know since
you know understanding the audience is
important people are busy
right people are doing things understand
really quickly
uh in a few minutes if that why
they're even receiving this write-up in
the first place why it matters
and of course provide some contextual
data time stamps really important
uh user endpoint information right so
let's say you have a user account
associated it is that user
you know what is their job title you
know that may
uh be very interesting for your
leadership what if it's a vip user for
example
uh what if it's a server and any like
related ocean data that you find is
always really helpful to
you know add more to your investigation
okay so the bottom line up front the
bluff here right
um summarize all the key information
put it all into one paragraph all the
way at the top
and i try to remind myself of the three
c's and that is
to be concise clear and correct be
try to use active voice try not to
passively say things
and be very clear about the information
and your conclusion about something and
just make sure you're correct right
make sure that you know you didn't
accidentally see say this is a false
positive just because you
you mistake the you know true and false
word just be very correct
honestly uh i've had to send my reports
or my write-ups to my fellow analysts
and i'm like hey can you read this
really quickly to make sure that you
know it's right
or it sounds good before i send this out
that's also really helpful
again that goes back to leaning you know
on your peers
because you want to make sure that these
three these three c's
are checked in order to make your bluff
statement incredibly
impactful for the writer oh
lastly write up importance
your write-up can invoke change in a
process right that's really important to
understand what if your investigation
led to the discovery of a visibility gap
for example
right and your management or your
leadership team whomever
they want to reference your
documentation your write-up in order to
invoke this change in order to make a
change in the organization can they just
forward your write-up right is it ready
did you write it with that expectation
or do they have to come back and reach
out to you and ask you for like a
summary of your write-up
um those are never fun i've had to do it
before because again
you know this is all a learning
experience um but just
try to write your write-ups with that
expectation that it may be
used as reference material right another
one here
i said this before can someone replicate
the actions you took can you train
someone
based on this investigation that you
wrote up can you give them this
documentation and ask them hey
um you know see if you can pull these
logs these these
things from this machine like does that
make sense to you and of course
um something else to keep in mind did
this investigation lead to a potential
improvement in detection that's
the whole point right is to continue to
improve our detections
as analysts to make you know our jobs
easier and to protect our companies
so of course would senior leadership be
able to use this write-up to address any
concerns
can be forwarded up that's just a
reminder here and a last question ask
yourself here
did you document your findings or no
conclusions in some kind of a wiki i
don't know what
people have out there whatever onenote
i'm not sure
but somewhere that it can be easily
referenced it can be searchable so that
everyone can learn from this process
it's something to keep in mind while
you're doing these write-ups
okay so now we're at summary
questions drive and investigation uh
they're key they're
you know the questions the quality of
the questions that you ask yourself
um determines the quality of your
investigation just something
really important build an effective
hypothesis
or remember those three terms that i
used earlier um just
make sure that you spend a little bit of
time trying to think about what your
thoughts are initially about this
investigation it really helps drive
everything
so answer to your question form the
foundation of a write-up
it doesn't mean that it is the write-up
it's the foundation and you build off of
that
an analyst reflects their efforts
through write-ups uh
i i love to read that because it's so
true
the what leadership sees is your
write-ups they don't see the amount of
hours you spent
looking at logs unless you're sharing
your screen and showing them something
which is always cool
always include a bluff statement people
are busy you don't want to bore anybody
either
make sure that the information that they
need is right up front and ready to go
and i'll leave it with just keep asking
questions
it's helped me throughout my career and
it continues to help me
and it's just super important for us as
analysts in the field
and these are some resources um so
i learned a lot from chris sanders
investigation theory course
it's one of the best courses i've ever
taken i mean chris sanders is amazing
and it really helps to understand how
investigations work there's some writing
tips by lenny
um i mean this is perfect uh
a lot of this stuff about like being
more clear and concise comes from that
generating hypothesis robert m lee right
for
thread hunting which is something that
we do all the time as analysts
and one of the most impactful books that
i've read uh is thinking fast and
slow because it really helps you
understand your biases which we didn't
really cover here in this presentation
but like confirmation bias for example
and false positive bias that happens to
a lot of analysts after
being bombarded by so many bad
detections
uh arguably bad detections um and of
course
communicating with intelligence this was
a book that i read because of a class
that i took
and i was blown away by how
amazing it was to help with like my
writing skills so that's another book
there that i think is really good
to share and that's it that's all i have
and of course i mean i want to say thank
you to everybody uh
grim everybody i mean this these
conversations are awesome so
i really appreciate it that was amazing
thank you
christopher uh uh that was great uh i'm
trying to look through uh for some of
the q a in there
um somebody it was me since you
mentioned uh the utc is like
just set everything to utc uh there's a
teespring shirt and
like uh stickers and such for utc or
gtfo
which is one of my favorite uh sock
analysts and forensicator phrases that
i've heard a few times right
yes there's there's one correct location
to set your servers
network switches etc you can make a
strong argument for user machines as
well
just standardize everything to utc time
zone conversions is
so much a pain like oh i'm investigating
now
but when i when the event happened it
was still daylight savings so let me
modify for three hours for the location
difference in another hour for the time
zone difference
oh but wait i'm in a county that doesn't
do time zones so it's only three hours
or wait no it's five hour
just utc everywhere that's one tip that
by itself justifies
your talk and there was a lot more all
the way through as well let's see
um uh i did want to oh emphasize uh your
little nugget so i
i usually writing like pen test reports
different focus but the same idea of
conveying
a message to the the reader or different
readers at different levels
and i loved the nugget you said a
competent reader of the report should be
able to follow along
the steps that you actually used yes
not just anyone outside of it but
somewhat someone somewhat familiar with
another sock analyst or junior stock
analyst or
probably even the manager of the sock
itself should be able to follow along
and go through the same steps and with
the same questions because you
identified them in your report
should come to the same conclusion
otherwise there's some
logical fallacy going on or some bias on
your own side so
i love that in other words every report
could also
be training material for others because
there is not enough time in this world
for everyone to
find the answers themselves this is why
we share
which may be a recurring theme after
every little little banter
that i keep bringing up um so
first of all thank you the great talk i
love the the background on i love the
little nuggets about like
we didn't have time for biases but it
turns out they're pretty important
i completely agree on all parts um one
question for you
and this one's always tougher and i
admit some personal interest here as
well
seeing good incident reports is a
valuable thing
a lot of them are you know constrained
to the organization for very obvious
reasons
are you aware of any public either good
examples
or bad examples of incident reports that
you
would point at and say this is an
available resource
that's tough um because
i would have to think about that um one
of the ways that
that one one of the things that helped
me out very much
was uh the chris sanders um
class that he gave and also
the book that i referenced there that
for the class that i took
that was one of the best ways of like
writing it does it wasn't really
well it's more about like national
security and all that stuff right
but it's super it was super helpful to
understand like
your audience and like why you're
writing this in the first place
um that was the most helpful thing for
me but i would have to look to see like
examples that i can share for that okay
if you're in discord we'd love to have
you share it uh it's
anytime that you you can um
commentary uh online shout out to ghost
nice presentation i've had to learn to
ask questions no matter what
in the past i felt i might look stupid
and finally realized
i don't and shouldn't care knowledge and
learning is what is important
i completely agree there i want to add
something to that
that was really hard for me to
understand too so you know i did not
have any
experience coming into infosec right i i
knew about
i.t but i wasn't assist admin so i
wasn't even really that much
in i.t right i was breaking fixed i.t
and you know i was so worried about
asking questions when i first started
because i didn't want to look dumb
right no one wants to look dumb right um
and what i realized
over time is that if you have a question
and it's a big enough group
you're probably not the only one that's
wondering that
there's just more than one person that
doesn't want to look dumb
so if anything just go out there and ask
that question because you may end up
helping not only yourself but someone
else
you know so that's the way i kind of
took it yes yes
um uh which branch do you serve in by
the way
what beard bottom line up front so
military no no nothing
oh right i would have bet money i would
have had money in the military
on that okay no no um that so
that's really funny you bring that up um
because
when i first started in a sock it was
primarily
uh you know people that were from the
military in my team
so that's probably where all this came
from i i learned a lot from them
so there you go i just reflect that
okay
i pretty much i started with the coast
guard and everything
uh so yeah it's that's why i learned a
lot of that stuff like i said my
military was me by me
i asked many questions but yeah
but no oh my god i have so much to say
about this um
you know i love it because this is
something that i i
work in and i try to teach you know um
not really just investigates there but
even asking questions and you know
people who wanted to
learn i guess more reports now this is
more from my throat intel side
i know unit 42 puts out like post threat
reports i think those are really good
like
threat intel reports um i'll put the
i'll post a link up as well
um man the biases i know i took a uh
i think i took a threat intel training
course right it was it was funny
it was funny i liked it it was great but
you know bringing out those biases was
very
key and critical um especially when we
were uh we were talking about like hey
you know do you have biases
no not really and then put up some
controversial just pictures
it wasn't like not safe for work stuff
it was just controversial like what do
you think you know what do you
what is your opinion you know and things
like that so it really does
it really helps and um there's a there's
a huge
there's a huge thing you like you say
chris santa's probably one person i
probably follow
who really has a lot of this stuff
almost down to a t uh yeah they've seen
some other studies when you know even
writing he was talking about like hey
you know any word over like eight
characters is like too long
make it simpler if it's over eight eight
ten k it was it was so
deep in in detail in depth and putting
those reports
on fancy word where simple one will do
jargon is useful if both sides
understand the same
term for the same meaning outside of
that audience which is a really common
situation
avoid jargon damn it yes because you'll
just confuse the audience or worse yet
they'll walk with a different
understanding because they have a
different understanding of that word
jargon is one of the one of the most
difficult things for me to learn about
writing more concisely which is so
difficult
um was i like using a lot of the ly
words
beautifully right things like that like
just to make it
sound nicer because i want it to be
pretty
and it ends up being super wasteful and
no one
wants to read that and it was so hard to
understand that you have to be very
selective with your word choices because
people don't have time to sit there and
like read something pretty
they want to read like the fact yep i i
actually got
a client brought it no no uh
another ciso and uh other uh pentest
head person uh brought up that i i was
using
like unfortunately fortunately things
like to just to chain together sentences
and
you're mixing your opinion and that
flowery language with
what it should be fairly objective given
my background given my understanding
this is the situation
yes and it's not just that it takes more
words
it's that to some audiences you are
diluting your message
because you're freely trading back and
forth between this is my casual opinion
on things and
this is the fact yes
so and the goal actually hurting your
portrayal of reality sometimes by some
of that flowery language
it's okay for things to feel rather
blunt all the way through
uh your report is not to uh
you know swaddle the reader all the way
through from beginning to end
it is to lay out a
a story if you will yes but here's the
situation
here's what i understood the initial
alert to mean here are the follow-up
questions that it brought to me
and here's the resolution conclusion and
by the way start off with your uh bottom
line up front your tldr
for the commercial world um and also
like
and also carry out that you know like
you said chris it's hard to kind of
write besides i've just shared some
links
some things that i use in my job word
word rake
is very i love it because it takes those
really what it does it takes a sentence
that really worthy and things like that
like hey cut this out cut this out you
can still say the same thing
without doing it something i truly
invest in in any report i write
i highly suggest it's like 120 bucks you
get 150 for like the
word and uh offers you something i use
daily because
it's written for more lawyers per se and
so lawyers have to kind of use certain
language but
it takes all the other extra words it's
not needed and it makes it really
concise
another application i use hemingway
editor
um it it definitely helps you with uh um
yeah hemingway's editor it helps you out
with uh active voice
that that it put everything as a more an
active voice also another thing is
perfected
um that i use this is more like make
sure your content is really
uh uniform you know it is it's
you know you use ad hoc with the dash in
the middle or do you just use ad hoc the
word you know it helps with those little
things these little nitpicky points out
so
these are something that i love sharing
i love making sure that people
understand like these tools are out here
um to help you
write effectively use the tools that's
out there to really just narrow things
down
and uh to really just make your writing
clear concise and to the point um
warwick is probably the number one thing
i use and then perfected is probably the
second one
so definitely something to look
i just want to echo like one last thing
here um
the reason that this is so important is
again like this is where values derived
from your analysis
like this is all at the end of the day
this is what people see
um and i failed to see that for so long
and i'll never forget
this one report that i wrote i spent i
don't know
the whole day writing this report i
could have sworn it was the best thing
i've ever written since college or
whatever
right and i sent it to my my you know my
lead my new analyst at the time
and you know they they wrote back in a
very kind manner it wasn't that they
were being mean but they were like why
did you write this
right and i'm like what do you mean
right and that's when i fail to
understand the audience
very quickly and then they're like i'm
gonna send you back like
um my thoughts on it and all i received
was
the entire thing was basically
highlighted and like how
passive voice was used here like why are
you giving me your opinion here
like why is this and that's when i
realized man this is a craft
this is something that i really gotta
get better at i was writing like
something like i was writing in my
journal or something i thought it was
great
and uh the reality is it takes time
uh to really get that ironed out it
really does
it's not dear diary today i investigated
an antivirus alert
hey others because this report will
stand forever
regardless of my human context i will
not be able to explain this report to
you
these words need to stand on their own
so dear future readers at this date this
started a bit of an incident
and here's the thought process of the
analyst at the time
what data supported what conclusion
given the questions that came up along
the process
yes yes definitely what more thinks it
is
and i'll let it go i'll let this one go
but no
um also in a word when you're writing
your uh
documents and work make sure you turn on
all these spell check features obviously
there's only a subset on by default
and honestly a lot of people are going
to check and
word has a lot of good grammar check um
since you mentioned word rake a lot of
people use grammarly and i had to double
check word rake and just my my ten
seconds not
good review of their privacy policy
means they they don't actually look at
the content it's local rules that are
applied
grammarly is not that way that is a
concern to many folk
that every text you analyze with word or
powerpoint or
web browser integration you're sending
that text to grammarly
that's probably not okay word break on
my 15 second review does not do that
but be careful when you're installing
other people's software that has
access to this information because it
has access to this information it's
probably not meant to be publicly shared
right and so like i mean definitely use
word
is something yeah i i personally vouch
um for people who don't who want a
grammarly style thing
what i found to use i use it a little
bit uh white smoke
is pretty much the same as gremlin um i
believe they don't
if i read it correctly i believe they
don't you know you don't send your
information to
uh white smoke they're like i said
they're pretty much the same thing as
family
uh and as far as like uh grammar content
and everything but
you know getting your writing together
definitely utilize
the tools out here it's one of the best
investments i make when writing anything
from email to report to anything that
goes
beyond me or maybe a colleague that
maybe a colleague of mine i run it
through word rate first
uh perfected next to make sure
everything's uniform and i'm taking out
all the extra wording
in there and those i can't highly
recommend those two
products that's fair point okay i have
another thing to look for as well
so i hope you're i believe you're
providing uh value to the audience but
you're providing value to me and that's
good enough to start off with so i'm
happy with that
so uh christopher i need to introduce
our next section any
last comment before we switch over no um
keep asking questions regardless of how
dumb they might
seem in your mind just keep asking them
that's how you get better
yep i i rephrased slightly in a discord
post and said uh
i'd rather appear like a fool for a
moment and ask
a stupid question then actually be a
fool on that subject forever because i
didn't ask that question
definitely perfect yep thank you very
much lopez