oh
uh don't make fun of people for what
they don't know all right
everything that everybody knows by the
time they're adults it means that
there's 10 000 people in the us hearing
about it for the first time
every day right just do the math if you
go from never knowing about it to
100 i've heard about it by 30 out of 4
million people
born per year it's a 10 000 people who
haven't heard of that
thing and of course as you get more and
more particular about uh
dn spy any dot run was an offhand
mention but a
really powerful thing what is that right
i love it
hand it malware it'll tell you what it
does in their sandbox environment
so let's hunt okay register
upload malware receive report of what it
does
all right there's you can do more in
your own sock and have your own custom
environment
but to get started takes registering
with an email address that's not bad so
the example in xkcd is like
what do you mean diet coke and mentos
and many people here have heard it like
oh yeah
diet coke and minnows you put them
together it explodes it's awesome
don't make fun of people for things they
don't know be
happy to share the thing that is awesome
right
come on we're going to the grocery store
you're one of today's lucky 10 000
and there's going to be some happy safe
explosions in their future
or so i hope all right so i want to have
a little bit more
positive uplifting message there so uh
thank you
uh stephen for that last talk um any
last
bit before we introduce ah wesley wesley
is here
wesley do you want to unmute and uh
webcam yourself
wait sorry i said wesley i thought i was
talking to matthew
i just went i derped sorry uh we do have
one spinel here as well let me uh
yep that's the live next talk on
gdpr and strategies for failure
i'm gonna assume there's like
counterparts that are at least heavily
implied of strategies for not failure
there as well but that seems pretty
likely
uh and there we are juan thank you for
for joining thank you for presentation
ah all right so
uh one i'll give you your bio real quick
before we get you started
after working as a sys admin in
hospitality ah sysadmin background i
i am completely biased but i think it's
such a great background for so many
fields within it
at a time where data protection laws
were crappy but growing around the world
i i added the crappy part
one has been trying to help other it
folks avoid the headaches involved in
analyzing basic compliance requirements
a lot of people hear the word compliance
and just run away or think
i'm not really responsible for that so
i'm never going to learn anything about
it and just ignore it entirely
um that's at least my bias take uh two
years after gdpr went live we've seen
some unforeseen consequences as to how
europeans communicate with the other
side of the pond
where the other side of the pond hi
american here
uh are you on the other other side of
the pond are you on the
european side yourself one i am on the
other side of the pond
where are you based out of curiosity i
don't think it said it here uh
switzerland
switzerland nice that's awesome um okay
so two years after gpr went live
unforeseen consequence was how europeans
communicate with the other side of the
bond hey
other stuff uh while cves and remote
shells are all the hype in the infosec
community
the fines involved with bad data
protection strategies
hey uh what's that headline what's the
maximum fine for gdpr
violations so it's uh four percent of
annual turnover
which uh of course this is not just uh a
one-time fine this is for every
uh breach encountered so you're saying
what
i usually hear at phrases four percent
up of global
revenue not profit oh my goodness that's
a headline like there's
teeth to this compliance it has a chance
it gets you to sit up and pay attention
because it can have some serious
consequences
which is beyond what many compliance
frameworks have in place
uh the fines involved bad data
protection strategies are the tools that
can a company beyond repair
that gets the executives to set up and
pay attention as it should
according to mackenzie juan can provide
the first gdpr talk i made it to the end
without dying 13 times
that is one hell of an endorsement was
dave mckenzie your
mentor for this on this side or
uh no so dave mckenzie was doing
mentoring for the uh beer con
ii okay excellent
all right um i will give you the powers
of presenter mode
poof you are now prompted to share your
screen
uh whenever you are ready unless there's
a little bit of banter you want to do
ahead of time
uh we're exactly on time for you
starting as well which works out well
so you have your full 30 minutes
allocated plus we have 15 minutes of
wiggle room for q a so do not
panic if you're at the last minute you
don't have to rush
anything else before you go
yeah i just want to make sure you guys
can see the screen yep yep
2020 bingo applied we can see your
screen
all right all right let me just minimize
the window
and yeah we're seeing the right one as
well so
nice backdrop okay yep
best of luck thank you very much all
right
um hello my name is juan and today i'm
going to be talking to you today
about gdpr and strategies in compliance
or rather some strategies for failure
now gdpr came around in 2018
it's a set of laws that define how
companies need to protect consumer data
as well as defining what they are
allowed to do or what they're not
allowed to do and with which
restrictions
it has had some unprocessing
consequences everyone remembers all the
this website uses cookies banner that
popped up
not sure to what extent that happened in
the u.s
in europe we're also seeing lots of
websites suddenly saying
this content is banned or not available
to you because
gdpr
so as i mentioned gdpr is a
text of law and the main issue of this
is that of course the people
implementing the controls for how the
data moves
are technical people but because it's a
text of law it's
open to interpretation at some points
most
specifically gdpr constantly mentions
the use of
state-of-the-art infrastructure when
talking about uh
security so aside people would take that
as saying okay
you just need to buy more blinky boxes
and then you're fine
of course we'll know that doesn't
provide any additional security
and these are some elements which make
it difficult to see eye to eye
between the people applying the law and
the people
trying to keep the companies afloat
gdpr as i mentioned protects citizens of
the european union
visitors to the european union and
companies who wish to target these
demographics
as key markets
need to be compliant with this that
means your local
corner store does not have to be gdpr
compliance
if on the other hand you are a big chain
of hotels trying to get european
tourists
you do need to make sure about this
compliance
i do come from the services industry
which means i'm not focusing here
on data portability uh
you wouldn't go to a restaurant to
request your data
so you can go down to the rest
restaurant closer to yours
and have them take it
from the services industry perspective i
think these are the rights which are
most critical to ensure that you're
respecting
the right to be forgotten this means
that
your clients can come and say i don't
want my name to be
associated here anymore the data needs
to be either
deleted or anonymized there is the
caveat that all financial transactions
are immutable because
money laundering tax evasion
but these records can't be processed or
accessed aside from
those purposes
the right of correction if for any
reason you need to change
your name email address phone number how
companies can contact you
or of course any data on the public
internet
which misrepresents you you can enforce
these changes
under gdpr you can't go to a restaurant
two weeks down the line and say hey i
paid here fifteen dollars i only wanted
to pay ten
that's not quite the same
you have the right of ownership to data
point all
any data point that links back to you
if you go to the bar assuming bars are
still open
and you pay for your drinks in cash the
transaction is anonymous
it's not owned by you or anyone
else aside from the company managing the
bar
if on the other hand you go to a hotel
you have a reservation
which links back to you by name email
phone number in the evening you go to
the restaurant
have a meal have a charge to your room
you're creating a transaction which
links back to your reservation
you then go to the bar grab a couple
beers
once more charge that to your room again
transaction link back to your
reservation links back to you
through name phone email
because these data points or these
transactions link back to you
they are technically your ownership or
you can control how these are used
had you paid directly with a credit card
or in cash
the transaction would not link back
directly to you or it would be more
difficult for the
property to link these to you and so you
have less control over this
finally because these data points are
yours
you have the right to restrict the
access to and the processing of this
information
this is specific for all information
that you're providing the property
or the business is to be used within
your business transactions you go to a
hotel
you give your name a passport because
they need to provide this to
authorities and they're providing you
with the room
that doesn't mean that they're then free
to contact you every week telling you of
the new menu
this also means that they can't just
take all your details
and send them off to different company
for saying hey uh taxi companies to
suddenly start emailing you about offers
for rights to the airport on the next
day
if you're able to cover these
five rights as a start for your
compliance
it's a good start for your strategy
now if you're trying to build up
your own strategy think about where the
data is going
if it were yours would you be happy with
it being disseminated in that way
now what are the risks in the case of
non-compliance
the first one is downtime
if you have a breach you obviously have
the
incident response and if from there it's
found that
you are violating the regulations
it's going to lead to a further
investigation extended downtime
loss of revenue
there is a potential harm to reputation
although
arguably in recent times or high profile
cases
the loss of mark
the loss of business from these breaches
has been
relatively minimal or short-lived
and of course as mentioned before
defines
up to four percent up to four percent of
annual revenue
per infraction this means if you're
disseminating
data to three parties that's twelve
percent
not just four something good when trying
to talk with
higher level management
obviously security and compliance are
not the same
one does not apply to the other but
a good security strategy will be
limiting how your data is leaving
providing some compliance and limiting
access to your data from third parties
likewise a good compliance strategy will
be limiting
how long you're keeping data for
limiting your exposure
providing you on the same hand with some
better security posture
so who am i i'm juan
i worked for close to three years in it4
hospitality
during that time we had the gdpr go live
and i was involved with implementing the
corporate strategy
developing our own procedures across all
departments
doing the risk analysis for all
where we found the key for us was hr for
all things with
employee data and marketing
for all things client facing if you're
coming from a different industry
different business case it's highly
likely that operations are going to take
a
much higher priority
in you so
with no further ado i'm going to start
with the strategies for failure
with a little tale hansel and gretel and
the forest of compliance
once upon a time there was gretel gretel
was the ceo
of megacorp she built this company from
the
ground up putting in her blood sweat and
tears into it
and megacorp is a big seller of goods
and services across the world
as part of her weekly routine redfield
would
cross the plains to get to europe she
would get the orders
come back to megacorp and make sure that
the delivery process was went smoothly
this happened for many years until one
day in 2018
as she was heading off to collect the
orders from europe
she was faced with this forest
the forest seemed dangerous and all she
all she could see around it was a little
sign that said
if you can protect the data you can
cross the forest safely
rachel thought nothing of it i can just
uh walk right in and it's gonna be fine
great i looked around found a little
path
walked through the forest for a couple
hours
but slowly the path got
smaller and smaller until suddenly it
was just
the space between two trees and not a
path anymore
she tried to turn back to head back to
megacorp but
she'd hit a dead end and couldn't leave
the forest
obviously as with any regulation any
standard
if you're trying to be above board
you can't go at it with no strategy
you need to think about what you have to
do or what's required of you
and then you have the ability to go on
because of course i'm a benevolent
narrator
we get to bring gretel back to the start
of the forest
gretel remembers that she can't just go
into the forest
and come out the other side unscathed
the pain or trauma from this experience
makes her rethink
her choices rattle decides to head back
to megacorp
and comes back the next day the forest
is still there
gretel decides one more day of waiting
one more week she no longer has any
orders from
europe which means she's also no longer
delivering there
she starts getting phone calls from
suppliers telling her that due to the
loss of
business they're having to lay people
off
gretel feels a little bit responsible
for this but
she's not ready to face the forest again
alone slowly
as the businesses uh have to lay more
and more people out
of work what used to be a prosperous
land becomes a
barren wasteland
of course it's very difficult to or
rather it's very easy to define
decide to not work with europe
however that's a strategy that's rather
difficult to explain to
higher level management especially if
you're
not working in news anything to do with
goods and services
of course they're going to be wanting to
target one of the largest markets
in the world
so once more because we are benevolent
we let gretel
try once again
gretel knows she can cross into the
forest
but she also knows she can't go just
anywhere
she decides she's going to try to get
some help inside the forest
after all forests are living things
she walks slowly carefully trying to
look out for sounds
and here's a little laughter from
underneath from underneath a mushroom
she looks closer and meets sophie
sophie comes from the forest and it
tells gretel
hey i can protect you all you need to do
is give me
your contracts i'll take a look over
them
and give you a paper to help get you out
greta thinks this is great because she's
a
respected businesswoman she always has a
copy of her contracts on her
so she gives these to sophie
sophie takes a look through the
contracts make some remarks
gives them back to gretel along with a
paper showing gretel the way out
gretel takes this and is on her way
once again she's able to get a little
bit further into the forest
but once more she starts noticing that
the trees around her
seem to be closing in and she's not able
to
see the edge of the forest anymore
until at one point she finds that she's
completely locked in by the trees
unsure what happened because of course
she was being protected by sophie
except sophie didn't really care about
gretel's business
she was only protecting her from other
parties but not from herself
if you get a lawyer involved in as part
of your strategy
it's very important to make sure that
they're
not only looking at how your
vendors and partners manage your data
this is one element of the
threat vectors or existing risks to
compliance but it is not the
end-all solution for it
we bring greta then back to the start of
her path
she knows she has to cross the forest
because otherwise
all of her countrymen and women
are going to end up in the barren
wasteland
she can't go at it blindfolded or it's
going to
end up in a mess and she can't trust the
help from inside the forest
she needs help before
gretel decides to contact a lawyer
beforehand
someone to check over her operations
after all if sophie was able to
protect her for a bit inside the forest
maybe she can get some protection from
before the forest and with that be able
to cross to the other side
the lawyer comes on site checks for
things
provides gradual with a checklist with
which gretel quickly
files as well as a paper stating that
the operations were checked
gretel heads up into the forest
confident this time that
she's going to be able to get to the
other side
as you can imagine once more she hits
the dead end
it's very easy to have audits done on
businesses
operations and relations with other
parties
if nothing is done about these audits
it's the same as having a penetration
test every year for pci
storing it and not doing anything about
it
you're not becoming compliant you have
simply created a checklist of things to
do which
you're not doing and the audit is not
part of the compliance it's
actually executing those tasks which is
gretel is now tired of getting lost in
the forest
she remembers that no matter what she
does no one seems to be able to get her
across
to the other side so she calls on her
brother
hansel hansel has been managing it for
her company ever since they went to
digital
unfortunately hansel is highly
understaffed which
has led to them having a couple issues
of burnout
but hazard has been able to overcome
most
challenges through his extensive network
of i.t professionals
hansel decides he's not going to
[Music]
brute force his way through the forest
instead he's going to contact one of his
friends
jack tells him yeah we worked with um
this woman rapunzel she sold us some
diamonds and um
we're able to get across to the other
end of the forest
so hazel sets up the meeting
rapunzel shows him the diamond and tells
him
this diamond will protect you to the
other end of the forest
look at all this list of high name
clients that we have
they've all purchased our diamonds and
they're getting to the other side of the
forest
also thinks this is great this is the
ultimate weapon tool
or the ultimate tool to get to the other
side so
castle heads off into the forest alone
and as his as he's nearing the edge of
the forest
he hears a noise just to his left
he thinks okay i can leave the forest
and be in europe where i can
just quickly look at what that noise is
so he gets closer to the forest i add to
the source of the noise
and he sees a very tall tower
okay so this is the source of the noise
but what he sees in the tower
impacts him even more where there's a
door frame
which should hold the door but it's just
the door frame
he thinks this is very odd and he sees
lots of gremlins
going in and out holding papers he
wonders what's going on here
so he gets closer to the tower
and asks one of the gremlins what's
going on
the gremlin hands him one of the pieces
of paper
and hansel sees his company's details
all over it
the edge of the forest which seems so
close now it seems so far away
he finds himself unable to leave from
this tower
because of course he's been putting all
of his data off premise
with someone who is selling him a shiny
diamond
if any company tries to sell you
at the end-all be-all tool of
for compliance 99 of the time
what they're selling you as a customer
relationship manager
they're going to be rebuilding your
databases off sites where you have no
more control over them
and because of the way responsibilities
are managed with regards of
who is supposed to own the data and
who's processing it
if they get breached they can claim that
it's your fault for
handing them the data and likewise if
you get breached
and it's found that you were giving them
this data you're of course
not much better off
hansel not wanting to be
beaten in such a way takes his memory
and decides to
call upon his heads of department
he has the donkey who is in charge of
well all the automated tasks
the cat who provides support but is
really mean with clients
the dog who the clients love
and the rooster that just makes sure
everything runs smoothly
he talks to the four animals and says
hey we need to cross the
the forest but we need to protect our
customers data
and no matter what we do we seem to
having to start all over again
they talk it through and realize that
all of them are affected by it
differently
the donkey who's primarily accessing
data for
automated tasks so he only needs to be
aware of the risks when he's accessing
this data
the cat who's working with the erp
the crm and various monitoring tools
needs to inform his
subordinates about the risks involved in
the data how not to move it or keeping
it
in company infrastructure and of course
training them in the behavior with using
the crp crm to ensure
compliance the dog who takes
orders from clients working the data
entry
all the importance on the behavior and
how he's going to be taking notes for
this
either directly entering it to the erp
or crm
rather than post it around it because of
the risks involved
for his clients
the dog subordinates who are directly
facing the
clients those at the front of the house
as we say
they need to be aware of the company
policies with the data protection
how does this link to their behavior and
the security
not only security for the data
but also the risks to the company if
they don't
comply to these policies as well as the
risks to themselves depending on how
they're
communicating with the other clients
finally the rooster this high management
person animal
understands that as a high value target
his behavior is
critical to ensure compliance across the
board
not only is he more at risk than the
others
to be targeted but policies affect them
even more
not less
armed with this strategy the team heads
up into the forest
whether or not they make it to the other
side is left
to the viewers for decision
i'd like to leave you with a little poem
it's not pii it can be pii
it was pii
thank you and i'm still around if
anyone has questions i'd like to thank
carrel who was my
mentor for the con zoe rose who went
through the slides and some humphreys
who also helped me a lot with the gdpr
elements
now i appreciate it one this is very
interesting because i know this is
something that we deal with
on daily basis gdpr everything
i also found this is it's a very good
way to really
get everybody in the organization's
attention you know if you can link any
of your
findings or um exploits back to
gdpr um any type of regulations people's
eyes perk up and you know it's like hey
well what do you say
you know they they understand those
costs so no absolutely very good
information
i i do uh a complete side note for the
actual content
i am always uh impressed with
intentionally choosing slides with
you know a handful of words at most or
zero
and going through the story time
nonetheless so
regardless of the actual content which
itself was awesome let me uh
highlight the the top tier speaking
capability that you demonstrated there
so very nicely done uh so comment from
the
discord coming in great talk help break
this complex topic into consumable
pieces
this is continue with that theme make
the complex simple make the complex
understandable
even if it's a complicated thing i know
you had a very early slide of you have
the right to be forgotten you have the
right to
privacy like there are gdpr i don't know
how long the text of it itself is but i
think it's safe to say at least hundreds
of pages if not thousands to be full
actual text but the the
one sentence description of the right to
be forgotten like
what that describes so much so quickly
so
you start off with big picture work into
more complex as necessary
you made things relatable via stories so
and you ended with a haiku so i mean how
much more awesome could it be so i'm
you're done good thank you thank you
um let's see yep we got uh nathan
up next nathan uh chung
uh pre-recorded talk on
neurodiversity in cyber security um
leslie or want any partying thoughts
before we move into uh next presentation
coming up we're doing fine for time we
have a couple more minutes if you need
it
i don't know why it was great man you
you should pat you like like jeff's
like jeff said you just passed a level
of just talking points and everything
and honestly
this is something like that's it's
always being interpreted different ways
so
i i take my hat up to you to take a
complex type of like gdpr especially
when you have a bunch of lawyers working
around it
and bringing it down to something like
okay you can use it more of like an
awareness thing like hey this is
what it is per se so hats off to you i
love it
i'm a big fan of the phrase mental model
building out your
your understanding of how something
works you can get into the of course the
nitty and gritty later on but
building out your mental model of like
this is what gdpr is
in a couple sentences or a couple
paragraphs and be able to
understand that and relay it to others
that helps things spread i like to build
up my mental model of a lot of areas
even though there's a lot of things that
i don't examine further in further depth
that's okay
if i understand what kind of the basics
are of that area that's being like
it generalist right sysadmin work
started off with a lot of general lists
and you dive deep into areas as
need be but you'll understand the the
overall scenario that's why
i'm completely biased i think
sysadminwork is a great segue to a lot
of fields within it
uh help desk very similar situation
network admin very similar situation
you just you get a big breadth of
experience before diving into something
that
really interests you for the one niche
or you stay a generalist which is fine
as well
okay with that being said again thank
you