uh maggie welcome to
uh grim con
hopefully that's probably stupid check
yeah yeah i gotta do a mic check
yeah no thank you for having me and yeah
we we will have a small pg-13 warning on
the talk
so you know there are any there are any
children around you know
earmuffs so uh
what uh undisclosed location are you
calling from because
you look like you're in the bunker of
some cia safe house
oh so you caught me no this is actually
really funny um
i actually uh planning making this
during the talk that uh you guys planned
this out really well because
um grimcon is actually on my last day
here now
at oak ridge national lab where i'm
sitting which i think is super fitting
because with this talk it probably would
have been my last day here anyways
i'm not sure how a contractor would feel
about me giving a talk with the word hoe
in the title but you know it's just to
get a roll of it
if we have not caught your interest yet
and what's about to happen in five
minutes
stay tuned yeah please if you're not
tuning in
the word ho shows up in the title from
oakridge national labs
that's fantastic so you're also our
first guest
to bring a little flair in the
background uh what is uh on display
behind you
oh so what do we got behind me so this
was i don't
kick my computer over um this was a
sensor that my team actually got the
there we go uh rnd 104 for doing some
uh high fidelity grid measurements and
then
over here we just have some fun drones
that we use
um another future drone and then we have
our uh
our video wall way in the background
here here we go
there we go um because we actually have
some uh we're the backup uh scada center
for a few of the local utilities that we
can actually
project and watch some of their uh scada
control stuff on our our big wall here
so it's pretty fun
so yeah this was this was my office i'm
relegated now to a visitor badge
because you know now i'm just yeah i had
to hand in my official badge and
badge and gun this morning so
yeah so uh yeah this is gonna be my my
last you know
uh last official uh thing i do
from my office so so what are you moving
on to
uh so i'm actually going over to uh
schneider electric
to work on their uh product security
research team
fun pretty pretty pumped about that they
have an office
over in grenoble france base of the alps
so hopefully gonna get this vaccine and
go meet some colleagues and do some
skiing next winter
that sounds awesome yeah i'm pretty
pumped about it
and i already ran this talk by my my
direct report there
they're good with it huh not endangering
my
my next employment move thank god this
is this is schneider electric approved
uh this is this is not representative of
schneider electric
unofficially okay can we start making
some high voltage jokes now
uh i mean i think that's uh you know the
hoe has high voltage in there somewhere
high voltage output something
yeah you can really amp this up that's
what it's all about
what was that oh man that's what this is
all about
ha ha
for those of you who are not familiar
with uh dadjokes on
twitter uh maggie is uh despite her
appearances
actually a dad yeah it's true it's very
true
you know why uh why pelicans are always
optimistic
because it's either black or white
because if they weren't they'd be
pelicans
and we just lost fantasy all right so i
got to do my favorite one on tyler
tyler what is a pirate's favorite letter
r r is great but tis the c they love
no i'm too cool for that
look at my hair oh that's right i got a
mohawk too dude
and a beard i mean you're one up in that
i've not been able to do that yet
yeah at your age you'll grow into it
eventually
90.
so one last question for you go on tyler
no i was just gonna say i'm right over
by idaho national labs and uh
i was curious what team you were on over
at oakridge
so i'm in there uh we just did ahead of
had a reimagining because of covid
so whatever the acronym is but it's like
the energy
resiliency and security team okay
yeah i'm actually gonna be interfacing
with inl a bunch so out that way
well when you're out this way yeah look
me up right now yeah
i'm not that way a bunch for yellowstone
anyways so oh yeah
beautiful is resiliency and security two
different concepts
so yes and no just don't hate in our
acronym sprays and i don't make them up
i don't make them up well you don't work
there anymore anyway so
it's just you know it's it's academia we
gotta add big words
oh you're academic well i mean the lab
is
oh okay but not you no no
completely academic there's no kinetics
based out of oak ridge at all
all right and with the oh i got to give
you presenter status
let's get you up on the board um
again final note for those of you with
children at home this is rated pg-13
yeah i think i only swear once and i'll
that yeah that exactly well
then
now now it's all gone oh god all right
i come with a permanent pg-13 rating so
it's not a problem
at minimum oh i i definitely uh
traumatized a little girl about a year
and a half ago at b-sides las vegas
um they did a stand-up comedy part and i
came out and did a unicorn bit that was
definitely pg-13 and i i apologized her
to during
her my bit about not all unicorns are
like this
she's walking right by the stage i mean
i don't know why the parents would bring
them right by the stand-up comedian
stage like they could have gone to the
back of the room
all right maggie the floor is yours go
away
cool beans all right yeah so
for any of you guys who are just turning
in and tuning in and miss some of that
intro
my name is maggie morganti a lot of you
guys know me by mags
and uh we're going to do a pg-13 talk
today called hoe the planet not your
mama's social engineering talk
and so a little bit about me i have a
master's degree in intelligence studies
from mercyhurst university back in
pennsylvania and when i was doing my
degree there
i interned at fire eye on their cyber
threat intelligence team
i always like to give a shout out to
fireeye because they tolerated my bad
jokes enough to actually stretch my
internship out
um from what was supposed to be three
months to eight months so you know i
always really appreciate that experience
and love to give them a shout out for
that
and after that internship completed i
took a full-time job
a few years back at oak ridge national
laboratory
that you know let me get into a bunch of
different kinds of cool research both
cyber related and not
but kind of the main thrust of what i've
been working on here
has been grid security research and
most recently a super sweet colleague of
mine megan samford
uh gave me a call a few months ago back
i guess now and basically said hey you
know i got this vp
uh position at schneider electric and
i'm building out a team you know why
don't you come work with me
and that was really a position that i
couldn't pass up
so i'm actually headed there now in 2021
i'm pretty excited about that to work as
a product security researcher for
schneider
focusing a little bit on their energy
management side
um pretty in line with what i've been
doing and for any of you guys that don't
follow me on twitter i do have a twitter
account i've included the my handle
there
so my dms are generally open unless
someone gives me a reason for them to
not be open
so if you guys have any questions
regarding this or um
ics stuff you know always feel free to
ping me
i'm always you know super happy to talk
about that stuff
and then um i kind of had to make this
joke i'm actually giving this talk right
now
i'm not sure if you guys can see from my
office here at oakridge national lab
and this is my my last day at work here
before i go on to work at schneider and
i thought that that was super fitting
considering this may have been my last
day at work here anyways
um has a guppy giving a talk with the
word hoe in the title i'm not sure my
lab director excuse me would have loved
that too much
and in addition to this being a uh a
pg-13 talk
i did want to do a disclaimer for any of
you guys that read the abstract of this
that this is not
sort of any you know morally judgey high
horse talk you know we're not gonna be
uh you know condemning any of the you
know the good floozies or boys out
there of the world
uh what we are you know again i come
from a research background
going to be you know studying them and
observing their habits
uh you know for the purpose of looking
at this from a privacy standpoint
and from a social engineering standpoint
um kind of as it relates to us
as a community and so any of you who
look at my background
can see that it's pretty heavy in the
ics operational technology space
and you may be wondering uh hey max you
know what are you doing giving a social
engineering talk
you know let alone kind of a uh a pg-13
social engineering talk and that's a
very valid question
so a few years back i found myself
in a new city at a new job single for
the first time
since i owned a flip phone and you can
all make fun of me for how old that
makes me
i'm aware of it and uh you know kind of
despite all of the horrible anecdotes
that i'd heard from friends about you
know
trash fire that is dating apps i
went ahead and you know had some wine
and sat down
in the living room with a few of my
girlfriends and got on a few of these
apps thinking you know oh this is going
to be so much fun
you know we have the lab here we have
the smoky mountains here we have ut here
you know there should be a ton of really
you know wonderful people in this new
town for me to meet
and um by the fact that i'm giving this
talk you can probably imagine that that
didn't exactly go
how i envisioned it and so i wouldn't be
someone with an intel background
if i didn't give you the key takeaways
of this talk first for why we're doing
it so the first one is
i think sometimes as a community we tend
to think of social engineering
as a discipline that requires you know a
lot of formal training
and courses and you know even like
apprenticeship sort of things
when really social engineering is just
um
emotionally manipulating someone to get
a result you want
and that's human nature i mean that
happens
all the time in the majority of
interactions we have whether it's
nefarious or whether it's not
so i really wanted to just kind of raise
a little bit of awareness to this
because i think sometimes
we get in this siloed thinking that
social engineering is
just kind of a professional discipline
when really it's not
and the second is looking at this from
the privacy standpoint
of when people do things to try to hide
their behavior that often leads to that
data
being significantly less safe and when
it is
you know highly sensitive data like
something that could make you
compromised
or sensitive pictures if that data is
not being stored in a way
that is secure and safe um
things that you're putting out into the
world might end up in places you really
don't want them to
and lastly social engineers can be
social engineered
um you know we we see it time and time
again that people that do have
you know formal security backgrounds um
whether that be
uh in the private sector or people
coming from the intelligence community
with you know extensive experience and
this still fall prey to it themselves
and you know whether for good or for ill
we are very much
kind of a a whole of life community
you know in addition to supply chain
village and car hacking village and all
of those other great
uh nonprofits we we have you know mental
health village
and all of the red team blue team deeper
fits and our own cooking shows
and this community really likes to you
know kind of embrace the total
of our lives together to you know make
them better and help our help each other
um you know stay more safe and stay more
secure so i thought it would be really
fun to give a talk
on the social engineering aspects you
know not of
you know your mom helping you break into
a jail for an engagement
or you know breaking into a bank but
more the actual day-to-day personal
interactions that a lot of us have
outside of work and so the first one of
these
is realizing that your everyday people
who haven't taken any of our conference
trainings who haven't gone through the
intelligence community
can still be really and i mean scarily
good at this
you know you don't have to pay 3 700
at you know your local hacking
conference to learn how to social
engineer i mean there are
you know layman people walking around
who are just absolutely excellent at
this
so you know not kind of getting into
that mindset of you know oh this is just
an everyday person
you know they probably aren't you know
doing anything deceitful
and uh one of my really sweet
girlfriends uh likes to
uh refer to people that you know kind of
had this sort of behavior
as tinder lizards and i picked that up
it's not my original content
but i just thought it was hilarious and
kind of had a nice snap to it and
you know really helps kind of visualize
this kind of like
scaly slimy behavior that we you know
kind of
typically associate with that like
caricature of a person's behavior
um so i made a fun uh animal profile for
you know this for the sake of the
presentation and i think the piece to
really pull out here
is that these people who you know
you may find out down the road are you
know actually fairly deceitful
probably aren't going to come across
that way to you at first i mean if
they did this wouldn't be social
engineering if you could spot a slime
ball from a mile away you'd never
fall for it so a lot of times this
behavior is
wrapped in very you know kind of
innocent innocuous
um other behaviors that you know
lead you to you know have trust in
someone
and not uh suspect certain things
so the way that we're going to go about
doing this and this is the part of this
that may or may not get me in trouble
but it's fine um is i thought a really
fun way to
present this would essentially be uh
doing an exercise where essentially i'm
going to role play
you know your typical skeevy tinder
lizard and walk
through some of these behaviors that
they use kind of especially in the
digital sphere
and ways that would affect us from an
infosec standpoint
and look at some of the problems that
you know i would run into if i was this
kind of person
and some of the really creative
solutions um you know that i have a
researcher have found you know
their personal experience or friends
anecdotes or reddit or podcasts
anecdotes
of kind of people uh things that people
have found partners were doing
that you know we would be mad about it
if it wasn't just like so damn creative
um so we're gonna go through some of
this together and you know instead of
kind of pointing the finger
to like you know this is how they would
do that you know do it in a very judgy
way i thought it would be really fun to
actually assume that role
and walk you guys through some of this
so for the next probably about 10
minutes
um i'm going to be role playing liz the
tinder lizard as your guide through
uh how a you know kind of skeevy tinder
lizard
would uh use kind of their the digital
tech at their disposal
and social engineering tactics um to
kind of get away with some things that
we wouldn't traditionally
you know want to see in behavior so
uh beginning of our journey you know
just kind of set the stage
for the purpose of this my character is
going to be liz the tinder lizard
and you know i'm a you know 20 something
year old girl
who you know has two or three guys that
aren't aware of each aren't aware of
each other that i'm talking to
and you know i still kind of want to
play the field a little bit
i'm not quite ready to give that up
so i would still like to be on these
dating apps kind of without any of those
men who also aren't aware of each other
knowing
so there's a few ways that i can do this
the first
is going to be constantly deleting the
app so that if i'm sitting here
scrolling through my phone you don't see
thumbnails for bumble
hinge tinder or any of the other million
of these that there are
but that's pretty thin as far as you
know kind of a
tinder lizard ttp because you know
people have friends that are on these
apps
and you know if my profile card or
whatever is still coming up
in a geographical area that you know
that person has friends in
they're going to say hey you know so and
so is still on these apps you know i
thought you guys were hanging out so
that's a pretty thin
rookie way to go about this the second
one is going to be you know kind of your
traditional cliche hoes in different
area codes
so say i you know know that i have
family that's about you know an hour or
two away
or that i travel across the country for
business a bunch
a lot of these apps will allow you to
uh set your location in a different spot
we saw this
uh that people were using it to actually
collect intel during the initial
initial uh covet outbreaks but you know
if i'm gonna be skeevy
you know maybe i'm gonna set my location
for somewhere that
you know the people that i'm hanging out
with wouldn't be matching with me
because
as far as this app is concerned you know
i'm not in
knoxville tennessee i may be you know in
atlanta or seattle or somewhere else
but again you know the geographic
constraints of that you know the
logistics are
not convenient you know then i actually
have to go to these places to meet those
people
so then we have you know kind of true
experts you know people like nathan here
with the you know the duck and the taco
mask to kind of mask your identity
or uh some of the other really fun
things that i could do
are adjusting what i tell the app that i
want to be matched with
so say i you know by current kind of
flaw
consists of you know men that are
generally you know 23 to 28
and you know they might all be short and
they may be
you know not particularly religious and
very politically progressive
and i've matched with them because the
app determined that's both
uh what we both want and it showed us
each other but if i
all of a sudden tell the app you know
hey i think i want some diversity in my
life i really want
um you know a tall over 45 very
religious very republican kind of q anon
sort of figure
um while that may or may not actually be
what i want
all of a sudden if my parameters change
for what the app
thinks i want to be matched with um
everyone that i've
previously matched with kind of won't be
able to see me anymore in their card
deck if i unmatch from them because
the algorithms won't think that we're
going to you know be a good fit
and then once i find someone that i
would like to talk to then we have a
whole other set of problems
that i actually have to talk to them in
a way that's not
you know suspicious to any other person
that i'm talking to that may or may not
be shoulder surfing me
and you know we can't talk about this
without just raising a glass
to you know the wonderful david petraeus
who really just brought
all of this you know kind of crashing
into the dod space
uh with his very public affair with his
biographer which we'll get into in a
second
uh so the kind of very common
um you know lizard ttp that happens
is uh the duplicate friend so say i have
a very sweet friend here in knoxville
caitlyn grace
most phones will allow you to have two
people with the same name
in your phone so the really easy thing
to do
is say i'm hanging out with johnny um
but i know that jimmy may be texting me
i'm just going to change jimmy's name in
my phone
to caitlyn grace and that way when i
have a notification come
that comes up on my phone if someone
sees it it just looks like my friend is
texting
but this is going to get really really
weird if a thumbnail pops up
um from my best friend with a you know
picture of
joke that's going to raise some
questions that i really don't want to
have to explain
so the next one is and this kind of goes
hand in hand um
with the uh the petraeus is the icloud
shopping list so apple actually has a
really super interesting feature
um that allows you to share
collaborative notes and this is a really
cool feature
for other applications um but what you
could
theoretically do is start a shopping
list and
you know it'll have grocery list you
know the first kind of few lines that
would be previewed on your note would be
you know batteries cheese bread wine and
then after that you can just carry on a
conversation with whoever you have as a
another collaborator on the note and
anyone kind of scrolling through your
phone
um unless they have questions about why
you have a collaborative grocery list
it's gonna look fairly normal um but
again if someone actually opens that
all of a sudden it's gonna look really
weird some of the things you have
added to your grocery list um and that
kind of brings us to
uh the david petraeus which if any of
you are i'm assuming most of you are
familiar with this
um he and his uh biographer who he was
having an affair with
uh basically were communicating
exclusively through gmail drafts
so they had a common email account one
of them would go in
write an email draft save it the other
one would log in
read it delete it make a new draft save
it and this is how they were
communicating
without actually having to send anything
back and forth
but again if anyone ever logs into that
email it's going to be pretty obvious
what that email is for
so probably not ideal and then you know
you have kind of the general
you know uh people have whatsapp
or other you know messaging platforms
that if they have family in other
countries it kind of you know goes back
to the whole like duplicate friend
you know oh that's no one that's you
know my my cousin who lives
in you know germany or france or
wherever and it's that sort of thing
um but the super super creative one
uh that i just i'm still not entirely
sure the application of this and why
samsung does this but for any of you
that have a samsung phone which i'm
hoping is none of you for security
reasons
um samsung doesn't actually allow you to
block people
uh samsung if you go in and block
someone
it will without ever uh indicating to
them that you've blocked them it'll just
neatly send
any messages that they send you into
this blocked messages folder that's like
four clicks off of your
general sms inbox and so what
i could theoretically do is you know if
i am hanging out with johnny
and i know jimmy might be texting me is
i'll just block jimmy for that period of
time
and any texts that jimmy sends me
are never going to show up on the phone
are never going to show up in my inbox
my phone's never going to light up ping
nothing
um but then after a period of time when
i either you know get back to my car or
get back home
you can reopen that folder unblock them
and no one is any
wiser i have no idea why samsung has
this as a feature
um if any of you guys know i'd be super
interested to know
um but that is uh a way that you know to
break character for a second
um something that one of my really sweet
girlfriends ran into and made me aware
of that i just thought was
super super fascinating and of course
no talk that deals with uh privacy
infosec romantic relationships
would be complete if we didn't reference
nudes and this is
super where privacy becomes really
really relevant here
regarding where any sensitive data of
your bits
ends up um so
the kind of uh first place that people
tend to hide these things are these like
vault apps that either
just look like a vault app or i've seen
them disguised as
solitaire apps and you know anyone that
has something like this on their phone
it's going to raise questions about you
know
why do you have this on your phone it's
going to look kind of suspicious
um so it's actually not a great place to
hide something if i'm actually trying to
be
you know kind of a shady skeevy tinder
lizard
so the next place that people go is the
trash cans
you know you delete something out but
you leave it in the trash
again probably not the best place you
know if
if someone's going to ask to go through
your phone they're probably going to
look there
so you know i is an advanced skeevy
tinder lizard just no better than to
hide something there
uh the next one which is you know kind
of a level up if you really want to
become
you know just kind of a more
sophisticated tinder lizard
is the strategic crop so
uh os agnostic apps like adobe lightroom
will let you do something really
interesting with your photos
where say you have a picture of
something we'll keep this pg-13 and not
r um
so you have a picture of something and
there happens to be a vase
or a lamp in the background what you can
actually do with that picture is crop it
to just be the base or the lamp
and when you scroll through your camera
roll it'll just look like
the vase or the lamp but if i want to
see that picture again
i can go into adobe lightroom hit crop
and revert the entire thing back to the
original
so someone would have to know what they
were looking for
to even think that the picture of you
know the face the lamp the flowers
whatever were maybe not
uh you know kind of not what they
appeared at first pass
and then the last one
um i actually found because part of this
talk i crowdsourced
um from some guys that i used to be
really good friends with in high school
you know
old old friends of mine that you know um
have made some poor choices in life that
i was aware of
and you know i i just generally asked
them i said you know how did you get
away with this like what were some of
the tactics that you used because i
would like to give a talk on this
and steal your creativity um for my own
purposes
and this i just thought was ridiculous
um that one of the guys
used to print pictures as
pdfs in his phone to his internal
storage
voicemail folder
because this morning cannot find the
discord chat link please help
um okay i don't know if bryson can get
on that okay
um yeah so he would
take girls nudes and he would store them
as a pdf file in his voicemail folder
because your voicemail can't pull over a
pdf so
someone would actually have to know to
go into the internal storage
of your phone and try to look at your
raw voicemail files
um so that one i and like again you know
this friend
my high school friend that did this was
not
like even a college educated person at
all i mean he's a blue collar forklift
operator
and you know has no uh you know kind of
formal background in check
and you know these kind of like just
wild creative things
that people are figuring out how to do
are really interesting and again
from privacy standpoint uh you know if
you're in a committed relationship with
someone and you are kind of sharing uh
those sort of intimate pictures
um and i'm not the person that's done
any of the work on this again
um you know this is a lot of work that's
been done by people that are you know
much more in the privacy sphere than me
but you would hope that those pictures
are being stored
in a much more kind of secure fashion
rather than just in you know kind of raw
form and some random internal storage
file where they could be accessed
without any sort of password or extra
security measures
and then of course the bane of every
pesky tinder lizards example
or of every pesky tinder lizard life is
your pesky notifications
so if i have my phone sitting up on the
table
and it's blowing up with notifications
that are suspicious like that's not a
good thing you know that's
that's how you kind of get had as a
pesky tinder lizard
so how do you get around this um the
most
rookie one is obviously going to be the
airplane mode
so this is you know your phone is
you know in airplane mode so that no
notifications can come through
um but to anyone who's looking at your
phone that's going to look really
suspicious you know we're not on a plane
we're at a brewery why is your phone on
airplane mode
um so then the next one is obviously
going to be you know kind of the
secret incognito locked messaging
app but as with the photovolts it's
going to look weird if i have that
because you know
why do i have that on my phone what do
you have to hide
uh so that's generally something that's
going to raise suspicion if i'm you know
kind of being this skeevy person
uh so kind of the next step that you
know we do
is you know either muting the contact so
that none of their things come through
so you know if i have signal and i
decide
that you know i just don't really want
to hear uh any notifications
from johnny while i'm out with jimmy
i'm just going to mute johnny's con or
mute johnny's contact in you know signal
sms whatever but that doesn't prevent me
from when i open it when i open up the
app
still seeing the uh you know the
notification or the message
um this also goes to deleting the app
which you can do but if you're
constantly re-downloading deleting the
app it's going to look strange
so again this one i actually come back
to that same
samsung soft block that you know no
notifications
ever come through because the message
never comes through which again if any
of you guys have any idea why samsung
has that on their phone
um i don't know and i would love to hear
your thoughts on that because i just
think it's super interesting
and so one thing that i learned when i
was in miami last year
at the s4 conference is that even the
best lizards fall
even you know the best strongest iguanas
when you know the the cold front moves
in even they
will fall from the trees so you know
we we've kind of gone through some of
the different ways that you know
liz the tinder lizard may you know
manipulate her phone manipulate the apps
on it
uh to make it look like you know she's
this innocent plant lamb who has nothing
to hide
um but if there's something to hide
there's always a way to find it
so location services
if you stay matched with someone that
you have met on a dating app
generally those uh apps will show you
how far away the person is
so if someone tells you that they are at
work
and you know they work roughly 15 miles
away from
you and you can check that on a map with
gps
but their app says that they are three
miles away from you
that probably suggests that they're not
exactly telling the truth um
this was uh the one uh
the one kind of personal one for me um
which i can't super get into because of
the lab but essentially
if you had someone who from a national
security
um aspect was transporting something
that was
sensitive and they left location
services
on their phone and you as a person who
had
you know had a beer with them knew what
they did for a living
it would be super problematic that you
could theoretically based on a
tinder or a bumble uh x miles away from
you
track that material because they were
dumb enough to leave their location
services on
so again from a national security
privacy infrastruct perspective
you know this has consequences that
reach pretty far beyond just someone's
feelings getting hurt
you know suddenly uh someone that they
actually haven't verified
themselves as being trustworthy can
track
national security stuff
and that's kind of the the length that i
can go about that in detail
um one of the one of the really funny
ones that i've seen
um again based on the location services
is uh if someone feels that their
significant other is using
um tactic number two about setting their
location
somewhere else that they go on business
uh you can play that against them
so say you were dating someone that
traveled to san francisco a lot and you
kind of had a feeling that you know
maybe when they go
out of town they're using tender bumble
hinge whatever
um next time they go out of town just
make your own account you can make it
you
you can make it look like a honey pot
and just set it for san francisco and
swipe through your matches and you know
see if the person comes up again this is
super creepy and invasive but
you know if if you are invested in
finding out like there are ways to do
this
um and this one's my personal favorite i
like to call this one the phone is lava
and so like if if at any given time
someone has suspicions you know really
all you have to do to check that is
reach for the person's phone
and if they look like they just saw a
ghost uh you probably have some reason
to worry about um you know kind of
suspicious
stuff going around um you know kind of
in that person's
general tech device
this one um uh someone
uh capped is the dominoes and i actually
found this
on a one of my favorite podcasts that i
listened to it's called call her daddy
which is extra not pg-13 it's like way
beyond r but it's hilarious
and there was this girl that wrote in
that basically
thought her significant other um
was not at work at night when he said he
was and
she wanted to and this i just thought
was brilliant from a social engineering
perspective
and she wanted to check this but she
didn't want to seem like you know she
was
psycho so she ordered doordash pizza
to his work and doordash lets you track
the driver
so you know you can call them and be
like hey babe like you're outside of
or they're outside of your work like
where are you i got you pizza delivered
you're working late um you know and if
all of a sudden that driver has no one
to meet
uh that's that's probably a pretty big
tell
um which i thought was just absolutely
hysterical
and really all of this to say that you
know
for as much as there are skeevy tinder
lizard ttps that people
use um
women especially i feel like um at least
you know kind of the women that i've
come in contact with
are like borderline fbi and there are
uh you know for as much as there are
creative non-tech
uh social engineers on kind of the
skeevy tender lizard side
there are some also really super
creative
um people who come up with ways to
you know kind of alarm trip on this who
are also not
technically uh you know kind of formally
trained at all
either and i just think it's super
interesting
um for us as a community to realize that
that
you know kind of outside the sphere of
infosec and outside the sphere of doing
physical pen
testing you know whether we realize it
or not we are surrounded by people who
in just their personal
everyday interactions are actually doing
some pretty impressive social
engineering back and forth with each
other
um you know that haven't really received
any training on how to do this
um you know haven't been to our
conferences don't do this professionally
and you know are actually scary scary
good at it and so again closing
statements
just a reminder that really all
manipulation
to achieve an end result is social
engineering this isn't something that we
have any kind of monopoly on
um the the general population is way
better at this than i think we give them
credit for
especially when the urge to reproduce um
is involved and uh also
that you know bring your own device
policies um this effects because there
may be
a different workaround people do with
their devices there may be things stored
on those devices
that are attached to your corporate
networks that you might not want stored
on those devices attached to your
corporate networks
and you know also the privacy
implications of where
people hide things when they're trying
to be deceitful
that just do not in any way shape or
form
um lend themselves to privacy and that
is
my talk i don't have a work email to
give you guys because i am in between
um but yeah if you guys have any
questions you can reach me on twitter
and uh thank you for grim for having
this
so that was a different talk yeah
uh i i want to point out in advance um
to
uh return the favor from uh your
participation from
several times in the past there is
a picture with your eyes closed out on
twitter now
during your talk i hate you i hate you
so much
that's not even cool that i had
forgotten all about that
well now you've been reminded and you're
welcome is this the entire reason my
talk was accepted
so that i could set you up for this yeah
i'm not that smart of a social engineer
that's just disappointing bryson's
revenge goes
far and wide he yes he has a long memory
and there's a country we're in on that
so i'm also going to get them at some
point in the future too
so are you going to be like an elephant
now not a unicorn because you have a
long memory
is that like a thing i i think uh
unicorns besides having access to an
infinite bag of holding because how else
could we carry anything um we also
can put memories there i love whoever
wild west is the phone is lava works
great with my teenage daughter
uh yeah so um i
actually had very smart before their
time parents
uh who when i was you know 15 or 16 or
however old i was when i got my first
cell phone
um every day when i got home from school
at five o'clock my dad took away my cell
phone
and locked it and he said nothing good
happens on a teenage girl's cell phone
after
dinner that's a smart man
yeah after after dinner that's so that's
the corollary to the
nothing good happens at 2 am
conversation too
that's awesome now that was those really
good talk there's some interesting uh
there's always interesting implications
when you talk about bring your own
device from an enterprise standpoint but
the general population
is very very creative and we've lost
the the insight that we're
technologically smart and we think we
can
lock these phones down the general
population is like a bunch of teenage
daughters they will find a way to
make whatever they're trying to do
happen on their phone
no and i think it's super interesting
because uh
you know both myself and a few of my
really close girlfriends you know kind
of had interactions with people that
uh we're not ideal but like
you know a few months removed from it
happening i was like you know i
i almost like can't even be mad about
that because like that was impressive
the way you did that
like i like i would have not thought to
try to hide something they're like
that's pretty creative like i almost
have to just give you props for it
yeah again like teenage daughters
there's always a way
yeah i i'm fortunate or unfortunate
enough depending on who you're talking
to to not have children
yet so my uh my dog doesn't give me
these sorts of headaches
i'm surprised ansel doesn't have a twit
uh social media account
yeah i mean i feel like he just he gets
so much spotlight on mine on
on his own that i just i worry that
it'll go to his head but he'll get like
foggy ego
all of a sudden be like well and also
for my eco stick like i don't know if i
could handle it my dog social media had
more followers than me
[Laughter]
you only laugh but it's probably serious
yeah
yeah i don't want to have to admit that
like i don't want to have to look at my
dog and be like
you're more popular to my colleagues but
i am like maybe you should just give
this talk
well besides the threat to your ego from
your dog uh
the continuation of these kinds of
behaviors
which can range from i like that you
added the levels from the
innocuous to the level 9000
uh creep what is your prediction for
uh the threat landscape in 2021
um in ics pacific in general
your call oh man okay
choose your own adventure choose your
own i don't know yeah
only i'm not giving you options no i
mean i
from what we personally are going to be
dealing with i think there's going to be
a lot of knee-jerk
to solar winds that's going to distract
from
other things that are happening um at
least for you know kind of q1 2021
i think everyone's gonna be pretty rock
around the wrapped around the axle about
sunburst
um and i worry that that's going to make
people miss other things that are kind
of going on under their nose
um that's kind of a big concern of mine
um
john strain and all them did an awesome
podcast
that i totally agree with where they
basically
uh talking about this is going to set
patching back
by you know five years um we're already
seeing that about you know people
kind of pointing their fingers and
saying hi i told you so we shouldn't
patch look at what happened to them
um and one of the things they brought up
during that webcast
that i understand but i'm not
necessarily sure i agree with was
uh jonathan from rendition sec
said that he thought that uh he was
essentially comparing
um corporate leadership to anti-vaxxers
that they were they were going to be
he was essentially making the point of
not patching because of solar winds is
equivalent to not taking the vaccine
because of side effects
which i can see his line of thinking
there but i would
reframe it that you know this was an
intentional act this wasn't like a side
effect
of you know like a nice yes we see that
sometimes applying a patch has an
unintended consequence and
you know it's a thing but i think that
this is much more akin to
you know we caught someone trying to
poison a batch of vaccines
and now you know your csos and uh you
know other people on your security team
are a little apprehensive about
uh you know taking that vaccine because
if they tried to poison one batch like
they're probably doing that with other
stuff and you know that's a concern
and i think that we need to be
sympathetic about that
um and maybe be a little kinder to them
than anti-vaxxer labels
yeah no i mean i think threat landscape
21 2021 is gonna be
you know a lot of the same stuff that
we're seeing now already and then a lot
more um
you know kind of continuation on from
the sunburst stuff
i think that now that we know before and
it's already been popped we're gonna
find more of it because like this wasn't
their only poker in the fire
and that's that's not high side until so
i know i know one comp one large company
personally and a couple of other ones uh
that are not as bad but they were like
yeah this wasn't a problem we hadn't
patched it in two years
kept making like he he hahas on twitter
about it about you know
like oh we haven't patched and i'm like
that's
that's like saying i don't have any iocs
for it so you just compromised in
general
well and if it's not patched it's like
making fun of people
that like have a vulnerability and a
smart door lock
you never lock your door like that
like we cash for a reason guys like
there's probably a whole end if you
haven't patched like
maybe now's not the time to get super
like morally on your high horse about
that
well that's not to extend this because
we don't have too much more time but i
read an interesting article
uh i was a research study i was about a
year ago and they were talking about
that
patching overall actually introduces
more vulnerabilities in the long term
on average
yeah i i of course because it's uh it's
a bit of a controversial statement and
it's counter-intuitive
but the the simple premise that they
they kind of pointed to
is that increased code complexity
typically leads to
increased surface area and increased
problems the end of the day
they're fixing known issues but it turns
out developers inherently introduce new
issues anytime they put
bits to the screen to commit
um they went through it looking across a
range of things and it was
it was interesting because it was uh i'm
always a fan of anything that is
empirically driven in our industry
because
we get a lot of opinions we get a lot of
well i did this in my garage and
therefore look what it could be
uh we don't get a lot of this is an
industry-wide study anchored
in in data that is uh
statistically relevant yeah
well and i mean kind of to that point i
think that you know to be
sane and successful in this space like
you just you have to embrace the nature
of the whack-a-mole
like as the lizard
yeah that's that tenacity that that
brought us to this industry i think it's
a
required characteristic because of that
very nature
well max thank you for uh mixing up and
keeping people awake in the middle of
the day with a
spicy take
well you know it was it's the first
non-ics talk i've given so you know i
had to
i had to make sure that it would you
know stick in people's memories
2020. yeah
well and like i mean honestly it's grim
com like
grin grim con i mean nothing i can say
could possibly be more ridiculous than
whatever bryson's wearing so i mean that
the freedom of that is just always
that's a good point you're done
thank you see ya