good morning everyone
for those of you it's you know east
coast or west coast anyway
uh welcome to uh track two this is the
noobs
track for grim con zero x3 our first
speaker today is nina jones um i have
well first of all her actual talk as you
can probably see on screen is fishing
and social engineering
101 so uh nina's currently on her second
year studying network and i.t security
at norov school of technology and
digital media through her studies she's
come to find an interest in phishing and
social engineering
which means she has found ways to
get great grades through class and well
played
right that's the one thing
uh that's my reader too i i agree jeff
as a result of your paper next time i go
back to school
fishing social engineering at the mark
of year end of year one at norov
nina lives on a small island on the
outskirts of norway
in a county where due to outsourcing no
i.t jobs exist on the market
him so if you're looking she's awesome
she's presenting it at conferences
um it'd be nice to land nicely
into a good environment as well uh
there's more to the bio itself and i'll
post in the
discord now i'll be monitoring as we go
uh the noobs track
channel pre-show banter yep all right so
nina go ahead and take it away uh
leslie and i will mute and stop our
video for your presentation
um then i'll compile questions from
discord i think you're in discord as
well
and we'll do a little bit of q a at the
end but any questions before you want to
take things away
no i'm good to go all right kim
let the games i mean speaking begin
enjoy everyone
okay hi so yeah
ah thank you for that very nice
introduction i appreciate that
my name is nina jones i was born in
wales
and i moved to norway as a child a
part-time employee
in a tool shop i enjoy a road trip
sewing and crocheting i play in a brass
band and to top it all off i am a single
mother
um back in uh back in june
when i was
finishing my
first year at north i am
had to
[Music]
deliver
and social engineering and as i was
writing
the um the uh the report i discovered
that the definitions of phishing
engineering um live
contradiction without
so
ladies and gentlemen we are
investigating technical issues on
uh looks like it might be on nina's side
it might be somewhere along the way
um nina if you can hear me i would
recommend turning
off your webcam for the sake of
bandwidth and going to
audio only for the presentation
let's see nina is okay i think she's
rebooting or reconnecting on her side
which is just fine that's exactly what
we want so
in the meantime uh let's let's give a
few seconds about ourselves we didn't
properly introduce ourselves wesley do
you want to go first a little bit of
background on yourself
sure um i'm wesley i'm here to co-host
with jeff
i'm just a tinker of things
i know pretty much absolutely nothing
about cyber security they give me certs
for whatever reasons and things like
that
um no i've been i've been taping for by
maybe about
10 years in the field and everything
i've done a little bit of everything
um like i said i still google everything
when it comes out
i google about google that's kind of my
my mantra on google about google
to really just understand things but
um you know i've did pen testing its
response and everything that i'm i'm
more of like a blue teamer i like blue
team you know
i don't want to say i hate red team or
you know i try to be absolutely
definitely something that i def i
definitely talk trash until i get my
butt kicked
on uh on like uh purple team engagement
so you know
it gets me better but you know it makes
them bring out their bad tricks
all right and as for myself let's see
not connected to audio
uh on nina so that's on you to reconnect
and reshare
there you are is everything yep and you
can see it
we can give it a shot as is um it may
have been bandwidth issues it may have
been local
cpu side it may have been something
outside of our control
um but if you want to uh essentially
restart as
is uh with webcam that's fine if it is a
bandwidth issue i have found that
turning off your webcam
but conserving that audio for sorry
conserving that bandwidth for audio
may be a right call so maybe let's try
with uh
audio and video and then worst case and
we have time by the way we're not we're
just fine don't worry
um but let's go ahead okay
where did i where where did i fall out
uh you were fell out somewhere in the
last uh slide i would recommend going
back uh at least one slide
yeah maybe one of two slides um another
slide
yep we heard your
intro uh essentially a single mother
background was the
the uh that was the clearest part that
came in
that's what a handshake disconnect yeah
that's pretty much it
so uh okay i will drop
off and let you uh take it from here
there you go all right
okay uh for what it's worth for me at
least audio is immediately cutting out
nina can you hear me
okay
do you have a different device you can
present from
i know it's last minute where okay
okay no things are going okay
no no stuff happens this is totally fine
uh i will share it seems only when it's
going full screen for whatever reason
problems that yeah that
those gremlins they're going to keep
going
may i ask you hope everything is fine
reliable and i'm back in business
um so well um
nina i cannot reliably hear you sorry
all right um we we may try for a
condensed version of the presentation
itself
uh but it looks like due to technical
issues uh we're not gonna reliably be
able to do the
entire presentation where only about 10
minutes and
we have 45 minutes allocated per speaker
even though each talk is around 30
minutes so
we're seeing a little bit of inside
baseball uh real quick right here
maybe go to panel mode have someone else
share the slides and nina talk
mike great idea um the the only thing is
coordination at this point
um i can reach out of band to discord
but i think she's rebooting her machine
yeah everybody uh may fix that okay and
nina is back in i will make presenter
how is it going everybody do you want to
switch uh display versions
we're seeing the presenter view thank
you
all right do you want to just try one
more time here
i'll have another go it was my internet
connection got lost
oh lovely yeah uh for presenting
essentially wired is better like i i
believe in wireless a lot but not enough
for
uh presenting somebody else uses the
microwave
there goes 2.4 gigahertz all right
thank you very much
i understand all right
thanks everybody for your um uh report
so many contrary and uh paradoxing
uh definitions and i decided for the
sake of the report
well uh the uh start sh
restart is a little bit of a sign that
uh nina's trying for one last reboot
uh which is totally fine we will find a
way
there we go oh bryson mentioned
congratulations to camel graduating from
the new speaker track at
0x001 now actually over in
the the experts track so yes apparently
uh
campbell has uh graduated uh so that's
awesome
so that's gonna be everybody here
everybody in the new track you're gonna
definitely graduate to the expert track
one talk and you're expert
just letting you know
well it looks like this was a grim con
xerox one was a fair time ago but uh
it's more about you've been helped up by
others and
at some point you have some advice you
have uh
made some mistakes of your own and
you're happy to share those mistakes
with others they don't have to make them
all right uh we can we can both be
simultaneously mentor and mentee
i have folks that i help and i have lots
of folks that have helped me
so same idea absolutely
that that's definitely a true statement
because i know when
even helping people um they're going
deep into a subject that i know a little
bit about i know
how things work they definitely helped
me to kind of understand the material
understand how to present it the way
they store it the way they want to tell
their story like hey that's a great idea
how to tell that story
i'm always learning something from
speakers you know don't don't be afraid
you can always learn something everybody
has something to share
whether it's the stories would present
way to really just title something i
i've learned a lot about
putting titles on uh presentations it
makes a huge difference in what you're
trying to convey what you're trying to
talk about so
yeah i have a favorite image on this
that i
just love i'll share my screen here
momentarily
open image new tab
go to i hope to see all of our attendees
present present as well you know even if
it's just something
um simple like hey you know how to
better your tcp connection or something
like that i don't know you know
so i gave
uh we can try for uh
swap again nina yeah thank you
i've already rebooted my system to see
if that helps
okay are you uh still have the same
internet connection and still uh on
wireless
it may be the issue more than anything
yes and yes as i don't have any other
alternatives
that's fine yeah we'll we'll give us
another pass through don't worry
this is okay this happens you'll be just
fine
do not worry all right i will uh
mute and stop my webcam and let you i
would recommend since it does seem to be
bandwidth related or internet access
related uh
we would love to see your beautiful face
but uh we'll stay probably say webcam
off as my recommendation
all right thank you
am i am i on i think i'm on okay well
um yeah when i was writing my report
i discovered that the definitions for
phishing and social engineering
were contradicting each other and for
the sake of the report
and for the flow of the report i decided
that social engineering
is a technique used to fish and that was
the definition i went for
so defining phishing i wrote that it is
an umbrella term which employs several
techniques to acquire personal details
in pursuance
of illegitimately extracting money from
a victim
while josh prulinger he claims that
social engineering is the art of
exploiting human psychology
rather than technical hacking techniques
to gain access to buildings systems or
data
and that's quite an important thing to
remember that social engineers do not
need to know anything
about coding or programming or hacking
or
anything which has to do with hacking
when you come when you think of hacking
um so um
[Music]
some techniques which social engineers
use
are on the left
hand side and on the right hand side um
these techniques can often then be used
for fishing
and some of these may be uh maybe
techniques you've heard of before
and others may be ones which are
completely new to you
here are more techniques which i
encourage you to
look up uh as they
are outside the scope of the report uh i
do wish i had more time to talk about
them but my time is already running out
um when i wrote the report i chose to
raise awareness because um
according to a state of fishing report
from 2020
88 of businesses worldwide experienced
spear phishing attacks the potterman
institute
um uh identifies that
uh through a study on plain sight
hacking
uh which was conducted on 46 companies
357 trials
then 91 of the hacks were success
successful
and out of those hacks 49
needed less than 15 minutes to complete
the hack
and the fbi reports that the financial
losses from business email
email compromise accumulated to 1.7
billion
us dollars in 2019 alone
so phishing is very easy um
a 2016 study um pointed out that 46
of surveyed leaders said their companies
fell victim to social engineering
and 50 of the leaders said that their
training towards their
employees was ineffective but why is it
ineffective
why do employees keep pushing the
buttons
for or unopening the mails and letting
people in who they don't know
so i wanted to look into that and how do
we train our employees
so the training techniques um which are
used
uh i i went through case studies and i
went through research and articles
and um the national institute of
standards and technology
they have a um a
special publications report which um
employs uh how to design develop and
implement security awareness program
um while a a
report called teaching johnny not to
fall for fish proved that interactive
games are most successful in raising
awareness
so um in their study they
found that if the goal was to identify
fishing websites they
placed 14 people in three different
groups all
three groups with 14 individuals in each
pardon me
um where group number one was given
existing training material where all
they had to do was to read
uh about fishing websites the second
group was given a
a tutorial plus the third group was
shown
again where they had to play a game on
how to identify efficient websites
and the improvement uh was uh most
success
successful for those who game they were
tested both before and after the test
and um uh and
in 2017 the use of games was yet again
uh proven to be the most successful by
another study by agamdi
um so in my report which i wrote
i made up a fictitious company
who had been subjected to a
um to a penetrate penetration test
and uh and we need to find out what
their own vulnerabilities were
and what we needed to focus on so uh we
decided to go for social engineering
and uh so uh tailgating
which is um a technique within social
engineering it occurs when social
engineers exploit the naivety
and trust of authorized personnel to
gain access to the company's facilities
and the examples of
tailgating uh can be acting as a
delivery driver so
you can pretend to have many boxes in
your arms and then try to
get somebody to open the door for you
because you're not able to do it
yourself
pretending to be a new employee hang
around the brake area to gain trust
which is especially relevant if the gate
the brake area
is around the main entrance acting is
part of the company's regular service
provider
uh if you think about it uh
companies normally use the same business
providers
no service providers uh so it should be
quite easy to dress up as the
electrician and then
get and get themselves in impersonating
an
employee who has lost the access card is
another way of tailgating
the mitigation against tailgating is to
train
employees on the risks of tailgating
hire security guards and receptionists
and train them accordingly
install rfid locks on gates combined
with the detection security systems
which
and the rfid locks they can resemble the
ones
the cards when you get a hotel room that
has an rfid lock
uh and connect these locks to the
identity of the employee or the cards
invest in high quality surveying skier
don't skimp out because you get what you
what you pay for block tailgaters uh
by not holding doors for unauthorized
personnel
and train employees to stay alert if
there are
um strangers uh in the building
and make sure the company badge is free
from personal details it is absolutely
not necessarily to say that
the receptionist called peter and
he is the receptionist
shoulder surfing is another thing it is
another technique
uh it's the practice of watching a
person who is getting money from a
machine filling out a form
in order to find out their personal
information and examples of shoulder
surfing
are on the commute to work during the
lunch break
spying through windows or just an open
office
to mitigate er against shoulder surfing
um you can watch your angles make sure
when you're looking at your screen if
you're typing in a password
or if there's something important on the
screen that nobody can see
the screen create strong and nonsense
passwords
and don't reuse passwords
cover windows invest in an app which
stores password or a password
manager and in the times of
working remotely know who you are
letting into your home
so if you have booked an electrician to
come and fix your lighting
then know that the electrician is who he
say who
or she says uh he is and um
uh even call the company and ask is is
this person who was supposed to come
dumpster diving is a practice of digging
through a company's trash bins or
dumpster to gain information
another man's trust is another man's
treasure
and to mitigate against dumpster diving
you can invest in a microcut shredder
which spreads
everything and with everything i don't
only mean
papers i mean laptops you know discarded
laptops
external hard drives discarded phones
anything where valuable information
can be stored and if you have an
incident response team in your company
then encourage the team to investigate
discarded items
plain sight and theft refers to stealing
information which is visible throughout
the building
it must not be confused with shoulder
surfing as plain sight indicates what is
visible to the naked eye even when the
employee is not there
anything readily accessible and not
locked in is vulnerable to theft
if i'd had a bit more time i would have
uh
indulged you in this article
uh the headline reads hawaii prepares
for unlikely north korea missile threat
if you google that you will have
a very entertaining hour
or two just reading through about what
happened it is
uh nobody was a hurt um
and everything ended well so it's a good
it's a good read
to mitigate against the plain sight and
theft
um make sure
uh your employees can secure their
belongings preferably in a locker where
there is an rfid
lock so they can use the same card to
open up
the rock around the and the doors
um i keep a clean desk
avoid post-it notes um
make sure even the cleaning closet has a
an rfid lock
because if a perpetrator can get into
the cleaning closet
there are lots of chemicals there which
can do a lot of damage on um
on people and potentially victims
uh and guests who come to the company
should register with a momentary rfid
guest id card
tech support and wishing is an
electronic fraud tactic
in which individuals are tricked into
revealing critical financial or personal
information
to unauthorized entities in such
instances scammers use a spoofed
normally local area code this is not
relevant to norway as in norway we don't
use local area codes anymore we only use
mobile phones
um gather information to use towards an
attack that's
what they uh that's what tech support
does um
so an example of that is that um an
employee receives a phone call by
somebody claiming to be from tech
support
and says i'm going to restart your
system please
give me your login credentials and i
will set everything up for you
so train your employees to be vigilant
of such
um also train your employees to verify
unknown incoming calls uh to report
incidences to the incident response team
uh or the it team or the the
or the boss for that instance be
suspicious and refuse to reveal explicit
information over the phone
implore a zero trust policy it is not
necessary that the receptionist
knows what's going on in the meeting but
that the receptionist needs to know
there is a meeting going on is of course
important
and i learned this one a couple days ago
send the
uh the scammer on a wild goose chase
um give them fake information and
just completely waste their time the
federal communications commission
suggests the checklist which i have
posted on the right
hand side um it is uh
of course free to download it and use it
for yourself
in phishing and spearfishing attacks the
classic phishing email scams are when
scammers distribute the same email to
possibly thousands of recipients on a
mailing list hoping someone takes the
bait
while spearfishing builds upon the
information the adversary already has
attained
the fishing and spearfishing attacks
exploit human
vulnerabilities such as fear greed
kindness and stress
so remember that if the person already
knows
something about the employee or
something about you they can use that
information against you which is why you
need to keep your credentials on your
personal information
private couple weeks ago
my fellow students and i were encouraged
to
fish each other and send some phishing
emails we did this
through the social engineer toolkit
which is incali
we had a really fun time the email which
is sent here was sent by my
uh by my fellow student um
and it was and we really had we did have
a good laugh i sent one to my mother as
well i'm pretending it to be from my
sister
and um and vice versa and i had
fun with that they but they fell for it
so the mitigation against fishing and
spear fishing is to evaluate employees
through its cyber risk index
the cri is available
in the references of this pdf and you're
you're able to skim through it yourself
um but basically it uh
it evaluates your vic your the
weaknesses of your employees
so that means you can treat employees
differently and train them accordingly
uh so because there's no use to train
your employees and things they already
know because that's just boring
um test them again after they have been
trained to see if they've learned
anything
um relaxed and fun competitions which
keeps school
of employees cyber risk index can be
announced
in the top three in the monthly
newsletter
um have a comic strip in the monthly
newsletter which focuses on fishing and
spear fishing and social engineering for
that matter
integrate official button to the
software technologies
uh uh where the employees can
press the official it button if they
think that they've been sent a phishing
email
and that then alerts the uh the team
the any or or the i.t
department for that instance
i am oh wow that was quick
sorry sorry i wow i breezed through that
one okay
so thank you very much for joining me on
this talk
my uh on social media um
you can have a look at my uh at the
report you can download it it's on my
linkedin profile
and please add me there uh and
uh also tell me that you've seen me on
grim con because then i know who you are
i'm a bit suspicious of people
on linkedin to be honest
i have to say i love linkedin as far as
penetration testing
i'm not sure i really understand it from
the user perspective as well
location
let's see if i can find the right nina
jones and share uh
will support specialists put in
are you technical support specialist at
ustavol
yes okay yes um
uh just a quick book recommendation
called no tech hacking
and um a game
game recommendation which uh what the
features are
social engineering challenges of other
features
and i will also post a quiz
to uh to discord where you can test your
yourself against social engineering
excellent um we have a couple of
questions if i may nina
and yeah you may want to go ahead and
try your choice
uh but to uh plop on the the webcam
again
and boom again
i ended up tossing it on the bed but um
[Laughter]
no worries all right um first a big
question you referenced your
uh end of first year report a couple of
times
is that available anywhere for us
grammacon attendees as
going above and beyond bonus material
yes
it is available on my linkedin profile
okay uh scroll scroll scroll
featured activity experience education
interests i don't see it all right
i will follow up with you and we'll get
the shared as well
you ran over and grabbed it okay
um yeah i don't
see it in there but that's fine we'll
we'll chat with you we'll get it into
discord so
the important part is you're happy and
willing to share it and we'll get it
over
um as far as a couple other minutes of
banter
uh uh i did want to mention on uh
tailgating
oh gosh this even applies to so a couple
more u.s centric examples
sorry uh i'm a usc and so i can't help
myself
uh us army right we have the common
access card smart card
right uh i say we worked with them i'm
not military
uh has your picture on the front and
it's supposed to be
not just a piece of plastic with a
picture on the front it's supposed to be
validate the smart card aspect but
in practice we all know that when you
show up to a military base you're you
show them yes i have a piece of plastic
with my face on it and they say all
right come on in
but you don't even always need that
right the context
of i'm in a very military looking
vehicle and i am wearing a uniform that
not everybody can just you know buy a
uniform
and i totally left my cac inside i've
heard tales of
exactly that story from multiple people
working just like all right well i'm not
supposed to let you in without a cat
but you go right ahead i've been there
right so this this absolutely happens
even in very secure
environments so not all of the
mitigations can help
if there are armed guards but they don't
actually
validate that people reliably have the
thing that you're telling them to search
for so
this is why we test our controls
sometimes we refer to the offensive
security community as
glorified qa which is fair right
yeah it really is double check jeff i
could i could definitely
uh attest to that um having my fair
share of military uh
common access cards military college
person wasn't in the military i'm
more meet by me that was my uh that was
my uh military
so um so no definitely you have some
who'll check you know they'll check the
front in the back to say hey okay this
maybe
this may look like an actual like uh
common access card then it's like
hey you just checked the front and it's
like then it's like for the people in
the car
you know so you only check the driver
some bases check all four
you know all four people everybody in
the vehicle and you know
it depends it definitely runs the gamut
as far as um
like you said jeff in the us uh in the
united states as far as checking those
common access cards is i've seen the
ones where it's like hey look you know
i looked at it for almost maybe 20
seconds to actually see if it's legit
and then i was just like that okay cool
you know um
i've seen big motions on let me scroll
down and then flip
and like the actual physical uh
display of how they're looking at it is
far more intense than the actual
uh inspection of the card itself right
i am making a big deal of inspecting the
front
and now i will flip and observe the
reverse
side and now i authorize you you are
cleared for
takeoff or injury or whatever that
absolutely happened so
uh thank you for uh this is a great talk
thank you for putting up with the uh
issues we had along the way as well um
any last questions for us before are you
able to uh
step in discord for a bit to share um
that survey link well i shared the
survey link but um maybe that
uh where in your linkedin the paper is
yes i will yes i will do that okay
thank you nina all right uh with that
said uh nina thank you very much
uh for uh joining at grimcon 0x3
and i will get to our next section where
just a couple minutes behind which is
completely fine
thank you for putting up with uh
technical difficulties along the way you
had a little bit of trial by fire
but you um emerged unscathed at least
from our perspective
okay great great talk man i i appreciate
it
it was a pleasure
all right but no absolutely
but let me uh i will briefly share since
i was talking about the uh
imposter syndrome thing before right we
also
i i suffer from imposter syndrome uh
often
as well um i think let me share my
screen now
people think that the side on the left
from your perspective right what i know
is a subset
of what other people know but reality is
we all have different sets of
knowledge absolutely
i still suffer from this today in
certain aspects and everything you go to
it's it's a common thing but honestly
it's one of those things you just
embrace
you know what embrace that you so you're
going to meet somebody who knows more
than you about
us a particular topic you know and
honestly ask them their advice
i found this i found people are more
willing to tell you and teach you what
they know
versus just you know like uh just just
walking in like oh man i don't even
belong here i don't really
i don't even fit in things like that it
happens i've been there i'm still there
i'll go to any conference and i still
feel like man this guy
no this guy he wrote the book on this
what am i even doing talking to this guy
you know like i need to get back in line
and things like that and honestly it's
not like that it's like hey look been
they've done that i still don't know
everything some people that helped me
write this book and that's the big thing
of beyond uh that's the big thing when
you're just
walking into anything doing any
conference uh going to any training
going to
talk to anybody you know everybody has
something to share everybody
has um everybody has something to share
and everybody
definitely you know has that symptom
everybody helps somebody
along the way get to where they need to
go so yep it has something that can help
others so this is one of the few
industries where we regularly share with
everybody else take advantage of that uh
both in terms of receiving the sharing
from others and also
helping others with your own charity
your west
well sorry wesley and i were talking uh
before things even kicked off of like
your unique take on a subject that has
been discussed many times will help
somebody else
your thought process will reverberate
will work nicely with others as well so
please continue passing on to the the
next generation as it were
and it's not like you you move from
noob to expert and there's some magical
transformation
i was talking with uh what uh jay beal
from in guardians last night about this
like
he turned 18 like okay i'm an adult now
so i'm supposed to know what to do and
like
how to adult right yeah we've just been
faking it this whole time buddy sorry
it's a lifelong lesson man you still
look you still learn stuff
today um you know so it's
and honestly like i said before it
doesn't have to be super technical your
talk doesn't have to be super typical i
actually gravitate to a lot of talks
where
how to improve security awareness or how
to like how to do more business
communications for our cyber security
because honestly a lot of this is just a
business so
if you have some of those softer skills
that you know how to
make a presentation or uh make a call
for papers or definitely know like hey
this is what we do in our
awareness program these are helpful
things because awareness programs are
very different across the scale and
honestly if you have
something that works and something
that's been very effective share that