this I'll
okay I'll
okay
us
thanks everybody its quite a pleasure to
be here in Amsterdam again
and to be at hack in the box which is
where my favorite things in the world
I to Tampa to talk to you about this
idea I love
embracing uncertainty because I think in
our industry we have to deal with the
fact that uncertainty is a way of life
for all of us
and on I took this job at Rs a
if the day after the security breach
which some you may be familiar with I
these were interesting time sit AKA
Chief Security Officer jobs
and to talk a little bit about that as
we get into itself
are some things we're gonna talk about
amid talk about
first of all security today I and
you know why should we change anything
at all and I guess the slight kinda
speaks to that
a subject I'm gonna talk about what is
big data and why it should matter tenia
view and what you do here
and died in a minute give some examples
for
in a big data but it is what it is
intended to
healthy lives in time for Q&A if I can
actually see anything
here so on let's talk a little bit about
security today
why change anything at all on cuz it's
all working so well for everybody right
on I guess I'll start with an analogy
how many have you have seen this cell
movie called
Moneyball by any chance with her Brad
Pitt any be seen at
yeah I I didn't have a good
footballer soccer analogy so I decided
to use baseball I know many view in
Europe
don't care about baseball it said see to
me baseball's about as boring as
football
a bite you know it's ninety minutes have
just people
trying to hit a little ball but the day
the movie was kinda funny CNTV side
basically the idea is this
this guy becomes the manager other
baseball team
and it's a losing team they're losing
all their games
and he has to try to make them a better
team the problem with in baseball is
you have to have cash money to do this
and in order to get these high-paid
players
you have to be able to spend lots of
cash spend lots of money to do it
and so mom had how do you do that
how do you do that on what is baseball
tell us
about anonymous well okay along came
this young guy
and he said listen you're looking at it
all wrong
II in baseball
the way judge a player in the old days
was based on how well you hit the ball
so if you hit the ball with an average
above to forty-nine
you are considered to be a really good
baseball player
and you got a higher salary and that was
there were other numbers but that was
the main number anything above 249 you
are good baseball player
you could get millions of dollars and of
course if you had 18 for these players
like the New York Yankees or something
you were you know Maki obviously a good
team in any but it is very expensive
teams again in the movie
this guy couldn't afford to do this
young guy came along he said well
those are the wrong statistics to be
looking at we should be looking at other
statistics like
the amount of times the person gets on
the base
at all the mind not have time they hit
the ball regardless
up whether they get on base and other
factors because
when we add up all these factors it will
mean that the team will win more often
no one had ever looked at the data this
way be four
and no one had ever brought players onto
a team
based on these numbers before so of
course in the movie
what happens is that this manager trust
this young guy
he acquires all these players that have
very low salaries based on these other
statistics instead of this one
the team is very successful they go to
the championship
they don't win but this model
which is actually true story it's called
picada becomes this statistical model
used to
identify the future performance at
sports athletes
not only in baseball but in other on
sports is well and notice to give an
example I pulled this off Google last
night
the column that I is highlighted here
these are two teams the Boston Red Sox
in New York Yankees
art you notice the batting averages you
again that's eight to forty nine then a
show do you notice the numbers are
are all over the place bite their last
three columns
ours an example love other types insists
it is sticks
that are used in the pic %ah to model
the model that
this young guy at the time put together
and you notice that in the rank order
the numbers between the batting average
and these other numbers don't exactly
correlate
right said the top batting average does
not correlate
two other numbers like on-base
percentage and slugging average in
things like that
and in fact if I were to call out a
couple numbers specifically here
are you notice on one of the players the
guy with the top batting average of
$3.10
has and I'll yeah an average shove 814
in one of the other figures whereas one
of the lowest averages which is a top
players
on the Yankees a batting averages 252
has one of the highest ratings overall
so he should really be the highest paid
player
and this model again is used in many
sports today
in golf in in football and in baseball
cell start thinking about this from a
security perspective because
if we can't do these kinds of things in
sports
I and why can't we do these kinds of
things in information security to start
predicting
the future activity of people that we
care about relative to attacks
and things of that sort their other
analogies
site I pulled down the hit list of my
Amazon page last night in
this will give you some insight into the
kind of crap that i buy
but you know Amazon for if thirty forty
years now has been
I figuring out pretty easily if you buy
one thing is forty other things that
you're interested in
and that's a very simplistic model
called the preference engine
grocery stores do another other type
server things do it
I was on my Facebook page last night
it's a picture by
a 13-year-old sign in the middle yeah
but are
one of the things I noticed on the right
is it was serving the an ad
for our martial arts some sort
okay so these two things I was thinking
well is it because somewhere on my
Facebook page i've indicated that I've
been in martial arts for a long time
because you know it also sometimes gives
me scuba diving add cinnamon to scuba
diving rated
you know that's very simplistic but I
also looks further down in my Facebook
page
and I noticed that I had a picture I
love my son
getting his black belt in Taekwondo and
there were other references to Taekwondo
and on the page so again the question is
to what degree
is this type of information data mind as
well whether it's
recognition a different patterns
visually your
just information that's posted as you
know I love this information
is is day to mind is part of an
advertising process
again if this type of work is easily
done
why can't we do this type of work
relative to things we care about and
security
should be very very easy for us to do to
some degree
welp one of the problems is that
security maybe 12-13 years ago for the
most part
moved away from what I would call a
technical discipline
and moved to a discipline in general
that
are requires certainty verses
uncertainty
and certainty goes around the idea of
audit right here's a checklist
follow this checklist everything's okay
you good to go necking manifests itself
in a lot of different ways for example
depending upon where you live maybe you
believe that
ISO 27001 you follow some regimen
you have your check lists are program
you have
some goal for ISO 27001 when you meet
those goals
you got a good security program
according to some peoples estimation
I would argue with that it's a buncha
crap but
I some people feel that that's certainty
on and unfortunately that's what
a level of management in a lot of our
companies believe to be true
right they bring in auditors who will
come and
they'll do an assessment I'll see if
only you were using this
you would be okay or you would be
measurable
in some way when we know that even if we
did everything
here or another regulations we would
still
be vulnerable on even if we're and
countless numbers a vulnerability scans
every day
it wouldn't matter and it's a complete
waste of time for the most part
so certainty is something people want
we've been building certainty in other
ways into our
systems as well if you think about a
classic doctrine in security you know
this whole prevent detect respond think
I'm sure many view from there with how
much money
and time do we spend on prevention
you're trying to make bad things go away
I firewalls IPS AVG all this other stuff
rate
so this is how the bad guys see the
prevent
side of what we're trying to do we spend
a lot of money and prevent
and you know the restive it is sorta
visible cell again
this is where the certainty comes into
the picture
but do you worry about the uncertainty
right what happens to the things that
you can't feel good about here
now you know sorry if this season
bothers anybody 1 I'm really sorry and
give a shit if it bothers you or not
few black invites but they the reality
is that
you know were trying to say well you
know if only I use custom start rules I
do this or do that you know
likes gonna be okay most of this stuff
it doesn't matter I mean
how many as you have had a breach in
your firewall on the last seven or eight
years
I I mean I don't know anybody who has
and if you have you you shouldn't be
working in this industry anymore
me get up go work in a grocery store or
something the
the reality is that this isn't the
problem honey what we need to do is take
all of this stuff
and just drive the cost at effect
because that's not where the problem is
today
so it this is not providing us any
certainty
if we were to put a value on any these
technologies are this approaches and say
well
what percentage do have certainty do I
believe this is gonna protect me
AV your IPS firewall next generation now
where this is that whatever
he it's not gonna do it we've also been
told anybody know who these three guys
are
if they now come on really
silly always does okay at a their
fear uncertainty and doubt we've always
been told in this industry don't sell
what you do based on these three guys
fear uncertainty and doubt I'm here to
tell you that you need to sell
this based on this because the reality
is that people should be afraid
they should have doubts and most
importantly we need to embrace
uncertainty
because we don't know what's going to
happen tomorrow
do you know white new things microsite
did you see the latest Microsoft thing
at in the last couple days I mean we
don't know
white is going to happen with Adobe we
don't know what's gonna happen with any
vendor we don't know I'll
what the latest attacks going to be we
don't know when are companies going to
do in to see their political position
from one day to the next
that's going to create some kinda
situation
where we can be subject to activists
attacks or other types of attacks
uncertainty is something we need to
embrace
this is guy eat Nate Silver Nate Silver
is the guy from that movie
remember that part that the young guy
played in the Moneyball they talked
about
is actually based on a real guy called
Nate Silver &
he has a book in in the book there's a
quote is Cesar recognize the omens
he just didn't think they applied to him
okay
he was getting some information
somewhere that somebody's gonna come and
staff
but it wasn't listening and we have this
information to
we just need to to learn how to deal
with it in some way
so there is a price that we're gonna pay
for all this chaos in turbulence
in our industry and in what we're doing
but we have to learn to embrace it we
have to learn to accept the fact that
it's a way of life
and I think that if we accept that if
you don't do anything this year read
this book
because it will help you understand that
we need more data
we need more analytics and we need to
accept the fact that we need to move out
at this limited world in which we view
things
into a bigger world now part of that
is starting with some some ideas
the first idea is that threat models
need to change
when we think about the adversarial
landscape
how much intelligence do we really have
about who the attackers are
and what they really want everybody says
I A and all this stuff
what you doing about it how many have
you have
a model that's implemented in your
security program
that's dynamic that really looks at the
adversarial landscape
and can link the adversarial landscape
to specific campaigns in attacks
if you have that and you're doing it and
your updating it on a constant basis
then you get
but is if you just are saying is sitting
there saying well
yeah I know about all that stuff but you
actually haven't implemented
and intelligence base process to
understand this and you not doing it
okay if you're not bringing any
information
and tracking specific groups and
starting to understand how they operate
for real then you're not doing this okay
and it's easy to just talk about this
but it's it's another thing to do it
and insiders is is is really tricky
especially if you're a net
a year a multinational company
there's venues like to talk about me she
stayed in all their survey points to one
country all the time when
when they talk about it publicly arm you
there was a recent to
mandiant reports APT 1 I'm sure love you
I saw that report people who have been
Traci
adversaries for some time familiar with
all the indicators a compromise in every
port
actually have a preview of the year the
next mandiant report on APT 2d
you wanna see it and they wanna see a
okay this is it
I'm just kidding it's not really a
Elton John in the corner for those see
the town you know who it is
alright guys have no sense a humor SP
Amsterdam
alright
alright so how do we start looking at
data differently
there is data I have bad guys that we
understand this is the security model
that we understand
from the old days these guys show up at
your door
we know they're bad it's pretty obvious
rate to get guns in
you know they look me and that's the
model that were used to that's what I P
S Navy does
we already have the signature we have a
rule
it says look for guys with guns it's a
finite dataset
with known questions its easy everybody
understands that right
the model that we're going for however
is a different one
the different one is that there's
everybody's dressed the same
in this case like Elvis Presley and
there's thousands have them but one of
them
has a bomb strapped to their chest and
all we know is that
everybody's dressed like Elvis Presley
or sooner we think that's all we know
but the reality is that there are other
data points we have that we haven't
looked at before
similar to the baseball analogy and sell
rather than a finite dataset we have
infinite amounts of data potentially
available to us that we need to bring in
we have unknown questions tomorrow it's
the elvis impersonators the next day
it's something else
we have till be agile and learn how to
ask those questions
and then we have to have a way to
process this information
so that means technology and it means
skills
that maybe we don't have on our security
teams
everybody still trying to figure out
who's going to do them our reversing for
them
their new skills you need beyond that
there's a lot to talk in this industry
about this idea of the kill chain
I'm sure you've heard that a thousand
times already till I
I stole this slide from Greg Hoglund it
used to be HB Gary on
however you want to think about APT's
think about this idea I've
adversarial phases right some sort of
intelligence-gathering are planning an
attack
creation exploit delivery exploitation
command-and-control actions on its hands
might do some
phases have an attack 7 820 pick a
number of phases it doesn't matter
whatever model you use what's
interesting to me from the Big Data
perspective
is that as your defenses fail
as the preventive solutions that you've
implemented fail
the cost to you increases
okay that cost could be you running
around with your hair on fire
trying to figure out what's wrong
calling it: people calling your friends
everywhere
trying to understand what's going on or
true losses to your organization
terms money intellectual property top
secret information whatever it is that
you
are responsible for so that's that top
red triangle there
as you know once the adversary moves
into your environment
the automation level decreases generally
and now you're dealing with more
hands-on keyboard
lateral movement net commands different
types of activities said
that potentially are more visible to:
even if you can't see everything inside
those activities because if encryption
or other types in
obfuscation techniques there's a level
of visibility that's potentially there
and that's where the opportunity is for
us with
big data because it's in that sweet spot
where the circle is that we have to
decide
what resources do we need to apply here
in terms of acquiring data and in terms
of analyzing that data
so what is that University information
that belongs
their internal to our organization
and externally in terms of collaboration
with people you know within a the sector
that you belong to for example
government financial services energy
telecom high-tech whatever it is you
deal
and then bring that together in a
machine-readable form in some
a timely manner because time really
matters here
one of the problems that we have is that
suppose you you doing what you do and
now you say well I yeah I i wanna do
this I want to get better
at this gap it you know in this little
circle here
where's the money come from
me can't is going to give give give me
five million euros
I don't know how that works in your
organization that doesn't work well in
mine
arm a you seen diagrams like this before
this is not to illustrate the hard on
the outside
soft and chewy on the inside thank this
is still a straight
where the money goes go back
and ask the question where do you spend
money on security
really decompose that budget and take it
apart and say
what do we spend on for a better defense
where we spend on
EV whether we spend on IPS
whether we spend on everything that
looks like a preventive solution
the big Wall around the picnic castle
there
the town add up all that money
and then ask yourself what percentage is
success
what percentage of certainty does that
provide you
that's that that's interesting enough
on then ask yourself in terms of
detection
which might be the little towers that
are around in the big tower there
how much you spending to detect
at the lateral movement for example
how much you spending to respond because
in the moment when you realize okay
there's been an exploit there's been a
delivery have some sort there's
command-and-control activity
how much money do you have to deal with
that part of it
and then to do the analytics and the
trend analysis in the intelligence work
that you need to do
after you discover all this
do that math and see how it shakes out
now tell you how it shakes out based on
some research that we did
that eighty percent have budgets go to
prevention
and this is based on he with the call
global 2000 companies about 250
companies we had when he's
big you know research firms do this
fifty percent for monitoring so the tech
side
and then 5 percent for response
now keep in mind a lot of things going
to prevention right you know the
vulnerability scanning configuration
all this kind of stuff security training
all love that sell now but
what is the right balance if you were to
say I don't like that
because I don't give I don't think a
deeper sense the right number what is
the right number if you wanted to start
thinking well I could use big data to
solve some of these problems when it
what what he thinks the right number
and there's no right answer here because
it's gonna be a different answer for
each review
well i i don't know yeah let's suppose
just for the sake of argument
it was 130 each
how do you get there from here you can't
just go from
you 2012 2013 and make that change
that's not gonna happen it's it's a big
transition
in terms have the way you do things in a
lot of different ways by
on you know obviously it is something to
think about
in terms of you know rethinking your
security budget somebody needs to think
about this
alright so let's talk about big data
because
big data is really how you started
dressing the part in this equation
which is uncertainty
so I've been there you know this job for
two years and
one of the things that I had to figure
out after this security breaches
saddam how do we stop doing traditional
security work
where I work on it was classic
environment where
on your people were running at ISO 27001
running at a lot of different compliance
functions doing
you know vulnerability scanning doing
everything that you might imagine in a
security program
you know and NY and then what happens
cell what do you what do you start to do
differently
you know in in the if you look at some
other that again a lot of the money was
in that prevent bucket
there are things that you stop doing
right away for example he stopped doing
ISO 27001 across-the-board
on not meeting that you don't tried it
have good security policies and tried it
make them successful but the point is if
somebody says well we
we need to be ISO 27001 across the world
just because why when I could use that
money for other purposes
so I think there are four areas that I
started to focus on initially in terms
and looking at how
I could get better view into how
I you could use big data the first was
security management
how can I get better visibility into
everything that's happening
you know it especially in terms have the
behavior of users the behaviour devices
things of that sort and look for
standard deviations from good behavior
now looking for bad so much to me we
already knew how to look for bad
as far as a new but looking for for
deviations from
good and the second area was in fraud
we had done you know we have a lot of
businesses where we have to deal with
fraud and so how do you how do you do
that
and the third area was an on
authentication
and dad you know user ID's passwords in
what constitutes add the speedo
authentication events and other factors
like that
and the fourth was how we track the
controls
in our in our infrastructure and drives
a control structure to provide
intelligence to everything else
and the talk a little bit about on all
that
when you do this you've got a set some
specific goals for yourself
rate because imagine when you go to
accompany anyone to change everything
that
that they're doing he can't just dumb go
in and done
you know say I'm gonna change everything
they have to get on board with some
basic ideas cell
there were some ideas that we put out
there the first was that I wanted to
have visibility into everything
if you think about the way we view data
and security
what are some things that we use in 8 to
look at data right
logs I but the logs that we were viewing
in security were like security logs
I Windows server logs you know either
takes a server logs
network device logs and and they're all
supposedly security specific
but if if you work with logs at all but
there's not much in them really and the
need you know they have a limited amount
data so we had to go out and say what
constitutes that University information
that I showed you on that kill chain
slider earlier that is useful and it
goes beyond security lots its business
transaction logs
full packet data it's its information
from
you know asset management systems HR
systems travel systems
things like that which means creating
data definitions for those environments
and finding ways to parse that into a
data warehouse I'll talk about
data warehouse in a bit more later um
actionable intelligence we had to figure
out what information
we need now and then what information we
could wait a little bit more for
an of any view use Mike security
information and event management systems
like
the when we have our time the other
vendors but they're all slow
don't week anyway now but I mean they
are you know and and the problem is that
like okay there's things that you need
to know right now
and then there's things that that you
know
are you can wait a little bit cell again
the paradigm shift wise
how do we organize that data in a way
that is actionable out talk about that
too
agility was important because we need to
be able to change things
right right new parsers rate new data
definitions wherever
on introduce new languages use
open-source
we wanted to do all that stuff and we do
we want to be locked into any vendor
solutions including our own
on and centralize incident management
10 that things that we also we're
dealing with was the fact that when we
did have our hair on fire
within wanna be dependent another group
for information if that makes sense to
you and I think if you encounter this
but when you
are in the middle evidence sent to run
around and try to get the network people
to talk to you are the windows people or
whoever
very hard especially if you speak
security and they speak networking IT
year whatever
doesn't always work out very well on
there are other problems so let's talk a
little bit about the visibility problem
on disjoint sets
if you have in infrastructure that's
grown up over time
it doesn't work well together rate for
example if you doing logging
may have locking up host and network
and different types of environments
where if you try to bring data together
just look from for example from layer 3
to layer 7
you'll see that just the definitions
have certain elements in those datasets
don't match up very well there's no
normalization
user ID is is a different thing in
different datasets
and that creates bottlenecks if you
think about it when I go to write a
query
the first thing that has to happen is I
have to resolve those differences in the
data schema
say the resolve them at the time of day
to capture
why resolve them at the time that the
query or I resolve them some other time
somewhere in there
right when do I do that so so this is a
problem
any in you as you start adding more data
for example for packet capture
host in memory forensics and things of
that sort
it becomes a much greater problem with
you different storage silos imagine if
you're geographically dispersed
organization we have multiple data
centers
on and you can't do this over over I
mean if you have all the ban within the
world it's very tricky to do this
so their architectural considerations
that you have to think about
relative to how you acquire data what a
pup reminding occurs on that data
where normalization occurs and what data
schema look like see have apples to
apples entities at the right time
and this is a fundamental problem that
needs to be resolved
in terms data management when you
thinking about Big Data
to other problems have to do with event
management and search
historically cm has not been optimized
to very large data searches
in the same with search tools like
Splunk you can't
on say you'll go look at this 100
terabytes of data and give me a result
in an ad hoc search it's very hard to do
I have you ever tried on especially
unstructured data
so again you know how do you create a
situation
where you can have manageable rules
running manageable parsing
and things of that sort and we can set
that up is part of that infrastructure
and were searching makes sense and then
of course there's the issue I love
intelligence I'm sure many if you are
you participating in the intelligence
life cycle in some way or another
where you're getting you no idea at a
basic level for example indicators a
compromise
you maybe you're pulling bad IP address
lists or domain lists from somewhere
you maybe have access to very privileged
data maybe you take the lead layer 7
I data you regarding now where or file
integrity data from somewhere
that's great but to look at that data
at the end of the life cycle not so much
use as as taking it at the inception
right when you're doing full packet
capture or analyzing lots or business
data
it would be great to join that data
right at the time he captured
right again how do you organize this in
such a way that you can
you can get that done so these are
problems that you have to solving
and you know there is a critical and you
need a road map to be able to deal with
this
from a process perspective one of the
things you have to ask yourself to is
do you wanna run a security operation
center where do you wanna run something
more than that
on act I have the interesting position
in this job
mind to be able to visit a lot of
companies
you know I it's one of the great things
about this job and I get to see where
people deal
the good the bad and the ugly and
you know a lot of people are very happy
that they have a sock and it they should
be
but a lot of sock Sox are set up
to wear they have a %uh a tool of some
sort
and the way for that tool to pop up
something look at this
look at this look at this you know boom
boom boom boom
and the problem is that if you think
about how Sam is organized
most sims are looking at some
correlation a firewall
and and lock events based on
known signatures see you dealing with
things that we already knew any
the attackers already knew and
correlated events based on that
now I'm not saying that for certain
classes have
attacks that's not useful information
for example exception to authentication
events and meets in
rules are very interesting in that
regard but
if your team is looking at certain types
in the vents
related for example to web application
problems
I it's not necessarily very useful
compared to
the exploit space that's out there cell
arm a lot of that stuff that goes on
there
could either be pushed out to somebody
else to do.
more cheaply I'll course if somehow
the cost given out of it but I call it
waiting for a smack on the head
compared to the other area where you
really more focused on
taking them the battle to the bad guy
you know hunting for malware
hunting for its you know things on your
network in some sort
I'll understanding the threat
environment the adversarial space and I
talked about
and gaining those core skills now I
realize that
some you work in small organizations
where you like how I
how do i do all this stuff well that's
why you need to find partners that can
help you with some
this and the we have a pretty large
security team but we still find
certain skills are difficult to maintain
and we've
we look very closely defy to find
and there's so many people here in this
room to find people that can do
this work for us when you start thinking
about intelligence
you've got it realize that there's a
journey to get there you can't go from
not using external intelligence to be
you know some kind cyber profit as I
call it
and I put some examples in here for
you're sort of how and another hard to
see in the back but
you for example you're an ad hoc user
Intel have intelligence
if you find out about exploits by
reading Computerworld
or some sorta publication and no offense
taken journalists and around this just
you know if that's how you find out
about exploits well
okay got some work to do on
in the US we have these things called
ice axe incident sharing and analysis
centers in these are collaborative
and cities among trusted partners within
a sector says
example the bank's working with each
other energy companies and so on
they tend to share information more
readily about things that are happening
to each other
cell maybe you're getting that
information but you're not necessarily
acting upon it many proactive way
if you're an end-user the information
you might be taking this information
and inserting it into your tools and ask
your tools to look for this in some way
you look for an indicator look for some
signature pattern or or whatever it is
that you
you got your hands on in some way on
if you're a creator I've information
you've
you you've actually on the other side of
the kill chain where your synthesizing
attacks you
discovered an attack somewhere and
progress perhaps
endured looking at the end that your
understanding tools tactics and
procedures the adversary
and your crew and you're contributing
that information to the community you
belong to
so you actually creating intelligence
that you share with others
are you writing your own rules
synthesizing data
and cyber profit it's more a joke than
anything by
this is where the EV companies come to
you they get information from you and
and they make believe it's their own
information
90 this is kind of the night chart bite
arm I I and I don't usually use lights
like this but I put this in here and
I'll send this to anybody who wants it
because I use this internally to I
judge where we are with certain advanced
capabilities
relative to the not the sock but the
other I think that we're doing
and you have to decide what's right for
you
I'll when you start to use big data and
you start to evolve certain capabilities
like forensics
advance incident response having a
threat intelligence team
and so on what are the capabilities that
you want for example in threat
intelligence
under Advanced I have detailed campaign
analysis
what does that mean well to me what that
means on my team
is that we have people that are
dedicated to analyzing
email attacks that's all they do the
analyze email attacks
the only thing they deal and then when
the analyze those attacks
they try to you connect the dots between
those attacks
and specific adversarial campaigns
and those campaigns are identified by
campaign code numbers
that's that's real work any and and they
work with other special teams
post forensics network forensics now
where reversers
some of which are employees Avars some
of which are
people such as yourselves to do this for
you know either is independent
consultants or as part of the company
right cell where do you need to be on
this
depends depends on if you your company
makes use
now you need to be at the bottom that
this chart but
if you're if you work in a year in
intelligence
intelligence service for the government
you probably do need to be at the bottom
this chart
weird teams are the best teams and I
agree with that
I this is a picture of what my weird
team looks like
on before the
the breach was just the box on the far
right
so that was the old sock that's what it
look like tier 1 tier 2
24 by 7 eyes on glass hit you on the
head
have a nice day okay now lots a special
teams
now Reversi cause our origin
determination
on we do a lot of social media work
internally and externally terms have
attack surface profiling
all the social media information comes
into my data warehouse
and it's analyzed against all odds the
internal data that I have
arm we do a lot of um actually bution
we do a lot of reviews internally
high-value targets
and try to make connections between
campaigns and high-value targets
we constantly evaluate how r tools are
working
and look at what tools we should be
emphasized
or what tools we should spend more money
on
and we have people that are updating
parsers in rules and and things of that
sort
this is a notional architecture
what goes into this first of all the
idea of collection
you have to commit to some idea of
collecting data
right arm
one of the tricky parts has been to move
away from this idea disparity collection
to say we're gonna collect everything on
a prioritized list I've got a list
about a dozen categories data that I
wanna call act
I don't know how to get there from here
on some of them yet
I'm gonna give you an example SAP data I
don't know how to get there from here
yet
I mean I know how to look at SAP logs
and I since I love you already know how
to do that too that's that's the easy
part
but how do you get in the middle are
those transactions
and look for deviations from good
because it's hard for business people to
explain to me
what a bad SAP transaction I mean it
some other obvious
but rate when things seem to be going
well
I'm not sure right so these are think
these are challenges but but but
I have a list and I want everything on
that list and I i so I
I have the I'd collection architecture
data warehouse Apache Hadoop
okay why well scale-out
n-tier architecture with inexpensive
equipment
I can add storage to the end of time to
it
and processors to the end of time night
it keeps killing at Forever
I can add full context text searching
with
Lucy I can add Esper
I can add all kinds of cool stuff to it
and I can add
cots vendor solutions to it
I can plug it into my Sam I can plug it
into
you know the art say stuff that I have I
can plug it into third-party
vendor solutions that I have on
and that's cool and with the Hadoop
stuff I can do a lot of the pre
mining that I talk to you about I can
set up a cluster
I give it a buncha tasks and i can tell
it to run to the end of time
and and and this is important when you
thinking about large amounts of data
right with never we talked earlier about
the fact that well how do I integrate
information when you're dealing with
hundreds of terabytes of data
it's easy if you start dedicating HDFS
clusters to ease say keep going keep
doing this keep doing this
and you know the good thing about that
environment as I can just keep snapping
in
additional libraries additional
capabilities to it
but that's where I'm storing months in
years
data log data and meta-data from the
full packet environment
business data and so on real-time
environments a bit different
in that environment that's where I need
the full context
a full packet information but you know
as you know on a
on a on a large network you keep for
packet data too long
cell you know they are you dealing with
you maybe a seven to 14 day horizon
but you still want a common meta-data
infrastructure that's normalized
with all your other data so that when
you search for something
as an analyst you don't have to know and
I like he had a la Torre
full packet artifacts you're searching
for something you get a result
and then it's only when you dig into the
data that you realize
all and looking at reconstructed for
packet sessions are looking at a lot
artifact
from I'll use something else does that
make sense
he on and there's other plugins he could
do the if you see on the day
on the far right this is box it's his
ass a criticality
the idea is how do you start connecting
the dots between this environment
and understanding if you've got pick a
number
100000 IT assets which have those are
the most important ones
which have those fell out of patch or
configuration management
and have that be yet another
intelligence feed into the process
because that's the way he should just
read that is just intelligence
feed any to speed up a little bit here
ok you get the idea
so there's a lot of stuff you could do
it this me now you can create
yeah I'm have an example here they just
do together
for name pipes %ah you many view
probably familiar with this idea but
on for example in this environment
%uh distances right outta my environment
you wanna the things we look for is
weird I named pipes
okay very easy to create parsers that
just
just basically catalog I I don't know
what's bad by the way
i mean to you I don't know what all
valid name
pipes are maybe someday you do because
you're smarter than I am in
can prolly name every single file in the
Windows
operating system I don't know but and
Hannah these things
but is very easy for example to at least
call out things on the network so he is
a very simple parser
you know here's how it works basically
just you
offset a few bites okay figure out the
name there blah blah blah
success capture some packets and then
bone you've got
you know a list the stuff here right now
again
I could have a parser like this running
till the end of time
if in this sock nobody would ever look
at it
II in the new world order that I've
created
on people do you actually look at this
so I have rules that call outs
differences here and differences are
things
like this
me again there might be something like
that for real and
you know Windows I don't know maybe bite
arm
maybe not so this is something worth
investigating
on the other is that on
what we're starting to do is look at
Esper
for complex event processing the data
warehouse
where once we understand using this
parser
for good make okay so we see all these
pipes
we overtime we know what they are you
know we see number of hits
when we see now c3 hits on pipes slash
lol bank it triggers it standard
deviation
now 33 may not seem like a big number
for you but three for this would be an
acceptable number
one would probably be acceptable number
whereas in other categories maybe it's
twenty-year thousand who knows you know
I don't know
it's with data scientists do figure that
shit out
now but the point is that that these are
things you do
me we we haven't so we have a lot of
stuff like that that we're working on is
just a
you know had how to figure this stuff
out and as you
look at this this problem you need is a
very simple problem like this
i've seen this type of stuff on the wire
then you go well okay you know what else
would you add to this beyond just the
simple
data science and looking for deviations
like going well okay
now I can parse all the pipes now I can
look for deviations from
a population of good you know for
example here's
you know here's a week or day %um prolly
days enough data for this environment
here's a day
information here's a deviation now how
can I
eliminate false positives in that
environment you hear some examples
wat listing on external intelligence
right where you know you put out there
has anyone seen
yes you get answers back yes i've seen
yes and then you would either blacklist
waitlisted
based on that many guys do this all the
time stuff
and and so on
there's more to this I in the Big Data
box
I mean what else is in there there
everything is going to transform because
we've only been talking about like
incident response in
really basic stuff like that but if you
think about it
authentication has to transform you the
fried stuff
although this has to has to go cell
you know there's this whole life cycle
that the we've had in security did
we've kinda been doing in silos that I
wanna see converge in some way
and I don't know how to do it yet
because I can't build
too many things off of the reservation I
get in trouble so we have to
we have to have products to do it but
just some ideas rate we know that
username and password is gonna die soon
which would die tomorrow on two-factor
authentication
who knows where that goes I don't know
we use your phone your eyeballs here
and which use but I I do like the idea
of some combination of elements coming
into play
you know we looked a lot it's different
things you're looking at speedo
authentication events geo related
collectivity if you know you login here
than here than here you know
it is just too too fast be you know any
Jews
your terms ground speed and things like
that arm
obviously there are other factors
related to yawn integrating the travel
system I mentioned to you
looking at the HR system we've done some
interesting work around
an affinity your problems with USB
sticks
in some places you can make them go away
effectively
but in other areas it's very hard to
make them go away
but you know we've done some interesting
data related to a senate work
internally related to authentication
events
USB and certs and then looking at people
that are contractors with and number of
days left on their
on their contract and correlating that
data in real time and creating a lurks
around that
very interesting just just that fact
popping up as an alert and then matching
that with
hosts who's based technologies gives you
really interesting insight into things
are going on but
you take these other data I think if you
can imagine
using this in a risk-based
authentication model in the brain that
and that could be good
arm fraud is another one you know
I know how many view match website is
part of your job
you can't do like web application
firewalls tried a
you deal with their you know the top 20
deal with
your rules based approaches it's a
feeling strategies you now
arm they the way to deal with it is
probably more the whole
you crowd based analytics rate you that
1000 5000 web pages you can't have rules
for all of them
the change constantly and the attackers
will hit them
right after you figure out a new way to
plug the hole so
but if you look at at crowds of people
coming to a website in the behavior of
those clouds in the car Netflix streams
others cock others crowds
you can get a good sense of what good
behavior looks like
and then use analytics to look for
deviations in that type of behavior
and it's reasonable to look at that and
yes some ideas here
you know velocity paid sequence for
example what is a sequence in activity
based on
thousands and thousands I've click
streams
in terms of the velocity up the other
check out effect
or or other browsing event or something
I'll you know and when you combine that
with origin or
other contextual information from full
packet
you know HTTP or HTTPS if you're in the
middle of clickstream
yeah it becomes very very interesting on
and again you know that can also lead
you to either
views into other types of problems like
man the middle on
man in the browser type of type attacks
and your last disorder this holy grail
which some people call governance risk
and compliance
I think today the issue there is what I
call analyst prioritisation
I mention to you briefly this idea how
acid intelligence on I am like the
anti-foreigner ability scanning guy it's
not that I don't believe in doing it
it's just that I think people do it and
rely too much on it
on you know every week when you do it
the numbers change
and you you can't get it. to to fix it
you know never be fixed properly so I
don't know what the numbers mean
I mean if I showed you my numbers you
probably think I was terrible
my job and I know what your numbers look
like but you know they did
like this every week up and down and
sideways right
what I want my people to focus on his
priorities Asian
may they should be focused on the most
important assets that are under attack
right now
and get it. to deal with those in a
timely manner everything else can
consort await and 'it's got too much
going on at like to think we're all I
till this and that and
Six Sigma Black Belt buddy it doesn't
work out very well
so this is a life cycle on trying to
optimize and data
will help us optimizer life cycle
I think I've got about four minutes left
sign actually gonna shut up
and and try to end this little bit arm
I know you some love you may say well I
don't know how any of this applies to my
job
on I will tell you that everything you
do is going to be driven by
big data whether you're I youjizz
he an analyst ya doing now reversing
where the responsible for an incident
response team with your and my job is
SSL
you've gotta think that everything's
moving in that direction
more data is better he really is
and obviously there are security
implications with big data to for
not only for what we do in security but
the business is going in that direction
to
with what they're doing with big data
but they do believe that
a great opportunity for us is to not be
behind the curve
rate you know I think this you know this
site is kinda
you know my story on this and then if if
we act like we're a cure and other
trends
nighty you know there's no excuse for a
so you know we we need to embrace
big data we need to embrace uncertainty
and we need to find ways to
to deal with it is a part of our job and
you we've done some innovative things
internally I think you'll see
other companies that are doing this is
well I would encourage you to look into
it
it does require investment requires a
commitment to architecture
it's very geeky technical data
scientists work when you first get into
it but it's really fine
and a you know as you can see the
vendors are all over it till
on I participate in a white paper with a
buncha people on this
which I'd maybe can get on our site or
just email me at now
by and it's not a vendor stupid white
paper it's just a vendor agnostic white
paper
but I feel free to you know paying near
download it if you want it
and I think we have about two minutes if
anybody wants to ask any questions
you
it looks to me that and
that you're trying to get ahead of the
curve you doing a good job but your
ask you to Division a very large company
you suffered a major breach
so you had things going for you to get
this arranged within your company
but in my organization I can never see
this happening
and it scares me a bit too you say dat
like
products like and trust the NetWitness
not helping you in this case
so you you say go out and try to find
partners but
hook who can do this for me who can
build me system like
a so
arm in and I could name companies
it won't but look more and more
I guess the way I would answer the
question is this: on
the managed security service providers
that today and I'm sorry if I offend
anyone out here
but the managed security service
providers that are out here
that are just doing managed firewall
NIDS
they're going to start feeling pressure
from olive you
who were saying you know the shit does
doesn't cut it right they're gonna have
to step up and provide more advanced
services so we see
in the US I i mean here in in in the
Netherlands we've seen service providers
step up and say
we we are going to provide these
advanced services and
and some of them are on I I was just
another country where I met a service
provider who's doing it this one here
and the Netherlands he's doing it me in
the US there's a bunch that stepped-up
it it's it's like everything else to
your point
I mean the larger companies for the last
two years have adopted
this approach to Big Data and it's gonna
take time for the wave to hit
but you know my goal is not to tell you
that a few not doing this you're behind
as much is
this is something for you to look
forward to in to move towards
overtime thank you yeah
I A T so I'm sure what a big companies
who approach big data analytics and
security for the first time
they bled as they try to figure this out
he give us any warnings or any
up was to trade of putting too much
focus year which the
dark side a big data as we begin to
approach this
yeah for sure I mean on yes certainly we
bled
and I some of my peers who have done
this on their own
II you know because if you think about
it if you were trying to do this two
years ago
one of the problems he faces you could
go out and buy
you know for example jean-eric big data
analytic tools
they're out there from vendors or you
could get all the open source stuff
bring it and make the hardware
investments necessary to do this but
then
you basically have a blank slate rate is
no
security in front so now you have to
figure out
all love that quote security analytics
and and that's no small task so that's
why
that's a great point I mean so that's
why I think
it is a balance between saying what is
your tolerance for being on that edge
today
or starting to work with vendors that
that get in that space in it's a tricky
decision
I think the way I'd always position it
to people is
there's a plumbing aspect to it that
can be dealt with today to some extent
in other words there are things that
we're doing in the back end at this
relative to data capture
our database management things of that
sort
that are eminently fixable today
regardless of the analytic space
the analytic space is is
is basically nascent I think that
there's a lot happening
over the next three years you can see
that explode in terms the vendor space
but if
in the analytic space it's going to be
folks such as yourself
that you know in some cases have very
advanced skills
and are comfortable with command-line
and comfortable with
you know taking a system that has some
basic capabilities in and
advancing yourself
yeah I'm I think about ING we had
another
a lot of problems this week with the
online banking
and one of problems was that we had at
the end you must have been dedust
and application there so am does
does attack on on that and people were
trying to login
am nine-g_ and that made and you stop
working
so my question is how would you go about
fixing their and why are the banks to
death right now
ready so I this I can't speak to any
particular organization
but I'll Diaz is a problem
day organizations should be able to
address depending upon
different aspects a you know did clearly
there are
layer 3 and four solutions that are well
known to everybody in
are out there there are they are seven
solution providers that have become very
very good at dealing with this
when we're talking specifically about
the iranian attacks like the other bill
to
3 type attacks that's an interesting
animal because
are the adaptive nature them and some
other
service providers shall mention hear
about the guy
talk about you on private have struggled
obey
to adapt to some of those attacks
I think I'll what's interesting there is
that arm you have to look beyond
the classic dedust provider for some of
these were advanced e das attacks to
either there are some providers that are
now looking at
behavioral based modeling I love I've
that environment
as an alternative to classic detox
protection and that's something I would
consider
in other words not just treated as a
network device based on analyzing
NetFlow
datagrams at layer 7 to do that
protection which is how
one of the major providers does it today
and arguably has done it fairly well
except for these recent attacks
by there is another approach which is
more based on
deep packet inspection and layer 7
behavioral analysis
I think that's a good alternative
approach for this type of thing I've
always thought that that
plus threat intelligence would be a
really good approach for
for the dust protection there's a player
that's doing that right now
I think that I can say that ninety
vendor names
thank you very much Eddie will now break
for
coffee break so please join me in
thanking Eddie for lodging
this year's conference