Google
okay I'll
yes and
good
hmm iraq
no yes so
this is the page fall Liberation Army
we're in the business love are showing
which really inside are the neglected
its
though the Intel processor out we're
going to start with the philosophy why
we do this
because this has been feelin a research
in our lab
and you as you can see it's turtles all
the way down
and then I will hit
a the actual details just about halfway
through the talk
no instructions were harmed
in the making of a stalk a our
great thanks to of the wonderful Intel
hardware that
up allowed us to have all this fun out
we're going to talk about touring
completeness
in people really over
value during completeness you can do
interesting computation with the systems
that are not touring complete
is just that Turing complete is the most
genial you can do
and it's really computation Weiss
something like the root shell so if you
can prove
about power a few instructions that
together they
make up a Turing machine that means you
can do anything there
that you can do with the regular
processor see memory
reading rating wise I wish
are we have the better Skeel a to talk
about exploits
and you know the kind of interesting
unexpected computation
but so it goes but can of I
the slogan for the day is that import
is a program any input
that is sufficiently complex eased
really just like the bytecode to
the code that out process is this import
and
every exploit isn't exercise in
programming that
weird a virtual machine that you find
up in yet art and
it really just doesn't matter
what its input our introductory example
he is up elf meta-data
serving as a program
that can actually arbitrary rewrite
memory so if you think of how you load
your
code I you've got I
this symbol table and
you've got their location entries and
together
the are TLD up
reads them and based on what you find
in the symbol table occasionally entries
it rewrites
your code and your day so
you she one piece of code reading the
input
and the other I
writing into memory so you ask yourself
what happens if the writing would go
right on top of the data that is being
read
we'll are if you've been through a
traditional computer science course
this should remind you of the table the
Turing machine there is some
finite state automaton that reads and
writes to the tape
and the condom for the tape are the
program and
the compensate the tape at the same time
get transformed
and this is the most to a
computationally capable thing
are which is up like unto a modern
processor
and so you ask yourself what happens
if you take the symbol table entries in
the relocation entries
Witcher just I she structures that are
embedded
in the binary and I
you right a program Dean
these structures a low
since I you she
you can read and you can write at into
but the area that your next period will
come from
the apt up Mike actually give you all
sorts of interesting
loops & brain chips as the
really cater goes through their
allocation entries
and of patches up the code %uh that's
not loaded
at the address out where it was meant to
be loaded
I if you're using flr them
are you know that's this is how your
program gets reelected
and there has been of at great bit Cove
up wonderful hacker research in
using this for a full-scale Shan in
using this as a Sr it OVA
on the Packer over code
up but I the
basic know the most basic observation is
that
those relocation entries content for
arithmetic
so they cover all the different types
you see the types
in the table on the right and I that
type drives
either mm copy or remember you're right
with edition Aki en la cops
Ian the appropriate data structures
so you see the structure of the bytecode
in the input you she that this
type bite a in blue actually drives
for something like a virtual machine
the end these up on relegation types
are likely implementations of the what
code that virtual machine
and this was done by up redecoration
fear of Beck's
in our lab if she's here I can see
I'll have her wave you no okay have
its and you can see that I E N you can I
see the tools
a.m. the I details of how all this is
implemented
in her report Satori on get a cop but
the takeaway is that
book once the data is complex enough
it's really just like the bytecode
and so I it doesn't matter
whether that meta-data is a red
by software or buy hardware
so we're going to show this the very
same effect
4 up the processor
for the in terms of the processor that
you know you would I
imagine to be a part way microcode
partly silicon
and so who's this guy
he is regarding this are kettles
swinging on its chain over the hearth
a.m.
because at that little a blow off steam
coming out to
all the cattle which what is named after
him
a unit affinity the unit have energy
this is James what we're
I he was curated for it by his
elders for just wasting his time looking
at Campus
and of course keep thats and
out we're going to push this as far as
it will go and hopefully
you know when we're on into an obstacle
too high for us other people will a
takeover
missus somewhere in siberia as you can
imagine
I well and will let you build the snow
plow
that can get through call those
am still picks so
consider the x86 mm you
people art to what to think of this as
some sort of a lookup table
virtual to physical hot and
just it's just like a look lookup table
up on the hardware
it's not it takes
complex data and performs complex logic
want
it's got States and transitions
everything that's got states and
transitions
is something like a processor may be a
weird one
it's not comment on it's a machine in
the show you ask yourself
we'll if this thing takes complex
input data can be programmed with that
input data
you know Mamu operations a right memory
they also read memory you've got the
tape
to every time with a drinking game right
I'm
every time I see import
well of an can drink on stage is such a
fancy hotel
%uh so why do this
we're looking for work the actual
computational models
of computers that surrounds I'll what
the you classical computer science
proves of Europe's
about what is computable church in
touring the founders of the field
did that for us but their computer
science when
away from the for question or what is
computable in particular platform
and started doing other important things
whereas hackers
%uh remained in that niche and
built programs we had programs called
exploits
for up platforms do you think that the
platform was not meant
to do and I thats
really why we do this we're eliciting
what actual computational model is in
the
machine so
let's take a look at the
CPU up with its memory management unit
I if you might be aware if you know exit
26 their various
tables that drive the memory trapping in
the
and memory translation in the protected
mode cell
up interrupt descriptor table the
a global descriptor tape interrupt
descriptor table
is where are you find the addresses the
vectors
for things like the page fault with a
double-fault
I that happens when you fail to dispatch
a page fault then you have the page
tables
a with all sorts of interesting bits a
scattered through them that cause the
trap that cause the page fault
to fire and most importantly
way and you I have a fort
you right bites
12 what the mm you the CPU
sinks is the stick so a page call him
for
needs to you some information about the
fault
in the memory now what would happen
if that memory was we're
the tables that you're reading for all
are you could put the processor
into a sort of 8 weird loop
in which mill instruction is
successfully dispatched we're every step
that you take
quizzes either at page fault or a double
fucked
xiao long as you formulate your tables
the GDT the page tables the I DT
up properly you let you can never give
the scoop
at it turns out you can use your
tables that described the memory
translation
drive the MU as the input as the program
boring bits and pieces all the mm you
logic
and it turns out to be touring complete
as we hope to show
to convince you of so
this up the situation is exactly the
same
as a the year elf example
from our previous talks that we started
with again
you have on input
and that is red and you have the ability
to write memory
possibly all over that input that is red
and so you have
are the beginnings ove a
a Turing machine and then it turns out
that the allergic
in the mm he is complete enough at to
make this an actual to reach
so om on
you know this is the principal now let's
take the deep dive
you can actually water that I am
t-shirt with a I fall investor will sell
with a poll just in time I can we asked
never
meant to of have a in Putnam
in any way I'm the let us have all this
I mean Bay they may call this processors
that purpose have all this fun
indeed and the surface and they're going
to do a quick overview of the various
tweaks that we're going to do together
horribly into making
Howard terrible terrible Turing machine
that runs without any CPU instructions
and the first step is that we're going
to go back in the old of days of DOS
be full into 286 in 386 days
when people were beginning to rate we'll
be talking operating systems for the
Intel processor
Rd first virtual memory system that in
forever Intel in fermented
is the segmentation based system which
is
nowadays completely unused the in the
book real multitasking was it ever used
it was
was some all versions if I was to are
however
for backwards compatibility this has
always been present in the process is
and
hecker Packers have always found this on
use mechanism and
me too clever thinks and so it's
actually still a valid memory to
our translation mechanism and its the
first step it happens from every virtual
address
on its long way to becoming an actual
physical address on the ramparts
a the segmentation mechanism is driven
by the global descriptor table
which is a table that is low can be
located anywhere memory and just
contains
are a pipe white entries describing
segments
segments are tagged or type regions of
memory
they contain a base address in a size
just the Rangers
memory addresses however they also
contain often disregarded
type field we can specify something is
meant to be a stack address
already here region or some piece of
code
and then there is registered as in the
process according to allow you to
specify which second is supposed to be
used for could fetch is what is supposed
to use for a sec addresses
excesses and so on and so forth long
story short this is what makes the ranks
rings 320 the bits in those
descriptor entries indeed
and afterwards
Intel added the second memory protection
mechanism that is the one that is
actually used in all the operating
system issues day today including
this Mac running the presentation
software that is the traditional virtual
memory
are system backed by page tables
are where there is a multilayer
hierarchy of tables at both provide
a lookup table translation function from
virtual addresses
to physical addresses however they also
contain a pretty interesting bits that
specify with this memory supposed to do
for example if this memory supposed to
be accessed by use a mod code a bike
rental code
and whether it's supposed to be read or
written to you and in new extensions of
the architect to when it's supposed to
be executive or not
and it gives us all these rules that
need to hold on to page tables for
memory access to successfully
are go through if any of these rules
have to be violated
Aug the processor interrupts execution
and traps into the kernel
also we hit the page fault at the page
fault is just about the most
overloaded the most hard-working up
interrupt descriptor table entry ever
because so many
hocker hardening patches have used that
have are
I'll placed there that some would check
I
over that because really you kept in
force %uh a pointy see
that you can't track the Vans that Darla
relevant to and so I
we're going to go through a few of those
examples because those were really the
inspirations
for the bigger for work and the first
our project that we drew inspiration
from is the open while project by solar
design a
back 1999 what's it is I want to do is
he wanted to prevent the very simple
r-spec overflow attack presented for
example in the Frank paper stack
smashing for fun and profit
and admit you have defected it was this
unused segmentation mechanism sitting in
a process it was then was in the silicon
and microcode however no one was really
using it
traditionally the segmentation make this
was completely disabled by just loading
all 50 segment registers with exactly
the same value
that just made them an identity
transform are
why this has the feature to both
remember addresses by adding an offset
to them
and limiting what memory exit I regions
a valid by comparing them
against the limit what ok molded is it
set the limit if the code segment
to just be loaded and if the user space
addresses
up leaving just enough space for the
stack at the top of the user chooses to
not be in the code segment
so whenever you would have and instruct
a instruction fetch
from the code segment that would cause a
are a pitfall
was imitation fault we're from the
cradle would check with the last execute
instructions
effort and if it was a return it would
see that oh well you just returning to
spec memory
that's probably going to be bad it turns
out the GCC into some weird conditions
emits code to support fancy languages
like objective-c
that actually will return to the stack
so they have some hacky work around
state to
still support the legacy code
or but debt that way they can defend
against that one very specific attack
every turn to the sack
this was the first non execute double
stack the first step
which actually overloaded the trapping
mechanism to do forty-six Department
the next one was up packs
Impax is really justice amazing
encyclopedia
all the things that you can do we have
a process or a such as it had the
emulation of the Annex bit before the
annex bit actually appeared
mp4 and it still maintains that one a
whole bunch of processes
processors that are don't have that
and I just what happened there
was a very creative you over the
memory translation leukocyte buffers
am this I he is for
the entry before the this is the page
table entry
in the pitch table entry %uh the blue
bit I
is the user supervisor I that was used
to
up muddle the non execute doubled it and
trap one trying to finish a code
from pages where this that was set to so
the Intel Arshi PU mm you has
to separate silicon pass one for fishing
instructions other for fetching data
and are there was a normal process
called flex 86
that try to use that I to detect self
modifying code and this is where the
creators of tax
got their inspiration for the page in X
are very using the
update Oct he'll be the TLB
and they're using the fact that you can
be decent current axed
from the beach table entry to the keel
be
contains the latest successfully
translated
at page table entries up for
foster look up of course if every lookup
had to go through the page tables
you now you would pay with three or four
up memory accesses per one memory access
that
wouldn't do so that's why out once P
a referenced six sheets it gets lifted
into the TLB and if it was a day to
fetch I through the data segment for
example
it would be lifted into the DT org
now the user supervisor bit was supposed
initially to protect
a supervisor data from being 'em
seen by users opts
but I they built this team Genia scheme
that actually uses the
hardware logic of the TLB translation
it's an additional potomac on to enforce
40°c just think about how wonderful
this
its I you've got this extra state in the
processor
because the there are actually physical
bits there's eCopy being made
and you use it in the way it worked was
like this
a detox of Fitch
has to go through the TLD
an instruction fish has to go through I
see the ideal be
UK so when you look up and get dressed
in the TLB
are you have eCopy ove the
page table entry if you've seen that
memory before:
and if the user bit the sect then you
get the tax issue just sale on through
this is a normal day to access through
the detail be
if the page table entry is not in the
TLB
then you have to walk the page tables
a and you always Sep that up $50,000
in the page tables should always causes
a fault so
when you I'm so
I'll remember when you're trying to say
shop to that address or fish from that
address
the PT and you don't have that in the
achille be
the PT will cause a fault because it
always does with this
setting over the bed now you hit the
page fall camp
now something better the page will
hamper steps im
examines the key IT if
it is of an attempt to fiction
instruction jumped instruction
then you terminate I you've just tried
to
a access the not execute doubled it
a you try to fetch from a page
but with the emulated not execute a bit
set if it's not an instruction that's
normal date
into before while bite lead
just before that Youssef the
user supervisor bit 21 which allows this
%uh bite viewed to succeed that
populates
the TLB lifts the
a entry in the two into the TLB we've
via right a user bit set
van you mediately concept see
descent can I text your page table entry
which always quite as a fault in the di
TLP
I entry which out never causes a fault
which
allows the excesses to sail through the
additional beauty of this
is that you lose I a four months
one the page table entries but
you don't lose performance on the TLB
lookups because the TLB
always has a valid setting out this bit
and it's just the page tables that has
the
setting that allows you to examine what
that
ob memory access was a Fitch of an
instruction where they tack
a reference and you keep them different
corner axed
and one step technique was understood
a whole bunch of interesting uses ovett
arose
for example there was an only berle I E
that plugin for all the debug
that a lot to trap on this complicated
condition that the code
at pH just written to with fish
instruction from
so the a
decompressor order the the update you
the the obfuscator just
finished working the on Packard just
finished working
and nao are the code is that the contact
is being jump to
veces %uh emulating a trapping condition
that x86 does not support but
it was Don with this dyssynchrony is a
shiner love
page table a and the TLB
but of course you ask yourself if you
really want to be evil
them why %uh stop at the
out by a stop at a setting what
manipulating one bit
you know this US bit you could actually
on Sep the a December nice
the physical page frame
that you are are referring to you can
get
eight different physical page free into
the TTL beat
versus the page dick so what happens to
them
is that if you access that page
as code you go to
one-page one physical Frank if you
accesses s
data say if you're an anti-virus
and you are on skinning it for
badness as as hopeless as a stock really
is
I you just get a different peach because
I the kilby entry is disorganized from
the page table entry from the actual
peace table entry
and you are %uh just basically you
getting a different think
and show what we see here
is design patterns something worthy of
the name
in which those trapping bits are used as
labels
as tags: spread through are
several places in memory M causing the
trap
at just the right conditions in the page
whole him being there to pick it up
and show that way you can come by traps
to have M %uh and/or or conditions
trapped on this a.m. that
which again the MU doesn't give you
you can labeled a at UT ref
a plugin of tax uses that to prevent
the colonel from reading user data if
you saw any key to stalk
them this is one of the ways to attack
the current
that he mentioned up intel's introducing
the US map
SM this map futures into the processor
that make it easier and more efficient
but tax had that I am before it was a we
have
tagging pages by intent the insides are
you colonel
are not supposed to look at the user
memory on the a small piece of your
kernel that dispatches the school's
I has any business looking into the apt
when it imports the arguments
so it's really coming back
the to the or tagged architectures where
memory was not just bites
where you could say which bites in
memory served which purports
and you know the in Exhibit is just a
tiny little step towards that
as you can imagine there are all sorts
of data flows that you want to block
only fume you out what date what all
those bites that are
public reading equal in memory are meant
for
and the only way to do so is to create
the tag a label
four pages you can't do that but you can
spread through the trapping bits
and as you overload the page will
himmler I you
can then make sense over those and a
trap the
undesirable slips to this is the
inspiration
we thought that there's a reason well
this worked
in the reason is that there is enough
computational power in the ImageView
and we ask ourselves well how much
what can we program with that
and with that and then we would
and that gave us a whole lot of tweaks
that we could potentially
build a machine from all that state how
we also need some not to do it together
and that's where the mechanism that
actually
implements the trap handling comes in
they waited too crude oil gets from
normal program execution
into exit into executing an all-powerful
page fault handler
Dera in on each other in fact three
different ways of handling interrupts
and conditions to have them a very
similar in one of them is by now
complete the
unused d typical way that all modern
operating systems use for
day-to-day interrupt handling is called
the trap gate or interrupt gate
its if you've ever programs in the old
days on DOS
in protected mode its are similar to a
fault
jump you just specify new code segment
which usually would be to Crennel's code
segment about causing itching to
transition from ring 3 touring 0 and
that address within the current
that's just like a regular function call
and in fact Intel
tries to be nice to operating system
developers and makes this behaves just
like a regular function call
which an x86 involves premises being
pushed to the stack
dairies a special configuration region
in memory don't get to later on the
actually contain spec segments featuring
if you switch to a different
arm ring like the Opera are lecturing
for
3 touring 0 the processes microcode will
be nice enough for you to look up
where you operating system kernel stack
is supposed to be
and will push various values about the
old state if the execution
to the new stack frame which you can
then just use like regular function
arguments in your page for Bentley
however this makes quite a few
assumptions about the state of the
processes
for example that tusk state segment has
to be said
that contains information but with a
kernel stack is has to be said well it's
stacked
the code segment that is specified in
the ITT entry
has to be a valid code segment and
various rules about the Rings being
transition have to hold and also ditt
entering
has to be there in the first place all
of this could potentially fail usually
only when there's a kernel bug
and into his best has a special
mechanism for handling such box named
I the double-fault the double fault is
when you have
any sort of air condition occurring
while trying to get from
execution to the into context however if
the first
instruction if the interrupt Headley
itself fails that's not a double fault
but just another page what which
is a fact that will make used to but it
allows us to actually keep looping on
faults
pharmacy so you she there is the
situation
out with the chicken an egg in order to
candle in memory fault
you have to be able to write to memory
those fights ago on the second describe
the condition
whale out what if you can try to memory
but you have a deeper fault I and then
of course
a even that may fail because that also
needs to write memory
envied from memory so then you go into
the triple fault otherwise known as
rebooked
but I you know in order to capture fault
you have to are ok ok was a fault
there's a beginning of a clock in there
you will see that will
learned to oscillate between page called
and the double-fault
as if this were a processor clock
and that's when tells hardware task
switching mechanism comes in
nowadays a modern operating systems this
is only used for displaying the last
blue sky to
board for displaying a blue screen of
death for a kernel panic as the last
resort
but effect is in very well designed
mechanism that allows you to wrist
to save and later on restore almost
all of the processes context at least
the wait was in the 386
you dude is by specifying a special kind
of entry in the interrupt descriptor
table
which does not contain an address like
the regular traffic it does but only is
selective for it ask state segment
for TSS which isn't index
into the global descriptor table that we
saw earlier with the old
segmentation mechanism and in there 0.2
this large
reason if memory 104 bytes long on 32 in
32-bit mode
that contains all the registers of the
processor
and the receive use microcode has
features for saving all the processes
state into what into such a region
and for restoring old CPU state from
memory
so now you're seeing the patter you've
got the fault
which can actually switched asks which
can actually right
although this a large block of
information
yet if can actually write that where
ever
the table the GDT is pointing to
show you she you can really gf right
over the memory that you are viewing and
that is driving the next step
of your fault dispatching in this is
exactly what we're going to use
and the actual my crew program is
running while switching to the task
is that at first when interrupts accrues
and
a tough skated specified in the in the
ATT interrupt descriptor table
the CPU will save on a fit state to the
location pointed to by special register
di Pasqua register on the next this is
actually the only pic peace
of this entire mechanism is actually
used during bootup
the kernel at one point sets the task
register up to contain a somewhat millet
task
so it is able to handle double faults
and independent message and off to its
anti mechanism is forgotten about
to think of this as a dark silicone up
that is dark to Linux
but I is the very bones our page for
liberator
and it will then walk all of these are
in memory tables
find a new task perform some basic
validations on that task
are and actually check if there is if
this task has already been used before
it with the so-called busy bit because
they want to prevent looping and we'll
get back to how we work around this
it will then load on a fit state from
memory and to push the error occurred to
the stack
because they might still be some other
parameters that you
want to save about the previous
execution state so it actually pushes
for bites
to the sack and it will then begin
executing the new AP
however that is after the entire
interrupt anything logic has occurred
and if that new your IP happens to be an
invalid memory location or any of the
page table constraints are violated that
will just cause another page fault
and not in fact a double-fault and he'll
have to insert
a brief digression a true gem that we
found in the Intel manuals
are in one of two dark and musty pages
that no one has probably looked at the
last 10 years because again this
mechanism is not used
our printed out home that contains a
description of the
Intel processor if specifically warns
against
placing this task state segment on the
page boundary
because the way it was apparently done
in all processes
is that the process it looks up the
physical address corresponding to the
first fight
if this 104 by long tss and then reads
104 continues physical bites from there
at the time this was not a security
problem because to excess and if these
data structures you had to be in the
kernel
and if the kernel could perform reached
a physical memory well it was no problem
because the kernel
is designed to do that however what we
were thinking at the time is wouldn't it
be nice if you had a virtualized
environment
and you could play city SS and the last
fight for page somewhere
and then re 203
by its that have on the next physical
page if you manage to get in the
fragmentation that might be completely
different p.m.
and we we have quite excited that we had
found the sleeping dragon there
and we're making plans to you know or
own all the PC to
however den we did the whole science
thing and the reality check came in
because by now Intel CPU's actually
translate this double work but doubled
and perform the safing which again is an
optimist
because this mechanism is no longer use
the optimization of reading 104
continuous physical bites is no longer
necessary so this has been pushed off
some went to the microcode with safe
they'd up
so instead of a sleeping dragon all we
had is this sleeping the new
however as as is the tradition cats can
also be quite interesting in this
fact in fact allows us to build our
computer for eggs and rocks
some must maintain that cats are more
interesting than dragons
course it is oh
taking little bit of a step back usually
when people talk about Turing machines
they talk about things like
tapes and and find its aight machine and
a lot of complicated logic but in fact
you don't need of that all you need is a
single CPU instruction
%uh that's a few instructions little bit
convoluted its
in theory contexts they talk about
different and French negative
there is a wonderful book on this that
if you have access to an economic driver
you can easily get
however if you intend to purchase it for
itself is a tiny bit expensive for the
monks information contained herein and
Wikipedia provides just about the same
things
the instruction is just that
you have are fine it's a different one
if you want to be doing complete a
theoretically infinite set of memory
locations
and you determined any one of these
memory locations and French
21 21 instruction if you have an
underflow to another one
if you don't have an underflow to make
his practical we also add a move
I one instruction because here simple
decry entrenched negative architecture
do we do move
issue overflow integers which tends to
be quite bad for performance if you
actually want to do a demo
however the move that's not the problem
or
and I will go in and introduce the
various actors
now in fermentation if the Turing
machine
Rd your IP address just have to process
will always point
at invalid memory so FF FF FF FF FF
if if
um so at no point will they ever be
a valid CPU instruction be executed
because it never is a place with us if
you could actually fetch
and every instruction it always tries to
you and sees okay let's handle an
interrupt
do some fits my Cricut magic and in fact
just to drive into another
by actually the same wall but with a
slightly different internal state
I'll to get our determined reuse the
fact that this 45 error code is pushed
onto the stack
so we have for each memory location have
fun such tasks state segment
and pushing that error code d criminals
respect for the value at that location
by four
and the branch is if it's less than for
whites are not
if it's less than four bytes the spec
which would fail because the spec point
is actually a separate interrupt 'cause
by having a sec for the wrap-around
thereby we would cause a double-fault if
to determine succeeds
to push succeeds that would be another
paid for
that's how we get our branch are we keep
a glow
we keep a single global descriptor table
around that will describe
fifty structures however we'll use the
will use different page tables to map
different things around and from time so
we can have a large number of
instructions then with
be allowed into relatively small table
in particular op one tss descriptor
their instruction in one ID cheaper
instruction
that turns out to be a necessity of
bouncing between the page fault in the
double-fault
out whose addresses are contained
therein
indeed and because the TSS allows us to
switch out page faults we always put
our target for branch
I for French not taking in 2d into a
14-page publication and we put
our top our target tss for the taking
branch that is
and underflow in the in the on
interrupted location
and that and by remembering memory at
out through the instructions which that
is loading
memory I went deep interrupt handler
does is it loads memory from one virtual
address
and saves it back to that same virtual
address however in the meantime it
switches at page tables
so while it may be writing back to the
same virtual address we can map that
same virtual address two different
physical address
thereby also giving us a free move
through changing at the mapping function
when the instruction changes the world
changers view of the entire memory
changes
on with the a specially formulated
PayPal table paper page table
well on we might into the net
yes indeed and wanna and luckily also
DTS contains a whole other bunch of
fights that will be written and read
up read and written from memory which
allows is to avoid some fifty
unfortunate and from tation constraints
that the real silicon has so we can look
around some problems
and to keep you interested we have
prepared a little demo which is
what we believe to be the world's most
efficient implementation of the game of
life
because it uses you receive you
instructions
to date argument on-screen cable
cable perfect
we have connection I A made my
sacrifices to demagogues last night at a
bar I hope they still hold
right now it's putting
okay so what is the state is it first
execute some normal kernel code
that will set up all the tables in the
correct way I A
have released the tool that
automatically generates a Seco double
set up tables in the proper way
from a more sane intermediate language
and that will then cause a single page
for which will compute an entire
duration of the game of life
it will then bounce are Reese use that
same double-fault mechanism to restore
sanity briefly and execute a series of
move instructions that will just copy
things from all over the memory
into the BJ framebuffer and then
just cause another page for at the end
of that instruction stream
which will go back and computer neck
situation the game of life
0 in fact does you wondering about her
performance this might be
this also includes a massive delay loop
that burn something like five hundred
million cycles between each iteration
if you run the underlay pushing you
don't see anything you to see a white
box
or white and now let's go back to talk
let's see how this works great city
and if there's one trick that alone from
circuits and occasionally while teaching
have to life
so will begin with a small fairy-tale
version of this
and then slowly introduce all the info
implementation constraints
that we have to work around and
oftentimes we use fairly excessive
methods of violence to deal with various
in from station constraints
so %uh sergei sorry mentioned
the inspection process love
bouncing between page faults in double
faults that we have is somewhat like the
clock for machine in fact
the page what's happening is the rising
edge of the clock
the first thing it does is right back
the
current value body current immediate
value for our calculation
into the output of the last instruction
by saving the TSS fate at the beginning
of an interrupt
Senate bill remember love this
is basically a silicon a microcode
microcode of course up but I'll love
this
is heart coded in the CPU in the MU
cell all you're doing is you're
triggering those canned
those operations with your fault
conditions
indeed and then this if you will proceed
to load
a new execution safe from the TSS and
attempt to save that fault error code
onto the stack which
we just use for its the comment of TSP
if that
determined of fails we get we raise a
double-fault
which will cause us to go back to the
very beginning after execution and
safety is estate again and cause another
clock
if however it succeeds we have just take
rented
out the second to buy for and will
then cause another page fault by setting
by jumping to an invalid instruction
again giving rise to another page 4
o'clock
going through this slowly if this would
be the initial state
this if you set up relatively sane
Leawood sect 4-2 somewhere in kernel
space
our except for the fact that ended
tusk register for example the Linux
kernel has set up the just points to an
otherwise unused region of memory except
that the CPU
except that we have prepared and I DTE
Energy DT
with the tools we have released and
something into kernel cause it's a page
fault
this might either be cleverly hidden
somewhere that you cleared the present
clear one of the various bits in the
mapping that mexico into
virtual memory well you just jump to an
address that's going to be invalid
like zero or less that then causes a
page fault
which will cause the CPU to walk to
interrupt descriptor table
CEO this is an interrupt 14th so here we
have a tough skate going to task one of
eight
first for the tasks which we look at the
task register
see okay currently running task f8 so we
have to actually do the full switch
West pasqua fake owed its energy ETF
points it is are points in the first yes
SNG
and so all of the state have to see if
you was copied into memory from the
Registers
wish also the manual says
and venice is OK now we want to go to
toss one of eight foreign trip ends:
again
walks the IDPs and the GB team and sees
okay this is from the second tss entry
we have
let's go in and they would all have to
register as Bruce
from Eric suddenly all of the world has
suddenly all of the world has changed
revenues that point do we have a new
task register we could even have a new
ERP
in our case the AP still going to be
invalid because we don't quite
want to cuddle to execute yep as a side
effect of this it also sets
a busy bit in the global descriptor
table which will be quite annoying
get to in a few sites another site
effective loading in New TSS is that the
page table base register cf3 has been
reloaded so the entire view of the
memory
and thereby to see views entire of you
have suddenly changed new instruction
it's a brave new world
and so whatever the TSS
and she's in the GATT may have be the
first yes essentially might now
coincidentally in this example points in
the same tss as before
but the second one now points to
completely different entry and so we can
do branching between the two different
instructions
and because the second tss entry that is
currently be
current essa entry points to different
occasion memory
the value that we just read before the
0x4 will be determined it and then
stored into that he is essentially which
is completely different
location in memory as I mentioned here
unfortunately happens to be this busy
bit
the in normal into normal mode of
operation you occasionally want to
return from interrupt because you would
like your program execution to resume
so Intel being nice and kind and not
wanting everyone to screw it up
as they did before the days of DOS day
provided
especial return instruction from an
interrupt that will
look at all the structures and restore
the state just before the entrapment be
tried in los instruction
Dept means there is eighty chain
link stored within the tusks state
segments if that
link everywhere to become a new it would
become an endless loop into wanted to
avoid that said at a busy but
specifically to prohibit
anyone from moving interrupts
and if this bit is set in a GDT
descriptor
for TSS the it will actually cause
another double-fault
all this actually 52 10 weeks is
artistically to implement isn't iMac is
about eight-week suspending
by a spent about eight weeks for going
out but trying out ways to clear that
one bit
and I had crazy scheme set up and they
all fail
until you realize that are well playing
around with their debug and single seven
things and reading to spec
closely that the CPU always saves the
state before
attempts to load a new tss so
what we do is we map to the left of the
TSS
over to the GATT if we picture he
discovers that just happened to be at
the end of a page
DDX dcx registers that
weakened specifies pasta topped if the
task will be
written over the GTX and if you
carefully crusty x86 for justice
they leave the same content in their
except that one bit will be cleared
so that's a nuclear option in other two
nucleus one bit
when you click the entire renew the
entire top of pics
but pay Italian again love this power
comes from front for free
from the MU I you only need to set up
the menu to do this
and odd that's where today the faulting
comes it's and this is the first
faulting continuity of our little fairy
tale explanation because because if this
mechanism suddenly all of these bits
that were marked as busy before ended
DTF and now locked is available because
they have always been overwritten
when noting new task
what to see if you will then proceed to
do is okay no
tries to invoke the intro pender so
we're going to give it its one from
midget
actual cause it to determine just like
pointer
oh and then it tries to jump to
construction which however so happens to
be
0xffff and therefore they'll be yet
another page fault
giving us another clock up
in this issue however then we notice oh
well dislike point is going to be all
zeros
so we actually come push again so
let's try having a double-fault it will
then proceed to do the entire
game again except this time we to
interrupt descriptor table 8
as opposed to of 14 that we had before
whipple loads a new state from the
double-fault
and try to perform the same game I get
as you may have noticed when I was
speeding up and skipping through the
slides
that's usually a good indicator them
lying again
because there is one other nastiness
that is in there
I mention very much at the beginning
that the CPU only performs this task
such a mechanism when you actually
switching to a different task
so you can never jump from one
instruction to the same instruction to
get
which mathematically turns out to be
graph coloring problem
so either you can write very generic
algorithm the tries to cut a
craft Cali instruction stream spent
about an week attempting to do this
all you can make your compiler just I'm
it bogus instructions at some point
and duplicate the same instruction the
few places that graph coloring becomes
trivial
now imagine my horror I'm a refugee from
math might degrees in math have a PHD
for for god sake
and of course I run up from that into
the bit slammed
a so that I can never see graph coloring
ref isomorphism
that sort of rock problems and we find
this
out weird machine that can be %ah gain
from the MU
one teacher have I meister student come
back to me and say
look there is this graph coloring
problem
faces what happens if nah people to you
can never run from it
and comes back and a slightly less
convoluted view this is if you look at
the
hypothetical front side bus which of
course no no longer exists because this
HyperTransport
cashing but when I actually do vile 7
through this example
is it alright to physical address 0x8
the FFS 0
initial think we had then redirects for
from another location di cuenta by four
and ready to get another location
and it will then feedback 0x8 up this
state originally wrote back that's just
what
a normal pension determined computer
which people apparently we're building
in the fifties back when
gates were really expensive rebuilding
would look like if it had your memory
testrake
so in fact we can compute just about any
function we want as long as you mind
minor performance it when counting on a
clock and a massive performance
improvement when counting instructions
0 while making it extremely hard for
someone who does not have access to the
FSP to figure out what precisely what's
going on
we have a few other instance are
restrictions in there one of them is
that you need to be to colonel to set
this up in the first place
then there is a fun time restriction
that you can't have two double faults in
a row to process it will reboot on you
again I was doing craft things there
until
I realize there was a waste of time and
just inserted
another bogus instruction that will just
always succeed
sometimes you can cheat me off it will
come back at me but
sager's and our one instruction is
somewhat offer to use
however we've written I've written a few
tools that might help you
around is in actually allow you to
implement somewhat useful programs like
the game of life
the biggest restriction that we have so
far is that you can only work with the
spec pointer if tough state segments
that are aligned in just the correct way
that we have
but I'm currently working on extending
it will so that allows a special
read from or peek and poke construction
essentially so you can reach from
up a tree bookish to put it in simple
world's awards we actually have a
compiler
of don't call it that pilot fix
I loved the other interesting side
effect of this is that no simulated have
tested
informants all is this correctly I've
developed the sandbox
so my particular compile I'm its coat it
happens to run a box because
occasionally I like debugging things
because
refundable however things like VMware
and Sen tend to crash and burn as soon
as they see double faults being linked
in interesting ways
sometimes they just have an assertion
that fails sometimes they go off and do
believe what he thinks
and so you know reptiles are interesting
but there are so many of them
with this repeal you can actually
compute the equivalent to what the
processor can compute
thats one big giant huge humongous
enormous strength and so to take away
food
does if you happen to be very white hats
womens anyone
%uh is that you should ticket rules how
they handle obscure
and we had edge cases the much more
interesting takeaways for those if you
happen to be wearing black hats
where you get a nice and big red pill
but
then again you can probably fix that
read till so it works just slightly
different
Lee and analysis tools or you can just
use this as a really evil mechanism
of transferring control win if you have
sacred would get
because this text is anti mechanism
actually allows you to restore execution
to an arbitrary location in memory
using a mechanism that is completely not
supported by any of the debugging tools
out there
even while it may not be particularly
performance you can use it to
balance execution between different
parts of your code well make it very
hard for someone to trace what is going
on
her some juniors be warned and
forbid straw hats that don't fit either
into black Hathaway take a degree it's
we're just excited that we found another
we had machine and if we working on
making it
artwork on 64 bit as well well loved his
legacy
craft has been removed that's where the
idea of overwriting things with the spec
point a comment comes in
of and of course we always working on
expanding this come Tyler thing we have
maybe
reading LVM backend remember
it's not about the collar over the
strong felt the weave
of if and then we thank you for so
patiently
listening to us
out seemed to have three minutes for
questions
we have few minutes for questions that
gets this time for one to two questions
anyone
shoeprints
be sites to if you look to any examples
of with machines where
things he thought might be with you
machines turned out not to be
so it turned out not to be tearing
during a bleak
up plenty in fact
most of the exploits but never Inc
I mean take any expectation to kick it
boroughs
opcode it borrows logic from somewhere
especially if it's entirely data-driven
so
all I it borrows won the as much as it
needs
and no one really up
thought about those things up
till approximately I 2000
when up care on backtrack
generalize the return to Lipsy trick at
the end
%uh using Tim notions I'll chaining of
thick frames
for what later became known as the
return oriented programming
actually wrote that pay you can ok
Fitch any program like that from the
those segments into no you know you
borrowed logic
so that was out the first time
way and up the jean-marie City the
the general nature over this is a
programming exercise
was are brought up in the hacker
community and the academic community
out when this was framed for them by a
sharp jump up with
in with his return a random programming
paper a quote one
a when he proved during completeness he
procuring completeness
of op a particular version over leaps
you
or other of %uh gadgets that we can
borrow from a particular know him she
in there made the academic community sit
up and take notice
it's not about malicious code you know I
used to read all those
on a machine learning papers about how
we detect malicious code
and lick good luck it's not about code
anymore
%ah finally the threat model has changed
its now militias computation
I'm and with computation comes the
question of characterizing it
but really you now up mostly you can
I'll the do nicely with a large enough
like for find the comment on where
pushdown automaton
like we say it like I said in the
beginning a Turing complete
is just are something like the rich
shout you dont always
want your exploitation to end up in the
actual shell
sometimes operating a few bits here and
there are enough
but what actually gives you the power to
overwrite those
is is the chaining is the a
computational model
that's contained in the input which act
as a program a
another question perhaps and believe
we're out of time home values in seconds
contact thanks nights weekly you doing
do I see him going up
now know how Phillips them both as well
for dis 2d still get the conference if
you have any questions
they'll be around thank you very much
thank you thank you
take a couple of minutes to hook up the
next weekend set him up on stage in will
continue right immediately after that
so we'll be back in no more than five
minutes
i dnt a pic thanks
saw I K and i cant make
going and time I move my