to speak about supply chain and axle
would be a lot of cases we worked on
last year we will explain you two cases
impact and how to how a lot finally of
company were compromised due to supplier
completed a lot about our view of the
next year and survey chief from the
attacks so it's basically just I explain
so many mystical and I'm working at
Cisco Terrace two years I'm security
researchers mainly work on malware
analysis apt that that ready to some
instances and I'm one of the organizers
but of conference in front of cemeteries
going here might predict yeah delete
this and kick off first
I am eyes were Mercer and Paul in
italics night around three years mostly
more inner I'd come out or not a power
analysis reverses it soon yeah I wrote
conference called besides Belfast which
is in Belfast they also come visit
please let me know we won't speak even
better as we did this introduction as
Paul mentioned we're gonna talk today
avoid supply to the facts who owned
ocean at is exploit trust relationships
if you share with either oil companies
or could be right back to an individual
business level we're going to cover two
different talks first of all we will
talk which piece of grounds were called
Yentob it's also called not magic so we
were one of the first people to discover
this ball and I will not force people to
work office Cisco I our ground
fortunately was on site so this is the
attack that occurred in your Korean has
been related to the financial dr. aneta
platform called me dock which we'll get
into a bit but that's what it started so
we got a phone call and Cisco IR got a
phone call invisibly said something
really Bad's happened
now anyone anything somebody about
operatives real assets in that so we
actually saw this on Twitter that it was
an actual tweet from the verified
confirmed Ukrainian government account
that said someone worked over with the
agencies private firms were hit by a
virus but there's no need to panic we're
putting our utmost attacks for the
issues so this was pretty funny but when
we actually get into a fight or what it
was it was unfortunately not funny at
all so what we started with with all
those of the past outlook from a
customer perspective of what was going
on what we started in information wise
was we were dealing with the 10th is
creative ground support appear to be
targeting every organization that you
create every organization can be a bit
sort of wishy-washy but that seemed to
be the consensus of the information we
were getting the fact that the soul was
comparative last flogging by that we
mean it was hopping rapidly with heard
any real time to respond do you
currently live actually hunt and every
vector we're on them so that's great
follow me through it - it's like
everything's proof the world is burning
but we don't watch and you help us okay
- the Polka soup sister why our guys
turn up outside as you say anytime
there's a system incident responsible
kids but they will work directly with
the Talos matter or policy so Paul I
stole a good subtle stuff we first try
to figure out what we dog is so it's a
windows.net up and beautiful but its
development dot that it's a tactical
setting application used abundantly
throughout the world not only in crib on
PA functionality which is dude because
we as security professionals constantly
say please pass your if you don't
bad things will happen but fortunately
this was the officer that it was the
flip of that use the large companies
that I mentioned I became the group's
being scoping if you create do the
ranking and lots of other companies with
it okay and some communication wise what
do we do so as I met it all started with
a phone call so whatever your provider
are 70 message to say that you do along
international business call here people
please stop we basically started do
lots of excessive calls as soon AT&T
were basically let in our our both our
IR guides new you're spending too much
money stop fooling you create life from
your crib
thirdly we actually need the full
nutrients we'll start with a timeline
perspective under this all start so we
pull 2017 April 14 2017 VDOT released an
updated Laughlin photo of the
functionality mentioned anticipate an
application application of all hits made
at 15th they release another minor
version release the key and everything
about Fiat says you would expect
unfortunately this time there was a
backdoor list of the 222nd p.m. and
there was a miller version release that
he carrying the same backdoor so we were
quite confident that there was it like
to run there to the point where we
guaranteed it so we started having to
look back and what was going on from an
opt-in perspective will must be
highlighted some started looking at the
factor will we identified so you peed on
me - dot-com thought you a was contacted
every two minutes that's the old theater
for me Dodgers I know that's you did
with that make sense well this back that
we did was have a 62 mile process that
it could actually issue what it could do
so we enter an email retrieval platform
that was a sushi look that they are
willing for execution of commands and
wanted we carried out by the attacker
okay and we determined that these
attacks so that these commands were
actually used to help distribute yet dip
or no can't do that you know familiar
with or forbidden so the backdoor was
simple in reality to start off by
stealing SMPP credentials into meal
credentials store them in the registry
and started using them to actually do
some communication pack you'll see yes
there is a yes so that you start seeing
lunate of different commands that I want
DLL all those boxes so then once we
started and if I were start trying to
build the pictures the what's going on
we started with the Ukrainian tax
document as I mentioned we have to
figure out well what's it doing high
security and we basically start forming
our in the timeline
so the meatball timeline that we came up
with Peter back to get will 2017 as I
mentioned that's when we started seeing
basically initial releases with packing
was included June 27th was when it
really got bad that's the day that we
got the phone call I meant at least I
saw all right
9:00 a.m. UTC we see that malicious
actor starts using stolen credentials to
perform a switch you jerk month purpose
of this earth very rare I don't know how
many people law or living things if you
give their bash but looking for things
like switch users on boxes it oh we
shouldn't be hot little it's quite
important is who you go to the things I
guess who from and I are in the response
perspective you're looking at what hangs
all the words being low to 10 minutes
later I don't know why it took 10
minutes it's quite elegant whose time
for coffee
he took his time so 10 minutes later he
modified something server configuration
that was being used to proxy the update
this is proxy to a third party who think
of all the different logic confirmed or
proxy traffic who's going through this
third party hosted platform so Tiger
knowing that the update server proxy and
all traffic 3 page of the box if you
don't know if that's bad I'm gonna tell
you right now that's very bad
you no longer have control your traffic
you no longer have control of your
update mechanism you're in a very bad
place so we start seeing what's going on
there at this point does it say is that
a time that we build after the fact of
course we don't real type speak so the
last before a proxy connection we see
that involved was the right three are
here 1231 original server was then
restored from the finger recent
perspective we see that disconnect that
IP from a lot VIP I think we very clear
that does not mean this factor was based
in Latvia false flag now the future is a
very very different conversation that we
could have a play after but this does
not being this reporter sorry this tiger
was situated in Lafayette that was just
where the box he was using Kiel from
third party who so provided another
block swipe use the DD 0 and come up
is dead there was no way we did recover
any more from them so we build a
timeline with other students no
ransomware at this point we figured if I
was delivered we figured out how was I
to you at perpetuate its commands around
there for structure so now we started to
look at the ante itself and the more
capabilities which is never fun in
another organisation that house
connection ID silencer credentials theme
which again has never found because the
more credentials I have a new
environment the more I can move around
here but I'm AM around somewhere that
stuff fun because it's just really
because so propagation started like this
five drop on purpose it dot dot it
contained everything that that you
needed to run from an execution of
propagation point of view with four
methods of publication I will step
through each one first one we go through
it
come online theft using baby cats may be
considered also to fight over food cuts
is on your network
it probably shouldn't be so this is the
to look we keep an eye out for if you do
have really now we're going endpoint
protection information etc maybe cuts is
generally a well recognized and well
regarded and hesitant to for stealing
credentials of a brand performant pasta
Hodge never types that Bisbee allowed me
to move through our environment without
needed any credentials gross naked pasta
in the pipe we see the malware uses all
the collect that's were going to
permission that we get probably first
step we see was some use of eternal blue
as well like to while let me go by
people really thought they could release
by the policies don't am i as in method
that this malware used to try to
probably get around itself it's a
legitimate fully supported platform that
exists within Windows he has exactly the
legitimate remove administration through
the photographer forcibly use this been
referred to law is difficult for
libraries this is where you can actually
from an attackers perspective bring into
an environment that you say we think
that's already our sailors and also
example this are tales included by
default with every way this plan
WMI appears attack and seem sort of idea
to internal blue go to curly rule months
a Buddhist atheist vulnerabilities that
were released by a shadow brokers
and unfortunately they're very effective
dual Potsdam is 70 to 100 well number
one class this is the water pride issue
and people did apply solar
infrastructure so this allowed even for
motor oil from water pride that you
could still actually probably get her
identifier so regardless of propagation
method only and uses its County acting
something of the Box it's all loops for
vulnerable hosts it could get to do so
maybe constant we've just explained and
then some of the eternal blue modular
sorry maybe captain waters and were able
to identify again we get a look at the
code from a legal point of view to you
know the cool tonight in and see what
it's doing you look at the baby can't
skip up you can actually directly will
get to the modules that our baby just so
that's one way that you're able to point
out what's going on one strength
we've got more memory cancel soupy crap
being used so we could identify some of
the crypt and symmetric-key profile
modules that are being used functions
interviews I don't we get a turtle blue
turtle room once the modified platform
with double call sort and double pulsar
is the black to work with it was use now
released by alligators if you didn't
have a mint 17 and one who applied
physically and you could carry that
stuff modified commander small schools
codes it would allow an attacker to have
look code execution all your relatives
then we'll we get here is a model fight
don't fall so our backdoor installed at
drops of perk dot and then the whole
thing starts over it because it's a worm
it constantly tries to replicate little
girl you revive it though also are
modifications that not were minimal it's
a bit hard for me to see there's no it's
not the koutoubia front but you'll see
some of the different aspects you see
some of the commands it's like a double
code cues and license see you see that
the C command and Sarah these th them
with Mike comes your babies but not
enough taxi sorry I'm not to make it
differentiation so if you have a
heuristic piece of signature-based
common technologies it would mess these
with this or that that's it but i cúcuta
committee you know applause are argues
and we can see it's the exact
he's cheers the look at the move a
alternative move a lattice we
incremented one bite on into the
opticals here again enough the trek up
hood some heuristic vs the signature of
his platforms and double pulsar
molecules new key and this guy was busy
clearly the double pulsar and this is so
the standard offsets it existed within
the league coupe it's available for
unfortunately unable to dine the news
and rabbit to their malware ID at least
these teams some of the bike cool
responses soon edge it actually uses
offset 0 X 16 for the standard offset
was 0x money for multiplex ad so it's
the SNP tropic information of speakers
publication using PS exec as I mentioned
PS exact is a really cool little general
where there's two of your systems
administrator you possibly use this even
if you're not is really useful use it
advice when you control control connect
them all portions I would have did from
perfect II thought that platform was
drop be as exact as DLL whose talk that
use distilled tokens as we've mentioned
that we're keeping by things like mimic
cups and then connect to a remote
machine run this basically execute lvl
30 to XE groaning perfect seatbelt up
the mama's pecan wood with it an ordinal
through next word zero one would say
capable Democrats work nobody am I was
the exact same uses still the
information that we've taken
supernatural harvesting is key for this
piece of malware actually moved from a
Louisville one will go for the view pass
information across India pipe music
dominate like C which is part of mm I
and then use another process called
create the Ron rock DLL 32x if you see
that the commonality
you see what is do the decryption clean
system you might want methodology used
actually it's your infrastructure so
whether you used internal dirt or mask
its attack or somebody online it's
trying to move from this escalation of
the concurrent user once it did that it
created a schedule passed with Priya to
reboot within what are no I we don't
really know why it did that
because there is no real rationale for
it the way that or if you just rebooted
the box to the way maybe they wanted to
try get additional information
there's nothing that exists within our
the excellent trees that are useful
information that they could be really no
answer yeah we get asked every good what
happens in that Sheldon reboot is about
where they will destroy the NVR or
physical drive zero so first physical
drive that is references that your
environment will be physical tried zero
and if it has some the NC people crib or
a seashell type print from an API point
of view it will let destroy your MBR and
wipe your disk if it comes it will
destroy the first 10 dis executive go
ahead rip some of the 5 G's no I'm
saying 2048 your you read a world apart
from a constant work respect of all your
thighs it could fit you can't beat the
boss because you're at the ours who's
your your pretty little stuff if you
were not you don't get the box back up
the attacker oxy had done some final all
clean up he tried to delete any notion
of you being able to find him all right
where they're provisionally the paint
that you see what's your rebooted
similar to catch it if you're familiar
with Benton read the sorry black
background with red writing basically
tell me : panty news in male at this
address and will give you information
but the thing about this was it's not
going to use the single address from the
big point perspective so he knew real
way to actually determine who pay to do
how to pay for a similar to walk right
the attacker they had also used a single
who steal thought that email here so
Will Smith one two three four five six
it who stood on it but they probably an
are this attacked pursuits jump out
being a pop star
so even though if you wanted to pay
which you should never do we've never
had the kid panel for awesome but even
if he wanted to you could you know I've
new communication from the actor
consumer kind in my opinion either I
knew they'd shut that thought for advice
Tiger was able to use it or use it
anymore
finder it Dan ran they're just able to
pay genuine ransom work don't really in
my opinion because there's some of the
things we just talked about single
Bitcoin wall makes it pretty much very
difficult attract without having people
sign addresses to prove whether pain
from its era particularly the dress
which was my blog those advances to kind
of talk to anyone if you're not gonna
really ours we're ready
you already in a bad place if you have
dollars with rhythm even if rain normals
will written it like the first 10
sectors of your disks booting your disk
Aquila problem
I definitely that's all for AV p XE
really it also wiped the firsthand disk
sector for that regardless of produce
they won't do what a VP thought ideas I
do which we have prizes amplifies as
people will we do yes because first he
is right sir this malware actually
looked specifically for Kaspersky which
might be extensible would be in an you
create we don't really do the Guru bitch
it was behind that but if you have a v3
dot X you rolling over it first etc so
the malware basically when I might
undone at white pollution on away he was
hopping from his perspective
so I listed compromising maximum
conversation but by a way for people
that see some free space here if you
want to see the invite widen up machine
or mostly machines as quickly as
possible is what the active is designed
for and what are accented from the
finance who could it be
there is at least be the remodel at all
these are impacted by this but there
were two whole days you reported
positive over 300 billion dollars sorry
three hundred million dollars over a
half a billion dollars for two companies
and that's how many people they talk but
only to mass destruction in a quick way
to cause greatest impact yeah so and
it's just you case you will see it's the
same of projects of ratchet compromise
and problems will find their targets but
to prove the goal was completely
different in warrant case it purpose was
to compromise a maximum number of
machine in generators and media coverage
extra in this case it's more
your position purpose was to compromise
a maximum of machine but after make some
filter out really with on several
specific really important mission from
the ethical point of view so it's about
seeking an application doesn't know sick
leader in the room so everybody knows
Sakina look so next question already
recommend to someone to install CCleaner
yeah some people are honest people I
believe so sickly therefore fuzzy only
guys about no this is an application
used to clean your system via registry
we have better performance clean malware
hardware segment so it's structure from
the website up our number so basically
it's used by billion of people it's
download massively each one bonus every
non-wage X direction so it's massively
used it normal that Morris everybody
knows this application so we receive
notification about a weird behavior
inside of Sakina application so the
first thing we do with this kind of
stuff we look at the binary so it's
signed by a bus just signatures is valid
binary method but if I strike for us so
our first reaction is young maybe about
a giant have an issue maybe it was
positive
something recurrent and we we start to
take a look at it to understand why we
have real behavior and we detected in
fact
managed to cut inside of the vegetable
pilot so the compromised machines of
version with the malicious code is a
version 533 and cloud fashion to they
have two different they maintain to the
front version but to say and Jack to say
binary bodies and if you look on the
change like what I'm going to speak
today is my notebook
very and and the thing is if you looked
at that night so here we have two my
topic and one week after that we work
certificate so anyway so something
realistic for making us a point of view
I don't know if you give us a lot of
windows binary but generally the first
thing you don't do is witnessing contact
real time is good at by compiler
managers had the fact that so basically
we both write this code it's
automatically done by visuals video for
Intel oh dear
what did this hat occur do he modify
attack in order to jump on malicious
code so basically when you are with us a
heuristic illegitimate binary signed and
his five megabytes you don't look
forward that just so it is case again
just to work on read time and really at
the beginning of execution of of the
manual he simply had a put inside of
front time to jump on Nash's cut what is
the purpose of the malicious cut it's
not so baby it's even a little bit
smaller purpose is simply to download
additional stage and execute it but you
do it with a really specific way so when
seeking has a legitimate application is
rent run demands we did the manager of
managers path and continues the
legitimate
execution of seeking orz application
works as usual she makes some big extra
detective it's a VM on that first he
makes some slips he wait delays if the
delay is modified so if he waits I think
it's three six hundred second if it's
less he decided it's a sentence the
delay was decreased bison ox it's a
common way to work for force angles also
I think he checked the user privilege
because Sakina most vibrant it add me so
if it's not read as I admit it's
probably standard something not normal
so if it's not executed at an execution
and if everything looks fine you finally
decide to contact SAP to do so he has a
really realistic way he tried to contact
an IP CIP on the slide and if the IP
doesn't reply it was ok during
investigation the IP didn't work so if
it does not work it generates domain
based on the month succulent dance and
based on domain he make DNS requests so
DNS requests gift to IP he makes some
solve and by manipulation to delight the
third IP and this find an IP will be the
c2 so the point is if you look at binary
and you simply work statically you see
an IP you say yeah we know not discreet
it's more complicated it generated the
main but this domain is not really used
as CC this domain is used to generate to
get to a bit and generate the final
address so it's very specific not
something common here is some domain
generated from each month of last year
here it's Open DNS output to show you
you really have activities on this
specific digits you have requests insist
domain during one month and the month
after
it's zero and the new domain Matthews so
you really can see the activities by not
so what is the purpose of of the
connection to the CC to purpose was to
register the mission so compromise
system by giving some information in
stock program process this kind of
information do we will see later exactly
what kind of information I see if the
mission was relevant for see how that
gets he can decide to send a second
stage to the mission to the compromise
system so the struggle stage is a dll he
uses sample stuff used legitimate binary
and bad legitimate binary with many
sheets cut but on a vast case the binary
was signed and the signatures was valid
so the attackers had managed to cut
before during or before compilation of
binary by the vast as side in this case
is simply batch binary but the binary
didn't have any signatures so they don't
think they compromise what I was tagging
tactics of the case is simply into
binary but said I'd use it like Kentucky
to west and yeah he started batch binary
which is to be and he used exactly the
same trick he decided to work on a
runtime so it matched runtime of
of the binary - exactly malicious code
so basically what liver cell phones
really take time to look at we can have
no information about about this thing
see beef they will reverse Iran in the
room he uses more tricks really Griffin
and it can make you crazy here on the
left you have Idaho capture the graph
view of ila Pro and if you look at the
end the function finished by a bot and
is really unusual if you reverse a lot
of binary never finished Bible but if
you switch the text view you can see in
fact finish my job so use a feature of
Ida Ida use some specific section to
identify the beginning and the end of
the specific fraction typical for run
type and enter guide modified to say to
either the section finish one bite
before and I don't have you forget to
display to you the job but if you work
in text you you can seize a job without
issue we are safe
haha is not impacted by this by setting
the body use
[Music]
yeah the purpose of this second stage
was Morris as a statement the previous
one but with an additional pillow but
instead of losing de leus get IP to
generate an IP he performed took went on
to legitimate website it up and
WordPress get information from this to
website make some byte manipulation to
generate a new IP
so the approach is the same but instead
of using DNS it used to legitimate
website during our investigation the
page this two page and this to specific
search on this website didn't give us
any results so we were not able to go on
the next page on the next binary but you
can look on Google of aspects research
and maybe found the next stage but we
didn't so I will speak about about it
yeah so on to stage 1 there is a crystal
about 64 function to encode and decode
string
I think it's Kaspersky or integers I
don't remember this movie yeah identify
that this specific piston
by 64 function was implemented exactly
with the same way on a group named
Liberty 70 or group for us so what is a
group we've indexed on Google search
about it but it's a niche to be a
Chinese occur so be careful because
consuming like this time it works
sometimes it doesn't work you must be
pretty careful based attribution on a
few few after weather good idea
but anyway just effect so that's what
Manuel part and subsequent interesting
maybe the most interesting part we had
access to a common core and we were able
to make investigation on the data a bit
of the c2 and information the people
compromised so it's really easy it's
simply PHP website of no rocket science
with a script itself as something that
can that is pretty clever for my point
of view
Sakina modifies the binary uses specific
requests make posters effect that to
connect to c2 and if you talk contact so
Sarah was exactly the good way
if you perform get instead of post if
you do this kind of thing it will
automatically redirect you to perform
the first so companies are trade Sakina
so in Ag you have suspicions you are
analyzing this stuff you find weird
connection to this wheel domain if you
found your brothers you put the domain
you will know what the heck to pay for
the developers of CK so you will say how
yeah it's very formats like it's not my
so it's it's better here is the
configuration file so you have user name
for that eval password the time zone so
obviously I can't
if I thought on my server pH happiest at
least Texan and you put DLL name is a
path of the stay on stage so key setup
is the second stage pushed on machines
at the rest attackers here is a database
creation and a request if you are good a
spill injection could probably speed
objection and here is asscher-cut
executed on machine to download the
second stage okay
the most interesting part is this
statistical so when a mission is
compromised with a stage one so billion
of machine developer country to mention
send instant application running
processes the rabbit the Machine sent
this IP and the Machine sent the domain
from activity a great point of view so
domain where the passion inside and the
ethicist implement two filters based on
this information so the first bit says
is based on the mail so basically if the
machine has the specific domain I sent
to stage two and the second filter buys
on IP if the compromised machine has
society i send specific stitch to the 80
was the truth
on this tab the domain was used
we found domain under configuration and
system a nice mesh organization company
entities that interests the specific
actor here is the list of the domain
that the attacker was a big fall so if
signal is external machine and the
machine is buying to one of this domain
theater cast specifically automatically
sends a stage to see on machine is not
by nominal system a who machine was
compromised by stage one it makes some
request every day to the c2 to see
if a second stage is ready for or
forward for it but that sort you know
provides that you don't bond got
additional pin if you are one of these
domain you will receive additional
pillow so as you can see it's mainly IT
company so this Atticus's group this guy
is mainly interested by IT company he
compromised a really a lot of machine
but after he did has more freedom on a
very specific target so if you look at
the data that you can you have three
tables the table names Terra table
contain all the mission compromised by
stage one so on mention where Sikandar
this discussion was it's done the ok
table was the table where you have
machines that see the stage two to
basically machine by this is the main
and get this was empty I did some
statistics about the machine to number
extra cos location regular but keep in
mind it's before they of that up because
the attackers had some issue both life
is hard and cut four days before the
acquisition he lost his machine due to
face stem food so he had to mince that
everything it starts at TB and that's
why we only have four days I think he
was a victim of his success didn't
expect so many that I dated
Sevilla compromised machine and finally
didn't paid off in this book and it's
only one seven two five we notified we
did not forget that successful to the
five service it's a table the server
table so yeah it's basically what they
said to you and I did the Machine IP
address Windows version process Lee
I mean as they live in they live in a
mist from activity to a point of view
MAC address software overlap here is an
example of data or you can guest change
machine and you have a list of vacation
running processing stock you have the
pocket table this one is more
interesting because it contains all
machine that receive a second stage so
own machine that the Atticus was really
wasting at this exact time where we have
the database we know that he sent a
second stage in control of 25 machine so
it looks like a lot but 25 deputies but
anyway it's it's not a lot compared to
the global mission you will see just
that but 20 little bit more than 20
machine receive the second stage so if
we look from that statistic point of
view I count the number of the tech
machine in the database and we are more
than 83 800,000 system so the guy had
access to almost 1 million mission and
he decided to compromise only 20 little
bit motivated so he has a really big but
net of ship at least in four days also
point it's hard to identify Keener it
was used by a lot of individual
individual user at home and my goal was
to identify complex organization extra
and to separate this kind of profile and
end users I don't have a magic way to do
it so you technically use ice we decide
to check if the machines bind to the
main I estimate that at home you don't
have to make and if I use this technique
I could count how many machine i bind
the metro
how many machine i estimated sport and
in this case is
41,000 mission so this is for my point
of view it's a short ride reticent
Morris the number of corporate machine
compromised bases guy with stage one and
potentially stage two later
if he wants a vixen was a query and
typically I would like to know if some
domain have a lot of a permutation so in
this case you have the output of the
account by the main so typically a
specific domain specific organization on
the D company has 960 compromised
machine in his organization by that
specifically and after several verdict
whatever so some organization had a lot
of work does they had a lot of
compromised machine with this signal
version installed during our
distribution I make some statistic about
operating system but simply protection
of life you have a lot of Windows 7 you
have some windows 10 and Windows XP so
it's agreed it's simply represent I
think but with the main we can make some
more muffins requests typically here I
was looking for domain containing gov
and I've got 500 machine from domain
containing god or same thing with 951 so
this machine have a bite
the male named go something about
something a little bit more dangerous I
check on install software on the mission
and the first query I was looking for if
some machine half PFC simulator instead
and I found Turkmen mission compromised
by stage one with the PFC simulator
pieces for scholastic history and other
stuff and in this case its simulator so
it's probably developers of this kind of
profile that are compromised very sick
he knew another one the second one is I
was looking for machine that had mud
boots inside and I got more than 200
machine within good juice application
instead and we would use protocol
supported by Patriots with that people
that work Boris on this kind of of the
main PC industry and the last one is
probably the worst Prairie the first one
was bill gives simulator so to simulate
and developed and the last one is
monitoring so I've got night vision
compromised with application used to
monitor his to monitor scholastic
industry of stuff extra and in this case
the article had access to two to nine
machine which gives monitoring system
it's tough luck be our dentist this is
all this much only receive two stage one
so she Atticus was not interesting by
this machine at this time it was here we
be for eternity with the value lit with
what she yeah this morning I decided to
make some Canadian statistics just for
you
exclusivity so I close to 14,000
infected system with IPP Canada or
Canada we make some search on Active
Directory domain 300 domain
contain dot C a2 to me
globally represent 1.6 percent of of
infection but the difference between
each list more active first one
represent free post
twits 32.9 2.8 everybody very close and
it's like this most popular cartridge
into situate first country so a lot of
machine so location to case a cop it
different on the purpose on where it is
produced as I said was to compromise the
maximum with machine and and go destroy
everything basically and in my case sick
little kid the purpose was to compromise
a maximal machine but send to Peter to
find a winner
very very specific target you can see
the list it's really really specific but
if we you notify this behavior inside of
secretive application the guy could keep
this but then during years and should
target change to profile X right ready
when designed then you can easily change
everything on the map speaking more
globally about speech an attack we did
more at the same previously and we have
the first question how we can be
protected about a channel and I think I
will have the same question so our
Moon's rights it's really really
complicated and I will not have any
answer typically if we if we look at
near jackets this kind of the if you
have a really separate network without
not a flat network for everything in the
same place your major application will
be compromised will be encrypted but
Manuel won't be able to propagate inside
of your network so if you have if you
leave it your network with very specific
business with few machine X trying you
got and they were correct network design
you can mitigate our lipids impact of
this kind of compromise for ccleaner
it's very different without hot
propagation and it's what should instant
and in this case it's more take care of
activity type it looks stupid but it's
fact and it's not positive freeware
thought it's massively used it's not
because it's he had to have a good
reputation that you can answer it
everywhere like that just because and in
this case I think you know it was more
complicated to identify caused by to be
signed you can just provider you could
have a contract I think they do they
have in service and just send the
application extra and in this case it's
really very complicated to identify and
to be honest we I have strict rules to
help you in supply chain attack and it's
what is very scary because you trust
your provider I'm fit sure you are not
able to count some mongoloid are you
have hundred thousand for different
provider and and forests its readily
complicate it would be more complicated
with time we have one more provider and
see first row is one more complex and
this kind of stuff extend with years
because simply with this application is
really used by a lot of people so we can
get lucky and a researcher will find it
that yen but if it's a provider more
explicit
specific application and the only a few
customers it would take a lot of time
before through the research optic type
you gotta find something yeah we build
it bomb at several hundred thousand
hosts in four days I mean if that guy
and say guy had that individual personal
group malicious actor whatever we want
to call them how to chips what they
wanted to do that bought that only four
days even thought that that's more its
porky of this Impala it's like knackers
which is one of the biggest most highly
regarded email spam not was the work we
do don't every older but they I wanted
to mine an cor cryptocurrency
interviewed millionaire it's Paul said
we find it but that doesn't necessarily
make it someone else we do we find it
looking at digital beta tested which is
how we identified it how do we not we do
now that we potentially would defined it
because obviously see clear about the
fire at the time all that came to
fruition was see Peter had befallen her
from well a fast that purchase a company
called Perico unfortunately they have
acquired a breach as a service at that
point which is okay and that's open you
also need to be a world is way off you
working.i precision type stuff you you
are a trusted supplier that little bit
you need to be sure that the people
you're bringing it here now order it
here infrastructure it's someone you
trust that's very hard to do it pulse it
we we definitely don't have the right
answers to difficult ask us we will who
would tell you but yeah we as the last
night says there we felt that at the
stories of the supplies here - we don't
be enjoyed be very questions please ask