thank you that was the nicest intro I've
ever had I think so thank you very much
who here is from Montreal yeah you guys
have an awesome city this is day two for
me in Montreal and man it I think I got
to move here just amazing so this talk
is really weird
last year I competed in the sec TF came
in third that was kind of my goal top
three this year they've accepted me back
again my goal is number one so I'm gonna
be shooting for that and since that time
period over the last year I've had
exposure to different people that are in
the business both good people and bad
people that have kind of coached me and
given me insights and and companies have
asked me to present and talk to them as
well so this talk has evolved over the
last year and so what you're going to
get is the product of that and has
anybody seen this talk before awesome
that's great perfect because just in
case I have added some some more
additional content and I've tried to
I've tried to incorporate some of the
information that really bad people have
given me so hopefully that'll make a
little more interesting for you so a
little bit about myself just so you know
like why I should be up here talking
about it so I worked in IT forever I've
got a bunch of certs and stuff I work in
the aerospace industry so a big because
of the industry a big part of my time is
security pretty much all of my time I
volunteer for a local search and rescue
team and I folk my focus in that team is
as a tracker so why is that relevant
here because for OSINT open-source
intelligence it's very similar to
tracking I found and and I also created
a nonprofit called trace lab so if you
want to check that out please do so if
you have any interest in OSINT and you
want to do good for your community let
me know looking for people that can help
out there trying to bridge that gap
between the traditional
search-and-rescue that are out in the
bushes typically that's what I do I'm
looking for footprints and sign and then
bringing that to the modern age where
I'm actually looking at your your online
presence and then locating you that way
so it's really interesting for me this
whole thing has evolved and taken off
over
last year for me which is pretty
exciting as we go through the
presentation if there's stuff you like
or stuff you don't like let me know
Twitter is probably the best way just
say he robbed this slide as a typo or
yeah I really like this slide you should
put more content in that area in your
presentation so that would be really
appreciated thank you all right so what
are we going to cover today this is
basically the high level what we're
going to go through today some
definitions some introductions then I'm
going to show you some of the techniques
that I used at Def Con and then I'm
going to talk about what bad guys do as
well and then everybody wants tools I'm
gonna go through tools a little bit but
I'm just going to tell you that tools
are very our tools are less important
than technique I find there's a new tool
every day so I'll show you some tools
but yeah it's I think it's really just
learning how to do OSINT and then
there's there's tons of tools out there
alright I have to show you this one of
my employers has asked me to do this so
I say a lot of things and a lot of those
things I disagree with even the next day
so nothing I say here today is is
related to any employer I've ever had or
ever will have so just have to get that
out of the way all right so let's get
into it
this social engineering stuff what what
is this this thing right so it's
basically manipulation and how does that
differ than from say influence influence
would be where it's in your best
interest I might be working with you and
saying hey you know what if you took
this course maybe you could get a better
you know a career advancement or
something like that I'm kind of looking
out for your best interest whereas
manipulation it's usually I'm gonna
coerce you to do something or say
something that that's gonna get you in
trouble so that that's what it's all
about there's a fine line there I find
that when I talk to people after they
learned that I'm into social engineering
immediately they don't wanna talk to me
because they think I'm gonna manipulate
them but that's not always true it's
sometimes I'm influencing so so so when
we go to the party tonight don't I'll
take off I'm not trying to trick you
okay all right okay so so what are some
examples of social engineering we have
what I call the golden oldies they are
still around today
impersonation we have both the physical
and the virtual impersonation so you
you put on your overalls and you and you
have like the the recycling or garbage
or whatever the vendor is and you just
stick your on your overalls and you walk
into the building like you're supposed
to be there and then also more popular
now is the virtual impersonation where
you're pretending to be somebody else
tailgating still a problem right we
still have people that just gonna walk
in behind someone else the trick now is
you if you're a lady you can put
something in your in your belly some
patty and pretend you're pregnant right
or you can carry the big stack of pizzas
or doughnuts right nobody wants to stop
you if you're carrying doughnuts um so
that's still a problem shoulder surfing
less of a problem now but you know you
still see it on the bus at the airport
it's great I always look because I want
to kind of see how much I can see screen
protectors are great but not all of us
use those dumpster-diving is a little
better now we shred most of our stuff so
that's that's a little better so I have
stay out of the for that's probably the
one that's improved the most but they're
still relevant right some more current
attacks so these are the ones we see
more today the email attack the phishing
right one of my personal favorites
phishing right that's where they're
phoning you and in the submission that's
the SMS attack all direct I'll trying to
misguide you and give you put you into a
cred harvesting area right so and and
what's really effective now is attackers
will use these in combination especially
if they're going to be targeting a whale
or your executive right so very
effective if you can do them within a
short period of time altogether and then
we get into more current stuff right
what's happening next and so this list
keeps growing and it's really busy slide
every day there's something new so
social media impersonation fake accounts
so you're in the lineup to rent your car
it's taken forever you're getting pissed
off it's like you know so you send a
tweet to the company it's like you know
this is terrible you and you get a tweet
back and it says hey I'm sorry about
your experience click this link and
we'll give you a free credit right and
it's not actually them it's just
somebody who's created an account that
looks like them so what that works
really well social engineering as a
service right we all want scalability so
you know the bad guys do
- so this everybody's everybody's doing
this now you can get nyle of service
attacks whatever you want as a service
now super easy takes you five minutes
virtual kidnapping another one which has
multiple benefits right so if I can get
your account I can ransom it back to you
I can do bad things with your account to
make you want to pay I can engage your
friends right and you can do a lot of
wonderful things they're whaling your
executives so the saffron rose we saw
that a little bit in the news executives
hold the keys to the castle right so
they're really gonna be my target a lot
of times they have control over the
money they have control over they have
authority so they can get other people
to do stuff so if you're not training
your executive that's probably something
you want to look at sudo ransomware a
hybrid attack so this is a one we see
more and more from sophisticated threat
actors especially in nation-states and
stuff so they know you have limited
resources especially in your InfoSec
groups and they know that you're
probably understaffed even right so if
they can distract you get you working on
this stuff over here they know they can
then come over here and do stuff and you
may not notice or you're definitely
gonna have less left staff to deal with
it anyway professional network
solicitation
again this is growing becoming more
popular if you get a solicitation from a
very attractive young lady saying that
she thinks you're amazing and you have
great knowledge and you should come to
this conference it might be fake just
saying is it I could go the other way -
so sorry that's the example that I've
seen so SME conference invite espionage
baiting so we see this a little bit come
to our conference my fake headhunters
those thousands talent program yeah
that's very popular you can google that
guy sock puppets so we're seeing that
more and more right so anytime you want
to influence a lot of fake news out
there do so this we see more and more
and this is really where we see it going
a lot of you know this does not new a
lot of companies and governments do this
more now now large employment in this
area as well
I think in Canada we don't really see
much of it but there is a huge effort in
this area all right so the origin story
of social engineering it's been around
forever it's not a new thing the people
who built the pyramids I'm pretty sure
they were really good at social
engineering and if you want to get a
crash course in social engineering you
can just walk onto a used-car lot and
and engage with the people there it's
wonderful I love doing that get a big
coffee and just go on there and let them
go to work and it's a wonderful
experience all right so the trend why do
we care right we know where it came from
it's been around for a while but why do
we care about this sort of stuff so it's
it's growing it's it's growing so and if
it was a stock I always like to like to
relate stuff to stock right so if it was
a stock it would be a super hot hot
stock from the growth rate of that right
this is from the 27t and Verizon report
and so yeah you can compare it to some
other things right the what they call
hack you know I forget the definition
that we put into that but that's the
stock recommended by your friend that is
never a good idea so that's why we care
just because it's it's used as a
precursor to almost all the attacks
right either OSINT or social engineering
of some type historically we've never
really cared about it very much for
those of you that have you're done your
CISSP you're very familiar with this
model right very focused on the
technical levels right and I think it's
time we started to look at the as the
people as an additional level of this
thing why would I spend time trying to
hack a firewall or do anything technical
when I can call one of your employees
ask for the password and then they will
give it to me
right five minutes so it's super easy
low-cost so it's the first thing we go
to all right so this is the kevin
Mitnick quote I've had great debates
with people about this and I'm not
saying it's people are very easy to
trick generally right it's not because
they're not smart or anything bad like
that it's just that you know you're
super busy we had a couple presenters up
here earlier that we're talking about
that you get hundreds if not thousands
of emails so that's part of the problem
so it's this is not necessarily negative
but it does seem to be reality does
anybody disagree that social engineering
is really a really big concern that that
anybody could could be tricked
somebody has to disagree otherwise I
can't do the demo all right thank you
thank thank you thank you sir thank you
sir
that's exactly what I was looking for
yeah thank you
all right so this is the interactive
part of the presentation and I hate this
part so I hate it because it's a
lose-lose situation for me if I trick
you you're gonna hate me if I don't
trick you I'm a fraud
so I lose both ways but it is kind of
fun okay so let's do this really quick
social engineering demo and let's for
the sake of the demo let's pretend we're
one big company okay everybody in this
for in this room right now we've all
just signed up for this startup we're
really excited about it I'm the one in
plus that guy right because that ratio
is about right right and yeah so uh so I
got to write some policies about stuff
that you shouldn't do right so I'm going
to say no to everything that you want to
do the first thing we're going to do
something that's visible I'm going to do
let's do hand flipping okay that's
something I was going to do dancing but
I don't think we want to go there yet
because we haven't enough beers so let's
say hand flipping I'm gonna write a
policy because everybody reads my
policies right no hand flipping allowed
okay so this is where you look at your
neighbor and you place bets if you want
so don't flip your hands everybody clear
so put your hands out like a zombie so
everybody can see your hands please all
right let's all right everybody let's
start with our palms up
all right that's the demo so I'm sorry
I'm sorry
typically I get half the room I notice
some of you didn't put your hands up but
I get half the room so it's a stupid
trick right ridiculous but it kind of
gives you an idea of that's the the
misdirection just a quick example if I
if we try hard enough we can get most
people with with these sort of tricks
right if you're if you want to do a
fishing program at work and you need
more ammunition to justify the cost just
Google that there's tons of stuff out
there you know executives giving away 50
million dollars with a bank transfer
super embarrassing day right yeah so all
right so Def Con se CTF what was that
all about really interesting if anybody
wants to do that let me know I'd be
happy to to go through it with you I'm
gonna be there again this year in
general I think the CTF s no matter with
its se or whatever it is super valuable
I would recommend that to anybody over a
course you're gonna learn a ton so I
can't say too many good things about
that so the the SC CTF is basically two
stages the first stage is euro cent so
you're given a target and I'll be
received in mine for this year shortly
and there's 16 competitors and we all
look at a certain industry last year it
was the gaming industry so I got a
company from from the gaming industry
and you've got about three weeks to do
your OSINT your open source intelligence
and at the time I was terrible at it I
didn't know what I was doing so it took
me about a hundred hours so that's
evenings and weekends and any moment I
could spare I was doing OSINT and you
have 29 flags that you try to collect
they're fairly benign things like what
kind of VPN do you use how long have you
worked for the company what kind of
browser do you have stuff like that not
not too bad right and then you collect
that you do your report you hand it in
and you get points and then you go to
Vegas and you go into a glass booth and
you have a couple hundred people
watching you and you've got 20 minutes
to perform and you're going for the same
flags
but you can go through multiple people
on the phone and the winner is the
person with the most flags the most
points so you basically have that kind
of recon and then the attack phase much
like what an attacker would do and these
are real companies which makes it a lot
of fun so these are the flags you
probably can't read that but it's you
know pretty straightforward stuff oh do
you have a cafeteria what's your VPN
janitorial janitorial is great if you
want to do physical pen testing later
what's your OS how long you work there
so pretty normal stuff right like if you
if this got in the wild you wouldn't
worry about it too much
but these are the ones that you probably
would worry about so you know and I see
this all the time with companies you
know I look at you know for job postings
I love looking at job postings all the
technologies are listed there even they
even talk about if it's a InfoSec job
their response capabilities what kind of
assets they have it's fantastic right I
want to take all your assets and
resources in an area over here distract
you and then attack over here that's
great to know that information
what's your patch level so that actually
is pretty good so if I'm going to give
you an exploit I kind of want to know
what your patch level is and what kind
of protection you're going to have there
delivery methods so I'm like am I going
to fish you what's that going to look
like am I going to drop some USB keys in
your elevator right that's that's nice
to get a nose so some companies they'll
lock the USB so that's not a viable
attack method exploitation
what kind of antivirus do you have right
is it behavior based or signature based
that's really nice to know on your
perimeter what does that look like all
these things are usually advertised and
not hard to find alerting what's your
sim does anybody look at your logs right
so that's a really nice thing to know
what are your hours of operations so
this is great for doing your recon stage
because I'll dial in to your PBX and
I'll hopefully nobody will answer your
phone and I'll get a bunch of
information from your phone from your
recordings and stuff like that machine
naming so that's quite often advertised
and very easy to get as well and that'll
help me locate key resources hours of
operate I did that
location of your asset so your your dr
as well right so quite often the DRP
plan is public or readily available so
that's really nice to know how you will
respond to these things so if I shut off
your HVAC if I shut off your generator
or something like that
a lot of people's generators out in the
parking lot actually pretty easily to
acts to access that I can just plug into
it turn that off and people freak out
that's a good distraction so all those
things are very nice to find and it's
usually out there easy too easy to see
all right so on the O's inside let's
talk about that for a minute the first
thing I want to do is you know I'm going
to acquire my target and start going
through that methodically step by step
up I'll look at the physical first so
where are you located
you know the country is important you're
building locations Google Street View is
awesome it's a slice in time but quite
often I can learn so much from that
right egress points you know what does
your roof look like do you have a lot of
HVAC on the roof do you have entry
points loading docks
what's all that look like points of
entry who does your parking right so I
can call your employees and say I'm from
that particular parking company that
works really well then I'm moving into
technical and quite often this is really
nice and there's a lot of great
information there who's registered your
website I'll get contact information
they're almost always IP addresses so I
want your block of ip what that looks
like and then corporate you know who's a
lot of registration information we'll
have a lot of people that are less
technical that I can reach out to your
lawyers your HR finance people property
management is really good and often
overlooked so I can call your property
management company and pretend I'm you
or a representative from your company
and they will typically give me a ton of
stuff and then we get into your staff
and this is where it just explodes as
far as information and just go to
LinkedIn that's your first kind of go to
stop and it's wonderful because it's all
it's all packaged up really nicely right
and you can get 90% of your stuff on on
the staff right there
it will try to make you pay as you go
through and start using it and that's
their their model but you can use
certain tools to get around that
recruitment extra link LinkedIn x-ray
was one of the tools I used but there's
a whole bunch of tools out there that
will help you do that some of them are
automated so you can just scrape it and
pull it all down I tend not to automate
too much just because I find it's more
effective for me to just do a little bit
more manually so then once you're going
through the people you've got a
collection of people you'll find that
about you know it's the 80/20 rule
there's gonna be some social butterflies
out there that post a ton of stuff and
those are the really the targets you
want to go for you don't want to so you
can spend huge amounts of time chasing
down everybody but you really want to
refine your search and get those people
that are just gonna give you a you know
a lot of information and even sometimes
their friends even if they're not
working for the company they will be
taking pictures and talking about they
their friend who works for the company
so focus on that and then for detection
so when I did this I was so bad I went
on LinkedIn and I was looking at all
these people and you know when you look
at someone's LinkedIn they then will
sometimes look at yours because they
wonder like who is this person why is
the person looking at my stuff so they
look at your stuff when you do that to
about a thousand people that all work
for the same company and then you
realize they're all turning around
looking at you it becomes a little
little nervous a little nerve-wracking
so that's what I did and it's like oh
that's a big mistake so you want to be
careful with that set up your platform
appropriately so that they're not going
to be taking a bunch of information from
you as well right there's a bunch of
options out there
buscador by Michael Bozell I've tried
that I'm actually not a big fan of that
I think you might want to just try it
out it's specifically it's a it's a
Linux distro that's specifically
designed for OSINT
I'm a big Michael pizzelle fan great
podcast great books great website great
tools on his website highly recommend
that it's a great starting point I kind
of lean more towards like a Kali Linux
platform running on VirtualBox or VMware
so you can then archive that for
evidence
and set up a VPN as well do all those
things I mean you're probably already
doing this as well but when I did it
I didn't do any of that and it was a bit
embarrassing all right so some
preparations I'm developing a course for
first responders and part of it is for
search and rescue and part of it it's
going to be for them retaining evidence
and if you're working for a company you
probably want to retain evidence as well
hunch Lee is a great product but there's
other products out there as well though
when you want to think when you start
doing this how are you collecting data
if it's even for a CTF you're gonna have
the same problem right you're going
after certain flags you don't want to
spend time learning all about the
company all aspects of it you really
want to refine your search because you
can go down a bunch of different rabbit
holes and that's that's kind of what I
did what's important what if you're
writing a report for your executive you
know what are they going to care about
so summarizing all that data and then
how are you staying undetected like I
did not all right so as I was developing
preparing for DEFCON part of that was my
pretext development and pretext is
basically your lie so you have them mark
and you're going to tell them a lie and
you have to develop that so that it's
believable and your receptionist's I
find are some of the best people to talk
to about this because they're they're
generally very good at quickly analyzing
somebody and figuring out if they're
legit or not and so I spent a lot of
time with our receptionist and and they
were they're awesome you should invest
in your receptionist as well right so
not only are they kind of the physical
firewall to your building quite often
but they're getting all those calls from
people like me as well and so typically
they don't get a lot of user awareness
training but I think we definitely have
an opportunity there to invest so
they've been super helpful then once
I've got a list of people for your
company I'm gonna take a look at okay so
who are going to be my actual marks so
whether it be at DEFCON or a real
attacker I need to have a shorter list
of people and typically that's going to
be on LinkedIn I'm going to look at
their connection scores and I'm going to
look at the ones that have say less than
100 because they're not well connected
only with your organization but in
general in the industry so those are
going to usually be people that are
fairly new to the industry which is good
because they're not going to know a lot
of people they're not going to know
what's inappropriate necessarily and I'm
also going to look for people that take
a lot of selfies that share a lot of
information hopefully that information
is inappropriate so if they have a
picture of their VPN configuration
perfect that's who I'm looking for
so that's that's sexually a true story I
I found that that person and they gave
me tons of stuff so basically I'm
looking for a high charisma low wisdom
scores and strangely enough that turns
in that translates into interns and
contractors and I think that mostly
that's because they're fairly new to the
organization typically in new to the
industry just out of school sometimes
and they're not as invested so from a
contractual if they're contractors
they're coming typically for a six-month
job and then they're going to another
company in another company so they're
doing some self promotion they're not as
invested so that's typically how it
works for me so I'll automatically now
look at the interns and the contractors
right away so all right some of the
techniques and this is mostly psychology
I want to develop rapport with you I
want to get you talking to me
and I want you to feel comfortable so I
will do some things like the
confirmation so how do you like your new
Dell laptops and in your mind you're
thinking well we do use Dell laptop so
you may not even consciously think about
this but you know your response if
you're having problems you're gonna be
oh yeah they're terrible the USB ports
don't work or something like that but
it's it's it's kind of like we've
skipped a whole stage in the
conversation which is exactly when I
watch right all of a sudden now we're
talking we're going back and forth or I
might you know if I if I can stand it
for my ego I might do the reverse
conformation where I'll let you correct
me and people typically like to correct
others so I'll say oh how do you like
your to Sheba's you're like no we don't
used to Sheba's we use Dells oh sorry
sorry yeah I got that mixed up so that's
often quite nice to do as well
name-dropping so this is pretty typical
oh yeah your VP mr. or mrs. so-and-so
said I should talk to you that works
quite well I've used that blowing smoke
you were recommended to us right so to
make you feel good real attackers don't
do this very much unless it's a very
targeted attack but at Def Con this
works great anytime you make somebody
feel good that's usually going to be
quite effective sales people use this
right so typically I talk about
attackers salespeople and then DEFCON
CTF people so those are kind of the
three main groups impending doom I've
used this one this works actually quite
well so something big is about to happen
and there's no choice there it's going
to happen that event is going to occur
but I'm here to help you get through it
so hey Larry's going to be on site
tomorrow we won the RFP for your HVAC
and I'm just calling to get that set up
and is there anything that he needs to
know before he gets on site can he just
is there a card he needs sorting some ID
or can easier Wi-Fi when he's there how
about the bathroom do you have a
cafeteria he could eat lunch there so
I'm just going to start going through
that and that's very effective allowed
to vent real attackers don't use this
too much you know if you can relate to
them and they can start to unload on you
you know you can be their therapist a
little bit that can be effective smarty
pants very effective you know if you can
say you know how did you ever figure
this out you know this is my first day
my boss is yelling at me you know can
you help me a lot sympathy agreed so
greed is something that real attackers
use a lot and you've seen this in the
phishing attempts that you've gotten you
know it's oftentimes sensitive it's
zero-sum so the first three people to
reply win a trip to wherever right or a
cruise the cruise is the popular one
right on your phone so that's that's
very popular we did a fishing program
where I work and the time-sensitive one
was the most effective and so I like
that sympathy and we're designed to care
about people which is a good thing right
but it's for attackers they utilize that
as well so you know I'm brand new to the
organization my
AWS's yelling at me I think I'm gonna
get fired if I don't get this done can
you please help me like who wouldn't
write if we were pretty cold to ignore
that so then my pretext for fishing I
basically got three different styles of
pretexts personally there's a ton of
them out there the entry method one is
the first one so a company that's kind
of set up to defend against this will
have their their ingress points kind of
designed to filter some of that so I
want to get past reception and these are
designed to do that so if I once I've
done my ocean I know you have interns
you have certain people that work there
from different schools I can call from
the school spoof the school number and
say hey I'm calling to talk to so-and-so
I just want to talk to them about their
their intern experience and see if they
can give us feedback on how we can
improve that going forward to get past
reception nine out of ten receptionists
they buy into that so that was pretty
good industry knowledge if you have any
industry knowledge whatever that is
right for me it's data centers and stuff
like that that's what I'll focus on so
I'll talk about things like HVAC because
I sound you know like I'm knowledgeable
in that area so that tends to work
targeted methods and Mitnick was great
at this right if you listen to some of
his or read some of his books he's he
likes to layer things and this is very
effective where you're calling one
person and you're getting a bit
information you're calling somebody else
getting a little bit more and then
finally calling somebody else and
getting that final piece but you're
building that house of knowledge right
from those little bits information and
each one seems relevant relatively
unimportant right but it allows you get
to the next step so the enemy of my
enemy so calling the property management
as if you're a potential tenant or
another one of the tenants as if you're
a potential tenant just asking them
about you know so what's what's it like
there what's the building like are you
having any problems what's building
management like are they good are they
responsive yeah I've even had any
problems with the sprinkler systems or
the building alarm who do you use for
security are they any good so people
typically responsive to that special
delivery
anytime you can copy a scripted response
which is typically quite easy to do
right so the FedEx one that I used in
Def Con was that they had a parcel that
had some border taxes and I asked them
would you like to you know pay for that
on delivery or just pay for that right
now
I can put it on your FedEx account right
now if you'd like to do that and she
gave me the the FedEx account right away
and they beep that out because I didn't
actually want that but just to confirm
that they use FedEx but anytime you can
copy a script because that's all people
are listening to is the script which is
very familiar to most of us can I tell
you a secret everybody likes secrets
right I got a group of people that we're
gonna lay off and they've asked me to
call you and find out about your company
and your benefits and because and I can
send you their resumes so I'd call a
recruiter and do that and the recruiter
is usually has a fiscal benefit and
helping me because they're gonna get a
if they bring somebody on there get a
bonus for that so they're very motivated
to talk to me to see these high
potential resumes so if you can locate
somebody who's going to get you know a
bonus to talk to you not that's even
better so that's what they're thinking
about and these are the full dump
methods and typically you wouldn't think
these would work very well but if you
get people on a roll they actually do
and in DEFCON this is great because you
only have 20 minutes to deliver a whole
bunch of stuff so you can if you can do
this and just blow through a bunch of
questions it works great you're a lucky
winner I didn't do that this is used all
the time very real attackers we're all
very used to it you're never the lucky
winner the upgrade opportunity I like
this one because you know some of us we
have different equipment different
vendors and nobody tells you when the
vendor changes quite often right you
just get some out of the blue call it's
like yeah hi I'm your new new supplier
your new account rep okay so I was going
to do that I never did it but I like
that one I might do it this year the
employee engagement survey we all like
to give feedback and I find the
engagement surveys great I use this one
it works really well hey so and so it's
not combining a few different techniques
so and so you're VP of HR told me to
phone you and said that you know you
be really helpful for this exercise I'd
like to get your feedback on the
employment engagement and how we can
make a survey to help promote that I've
just got a few questions for you if you
have two minutes it's always two minutes
right actually I want 20 but it's always
two minutes and then I just go back
through all the questions there's some
discussion around if you get caught as a
social engineer what you should do and
they say that you know you never get out
of character even when they're putting
the cuffs on you you just stay in
character I don't want to go to jail so
I'm not going to follow that advice so
what I was prepared to do was if they
catch me and and say well I'm not really
believing what you're what you're
selling here I would immediately because
then I wanted people to feel good I
don't want to be victimizing people I
would say hey congratulations that's
awesome
you caught me so you know because I was
hired by your company to do this this
test and see you know if you would fall
for these tricks and congratulations can
I get your name because I want to tell
your VP of whatever that you did a great
job yeah so thank you very much and just
to baseline these questions can I just
go through these questions with you real
quick just to make sure I got the right
answers and I was just dying to do that
so maybe this hearing so the spirit of
DEFCON is to not victimize I mean you're
targeting a real company but you don't
want to hang up on somebody and make
them feel like crap right or make them
feel as old they just gave away that
everything so that's what I'm trying to
do there who's that alright so that's a
lot of information just a real quick
reflective moment some questions for you
you don't have to answer these out loud
but just something to think about would
you know if somebody in your company had
been socially engineered especially your
executive would they come to you and say
you know what I just I just wire
transferred 50 million dollars so that
would be bad does your insurance cover
that that would be something interesting
to take a look at I haven't not seen in
the news any any it's probably not
advertised very much but I'd love to see
insurance companies respond to that
right
that would be interesting if any of you
have information on that I'd love to
talk to you about it do your internal
resources have the capabilities to
respond to this sort of an attack right
that's another thing we do a lot of
technical training but how much SC
training have you had right sans is a
new Osen course it just came out so if
anybody's taken that I love to talk to
you about that and then who's all tamiya
right unfortunately that has been the
response by a lot of big companies is
you know they let somebody go like okay
we fixed the problem so once I was gone
they did a crappy job well you know I'm
not that it's not a good response to
this right I don't think that's a good
way to go about things but ultimately
that's sometimes what happens and it's
if we've covered ourselves as InfoSec
professionals right and shown that look
we did the user awareness training we
did these different things the chance of
us getting fired is less likely so I
think preparing for this sort of attack
as far as you know ensuring you have a
good career that's that not prematurely
ended I think is a good idea it's
unfortunate but that's the risk some of
us face alright some recommendations oh
sit yourself this is a lot of fun I have
a Google Alert for my name so now I've
discovered there's a lot of other people
with my name out there and well not all
of them are wonderful people host at
your company find the butterflies those
are the people you want to go talk to
and say hey you know you probably want
to put the VPN information out there you
know nothing wrong with some
self-promotion that's not gonna stop
they're gonna keep doing that but you
want to look at that and what's at risk
right is it proprietary data is that
money some fishing recommendations do a
fishing program so a lot of people tell
me no I'm not going to do that I'm not
going to trick my users you don't have
to trick your users right it's more of
an educational thing you can make it fun
reward the people that do good work
right that that figure it out make them
into champions don't punish people
because then they will be upset
you can put EXT on your incoming email
so when your CEO gets an email from the
CFO it's not really from him or her it's
going to say EXT and that's going to be
a tip that oh I see that's nuts actually
not from that person
so you can stop allowing active links
although nobody's going to do that and
provide other channels email is terrible
right so we all get so much email use
different tools slack Twitter blogs
bitch your executive be very careful
with that they don't have a sense of
humor that we do so be very careful
there
invest in your receptionist's you know I
find that these people are wonderful
people very patient there their job is
actually usually quite challenging PBX I
love your PBX is because I can dial into
your PBX is and dial by name and get all
your information I can get your D IDs I
can get you know your voicemail you know
you may want to remove dial by name most
of us still have that I find I give di
DS only to externally facing people a
lot of companies di DS for everybody
direct inward dial you don't all need
that some of that can go through
reception you can have an extension stop
answering your phone I got in trouble
for saying that a bunch of managers
looked at me really really bad when I
said this the first time and it's like
so of course if it's your boss answer
your phone
but typically someone's phoning you
because they want something and so I
love voicemail my voicemail goes to my
email I listened to it and deleted I'm
get on the offensive so we always talk
about how we can't scale and how they
attackers only have to be lucky once
so you know by developing a culture of
you know where we're looking at this and
we're having fun with it and you know
start giving out Starbucks cards right
you did a great job here's a Starbucks
card take a picture of them put it on
your on your intranet and start looking
short you know instead of just saying no
all the time we can say yes right we can
say yes this person did a fantastic job
and here's a Starbucks card developed
that cultural change of proud
protectionism and you know some
companies do this better than others but
when the people are proud to work for
that organization they're more likely to
not let that person through the door
with the pizzas that doesn't have the
card to get through make create
champions as well right so when people
are doing a good job you know make sure
they're recognized this is a cheat sheet
you know I'm not going to go through all
these things but from all the
people I've talked to and the actual
intrusions that I've I've seen these are
the things that will help some of your
problems go away it will make you a
tougher target we talk about things like
patching people's like no I can't patch
it's gonna break stuff yes it will
you still need to patch right develop a
system where you know it if it's
important system have to patch this one
and then patch this one do things like
that to FA there's lots of stuff
activity this year on ola if you don't
have to FA on your webmail that's a
that's a fantastic opportunity for
people I've seen a lot of this year
assume I'm already on the inside as well
because I probably am so if you're not
actively threat hunting and you haven't
found me yet I guarantee you there's bad
stuff on your network I I haven't seen
one where there's not really so just
it's just levels of bad right all right
so everybody likes tools these tools are
not going to you know make you an expert
at all in this these are pretty just you
know high level tools there's a new tool
every day and but these are some of the
ones you can start with it's really
about technique and what your target is
right so if you only have an email
address for your target your tool set is
going to be different your techniques
gonna be different I love looking at
things like IOT any sort of systems
they're they're fences electronic fences
their ID cards their HVAC systems it's
all usually plugged in the internet and
usually they've forgotten how how that's
working some technical tools wiggle
dotnet is interesting you can get their
Wi-Fi SSID usually from that some of
these are just better than others
there's a bunch there you can collect
pretty much everything they've got by
these tools here as far as you know who
their technical people are their contact
information
I had executive cell phones executive
addresses home addresses their pet names
you know where they went to the GM
everything it's all their corporate
indeed.com fantastic your job
descriptions are amazing I know about
all your technologies your all your
infrastructure from your job
descriptions you probably all need to do
that
pastebin is great too a keyword search
on the company do a keyword search on
your company if you find stuff in pay
span that's probably and probably not
going to be good
security guards those are those are
really good opportunities and yeah so on
the staff we went through some of this
already recruitment are actually what's
that - a recruitment geek that that URL
that'll have the tool there you can use
SlideShare is fantastic for some reason
people like to put reference letters
there so that's where you can get a lot
of executive home addresses and weird
stuff like that which is fantastic in
Canada I'd never knew this a really bad
person showed me this that you can get
criminal records so a lot of people come
to me now and they're like hey Rob I'm
renting out my place that this person
can you just check them out for me so
I'll tell them like if they have a
criminal record what their assets are
all that stuff is pretty easy to do and
then personal websites we're all doing
the self-promotion and that's not going
to stop so there's tons information on
there alright some resources these are
some the typical go-to ones that I
recommend in the US Michael bozell Intel
techniques is a website you can go there
if you want to do some quick OSINT he's
got a bunch of tools there that's
probably the first stop he's got a great
podcast he's warned of the privacy side
now great books a great resource on the
west coast where I am Paddington is kind
of the go-to person for training he
trains all the agencies social engineer
of course he runs the SE village he's
got books podcasts you name it he's got
it and then if you're into the kind of
psychology of the whole thing
Robert calvini is is a great resource
too so lots of stuff on YouTube you
don't have to go on spend money just
just google him and you'll find a great
lot of great stuff yeah so there's a
bunch of other stuff in there there's
there's Twitter accounts where you can
get tools and stuff like that so if you
want more resources just let me know and
I'll send you what I got
alright that's it
thank you