[Applause]
good morning so as David just said I'm
Stephan Kaba work at canonical on the
next index II team and the project
leader for all of those projects and
have been for a number of years now
today we're gonna be talking about
container and Gatineau security
specifically first thing first is like
what are containers really continuous
peculiar system level system-level
virtualization there's no hardware
enablement for containers the host
kernel does all of the motorization bit
like effectively it the the host kernel
will give containers their own view of
the system now what that means can vary
quite a bit the containers can share
some resources we put with the host it's
kind of pick and choose for a lot of it
you can totally make a container that
doesn't have its own network stack but
shares it with the rest of the system
you can have two containers share their
network stack you can have two
containers share the file system you can
really pick and choose and that's then
used differently in different pattern or
run times on top of that you can apply
resource limits which effectively lets
you then slice your physical machine
into a number of containers making it
easier for like planning in general but
also giving you bit more of that virtual
machine feel where you can dedicate
actual resources bit of history of
containers in general it's not a new
concept doctors have been around
continues of you know around way before
docker has been a thing way before that
in fact the Alexi project that I'm
leading where it's our 10 years
anniversary this year so we've been
doing containers in mainline Linux or
decade now and continuous have been a
thing for another decade before that
the concept of containers themselves
effectively started in about 1999 when
the Russians from better also started
looking into the general idea of doing
containers on a computer because at that
point nobody had containers yet then bsd
jails were effectively first
implementation of the concept just
perimeter a year later linux v server
was the first implementation of the
concept of containers on the linux
kernel which released in 2001 that was
then followed by solaris implementing
their own concept of containers called
service zones those who introduced in
2004 and then the virtuoso
developers who started all the way back
in 1999 released openvz in 2005 as one
of at the time best implementation of
containers on linux one thing worth
mentioning the Linux V server and up in
busy where both rather significant patch
set on top of Linux
you couldn't just take like your normal
Linux system and then run containers on
them you had to apply was that
potentially hundreds of thousands of
lines of changes on top of the Linux
kernel to get you to have containers
that was a bit of a problem and that's
why in ran 2007 ish those a number of
talks to implement containers on Linux
in a clean way like in the actual
mainline kernel for only one who's been
dealing with the Linux kernel community
they're not just us of much of a
challenge that might be there is no day
the leadership of the next community
doesn't do camera wide design that's not
a thing so nobody decided like hey we're
going to do containers on Linux and then
we need to change those 50 different
subsystems
that's not happens work
instead there's been pushed for
subsystem subsystem switching to like
implementing some bits and pieces of
containers in every large number of
subsystems in Linux that you could then
piece together to create something that
fits like a container the coop project
leader of the LXE project in front of
mine surveilling keeps saying that
containers are effectively been illusion
it's not a pain the Linux kernel doesn't
know what the container is there's no
such concept there's like 50 print
pieces that user space can use together
like darker or Alexi or whatever else
can piece all of those things together
and that gets you what you would
actually call a container that makes for
pretty big definition of other container
is on the docks as a result but that's
kind of what happened so the Alexi
project was started in 2008 as the
reference implementation reference user
space implementation of containers on
Linux and been evolving ever since we
effectively every time a new kernel
feature would land that could be used to
support containers we were adding that
to Alexi and that's the project grew
darker started in 2013 so five years
after that as effectively a at the time
premature wrapper script around Alexi
giving it the layer an image work people
are used to but using Alex in background
they've since switch to their own
implementation of the actual runtime in
go since and the project I mostly work
on these days is Lex day and that's
started in 2014 as a way of doing system
containers differently effectively now
the somewhat even more technical part of
this the different assets we've got a
bunch of different technologies in Linux
that when you piece together effectively
get your containers the main defining
feature for that would be namespaces
that effectively is what you use to give
a process a different view of the system
done
the other processes on the system we've
got a namespace for the amounts table
which then lets you use a different file
system for the container we've got a
cool name space just for the hostname
that's the UTS namespace that's the only
thing it does it's just that you can
have a different host names and host IP
C which is taken like separate all the
shared memory handling between
containers the feed namespace is what
you use that you get a natural init
process and a process tree that's
computers look separate from what the
host house
there's the network namespace that's
obviously used to give you a separate
network stack with your on if 0 or
whatever device and you won't look back
then there's the user namespace that
other than next D not many people
actually use sadly that's the big
security in n space it's what you use to
effectively prevent just about every
attack against your containers more on
that later
and lastly the last one we implemented
that couple years ago is the C group
namespace which is to allow the use of
resource limits inside the containers
themselves instead of just to product
the containers then for resource limit
we've got the C groups C groups that you
do things like limiting amount of CPU
time limiting memory usage and doing
some amount of priority type operations
on block device and network devices
there's also a secret that this should
limit the number of processes that the
container can run which is effectively a
fork bomb prevention mechanism because
otherwise in a very easy way to commit a
kill your host was just trying to thaw
climb in a container and if the pin name
the pizza group wasn't configured then
the entire system would lock up so
that's big start then we've got LS Em's
so Alison's our Linux security modules
they're used as extra security mechanism
to prevent things like file accesses or
accessing specific sis goals or
accessing some specific privileged
operations the ones that relate to file
system access
is are typically Apollo and selinux they
work differently but if it if they do
the same thing they let you mark in the
ball files in a container house you
cannot write to those things like that's
how you block the most dangerous parts
from privileged containers effectively
SEC come lets you filter sis goals so
and it's it's cool that you think might
be dangerous you can completely block it
from the container and lastly
capabilities lets you back turn-off
whoo-hoo bunch of channel api is in one
shot in a very badly defined way you've
got a fixed list of capabilities that
exist but what they actually do is not
necessarily well-defined so you can drop
a bunch of them and you've got to hope
that's the next person will continue
cisco will actually do the right
capability to check as well or the
nooses golden might just bypass it and
then mom so much for blocking it and
lastly we also have process limits and
user limits and also concept in linux
that play a bit of a role in there you
could set process limits for your
container process tree to limit the
number of files of the container can
open for example or limit size of shared
memory and that kind of stuff user
limits are mostly an issue more than
like a feature what get on that bit data
as well but they let you do limits for
an entire for a specific user ID
unfortunately across container
boundaries alright so that was quite a
bit of talking first thing we can do we
can just create a container as in from
scratch we data container runtime all
right let's
it's just unfortunate I don't have
another screen to see what you're seeing
you're seeing the right thing
good okay um so I've got a for the in my
desktop which is effectively a process
tree in this case it is a debian burst
root PI system effectively obviously my
host itself is going to be Kubuntu so
that's different enough the the first
thing you'd want to do for a container
because it's a different root PI system
would be creating a just doing others
routes on creating a month in space so
we do not would now have a new month in
space that's great then it's useful to
have a mount even if you've just
Mountain yourself onto yourself because
once you do and not as we get your I can
actually show you that you should have
your own Mountain tree yeah yep yeah
that last nine shows that you've got
your own mapping tree now that if you've
got a mountain tree for your container
you can mark that as the root filesystem
for it oops there we go it's kind of
counterintuitive that until you CD into
your own directory you're not actually
under new mountain tree and so pivot
rate doesn't work we need to do CD in
your grant directory yeah once that's
done I've technically pivoted my shell
doesn't really know about it yet but now
if I look at what we had before I've got
the Debian version thing here but if I
do CD / and I do it again I'll start it
see they generally depend version now
it's there
so with that what girl names base not
pivoted the stash of that container is
the Debian tree now that's all nice and
fun but it's kinda useless because like
it's gonna be missing a metal file
systems like in this case pork should
mount those Mountain Park that's mounts
it's a fast
go
I think Apicius devices always a nice
thing to have if you like adding a
terminal thank ok so we've got a new
martin space the route by semi set up
and we've got a basic file system to
mount it effectively now let's do if we
look at the flags I'm gonna do a bid
which is B and I'm gonna ask it if that
wasn't what I wanted is it
I wanted fork not okay so I want a new
pin and space and I want to fork into it
the reason why I need to fork is because
when you create a new bid name space
your current process itself will still
have a ID with the parent instead of
within your own your name space we need
to fork once you do that I should see ya
some Pete one so now I've got secret we
made a new bit namespace and I'm the
only pit inside it so I become PID one
like if I'm the ended process at that
point you should unmount pork because
it's no longer showing the right view
and your mallet again once you've done
that then you can look at the process
tree and you'll see that you've just
have yourself a speed one if we look at
the network devices we see a syllable
bunch including my wife has device I'm
using right now we can fix that so then
share a network namespace this time and
they're all gone and lastly because it's
fun to have a host name we can ensure a
UTS namespace at which point we can do
not and if we spawn a new shell inside
it we've got in your host name so that's
pretty much hard to set up a container
using just the basic utils that shape
with 13 X destroy these days without
using any of the ocular XE or any of the
container runtimes and that's gonna
shows you all of the namespaces the ones
that they don't use here are IPC because
we wouldn't actually notice it anyways
also didn't you
the secret in space because same thing
you wouldn't actually notice it and the
lava engine shows is the username space
because it is
let's see tricky to set up we've got
gotten all runtimes that do not pause
because there's a good reason for it
it's complex
alright let's switch now the there are
different types of containers because
obviously that wouldn't be fun if there
wasn't so on on the next we move this is
three different types of containers
there are system containers which is
what I mostly work on those are
effectively virtual machine alternatives
they don't require only change to what
to run inside it you can effectively
take any physical system or new virtual
machine or anything you've got and just
stuff it in there and it's going to run
exactly like if it was a via phone
machine obviously running the host camel
but that's not actually a problem so
long as it's Linux the other type of
container which a lot of your poly
familiar with are what we call
application containers those are things
like docker they're effectively a means
of distributing applications and the
because of the way they're usually
managed tend to be a bit more ephemeral
they tend to be idly stateless the
prettiest throwaway we'll ask your
system containers you will normally run
like your normal system management tools
monitoring run your page supply security
update to all that stuff exactly like a
virtual machine and the the first type
of container that are run here when you
most of you are probably using them
right now and you've possibly never
noticed is embedded container so that's
effectively normal applications which
are you making use of some of the
container features to protect themselves
against someone attacking now so let's
look into some of that switching back
there we go all right so the first thing
we can look at is it's a system that's
running a docker container we're saying
it's a next cloud guy that's running if
you look about halfway through the
screen you're gonna see doc your
container d running then the corner of
the shame then effectively Apache
running inside it that next cloud
running for you and that's it
there's no actually need process in
there there's no syslog there's no crown
there's no none of any of those things
so that's an application container it
typically runs one or maybe two
processes you don't usually go in and
apply updates through the package
manager you just replace it with a new
copy of the image the other type would
be a system container so let's create
one of those crates see one so this
one's going to be created using Ubuntu
1604 as the image ago and if we look at
that it's starting now doing HCP
having so it's the tree at the bottom
and it looks a lot more like what we're
gonna have on your laptop or normal
server see it's running an init process
it's running John all day turning you
dev it's running a DHCP client it's
running a syslog server tuning from at
all those things you can enter that
container you can apply black edge
updates install packages as you normally
would you can run your configuration
manager it's effectively exactly like a
virtual machine except it's extremely
cheap compared to our machine and the
last type of container would be if I
look at my own laptop and hopes
differently with my staff constants that
was my damn thing let's see now that I
got ok so Chrome for example let's look
at one of the processes from Chrome so
if one thing you can do on this that's
not always super easy to compare but
like if you look at box set of an ass
it's going to give you all your names
is an ID for all of them now let's do
the same thing with the process from
chrome there we go
and if you start comparing them you'll
notice that shrooms got a different
network namespace it does have a
different speed namespace it does have a
different bit for children namespace
which comes with the pinyons case it
does have a different user name space
and it shares the UTS namespace of the
host the reason why they do that is big
of the sandboxing this thing is
effectively a rendering process for
Chrome which means it's got no reason to
ever connect to the internet so even if
you try to attack the rendering process
you won't be able to get out the only
thing that this process will see if we
go but - yeah we want to pit namespace
from whatever cause it was one name okay
I just need to unshare amount and
facility I cannot nuke up your
yeah
okay so that's what the that's what the
chrome process would say it only sees
itself running as the user it doesn't
see any other processes it cannot try to
attach or do anything to any other
processes because it just doesn't see
them now let's do the same thing with
network what can it see as far as
network well I looked at the non
configured loopback device that's what
it sees it doesn't have any kind of
network access whatsoever it can't that
also means it can't connect to any
abstraction next circuit either so
there's no way for it to enter network
and the last thing they do and we can
try and look at that sure that they set
up a username space and what they do is
in the map view the map through your own
user into their namespace and they don't
map anything else that means even if the
process had some way of frankly
escalated to route it can't because
there's no route like there's literally
no UID 0 in the chrome sandbox so they
cannot switch the route which eliminates
an entire other class off but
interpolant
so now that we've done the different
type of containers let's do the other
step of that which is going through some
of the containment options a lot of like
the the docker container showed earlier
for example is what we call a privileged
container that means that if you look at
who owns what and I'll show you that
again in tiny bit you notice that some
of the processes in there will run as
actual route some of the processes in
there will run out like UID 100 or
something those are privileged
containers they are not route safe they
are the security nightmare waiting to
happen
because if you get to root in there you
are real route and if you find any of a
number of MIS configuration or spits
attended up-to-date or missing security
confinement in the camera you can escape
the container and you're gonna have root
on the host which is a bit of a problem
then you've got introduced containers
that's what Lex D will do for you by
default that's why we created laxity in
the first place we wanted to be used a
newer security features available in the
kernel by default in something that
users can understand and use and food
containers mean that we take a big chunk
usually 65535 UID and GID s are
committed outside of the range of normal
I either use on your system and we map
to that so you are g 0 and your
container is actually going to be like
UID 1 million on your hosts meaning that
if you even if you do find some way of
escape first of all it means that route
in your container is only route against
the things it owns itself so even if it
can see something from outside the
container it has no control over it
second thing means that if you can
somehow escape the container and get on
the host you're going to have just as
much right as a nobody user that's the
that was the the real fix in the Linux
community to make containers of activity
route safe and that's why we really push
for people to do those containers
then you've got a third step which is
what we call isolated containers and
next day that means that not only do we
use the mapping technique but we use a
deep committed distinct map per
container that completely excludes one
container being able to attack another
or one container being able to do s
another because they do not share only
your ideas or three ideas whatsoever for
any kind of environment for Europe allow
completely random strangers to access
containers and potentially get through
it and said containers that's pretty
much the only thing that's safe
otherwise it will be safe in Austin
previous container and that it will not
be able to attack your hosts but they
will sure be able to do as themselves
the other thing that's worth mentioning
here is for those using docker there's a
- that privileged flag yeah so don't
think that because you don't pass it
your containers are unfinished that's
not true
dr. is privileged by default that starts
privileged minutes so privileged that
it's like a security nightmare it
effectively turns off a number of
default confinement options on top of
their privilege containers so then the
limited mitigate one that mitigation
they had in place or previous continues
to be coxswain is effectively turned off
if you pass that flag there is a way of
running docker and privileged my
understanding is that a lot of the
layers and images effectively don't
really work well with docker if you use
that so that's a bit of a problem
well internal if that works is actually
running docker inside the lxd container
because then it thinks it's privileged
but it's not and things tend to work
quite a bit better if you don't actually
at least it works a lot better than
running the contributors itself so a few
things about like why previous
containers are a terrible idea
and you know the it's kind of your
grocery list of stuff you need to
address if you write a container runtime
to make it vaguely sane the first thing
is you need to be using up a no asset
annex to restrict access to POC insists
the reason for not is there a number of
files a
Hach for example the you dev handler or
the Coulomb handler that did you set a
path that if you do some specific
actions will be executed by the kernel
as real route outside the container
without any containment so if you can
write to those files just crude like you
just trigger the action and you run as
we wrote and host so those files must be
blocked
at all costs the other thing that's
always kind of funny is this right
trigger which if you don't block then
the user can do like a memory dump or
can reboot some system or do other
potentially interesting things like that
that one usually want to block as well
but done whole bunch more of those like
a previous container that's not properly
restricted in stash prod will be able to
like reconfigure memory mappings don't
direct it it's probably like two
thousand files and off boxes that are a
terrible idea just thinking about them
um slash this is kind of seminal it does
belong to trigger you dev which combine
the pork issue I just mentioned lets you
have to be run any code you might have
root on this post but it also allows you
direct PCI access which means you can
actively DMA your way out of the
container so you need to block search it
as well then we've got some interesting
system calls that's way like legacy
system goals that have be causing issues
to people in the past there was a
exploit a while back called shocker
which was effectively a way of getting
out of docker container it was using a
little used Cisco called
opened by handle at that school is
pretty interesting
because if you continue is based on a
bind mount you can get a handle on a
directory inode and then the kernel will
write nicely that you asked for a
relative part to that so you see your in
your container and you open slash you
get the inode and then you use open by
handle and she asked for the slash that
does / the / on both of those and what
you get is actually a handle on two
real slash of your system which then
lets you true to into that and you're
out of the container and your real route
out of the country
so obviously that this goal is now
blocked everywhere that thankfully we've
got SEC comp so unless you're using like
completely new content of runtime that
someone wrote over the weekend your poly
fine most of the big cotton or n times
are fixed art there's been severe sign
for that and it's been fixed for quite a
while the other obvious tax is if you
don't configure cgroups properly your
privilege container will totally be able
to make note dev SDA and then can write
direct to your desk so that's bad and
same thing with TTY devices so the
container could make node Devta ty1 or
something and then they can directly
read and write to any of the device on
your system making it very easy to each
drop on you get your password inject
whatever they want in your shell it's
it's great
so obviously you need to configure that
properly as one then down to kind of
like big hum as you can use to block a
bunch of things privileged containers by
themselves should be fine if no process
runs as route in the container and you
don't have any set UID binary that lets
you go back to root at that point you
don't actually have any privileges you
can still do some amount of dosing by
using your limits but at least you count
s credit back to root so that's good
that's the approach is effectively used
for applications on Android a chap
Legation runs as it's on your ID entry
ID and that's how they do most of the
previous separation the other hammer I
mentioned earlier was capabilities which
you can drop a bunch of them like can
drop cabinet admin of capsules I mean
that we'd look a lot of stuff except
when they don't
so it it really depends on everyone in
the next community doing their homework
whenever they add a new kernel feature
and adding the rights is capable check
in the kernel if someone forgets Oni
then there's no capability check and you
can run it it
it's a useful tool but not something you
want to entirely rely on because there's
going to be done that doesn't off data
as well it's just no guys do anything
for you and some of the other issues
that we have security fixes for the
first one as I mention is you can set a
user limit in a container that limit
well across container boundaries because
it's tied to a given UID so you could
have two docker containers they each run
the same workload if you've got control
in one of them you can set the user
limit on your current UID which is going
to be the same UID in the other
container and then you could set the you
limit that says I can only spawn one
process and that prevents the other one
from ever spawning as a process the
kernel just ties it to a global UID and
it crosses into any containers so you
can have a container affect the host
effectively or you can have a container
affect another unless they are isolated
containers which means unpervaded with
non-overlapping your IDs and G IDs in
which case you away that issue you also
a category of attacks that means fixed
somewhat recently that was effectively a
timing attack against executing
processes inside the container the way a
process is injected inside a container
is by attaching to its namespaces then
dropping and above privileges applying
security labeling and then at the last
thing change to the right user in the
container and then exact that ask you
one the problem you've got is between
the time it enters the container and the
times it exacts it is technically in the
namespace of the container but still
runs ours real root and because of the
way security checks were done in P trace
a process inside the container could see
that process appearing for like
appearing as reroute for like a few
milliseconds and if it could be trace it
immediately it would be able to do code
injection into it while still running as
root that's now been fixed so that route
inside an interior container cannot be
trace a process that's got a user that's
outside of its namespace
so that's been resolved for entropies
containers it has not been resolved for
previous containers so you could if your
route inside a previous container you
can see TOI go out and get if you could
get to interact code inside the process
that it has a number of references to
the host the other thing that I believe
fixing most of the runtimes by now that
we keep finding new ones every month or
so that don't have it is a TTY pushback
so that means that unless the container
runtime if it really creates a pair of
console devices one that's inside the
container once that's outside of it and
then mirrors traffic between the two if
you don't do that and you don't strip
escape sequences the process inside the
container can write escape sequences
that actually inject code inside your
prompt from the attacking of the
election process so the container could
effectively send the escape sequence for
background the task around our RF / exec
and as soon as you exact the task in the
container that gets that diagrams
yourself runs that Alice the your grant
user and get done Aleksey ours had fixes
for that for at the past three or four
years now but we noticed like currency
didn't have a fix for that does affect
two months ago so there it's still
something that like every person who
writes a container runtimes goes to
think of all those things because they
are not kind of security issues they are
things like user space must do right and
there are a lot of those all right so
another quick demo just want to show
what privilege and pivoted and isolated
containers look like so switch to that
I'm going to switch to that system so
right now we've got one next D container
running its c1 if we go at it process 3
which is at the bottom we see it's if
you look at has been in it it's running
at us
UID 1 million so it is an unprivileged
container it is running with a static
map so if I launch a second one
code c2 is going to use the exact same
map as the first one and there we go we
can see the beginning of c2 and c1 both
running as 1 5 1 million so that's not
so great because mean c2 can technically
do sc1 that's why we've got
we've got a specific flag to say to
please give me non-overlapping and if we
see now we've shifted by sixty five
thousand thirty six new ideas for the
that last container at the bottom so now
that one cannot affect c1 or c2 and c1
and c2 are not affected the the last
guitar category would be a privilege
container which XD can also spawn with I
wouldn't recommend it but there are few
use cases when you might need that so
now we've got a c4 container at the
bottom that we see is running as
railroad so that's your three container
types running there um now veteran
machines and get old machines ish
so effectively like why would you use
containers instead of VMs is something
that keeps coming up especially when you
consider things like system containers
that run through the same thing as a VM
well I'll get into some more details of
that but density is a thing you might be
able to run I don't know 200 300 VMs on
the system you might be able to run
twenty thirty thousand containers on the
system so obviously we're talking mostly
idle workloads if they all if you spoon
a container that friends 100% CPU
doesn't really do any type of NIT that's
like purely CPU bound that will perform
perform the exact same way as a virtual
machine but if you're looking at doing
disk access network access like any type
of iOS you get much better density the
other thing where you get massively
better densities because containers when
they're idle do not get interrupts those
are handled by the kernel in general so
you don't need to like keep having to
reschedule a tiny bit of time for every
one of your VM to just go see what's
that last internal is work out or
whatever like that does that you run
each one of them um especially either
ones which for a lot of people doing
things like web hosting where you know
it's like your family website in
might get like one visitor a day or
something you're gonna be able to run a
lot of those compared to giving even a
small virtual machine for three singer
one of them the other thing that's been
a thing somewhat recently is effectively
running container images inside the
virtual machine so that's just named a
few times just to be clear containers by
Intel Nights have something they change
them again anyway
the the idea is that hey we've got that
fancy hardware stuff how about we use
that for security which fine you've got
the hardware yeah that's great
I propose a hypervisor attacks exist
there's been CVS against qmu and the
other half as those reason to be often
especially specific specifically for
things like virtual devices which you
need for and above that stuff so saying
that it's like the sick that it fixes
all your security problems is not quite
true in one case you have to trust the
Linux kernel in other case you've got to
trust the business based hypervisor
that's will run a through it and we'll
let you also attack the count the the
main downside to that is obviously you
do is the density because you'll be
running virtual machines so all of the
normal traders of a Turing machine
apply but you also get some of the other
you also get the constraints of
containers like you will not be able to
easily see the entire process tree like
I did you're gonna see a single process
running you also won't be able to do
things like sharing like a GPU very
easily between multiple containers you
won't be able to pass USB devices
because all of that stuff you're dealing
with virtual machine you're gonna have
to deal with virtual PCI buses and all
all of those things and doing all of
that you're still running a container
image on the same kernel inside the VM
so you still can't really run other
operating systems so you're not really
gaining that you know getting the usual
gains of running a virtual machine if
you don't so it seems like a bit of a
bad compromise I think
like I don't do virtual machines if they
make sense or do containers if they make
sense that don't try to have that in
between thing but I understand that for
some companies it lets them get the
right check boxes unlike security audits
and stuff and that gets them to run
containers but not so that's a thing um
just going to go through a couple of
three use cases like 450 continuous
security done right so using all the
security bits I mentioned before one of
them is Norfolk so in here you're just
using Wi-Fi that's fine in the other
room that we are setting up we are
running the CTF over the weekend we run
a lot of containers so we effectively
simulate a full internet for every
single one of the teams we're gonna have
50 this year the numbers I've got here
thought from last year that means
running 250 or so BGP rotters per team
except the numbers here from last year
so yeah we were running a total of 272
containers per team's twelve thousand
five hundred and something containers
total running on four physical systems
we were running like millions of routes
very complex network using the GP over
the place we're also running on above
virtual machines last year because of
some Windows workloads so running that
off-site and connected to to our
containers the the penis worth
mentioning is because it's a CTF and the
entire point is to you know try to win
it at all cost pretty much people are
like we cannot assume that are gonna
play nice so we do have one container
per team that's obviously using its own
UI d JD map as I mentioned earlier the
inside that container
we've got 270 or so sub containers for
all of our writers and for the action
contests that control challenges in
there and all of them also have their
own UID and GID map just in case so what
can we assign something like 100 million
new ideas and gids per team or something
enough so we've got plenty we're fine
really trying to make sure that and we
also do it so don't we limit obviously
the memory in above processes CPU we do
actual CPU pinning for every team so
that they can't hog the CPU and effect
another team we don't overcome it
in general like we just don't we splits
the physical systems equally and yes
you're welcome to try and try and run a
bunch of fog bombs or try to use the CPU
and the only person you can affect is
yourself so have fun but it's going to
be really slow you're going to manage to
make yourself go offline but the team
next to you is not really gonna notice
so that's fixed ly what kinda looks like
we've got four physical systems those
four physical systems we've been divided
into four virtual machines the reason
for that is mostly so that if the kernel
blows up we only lose 1/16 of everything
instead of a quarter and then on top of
that we run between four and five
simulations per VM and in there we've
got about 200 containers so that's what
it what the container listing cannon
looks like for last year so we had a 244
BGP riders we had 32 ish challenges and
we had a number of templates we could
use to create new challenges that makes
it pretty easy for us to copy systems we
can do any Linux distribution that you
want we can run each challenge in a
distro that's not been updated for the
past decade if we need to like we
successfully run CentOS three on my
laptop inside the container that's
that's a thing we've really done some
pretty crazy stuff and we definitely do
obviously we very much don't want anyone
to be able to get real root so we try to
make sure that doesn't happen
and it's never it
never did we've been running containers
for north deck since before Norfolk was
good not sick never had an employment
not the other thing that's that we run
when that I run that's somewhat
interesting is we give rude shells to
everyone on the internet so that's on
the leg ski website we've got a way for
you to try it online you just click a
button and you get a root session
terminal in your web browser of a
transcript and in there we actually run
a lengthy daemon that you can then
create containers in so you effectively
in a container and you create sub
containers we've had about 10,000 people
do that every month for since October
2015 we've not had a single person
managed to escape it at the beginning
we've got we had a few people try to do
s it unsuccessfully the only thing that
happens like if you try to run out of
memory or if you try to run out of
processes the can a lot of memory killer
will be very happy to kill your entire
container and you're just out but
everyone else it's perfectly fine we run
up to 32 users at the same time on the
system we give them a single CPU with
give 156 Meg's of RAM think 5 gigs of
disk space is something odd and I think
we kept it at 200 processes so if you
exceed when it processes then just going
to get any new bit and if you exceed
your memory allocation random starts
going to get killed by the counter for
you that random stuff might be your
terminal all the containers are
obviously isolated the machine itself is
throw away and redeployed every day just
in case we not had any problem with that
except in January where we took the
service down for a few weeks
for obvious reasons now just a quick
recap before we take questions first
thing is like not all containers are
created equal you do have to keep in
mind that you've got privileged
containers and finished containers and
isolated containers and you do have to
keep in mind that not all container
runtimes are particularly great at what
they're doing and that privileged
containers
a big variety there too you might have a
privileged container like the ones that
rerun in next day for example where to
the best of our knowledge right now
there is no way of it's keeping them if
you run it on a bun - with Obama SEC
camp all those bit enabled which we do
by default there is no way of getting
root on the host that we are aware of at
this point that's not to say there won't
be and if there is there's no guarantee
that we'll be able to fix it which is
why we don't credit to it safe because
it is not safe by design it is an unsafe
design that we've patched as much as we
can to make it safe that's also what's
docker does by default so that may be
something you can do there D and that's
really the best question I like if a
container one time forgot to block open
by hand alert then you're out of the
container if one of those runtimes
didn't set up a panel or the sysadmin
turn it off or your system somehow then
you're out of the container
same thing with c group same thing with
any of those things if any one of the
system systems are showed earlier is
somehow disabled on the system and you
managed to get root inside that
container you're out so those are food
containers and previous containers are
set the main attack you're gonna find
there is being able to the US I do he
process on the host or another container
next to it that's still a problem and
you can still make quite a bit of damage
with that but it's not a straight path
to route on the host and then isolated
containers from those there are some
edge Kamel limits you can try and attack
like I don't know some TCP buffers
some of that kind of stuff you can try
in the US part of the network stack
maybe we don't necessarily have all the
right tools in memory limits necessarily
like not everything is accounted
perfectly right so these days are not a
true fan on you won't be able to do as a
415 kernel D the memory C group has been
has gotten a lot better and actually
accounts for most of that stuff
the other thing too so that's the
attacking side so effectively if you
find yourself inside a container don't
assume that because you're in a
container it's safe and there's nothing
you can do there's a good chance there's
something you can do and you can go
further and try to get access to the
host which would then get you access to
all the other containers that might be
interesting if you're the sysadmin you
might want to audit your things so that
someone can't do that just a part and
the if you're running production
containers but really cannot life
patching is your friend you really
should consider that because if you
don't and there's a nasty name
space-related cv showing up in the
kernel you're going to have to reboot
your systems immediately I might have a
walk around of like blocking the
specific sis code as being attacked but
oftentimes those sis goals are going to
be rather useful so if your life arching
then they're particularly will not be
any downtime or you're just gonna have
to block your users for a few minutes
until the life much hit when the CV is
no longer an embargo if you don't have
any such mechanism you should
effectively have all your systems check
for security cannot updates every 15
minutes or so and if there's one make a
post update trigger that we watch the
system immediately otherwise you can be
attacked pretty easily the other way is
obviously never allow anyone to dig you
don't trust inside a container but
that's not always practical because
people like to run web servers and
whatnot in there and those can usually
be attacked easily enough unless you
topically trust all the PHP code that
everyone you're hosting is running but
that seems somewhat unlikely alright so
I think we've got about 10 minutes for
questions we'll sue the link to that
website I mentioned earlier to try it
online we also have like a bucket of
Lexie stickers in the entrance on tables
and at the bar so if you want to get
some of those afterwards you can go out
and contact in for instead