thank you for being here I'm super
nervous
the first thing I always have to say is
that desert is my is my taste it has
nothing to do with my employee and the
things that I did here I did outside of
the work time so that's me I am a Maori
sort of f-secure I also know her again
organizing the black hoodie that's a
reverse engineering but you came here
just for women I am a really proud
program in the program committee member
of a club and our copper papers is open
so submit
I'm also ambassador for disobey that's a
kind of a haircut conference in Finland
and today I'm talking about yeah malware
analysis in logical programming so I
will try to explain really shortly and
without the mess what constraint logic
programming it for data we'll talk about
asymmetry solvers and how we can use
them in a malware analysis then I will
talk about the applications of the
constraint logic programming in the IT
security I will talk about binary
occupation and how you can use the SMT
solvers to do it malware so first of all
SMT solvers can give you like youth
silver for equations so if you have a
system of a lot of equations you can use
this empty service to solve those
equations for you
the main difference between smj servers
and the set servers that most of the
people know about is that in the set
service you can just use boolean
equations to and resolve between two
values like to enforce
with SMT solvers you you can resolve
with normal equations also much much my
stuff and so and the good part of it is
that a lot of real-world problems can be
represented as problem of solving system
of equations I hear a lot of people
saying that SM chains over than symbolic
education is like I hide now
a lot of people are doing it and stuff
and before no one was really talking
about real world applications of it and
I just don't believe that it's a -
because it's a really old theory yeah I
guess we just don't we didn't have the
computer power for it many symbolic
education before so it was work a
hardware problem or technology problem
then the problem of the theory so what
are constraints we have like two main
programming validations that we use like
our size of building programs you have
the imperative programming that's a kind
of that you just stage the computer what
you already want the computer to do and
then you have another way that it's like
describing to the to the computer what
you have right now and what you want to
get from it so you are just describing
what the program which most accomplished
in terms of the problem that you have
right now rather than just say the
computer like to the computer yet do it
this way and find out what you are going
to do next
so you are not like a mom say - hey
don't go there and do this stuff and I
come back you are just saying I have
this problem Soviet for me so if you
think about a freighter that is a guided
eye
I really really appreciate the idea that
he had on computers he notice it like a
way ago he says like conflict constraint
programming is like the Holy Grail in
the computer science because you using
it you have the computers there to do
this stuff that you will when you want
the computer to do to solve the problems
for you right so with the constraint
programming with state constraints about
the problems that we have and the
computer will find the solutions for
this constraints for you of course that
there is a theoretical limitation that's
like I will talk about that after no
it's a bit complicated to understand but
circa 90% of the real world problems
that we have in the HSA huge for example
even the max or stuff like that they are
yes problems that you can define in this
kind of models and they can be written
like combinatorial problems so you can
use symmetry service for solving it and
constrain solely for infinite or more
complex domains are also possible but we
still don't have the computers for it so
don't worry
I told you I am NOT putting the
equations here and I'm not talking about
it myself it but to explain how SMT
solvers work we need to talk about
predicate logic or logical programming
and where that you can see these SM
chains over like a black box so you have
this formula that's the theory or the
problem that you have are the goals that
you want to achieve then you put this
stuff inside the SMGs over it will
reason enough about these logical
connections between your problem and
your goal and then you say for you like
is
feasible or is it not feasible to
achieve the goals with because domains
the constraints that you have in your
domain and the best part of it is like
it does it is not just saying to you
like yeah it's feasible you it's
possible to to do that it's also giving
you instances of the ways of solving the
problem that means you also have all the
possibilities of the solution for the
same problem so to understand why you
have stuff like that it's like SMT
servers I need to think about who wants
to prove a lot of things we had in the
keynote someone talking about that SEC
and they are also coming from them
mathematicians then SMT solvers will use
it before to prove large theorems so you
can break the really biggest problems of
the madman is Molly no problems any
reason about all of them and if you can
prove all the small T rooms you can also
prove the bigger one so the same idea
you can apply for hardware or software
verification for example and then you
can also think about proving that your
software is secure or that the language
that you are using is also secure and
symbolic execution is the most known way
of using a semjase office today
the symbolic execution of a program is
nothing more than a path generating that
it's constructing oh the structure of
the program expanding all the paths of
the control philosophy of your system
and we said you have like this hundred
percent code coverage that you have in
the code verification and the same thing
you can do with binaries
let me then it's possible to to know
that if you are in the time like if you
can't like every where for every line of
code you can know exactly in every line
of code which kind of input and output
makes it possible to be in this point of
the branching or something in the entry
point and to the end point of your
program so it looks like that you have
you one input and if you see the second
line of code you can see that your
domains are going to be changing every
single in every single node and if you
do it for a small hole like here you
have eleven lines of code not even dead
you see already how many paths are
possible and that it's one of the
biggest problems with the symbolic
execution it's know as exposed aspect
death explosion that I'm also going to
talk about after the problem is that the
precision of this graph that we are
generating in the performance of the
analysis of the code they depend really
strong on the options that you use to
generate this kind of control flow that
means that they contact sensitivity of
my graph that I'm generating is I guess
one of the most important point to think
about when you consider if you are doing
like power detection or malware analysis
the configuration of these parameters
will determine the representation of
this kind of system calls for example or
the branching points and if you have the
possibility of having a high context
sensitivity you can also enable us
references between different system
Cisco's that are invoked in multiple
locations of the code or even thinking
about global variables the context
sensitivity may also depend on the
function or the calls themselves
and furthermore that means that
increasing the context sensitivity
inserting a greater number of say squad
clothes that you have in your in your
program so you have a lot of nodes in
your graph and you can imagine how it
looks like in in a memory so it's
important to keep in mind when you are
working with symbolic education that you
don't have concrete values you have like
symbols as arguments you are going to
explore any feasible path in your code
and you have a program state you also
need a lot of memory because the
symbolic values are stored in a memory
and you have and you have like a also a
problem with the time that it takes time
to resolve about all this kind of
domains that you have so about the
applications for the IT security like
here you can define a model that's
pretty simple to understand you can just
say my software is secure because
nothing bad ever happens that means that
if I'm checking that my program safe I
need to negate it because it's a pretty
good logic so I will negate and say ok
if something bad happened that means
that my software or my hardware is not
secure and that would be this formula
that I am putting inside my asymmetry is
over and otherwise in it fees go is it
possible that something that happens
that makes my software or my hardware
not secure so that's the most no idea of
using symbolic as a cue to is for
furthering or good verification or for
binary analysis but mostly for assuring
or just kind of proving that your
software or your hardware is really
secure then you have like as a kind of
natural thing that
it's coming with their exploitation so
you can ask you can of course just take
the inputs that you have that are
causing your program to not be sick here
as a proof of concept but you also can
think about create some kind of ultimate
expert generation and also automate
payload generation so so that you don't
me you can use just the output of your
switches over that you all the instances
that you have and create a payload for
it and that's the part that I most like
it's to use this kind of symbolic
education to analyze malware the problem
of malware analysis is that my way is
mostly obfuscated they use all the
compiler optimizations that they having
and you also have like a trend with
ransomware so how binary office caching
works it's a funny thing that that
that's one of the thing that's made me
fall of with the malware
because it's kind of the whoa if you
think about because malware is if you
think about the technical part and the
educational part of it it's really
interesting and some tech techniques
that you will see in malware are not
really different than the things that
you use for sampling software protection
systems so you have this game that you
really want to pay but you don't even
want to pay its associated and then you
have this malware that don't want to be
found
it's sophisticated and they use the same
tools and the same techniques so in both
cases the laser program that it's doing
something somebody puts kind of a cover
or stuff around it that makes the
program a really difficult to analyze
and to understand how how it works
and the problem is what is inside but
that it is something that you can just
know when you are inside so in one case
the objective would be to make the
analysis of the program so hard that
that you cannot write
cracker for it and in the other way it
would be just to make my heart really
hard at work so it's really doable
really nice and so which kind of my
workstation I'm looking at right now
well when you are analyzing my where you
really think on the beginning it is for
me that I'm new in the industry
I was like yeah what can be so hard it's
just assembly right okay and then I got
there I was sitting in front of my first
binary at all and I couldn't even
understand what what is this about
I never saw it before no one is using
this assembly code I use it to write
coding assembly and I never used this
kind of instructions and yeah compiler
do and the same thing works with packing
if you are a normal person you're just
like sleeping everything or maybe doing
it car
with easy but they can write their own
peccaries what it's really nice
sometimes and you have a lot of
different values of the station's like
sharing and stuff like it so sorry is
also something that I see a lot because
the word to go for my where they don't
want to you to see the strings and
that's a really fast technique changes
you hide them where else or the registry
fees or whatever if they don't want to
see another easy way to obfuscate
malware is just put a lot of garbage
code around it so you write a lot of
stuff like wires while you're too and
it's over always false or you put some
if true and then it's always false and
stuff like that so using a same chance
Louis it's also possible to simplifying
the code just writing the constraint and
saying if this branch is never taking
we don't need to analyze it you can just
delete it from your control program and
then you have less co2 analyzed well
with the Pickers
sometimes my where they developers they
go a bit further when they want to make
your life hard and they write their own
pecker and most of them are really easy
you just put a big point in really your
memory dump and that's done but
sometimes they are not so easy sometimes
you have the pecker inside the pepper
and then you need to pack a pecker and
and with the SM cheese over it's also
possible to with your just resolve all
this kind of stuff and in the end you
get really the last memory down you
don't need to think about how many times
you need to unpack something so the
limitations there is a really good one
if you think about the theory of it I
guess everybody knows what a penny
machine is and that just means it it's
impossible to write a software that will
prove that your software is safe because
a software cannot read a software and
today and is the practical thing the
practical thing is you need someone
behind the code when you start because
the SMT service they cannot take the the
first constraint they cannot generate it
you need a person that is saying like
okay it this is a constraint you I know
that it's not going to happen
so what I learned when I was doing it
was that symbolically the question is a
powerful tool it helps me a lot when I
am analyzing my well because I don't
need to find out which key
he's using for the show or we commit how
many times I need to go through this
unpacking algorithm or whatever and of
course the simchas of asking is being
used to simplify the control flow graph
that means I can just delete all the
control flow graph before the garbage
code before I even start analyzing
anything so I know I'm not starting any
binary anymore without running it before
what I didn't - now is like I wrote this
binary garbage code eliminated maybe I'm
just painting everything before I start
analyzing any kind of binary I have the
shorter search so it's a short search
everybody knows there are plenty of them
out there but mine is pretty fast and I
also wrote some algorithms like you can
resolve an easy cryptographic algorithm
like safer and stuff like that and I'm
trying to write more to help people with
problems with him somewhere so what I'm
working on right now is - I want to
finish my generic young Packer I'm
writing a simple spool sella turcica
constructor causing malware we don't
have this funny nice table on the end of
the binary I'm also working on the
hidari - in integration so that can be
used together as a plugin and a lot of
other stuff that I am NOT a stew not
talking about but I plan to do a little
step yeah that's it