okay
foreign
now because
your description
good morning everyone
thank you for waking up
all this last day of Chess already
so this is a special specialization
because it's about the best paper of the
conference
so let me tell you a few words on how we
identify this best paper
so for this Edition with Thomas we
decided to had a field in the reviews
where the PC members were had to decide
whether each paper was each paper they
reviewed was a potential candidate for
the best paper Awards so they did and
based on this field and on the novelty
scores like the impact of the
contributions we identified 14 papers uh
in the four issues and we submitted them
to a vote by the PC members
so at the end of this vote without more
suspense the winner is Miracle micro
micro
architectural leakage evaluation by Dan
Page Ben Marshall and James Webb please
upload them
thank him
so please come all of you
you will get your certificates in the
picture
okay so on its version you can yeah
so in a in a nutshell the others that
they design
um an infrastructure to identify hidden
micro artificial features uh in modern
group processors based on poor
consumption but they'll they'll tell you
more about it in a second
congrats to all of them
talking about
it does not matter okay
okay
good morning can you hear me
yeah thank you people are back so yeah
congratulations on making it all here
I'm gonna do my best after the the fun
last night
um so first of all thank you to the to
the program committee to the reviewers
for awarding us best paper this is a
wonderful surprise and quite unexpected
and also a particular thank you to our
reviewers this is a 40-page paper it was
not easy to to write I cannot imagine
what it was like to review so thank you
for you for the efforts in the reviewers
um it took about two years of work to
get this to the point where we could try
and publish it and then another sort of
almost Year trying to get it published
as well so it's really nice to be able
to finally talk to you about it and
share it in a venue like chess
um so as as introduced this paper is
called Miracle referring to the fact
that it's a miracle we got it published
um about microarchitectural leakage so
this is looking at
um how does the micro architecture of a
CPU impact the power leakage that you
can observe in very basic sequences of
instructions
um so I'll give you a little bit of an
outline kind of the context that's
really really important here I'm not
going to try and tell you about all the
results we found I'll just try and give
you a bit of a taste I think the context
is actually more important so you can go
and read the paper and understand it
properly I'll try and give you exactly
what we set out to ask and then what we
actually did because as I saw from the
case in research those two things
weren't exactly the same by the time we
actually finished it
um tell you a little bit about the
selected results and what we think
should happen now in terms of how we do
this research based on what we've
discovered and also I think particularly
important for a paper like this is where
I think speaking only for myself and not
my co-authors where we could have done
better in this paper and maybe this
gives you some ideas for how to extend
our work and then what next and
hopefully by that point you'll have lots
and lots of questions
so background uh we all want fast cheap
secure everything
um and this is impossible because we
build our Computing systems on
abstractions and these are great for
managing their complexity
um you know you start at the top you
write some C code and you can compile
that c code and you can run it just
about anywhere that's great because it
will be functionally correct and this is
because we rely on instruction set
architectures by you know arm Intel risk
five and they provide this this contract
it's guarantee of functional
compatibility across hundreds of
different kinds of device
and that's wonderful but it's an
abstraction so unless that abstraction
captures everything you need to do to
reason about the requirements of your
functionality it's not going to go all
the way and for security we know that
this is a massive problem because the
moment you turn up with a stopwatch or a
Power Probe you can completely destroy
these beautiful abstractions because
they leak they are leaky abstractions
they let you expose information about
the underlying implementation of the
device so for timing this is actually
built into the architecture it is an
architectural flaw that you know how
long something took and obviously I
don't need to tell you all about the
sort of extensive literature around
timing attacks and cryptography you're
probably all very familiar but you've
also got power consumption right you've
got power consumption coming from the
data you're Computing on and this is
affected by how the data is computed on
how does it move through the system uh
which registers does it touch which
registers get updated in the meantime
all of this and
you know this is very hard to capture in
a model
um and if your model doesn't capture all
of this information it's very hard to
sort of reason about the security
um so that's why I'm always very
impressed when people come up with
formal Notions of this security it's
just a really really difficult thing to
capture
um so what we wanted to do the problem
we wanted to try and solve was how do we
repeatedly and easily build an
understanding for a particular device
and how it behaves under
um sort of power leakage circumstances
so just looking at really basic
sequences of instructions how do they
differ do all devices behave the same do
they not what is the difference between
those devices
um
and where are my notes
yeah we kind of wanted to do a little
bit of a reverse engineering exercise
basically because there's been lots of
papers in the past that focus on you
know a particular device or a particular
Cipher on a particular device and we
wanted to back up a little bit this is
not an attack paper this is not a
countermeasure paper this is just doing
fundamental Research into how do CPUs
behave if you care about power
consumption and the leakage it might
lead to
um so oh good I should have really moved
on a slide um so yeah we wanted to
understand what does the ISA expose to
you what tools does the ISA give you to
understand the implementation
um and we we did this because we had a
lot of guidance from past papers that
sort of mentioned oh during building
this leakage resistant AES we found some
registers that ruined our results and we
had to do this little change and there's
dozens of papers that kind of mention
this and we kind of refer to this as the
folklore of the literature everyone
every every postdoc every PhD who's
tried to write some leakage
implementation stuff has come kind of
come across these effects but no one's
really written them all down in one
place and tried to repeat them that was
what we tried to do
um we didn't really know why no one had
done it before until about six months in
and we realized how hard it was
um and we wanted to you know see okay we
kind of know something about designing
CPUs there's only so many sensible ways
of Designing a microcontroller so let's
try and use our knowledge of that to
find new problems that other people can
go out and solve
um and we wanted all of this to be
reusable we wanted to make sure that we
could create a suite of programs that
you could all take out and run on a new
device and kind of characterize it from
the point of view of okay these
instruction sequences are going to leak
so I need to do something about that in
my leakage resilient program or my tool
for capturing leakage and modeling it
um
we wanted to also you know assess do
different devices leak differently
spoiler yes they do and we'll see why in
a minute
um and we also wanted to try and explain
all of this it's really hard to create a
coherent way of explaining all of these
results and a paper turned it out to be
it turned out to be a really horrible
way to try and do this because sometimes
scientific publishing doesn't let you
explain all of the things that you
really want to explain in the paper so
I'll talk a little bit about how we got
around that as well
um so the kind of papers that led us to
try and investigate this this is a
selection of them that you all should
definitely go out and read because
they're great there are many more listed
in the paper
um but I think one of the some of the
standout ones for me at the mind the gap
paper they they were kind of the first
ones I'm aware of that did a like a real
I don't know deep dive into some of the
effects that we investigate here they
sort of look to load after load leakage
and how if you have two load
instructions separated by a bunch of ALU
instructions oh actually the two load
values still leak why is that it's quite
interesting
um and it was a great starting point for
us to try and replicate their
experiments across a bunch of other
devices
um the other one I want to kind of call
out is the one on the bottom right there
the on the effect of microarchitecture
leakage that's probably the closest
other paper out there in terms of what
we tried to do they looked at four
devices and a bunch of different
experiments and having read the paper I
think it's great because our results
kind of reinforce one another so it's
quite a nice validation so the point of
Miracle was to sort of take all of these
works that look a particular device or a
particular a cipher or a particular
Effect bring them all together and under
some sort of coherent framework
first we needed to describe the problem
you know why is my implementation broken
and we all know what the Leverage is
like in terms of terminology so we
decided okay we're going to take all of
these different terminologies that
everyone else uses and introduce a new
coherent one just for our paper we hope
it's somewhat useful but it did mean
that when we found different effects we
finally had a consistent vocabulary for
describing them so for example it let us
pick out the difference between you know
this leakage from combinatorial logic
that can be glitching or it can be from
non-glitching because sometimes
combinatorial logic just changes that's
that's by Design whereas glitching is
not and it let us tease out these
effects it was also
um as we sort of did more and more
experiments we found out that you know
you have to differentiate between
instruction between leakage that occurs
within an instruction or because of
interactions with other instructions and
you also had to work out is this leakage
because of a feature of the architecture
is this like an arm phone instruction
that forces you to overwrite a
destination with a source I would call
that a source of architecture leakage
because it's built into the ISA thanks
arm or is it something that's happening
because of a choice someone made in
implementing that so there's micro
architectural leakage and it's really
micro architectural power leakage or MPL
as the paper refers to it um that we
really wanted to dig into
um so this is sort of the map of how we
tried to describe each of the effects We
Found You can disagree with it if you
like
um but we found it quite useful
which devices did we look at we looked
at 16 devices in total or rather we
actually published results on 16 devices
there were others but getting embedded
tool chains to work as a really cursed
process so some of them didn't make it
but we had three broad evaluation
platforms we had scale platform which
was developed by Dan at the University
of Bristol as a teaching Aid we had the
chip Whisperer platform basically the
the chip Whisperer UFO board we just
went and bought all of the
microcontrollers that you can plug into
it pretty easy and if Colin is in the
room thank you we could not have done
this without you
um and then we also use the sasebo G3
platform to look at fpga based uh
microcontrollers so those were the
microblaze things that xilinx will sell
will sell you and also we looked at the
Pico rv32 and this is important for a
reason I'll get to
we had four different device vendors
again this is important we wanted to try
and answer the question does an arm
cortex M3 leak differently when it's
implemented by nxp versus when it's
implemented by St microelectronics hmm
interesting and then six different
models of CPU you've got your regular
arm cortex M some things that we all
know and love from the leakage
literature uh you've also got the
microblaze chip that's uh built into the
that's a soft core built into the xylex
fpgas and then pick rb32 as well which
is an open source risk five chip or
design rather we have five different
pipeline architectures a game really
important how does my leakage resistant
code behave differently on different
pipeline architectures how do the
forwarding paths affect that really
really important to know and then we've
also got six different instruction set
architectures so that's the functional
guarantee versus the actual
implementation that you're trying to
match
um
yeah so just want to ram home this is a
lot of devices to try and manage it was
pretty horrible
um but I think platforms like chick
Whisperer are amazing for for enabling
this kind of research so like can't say
that enough
um in terms of the actual micro
benchmarks that we tried to construct
there's a you know a little sample of
them there but basically they are tiny
little programs that are re-implementing
very very common sequences of
instructions they're not Xboxes they're
not mask gadgets anything like that it's
just sequences of very very common
instructions that you get across all
micro architectures so this example set
here these are the ones we try to work
out or that we used to try and work out
do consecutive load and store
instructions leak even if you put an ALU
style instruction within them so you've
got load then load load then store store
then load store then store all of these
um and we always use these to use each
Benchmark to drive a hypothesis so we
had a hypothesis do does load off the
load League that's a hypothesis then we
go and Implement that test for all of
the architectures that we're looking at
and this was the same for everyone so
this is a very hypothesis driven work
in terms of some results for this so we
found that different CPUs behave
completely differently on these very
very very fundamental sequences of
instructions
um so the each row here represents a
particular CPU each column represents an
um a particular experiment so you see
that load after load that's a very
common effect and I think lots of people
have found that in their work
um but when we start looking at load
then store or store then load we find
that actually different CPUs behave
quite differently
um in the middle there the arm S2 and S3
those are both arm M3 cores implemented
by ft microelectronics so on the same
CPU core on the same architecture
implemented by the same company on two
different devices you've got completely
different leakage behavior for load and
store instructions which if you're
trying to either create a robust
implementation or an optimized
implementation that is portable that's
just a nightmare right you've got such
different behavior for something so
fundamental and this was quite
surprising to us but we're also are very
happy to find it
so another thing that we found we wanted
to look at speculative leakage so put
aside what you know about speculative
leakage from the world of Specter this
is you know kind of related if you
squint a little bit but it's also quite
different basically pipeline CPUs run
ahead they fetch more instructions than
they execute this is just the nature of
pipelines now what we wanted to know is
is there an instruction that is
architecturally speaking not executed so
if you're running an architectural
leakage model and you're just fetching
instructions one at a time
um you won't see this effect this is
quite important when I talk about
something later but the instruction is
still fetched it still does something in
the micro architecture even if the
result is thrown away does it leak yes
yes it does so you can see in this
little example here after the done label
we've just got a bunch of xor
instructions and all we did was go is
there Hamming distance between ra and RC
or B and RD and the power set of those
and low for some CPUs there is for some
CPUs there is not why they differ I'm
not sure I probably need to look at
their source code to know exactly why
this is happening and
um for some reason didn't want to let us
look at the source code of all scpus
but that's just one experiment we did
you can see for all these other
experiments looking at different kinds
of jump and Branch instruction even then
the results were quite different between
CPUs
um to our knowledge no one's really
looked at this no one's looked at uh
microarchitectural Power leakage for
instructions that were never executed
which kind of frightening to think that
something that you didn't do can still
cause leakage
and this is really important because
when people build leakage models
that usually assume that only executed
instructions leak and an executed
instruction is one that the programmer
can see the result for
this implies that even if you didn't
execute the instruction there's still
some leakage can you exploit it I have
no idea but that's not what we were
trying to look at here we were just
trying to look at if you wanted to build
a complete leakage model do you need to
include this I think you probably do
um so that was two of our sort of case
studies there are five case studies all
looking at different kinds of categories
of effects the other ones looked at ALU
instructions and how the operands and
the results intermixed to the pipeline
registers we've also got quite a few
that look at the memory hierarchy so
again a lot of Works tend to look at the
CPU only we kind of tried to expand our
scope to the uncore the memory
interconnect and again we found quite
different behavior in terms of how
memory instructions worked and
interacted in the course so if you end
up with weird scenarios where if you're
loading different memory locations to
different architectural States from
different aligned bytes those bytes can
still interact for some weird reason
um as someone who's designed CPUs I can
sort of look at that and go I can see
how someone would have written it that
way but by the time you're sort of
building a CPU for leakage resilient to
like why on Earth does that happen it's
really weird so this there's other
things to look at if this is piqued your
interest
in terms of sharing all of this um we
couldn't put all this in a paper it just
wouldn't work so all of the experiments
all of the code and the tool chains and
everything for getting it up and running
on all of these chip crispr devices it's
all on GitHub I apologize to all of the
postdocs and phds who get pointed at
this it is my code
um embedded code is pretty cursed
there's no easy way to really structure
all of that code for lots of different
devices but we did our best feedback
accepted as well as put requests but
it's all there and I think that's a
really important thing we want these
benchmarks to be repeatable and reusable
across other devices otherwise this work
is kind of pointless right if we can't
repeat site Channel experiments it's not
science
um we also built a browser-based
interface for actually looking at all of
our results online again we couldn't put
any graphs in the paper there just
wasn't space so we shoved them all
online and you can pick two CPUs compare
the results for them so this this
particular graph has the stm32 F3 and F4
looking at load off the low code one of
them shows leakage one of them doesn't
fun stuff
um at the funding so uh I'm really happy
with what we achieved but I do think
there are areas that we could have
improved and done better in
um the first was there's actually quite
a lot of uh papers that talk about these
sorts of effects but and we wanted to
sort of systematize them and bring them
all together but we ran out of space
that the reviewers said no do this in
another paper we want more information
on how you did your experiments so that
got cut
um but I think if people want to write a
big sock paper on the sort of the
lineage of all this work I think that's
a really good opportunity there
um we also quickly found that when
you're comparing lots of different
devices they all have completely
different noise flaws and noise
signatures so having a consistent
quantitative way of saying this is
leakage this is not would be really good
unfortunately for us it became a very
manual process we had to sort of look is
there a correlation Peak or not manually
and that was quite difficult
um so that's again another thing we
could have done better and we also kind
of had kind of went for breadth over
depth we wanted to show people mainly
that there there is such difference
between different CPUs this is worth
investigating more for particular
experiments so we could have gone in
deep on any one of these experiments but
again we just wanted to show breadth we
also really really wanted to include an
x86 microcontroller but man just don't
try those things are horrible
um yeah with no apology to Intel I get
your tool changed together man
um so conclusions uh like what have we
learned from this so one uh in the
literature we need to be a little more
specific about naming our devices if you
claim leakage resilience on an arm M3
microcontroller this means nothing
because different arm M3s leak
differently so you need to say the exact
device that you tested it on and that is
the limit of your claim for leakage
resilience if you want to claim any
broader result you need to test on more
than one device
um and that's more work but I think it's
worthwhile because hey the Holy Grail of
uh sort of leakage resilient software is
something that's portable that we only
need to write about once and forget
um and we can't do that unless we know
which devices we've tested it so that's
one really important thing
um moving on from that again if you're
if you're actually implementing a master
implementation of something I think we
need to start using more than one device
to show that it's leakage resilient I we
didn't look to see which devices people
actually used for you know first order
secure AES but I wonder if it's on the
slightly more leaky M3 or the slightly
more slightly easier to write for M3
we've found exactly the same thing on
cortex M4 devices as well different m4s
well they're the same in for M4
implemented by the same manufacturer on
different devices it leaked differently
so which ones should we use for
evaluation I kind of leave that to you
um but what I do think when people like
nist are saying okay this is going to be
our standard evaluation platform for the
lwc uh competition or the pqc
competition they kind of need more than
one right if you if we all develop on
just one device we're going to end up
with quite skewed results uh kind of
simple observation but it might make me
unpopular for the amount of work it
generates
and then if you're building leakage
models again you kind of need to do the
same or you need to say we have built a
leakage model for this device
um which makes me think okay building
leakage models uh for a particular
device isn't actually what we want to
focus on as a community what we should
be doing is generating a methodology a
flow to say here's my device here's some
tooling and I'm going to push a button
and it's going to generate a leakage
model for this device and I think a nice
way of validating those models is to run
the kinds of experiments that we've
shared as part of the miracle study they
kind of become leakage they've become
unit tests for your models because
they're modeling the very low level
behavior of the cpu's
um I think this is quite a nice thing to
do and I think papers like coco or I
couldn't find a short name for this
paper but masking in fine grain leakage
models these are great examples of that
kind of Direction they're building
models using sort of formal basis and I
think uh sort of the empirical side that
Miracle tries to do there's a really
nice tie in here
so what next well there's always more
devices
everyone's bringing out microcontrollers
all the time we can always add to this
really easily
um and there's always more micro
architectural effects like I say we went
in went for breadth not depth there's
more out there folks uh the truth is out
there
um this was not an attack paper or
accounts managed paper can you exploit
these I don't know and you might say
well if I can't exploit these why do I
care well
you know I work in Industry now so I
care because it means I can fail a
leakage evaluation when I'm trying to
get my thing certified that's why I care
I don't necessarily care that you can't
recover the key it's just got to pass
the leakage evaluation so you kind of
got to broaden your scope about what you
care about now
um which types of leakage are more or
less dangerous is it sequential is it
combinatorial is it architectural
microarchitectural which one's easier to
exploit I don't know
um and then how do we look at not just
the CPU but like I said we were starting
to look at the wider system because it
all has an effect
um and the bigger picture this is kind
of my challenge to the community so if
you work in sat solving and you work in
sort of that area of Academia they have
this language called sm2 or smt2 that is
like a common interface to all academic
sat solvers so they can all run
competitions together I think we should
create a standard way of describing what
do instructions do to micro
architectures and then vendors of CPUs
can say hey this is what each
instruction does go and build a leakage
model for the CPU and it becomes really
easy to just focus on the modeling
rather than uh sort of actually reverse
engineering which is what we spent all
our time doing
um
So yeah thank you for listening it's
been a pleasure to present this I can't
emphasize enough this took so long it's
it took longer than the average postdoc
contract to actually get this work out
um so I think there's probably something
to be said about you know do it being
able to do fundamental engineering
research and present it at a venue like
chairs is really really valuable and
anything that enables that is really
good so thank you for listening
congratulations for making it all the
way through off the banquet I really
hope you've got some questions
thank you thank you then is that is
there any question in the urgents
community
interesting so just to make sure I've
understood the question you wanted to
make sure that given that you're
operating on a 32-bit word do different
bits leak different amounts we could
absolutely have tested that yes it's
probably in our data set somewhere but
we didn't pull out the results yeah but
that would be a really interesting way
to look for different implementations of
the same CPU implementing differently
because that kind of does Bit Zero leak
more than bit two that's very much more
dependent on the synthesis and the place
and root of each device so yeah that
would be a really interesting follow-up
so oh sorry
um
[Music]
so the life made our experiments much
easier here in that none of these
platforms have CPU caches they're all
microcontroller targets so CPU caches
aren't a thing
um not in these platforms anyway they do
exist but not here if you wanted to try
and write leakage resilient code for a
cash man that's just a next level
World of Pain because you don't know
where your stored data is going to end
up in the cache you're going to evict a
different cash flow it's a mess
definitely something that you could try
and model formally because you can
reverse engineer the eviction behavior
of the cache especially if you know it's
replacement policy so yeah definitely a
cool thing to look at the only kind of
caches that these platforms really have
are the flash caches
um we didn't look at those we
deliberately tried to keep everything
executing an SRAM because it made our
analysis in life a little bit easier but
yeah definitely you should write a paper
on that
maximum yeah
[Music]
so we definitely saw different pipeline
effects affect different pipeline
lengths affecting our experiments
completely differently as you might
expect one of the interesting case
studies to look at there is the
microblaze core so it's the same
fundamental microarchitecture but xylink
slightly parameterize it between three
five and nine pipeline stages steep so
it's a really cool Target to investigate
this in the way we tried to compensate
for this different difference in
pipeline length for our experiments was
to basically pad with an inert
instruction we didn't use knob you can't
use knob for this kind of thing because
it has no guaranteed architectural
effect but you can use another inert
instruction like adding something with
itself just making sure that register
doesn't do anything so yeah Pat We pad
the the Prelude and the exit load of the
the micro benchmarks to make sure that
it's just that going through the
pipeline sequentially and nothing else
but yeah you're right that's that's
exactly the kind of nightmare that I had
to spend a month trying to work out how
do I do this across a bunch of different
devices
okay
[Music]
hello
we did not but I would be fascinated to
know whether our revisions differed yeah
um so as far as I know the the main
difference I could observe was because
we did try and work this out we looked
at the actual device data sheets for the
cores that were leaking so differently
for the M3 case I think the the one that
leaked less was marketed for sort of
medical applications and they said oh
it's very low noise it doesn't do very
much ah interesting okay and then the
one that was uh leaking somewhat more
forgive my terminology
um was sort of high performance this
thing goes fast
I'm not sure why exactly that makes such
a difference it could just be that
someone forgot a register enable and it
it's it's uh it's behavior that you
don't care about during the verification
stage so yeah I think the the
thing we could see was that the way the
the way the device was marketed seemed
to correlate with the behavior but I'd
love to know if it's a later generation
M3 I think that would be a really cool
thing to know
all right
[Music]
um oh I mean
engineering challenges yeah I mean if
you search the get commit history for
expletives that would probably be a good
way to to work out what the problems
were I think the first problem we faced
was okay how do we just get all our
programs to compile for all of these
different devices and you know I learned
an awful lot more about make files than
I really want to know to do that that
was one thing
um the other is how do you keep a
consistent measurement set up across
different devices this is not something
I'm sure we solve perfectly but it was
good enough to be confident in our
results
um the other was just how do you collect
this volume of data and then analyze it
sensibly like this I ended up talking to
social scientists about how do you you
know compare different data sets like
this and that was kind of why we built
this web-based interface to try and have
a tool that we could easily compare
different devices with
um
there were numerous others but those are
the ones that I still wake up from
nightmares about
okay one question so yeah go
ahead
[Music]
so
um
[Music]
uh I I'm sorry I couldn't quite
understand the question you're saying
how do how do RTL simulations fit into
this
[Music]
okay so RTL simulations definitely have
their place if you've got access to the
RTL
um so if if you can do this if you're a
vendor um nxp EST if you're here if you
want to publish this information it
would make our lives much easier
um The reason an RTL simulation is so
important is because the reason these
effects can manifest or not can
literally be down to just one lazy
engineer including an and gate on
whether or not the register update
enable is there or not and you can't
really find that out find that out as
the root cause unless you've got the RTL
and you can see it toggle in the
waveforms so I think as a as a way of
working out what's going on yeah use RTL
simulations man they're really helpful
thank you
so we also have one online question
um about the speculative execution
regarding leakage from from non-executed
Instructions is there a difference in
the leakage compared to the same
instructions being executed
oh that's a good one no not really
because
um
so when you said difference
um you do see different halves of the
instruction leak so typically a
non-executed instruction will only leak
the the part of it that reads its
operands because the result is going to
be thrown away so the leakage is
different in that respect in terms of
the magnitude of the leakage
um still there still detectable there
was no there was no obvious like
weakness in the correlation because it
was executed or not
um
so yeah and the reason for that is
fundamentally it's the same CMOS logic
toggling in exactly the same way
regardless of whether the instruction is
thrown away halfway or not
um so yeah that made sense to me as
someone who's had to build a CPU power
plane yeah
okay thank you thank you Ben we are
running out of time so next question in
the coffee break thank you thank you
again
so we have a quick track switch break
for those of you who want to go in the
other room
foreign
uh yes um can you tell me which which
session are you it's the next episode
you're a second so this should be clear
Okay so we've had them great uh yeah 22
slides okay yeah that's okay
um yeah if
foreign
thank you
for which uh which makes things like
um this one this one
maybe this one okay yeah but for now I'm
sorry because we had some type of
glitches so you will have to change
sites like this it's okay uh yeah yeah
no problem okay we usually have a
pointer but I cannot find the USB
um
yeah yeah sure sure
thank you
okay is there a laser or this laser
pointer for this uh yeah it should be if
you if
okay
okay please give us yes
it was awful
yeah thank you
this is okay so everything works yeah
okay
I think uh we're waiting for session
yeah yeah I know she's just here okay
when it's okay once it goes to uh red it
means it's time for questions and you
should end up your destination okay
um and maybe go a little bit over time
but okay I'll try to see uh yes I mean
the session chair will yeah yeah okay
hey
foreign
boarding uh you're uh handling that
right yes yes
thank you
so we are reaching uh two minutes
that's okay but uh yeah
I'll be sure she's taking the time sure
thank you
okay thanks
everyone
so welcome to the second session on the
attacks on bus Quantum systems so we
will have two talks in this session uh
both on the side Channel assisted
attacks on the post Quantum schemes and
so the first talk is given by a
suppressana Ravi and it will be about
attacks on Andrew Andrew camps
uh uh hello everyone I thank you for the
introduction so I'm president Ravi from
Narnia Technological University
Singapore and this work was jointly done
with martinez Friedrich izeman Shivam
Bassin anupam Sato padya and sujay Sinha
Roy so let's start with a bit of
motivation so I think it's fair to say
that lattice based schemes have
dominated the pqc process a process in
the category of camps and uh
predominantly there are two major
categories of lattice based chems once
based on the learning with the error
rounding problem and the others based on
the entry problem and during the course
of the pqc process lattice based chems
were heavily scrutinized by side Channel
attacks and there were several
categories of sites and attacks and one
of the most prominent categories of
attacks was called a side Channel as
it's a churn ciphertext attacks and in
this the attacker's main idea is to
craft malicious ciphertexts and query
the decapsulation procedure and the
corresponding side Channel leakage is
used to actually realize on Oracle which
provides incremental information about
the secret key and the attacker queries
the decapsulation device with several
ciphertix to actually recover the entire
secret key
now why are these attacks interesting
because these attacks have very nice
features so firstly attacks are fairly
generic because they exploit inherent
algorithmic properties of the target
scheme and in most cases they require
minimal or almost no knowledge of the
implementation and hence can be readily
ported so the attack can be readily
ported to both hardware and software and
uh through this talk I'm also going to
try to convince you that this is
probably the easiest side Channel attack
that's possible on lattice based camps I
might be wrong it's debatable but I'll
try my best so there are three different
flavors of such attacks based on the
type of Oracle that you want to realize
through side channels so first is the
plaintext checking oracle-based attack
the second one is a decryption failure
Oracle and the third is the full
decryption Oracle and if you look at the
taxonomy of existing side Channel
resistance ciphertext attacks you'll
actually see that there are quite a few
attacks on the LW and lwr based site but
there's probably none on the intro based
schemes so this Begins the question if
there are similar attacks that are
possible on entry-based camps and if so
our entropic based chems are more easy
or difficult to attack compared to lwnl
learning with the error and learning
with your rounding base camps so we
answered these two questions positively
in this work by proposing generic side
Channel as to turn ciphertext attacks on
entry-based chems so we target both the
final both entry which is the finalists
and the Enterprise which was the
alternate finalist candidate and we show
that uh the attacker requires
approximately the same effort to break
both entry-based chems compared to camps
based on their learning with the error
and rounding problem and our attack
requires a few hundred a few thousand
turns to have a text queries for key
recovery and the attack works for all
parameter sets of entry with uh and
enter enter Prime with 100 success rate
and we experimentally validated our
attack using em side channel on the arm
cortex M4 microcontroller
so in a nutshell there is a contribution
so we try to level the playing field by
proposing attacks on the for entry-based
chems as well
and let's start with a bit of background
for entry-based chems so as you all know
chem chems are cryptographic Primitives
that are used to derive a shared key
between two untrusted parties so you
typically have three procedures the key
generation encapsulation and
decapsulation so here we have Alice
running the key generation process to
generate the public key and secret key
and you have Bob using the public key
and an internally uh randomly generated
message to generate a ciphertext and a
shared session key
and you have uh uh Alice who uses a
ciphertext decapsulates the ciphertext
with the secret key to generate the same
shared session key
now it turns out that Alice can actually
reuse her public key and secret keypad
multiple times to generate multiple
session keys and this is what we refer
to as a static key setting and uh and
our attacks are actually applicable in
this particular setting so Bob is our
attacker who actually uh queries uh
Alice with malicious ciphertext for key
recovery and compromise of the secret
key leads to recovery of all the session
keys
so this is how decapsulation looks like
so we start with uh decrypting the
ciphertext to recover the message and
then the message is spread into a
re-encryption and a verification process
which basically validates whether the
ciphertext was a validly crafted
ciphertext or is an invalid Cipher text
and for valid ciphertext you generate a
valid key which is marked in green here
and the key is basically dependent on
the message public key and the cipher
text and if the ciphertext is invalid
then you basically generate a
pseudorandom key which is marked in red
and this works fairly correctly with a
very high probability and this framework
is secure against own ciphertext attacks
so how does a side Channel based turns
architecture attacks work so basically
the uh the basic idea is that the
attacker builds Cipher texts in order to
control the value of a secret dependent
variable which we refer to as the anchor
variable and subsequently the attacker
uses side channels as an oracle to
obtain uh some information about this
anchor variable and the attacker does
this for several such Cypher texts which
ultimately results in key recovery
so in order to understand how this
attack works for entry-based chems we
need to understand how entry-based
encryption Works which lies the core of
entry-based chems so we started the key
generation procedure which involves
sampling of two ternary polynomials f
and g and as you all know uh entry works
with polynomials and polynomial rings so
we have two ternary polynomials f and g
and then the entry instance is
calculated as H equal to 3 times D times
inverse of f where the entry instance is
the public key and the ternary polymers
F and z are the secret keys
in encryption procedure you have the
ephemeral uh so you uh sample and other
attorney polynomial are you multiplied
with the public key and you can generate
H times R and then you add it to the
message uh which is encoded as a ternary
polynomial again and you generate the
ciphertext and in the decryption you
multiply the ciphertext with uh the
secret key polynomial F and then you
reduce it modulo 3 and multiply it with
f inverse which gives you the message so
I'm not going to going to go into the
details of why this decryption Works uh
but what's important to note is that
there is this particular variable called
a uh whose absolute maximum value of the
coefficient should not cross a certain
threshold that's called Q by two and if
it does then it results in a decryption
failure but uh chems like intro and
intro Prime were designed in such a
manner that uh this particular failure
does not happen so they are basically
perfectly correct camps
so now that we have some background on
entry-based chems I'll jump into the
first attack which is a plain text
taking oracle-based attack
uh so this attack is basically inspired
from the classical German cyber text
attack on uh the original intro scheme
by you all may and you encrypted 2000
and the attack Works in two phases so in
the first phase uh which is called the
pre-processing phase we search for a
base ciphertext and whose leakage
actually reveals critical information
about the secret key and once you
identify the base ciphertext in the
subsequent key recovery phase you use
the base ciphertext to build multiple
attacks ciphertexts whose leakage
ultimately recovers the secret key so
this is the whole idea and now let's
start with the first pre-processing
phase so the attacker choose a
ciphertext of this fashion which is k1
times T1 plus K2 times T2 times H where
T1 and T where T1 is X bar I one plus X
bar I2 and so on until I am with M terms
and T2 is X bar J1 plus X bar J2 until
so 100 uh X bar JN with n terms where i1
I2 until I am at J1 J2 until JN are
randomly chosen indices and the
constants K1 and K2 are basically
multiples of 3 and now if you look at
the corresponding
intermediate variable a you can actually
see that a is nothing but 3 K 1 times T1
times f plus K2 times T2 times G
now what's important to note is these
two products T1 times F and T2 times D
so if you look at T1 times F it's
nothing but X bar I 1 times f plus X for
I 2 times F and so on and uh in intro
basically Works in polynomial Rings
where multiplication of a polynomial
with X bar i1 rotates the polynomial by
i1 indices so basically uh the product
T1 times f is nothing but rotation of f
by i1 plus rotation of f by I2 and so on
and so on so T1 times f is nothing but
the sum of rotations of F and if you
look at the absolute maximum value of a
coefficient of T1 times F it's nothing
but M so if you want to visualize this
here you have multiple rotations of F
and the maximum value of M is possible
when any particular coefficient uh for
all the sum rotations of f has a value
of 1. so only then uh the absolute
maximum value for the coefficient is
actually attained and this is what we
refer to as a collision now obviously if
you increase the number of terms M then
the probability of collision actually
decreases
so now uh with this idea if you look at
the variable a and if you want to
compute the absolute maximum value of a
then it's nothing but 3 K 1 times M plus
K2 times n because T2 times G has n
terms so this is the absolute maximum
value for a coefficient of a and the
absolute maximum value is possible when
there is a collision at the
corresponding index so if there is a
collision between rotations of F and
rotations of g at the ith location there
you have a collision
so now what the attacker does is you can
actually choose a parameters M and K1
and K2 in such a way that when there is
a collision then that corresponding
coefficient goes greater than Q by 2 and
we also choose parameters to excel
actually maximize the probability of a
single Collision
so this is a visualization of the
coefficients of a and if there is a
collision at the ith coefficient the
corresponding coefficient goes beyond
the threshold of Q by 2 and this is what
we refer to as a wrap failure and if a
collision occurs then this particular
variable e actually has a non-zero value
where with with a single non-zero term
and if there is no Collision then the
value of e is actually zero so what an
attacker essentially has done is that
using the chosen ciphertext he has
restricted the value of e to just two
values it's either e with a single
non-zero term or E with zero
so now how do you detect such collisions
the obvious answer is through side
channels so if you look at this
particular operation here you are either
multiplying with a 0 or e or you're
multiplying with a non-zero e and this
is a very easily distinguishable through
side channels without relying on any
leakage models and so on
so this is what we refer to as a side
Channel based plain text taking Oracle
through which you are trying to
distinguish whether e is actually 0 or
non-zero
so how do we detect collisions so we do
this using a simple veg t-tests so
basically you decapsulate uh so you have
two sets so in a first set you basically
decapsulate a zero ciphertext which
corresponds to equal to zero and let's
say you get 10 repeated executions for c
equal to 0 and in the second set you
build a chosen Cipher text uh and then
you decapsulate it repeatedly and then
you get the second set and then you
compute the Welsh status now I'm going
to meander off a little bit to explain
the exponential setup so we performed
our attacks on optimized implementations
of enter and Enterprise from the PCM for
library and the target platform is the
sm32 F4 based on the arm cortex M4
processor
uh so if you compute the Vesti test you
will observe two possibilities so the
first possibility is that you don't
observe any leakage which means that
there is no collision and if You observe
several Theta speaks then uh you know
that uh there was a collision
so now what the attacker simply does is
you select the features above a certain
threshold as points of interest and you
build templates for both the classes uh
equal to zero and E not equal to zero
so now that we have the templates and we
I've identified a base ciphertext we are
good to go for the key recovery phase so
in the key recovery phase the attacker
actually constructs uh attacks
ciphertext using the base ciphertext and
these ciphatex are constructed in such a
way that uh the value of e is restricted
only two possibilities e equal to 0 and
E not equal to 0 and the value of e
actually depends on a single coefficient
of f
and obviously
[Music]
um
uh f is a ternary polynomial and F has
three possibilities so you can use the
information about Collision or no
Collision as a binary distinguisher for
uh to actually distinguish every
possible candidate of F and uh obviously
we have side Channel information so you
can use the side Channel templates to
classify whether there is a collision or
whether there is a no Collision
so here we have a visualization of our
classification so on the left hand side
you actually see uh the template for
class o which is equal to zero and you
have a template for class X which is e
not equal to 0 and on the left hand side
you see a trace corresponding to class o
and on the right hand side you see a
trace corresponding to class X so you
can see that though both the graphs are
both the trays are very easily
distinguishable for both the both the
cases and uh through our experiments we
also verified that the single trace
classification works with 100 success
rate
so on to some results so we validated
our attack on all the parameters of
entry and the number of traces required
is between 1800 and 2900 and if you
compare uh this with uh the same attack
on kyber it also requires approximately
the same number of traces
and if you look at the attack on enter
Prime uh the number of phrases are
slightly higher because there are a few
complications like a rounding of
ciphertext and so on so the number of
phrases slightly higher uh compared to
the attack on intro uh so uh yeah this
is our uh these are these are our
results for enter Prime and obviously
you can see that at no point during the
attack the attacker requires any
knowledge about the implementation so
the attack is fairly generic
so uh though the attack works really
well on Android Prime we have a few
observations particularly on Android
Prime and what we observe is that this
information about this anchor variable
which is secret dependent actually does
not propagate Beyond decryption so in
order to uh so what happens in enter
Prime is that it has a special weight
check uh failure of weight check
operation which actually fails for all
our attack ciphertexts so uh for all
that attack ciphertexts the output of
the message is the fixed uh invalid
message so in order to perform the
attack the attacker can only rely on
leakage from the decryption procedure
while uh leakage from the re-encryption
procedure and the comparison procedure
is still cannot be used for key recovery
so the obvious question is whether we
can widen the scope of our attack to
also Target the re-encryption procedure
and the comparison procedure
uh so this brings us to the second
attack which is the decryption failure
Oracle based attack and I'd like to just
simply present the idea for the attack
so the key idea is that the attacker
takes a valid Cipher text and then adds
the attack ciphertext that you use for
the plaintext checking Oracle attack and
he builds a pert up Cipher text so the
attacker basically queries with pert up
Cipher texts and these cipherteks either
decrypt uh to either a valid message or
an invalid message so either I have a
decryption success or a decryption
failure and this information can
actually be used by an attacker to
actually exploit leakage from the
recryption procedure to recover the
secret key and this is what we refer to
as a side Channel based decryption
failure Oracle
and some results for the decryption
failure Oracle based attack so uh we
performed our attack on enter Prime and
the attack actually requires slightly
higher number of traces between four
thousand and five thousand because you
have uh possibilities of false
collisions false positive collisions
false negative collisions multiple
collisions and so on but an attacker can
choose parameters in such a way so as to
maximize the probability of a single
Collision uh so if at all he uh
identifies a false Collision false
positive or A first negative Collision
he just has to Simply repeat the attack
because that can be easily detected so
that's why you have slightly higher
number of traces for key recovery and if
you compare this with the same attack on
kyber it requires approximately five
thousand to eight thousand traces so the
cost of doing the attack on both and
true and LW
or kyber is more or less the same
so I I'm not touching upon full
decryption Oracle based uh attack uh
because of lack of time so I'll directly
jump to conclusion
so uh in this work we've basically
demonstrated generic sites and let's
search attacks on entry-based chems we
have demonstrated three types of attacks
uh belonging to the plaintext taking
Oracle base category decryption failure
Oracle and full decryption Oracle and
the take home message of this talk is
that breaking introchems through such
attacks is actually very similar to
Breaking LW and lwr-based camps and uh
uh we exponently validated our attack on
the arm cortex M4 microcontroller and
our attacks basically demonstrate the
ease of attacking unprotected
implementations for key recovery as our
attacks are implementation agnostic and
I hope I hope I've convinced you that
this is probably the easiest side
Channel attack that's that could be done
on lattice based camps so the code
package is available at this GitHub
repository and uh yeah thank you very
much for your attention
thank you president for the nice talk
are there questions
I've seen the chats
so I have some questions
um what is the success probability of
the sectional part of the of this attack
and also what is the complexity of
finding the base side for text because
is there some trailer up there yeah so
yeah so uh these are results for enter
Prime and you have uh you have two uh
two numbers here one is dbase which is
the number of traces that you require to
find the base ciphertext first so you
have to go for multiple iterations so
you build different ciphertext and you
check if there's a collision if there's
no Collision you go back you try with
another ciphertix and so on and so it
requires a few iterations uh but then if
you compare it with the total number of
traces it's uh okay
and also and also for the other question
on uh side channel uh classification
success so uh the number of points of
interest are range between few hundreds
and few thousands because you have
several operations uh to actually Target
so at least from our experiments we did
not observe any uh failure okay yeah
okay so it's like a really simple uh
exactly and so I had another question
but uh other questions
so how do you fix the thresholds uh the
threshold is a parameter of the
experimental setup actually so it uh so
if you want to Target a device you'll
have to perform attacks in the same
device earlier so it it could I mean it
basically varies from device to device
but then uh yeah yeah okay so you just
maximize it and until the attack works
better okay
and last question uh did you analyze the
combination of this attack with lattice
reduction uh because intro can be solved
with uh should we uh we were able to
perform 4K recovery so we did not okay
yeah but I think
okay well thank you thank you president
okay
thank you very much
so the next stop will be uh given by
Andreas Johansson and uh so it's about
an attack on my kitties implementation
foreign
uh so this is the outline of this
presentation
so a few years ago news announced a
competition to find new cryptographic
schemes that are believed to be secure
even if sufficient large
quantum computers are built
so this summer list also announced that
uh
that well a lattice based scheme had
been selected for standardization
but they also announced that there will
be an additional round with alternative
candidates and possibly some of these
candidates will be standardized in the
future
um and the classic Michaelis is one of
these alternative candidates
so just make a list is a key
encapsulation mechanism that is intended
to be used during the establishment of
symmetric keys
so it is built on near writer's dual
version of the original Michaelis and
the original maclease
um
it's a code-based scheme
that was proposed in 1978
um and it's a security is considered to
be well studied so both the um
original and the classic maclist make
use of binary copper codes
and the security relies on the hardness
of decoding random linear codes
so this is an overview of the encryption
and decryption and classic Mac list
so first we have a plain text of length
M and Hemingway T to get to ciphertext
we multiply the plain text with a public
key then we send a ciphertext over
insecure channel to the receiver where
we use an error correcting algorithm to
decode a ciphertext with a private key
or secret key
so to set the security level in classic
mcalees we have pre-system parameters so
n will set the length of the plain text
T was at the Hamming weight of the pen
text and M will Define the final field
over which all the computations are
performed
so the secret key in a classic make a
list is a binary copper code and this
code is defined by polynomial D of X of
the degree T and the support n that
consists of n distinct elements
so the input to the key generation
algorithm or a free system parameters
ntmn so first we choose a random support
and then a random polynomial e of x
then we use the polynomial and the
support to construct a parity check
Matrix for the code and this Matrix then
a stand transformed into a binary
systematic form and the transformed
Matrix is used as the public key and as
a single key we use this G of X and the
support
so there are some relations between the
two secret keyboards that we can take
advantage of during an attack so first
if we know the support then we can
recover G of X by using the definition
of a copper code
and also we don't need to know the full
support to carry out this
second if we know e of X then we can use
the support splitting algorithm to find
the support but this only works if n is
equal to 2 to the power of M
so any case that we have that n is equal
to 2 to the power of M then we can
sketch on the idea of a key recovery
attack
so first if we can get some partial
information about the support then we
can use this information to recover G of
X and once we found G of X we can
recover the full secret support
and in the submission of casting like
list there is actually one parameter set
that can be attacked in this way
and I get back to the case when any
smaller later
so to recover G of X we make use of the
definition of a gopa code so from this
definition we have that all code words C
must fulfill this relation
then we can construct a new polynomial C
of X and then by the definition of the
gopa code which can factor C of x to get
G of x
and to be able to build this C of X we
only need to know the secret support at
the
at the index set of decoder so we only
need to have partial information about
the secret support
so if we know G of X then we can pick a
random support and construct a new code
c0 then from CCO we can drive a generate
the Matrix and we can also uh derive a
generator Matrix from the probability
then we can feed these two matrices as
input to the support splitting algorithm
and the output will be in the
experimentation between the two codes
so then since we know the support of c0
we can use the uh this index permutation
to recover the secret support
now in the case that why this only
worked for n is equal to 2 to the power
of M is that for smaller n is hard for
us to guess uh which subset of elements
are in the secret support
so in our work we have attacked both the
hardware and software implementation of
classic maclease so the hardware were
synthesized with level one parameters
and then implemented on the silinks
Arctic 7 fpga
the software implementation was compiled
with level one parameters for a cortex M
for microcontroller
both the hardware and software were then
integrated with a ship whisper which is
a framework for measuring side channel
that can be used for measuring size
channels leakage
so both the hardware and the software
implementation make use of the same
decryption algorithm so the input to
this algorithm is the ciphertext and the
two key Secret Key Parts
so first the two secret keyboards are
used to construct the double size 30
check Matrix which is then used to
construct the double size syndrome and
this genome is fed to a belly cap messy
algorithm and the output is an error
located polynomial Sigma of x
and to recover the plain text this error
locator Sigma is evaluated over all the
support elements and if
this thing evaluates the zero for a
particular support element then we see a
set this bit I to a one otherwise zero
so in our work we have focused on the
fifth step of the decryption uh someone
should note that we can control the
shape of the sigma so for example if we
encrypt um create a plain text with a
only the three first bits are set to
once and grip this and send it for
decryption then this Sigma will be of
degree three with roots at the free
first supporter elements
so both the hardware and software
implementation make use of an additive
fft to speed up the evaluation of their
locator
so the
array evaluation is done in a
deterministic way and this Sigma is
evaluated over all the field elements
so no matter which element are in the
secret support for fixed Sigma this fft
will run through the same steps
so the only input to this additive fft
is this error locator which we can
control by Crossing ciphertext
so important thing here is that if for a
fixed Sigma no matter which element or
in the secret support this fft will run
through the same intermediate values
during the evaluation and this is what
we exploit during our attack
so the idea for attack is that if we can
create the plain text where we want to
set with i201 then if we encrypt this
send it to the the decryption then the
sigma will be of degree 1 with a root at
the support element Alpha I
then depending on the system parameters
there are only 2 to the power of M
possible uh degree one polynomials and
in if we can distinguish between the
evaluation of different uh polynomials
then we can predict the value of this
Alpha I
uh so if we can
determine arbitrary support elements
then we can mount the partial keyword
recovery attack
so here the goal is to create this
polynomial C of X and as I said before
we only need to know
the support elements at the index set of
this cold war C so to reduce the number
of support elements that we need to
determine we would like to find a code
with low homing weight
so we can get Valley covers from the
generator Matrix which can be
constructed from the public key and from
this matrix it's quite easy to find a
codeword with a weight of R half plus
one where R is equal to n times t
however by using information setting
coding we can find a codeword with even
lower weight
yeah and this in turn means that we
don't need to determine so many Alphas
which also means that we can reduce the
time that we need to be physically close
to the device under attack
for a full key right here we attack
there are two cases so first uh if n is
equal to two to the power of M then we
use our partial keyword cable attack to
get D of X and then we use the support
splitting algorithm to get the support
and we're done when n is smaller than 2
to the power of M
then we speak about
then we tweak our attack a bit
so now we try to find a matrix P such
that when p is Multiplied with a public
key we get the parity check Matrix
so to be able to construct P we need to
know the M times T first elements in the
secret support as well as as this G of x
so one way to reduce the number of
support elements that we need to
determine is to form the generator
Matrix and then we just pick a random
row
since this uh we only already need is M
times T first element we only need one
additional support element to get G of x
so from our two attacks we can see that
the number of the support elements that
we need to determine depends on the
system parameters so this table is from
classic Michael release submission and
it shows the system parameters for
different security levels so for the
first four we see that n is smaller than
2 to the power of M so in this case uh
we need to recover the
or Plus One support elements
but for one of the level of level five
parameter set we see that n is equal to
two to power of M so in this case our
partial T recovery attack is equivalent
to a full herocabulary attack
uh so here we use information is
information set decoding to find a low
weight code word uh so in this table we
see that by running this algorithm for
about two minutes we can find the code
with a Heming rate of 695 which is about
60 smaller than the random case
so we carry out our attack as a profile
inside Channel attack which consists of
a profiling phase another attack phase
so during the profiling phase we assume
that we have access to a device that is
similar to the one we later on the
intend to attack
uh but we have full control of this
device and can set the secret key
we then craft multiple ciphert text and
send them to this profiling device and
then we measure the power consumption uh
while it performs decryption and then we
use all of this measurement to construct
a classifier that can predict some
partial information about the secret key
so the attack fast is quite similar but
now we have a device that we can only
set the ciphertext to so and we have no
knowledge of the key of course so again
we craft multiple ciphertexts similar to
decryption measure the power consumption
then we take all the measurements or
traces and feed them to our pre-trained
classifier to predict the some partial
information about the
yeah
so before constructing our classifier we
evaluate if it's impossible to exploit
the leakage of this additive fft
so for this we collect multiple traces
that corresponds to the evaluation of
degree 1 polynomials and then we split
all the
traces into two sets so the first set
corresponds to ciphertext that before to
a specific ciphertext which in turn
generate a specific Sigma as input to
F50 and the other set corresponds to
cyber text that generates random Sigma
sub degree one then we calculate the
t-test between these two sets
uh for the hardware implementation we
can see that there seems to be some
leakage present uh during this additive
fft step which occurs in the second dark
gray region
uh for a software implementation we can
see even more pronounced leakage so
during the fft which of course in the
gray region
and the leak is detected towards the end
of course during the re-encryption but
we have not investigated this further in
this work
um
so we use the ship whisper light to
collect traces
so that related to use to construct our
classifier
so we use the following procedure so
first we load the secret key to the
profiling device
then we pick a random eye and then we
create the plain text where only beat I
is set to R1
and encrypt the plain text and send it
to decryption and then we measure the
power consumption uh
while the fft step is executed
and afterwards we label the trace with a
support element Alpha I
and then we repeat this procedure
procedure multiple times with multiple
keys
so then we use machine learning to build
a classifier
so the goal of this classifier is that
if that it can predict this value of the
degree one polynomial Sigma
so if we can construct such a classifier
than during an attack we can generate a
plain tags were only bit I asset to a
one send it to the Target device
and I measure the power consumption and
then feed this to your input to our
classifier so then we can predict the
value of alpha I
so we make use of uh deep learning and a
multi-layer perception model
with only a hidden a single layer so for
the hardware implementation
we use around 400 000 traces for
training and for software implementation
we use around 35 000 traces
so this is the result uh we then
evaluate our classifier on a new set of
new keys that were not used during
training
so for the hardware implementation we
perform experiment on 30 random keys
and for each key we can successfully
recover the complete a complete secret
support
and each supporter element only needs it
requires one trace for prediction so we
have an accuracy of 100 percent
for the software implementation was
similar assault so here we perform
experiments on 90 random keys uh and uh
here we also get an accuracy of 100
so once you note that uh if one use our
partial or full key recovery attack as I
presented earlier we actually don't need
to recover the full SQL support but this
result shows that this our attacks can
be carried out with a higher success
probability
so to conclude this presentation we have
presented to our knowledge the first key
recovery such Channel Tech on both the
hardware and software implementation of
classic Mercedes and our attack exploits
the leakage that occurs during the fft
step of the decryption
uh so for the level one parameter set
our partial key recovery attack requires
273 traces and a full keyword key
recovery attack requires
796 traces
whatever for one of the level five
parameter sets Which is higher security
uh our partial team recovery attack
requires 679 traces and in this case our
partial kit recovery attack is
equivalent to a full keyword camera
attack
uh so for future research we have some
idea so how we can improve our attack
such that fewer traces are needed during
the attack phase and also we are unaware
of any protected implementation of
majestic machines so we are interested
in looking into how one could Implement
efficient countermeasures
okay thank you for listening
thank you Andreas are there any
questions in the room
the ninja Jets
so I had several questions
um I I didn't really get the exact cost
of the remaining uh like a key recovery
the crypto analytic Parts is there
possible trade-offs like trading some
Precision in the classification so
requiring less traces uh and then having
a more costly uh
um key recovery phase do you think there
are some Traders like that I'm afraid of
between well working the in a number of
traces
I mean the pre-processing thing is that
uh no the the post-processing step when
you have at the end when you uh from the
information that you got to recover the
key
uh
sorry what what is there
no worries uh you had a slide with the
the attack uh without the sectional just
at the beginning when you presented the
the two techniques of attacks when uh
you have M which is equal and
when oh this one so what what is the
complexity of this and the the
complexity of this uh
this procedure I mean the
Tech Shop complexity in number of traces
uh no in work so I suppose that it's
like uh easy to get on the machine like
uh
I'm not sure okay Lawrence okay you can
just get the player
other questions
yeah and uh so you said that uh
oh sorry uh ah yeah maybe okay you said
that the fft
um was the the part that you attacked
inside channel would you think that fft
would be a like avoiding fft would be a
good country measure
so no I don't think you should avoid
this relative because it will be a huge
penalty in the efficiency
so but maybe one should take a look at
what happens before the fft and maybe
see if we can Implement some
countermeasures even earlier to disable
this so the key thing is that we can
control this shape of this Sigma so if
we can get rid of this then this will
actually
uh yeah remove our attack
okay thank you very much
no questions okay so let's thank Andreas
and president again
so one quick announcement so there is
the coffee break so uh please take a cup
of coffee and tea and go check out the
posters so the poster author did a very
great job and we invited the speakers
from uh the last chess sessions that
were online to present our paper as
posters so please go check them out
like