welcome for the third time to this
session on deep learning for Science and
Analysis it's my pleasure to introduce
our speaker Stephen from radbot
University and this is Joint work with
Guillermo perin and Lee Chao
sure
yeah okay hi everyone welcome to the
start of the session after lunch so I
will talk today about deep learning
assistant template attack and like
Ileana already said it's a it's a joint
work with Lee Chavo and guillerme piran
so what was the big idea of this work we
all know that hopefully we believe that
deep learning works well and it can help
us make attacks more powerful and break
targets more efficiently but still we
had kind of question okay but we do not
necessarily need to use deep learning
only to attack so we could use deep
learning Also let's say in a feature
engineering phase so to make our
selected features more powerful somehow
better and then use such features to
make the attack and then you could plug
in also some kind of simpler technique
and still hope for a good
performance yeah since there was already
a lot of talks I will skip the basics on
site Channel analysis and I will
immediately go into profiling side
Channel analysis and I will just mention
here
the attack consists of two phases
profiling phase and the attack phase in
profiling phase we learn things about
the leakage and we build the model
whether it's template or machine
learning model and we use that model to
break the target
and one option that is very very that's
a traditional how to do this attack and
yeah yesterday there was also award yeah
was it yesterday two days ago two days
ago there was a word for uh test of time
so 20 years template attack
is successfully breaking targets but in
let's say last couple of years people
move their attention from template
attack and went to
more powerful at least more fancier deep
learning things to do the attacks and
this is the Deep learning perspective
and what what is the point what's the
goal of everything when we are doing is
well we have measurements we have traces
and then either we say we take Road
traces or we service take some interval
but in the end
mostly at least with public available
targets there is only a couple of
leaking places and everything else is
somehow meant
to be disregarded and of course with
let's say template attack you want to
select your features so that you have as
good attack as possible with machine
learning so simple machine learning
attacks like seven years ago support
Vector machines random Forest you kind
of also try to do feature selection to
make the attack more powerful and then
we went to deep learning and said yeah
the advantage of deep learning is you do
not need to select features so you leave
everything for deep learning to do and
while I mean apparently this is good
scenario because we constantly report it
works the question is
is it always the best solution because
if we know something about what we are
trying to do it does make sense to
pre-process to do feature engineering to
do whatever to make the attack more
powerful I mean just think of it why
would I make life for my neural network
more difficult if I know something I can
use that knowledge to then plug in into
something and make the attack more
powerful so the question is how to
select relevant features
and of course since with many techniques
we needed to select features there are
many techniques how to do that so I
don't know based on correlation uh sosd
sosd chi-square
autoencoders more recently deep learning
approach uh so there is quite a lot of
options
but there is also one more recent option
that is based on the concept of
similarity learning and
what we call what is called triplet
networks and then triplet loss and so on
so on the concept is kind of simple
yes you can see the pointer okay barely
but hopefully you can see so what do we
want to do so here is the example AI
so that's called anchor then Pi be like
positive for example and end I plus one
or whatever n is negative example so the
point is what we could do is we could
try to make a system that minimizes the
distances intra class so whatever
belongs to let's say to a leakage will
somehow come closer to boost the effect
of leakage whatever does not come is not
part of the leakage will simply move
away so inter-class distance will
somehow increase and by doing that
intuitively you can think okay if
relevant things are grouped together
while irrelevant thing is discarded away
if you plug in the relevant things it
does make sense the attack could be more
powerful
so this is the whole concept how
triplet networks can work and like I
said there are three types of let's call
them labels positive anchor and negative
positive and could have the same label
while negative can be any label that is
not correct and that's why we call it
triplet Network there are three deep
learning networks each of them makes its
own embedding you fit all that into a
triplet loss function and what you're in
the end obtain is somehow embedded
we could call it oscillating space which
is compressed but contains the most
relevant information about the leakage
one could ask okay but what is it that
are those final embedding space what are
those leakages because we could do that
with other techniques
it is non-linear combination of leakages
so your triplet loss will build
something that is non-linear which is a
difference from many simpler techniques
like PCA that will build a linear
combination of features and one could
also say well out encoders will build
something that is non-linear true but
out encoders are non-supervised while
here we are in the supervised model so
we also use the information of labels so
in a way you can think to try to use all
the information you have so you are
building no linear representation where
also label gives you extra information
so yeah uh the example with two apples
and and one uh a negative of banana is
example of positive anchor negative
setup
and now some someone can ask okay but
how do you do the learning what does it
actually mean so basically you define
your anchor and you define the distance
up to the positive example
and then what is in that margin in that
uh euclidean distance space you can say
Well it belongs to intra class what is
outside of it it's
inter class difference so here you can
see where very easy example and this is
called easy positive easy negative why
well because the the distance from
anchor to positive is very small the
distance to negative is relatively large
and then for neural network it's easy to
say yeah this is the same this is
different
you can also have a different example
where negative example is as close or
even closer than positive example and
this is called hard negatives or hard
triplets and this when you have is make
your algorithm uh
struggle a lot to to converge to learn
because the distance to negative example
to what you want to avoid can be smaller
than the distance to the positive
example what you want to take
so there is something in the between and
this is called semi heart which is
basically telling you that
there is
the distance till the till this kind of
example is larger than to the easy
example but it's smaller than to make to
negative examples that are easy and here
you govern how far do you do this
differentiation by adding a parameter
called margin so the bigger the margin
the bigger is your centroid the bigger
centroid your approach becomes easier to
to do classification but it's also more
difficult to recognize the differences
between examples
of course uh you could make
something more because a side channel
will offer you a bit more information
that we maybe don't have in some other
domains well triplet networks are
commonly used like
NLP so natural language processing why
because think of the example
you want to say what name is more
distant from some other name Alice Bob
Eve
it's very hard to say if Ali's name is
closer to Bob or it's closer to Eve
objectively of course we can say
whatever we want what's closer what's
further but inside Channel we have the
the nice side that when we talk about
labels depending on the leakage model
some things are closer than some other
things just consider the Hemingway
leakage model and there the the
consumption is proportional to the
Heming rate so one would say well to
Heming rate one Hemingway two is closer
than Hemingway seven so you you we can
use that extra information about the
labels to build what we actually called
hybrid distance
and this is represented here with uh
with uh with this formula
okay so how does the whole attack work
well you have your measurements your
leakage traces you put them in triplet
Network you obtain different embeddings
from those embeddings you plug those
embeddings as input to your attack
so in a way it's very simple and attack
in general can be whatever you want and
this is let's say pre-processing phase
so uh the experiment wise we did on
yeah different neural networks different
data sets so common suspects ask at
fixed key ask at variable key aeshd data
set Hemingway Heming distance ideal
leakage models for neural networks
we did quite a lot of experiments
very small neural networks work fine
which is always nice easy to tune you
also don't need to tune them a lot and
for the attack itself we used template
attack okay so we wanted to say if if we
do nice pre-processing
and then if you plug in template attack
can that compare with state-of-the-art
deep learning attacks direct ones
so result wise here you can see a bunch
of numbers for different data sets uh
yeah uh mostly we were quite happy with
the results because for for most of the
scenarios you can see that template
attack actually managed to get good
performance of course there are cases
where other works actually don't know
which one is this worked better
but all in all the numbers looked very
nice so template did manage to to use
the information from embedded space to
to break the targets more efficiently
than I don't know methodology paper or
so and so on
and one could also ask yes but what
happens when you add more noise the
synchronization to data set whatever so
we we tested also between that here the
comparison was a bit more difficult
because of course not every prior work
had all the setups that we wanted to
consider but what we did see is that the
same triplet Network used before for
embedding still works very nicely for
new attack when you also add some kind
of desynchronization or something
and of course
one could ask why did you use the loss
function that we used and because there
are many loss functions and these are
not the classical loss functions like
categorical cross entropy or whatever we
know from before there are specific loss
functions just for similarity learning
so
those are also a bunch of those we also
tested
most common examples like contrastive
loss lift structure uh pinball hard semi
hard and so on so on but the one the
hybrid one actually worked very nicely
because it included information about
the labels and there are many hyper
parameters extra ones to consider so if
you remember our loss function from here
we needed to
add new parameter Alpha so what happens
when you add Alpha how how difficult is
to to tweak that hyper parameter and
how how important is the embedding size
how important how long do you need to
train how big training set needs to be
and so on so on so classical questions
so some kind of of study on the
influence of parameters hyper parameters
the most important message so there are
different graphs showing here so loss
function you can so Alpha hyper
parameter you can see
small values are rather stable
embedding size this is in my opinion the
most interesting one you can see that
the small embedded size work very nicely
and why is this interesting well if you
have small embedding size that means
your covariance matrices with template
will also not have strong requirements
which will allow you in many many
situations to build your template
attacks so you will not get singular
singular Matrix and so on so on
triplet margin so how big is the
difference between a positive negative
again we found this to be quite
reasonably easy to tweak so whatever we
tried unless we tried very stupid values
worked good
and also very interesting thing
to to train something like this you need
very little time so
a couple of epochs is enough to train
uh your model to do embedding extraction
and training size again
reasonable training sizes work stable so
unless you really feed extremely small
set that is not enough to generalize you
will get good results if you feed a big
data set of course it works nice but it
takes more time and so on so on and to
conclude
is well
it seems cool because indeed we can be
found that you can
make embedding that works for template
attack which was not clear at the
beginning can you really combine
features in such a non-linear way that
they will still make sense for for
template attack to use
and in a way with minimal computation
efforts we we were quite lucky to see
that we do match state-of-the-art deep
learning attacks so really attack that
attacks on the raw features which is
also telling us that this non-linear
embeddings do contain a lot more
information than just judging by the not
by the size of embedding because for
instance size of embedding was 30 40 50.
so very small when you compare it with
raw features of thousands or to 700 for
us get fixed and so on so on
uh yeah the the evaluation of critical
hyper parameters showed stability which
is always nice because even if you have
good solution but becomes very difficult
to tweak very difficult to reproduce the
results then it's always problematic so
we found at least on the data sets we
tested to be very easy to to tune the
hyper parameters that being said yeah
paper is everywhere uh available on
chess page there is on our git you can
find the code
uh who was at the tutorial Sunday I also
gave the quote for this I believe uh
some people tried it already they told
me it works even works so that's nice
the and that being said yeah uh quick if
you have any questions I will do my best
to answer
I think we have a question there I will
give you my microphone
hello hi thanks for the talk uh I just
wanted to ask if you can comment a bit
more on the difference between LDA and
your method for selecting features
because LDA is also minimizing the intra
class difference and maximizing the
inter-class device yes so that's
precisely what you're algorithm is doing
as far as I understood yes but it's yeah
it's in the way how to to do it so with
uh with LDA
I mean l in in ldm means linear so you
do it in a linear fashion here
you do it in non-linear fashion and we
assume anything that can be approximated
with with a neural network function and
then from the universal approximation
theorem is seven we could approximate in
theory whatever we want so you can build
extremely complicated function that Maps
your original features into embedded
space and even more than that you use
the information about the label because
one could say out encoder also does the
non-linear part but once you add the
information about the label you can
actually really tweak the differences
like I said Heming rate
2 and Hemingway 3 are potentially more
similar than Hemingway zero and
Hemingway eight at least from the from
the Hemingway leakage model from the
consumption proportional leakage so once
you the more information you add
potentially the better attack you can
have and since its profiling attack and
we always say well in profiling phase we
know whatever we want to know there is
no reason why not to use that kind of
information so LDA is always a good
choice it's much simpler to do than than
this thing but the way how you embed the
space it's very much different
so what sort of extra information you
can add for example to your method done
to LD this is the part that is not very
clear to me oh
but I mean uh
LTA will build you a linear
combination of features yeah so I don't
know feature one plus feature two or
whatever here
it can be whatever you want so uh the
non-linear combination of features for
instance in a way can also com be
combination of a mask already with with
the intermediate value so already the
the embedding can have the must part
I'm not saying that that this of course
happens but you give the opportunity for
neural network to allow that so you can
already have the data set unmasked
and let's say aligned even before you
start with the attack part
so you have time for a short question
and a short answer okay I will try uh
then let's keep this question short
um you analyze the influence of
different hyper parameter choices yes
how did you optimize the hyper
parameters was this done manually or did
you use some Optimizer here we did it
manually so because
some of these hyper parameters for more
side Channel Side you know like training
set size this is something that one
commonly plays manually and from the
deep learning side you had the parameter
hyper parameter Alpha which we said well
let's just do a grid search you know
zero one zero two zero three and then
when we are somewhere interesting then
let's try values between zero one and
zero two and things like that and
embedding size we also uh well embedding
size was actually quite easy because for
instance Ascot fix key has 700 features
it does not in the in the interval it
does not make sense to say well I have
my small latent space that is 699
features then I can just plug in the
original one so we said it makes sense
to start for smaller and then see how it
progresses so we started with extremely
small embedding space and at the moment
when the results started to go verse
will set we will stop here of course it
does not mean that
going for some strange numbers somewhere
else would not work but we also want to
help our template attack to to be as
efficient as possible and for that
having less features is good otherwise
we can have problems with with
covariance
yeah did you try going back to uh yeah
did I try what embedding size one did
you try that one
yes yes we tried that I don't think it's
in the paper because that did not work
well as far as I remember but this would
be definitely for offline because I
would need to check
thanks Dearborn again
our next speaker is online
yes I'm principal online
hey uh do you want to give the
presentation through Zoom or should we
just play the video
I think it just plays a video it's a bit
safer in terms of connection quality
okay
so the topic of my talk today is braking
Mast implementations of Clyde by means
of site Channel analysis and this is
Joint work with Friedrich alaus and
Donna Schindler
um to give you a short outline of my
talk I will first give a brief
introduction to side Channel analysis
and I will talk about the chess
challenge 2020 which was a power
analysis task I will describe a
blueprint of a solution
um that outlines these the main steps
that we take to to solve the chess
challenge 2020 software challenges I
will discuss some minor and some major
problems that we had to overcome and the
most significant problems that we had to
overcome was a convergence problem with
the Deep learning model that we use to
break this chess challenge 2020.
and um
this we invented a trick called the
scatter shot encoding that helps us
resolve this convergence problem
and in the end I will first Analyze This
by using the scatter shot encoding on a
synthetic problem
and we will
supply a comparison to this to of our
results to results obtained using the
stochastic approach when used on the
same task of the chess challenge 2020.
so
mathematical crypto analysis tends to be
difficult for unbeaconed versions of
modern ciphers so it's much easier to
break the implementation one way to do
this is by side Channel attacks this
means using physical side effects of
computation to gain additional
information
and about the secret that is being
processed by an implementation and a
site Channel attacks are a very
practical threat when the adversary can
do the required measurements and
physical side effects of computation
might be things like power usage or
electromagnetic emanations or acoustic
imaginations
can we do anything about it yes we can
do things about it we can try to in in
various ways we can try to make it
impossible for the adversary to try to
either perform the measurements uh on
the physical side effects of computation
that they want to exploit or to exploit
the
um to to get useful measurements
and one of surveys we can prevent the
adversary from getting the from from
retrieving information about our secrets
from the measurements that they can make
is to employ masking and
um masking has a fairly good theoretical
justification but tends to also be
relatively expensive therefore there's
interest in creating masking friendly
ciphers and the Clyde Cipher this was
which was the object of the chess 2020
challenge is one of those masking
friendly ciphers
so to give you a basic idea about
masking
um usually a side Channel adversary will
have to use multiple traces multiple
measurements in order to extract
enough information about the secret that
they want to extract to gain a
significant advantage
and the idea here is that the secret
that is being processed by a
cryptographic implementation remains
constant across across executions
and the only thing that changes is the
data that is the other data that is
being processed by the implementation
and the noise that's the implementation
generates and therefore the secret might
generate a
consistent signals at the adversary can
try to exploit to extract that signal
that secret and the basic idea of
masking is to
structure the implementation in such a
way that this assumption that the secret
remains and remains constant across
implementations across
executions is from so we break up the
secret key and the data into shares in a
SQL sharing scheme one runs the
execution
of The Primitives that one is trying to
run on these shares instead of on the
original data so one has to rewrite the
um the um for instance the encryption
operation
if it is if if The Primitives that we
are trying to protect and encrypts
something and we refresh the shares
across executions or even within one
execution of the scheme and in this way
um we prevent the adversary from seeing
the same
um the same sensitive values when they
observe different executions of our
primitive
so in the chess challenge 2020 we had to
break mask implementations of the
masking friendly Clyde Cipher the power
analysis
Clyde is a tweakable lightweight block
Cipher with a 128 bit block key and
tweak size there were seven different
targets for software and three Hardware
targets all of them were masked
implementations the software targets had
three four six and eight-fold masking
only the software targets were solved
and the power traces for the software
targets were captured at fairly high
resolution
on the order of several tens of
thousands of data points per Trace
the power traces included roughly the
first round of the cipher but excluded
the randomness generation and hence we
had to treat the randomness used for
share generation and refreshment as
completely unpredictable
um breaking a challenge meant achieving
a mean key rank smaller than 2 to the 32
using a number of traces chosen by the
team that was claiming a break the goal
of the contest was to break as many
challenges as possible with as few
traces as possible and it turns out that
our team was the only group to submit a
solution to any of the challenges within
the contest
um
it's a
it's a organizers of the contest
provided 200 000 power traces together
with the secret key secret key shares
tweak values and plain text values for
each challenge for training Solutions in
addition they provided a python
implementation of the mass Clyde logic
um they also provided test data that
with fixed keys so that uh so that
um and so that competitors could test
their Solutions against up to 100 000
traces with a fixed key for each Target
and entries were evaluated against a
data set kept secret by the organizer's
key ranking was done by standard
histogram based methods
so Clyde acts on blocks of 128 bits
which are arranged as four times 32-bit
arrays it runs six rounds of encryption
each round being composed of a three key
addition and Xbox layer an lbox layer
and the addition of a constant another
Tweaky addition happens in the at the
end of the cipher the three key schedule
is fairly simple and on the whole the
cipher is implementable with a fairly
small number of gates which
which contributes to its being masking
friendly
so our solution uses deep neural
networks and all of our code and data
can be downloaded from GitHub
so we wanted to achieve the following we
wanted to first of all if possible win
the contest by having the most efficient
attacks we wanted to use a fairly highly
Auto automated attacks so we tried to
avoid too much manual tuning with
regards to hyper parameters point of
Interest selection or leakage Target
selection and we wanted to break all the
software challenges using the same
methods
and basically what we do is we get
predictions for the shared Cipher state
for all of the bits of the shared Cipher
State at some particular point of
execution then we derive I guess for the
unshared state which of course comes
with an increase in uncertainty of our
predictions as we have to predict as we
have to combine predictions for
different shares to get a prediction for
the unfair state
see unshared State then only depends on
the Clyde logic and the inputs and not
on the masking anymore which means that
for each key hypothesis we can calculate
the unshared cipher State given all the
inputs to Clyde and compare compare the
results of that calculation to the
results of the side Channel extraction
and that allows us to Output a ranking
of the keys and in the end it allows us
to Output a ranking of the keys where
the target key is among the first 2 to
the 32
um
keys in in this ranking as desired
so how did we pick the leakage Target we
just Target the state after the first s
box
then how do we avoid a large search cost
when ranking key hypotheses well giving
the leakage Target we can rank key
hypotheses vulnerable at a time so we
have only 16 hypotheses per nibble and
how do we process large traces without
manual point of Interest selections we
reuse a neural network structure
introduced at SEC 2020 by Gore Jakob and
Schindler which was designed to handle
large traces directly and the main ideas
behind the networks
are to deal with large trade sizes by
sub sampling the traces with varying
offsets and then combining the
predictions made for the the sub-sampled
sub traces
and um
yeah we've just reused that Network
structure
when we try to implement this however we
saw that our networks converge well for
many bits of the shared state but failed
completely for others and of course if
we failed completely for to converge for
um one for for some bit of the shared
State we will not see the um we will not
see one
the corresponding bit of the unshared
state and if that happens then
since we don't see any bias for that bit
more data is not going to help us
resolve the problem so we had to we had
to solve this convergence problem in
order to um in order to get predictions
that uh get us to the desired key rank
so the problem
that we saw was that when predicting the
internal Cipher state naively so one bit
at a time then all predicted bits are
close to independent of each other which
means that we can make progress on
learning to predict some bits while not
learning how to predict the others and
in order to solve this we invented a
trick that we call the Scatterfield
encoding which is an alternative
encoding of the data that we want to
predict namely we pick random subsets of
the target bits and predict instead of
the target bits themselves the Hamming
weights of these random subsets of
Target bits and if you have noisy
predictions of these Hamming dates then
we can obtain noisy predictions of all
the target bits by some linear algebra
post-processing that we do
and all of these sub problems that we
that we construct all of these
predictions of these hemming weights are
strongly related to each other because
these uh these subsets of the target
bits are not disjoint with each other so
they they share a lot of bit bit
positions and
therefore one would hope that
convergence across the subtask should be
more uniform than than it is in the case
when we naively try to predict the
target bits themselves and this is
indeed true so here we see the
performance of our solutions to the age
here challenge which is the hardest one
of the software challenges and we see
that with about 35 000 traces we get um
we get below a median key rank below
that uh below the target of 2 to the 32.
so our solution Works quite efficiently
for the three share Challenge and um but
we see that the that the number of of
traces that we need to get to be below
that key rank uh it it does rise fairly
fairly quickly but we managed to solve
all of the software challenges
um after the challenge was closed
another solution was published by
Bronson and stand there and that
solution is based on deep belief
networks and their solution is more
efficient than ours for the six and
eight share challenges but comparable
for the four share Challenge and less
efficient for the three three share
challenge
so to analyze our technique further we
we looked at the scatter shot encoding
in more detail because the scatter shot
encoding is a slightly counter-intuitive
trick because it basically just
multiplies the values we would like to
predict by a fixed random binary Matrix
before running training and one one does
one devices helps and to answer this or
to get more insight into this we
designed a simple synthetic problem
namely learning to predict a particular
F2 linear function that is that has a
very simple structure it basically just
outputs an F2 linear combination of its
input bits so there is no noise no
Randomness and the function to predict
is quite simple but it has this function
has components that are a bit wise
edition of many of the input bits and
those components are quite difficult to
learn for a neural network and looking
at the performance of neural networks
that we tried at learning to predict
this function we see that the naive
approach and the scatter shot approach
show qualitatively similar behavior on
this simple synthetic problem as on our
side Channel Challenge and so to
illustrate this here is the learning
history for the um for the on on the
synthetic problem for the naive
prediction of all of the bits by a
neural network so we see that the neural
network repeatedly gets stuck and in the
end it fails on the on a few of the
hardest bits it fails to see any bias
whereas with the scatter shot encoding
we get a fairly smooth learning history
and also we um we do obtain some degree
of convergence even for the hardest bits
so we see at least some bias even for
the hardest bits here
we also compared our results with
results that one can obtain by applying
the stochastic approach to the uh to the
to the chess challenge 2020 which
required adapting the stochastic
approach to dealing with secret shared
Keys accounting for the high number of
masking bits becomes quickly intractable
even for the three share challenge
both the scatter shot encoding and the
stochastic approach see large biases in
the same OS boxes however so we see um
we we see a Sim leakage of a similar
nature with both approaches and we found
that our neural networks draw in
information from some parts of the
recorded traces that are surprising and
therefore missed by the manual point of
interest and Analysis done for the
stochastic approach and overall the
neural network based solution
significantly outperforms the stochastic
approach here
it's a deep learning approach finds more
unanticipated features and therefore
yields better better results on this
problem however the features exploited
by the stochastic approach are human
comprehensible by Design which is an
advantage so in conclusion we can break
implementations with a significant
degree of protection
using neural networks without a need for
deep analysis of the implementation by
an analyst however masking Works in
principle because we see that the um
that the number of traces required for a
successful attack Rises quickly with
masking order and study of simple
synthetic problems can be quite
insightful for deep learning based
General analysis as we have seen with
our synthetic task
and I think for future work it would be
quite desirable to gain a deeper
understanding of the scatter shot
encoding and
um versus and to see whether there are
other similar tricks and since the
scatter shop encoding could also be seen
as an advanced loss function it would be
interesting to see whether one can learn
Advanced loss functions for side Channel
analysis and this concludes my talk
thank you for your attention
thank you I think Aaron is also online
are there any questions from the
audience yes
uh
uh hi do you hear me okay I can hear you
I uh it's uh Olivia so that you know
whisping uh so thank you very much for
the token for the paper and for
contributing to the the chess CTF
um I think one key ingredient of your
attack is knowing the values of the
shares when running the attack
which is usually not done
um by the the rest I mean a larger
majority of the rest of the community
especially in the Deep learning area so
could you like comment on that and do
you think that you could have succeeded
with such a and impressive success
without knowing the randomness used
I I think I think knowing the randomness
used was essential for for what we did
yes I mean we we
um we use the um the supplied uh flight
logic um so it's a mask light logic and
so and the um the the known values of
the randomness to derive those internal
uh to derive those um internal share
values uh during training and um without
modification of the of the methods uh I
don't think that we would have been able
to get a model that performs that well
just if we had just known if we had just
known the the unshared keys and see
um and and the algorithm itself then I
don't think this is the most methods
that we used that we could have uh
obtained that result yeah and I'm
feeling like as the BSI you are in a
position like say saying is it relevant
or not to know the randomness when you
analyze a cipher so personally I think I
think it makes sense to um to
look at
um
an attack an adversary model that is uh
that is strong enough to well that is um
personally I think it makes sense to
look at powerful adversary models um
because
um
I mean the the algorithm is supposed
certainly supposed to be known by by any
by the adversary by kirchhoff's
principle and
um
I think in terms of
in terms of evaluating
um the
worst case that one can I mean the the
worst case that one has to deal with
when ensuring that a particular
implementation is secure it does make
sense in my opinion to
looking at an adversary who can be
assumed to have weakened the
implementation in such a way that he can
that for training purposes he can see
the randomness
um but I I think it it also makes it it
also makes perfect sense to look at Vita
adversary models and and to to see
um how much one loses
um if one
um moves to a weaker adversary model
we have one more question it's going to
be short and if possible the answer also
short yeah sure uh hello sorry so you
mentioned uh hi this is Marius uh you
mentioned the use of stochastic models
with a manual selection of points of
interest but there is also a method that
we shown on how to combine stochastic uh
models with LDA and PCA did you try that
so automatic selection via projection of
lempc with stochastic models
um we
we did it
um
we did a we did a we did have more or
less a semi automatic approach to the to
the point of Interest selection
um but I'm
I'm not quite sure I would have to talk
to I would have to talk to my
collaborators what exactly we did
um what what exactly
um which approaches we exactly used to
do the point of Interest selection for
the stochastic approach as I mostly
dealt with the neural network side of
things
thank you very much for this answer and
let's thank the speaker
foreign
who came all the way from Japan yeah
so
um
you have the floor yeah
thank you for the introduction I'm
living with University Japan today I'm
talking about Singapore Singletary
attack on artificiality this is the
collaborative work with
tried to distinguish squaring and
multiplication during the modular
exponentiation because the secret
experimented the directory represent the
secretary of the RSA signing over
decryption
uh
is very important to be because a public
key cryptography is not necessarily
perform the other frequently Primitives
artificiality has been also studied for
a long time so this attack estimates
that secret key
secretary from partial information of
the secretary
this is so attack estimates
security key by discarding the wrong
secretary contradicting the statistical
leakage within like this
and by such a binary three manner
obtained by the attacker is not always
corrected or correct
and actually this talk is about deep
learning about social and Ducks uh let
me omit to introduce drsca because
previous talks likely introduce the
grsga
and what I'd like to say here is the
deer is very strong theory for Ortho for
the fgf but we we should still consider
what to run by the year for efficient
key recovery
in my opinion for symmetric key
cryptography it will be a very
established because many existing beers
focuses on the conditional probability
distribution of the Xbox output uh
and its optimality is well uh either
Analytical in some studies
on the other hand foreign
dependent on the algorithm itself
so today uh we talk about the
essential new deep learning basis or
cycle attack or artificiality so with
reality is how to estimate the figure at
this point from digital traits and the
new partial key exposure attack
major
implementation is
in the many open source libraries so why
the existing drfcs or rsf were discrete
longer revenue for targets binary
exponentiation
using actual implementation using the
GMP this is the major March prevention
library and this is a frequently used in
the cryptographic operation
and we also confirmed the availability
of The Proposal attack to some related
to cryptographic libraries including
open SSR bota and revision Crypt
okay let me start from RS encrypted
systems so I so I know uh credit
Graphics has seen this other formula so
very very frequently and forty thought
yes so you are interested in how to
implement these formulas Security on the
exchange
so let's focus on open source RC
implementation because such an
implementations uh have a very high
performance and very practical because
this is implemented by expat of the
cryptographic implementation
is usually useful for the RSA
description of signing because it can
release the computational cost by factor
of two to four without almost no
overhead
uh in implementing RFA the explanation
algorithm is very important which mainly
determines the security and efficiency
so this table summarizes the
exponentiation major exponentiation
algorithms for implementing RSA as a
decent classified to two types of the
binary exponentiation and the windowed
expression so actually many open source
libraries uses
we know the explanation thanks to its
high performance and some levels of
resistance to the financial simpler
analysis
so I introduced a fixed window
exponentiation so this is the fastest
constant time exponentiation to the rest
of my direct so let WD of the window
side as a parameter so solving the
explanations of that two stages of
pre-computation and Main Loop in
pre-computation we make precomposition
table which contains two to the power of
w elements and in the iso address of the
table it stores uh sheet to the power
right yes C is the base
and now for all following the main Loop
uh
we perform scouting double times and
then powerful multiplication with the
pre-computation template value uh
according to the temporary window
barrier and we repeat this procedure so
this figure shows the example of a
strong window exponentiation we still
will be the exponent and the double
because uh explain the detail of it so
we have a three four bit temporary
window body because double equal four
and after the pre-computation we perform
scaling the scarring scaling scoring and
then perform multiplication is a free
computational table value yeah the
temporal window value is the 1101 we
perform the multiplication with this G
to the power of 1 1 0 1 so starting
so we repeated this procedure until the
end of the exponent bit
now how about the security of a
statistical security of this
exponentiation the in fact this is
secure against the simplified analysis
because squaring multiplication sequence
is independent of the secret experience
however they are the other possibility
of the leakage on the temporary window
value in fact the attacker can make
about the temporary window barrier
immediately have the secret key because
temporary in the body directly
represents the secret experience
analysis
so uh because the multiplication operand
they draw it from the temporal window uh
sorry uh in order to from a
pre-computation table so which the
Consular leakage and the security of the
operand routing
in fact uh many open source libraries
the employee dummy Road or other counter
measure to hide the temporary window
body so this figure shows the operand
loading uh listening GMP uh the main
idea of this implementation is the old
operands are accessible in every
multiplication even if it is not
actually use the photographation and
this algorithm shows the mask value to
determine uh two uh to the road and this
right figures of equivalent to represent
such representation of this algorithm so
these are the facts operates with two to
the power of w iterations
this intermediate resistor is stores the
pre-composition table valued auditory of
ice address
so otherwise if the foreign discarded
such a combination of the window the
exponentiation and the terminal the
related to be sufficient to protect
again against the motor timing attack or
remote cache data but we are talking
about the power volume social attacks on
such an implementation today so in fact
uh Library developers does not always
consider such a physical Sagittarius but
such an open implementation first choice
if you would like to implement RFA or
embed devices due to its high
performance maturity or high prevalence
so uh very similar to the profile data
includes the development of the new
techniques for data sets
summarizes that proposed the methodology
so the proponent focusing on the first
fact that the operand rolling concept of
the only one three Road and all the
remaining load are dummy Road
so this factor is the two important
points for the social attacker so the
first point is the value of the list is
changed only when the Three Rod but this
makes the difference in the financial
Territory between the three and dummy
road which can be exploited by the
attacker
then
the second point is more important so
although
fully depends on the temporary window
body and actually interior and the
mirror sequence represent the temporal
window body of the wild code
dependent on this value so namely the
the temporary window bar is the 1101 so
I mean 13. so 13 is loading the battery
load and the remaining order is the
tummy road so I'd like to say the
distinguishing the true and dummy road
is sufficient for recording a secret
experience and secret key
and uh so so let's consider how to ex
how to distinguish between dummy rules
so we use uh DNA dsga for this purpose
so we employ two classification neural
network to distinguished through and
dummy road so proposal is the profile
data containing the training and attack
queries in training phase we train on
neural network using uh
the in and these figures of the overview
of the attack phase so in turning phase
we uh trained the neutral neural network
to imitate uh conditional probability
distribution of the reload a given 500
Trace so to determine the three load we
perform uh two to the power with W2
classifications to distinguish to
another mirror in estimating one
temporary window body
and we estimate load operation with
highest probability of the three load uh
because it is most likely one
this is simply done by taking org box of
the origin outputs for these inferences
what is the important here is that any
inference is released to classification
from to the power of w classification
so such a two classification is the
first simple task than two
multi-graphical Transportation so this
is the
Improvement the reaction of the learning
cost and finally uh efficient attack
so we also propose a new password key
exposure attack but let me omit the
detail explanation of this the detail of
this algorithm due to the time
constraint
uh however the proposal key idea of The
Proposal attack is we perform that this
uh
in the WB assuming that the wb1 while
the existing attack is
uniformly distributed
foreign
hmm
and uh are we demonstrates a
experimental attacks on uh 10 24 bit
artificialt implementation with uh GMP
uh here uh 10 020 artificiality
implementation meet so we require
128 times two temporary window body
estimation for double equal to four so
double equal four is the the determined
by the GMP of the optical parameter in
this case
uh we used to almost 60 million in
electronics for the training and this
figure should I iterated for today and
dummy Road all right please note that
it's quite difficult at least for me to
distinguish 300 from these types of
geratoices and we use the convolutionary
CNN for our experiment
and this table shows the other dessert
so we evaluated the testified accuracy
using 24 different secret keys I mean we
performed the estimation of 48 exponents
48 times 700 128 bit temporary window by
estimation and
48 times 128 times 63 and damilola
distinguish
99 percent and uh
uh
you know Network also can achieve the
exponentary companies 80 percent to
accuracy because this is the success
rate of the other attack is the almost
80 percent even without particular
attack
uh really also perform the temperature
attack and treated the power of w
classification in here for a comparison
at the temperature the major existing
method and the multiples concentration
is the straightforward extension with
the existing new dnsta
after that we cannot achieve very high
accuracy for using them and they are
interesting for the key recovery even
using the partial key exposure attack
during the exponentiation
and finally we average accelerator with
the overall success rate using partial
key exposure attack so we generated to
100 random artists she she artificialt
secret keys with wide errors to simulate
errors increditing the ourca
this figure shows the result the
horizontal axis is the number of the
errors and particles axis is a
computational cost
so we confirmed the proposal attraction
with 100 substrate within a few
thousands of seconds it's very
practically feasible rate
so we confirmed the feasibility and
effectiveness of the proposed attack
so this result does not mean our attack
is superior to the Head titled attack
and the actually means our attack is
very calibrated to our drfca
okay it's closing uh that's close in my
talk we developed a new dsga on
applicability without a crtrc
implementations in our paper we propose
the contamination against propose the
attack please see a paper for detail
uh finally uh we'd like to say that
offer stronger attacks
implementations but if we implementation
details are available so we can achieve
a stronger attack a doctor thank you for
your attention
uh thank you
that's good
uh okay sorry thank you for the talk uh
you said that the integration algorithm
was not applicable can you elaborate a
bit on this uh you said that the inigir
shasham algorithm was not applicable for
the Q reconstruction can you elaborate a
bit on this or
sorry uh
speak literally because I found it not
very clearly I think sorry ah please
speak slowly because the fund is not
very clear
maybe we can take this offline after I'm
not sure I understand what
in English
I'm not sure
as well
so the first one yeah you said that the
it's not applicable for you I know yeah
so so uh why uh
the difference of the leakage model so
we can uh estimate the Secretary of a
complete secretary
Erasure but contains the trips so this
is the this indicate model is not
covered by heading attack
okay thank you
yeah I I'm under the impression that you
didn't make it very clear how many
traces you need per key
sorry about it how many traces you need
per key
how many traces you need I'm having
tries yes
only one tourist for the attack
so this is a Singletary attack
is the data set publicly available
your data set is it available
sorry your data set is it available I
have already publishing uh sorry
um thank you very much for a very nice
presentation what was the target uh
what did you run it on the the
experiments
uh
was it was it running on like bare metal
I assume okay
thank you
okay
um
the flight uh
we talk
and it's my pleasure to introduce our
next speaker guillerme perine
and in the meantime I want to thank you
as the audience for having a lot of
questions and having interesting
discussion makes my life as the session
chair very easy
so hi everyone
good afternoon so um I will talk about
today some about a very specific uh open
problem in deep learning basic sidechain
analysis that is feature selection that
we believe it's not really well covered
in the recent research
so uh the context of this work is
profile inside Channel analysis like it
was we saw many presentations before
already describing this context so I
will skip this part
um so we had many assumptions for this
work and the first one is about the
different it's about assumptions on the
attack itself like we have a white on
the extreme sides we have white box
profiling analysis we have black box
profiling attacks and uh although uh
what was the worst case security
evaluation is possible with a white box
profiling attacks on the on the black
box side this is not really possible and
then this how you differentiate both
types of evaluations is on the
assumptions and the knowledge that the
attacker is considered at the attacker
possessed so for example for the white
box analysis you have knowledge on the
randomness for example the masks and
also the source code the of the
implementation while in the Black Box
scenario you don't assume any previous
knowledge about a Target basically what
is public available only so white box
profiling attacks are fast and efficient
in order to uh describe the security of
the implementation and black box attacks
are more difficult to implement and
subject to many mistakes for many
different reasons and this is also
related to the profiling model
reliability so as an example you would
do it for example you choose deeper
neural networks to do a profiling attack
but if you get better results in these
things that you don't or good results
depending on the perspective if you
don't break the target then you need to
understand if the target is really
secure or if the profiling attack is
wrong
so there is this gap between these two
uh scenarios and one thing that we ask
ourselves is uh if we apply deep
learning attacks which provides in
practice very good results how the IP
parameter search effort actually covers
uh this Gap can not make of course white
box and black box equal in performance
but reduces the gap between those two
approaches
and obviously on the white box scenario
we have feature selection and on the
Black Box scenario we don't have feature
selection IDs
so the second motivation is about the
model size so
um to define the neural network you want
to implement so it's becoming more and
more large the options for for
describing to implement the attack and
when we go for for example small models
and usually this is the this is selected
based on small data sets as well so
small models uh they have their own
benefits for example they are implicitly
regularized so they are less prone to
overheating but they are more efficient
on the small uh data sets and I would
like to refer to this very nice work
from vouchers from 2020 which this puts
a very nice perspective on how what is
the capacity of small models against
several data sets
so also small models together with
optimization methods deliver also very
good results so next year's we saw
papers uh or in the recent years we saw
papers using hyper parameter search
together with the small neural networks
and they were able to get even better
results also on small data sets not
really large scale data sets
and finally we saw Publications for
example last year a paper appear shown
uh showing very large data sets wrote
measurements on some devices ending
consider a very long very big neural
networks for that so the attacks were
crazy efficient very few traces like
zero one to ten traces for some data
sets were enough to break the Target on
applying them on the road trade so it's
quite impressive to see but the the
models are very very large so this also
puts a question like is it necessary to
improve the model size if we improve
this the scale of the data set
so feature selection basically uh
yeah so we need to select in the main
points of interest in our attack so if
we can if we go for the more black box
evaluations but we also select small
intervals which is also done mostly in
the recent Works uh we don't see that
even a small neural network we struggle
so much in finding the second order
leakages and first order musket
implementation for example because we're
going to have several points of interest
leak information and then to
differentiate between what is noise what
is leakage doesn't become a very
difficult task and for people that
practice on this topic it we see that
it's not really difficult to find the
efficient neural network against data
public available data sets
on the other hand if we do uh if we
apply if we take a much longer interval
where the location of the points of
interest is related to our intermediate
variable are more cons are concentrated
in almost very specific points of
interest then we see a situation when
the neural network needs to uh find
these points of interest and discard the
rest of the uh of the trace so if the
leakage is located in some specific
points then we start to question
ourselves if small models are enough or
not for uh for the task and also if we
ideally here or intuitively we would go
for more for larger data sets because
this would provide more capacity but on
the other hand larger data sets a new
networks sorry they are they are they
can easily over fit depending on the
size of the data set and in terms of
number of measurements and therefore you
have another problem a problem to solve
so one way to to defeat the Regal of
your fitting obviously is regularizing
the model in a way that you reduce its
capacity either by reducing its size or
by applying some explicit regularization
techniques like for example Dropout or
uh l102 early stop in debt augmentation
and so what we wanted to do the model to
do using the regularization is to make
it more insensitive to noise or all the
relevant features contained in the trace
and make it more uh
looking only to the relevant ones that
appear in the in the measurements
so in reality feature selection either
in academic or in Industry are done they
are done in different ways so
if we considered all the Publications
that we have recently uh in the previous
works
we see that feature selection is usually
take into account because we usually
attack data sets that are already
optimized for in terms of interval of
selection so I can give an example of
ascad data set that is massively used in
our previous works and we attack a very
specific interval which already is
selected based on the knowledge of some
of the randomness
uh but there is a reason for that it's
because we are more interested in the
method itself of the attack and not
really on this practicality of the
attack so we invest more time on the
optimization algorithms metrics loss
functions Etc rather than the Practical
aspects and for industry or real world
targets uh I can say that this
pre-processing part of feature selection
will never be ignored because it's not
smart just to take a row measurement and
throw away into a neural network so
usually we're going to do some
pre-processing steps because it's it's
intuitive to do them
and pre-processing can be difficult
sometimes and so uh you can trim as much
as you can you can optimize as much as
you can but there is a point where you
cannot do it anymore and then this is
why deep neural networks also became
more popular in the domain because they
are assuming to bypass uh the problems
of feature selection and but to what
extent this is really true we don't know
exactly but then we started to
investigate in this work a bit more with
more experiments
so for that we defined the three uh the
scenarios the first one is similar to
white box evaluations where we select
points of interest based on leakage
assessment and masks are known for that
so the second scenario is optimized
points of interest which which you're
going to see it's similar to previous
works so we use a
yeah so masks are known for the
selection of the intervals or for the
feature selection on the second case but
there is one data set that we use that
we don't have access to the masks and
still we were able to define the
intervals for the the data set
and finally the most interesting
scenario which is completely back black
box where we don't know the masks and we
attack all available features or
intervals where the attack should be
obvious discarding some of the parts
that are Irrelevant for example we
attack the first round of the s-box and
then we simply discard the rest of the
Xbox rounds
so feature selection what we usually do
is when we have
a different data sets to attack we go
for different hyper parameter tuning
strategies and also depending on feature
selection we also go for different hyper
parameter tuning strategies but in this
paper what we do is to see how the same
parameter tuning strategy the same
configuration the same range can be
applied among uh for multiple scenarios
and multiple scenarios I mean different
data sets leakage models model types I
mean convolutional neural networks
multi-layer perception and feature
selection scenarios and for each case we
we search it for up to 500 models and
except for the first scenario where we
the the to find good models were not
very difficult so we searched for 128.
and the total number of experiments in
this paper is around 50 000 to cover all
the possible scenarios that we want
and we implemented Grid in random search
grid search for the white box case and
random search for the other two
scenarios so but even but to make it
more realistically we defined very large
search space you know in a way that what
we cover with our search is really
irrelevant amount compared to the other
possibilities and this we keep kept
using small neural networks where we
allow them to go up to eight hidden
layers only
and to the valuation metrics to select
the model from the random search from
the upper parameter search was guessing
entropy I mean the number of attack
traces uh necessary to reach guessing
entropy equal to zero or to one
depending how with the scale we're going
to use and a perceived information for
the uh white box the first scenario
which is white box
and
we use the perceived information in the
first case and because it's a new metric
and also we saw that the results uh the
that are
that are computed with equation there on
the right are quite precise they're
quite uh
I would say it yeah accurate for what we
are measuring if compared to the
guessing entropy
and then for the perceived information
we estimate the amount of traces
required for asserting success rate
so we did experiments on four data sets
ascad version one uh on fixed key and
random keys and dpiv 4.2 DPA from DPA
context data set
and also chess CTF 2018. so the only
data set that contains the same keys and
defer in the attack and the profiling
phase is the Ascot with fixed key there
but all all the rest of the data sets
they have different keys on both
profiling and uh validation or attack
phases so they are also first starting
musket software implementations and we
always so we always search for a model
for uh for what single key byte and then
we extend the same model on the rest of
the key
so there is I will share some results
from all the scenarios we tried so first
for the refined points of interest which
is uh what in the white box case
and here we saw that uh we tested it we
applied the on the all data sets I will
show for two of them and we we applied a
gaussian noise on the traces to see how
uh white box and the hyper parameter
search can actually work how the
resilience of the of the of the
implementation when it's more noisy
against hyper parameter search we saw of
course that more noisy the data set
becomes more tricky we need but what we
saw is that we keep increasing the
number of points of interest
for the attack then the noise really
doesn't care it doesn't affect so much
the performance of the attack
so and on the white axis here what you
see is that that metric derived from
perceived information
and we use this in this scenario because
when perceived information is positive
then we saw that the the amount of Trace
is estimated using this metric is quite
aligned with the amount of traces
estimated using guessing entropy
and so the purple line there is gaussian
template attacks and with what we saw
interesting is that gaussian template
attack sometimes is better than the
convolutional neural networks and
multi-layer perception
when we have a reduced amount of models
when we go for more and more and more of
those we always find somebody that has
more uh capacity in terms of number of
required traces and we always find some
results showing that the key is possible
to be recovered with a single
measurement
here on the behavior for the two which
is a little bit more noisy data set it
contains less uh points of interest to
be selected that are very leaky and we
saw that again deep in your networks uh
were in in general more efficient than
gaussian template attacks but the amount
of traces required there's soil is more
that we cannot say more efficient but
because both methods work quite well
so we also did the optimize points of
interest mostly for a reference because
this is a these are data sets largely
considered in previous work and from the
amount of from the performance that we
found with iPad with our hyper parameter
search process
we see that we are actually
aligned with the state of the art it's
just to set some reference so our IP
parameter search is not really biased to
make better or worse results in some of
the case
and so we could see for example we sell
pre-selecting a specific interval for
attack we cannot reduce the we cannot
reduce the amount of traces below for
example 78 for cnns on ascat random keys
but we were able to get with a single
measurement on DPA before the two so
indicating that deep neural networks
although can actually do quite well even
when the the interval of the feature
selection that we are doing includes
more noisy samples
and for chess CTF which is um we had
much less measurement I think 30 000
measurements for profiling than uh the
performance the model was not good for
all scenarios but for Hemingway to
moderate Works quite well
so now finally for the last uh scenario
here on the non-optimized points of
interest which is more aligned with
black box evaluations uh we we saw this
was very surprising because this was the
starting point of the paper we started
directly working on the all this uh on
the road traces and then we saw that uh
for ascad random Keys specifically we
were able to get the key in this in the
attack phase with the single measurement
using a single uh
single heating layer MLP containing 500
euros
and this was uh so and when we compared
to the previous work where uh that I
mentioned at the beginning of the
presentation that Implement a very large
neural network containing up to 30 or 40
layers then this there is quite a big
difference so with a single hidden layer
here you can recover the queue with a
single measurement so
that was quite interesting
for Ascot fix key also we got with a
single measurement but this data set is
the same key on the both sides so I
might be interpreted differently if you
go into more details
or so with less leaky data sets with
Ascot is the Nascar is relatively more
leaky than DPA V4 and chess CTF so for
these two data sets here uh we saw also
very good results on chess CTF we could
get the key with eight measurements on
the road data set and um
yeah so but it worked better for uh for
Hemingway to leakage model so we
attacked the first part of the Implement
so this this implementation has somehow
um
600 000 points I think so we attack only
150 000 points which are the first part
of the measurement but without any this
can be considered as without feature
selection because this is obvious and
eight traces is already a very small
amount for DPA before the same random
search strategy we were able to get with
400 traces it's relatively much more
than the other data sets but considering
that we didn't change anything in the
search strategy this is quite an
advantage
and then we apply this the model found
for one key by to the rest of the uh of
the key bytes and we can see that we are
at least for one scenario uh one
combination of model type and leakage
model we were able to get the the full
key and specifically for ask at the
random Keys the third line on the table
you can see that we needed three
measurements for the full key recovery
on the
on the raw data sets
um yeah so we also did analysis on the
synchronization
uh and then we didn't change any hyper
parameter in the search in the search
space we just apply the same random
search and we were and we did with and
without data augmentation applying
random shifts during the training
and we saw also very good results for uh
for all data sets except for dpav4.2
where we reduce the get the entropy of
the key but not to want to consider as a
successful attack but for ascad random
keys for example we could take with 25
Trace
and obviously so this is a summary of a
result and that showed that with with
more relaxed feature selection scenario
more hyper parameter search you need
more effort you need on this side
uh when we have the synchronization for
in some cases only one percent on even
less of their of the search space gave
us a successful result and but for white
box sometimes it's 100 of the mods that
good positive results
and yeah so this emphasized that it's
very extensive random search is some
somehow necessary to to make very
efficient attacks on Black Box way
so in conclusion there so we concluded
more or less that yes deep learning can
skip feature selection which is uh
written in many places that you can skip
so somehow it can as long as we do long
hyper parameter search Pros so the
important the Opera parameter search
needs to be applied and we apply the
same search strategy on all the targets
all the all the situations and we would
say that black in black box scenario to
estimate the strength of the attacker
the learnability capacity is something
to be taken into account
and we emphasize also that small modules
and small CNN and MLP models uh can
defeat multiple targets uh first order
musket implementations even on very
large intervals or raw data but of
course I think we should invest on more
complex deep learning approach also
random search approach when we move to
more difficult targets for example a
Target Ascot V2 which is publicly
available and contains more protections
okay so thank you very much for
obtaining this presentation if you have
any questions I would like to have I
would be happy to answer
thank you
questions
thank you very much for a nice
presentation I have a question about the
the fixed um fixed key data set how did
you make sure did you choose did you
select the part of the trace that like
like yeah I mean the bias due to the key
did you try that method or
selecting part of the trace you mean
like yeah how how did you make sure that
it's not biased how I make sure that for
example there is no first order leakage
for example or that I don't learn only
the key I mean okay you are using
identity model yes yes so there is a
there is a an issue in that so this is
why I I included most results on the
desk at the random keys because I think
there is this is something to be
investigated but I believe if you learn
a data set that has a fixed key and then
apply attack phase on a fixed key your
own identity leakage mode you can only
learn that situation it doesn't
generalize to different keys so that
could be possibility
[Music]
yeah man
um
we went over time
I went