so my name is edward miro
i am here to do a speaker introduction
but before that i just want to give a
shout out to some of our
sponsors mongodb microsoft verizon
salesforce amazon information security
elearn security intel and remediant
thank you so much to all the amazing
sponsors and to all the attendees who
are here this is an awesome event and
i'm so proud to be
one of the volunteers for that uh also i
just want to remind you that there is a
career village going on
uh there is a capture of the flag and
yeah
try to get involved there's a badge
workshop you can learn to solder there's
so much going on so
definitely check that stuff out while
you're here and next up i have the honor
of introducing carlota
sage they're going to be doing a talk
uh called stage one low tech and
insecure
building better boundaries at work and
in life
um if you have any questions there may
be time at the end for q a but if not
we're going to move it over to the
career village
thank you carlota and take it away thank
you so much i appreciate that word
uh yes this is low tech and insecure
just to be very clear this is
not a technical talk this is not your
entry-level physical penetration
talk this is not an hr talk either and
it's not even a soft skills talk
this is a life skills talk and it's
about
building uh confidence through
boundaries
i am carlata sage i have worked at a lot
of silicon valley
uh tech companies i have
when i've gone to a lot of different
colleges and universities
uh and i want to to give a little aside
to our hiring managers
out there and remind them that the
carlitos age that dropped out
of auburn university had the exact same
potential
as the carlotta sage that graduated from
columbia university with her masters
i just didn't have the experience or the
guidance to know what i wanted so
hiring managers please don't let the
lack of a degree
keep you from hiring a really fantastic
person i've been very lucky in my career
in that regard
but enough about me i want to talk about
confidence what is your confidence level
and the reason i ask this question
is that over the last 10 years i've had
a lot of
younger women and men come up to me and
asked me to be
their mentor and at first i was a little
horrified
because i am not historically someone
that i would have gone to for mentoring
uh but as i asked them what is it that
you're looking for that you feel like
carlota can
teach you a lot of what came back was
i i just you're so confident and i i
just feel like i
i'm an imposter all the time there was a
lot of talk around imposter syndrome
i do not personally suffer from imposter
syndrome so i cannot guarantee
that the talk that i give you is gonna
going to help you
understand or resolve your imposter
syndrome but what i can tell you is that
my confidence comes from knowing my
boundaries
really really well uh we don't all as
human beings
start out on the right side of this
image that very confident
you know ready to face the world i tend
to be
on that right side maybe between those
two right hand figures
sometimes the world pushes me down to
the left sometimes you know
i need a extra hand to help me get back
to the right
most of us are somewhere in between
hopefully
you are not on the left but what i want
to to help you understand
is that building your confidence is
something that
you can do and you may have to engage
a mental health professional a career
coach a life coach
but you you need to take ownership of
that if you feel like you're an impostor
don't feel that way you've got to find a
way past that and you can learn that
piece
so what i'm going to give you today is
carlita's crash course
on finding your boundaries so that you
can start to understand
where you are on this image and where
you want to be
and how to maybe start practicing some
of those pieces that will build your
confidence
uh i'm going to start with physical
boundaries because those are some
very obvious very common
uh especially egregious places to
push on people's boundaries and has
many people in this audience know both
female and male and other
identifying uh non-binary folks
um the physical boundaries are so
important
and sometimes that you
you get that hand on your knee you get
that hand in a strange place you're not
comfortable but you're not necessarily
comfortable saying something
i want you to start practicing where
your boundaries are
physically and i want you to start
practicing defending them
because it's very important people who
push on your boundaries
especially abusers are going to start
very small
and you have to defend those small
boundaries so that
by the time that they're trying to push
on those bigger boundaries
uh you've got those defenses built up so
if you find that hand
on your knee or sliding down your skirt
or up your leg
you need to be very clear and you don't
have to be angry about it i used to be
very angry about it i'm very much more
uh just simply certain about it now
but you need to be very clear remove
your hand from my body
you do not have consent to touch me it's
very simple
and i talk about this because especially
at conferences
uh we get a little loose we get a little
we get to cut up we get people who are
of our mindset we get our tribe we get a
little alcohol in us
um and we may we may also push on those
boundaries so i
i put this image up so that people can
understand and have kind of a level set
that this
is not okay and they can point back and
say you know
carlotta said it's not okay it's a
really basic thing and when it comes to
defending your physical boundaries don't
be shy about that it is not a request
you do not have to say please this is
your space
remove your hand from my body and it's
very simple
next i'm going to talk a little bit
about verbal boundaries
and this is a much more difficult space
to talk about because
words can literally kill we hear stories
see stories all the time
about cyberbullying cyberstalking
and people literally beating other
people down
with words and telling them that they're
worthless telling them that they should
die
it is not okay um even in the workplace
even if we're not going to that extreme
choose your words well choose your words
thoughtfully because
the words that you choose build people's
confidence in you
they build your own confidence as well
but they also build
the people's confidence in you they
build
your credibility they build your ability
to work
in very difficult situations i'm very
good with collaboration i've made a lot
of my career
around getting technical teams who are
antagonistic to work together
um and part of that is the word
selection
uh i will give you a very personal
example
from my own life my own career i worked
for
a heavily asian company and i had an
older
gentleman for a boss an older gentleman
from hong kong
and he would call me girl and that did
not bother me because
i knew that he was not saying it in any
malicious kind of way that was just
the era he came from um but
the younger men started picking it up
and the way they said it was
not okay they would say it very
derisively very kind of viciously uh
so the next time the boss called me girl
and in front of the rest of the team i i
called him on it and i very gently
well not very gently very uh assertively
said
you may call me woman or you may call me
the b word
but you are not allowed to call me girl
anymore and
when he kind of paused i said i want you
to say in your native language
uh which i believe was either mandarin
or cantonese i'm not sure because he
came from hong kong
uh i want you to say what you just said
to me and i want you to use girl in your
language and he said it out loud and
the look on his face of just
regret he said oh crolitta i'm so very
sorry
i will never call you girl again so
it matters it matters how people in the
workplace
refer to you and it's okay to push back
on that
and it's okay sometimes with sunglasses
but that boss for certain
um it's okay to push back on on them in
front of other people
especially if you can give them you know
that empathy if you know that you can
get them
to come to an empathetic place with you
uh i hope that you will still make
room for people for whom english is not
their first language
i make a lot of room for older
generations because
uh generations older than me did not
have the internet
we are much more aware and the
generations that came after me are
incredibly aware uh i i know there's a
lot of discussion
on do we have to change safe whitelist
blacklist to safelist except
for example language has always evolved
and it evolves without us so the fact
that we're taking some ownership of that
evolution
i see is a very good thing
in terms of boundaries though
you have to work that one out this one
is a little
softer a little harder to to define
you definitely want to talk to your
peers and get their feedback
listen to the people you trust if they
say no it's not okay for them to talk to
you that way
figure out where your confidence level
is and confronting that
that's a very tough boundary sometimes
to defend
but unfortunately i don't have a lot of
time to keep going into that
the next boundary that i want to cover
though are your emotional boundaries and
these are
by far and away the the most difficult
um you think words are tough emotions
are very tough
the thing i want you to remember about
emotions when you have that
emotional response to a situation or to
something someone has said to you
you need to understand that that is your
emotion
and it is not right or wrong it doesn't
matter if the other person
understands it or agrees with it or
finds that emotion
reasonable you need to own that this is
how i feel about this
i'm afraid of dogs that is the way i
feel about that bringing me a dog is not
going to make me feel better
right um that's just one example
the other person though needs to
understand that they cannot
fix that emotional response and they
cannot bend
that emotional response to me be more
favorable
for them you need to own this is how i
feel about this
you need to ask for more time and it
could be that
you do have some very tight emotional
boundaries there that need to be maybe a
little more flexible
the other thing about emotional and
really all boundaries
is that they are flexible they are
flexible for certain people or for
certain situations
you're going to be more comfortable or
less comfortable with your family
depending on how you grew up
you're going to be more comfortable with
your friends than with strangers
um the biggest thing is that you own
that
and then you think about if if somebody
you really trust
is surprised by your emotional boundary
then then maybe there's a discussion
there that you need to understand
where that feeling is coming from and
then
resolve that conflict because if it's
someone you really trust
you really want their input the problem
of course is
if you really trust an abusive person
that's also an issue that can
really really mess with your emotional
boundaries
but we're going to get to that in just a
little bit uh
the the biggest topic that i want to
talk about are the more sensitive things
intimacy romance sex in the workplace
and in industry conferences
we spend a lot of time with the people
we work with
and in security especially sometimes
that's a
crucible and that pressure
can actually forge a very close
relationship
uh if you are interested if you feel
like there is something beyond
a work relationship there you need to be
very careful about how you approach that
the simplest thing to do is to say
don't if you are
interested in a co-worker or in a
an industry peer if you feel like that
spark is there
be very careful be very careful about
revealing that because it will change
the dynamic of your relationship
but the reality is we're human
and we're not mannequins and we do have
those feelings and sometimes
we trust the other person enough and and
you really want to think about if you
trust that other person enough
maybe you trust that other person enough
to to see
if there is more available there and you
have to be very careful on how you
approach that
the best way is not to stick your hand
down their pants
it is not to suddenly lean over and kiss
them
some people respond positively to that
but it's not going to be very common
the best way to approach that is to ask
for consent and to say
i feel like there's something more here
is there the potential for that
am i is this a one-sided feeling and
you need to be very ready for rejection
for that
if you are the target of somebody else's
affection you need to be very
certain when you reject that person um
don't don't maybe them if it's a no it's
not
be very clear draw that boundary very
firmly
that there is not something more more
available here
if that changes now it's your turn to
ask consent uh
if you know how you you a few months ago
asked me
if there was more here and at the time i
said no but has i've gotten to know you
i think there could be more here are you
still interested
maybe they've met someone maybe they've
moved on
be very careful how you approach those
the easiest thing is always going to be
to hold that feeling to yourself and let
it pass let that crush go by
but if you are a risk taker you have to
think
very carefully on how to approach that
and the consequences of that because
whether
that becomes a relationship whether that
relationship is successful or goes
sideways
there is a risk to your credibility into
the person's credibility
that you need to be very cognizant of
especially if it's a very small
workplace
it's very clear that you two are cozy
that can have some serious ramifications
so you need to be very careful
how you approach those pieces
uh sometimes though
people particularly of a certain gender
tend to send pictures of their genitalia
and that's fine if you've
asked for it if you have not
then you can send this back to them
right
you should not be starting your
workplace romance
with a dick pic ideally um
i've had more than my sheer fair fair
share as i'm sure
many women and and transgender and
maybe even men are getting them from not
just men but from women
uh sending an intimate photo of any
of any sort especially to a co-worker is
a very bad idea
so you need to make sure that you have
very specific permission to do that
but you also need to really trust that
person if you're going to do that
it is once it's out there it's out there
i would
recommend highly never doing it if you
are the recipient
of an unsolicited picture you are
welcome to screenshot this
and crop it and send it back to that
person so that they know
this is not acceptable behavior uh
never ever ever do anything
of a remotely sexual nature with a peer
uh or a manager or a sub or a somebody
who
reports to you never do that without
treading very carefully
and asking for consent um
and even then again that default state
of just know
is really important
so now that i've given you a bit of a
crash course on what kinds of boundaries
are out there and
and just a few tips on how you can
handle those boundaries i want to talk
about
how pushing boundaries becomes abuse and
we talked about this i alluded to this
in that
that initial slide with our mannequins
pushing boundaries can be a very good
thing they can break you out of your
comfort
zone and force you to grow and some of
us like to leap out of
our comfort zone and and force ourselves
to grow
um but pushing boundaries repeatedly
to the point where you have to ask a
person to stop
that's a little less good but that's not
necessarily abusive
maybe you have a friend who knows that
you're an introvert you're you're in
your shell they
want you they they love you and they
want you to grow with them
and that that's a tough call um
but once you ask that person to stop
that then it should stop
right uh if you ask someone to stop
pushing a boundary
and they keep pushing it and it doesn't
matter if that's a physical boundary
an emotional one a verbal one a sexual
one it does not matter
if you have said this makes me
uncomfortable
please stop doing it or just stop doing
it
and they continue hammering on that
boundary
now you're getting into abuse
this is a really tough tough area to
navigate
um i think it's it's really important if
you are uncertain
am i overthinking this uh go with your
gut
your gut is really good most of the time
uh if you're still uncertain engage
outside counsel and that that that
counsel does not have to be legal
counsel
that council could be again a life coach
a therapist
a counselor a priest or preacher
um someone that you trust someone that
you feel like has good objectivity
someone who perhaps knows how you think
and run these scenarios by them
and see what their call on this is
because
abuse in the workplace and in life is
pretty rampant
unfortunately a lot of us come from very
toxic
or very traumatic or very abusive
situations uh his children
both male female gender binary
i'm sorry non-binary
there are a lot of places that
abuse is a problem and we carry that
problem with us
unfortunately we carry those scars with
us and we carry the behaviors that we
learned from abusers and toxic people
with us into the workplace and into the
industry
i i think a lot of the gatekeeping that
you see is
is just a kind of a generic abusive
they want to control that space right um
you need to be able to step back
and ask for help to make sure that
you're calling this right that it's a
pushing of a boundary versus abuse
but also perhaps to coach you through
some of it
this slide has brought up a question
that i thought was very interesting at
the last time i gave this talk and
that's how do i tell
a manager who's not a good manager
from a manager who isn't the right
manager for me
you know from a manager who's just
outright abusive
and that again very tough
very tough call sometimes if there's
ever
any physical or sexual interaction
um that's very clear and if there is
don't go to hr hr is there to protect
the company
you need to file a police complaint and
then go to hr
the verbal emotional is much more common
and much harder to prove that's where
you need to take that step back
look to somebody that you trust run
those situations by them
and get that input get that feedback on
what you're seeing and what you're
feeling and in a lot of ways
it almost doesn't i won't say it doesn't
matter whether it's
a manager who is not good for you versus
a manager who's just not very good at
managing
versus a toxic manager because the end
result is that at some point you have to
leave that manager
it's a question of how quickly do you
need to get out the more
they are on that abusive side of the
scale the faster you need to be leaving
um it's it's very destructive to your
mental health and i would encourage you
that if you're in a toxic workplace
and you you have a really good therapist
on speed dial because it will make
all the difference in the world i hope
that you are here if you are
in a toxic workplace i hope that you're
here here and you come to the career
village and you
let us help you find a way out of that
toxic place
uh if it's just a bad manager maybe you
can stay with that company
and move around and if it's a good
manager who
isn't the right manager for you you have
more opportunity to actually have a
discussion with that person
and say this doesn't feel like it's
working i i personally have literally
said to
a new manager in my 30-day review i
don't think i'll be here in 90 days
because it's clear to me that i am not
who you want to dire
i was able to have that conversation
with him because in my judgment
he was a good person he was just not the
right manager for me
and i was correct that i was not the
person he wanted to hire
but i was the right person for the role
and we managed to work that out
uh it's a judgment call
on whether you can have that
conversation with a manager
i hope that you can have that
conversation with your manager if you
feel like you're
reporting to someone who isn't the right
manager for you if i feel like
somebody is reporting to me and i'm not
the right manager for them
i will find them the right manager i
will encourage them especially if
they're a good
worker i want them to stay with the
company
i'm going to encourage them and find
them that right place for them to be
because if we take care of each other
even if we're not right for each other
in a work situation
we're in a personal relationship if we
take care of each other
that's the number one thing we can do
so from that point of view i want you to
think about
where you are now do you feel like
you are on the right side of this image
do you feel like you're on the left side
of this image
do you feel like you have a little more
information perhaps to help you path
your way
across this to the right i hope you do
i know i don't have a lot of time with
you we've got just a few seven minutes
left we could do a little q
a and if not we can meet in the career
village and i will
be happy to answer any questions
if you are coming from a more traumatic
uh life experience
i would encourage you to get help
uh this industry is so hard on us
it's so hard on us from an emotional and
from
a psychological point of view we are
constantly fighting an uphill battle
um a lot of us are drawn to this
industry because we've had some kind of
traumatic event and we
really believe in protecting other
people if you
feel like you're going to hurt yourself
please
get help if you have been hurt please
get help and if you are the person
hurting someone else
please get help you do not have to keep
doing what you're doing
and yeah incredibly well said i i don't
mean to interrupt
no no no i'm at the end i have a few
questions that i think are really
interesting um overwhelmingly positive
response from the audience
a lot of people are saying i wish she
could come to our company and replace
the training that we have because
this is powerful also they loved you
talking about dick pics i'm just kidding
so i had to add a couple questions can
there be consent between individuals in
different
layers of the same reporting structure
like can a senior on a team ever make a
romantic play to junior and have real
consent exist
because of the dynamic that is a really
great
question uh it is going to be
exceedingly rare
i i will never say no it will never
happen
because then somebody is going to pop up
with the edge case where it did happen
to happen
um i would encourage you if you are
romantically interested
in a subordinate or subordinate find
them another role
in your company so that they are not
reporting to you
and then make your play because i i
think it's absolutely correct
you are putting that person at risk and
you're putting yourself at risk
uh that your other option is go find
another role
um i have absolutely started dating
people that i was working with
after i left the company absolutely
another question what do you do when no
just doesn't work with a colleague
there are situations where reporting
this ends up making the reporting person
be known as a victim
or as the bad person for possibly
unknowingly leading one on
that is so unfortunately common because
like i said
hr is there to protect the company and
not has much to protect
you um i have certainly heard of
situations where someone has victimized
several people at a large corporation i
was and still had their director title
uh even after the metoo movement so that
that
is a real tough one that's i think where
you start engaging outside counsel
not necessarily legal but definitely at
some point legal um
start documenting religiously
if it is a continual effort on that
person's part and no is not an option
if there is a single hr person that you
trust or a manager that you trust that
can step
in um i would certainly talk with them
about it
um the problem and and this is a problem
especially that
that women and uh minorities and
and lots of people face because when you
complain
you become the problem right and that is
a
serious issue and i have never worked at
a company where that wasn't
really an issue to be honest um i'm
gonna have to think on that one because
okay
and this is and again this is a problem
because
your usual best options to leave but
that means that you're making a lateral
movement and you're suffering your
career is suffering because
this person won't leave you one i'm
really glad you brought up that
hr is there to protect the company and
not the employment i think that's a hard
lesson you
have to learn at some points in our
industry and it's so counter-intuitive
okay i think we have time for one final
question
and i think it's uh i think it sums up a
lot of this quite well how can we start
getting our companies to start
incorporating these
key topics oh yeah a couple
corporations aren't good at honesty i
mean that's very very truthful
um these are tough discussions to have
and i'm gonna have to think on that
question that's a i haven't gotten that
question well we can have people
check you out in the career village
right there yeah let's do a panel on
that in the career village uh later
today because i think there are ways to
do it i just uh
usually i'm the person that's advocating
that level of honesty
um but i i don't know
how to formalize that yet
great well thank you so much for your
talk it was amazing everyone in the the
chat loved it if you want to talk to car
a little more please
find them in the career village here
today all day
so thank you so much and uh yeah we'll
be looking forward to the next speaker
coming up here in just a couple minutes
fantastic