all right welcome back uh my name is
edward miro
and i'm going to introduce the next talk
here but before i do i just have a
couple of announcements
i just want to make sure everyone's
participating in the raffle prizes that
are up for grabs in each of the tracks
there's uh one raffle prize each day
uh check the pin note in the channels
and please
sign up for the raffle also if you're
interested in learning about
lock picking there's a lock picking
village and workshop going on
and uh yeah just wanted to make sure
that you're taking a look at all of the
extracurricular stuff
and getting involved with the community
there's a lot of great awesome resources
available
i just want to thank the sponsors again
of course our
diamond sponsors are microsoft and
mongodb
platinum sponsors verizon salesforce
amazon information security and of
course our gold sponsors remedies
intel and elearn security and then
personally i just want to thank all of
the organizers and the volunteers behind
the scenes who are making this happen
you guys are all
rock stars and i'm honored to be
a a co-conspirator in this
operation so this next talk is
pre-recorded
and the speaker michelle quiroz is going
to be in the chat to answer questions
throughout
and if you have any questions that don't
get answered during the talk
feel free to post those in at the end
and we will make sure those get asked so
this next talk is called into the
unknown from a stay-at-home parent to an
infosec career
by michelle quiroz she works for
insighte
and yeah check out this talk
hi everybody my name is michelle i live
in las vegas
and i work for an i.t security company
called incitee
we do penetration testing security
consulting
and security research and this is kind
of a story about how i transitioned how
i went from being a stay-at-home mom
into an infosec career just a little
side note that
will hopefully make the talk make a
little bit more sense as you can see on
my cover slide
i also worked for a very long time as a
character performer so i worked
with a character visit company and i
would go to parties on events
dressed up as different characters like
elsa as you can see here
and that kind of inspired the title of
my um
my talk for or one of her most recent
songs that came out with frozen two
um so um please excuse my nerdiness with
that
i do love disney references
so another side note
is i'm very much a people person so i'm
not used to giving a talk like this so
please bear with me if i'm awkward
i will try my very best not to be
awkward but i can't make any promises
because i can be awkward so
i will do my best but here we go
i thought the best place to start would
give you b to give you guys
a little overview a little uh background
and information
a little preface to the story so you
guys can kind of see
where i came from and make things make a
little bit more sense hopefully
i grew up in virginia until i was 12
then moved to texas
i grew up with three brothers um with a
dad who was an engineer
um or at least i thought he was my
father i just recently found out
that he's not actually my father but yay
23 me christmas gifts
um but my real father is actually a
teacher and he's really cool too
but growing up with an engineer as a
father i
learned to look at the world a little
differently i love to take things apart
understand how things work and really
challenge myself
and push myself i mean it didn't i mean
having three brothers as well challenged
me a lot
i was always chasing after them trying
to do what they did
wanting to climb the same trees and ride
the same bikes and
they might have been riding away from me
or climbing the same trees but
i think it was part of the game and i
still did it so
um no but really i had a great childhood
in that sense
that i was pushing myself constantly
and i went to college and i wanted to be
an engineer
and about two years into college i got
married and
got pregnant and i was 20.
um i'm not sure i recommend that to
anybody
but my daughter changed my life
as i'm sure most parents know how that
goes
so i started to change my goal there i
started to
invest in her and wanting to spend my
life teaching her how to be a
responsible human being to
be a contributing member of society my
goal from when she was a baby was for
her
to need me less and less every day and
become a strong
and independent beautiful human being
and that started to work i taught her to
read i taught her to write
and she was growing up she started to
learn to play cello
and then she got older and she didn't
need me every day
and so i started to realize you know
it's time for me to figure out what i'm
gonna do with myself now
i could pick up where i left off i could
go back to school
and i had to figure out what i wanted to
do
i decided that going back to school
wasn't for me i'm not i do think
that there are definitely people who
need degrees and that it can be amazing
and i love learning as you'll find out
later on
but i do think that there's also things
that you can't learn in school and that
sometimes that experience and just
getting out and doing what you want to
do
is great um and i i know in america that
we put a lot of emphasis on training and
degrees
and certifications and i'm not saying
those are bad at all
i just i just know that often people
feel bad when they don't have these
things but i want to encourage you
if you don't have a degree that's okay
especially in this community especially
in infosec
you can train yourself you can teach
yourself you can
learn step by step um and so i just want
you to know that that's possible
um so as i was trying to figure out what
i wanted to do with myself what i wanted
to do with my life
i started doing something i was
passionate about
i started getting into working with a
non-profit
that focuses on bearded dragons i was on
the board of this nonprofit when it
started i helped create it i helped
build and write the bylaws
and it was something i was passionate
about helping these animals
these are pretty common pets and they
are the coolest lizards
and if you don't agree you can fight me
um
but really they they're really amazing
animals but they have
needs that other animals don't have like
uv
lights and calcium supplements and when
they don't have them they
can get severely disformed and
disfigured and we see
so many animals like this that need help
and that need people to be educated and
to
understand what they're taking care of
when they get these cute little baby
lizard
um and so i got passionate about that
and
one of the other board members owned i.t
security company and he saw my passion
he saw these qualities that came out
while i was doing this and said you know
i need someone to do business
development
and you can talk to people and there
aren't a lot of people in i.t that can
talk to people
which is kind of cliche and there are a
lot of people in i.t that can talk to
people but
um it was something that he saw my
passion and i was doing something i was
passionate about
and so i started my career in infosec
and i've kind of prepared some points
here that i think that i hope you guys
can take away
something from this and what i hope can
kind of
help you along your way or encourage you
in your infosec
career path um
the first thing i ran into was
experience i didn't have experience in
this
um i didn't have experience with
computers very much at all
i mean heck i use the same password on
every site and i don't think that
qualifies me for any sort of infosec
award except for maybe the worst infosec
personnel ever
um and so i needed to get experience but
as i went through this job and as i
learned and i trained myself
and my company trained me i was able to
find these areas that i didn't think
applied before these jobs
that i had when my daughter was in
school because i only wanted to work
while she was at school and i was home
when she was home so i worked as a
substitute teacher
and i worked as a um
as a instructor at a ceramic studio and
then of course i worked at these
character visits
and i would go to these parties and
perform as kids
and there are so many skills that i had
that i didn't even realize
applied um for example
when i do social engineering jobs when i
go on um
a tactical social engineering mission
and i have these goals to accomplish in
these roles to play
it's just like being a princess except
for the people believe you more
and they're less skeptical i mean the
kids are great and they come up with
some of the most amazing questions to
ask you
and they will be skeptical occasionally
but you have to answer
quickly you have to know exactly what
you're going to say
and you're going to have to be
believable and you're going to have to
believe it and they will believe it
and i think that was one of the best
trainings i could have had for social
engineering because
it's kind of tough sometimes and also
i haven't mentioned i don't know if
anybody
here has tried to wrangle a party of
kids
um and 15 kids in a room from ages four
to eight um and keep them entertained
for an hour when they have a whole bunch
of sugar in their systems from cake and
candy um that is also a skill that you
can't just learn in school
so learning to manage people is
something that you kind of got to get an
experience you just got to get on the
job
and so that's just how i could found
ways that different things i did
to be applied in my infosec career
and coming back to being passionate
about something
um that's something i think that you
guys could take away from this is
learning finding something you're
passionate about if you're passionate
about infosec
um volunteer add little
different conferences like def con or
the here at diane initiative
if you can do that people will see your
passion that will bring out your best
qualities
people will see the things that you're
good at and that
will inspire companies to hire you
i know inside we'd much rather hire
someone with the right mindset the
determination the people who want to be
a hacker
who have the right mindset the
determination and creativity
and then we can train them to do a task
but you can't train someone to have the
mindset you can't train somebody to have
the passion
either have it or they don't so that's
why i just
if you can get out there do something
that shows your passion
and that will show the best qualities of
you
another problem i had when i started was
i had no
idea what i was doing and i mentioned
this before i had the same password
everywhere
i didn't know about computers or
security so
my um the owner of the company sat me
down
and he got a big dry erase board and he
started with the osi layers
and it was a long four hours i think i
had a headache by the end of
and i still didn't understand anything
at the end i still had no idea what i
was doing
but i figured out enough so i could do
business development
and i was excited and i started to learn
i
started to change my habits i learned
how security can be easy in my life
and i continued to learn as i went and
that's what i think everybody here can
do
you can learn as you go you don't have
to be the best you don't have to know
everything before you start you know
just get started do
find any job in infosec you know i
started with business development
and i pushed myself i learned i asked
questions you can ask questions to
people and
learn um and hopefully be respectful of
their time
i know i probably wasn't always but i
tried um
and you just need to do it this is a
picture of me after when defcon i
went and i bought a badge and i wanted
to learn to solder and so i went to my
um mentor and i said hey
you know how to solder i got this badge
can you teach me how to solder
and he said sure and so i came to his
really cool soldering station
get a um everything i needed and he goes
okay
here are the instructions here's the
soldering station
don't burn yourself and don't mess up my
stuff and i was just like
okay so i learned and i
looked it up and i read the instructions
and i think this is a dark
net badge but i i learned and i showed
him and he would make corrections and
then finally he kind of gave me an
example once i kind of figured it out my
way but
i really think that some of the best
teachers are people who force you and
push you to figure it out yourself
and just learning as you go don't feel
like you need to know what to do ahead
of time before you just start doing it
you need to just push yourself do what
you need to do and you will learn along
the way
and that leads me to the next point is
you should push yourself outside your
comfort zone
i know it's so cliche to say you know
when you're outside your comfort zone
that's where the magic happens
and that's where you find your true self
but i think there is some truth to
the importance of pushing yourself
outside your comfort zone though
because that's what trains your brain to
be able to handle situations that you're
uncomfortable in
when you make yourself uncomfortable on
purpose you learn to adjust faster
you learn to figure yourself out and how
to
deal and cope with the stress and cope
with not knowing
and the fear of failing and
i think that's so important that i've
purposely tried to push myself
put myself in situations where i'm not
comfortable
this is a picture of me doing flying
trapeze
and i was scared i thought i would fall
i wouldn't be able to hold on
but it was so much fun and i was so
happy that at the end of it
and so i started in my career pushing
myself to do things that i was
uncomfortable
signing up for talks like this one um
[Music]
because i knew that it was important and
as i go i'm finding myself doing things
i never thought i could do things that i
never would have before
thought and it happens little by little
each time you make yourself
uncomfortable you grow
and you make yourself into a stronger
person
so i just encourage you find a job that
makes you uncomfortable
find a job that you're not always in
your comfort zone where you're learning
that you're having you're forcing
yourself to learn every day or else
you'll be swallowed whole
and that is where you will grow the most
if you know what's happening in your job
i would i would challenge you if you're
watching this if you feel comfortable in
your job and you know what to do every
day and it's boring
find a different job that challenges you
push yourself find another job or you
you in the community if you want to stay
in infosec if that's what you're in
that makes you work hard that you feel
like you don't know what you're doing
and you have to try harder
every single day and you know
as i started doing this as i was pushing
myself as i was learning
i started to have fun um and
i know i said before that i love
learning and like having fun
but i was and i
started signing myself up for talks
i started loving to getting passionate
again going back to that finding
something you're passionate about
passionate about teaching people about
security
because this was something that changed
my world personally these were things
that i always thought were
so complex that i didn't understand or
that didn't apply to me
or that it would just make my life
difficult and that's not what security
is
security makes your life easier if it's
done right and
i started doing talks around the valley
because i really want
people to understand what i can see now
i started to have this gift
where i could take a technical idea
and translate it make this bridge across
from the technical
and the non-technical and teach people
what i could understand
in a way that they would understand it
so i started to do these talks around
the valley
i would do lunch and learns and
different talks about different
ideas to help them learn about security
to get passion about security to be more
secure in general
and just to think a little differently
and understand that
security will help them it's not just
going to hurt them and it applies to
them
and so i mean if you're listening and
you want a security talk
in las vegas area or surrounding
let me know i'm your person i would love
to do it um i would come in i would do a
talk
um teach people about security because
that's something i'm passionate about
um and often i would sign up for these
talks
and i would just pick a subject that i
was excited about and i would have
no idea what i was going to talk about
and i wouldn't even understand the
subject
and then i would research it and that's
where i got to learning that
by teaching other people it would teach
me by forcing myself
to find a subject that i didn't
understand i would force myself to learn
that subject
my first talk was on passwords and i
already told you before
i had the worst password policy before i
used the same password over and over and
over again
um and that's what i researched first
because it made such a huge difference
in my life to be able to have a password
manager
and that security could be easier and
that i wouldn't have to remember all
these passwords
and i could teach other people that um
and i know i said i could give talks for
you guys earlier and you might change
your mind now that you know that i kind
of
figure it out as i go but i promise i'll
be ready in time for the talk
um but it became something i love to do
to research things and to learn more um
and i sense that have given this talk
again there were people
there that were way more technical than
me that i was so surprised that they
would ask me
um some technical questions
and i realized that we often
um compare ourselves our weaknesses with
other people's strengths
or we put people on this pedestal what
we think that they know
and because they're good at one thing
that they must be good at all things and
we compare ourselves to that
and it's so not fair that we should be
realistic in that and
and find our strengths find the things
that we're good at in our
our qualities that make us special and
that we have that passion that shows our
best qualities and
focus on those things um and
as i've done this and as i've learned
more and i've
done this talk other times um i've added
more to it i've added sections for
developers
for people to uh focus on
as they're developing these applications
as they're developing these systems
to make the security built in don't rely
on the user to be secure
you take the responsibility on yourself
and it was so fascinating to me to learn
how to do that how to make it secure so
i could teach other people
even developers and
of course there's still things i don't
know and i'm never afraid and
i think that's another thing to mention
is you should never be afraid to tell
somebody you don't know
but you can figure it out or you can
find someone who does know and answer
that question for them
so that leads me to my next point is to
never give up
and i know in this field there is so
much to learn
i know there have been times where i
felt like i there was no possible way i
would ever know what i want to know and
i should just give up now
that i would go to talks in meetups
where there would be so many things that
i wouldn't understand
highly technical ideas and i would just
be so frustrated
that people were there that understood
and i didn't understand
and it wasn't fair and so i would write
down
the things that i didn't understand and
i would go look them up
and i would research them later and try
to figure out what they meant and put
the pieces together
little by little and i started to
realize over time that i have
things i'm good at that other people
aren't and if you have that right
mindset that determination to figure out
things
and to use your qualities and your
strengths to your benefit
that you can take yourself to the next
level that you can do the job that
you're meant to do
and love doing it i know that i'm not
going to be a pen tester
not because i couldn't do it ever
because it doesn't make sense for me
and my passion and my qualities um
and so i focus on the things now that i
can do
the research the security and adding to
what other people need the different
mindset and the different way of
thinking
that adds value to my company to my team
um in other ways other people wouldn't
so find your niche
find your sweet spot and your passion
focus on that
and if you can i think one other thing
that i would want to add that would help
is to find a mentor if you can and when
i say a mentor i mean someone who pushes
you
who challenges you i know there's so
many times
when i was so frustrated with something
that i knew i would message my mentor
i'd be like hey how do i do this and i
knew he knew
and he did and he would just tell me try
harder
and those two words were so frustrating
um that would be like on the verge of
tears but i knew
if he told me to try harder just like
with my climbing in the gym
that there was a way that that route
could be climbed that if other people
could climb it i could figure out a way
to climb it
and when he told me to try harder i knew
that i could do it
and i just needed to try harder so find
someone who pushes you find someone who
encourages you
and hope that they put up with you
because i know there are many times
where i've asked these questions
that made this happen um that would take
hours and hours of explanation where i
just wanted to understand how something
worked and i really appreciate the time
that he put in
and explaining to me and i hope you guys
can find something like that too because
i really think it helps
so thank you guys so much for listening
these are just a few
points that i hope you guys can take
away i hope that i pulled out some
universal truths that you guys can
hopefully get inspired by or motivated
by
um and just find something you're
passionate about find something that
pushes you find something that makes you
uncomfortable
find something that um teaches you
and and find just do it just find
get started in that career find the
career that you want find your
niche find the areas that you're good at
and focus on those
things and thank you so much for
listening to my talk
if you guys have any questions here's my
contact information
i'll be around for questions and
i'm more than happy to answer those and
thank you guys again so much