and we're back on stage two for the
diana initiative hello everybody i'm
josh again
um and a quick announcement for y'all
um don't forget to visit the expo hall
we have sponsors with contests and swag
community organizations you should
really find out more about and the red
team village with
five red team talks going on um and
there are raffles happening throughout
the event though those should be closing
up pretty soon
um and yeah uh while you still have time
go visit the expo hall
um and with that i'd like to introduce
our next speaker
ava ava black is an open source veteran
who came out as trans after burning out
on tech in 2017
drawing on a lifetime of meditation
practice they are a contributing author
to the book transcending
an anthology of trans buddhist voices
but they came back to tech
thankfully and now are a member of the
kubernetes code of conduct committee
a project manager project manager for
open enclave
and a board member of a seattle-based
non-profit that educates and advocates
for consent in all aspects of life
please welcome ava black
hey folks um well i wasn't in for myself
but
josh did a great job of that um it's
easier for me to talk about tech that's
usually what i do in conferences but
today i'm gonna be a bit more
a bit more vulnerable and talk about
myself um i wish i didn't feel the need
to talk about gender discrimination or
trans issues in 2020 but i kind of do
like like a lot of other folks yesterday
and today have already talked about
diversity and inclusion and company
diverse and inclusive companies
just perform better so the original
title you can see
but i kind of changed it a bit this
talk's really more of a personal story
and journey
so i hope that through the experience of
seeing me a little bit more
you learn to see other people um and
have more compassion and
that compassion helps you she helps
treat the technology you
and the companies you work in build now
this
this talk could start anywhere in my
life but i want to give you a little
extra background on me
um so if i don't talk about too much my
early childhood was spent in indian
communities
my first exposure to american culture
was second grade
and i really didn't fit in in uh in
today's terms
i probably would have been labeled
neurodivergent and genderqueer
instead of all the other labels that
were used back in the in the 80s
so i went through primary and secondary
secondary school as fast as i could
i was um lucky enough to get through
college pretty quick and jump into a
startup
uh the first during the first.com bubble
i was still a teenager
a long-haired eyeliner wearing goth who
kept odd hours and wrote angsty poetry
and i loved linux back in the 90s
when i really didn't fit in in the tech
industry back then
i bounced through some startups and back
to university and back to startups and
then eventually i fled california
and really um so in 2011 i was kind of
living off grid
doing database consulting and a friend
convinced me to go to burning man
if you've never been it is exactly as
hedonistic as you might have heard
disproportionately filled with tech bros
who party without a care in the world
it's also completely different from that
it can be a safe space for vulnerable
self-discovery for a lot of people full
of compassion and self-expression and
beautiful art
where queer and trans folk find a safe
space unlike anything in
the default world it is all of that and
ironically it's where i learned how to
act like a tech bro
the burn gave me a chance to learn about
a culture i had never felt safe in
growing up
men arguing with each other i learned
that if i spoke over others my point
would be heard
if i used rhetoric i could convince the
whole group that i was right
and if i kept showing up and i kept
stating my opinion
sooner or later there wouldn't be any
opposition left
and i learned how leadership can emerge
from open conflicts
you just need to be perceived by the
group as somebody important
someone the current leaders are willing
to treat with respect
and then your opinion carries more
weight now to be clear
i think these are toxic norms they don't
represent the ideals of burning man
nor do they represent my ideals but for
a couple years i thought this was just
how business gets done
and i came back from the burn with a
completely different approach to work
within a year i started a new open
source project i was flying all over the
world
talking at conferences partying with
customers meeting clients
it's like i had just found easy mode and
i got promoted
and i got promoted again and then two
years later i was up for another
promotion
and instead of staying there i spun out
to a startup
um someone offered me the role of vp
running the whole like the whole
engineering wing
in hindsight i was really unqualified
but as is typical for someone who was
perceived as a man
i was hired based on what someone
thought i could do even though i'd never
done it before
and so in those five years my income
more than doubled
but i didn't really stop i was flying
flying everywhere too much i didn't stop
to think about this but i began to track
little discrepancies how differently men
would respond to my emails before and
after they heard my voice on a phone
because to most americans my name back
then even back then it was feminine
so while i was vp of engineering my ceo
tasked me with building an unbiased
hiring process you wanted to double the
team size
you want me to follow the google play
book
i'll give you a brief rundown on what
this looks like if you're not familiar
with it but chances are if you've
interviewed anywhere
in silicon valley or the tech industry
in the past five years you've probably
run into this process
from the outside from the inside the way
it works is that
someone receives a resume removes the
name removes gender markers
and sort of scrubs anything that might
be identifiable
and coordinates the interviews the
actual interviewers
then write up written reports which are
again scrubbed
of identifiers all those reports are
collated along with scores and metrics
and passed on to a committee
who never meets the candidate and just
judges off
these reports and makes a decision
proponents of this approach claim
that decision is not biased but i will
tell you it is
the unconscious bias is hiding in plain
sight in every step
of that process there's bias when the
applicant writes their cv there's bias
when the screener
reads it and subtle aspects of language
and word choice or schools you went to
prioritize or inform that person's
prioritization
there's bias whenever any interviewer
hears a voice
or sees a face on zoom and all the work
that companies are busy doing
i'm sorry to say it it just hides the
bias in the system
it doesn't remove it and going through
this process
even as my ceo overruled my objections
it really required me to learn to see
the biases each of my employees had
so that i could compensate for it when
making those hiring decisions
and it really forced me to analyze my
own biases
and so there i was studying bias and
hiring and studying bias in machine
learning
and re-evaluating a year of my own
management decisions
and at the same time noticing how my
list of queer friends my community had
kind of shrunk
and i realized one day that even my own
primary partner
thought of me as a man and like manly
man
and sure i lived on a farm but
that didn't define my gender and i
chopped wood and that didn't define my
gender
and yet i began to to really
think more deeply about how gender is
this intersection
and how bias plays into it and the more
i looked in the mirror of my community
the more i realized the lens i was
seeing through and the lens i was seen
through neither one of them
reflected me nor was the impact i was
having
the impact i wanted to have you see at
work
i was meeting with execs from companies
in south america and middle east markets
where the company found the right
product fit
i could see every day how those
executives talked about women and i knew
if i came out
i couldn't do that job anymore i had to
make a choice
so i came out to my friends for my
birthday what was he gonna do
everyone was awesome and supportive and
you know one one partner gave me a tiara
everyone gave me some beautiful jewelry
um the best birthday gift was
the welcoming support from all of my
friends
but after that party i had to put on boy
clothes again and get back on a plane
and go fight with my ceo because
passionate debate is how business gets
done for some people um
i knew that i had to leave that company
it just took a little bit of time
and i i told myself i'll just take six
months off but let's be real i burned
out
i walked away with no idea whether i
want to or even be able to get back into
tech
let's pause for a moment now and smell
the roses because this talk
gets a little bit dark and it's about to
get kind of darker i want to talk about
what i've learned about bias
through that process and then in the
window of a sabbatical for a while
i did a lot of self-reflection and
therapy and naval gazing on questions
like why is my favorite color red
might seem totally irrelevant but bear
with me for another minute it's not
i was told as a kid that i was
colorblind
it's not that simple it's about 10
percent of the world is labeled as
colorblind but there's actually a whole
subclasses
um more than ten of them for different
variations of this
um different variations in the color
cones in our eyes people have a little
different reception
on their blue red or green or they have
none of one of those or they have extra
for me i just don't see red as much as
everybody else
the colors are shifted quite literally
my perception of the world is biased
because it deviates from the norm
and as i thought about this i thought
what about imagination and memory like i
perceive these two
without getting yet into the structural
or chemical differences between brains i
thought
well what's in there is just a garbled
pile of my own experiences but
somehow all of those memories affect my
judgment of everybody i meet today
we call this learning when it is
explicit or bias
when it's implicit and there's a real
time connection
between our physical senses our memories
and our impressions of people when i
imagine a rose it doesn't bring up
the smell or the memory of my
grandmother
but whenever i smell a rose it always
does
and that momentary flashback is going to
impact
my perception my impression of a moment
in time or a person who's wearing
rose scented perfume so our experience
of the physical world is completely
unique because it is
mediated by our own past
and i mentioned chemical state but
there's so much more going on in the
body
and i don't know i'm not always good at
eating sometimes i forget to eat
breakfast or lunch and
in the afternoon afternoon every email
i'm getting just seems kind of snarky
and my responses are definitely snarky
um
and more than like i'm gonna eat lunch
and i'll come back and and look at the
same email and i've learned not to send
my responses right away
um you ever do that you realize that
like it's it's really just my body
kind of making me grumpy right now so
more than just how i respond it actually
affects how i perceive the world
i'm walking by a rose and i'm upset or
hungry that rose isn't going to smell as
good
if i'm sad it might smell stronger so
all of this
all of this together is what i would
call perception or perception bias it's
the sum of our of
the actual sensory input which is unique
mediated by the state of our body
combined with whatever memories we have
in this framework by the way it isn't
new i just revisited
it while i was taking this this break
it was introduced to me as a kid through
meditation
and i kept coming back to this teaching
and during my during my break
the act of meditation is just the act of
observing our thoughts as they come in
as they go
being patient about it and
not getting attached to not getting sort
of caught up in those thoughts
the actual mechanism it works
to decrease the the coloring the impact
of our thoughts
on our perceptions just by observing
them
now sitting on a cushion is not the same
thing as meditation that's just where we
go to practice
to train our mental muscle it's kind of
like a gym
like you go to the gym to lift weights
you sit on a cushion to work out your
brain
and if meditation is increasing your
anxiety change it up slow it down
ask for help right if you're going to
the gym and it hurt you'd ask for a
physical trainer to give you tips on
your posture
do the same thing with your brain
so about a year after i left that role
and and came out
uh i started looking for work in the
tech industry again i'm like i'll try it
again
and i i thought by this point in my
career i should be passed all of that
exam by whiteboard theater
but i turned out i wasn't um i was asked
over and over again to pass
these sort of panel whiteboard exams by
old white men
and i say old white men not to
categorize
people in a negative way but draw
attention to a divide that i suddenly
found myself on the other side of
gender shouldn't matter but it does um
and it is
only through recognizing that we're
going to be able to improve things
i was suddenly really aware in a way i
had never been before
because i was aware that they were aware
and that they were uncertain of what to
do about that
i would inevitably be ushered to the one
single occupant bathroom
somewhere on campus far away from where
my interviews were happening
because they didn't know how to ask or
want to usher me to a
gen to a gendered bathroom
and i was
there's a type of bias called stereotype
threat that is the fear of reinforcing
whatever biases someone else might have
about us
since i couldn't know what bias they
might have had but it was obvious that
they were having some experience
my anxiety just filled in that gap and
things got rough for a while
so i'm going to warn you all the next
couple of minutes of this talk
might get a little bit extra rough and
then it'll get happy again i promise
there was a happy ending
um if you don't want to hear the actual
stories that i faced from some of these
tech companies
go ahead and mute i'll do a little wave
uh when i'm done and you'll see some
happy slides
a photo of deathcon um which i wish we
were all at this year but uh
yeah and so
oh yeah and names of companies and
people are scrubbed from all of this
um one uh one one colleague that i'd
worked with right just
like he was really excited that i'm hey
you know you're back in tech it's so
good to hear from you
we talked on the phone for an hour it
was super clear that
i could help his team grow and i knew
the tech they were using inside and out
the call ended with a really
enthusiastic yeah a recruiter's gonna
reach out to you right away
and i could tell they pulled up my
linkedin i'd already changed
uh details up there and suddenly a week
went by
and i checked in and i got a
cold email it's cool i just got a
time check i thought this was a 30
minute slot um let me skip through some
of these
to get to the points because this kind
of goes on for a while
four companies gave me um a sort of
really weird
uh pushback
and then one company i got kind of
grumpy after a year
of this um and about 30 companies and
one
one manager actually brought me in
afterwards and said look i really want
to hire you we need your talent
but i don't know how to hire someone
like you so
what changed right i am just as skilled
as i ever was
um i like to think i'm more
compassionate than i used to be
um but obviously the way people perceive
me has changed
but along the way i learned so much more
about myself and about infosec and i
wouldn't have had the chance to go to
defcon if not for this rather extended
break
um i landed a job at microsoft or now
running an open source project
but the real point i want to get to in
the last few minutes is
the internal changes i realized my own
perception of bias was
changing the more negative experiences i
had
the more i expected to have them now i
have to intentionally counter that bias
and also my hormones changed everything
everything got richer sounds became
deeper my imagination got clearer i
think
better i still see colors the same way
unfortunately and i kind of like it
um but flowers when i walk on the street
bring back different memories
it's really interesting how much that
changes
and how much i reconnected with an
internal sense of self that i've been
missing for
15 years and only my experience
i'm not suggesting it's universally true
but damn estrogen has been the best
antidepressant i've ever taken
it's not medical advice hormones are not
able
um but i'm starting looking into this
and i'm
to skip some of this because
i'm running low on time i thought i had
more time
[Music]
we are as a society still learning so
much about how
diverse our bodies are beyond a simple
gender binary
this chart was published about three
years ago in scientific american
represents some of the many pathways by
which biology develops not just along
binary lines about
one to three percent of the world's
population falls in the middle here
and how does this all relate to
technology
machine learning is fairly easy there
are quotes there
um creating a model that reproduces the
bias present in
current social economic or criminal
justice systems is really not hard you
feed in historical data
you get back out the bias the system
already had what is really hard
is not reproducing epistemic violence
against marginalized groups and that
work begins in our own heart
it starts by becoming familiar with the
edges of your own comfort zone
learning about other cultures other
people other way of life
learning to value those differences you
have to see them first to be able to
value them
learning to value the diversity in human
biology as our strength
my advice would be if you can go live in
a different culture you don't have to
move to a different country that's one
example
you can find other cultures in your own
city
by by living in one and embracing it for
a little while you can
look back and see your own culture
differently
and learn to see that delta it was part
of your bias before
and if you can kind of recommend it for
everybody
practice meditation you don't need to
find a quiet mountaintop to sit on
over time you learn to build a quiet
place inside yourself
find a tradition or a teacher or anybody
[Music]
and stick with it it is not easy to see
yourself
clearly and to understand your own
biases but it is
worth it it is the only way we improve
this society and make our companies more
inclusive
thank you so if there's still time
i'll take some questions otherwise you
can find me online ava thank you so much
for that talk that was excellent
um uh we have time for one quick
question um and red
asks how do you remove your own bias
when interviewing candidates
the unfortunate answer is you can't
we all are biased all of us all the time
it is inherent in being human
but by becoming directly aware of
my bias that is to say how my judgment
is different than the norm or different
than yours different than other people
on my team
i can do my best to compensate for it so
we can build
review panels that are inclusive and
welcoming and talk about that bias well
i don't know enough
to judge that does someone else here
know enough
for sure getting getting feedback from
other people having other voices that
yeah i yeah thank you great
thank you so much for speaking again
let's have a virtual round of applause
for ava
and with that uh i will be signing off
see you all next time