hello
everybody uh welcome back to stage three
of the diana initiative
my name is josh i'm your mc for this uh
talk
and uh today we're going to be hearing
mclarson
welcome before we do that i have an
announcement to make really quick
um our raffle winner for track three is
a sydney brazil
woohoo of applause you win
a new car i actually have no idea what
the what the prize is for the raffle so
you'll have to check in with nicole for
that um but uh yeah congratulations to
sydney
um and uh taylor who is with us today
is a multi-disciplinary investor product
manager and technologist
living in austin texas since 2011 he's
worked at large scale
hyper growth technology companies he
specializes in software as a service
products
and has experience with data science
machine learning mobile apps
cyber security web hosting and web apps
so like everything
basically experience with everything
when
not advising companies or speaking at
conferences about technology
taylor can be found geeking out with the
latest apple gadget skiing
or enjoying the expansive austin art
scene he also enjoys volunteering with
local human rights and lgbtq
organizations around central texas
as well as mentoring young technologists
looking to start careers in tech
and yeah please give a warm welcome to
taylor
um and uh i will note uh for this talk
we will be doing
uh question and answer um please throw
your questions in the chat
i will collect them and then we will do
q a at the end
um and uh yeah please take it away
taylor awesome hi everyone so my name is
taylor mccaslin
um you see my twitter handle there
digital sass feel free to tweet
questions um or feedback you've got for
me at this presentation
also at the end there'll be a link to
the slides as well
so this is one of my favorite topics to
talk about and it's
about how we build products that people
trust
when we think about technology products
they have the opportunity to really
allow us to do
new things that we were never able to do
before but
unfortunately a lot of technology
companies aren't taking that privilege
and responsibility to heart
and aren't building products that we can
trust
so this talk is intended to help you
understand how to design
privacy consent and security into your
products
so that people love them and use them
so a little bit about me before we get
started um
i am a senior product manager working in
secure at get lab i use he him his
pronouns
um you'll see my twitter handle
throughout this i've spent most of my
career focused on
ux at hyper growth enterprise scale
technology companies
so that really is the lens through which
i think about
products i want them to be easy to use
and i want them to be delightful to use
um part of that's probably from my
strange background i actually have a ba
in theater and dance
so i look at the technology world from a
very very different perspective
i also run a small angel investment
fund really focusing on companies who
get
the specifics of what we're going to
talk about today
right in their products i also
have worked at a number of companies
that i'm sure you're probably familiar
with there at the bottom
so today i want to talk about what is
trust
the types of trust that you can build i
want to look at
why we should care about trust in
general
um we'll look at a couple of examples
that i like to call
trust fails um so seeing companies who
have failed at building trust with their
customers and then talk about the
specifics about what it means to build
trust into your products so to start
let's talk a little bit about the word
trust it's something that it's a very
simple
word but it has very complex meanings
and it's really hard to describe if you
think about trust
it's really it's just something you you
know it when you feel it
and the way that i like to talk about
this is every single day if you get in a
car and you drive on a road
you're trusting that the other drivers
are gonna
obey the traffic laws and understand
that
you don't cross the double yellow line
in the middle of the road that's you
going out on a limb and trusting other
people to follow rules
that's kind of what this is about it's
about how
people actually think about and present
themselves
to the world and how we think about that
trust
so what is trust if it's hard to define
but you can feel it what are the
qualities that make up something that
you you think is trustworthy
so i want to talk about this through the
lens of two women who've done a lot of
work
in this field uh francis fay and rachel
botsman
um both of them have a lot of work on
trust i
suggest you go and google them and look
up all of their work
francis faye is uh from the harvard
business school
she's formally worked at uber as their
svp of leadership and strategy doing
a lot to fix the trust problems at uber
um rachel botsman is from the university
of oxford she's also the author of
a wonderful book that i highly recommend
who can you trust
um i'll talk about some of their
perspectives here in just a moment
because i think they each have a unique
take on what trust
means and i think it gives us a
framework to look at
how we build trust into our technology
products so let's start with francis
faye
she really approaches the topic of trust
in the the sense of
psychological trust trust between one
person and another person
and she thinks of trust as a triangle if
you think about
a stool with three legs that's very much
how francis thinks about
trust and her point in a lot of her
talks
is that if you don't have one of the
legs of this triangle of trust
the whole thing falls down and those
three sides are authenticity
logic and empathy and if you're missing
any one of these
you can't really establish trust or it
doesn't feel completely authentic
so let's talk about what each of these
three items mean
so her posit basically is that you're
more likely to trust me if the following
are true
you feel like i'm being authentic to you
that i'm not you know putting up a
facade or saying something that i don't
believe is true
um you you want to feel like your
products are authentic
second you want to sense that i have a
real rigor
in my logic and what i mean by that
basically is that
you see how i have come to the
conclusions that i have
it's not something that i just pull out
of a hat like magic um you want to see
that there's some
methodology to my logic and then thirdly
believe that my empathy is directed at
you
and this is one of the critical pieces
that
when you talk to someone who's very
empathetic it's really easy to trust
those people
because you just feel like they care
about you and this is a quality that's
really hard to translate into digital
technologies
but i think it's one that is really
worth looking at
so if those three things are true you're
likely to have trust now i do want to
talk
one quick bit about rigor in logic
there's a little trick here that a lot
of people don't realize
um there are sort of two different ways
that you can communicate
logic and ideas one of them is uh i'm
gonna take you on a journey and i'm
gonna tell you a story
and it's all gonna culminate into an
idea in fact that's a lot of what i'm
doing in this presentation today
the second approach is that you start
with the idea up front and then you talk
people through the journey of how you
got there both of these are
totally reasonable ways to explain how
you get to a conclusion
and show the rigor in your logic but
there's one trick to this
that unfortunately attention isn't
unlimited and so if you go with the
first
point where you sort of meander around
telling a story
before you get to your idea you'll lose
people's attention and your idea won't
actually come across this is
really important in technology where if
you don't help someone accomplish a task
immediately or help them understand what
you're trying to do
they will leave your product they won't
use it they will think it doesn't work
so i think it's a really important thing
to think through when you think about
your technology products
so moving on to rachel boxman she talks
about trust more in the sense of
communities so humans to humans rather
than a singular person to another person
and in rachel's book she talks about how
trust is a
confident relationship with the unknown
and i think that's a really interesting
way to think about trust
because it is very much about how do i
trust something that i
don't understand or i don't fully know
and when you think about technology
products
we don't know what's happening in the
background we don't know where our data
is going
how it's being accessed what's happening
with it so it is really
building trust with something that is
unknown and so the way that rachel talks
about this
is basically through the concept of
trust leaps basically how you
go from known to unknown in waters of
uncertainty
and that really is what trust is about
it's that
what has to be true for you to feel
comfortable with something
unknown when you have uncertainty about
it
so when we look into this um i like to
use this reference of
you've probably heard like in 1998 back
in the day before the internet got huge
people your parents would tell you don't
get in the car with strangers
and then fast forward to the internet
our parents would say
don't meet people from the internet
alone and then
when you start looking at some of the
technology that we've created like uber
and lyft we now
summon cars from the internet and get in
them with strangers and let them take us
places
so it's interesting to look at how trust
has evolved
and how technology has allowed us to
make these trust leaps
and unlock really interesting
capabilities
so the way that rachel talks about this
is what she calls the trust stack
and there's basically three premises to
this one
is to trust the idea you want to believe
in whatever it is you're trying to
accomplish in the system of
lyft um or airbnb for example i'm
trusting that i need a ride somewhere
and that someone is willing to take
take me there in their car with airbnb i
want a
cool place to stay and on the other side
someone has
a cool place and they want to offer it
to individuals
those are two pretty wild concepts
without
trust in them um so that sort of steps
us up to the next pieces trusting in the
platform
i'm not just going to go get in a car
with a stranger off the street
however lyft and uber have created a
platform where
we have profiles and we have ratings and
you've got the confidence that there's
been some rigor and some thought
put into who each of those people are
and you know that there's a rating
system
um tied to it airbnb is very similar i'm
not going to go to a random person's
house and stay there
but through airbnb i can look at ratings
and reviews
uh hosts can see my profile and see what
other hosts have said about me
so you start build that as you start to
build that trust in a platform
and then the third piece is trust in the
other users once you trust the idea
you trust the platform is a safe place
to explore that idea you then want to
trust that the
person that i'm getting in the car with
or the the person whose house
i'm staying at in an airbnb are
trustworthy people that
they're not crazy drivers that they
don't have spy cams hidden in their
apartments um so those are things that
the platforms then have to enable
and in many technology products that
comes across in
the frame of ratings and reviews or user
profiles
so you can see how technology products
are stepping in to fill in these gaps
so that they can help us build trust
with unknown parties
now the interesting thing and i've kind
of touched on this already is that trust
evolves
it changes it's not a stagnant concept
and this is something that i really like
the way rachel talks about this
so with her concept of trust leaps if
you apply them to different industries
like personal
transport or payments you can see really
clear
leaps of trust as we've expanded our
horizon
and gotten more trustworthy of unknown
context
so for example with personal transport
before you were really limited by how
far your horse and
your horse and your car could travel um
you really were in a small
community where um you kind of knew
the the relationships between there then
we introduced trains where you could
cross the country
there's no way you could know about what
was happening on the other side of the
country
you then see how that grows and adds to
itself you see ride sharing there that
we've talked a little bit about
when you look at the payment system
before in
before proto payments um we really had
this
idea of bartering that i could see that
you had a goat and i valued a goat
is something that i wanted um so it was
easy to barter
we then moved to fiat money and
currencies where rather than trading
goats
or cows or crops we were instead trading
coins
that represented value we've now moved
past the point of coins
actually having gold backing them in
banks somewhere and now we're using
credit cards and digital payment systems
that have
no tangible aspect in the real world
other than
we're trading bits between computer
systems that we trust
respect our net worth and values
so rachel continues to go on to talk
about how this trust evolves and the way
she talks about i think is really smart
um she talks about local trust is the
way that you have to start
peer-to-peer you then move to
institutional trusts where institutions
like banks
and governments sit in between
individuals
to help connect and provide
institutional levels of trust
we're now moving into a more distributed
functionality uh this is
i always joke that i don't want to refer
to crypto um
but it's true crypto allows us to start
doing things like
distributed payment systems um credit
cards even now have shattered the idea
of banks that i don't need a bank to
endorse me
to be able to swipe a credit card to use
um and purchase services so you can see
how that evolution of trust
changes and when you look at these
there's some really unique
properties about what it means to have
institutional trust and distributed
trust
institutional is opaque it's closed it's
a centralized system when you think
about a giant bank
or a government it's really unclear how
a lot of things work and happen and
function in the day-to-day
uh society it's it's very top-down
um you have to buy into that system and
believe that it works
whereas when you look at something like
distributed trust it's about
transparency inclusiveness this
decentralization
it's very much bottom up so it's
interesting when you're building your
technology products to think about
what stage of trust are you in and think
about the different levers that
make these types of trust choices true
for your technology product so the thing
that i
like about trust and technology is that
i believe that technology
accelerates the race the rate of trust
leaps and
further distributes trust so we're
taking those concepts that
francis and rachel have talked about and
applying them
to the speed at which technology evolves
it helps us
make those leaps um to trust platforms
that we otherwise would not have trusted
before
so now let's jump into the types of
trust
so this is a framework uh that was part
of a research project
from hsbc which is a bank
as you can imagine banks are very
interested in how they
uh how their customers perceive them and
trust them
um this this survey is from 2017 with 12
000 participants in 11 different
countries
so it's pretty wide ranging i encourage
you to go look at this study if you like
the framework
so basically they said there's sort of a
quadrant system of what it means to
trust something
on the x-axis you've got long-term trust
and
temporary trust and on the y-axis you
have very deep trust and very shallow
trust and this creates an interesting
matrix where
you've got things that are short lived
but deep which are functional you've got
those things that are long-term and deep
which are very much
love related you've got the shallow but
long-term these are things like
necessary needs and then you've got
the shallow and the temporary which is
really lustful types of technologies
so if we think about what are some
concepts that we have today
um not looking at technology you can
start plotting things
into this uh matrix so if you think
about
friends and family and loved ones they
are people that you have long-term
relationships with
and those relationships are deep they're
in that top
left corner of the graph
when you think about experts like your
doctors
websites that you consult your
smartphones
these are things that are relatively
short term
in terms of the span of your life but
there's still things that you have very
deep relationships with and then when
you look at the shallow but long term
you've got things like governments
work in financial institutions and then
the fun part is when you get to
temporary and shallow
you can start seeing some of the new
technology and startups coming there
things that pop up they're cool i try
them once and then they die
and it's really the key for these new
technologies to figure out
as they emerge how do they move up into
that top or right
to top right corner of something that
forms a long-term relationship with
someone and has
deep impact on them so let's go a step
further and look at some brands that are
actually doing this
today so up in the top left corner
you've got brands like apple and samsung
who have cultivated this almost
cult-like
fan a base where people just love their
products and will go
out of their way to use them when you
look at the necessary quadrant there are
things like financial institutions
none of us love our banks they're there
because we need a bank to put our money
into
we have shallow relationships with them
they're not things we think about other
than
it's where my paycheck goes um when you
think about the functional area this is
where a lot of technology startups live
today once they've
moved out of the emergent stage things
like weibo
google paypal amazon these are things
that we don't necessarily have a deep
relationship
and they're not very long term but they
still provide a functional value to us
so think about this framework where your
particular technology product might
actually
fall in this system so
why do we care about this what actually
is
worth thinking about trust with our
technology products
this is a survey again from that hsbc
survey where basically they
asked millennials generation x and baby
boomers about
what percent of their daily lives they
were concerned about
and what's really interesting about this
first of all is you'll notice there's
not
really a ton of difference between the
different generations
but one of the things i like to to focus
on is if you look at the areas with red
they're the areas where technology
is causing concerns for these people in
their daily lives
personal data being leaked that's a big
problem in the technology
industry bank account hacking debit card
cloning
identity theft email scams these are all
problems that technology have enabled
and now they're part of the largest
percentage of our concerns
day-to-day this for me as a product
manager and as someone who builds
technology and believes that technology
can create great change in the world
this concerns me
this is not that vision of how
technology can change the world for the
better
instead this is causing a lot of worry
and anxiety for people
i want to see this change so technology
distrust is causing much of the daily
worry that we have
and to me that's something that it
doesn't have to be that way
with a little bit of intention and a
little bit of responsibility we can
really make an
impactful change here
so let's take a look at a couple of
companies that have done this wrong
so these are what i call trust fails and
there's a really great website here that
has
a ton of data breaches and hacks so if
you go to that website and this is
actually
a trust of a test of your trust in me
will you visit that bitly link that i've
provided there i promise it just goes
the information is beautiful website
which has a really cool
infographic that you can explore and
look into
we'll talk about a few of these examples
but already you can see
the scale the scope the severity of the
data problems that we have in technology
is purely behind technology companies
just not being
responsible for the data and the
technologies that they create
i want to see this change so let's start
with the obvious one we've all heard
about equifax
we've all probably had to deal with
freezing our credit reports
one of the largest sensitive data
breaches
that happened in 2017. i won't spend
much time here but
lots of data was uh compromised in this
breach um and i think this was the
moment where we finally realized like
the scale at which this can happen
can be really wide ranging let's look at
something a little more sensitive though
um so i am an openly gay man um there
is an app called grindr which is
basically for you to connect with other
lgbtq
individuals um it's a hookup app let's
be frank
um the technology behind it though
provides you to do some interesting
things like remind
people to get tested for hiv and
unfortunately for grindr they
had a third party data leak where not
only
could someone track a person's
individual
gps location but they also could access
data about their hiv status
and could access that information in
unsecured api calls
this is hugely problematic so you take
an
app that's intended to connect an
at-risk minority group
and then don't put the correct privacy
controls in place
and don't take responsibility for the
data you're collecting
you're putting people at real risk
for example if i were to travel to
countries where i could literally be put
to death
and my location can be easily found in
health
data around my hiv status could be
exposed
we're talking about legitimate safety
concerns for me
as well as potential impacts to my
insurability as a person
if data about my health status were to
be leaked in a way that i
couldn't control um so these data
breaches are
really sensitive and our technology
products are just
causing us to put more and more
data out into the world and in some
cases data that
we don't even realize is leaving the
safety
of our own devices if we look at
facebook we've all heard about the
cambridge analytica
um breaches were basically facebook
didn't put the correct
controls around the data they collected
so
a company called cambridge analytica
scanned
facebook profiles for what is called uh
psychographic
data to profile people and then that was
used
by russia to influence the u.s election
of course this is an election year in
the united states
and again this becomes a really
interesting um and concerning problem
about how accessible our data is
on the internet and how that can be used
to manipulate us
continuing on with facebook um they also
have
other issues so they've got a product
called portal
which is basically a video camera that
will follow you around as you move
and when they release this pro or this
hardware
project i think it's a really cool
concept
but when they released it even their
executives and their
uh privacy policies didn't make it clear
if facebook could use the audio in the
video that it was collecting
um in those video calls to do ad
retargeting to you
um an example of how a technology
company
created an interesting and novel
technology but
then didn't put the correct controls
around it
to create that cycle of trust
where people would actually use this i
personally will not be purchasing a
portal device much less putting it in my
home and letting facebook collect all of
that data
continuing on there was a pew research
study done specifically on facebook and
trust
and they found that only six percent of
adults trusted facebook
sixty percent said they don't trust
facebook to protect their data at
all and three quarters of adult facebook
users have taken
some action to curtail their facebook
use
this is a great example of how if you
don't build trust with your customers
or if you actively break trust with your
customers
they'll go do something else this is
where
trust actually turns into very real
financial concerns
for your business
um i laugh at this photo every time it
circles around social media so this is
zuck in his office
um joking but if you zoom into his
computer there in the bottom left corner
you'll notice zuck himself doesn't even
trust the camera and the audio ports on
his computer
this is one where if even a billionaire
who runs facebook doesn't trust the
hardware and the systems that
even his company helped build how does
how can any of us
individually have any chance at securing
ourselves and our data
amazon itself has struggled with some
privacy concerns there was
a very strange story about a portland
couple who were having a private
conversation in their living room
and then got a phone call from their
friend who
said basically the alexa device was
streaming
their conversation to her alexa device
basically in their conversation alexa
had misinterpreted some of the
wording as signal words
and then started a connection call
that feature of amazon echo was
actually on by default for customers and
it wasn't until recently that they had
changed that
and made it an opt-in feature so an
example of rolling out
new and novel functionality that some
people might use but
by turning it on by default creates this
opportunity for people to have things
happen that they don't expect
um alexa and amazon have moved forward
on
other interesting devices like this ring
device and sunglasses
that have alexa built into them so now
it's not even just a stagnant hardware
device
in a home it's things that can be
anywhere on a person
um live and recording conversations and
doing
who knows what with them um so it's
interesting to see
how these technology companies really
have to grapple with concepts of trust
so that brings us to what does it mean
to build trust in tech products
so going back to our framework from the
bank
if we look at some of the technology
concepts that we've got it
and we touched on some of these earlier
about how
um brands that can engage fans create
this like
uh die-hard fans who go out of their way
who stand in line
for days and weeks to purchase the new
devices that come out those are like
concepts of love
you've got someone you've created
technology that people love so much that
they go
out of their way to go and get it when
you think about functional items like
our phones and even our wearables these
are devices that we
wear on our person and have on us at all
times
they're very personal but they're
devices that when the next one comes out
or when the screen breaks on this
they're gone and you move on when you
look at the necessary
um section you've got things that are
high switching costs
uh banks again are a good example of
this nobody wants to go and switch banks
because it's a pain to do
creating a new account moving money
between it changing all of your paycheck
uh etfs uh it's just something where
it's not a very deep connection but
because of high switching costs we let
it be long
uh things that are in the necessary
column tend to not be things that are
super trustworthy or
have much thought put in them because
they know that you can't go anywhere and
it's a pain to do
we're seeing technology change some of
that um and then the the lust
category you see things like low value
luxury items handbags
um as seen on tv type products and when
you think about all of these different
types of
technologies and how they impact our
world there are ways that you can break
trust with these things so when you
think about this
think about things like scandals or
betrayals
for people you love a betrayal could
break that trust
for companies that you love their
products for example i'm a big apple fan
if apple had a giant privacy scandal i
might be less willing to be
a fan of apple products when you look at
functional items it becomes much more
about breakage
or fading fads i'll tell you a quick
story about
um not the apple watch but the uh
the fitness band one of the companies
basically was
aggregating fitness data and they
released a blog post that basically said
huh really weird uh in time-adjusted
data we've noticed that around seven or
eight o'clock in the evening there's a
lot of activity
um and then they wrote a blog post about
people having uh
sex um that's not how i want my personal
data to be used even in an aggregated
form
it feels invasive um and with these
devices that literally are on our bodies
that are listening to our heart rates
that are
listening to audio or recording video in
the room
they're very sensitive things and when
something that we don't intend to be
be public becomes public that's a moment
of broken trust
so lots of different ways that you can
fail at trust
but there's a lot of things that you can
do to actually build it and i believe
that trust can be a fundamental
differentiator for technology products
and we'll look at a couple examples of
technology companies that get this right
and use it as a core differentiator for
their products
so we've talked a lot about what trust
is
how do you build it between people and
between communities but what about
humans and machines
as we're building these technology
products how do we help
individual people who may not be super
technical
understand how the systems that we build
and the technology products that we
release
work in a way that they actually trust
them
and so i want to take us back to francis
and rachel's frameworks of
building trust through authenticity
through empathy
through logic looking at rachel's
framework for adding competence
reliability and honesty into our
products
and what that actually looks like in
practice so
to start i want to talk through a few
examples of technology products that
actually do a good job of this and
you'll notice
this is a bit in conflict with some of
the privacy problems that i mentioned
earlier but one thing that the amazon
echo device does do is that it's
very clear when it's on when alexa is
listening
the blue light is on and it lets you
know that it's listening
that's a really great example of using
technology like the light up
ring around the edge of the device to
make it
extremely clear how technology is
functioning
when you've got it muted it's turned red
and you've got a
good sense that the device is not
listening
we can go into the problems about do you
actually trust the hardware behind all
of this and the lights actually mean
what they think they do
but having clarity in the technology
that's super clear
that even a child can understand if
your listening device is actually
listening or not is really
clever consistency is another way to
build trust
with people um i look at this from the
apple human interface guidelines where
providing consistent messaging helps
build and train people with how to
interact with your technology product
it doesn't matter what this modal says
at all i know the default action is the
blue button
and it's probably what triggered the
action that i'm trying to accomplish
um it's this consistency that allows you
to start
understanding and feel like you've got
control
in a system if every single modal that
popped up
looked different and had different
button styles it would be a lot harder
and take a lot more cognitive load to
understand how that technology product
functions
the next one is prove value so with
technology products they're very
fungible
unless they're accomplishing something
for us we're going to move on and use
something else
so in your products make it clear what
value you're creating for your users
one of the things a great example of
this i think is my apple watch
at the end of the day i always check my
activity rings to see how i'm doing
and if i'm having a lazy day my watch
will tap me on the wrist and say hey
stand up go do act something active
it's a way where you can be validated
with the technology and how it's helping
you improve your life in some way
the next one is a fun little story about
building common sense
um there are some major travel platforms
and there's a fun
story about a company where someone
typed into
a travel search engine uh trip to paris
and what they intended was a trip
to paris france as most of us i assume
would think the word
paris would it mean instead the tool
provided them uh information about a
trip to paris texas
which is not as glamorous as paris
france and is almost certainly
not what that user was trying to
accomplish um
because they were in a rush or for
whatever reason they ended up buying the
tickets
to paris texas rather than paris france
it's an example of where just with a
little bit of intuition and common sense
you can make your technology products
seem smarter
and actually help users accomplish what
you intend to do
so let's recap some of the things that
we've talked about these are very much
educational related things prove your
products
competency and show your logic make it
clear what's happening and why
set expectations along the way um to
help
give people a sense of what you're
actually accomplishing with your
technology product
explain and prove value you've probably
heard the term of a 10x technology
product that's something that you're
willing to use it because it makes the
experience
10x better than what it is today
i think this is one when you look at
things like productivity apps
do they make your accomplishing tasks
and goals
10x is easy as just writing down a
sticky note with
um checkboxes on it probably not and
that's why i've never found a
productivity tool
that works better than my sticky note
system
next build consistency consistency
builds
confidence and even if your product
isn't fully fleshed out if it's
consistent i have a sense as a user of
how it works and that helps build that
consistency
or that helps that build that confidence
for me also
be relevant contextualize those
interactions
if i'm searching a travel website for
paris assume i mean paris france
not paris texas build in those common
sense
um gates to help people understand what
you're trying to accomplish
and again like i mentioned earlier
simplicity wins
one of my favorite things is to see
alexa devices with these red circles on
because it's super
clear what the intention of the device
is
at that time it's not listening to what
you're doing
and i think it's very hard to get
simplicity that's so simple
a child can understand that when the
light's red it's not listening
and when it's blue it is
let's talk about design empathy for a
moment so this is a screenshot from the
spotify app
from a few years ago um i was trying to
play some music and i i literally have
no idea what's going on here
i don't know why it's not playing music
it's given me no information about why
it can't play the song that i've chosen
build empathy into your designs as it
turned out i had a vpn turned on
at the time because i was traveling and
my vpn had disconnected from the
internet
nothing about this error screen helps me
as a user understand
why this app is not functioning the way
i want it to
provide context and design empathy with
your users
it'll build that trust with them this is
very frustrating but had it just
said can't connect to the internet
that's something that can
queue me into what's wrong and how i can
go about fixing it
next is building in helpful tool tips
so this is a feature that that mailchimp
added to their sign-in form
um and they found that users were happy
were struggling logging into the right
account so they put in this
warning message about hey we can't find
the account that you
mentioned that you're trying to log into
here now before all of the security
people say oh my god you can't do that
you're gonna expose account
information and you create an
enumeration mechanism to determine
if someone has an account or not behind
the scenes
mailchimp has implemented web
application firewalls
rate limiting and other secure
technologies
to not show this message to um things
like
bots or scrapers that are hitting this
page frequently
they've put technology protections in
place
allowing them to expose usability
friendly
options to help users get logged into
their accounts
and i think what's really cool about
this is they've taken a technology
problem and turned it into a real value
proposition
not only does this help the user get
access to their account
but it also gives mailchimp really great
uh telemetry data about attackers who
are trying to enumerate
accounts that's something their fraud or
abuse team can take action on
yeah so we talked about that um the next
piece is
automatically updating part of the cool
thing about technology products is
you can have them auto update while i
don't like google chrome
it does get auto update right i don't
have to think about chrome being up to
date it automatically updates in the
background
helping take some of the load about
updating technologies off the plate of
the user
is a way to help you build trust with
them
but you've still got to be able to
handle problems and errors
in a recent press release or a press
conference that
amazon did for some new alexa devices
they wanted to introduce the concept of
helping people understand why alexa did
something wrong
so you can actually ask your device why
did you do that and it'll explain
what happened that caused that trigger
many of the devices now allow you to
look at trigger words so you can
understand
why something has turned on or turned
off
so a fun story here is
when you think about failed interactions
in
human space in reality in irl
interactions are one-off when you go to
a restaurant and you have a bad
experience you don't apply that to the
entire restaurant
or to all restaurants in the world
instead you say
i want to talk to a manager to make this
right
with technology products you don't get
to talk to a manager
you have to put your best foot forward
and if you fail at that you can really
damage a brand as we saw earlier with
facebook
the damage has been done with people
trusting them
and people are looking to other
technologies other than facebook
so with some of these concepts this is
really about building security into your
apps it's about
building reliability and empathizing
when things go wrong
so make sure that your product does what
it promises
ask for consent before you collect data
secretly
if you do collect data secure the data
that you're entrusted with and if you
don't have the security investment to be
able to
protect that data don't collect it
make security easy set smart defaults
and handle problems empower users rather
than
then blame them when something goes
wrong help them fix problems and it'll
create technology that
your customers are more likely to trust
and use so let's keep looking at some
examples of this
so apple gets transparency and consent
really right
they're a privacy-minded company in fact
that's why i feel comfortable wearing an
apple watch on my wrist
all the time that's why i have all my
apple devices because it's a company i
trust with my data their privacy page
is top notch i highly recommend you go
to apple.com
privacy they talk you through how
they've built
privacy and consent into their
technology in fact i love this icon
of two people shaking hands because that
is really
what trust is about it's about
understanding each other and what you're
trying to accomplish
next is privacy controls if you go into
the settings app
on your twitter application you'll
notice there's
lots of different settings and what's
cool about this
and what i like about the way twitter
has done this is they've
put real context and given you control
about how your data
is used if you haven't go take a look at
those privacy controls and think about
how you can apply them
to your technology projects then we've
got the fun one we've got
google who on their privacy page
lead with the top header we do not
sell your personal information to anyone
and
i know technically what they're trying
to say here
but no one would agree with this
statement at all
google is absolutely using your data to
sell
ads um which while not maybe
exposing or selling your information to
third parties
they're providing access to your data
so that they can sell ads um definitely
be really cognizant about the messaging
of your technology products
um here's a fun app that i actually
really like um it's called sleep cycle
but what you'll notice there in the
middle is that link icon with the name
emil emil was one of my co-workers
previously
and we were at a convention in a hotel
and this app has the concept of a
partner link that broadcasts your device
name
on the network that you're on so it can
pair with your partner
and cancel out movements in your your
bed
um i do not share a bed with my
co-workers i was alone
in a hotel room using a vpn and yet this
um was broadcasting emel's device
to mine and mine to his they had since
added uh this feature with which was on
by default previously they now have
a modal that lets you opt into this
feature and explains it to you
but this was really terrifying to me the
first time
anybody could have used this app to
enumerate if i was on a network
somewhere
actively sleeping um next you've got
things like smart defaults um if you've
never
looked at your options in your iphone
um go to settings face id and passcodes
and take a look at how much data you're
allowing to be accessed when your phone
is locked
this is a view of what my settings are
and i encourage you to potentially
adopt some of these settings to reduce
the amount of data that you're
allowing someone to have access to when
your device is locked
here's an example of where with apple's
approach to privacy privacy is still
really hard to get right
in their new os releases they require
additional security permissions to give
applications
access to your data and unfortunately
the way this was implemented
creates this nightmare of pop-ups and
modals that
are really hard to understand when i
upgraded to this version this is an
actual screenshot of my system
and all of the um
privacy prompts that were brought up
this is a lot of work for me as a user
to have to
think through what i'm approving so
think about the user experience of those
solutions so in recap be honest and act
with authenticity
with your technology products um be
transparent with the data that you
collect and use
provide smart controls and consent and
for people to consent or object to
collecting data
handle when people opt out of providing
data
set smart privacy defaults don't auto
opt people
into new features that might have
privacy concerns
them explicitly let people know when
behaviors
or features change in a way that might
impact their privacy
and i think finally to close this out go
and talk to
actual people who use your technology
the things they will tell you will blow
your mind
just having a conversation about how
they use your technology
will open a brand new door of all of the
different things that you can
you should consider as you're building
trust into your technology products
um and really listen deeply
empathize with them ask why ask them why
again
um really get to the heart of their
questions and
the ways that they're using your
technologies i promise you
if you do five of these sessions you
will be shocked at the things you'll
learn
from your users and how they think about
and use your technology products
so that closes out today i think that
while building trust
isn't easy it's how you can set yourself
apart
and really differentiate your products
um
that concludes my talk today if you'd
like to see the slides or dig into some
of the examples
you can find the slides at that link
there so i think it's time for questions
awesome thank you very much taylor that
was excellent talk
um so i was able to collect one question
and uh so how accountable is distributed
trust
if that distribution makes attribution
potentially more difficult and i'm and
i'm assuming attribution of like an
account to a person
so the way that i'll talk about this is
that when you think about
um the way that rachel talked about
trust leaps
part of the problem with technology is
that
as we're adding new concepts like
distributed trust
we introduced these new types of
problems
about how you think about some of these
distribution and consent mechanisms
part of the the point about privacy is
that you shouldn't have enough data
to be able to go and make some of these
concerns so you've got to think about
in your product what is it that you can
do how do you collect
data in a way where you don't need to
know the specifics but that you can take
action on those types of things
we're still very new with a lot of these
distributed concepts
um strangely we're breaking some of that
uh down
in things like cryptocurrency we're
already seeing
like the u.s government have to grapple
with how do you do
taxing on a cryptocurrency that's
completely anonymous
um as you remember uh twitter recently
was
um had a security incident where people
were posting crypto
addresses on public figures even
put uh political figures twitter
accounts
and it's a strange thing to grapple with
about you've got
this attack framework where people have
complete anonymity but that you can
still
gain context and pieces of information
to piece that story together
i still don't really believe that
anything is private these days
even if you're using crypto or whatever
vpn like there you still leave digital
footprints
um so i think it's about thinking when
you're building your products
what data are you collecting where is
that data going how are you using that
data
and how can you have as little data as
possible
um the way that i think about this when
i talk with my technology teams
is if we don't absolutely
need the data to accomplish whatever it
is we're trying to do
don't ask for it it's one other thing we
have to secure and protect
it's more storage we have to pay for
it's more
security that we have to protect things
with um
and if it doesn't really provide value
for the product that we're offering
why collect it sure sure
thank you so much taylor that was an
excellent talk let's give a round of
applause virtually
thanks everyone feel free to tweet your
questions at me um
and again the slides are there at that
link i'll tweet that link as well
thanks for your time today and i hope
you enjoy the rest of your
diana initiative virtual conference cool
to you taylor
bye