all right
everybody so we are unfortunately
at the end let me
share up this slide deck
and see if this works as planned
because we've been having technical
issues today haven't we
so uh good news we had
zero incidents uh and three warnings
from the uh security team there were
other warnings from moderators in chat
but nothing
too major so i think that's uh pretty
successful
uh so i'm excited we also
had record breaking one thousand hundred
registration uh 462
students um and out of that we had
68 sponsors 76 speakers and villages
and 132 staff and volunteers we were
able to give out more than 200 free
tickets thanks to the people who
gave like 5 10 50
extra dollars when they bought their
tickets as well as defend khan
for sponsoring a chunk of those tickets
we had our badge workshop this year
which instead of having our solder maker
village
we actually had five separate workshops
to walk you through making your own
badge from off the
shelf parts and there were awesome
participants i think everybody
managed to get through and get blinky
bits at the end
our lock picking workshop run by
lockpick extreme had
40 enthusiastic and engaged participants
that mostly all got through all the
different locks that they had in their
pits
career village had 34 one-on-one reviews
and interviews
one live crowd-sourced resume review i
am intrigued i missed this
i wish i had seen this and one live
informal interview
there were hundreds of questions
answered and i know that channel was
hopping the entire time
for our capsular flag competition
sponsored by mongodb
we had many participants and about 20
different prizes
now this is the part you all care about
right so
daddy cocoa man bad boy 17 and kronos
were the top three
winners there with over 4 000
points in room each so congratulations
to the winning teams um i believe the
ctf team will be reaching out to you
if you don't hear anything you can
always dm us on twitter and we will get
you sorted out
uh so for those of you who were jamming
out to the tunes and cracking through
and finding all the flags
congratulations i hope everybody enjoyed
it
so we of course want to thank
all of our sponsors without them we
couldn't have had this platform
which although it's got some ui and ux
issues and isn't quite intuitive i do
think it did work out we were able to
bounce between different stages go to
the different villages
hit the expo hall do some networking so
we couldn't have afforded that being you
know
running our non-profit and having this
platform without them
you'd really be shocked how much it can
be to run a virtual event
uh and if you think that's a lot wait
until you hear how much it takes to run
our event in vegas
so amid the uncertainty of
they still took time and money out of
their budgets to help us out
i specifically want to call out mongodb
microsoft salesforce verizon
amazon information security elearn
security
remediant intel thermo fisher scientific
coinbase and n8
so we had a bunch of raffles too
everyone should
be getting emails from me or have
already gotten
emails from me these slides will be
available later so if you spot your name
here
congratulations and i will be reaching
out to the email address on the ticket
link and we will arrange how we get
these to you
we've got exclusive tdi beach towels
there were only a certain number of
these printed
we had some of them go to our keynotes
and then we are going to have some of
them go as prizes and other than that
you can't get them limited edition we
have a
clock kit sparkle invaders and
an iot weather camera system
we also have two tickets and workshop
credits for b-sides orlando
e-learn security sponsored four
different
course sets so to those four winners
i hope you have some free time to learn
uh it's gonna be amazing
wi-fi pineapple tetras thanks to hack
five
and gift cards thanks to no starch
we had our keynote winner uh
so we've got bill and niday and if i
mispronounce your name i greatly
apologize
and we've got uh gwen for
this the pen testers blueprint uh triba
hackers book and a three months premium
we hack purple subscription so once
again
tons of things to learn i love that our
society is always
learning and sharing things with one
another if you haven't
followed a lot of these personalities on
twitter they've got
the tribe of hackers podcast and they're
just constantly
helping out and educating people just
like in our amazing keynotes like
kirsten was dropping all the knowledge
bombs
on us so also if you want to leave
feedback about our speakers go into
sketch you don't need to make an account
for sketch we've been having problems
with that if it prompts you just
ignore it click on the talk that you're
interested in and then click the
feedback
survey button if this becomes a problem
i'll just publish a link
in our twitter to all of the talk
feedback links
not the most elegant but we'll do
whatever it takes
also we want to know how we did what did
you like what did you not like what
ideas do you have for next year
we'll tweet it we'll email it please
take the time the questions are all
optional so if you don't want to answer
one just skip it
also i really need to thank the
community
we raised fifteen thousand dollars
in donations from individuals which
remember that whole
multiple hundreds of tickets free that's
thanks to you
so you all support us and then we in
turn try and support
everybody that is a part of this
community and needs that support
the free tickets went to people that
were students military veterans
people who were underemployed and
unemployed
and of course there wouldn't be a reason
to show up
unless we had some things for you to do
so
thank you to our keynotes and our
speakers it takes
hours to prepare and hone in exactly
what you're going to say
to put together your slides and
that is a lot of time and effort and we
deeply appreciate you
taking the time to do that to come here
to spend your friday and saturday with
us and make sure that the community is
learning all of the things that you know
and just raising everybody up like that
it's amazing
and last certainly not least the
hundreds of volunteer squad we've got
um we put out the call everyone answered
it
it was a bit chaotic but there were over
100 friendly
people who donated their time to bounce
around answer your questions hang out on
social media review your resumes
so if you know anyone who volunteers at
any conference give them a hand
finally i got a couple more things and
this one i
really hope sticks with you our slogan
this year was breaking boundaries bite
by bite
boundaries can come in many forms
self-imposed and those
imposed by your company even those
imposed by your society
when faced with problems it can seem
daunting
the most common advice is to pick one
specific area of a problem and go after
that
take that bite break it and then go to
the next
remember it only takes a bite to
overflow a buffer
we can break the systems that are
stopping us
this year many of us face a host of
different boundaries
problems and systemic issues i hope that
at this event you were able to make some
friends who in the future could be part
of your support network
and find the tools and skills to raise
up yourself and raise up
others and since we're normally located
in las vegas i
am going to make a specific call out to
my peers in the united states even
though i'm currently in canada
diana initiative stands firm with all of
our brothers and sisters
black brown trans queer
non-binary and all underserved
communities
this year is exposed to the masses the
trauma you have all been systematically
experiencing for generations
you've been breaking boundaries bite by
bite and laying
the road to equality before us
you matter and we hope to partner with
all of you
in building not just equality but equity
within our industry
so we do hope to see you next year
it's going to be on august 5th and 6th
circumstances willing once again at the
westin hotel in las vegas
no casino and no smoking
and uh we do have a final raffle draw
which i did
right before i came up on here and then
don't forget to go
in the reception area there's free swag
and discount so edit copy edit paste
them into a notepad file
we might also email it out to the
attendees and of course
join us afterwards in the networking
area for the social hour
so karen you won pentester's blueprint
three months premium subscription to we
hack purple
and your choice of any of the four tribe
of hackers books
thank you everybody and i hope you have
a great rest of
the event