alright alright alright the our keynote
this morning is someone you probably all
know Amanda Berlin is the author of the
defensive Security handbook world
renowned author
Guinness Book of World Records holder
for the largest game of pong ever played
at code mash all-around amazing person
trampoline expert and I'm sure you don't
know that but trampoline expert so
Amanda's gonna give us a talk yeah yeah
obviously man is going to give us a
amazing keynote here about hackers hugs
and drugs everybody give around a round
of applause to Amanda she's an amazing
speaker and fun and friend ahead yes
trampoline expert I was professionally
trampolining in my backyard and yeah
that's why I'm on crutches
sorry so welcome to converge this is
great this is what yours converges this
like 2004 all right here for heard so
I'm gonna be talking a little bit about
mental health which nobody likes to talk
about right so I want to start out and
with a little bit of a story about how
about eight years now um I was married
had two kids living in a really really
shitty town in a really shitty house my
second son was about a year old and my
oldest was seven our roof leaked there
was like mold in the house and animals
running everywhere and it was just
absolutely horrible so without going
into too much detail of a marriage
itself I didn't really have any control
at the time of what happened in my life
or my children's life
I remember the one night that's
something that like something actually
clicked and I realized something was
wrong with me I was in the shower just
had gotten out and like broke down on
the floor sobbing
couldn't speak this is exactly how I
felt like everything in my head was
static
like I couldn't physically speak it's
not like I didn't want to talk I
physically hurt to think of any coherent
thought after I calmed down an hour
later I realized what kind of had
triggered it and it was at my shower
curtain was Bernie stupidest thing ever
at the time right it just seemed really
immature that I should break down for an
hour over something that tiny excuse me
what's going on they're coming so
looking back at all of that now a lot of
the anxiety problems that I had and at
the time I didn't know it was anxiety
were because of that lack of control and
just the dirt and just it just drove me
crazy now I live in a great house and
that's clean and other than not being
able to do much cleaning now you know I
realized that that was one thing that
really tripped off my anxiety but I
thought at the time too like once I
realized that that I can handle all of
this on my own like I've never been able
to uh not overcome a problem that I had
been faced by myself you know teen
pregnancy or whatever and I just did it
right I never really asked for any help
and you know I was at the ripe old age
of 25 I shouldn't have all the answers
myself right so why in the world am i
bringing this up at information security
conference one because I consider this
like this is our community consider a
lot of you my family more so than a lot
of blood relatives that I have this
isn't the first group of people that
have truly understood me like either
being bullied when I went
growing up or the anxiety problems that
I have all that kind of stuff when I
begin tweeting posting stuff on Facebook
you wouldn't believe the amount of
people that showed up like in my DMS and
at conferences just talking to me about
the same kind of struggles that they had
so I thought I would go ahead and put a
bunch of research behind that and see if
the trend that I was seeing had any you
know actual doctors looking into it a
lot of people also struggle and struggle
alone like I did for the good part of
ten years and those are the kind of
people that look like they have it
together just like everybody's super
surprised when you say you're depressed
and they're like oh but you're always
happy and laughing and whatever so
looking back in my life after I finally
got some help I'd been struggling since
my teens and it had gotten progressively
worse but it was always there and always
will be we never want to admit
anything's wrong with us right and
what's the first step to almost any
12-step program the admitting you have a
problem right accepting it but if you
accept it and stop there it's just gonna
make you more angry and depressed and
it's not really gonna do anything you
can't just accept there's a problem you
have to accept that you need help in one
form or another and that's what I
finally did after ten years not dude not
only two people in our industry have the
normal stresses of like an everyday job
I mean you have life stress money stress
all that kind of stuff kind of building
on top of each other but all of us are
extremely passionate about what we do
it's not just a nine-to-five job anymore
this is our career our passion our hobby
none of your none of you are here
because you have to be at least I hope
not
otherwise this would be really
depressing
yeah the InfoSec community is really
hard to compare to any other we put
stress on ourselves in form of research
learning teaching building our careers
and you know we take it from our bosses
our family you know all those external
entities as well and a majority of our
roles cater to the fact that we like to
sit behind a computer and not talk to
anybody I know mine does I have to force
myself to leave the house to interact
with people and then you can add to that
roles like insert response or any type
of law enforcement role that has to do
with child trafficking or abuse cases
any of that ocean that goes around that
and and you know if you're depending on
what level clearance you have you might
not be able to ever talk to anybody
about it so let's talk about a little
bit of the research I was able to do
next when I first thought about talking
about this topic I went to Google and
searched mental health issues and STEM
fields and most of them were about women
so after removing women from the search
it took it from 6 million articles down
to 2 million and when it comes to mental
illness illness really the sexes are
different right women are more likely to
suffer from anxiety or depression and
men tend towards substance abuse and
anti-social disorders but of course
nobody ever wants to talk about the men
even though they make up 70% of our
industry and really looking at the crowd
it's like 95 percent but the hypothesis
I was trying to make is that it seems
like people in stem have a higher rate
of mental health issues at least from
the feedback I was getting from people
which turns out there's a few studies
that prove this and I read way more
medical journals than I ever thought I
would in my life the first one is the
Savannah IQ interaction hypothesis which
I have a quote from it states the
finding of an association between
progressively increasing risk of bipolar
disorder
and high arithmetic intellectual
performance is rather surprising they
explained that arithmetic tests not only
take mathematical skills and rapid
information processing and then they
would also they say no high scores in
that field with such rapid processing
power may also share a tendency that
experience mania and a high state of
focus and psychomotor activity so this
this entire study that's just based on
people in stem and the fact that you're
more likely to be messed up so the
Savannah IQ also talks about people with
higher intelligence tending to
self-medicate medicate with alcohol drug
is more than the average person it kind
of shows how much research the writers
of mr. robot put into it so how many of
you have watched mr. robot right it's
great show if you haven't watched it I
highly recommend but without any
spoilers the main character Elliott
actually micro doses with morphine right
to keep himself saying and then he uses
suboxone to kind of like take him down
from it from any with withdrawal he
might experience so why I don't
recommend that in a professional
capacity at all it's a basically a good
gist of the part of that paper so let's
move on to some more statistics not only
does the city IQ talk about the smarts
to depression correlation but there was
also a recent study done at Berkeley
that showed that between 42 and 48
percent of Berkeley PhD candidates
suffered from depression to suffer from
depression and that's compared to the
seven percent of the normal population
so which makes sense in the Google
results there were significantly more
results involving women because one we
report it more and two people are more
likely to focus on minorities I don't
want to try and focus on men in this
talk but I mean technically you're the
minority in this case you're not
reporting it as much so what do they say
it's not like you guys are not having
issues men are just reporting it was so
I know this is the u.s. and this what I
found out is I gave this talk in New
Zealand last year and this didn't really
matter to them right but what what I
wanted to point out with this is that I
I'm not really sure if it's yeah this is
these are US numbers but is it you know
we live in you know fairly alright
country right depending on your views
you know we're able to come here without
anybody shooting at us most part but is
it is it just us is that the rest of the
world that's like that I don't really
know he wasn't able to find a whole lot
on other countries all of this and we
think that everybody kind of has it
together better than we do ourselves I
know I'm guilty of it
a handful people Hardy Don talks and
research on impostor syndrome and that
could go hand-in-hand with mental health
as well
so imposter syndrome if nobody knows
what it is
it's the feeling that you don't belong
here because you don't know enough or
you've not you know the right
certifications or you don't have the
right background or why are these people
paying me this money into what I don't
think is worth this kind of money or I'm
never going to make it in this field
because I don't know all of these things
all of that leads to all of that is
impostor syndrome and a lot of us a lot
of us suffer from that constantly
sometimes more
more than others every time somebody
asked me that give a keynote oh my god
no idea why they want me if they're
talking you feel like you're drowning
and everyone around you kind of just has
their together I know I can think
of a lot of people that have talked me
through situations like this as well of
all of the times that I've been limited
because of my brain deciding to go on
some crazy direction I found where the
US Preventive Services Task Force
recommends that all adults be screened
for depression which is extent
astounding to think of when I read that
my mind went back to the whole us thing
right is it really just us citizens is
it because of our first world problems
honestly our government partly doesn't
have a doesn't help a whole lot in that
aspect but in the grand scheme of things
we don't really have it that bad but
that doesn't really matter when you're
like huddled on the floor in a crying
mess because that's just you and you
know that has absolutely nothing to do
with you know and any of the stuff
that's going on in the world so I'm
gonna dive into the different types of
mental health issues and their
characteristics I'm not going to cover
everything because that would take all
day
but I'll cover some of the more common
ones when I talk about the symptoms of
the diseases pay attention
they don't just include all of the stuff
going on in your head but it's also a
lot of physical manifestations of that
kind of stuff so first there's social
anxiety is disorder or general anxiety
disorder which I definitely definitely
have a fear of situations where you
might be judged like standing up on
stage in front of everybody
worrying about embarrassing or
humiliating yourself like calling 911
because you're on a dreamland
concern that you'll offend people
intense fear of interacting with
strangers like I said it's very
difficult for me to get out of the house
when I'm by myself
like what's the kids it's different
because I can I can focus all of my
energy and attention on them and I don't
really have to touch any funny you avoid
things are speaking to people out of
fear of embarrassment and avoiding
situations where you might be the center
of attention you have anxiety in
anticipation of a future activity or
event like on the way here I was just
super nauseous I can tell you that like
when I when I did go to New Zealand like
I'm always worried that I'll be annoying
people or wrong because they're like I'm
very
you're very out of your element so you
know how and hear when you're like
walking down the aisle the grocery store
you you come well I do anyways maybe
because I'm crazy but I consciously make
an effort to walk like I'm driving right
you walk on the right hand side of the
aisle just like you drive on the right
hand side of the road I did the opposite
just because I was freaked out that
that's what they did and they were gonna
see me on the wrong side and everybody
was gonna know I was an American because
I was walking on the wrong side of the
sidewalk so you might say that a lot of
these things happen you ever now and
then but all of these things specify
that they're intense fears I know I'm
not a doctor but if you experience any
of these symptoms blah blah blah and if
you haven't gotten help it wouldn't hurt
to do so I have a whole end of the
presentation to talk about that kind of
stuff you might avoid normal social
situations using public restrooms
I had a friend that I used to work with
that couldn't eat in front of people she
wouldn't go out to lunch with us she
wouldn't eat in the cafeteria she if she
couldn't eat at her desk that was like
turned away from people cuz she didn't
want to see that she didn't want to see
them sorry she do
want them to see her chewing and
swallowing which yeah I mean to a lot of
us that doesn't make any sense right but
to her it was it was a very intense fear
so yeah all of this and dating in your
30s and small-town America is super fun
it's it's own separate kind of anxiety
he'll going to work or school attending
parties entering a room when somebody's
already exceeded if you ever been one of
those people or saw one of those people
that would like be a couple late a
couple minutes late to college class or
whatever and look through the window go
nope I'm not doing that
just turn around skipping class today I
cannot walk in what everybody is sitting
there because they're all gonna turn
around look at me when I open the door I
don't know how many relationships I've
ruined because of anxiety and panic
attacks not just like romantic
relationships but friendships business
relationships whatever and I'll over
invest myself in any kind of
relationship and then push people away
because in my head I've already messed
things up a million times I'm being too
needy I'm not attentive enough I'm not
doing the right things the list goes on
and on and again this isn't just me
talking people have different leveling
of different levels of anxiety and deal
with different symptoms that they
experience but a huge common theme is
overthinking and being around people
so next up super fun one is bipolar
disorder previously known as manic
depression and there's two sides to this
one
there's the manic mania part some of the
symptoms are your abnormally low out
during the mating part anyways your
abnormally upbeat and friendly jumpy
increase activity super energetic you
have an exaggerated self sense of self
well-being and like confidence you're
super in phoric decreased need for sleep
unusual talkativeness racing thoughts
poor decision making is one that I've
I've definitely had people tell me
stories about that have before they knew
they had but before they knew they were
bipolar they just people just thought
they're being dicks they were making all
of these rash horrible decisions that
would ruin marriages and friendships and
you know like I'm not going to work
today I'm gonna go on a shopping spree
that kind of stuff and then the second
part is all of the normal
characteristics of depression so like
depression sorry depressed mood mark a
marker loss of interest for things that
you once cared about weight gain
sleeping all the time loss and appetite
by kind of stuff fatigue loss of energy
think about planning suicide decreased
ability to concentrate think next is
borderline personality disorder which is
also called disassociative identity
disorder disorder that's hard to say it
includes pattern of unstable intense
relationships distorted self-image
extreme emotions and pulse it miss you
have an intense fear of abandonment
rapid changes and self-identity you
shift your goals all the time you can
see yourself as being just the worst
personal world or not existing at all
shifts between those different
personality disorders so I know I'm
gonna make a couple like helper
references sorry to talk about mr. robot
but it's anybody ever read the dark
power series Stephen King so they cover
that a little bit there's a character in
there that doesn't know about her own
personality her own other personalities
and they do a really good job of
explaining the different stuff that goes
on in that kind of disorder let's see
here there are inappropriate intense
anger losing your temper having physical
fights more impulsive and risky behavior
gambling reckless driving unsafe sex
spending sprees binge eating drug abuse
all like just all the things that you
probably shouldn't be doing and mood
swings see here oh yeah the
personalities are created as a coping
mechanism a lot of times this disorder
comes after like in intense like child
abuse kids will create different
personalities to kind of cope and deal
with that one of the worst cases of
child schizophrenia was a southern year
old little girl named Janie she was
diagnosed in 2009 her hallucinations
were in the form of imaginary children
and animals there's there was a little
girl named these are her personas that
she created there's a little girl named
24 hours a rat named Wednesday and a cat
named 400 that told her to do bad things
and that if she didn't do it they would
scratch her until she died so over the
years her professor identified more than
200 different animals that that little
girl had made up she was increasingly
self harming what Artie at7 had
attempted suicide several times and was
violent to her entire family they to do
a hurt her mom and dad had to do a
24-hour watch on her in their home
because they didn't want to like
institutionalize her they would be up to
all hour
time with her so she was never alone
with herself or with her baby brother so
depression it's one of the most talked
about mental health issues out there
many people with will associate just
being sad with depression but it's way
more than that according to a recent
study depression is the leading cause of
physical illness in the world the
feelings of sadness cheerfulness
emptiness emptiness hopelessness angry
outbursts even over small matters loss
of interest in things you once loved but
all your normal activities that you were
you were doing all the time sleep
disturbances including ssam Nia insomnia
or too much sleep lack of energy changes
in appetite anxiety goes along with
depression a lot slow thinking feel
feelings of worthlessness or guilt and
fixating on past failures and blaming
yourself even though you're not
responsible you know unexplained
physical problems such as back in and
headaches like I said there are definite
definite physical manifestations of a
lot of these mental health issues Ison
is post traumatic stress disorder it is
a mental health condition that's
triggered by terrifying event a lot of
people will associate this with active
military personnel that have seen combat
and that happens a lot a lot of veterans
struggle from PTSD it can also happen
for other super traumatic events rape
you know seeing murder you know anything
like that you relive the traumatic event
over and over again you have flashbacks
of them even though you don't want to
upsetting dreams or nightmares and
severe emotional distress or reactions
to something that reminds you of you
that happened
so next is obsessive-compulsive disorder
this features a pattern of unreasonable
thoughts and fears which are the
obsessions that lead you to do
repetitive behaviors which are the
compulsions a couple well one at least
super famous person had OCD fairly bad
nikola tesla he actually would walk
around a building three times before
entering it most things had to be
divisible by three like you've stayed at
a hotel the number room he stayed and
had to be divisible by three he wouldn't
eat alone with women he had an intense
fear of women's earrings intense fear of
circle shaped objects which I mean he
still pretty successful but yeah that's
definitely one of the most most popular
cases of OCD another one I found it was
a case in the 1800's of a young lady
that would wash our hands repetitively
so like 200 times a day due to fear of
contamination another lady in 1900s was
obsessed with the idea that she would
have an affair she was happily married
never had thought about having an affair
but that and fear was so compulsive that
you could walk up to her and say you had
an affair on your husband and she would
automatically believe you she even
created like a legit chastity belt to
give her husband other things are a fear
of contamination or dirt meeting things
or early and symmetrical aggressive or
horrific thoughts about harming yourself
or others unwanted thoughts including
aggression based on sexual religious
objects and a lot of people will also
associate OCD with like I like using
Excel or I like my destiny untidy no
it's not the same thing these are very
very intense to the point where it's
that's messing with your normal everyday
life
so we can all agree that one of these
conditions so now what what if you or
someone you care about is experiencing
one or more of these how do you cope or
how do you help them cope a while back I
put out a survey on Twitter asking about
20 different questions about mental
health and how you feel about mental
health and several of the survey
responses are up here for the one
question the one question was do you
participate in any activities to read or
reduce dull or improve the stress or
feelings you're having such as alcohol
prescription drugs other drugs exercise
medication or other this question alone
really set me into like a panic attack
afterwards because I didn't set it to
multiple to multiple answer people like
I do all of these so like I was beating
myself over that because I didn't put
out a question correctly so out of 860
responses these were the results that
other category my favorite responses
were pretend to be a Vulcan masturbation
cats and Twitter in that word name of
those were withheld for privacy of
course so there are a lot of different
coping and relaxing relaxation methods
that you can do to help out with this
kind of stuff including medicine but not
always and you see here the earlier
hypothesis at work in the Foos in the
form of booze and drugs when I started
this I also reached out to a friend of
mine who's a mental mom a mental health
counselor for his day job and he said
the quickest way to improve your brain
chemistry is moving around and he asked
me what are the two the two best ways to
improve your brain chemicals without
drugs
anybody know exercise is one of them
sex sex is the next one I think only if
you're doing it right
I use my mom as a sounding board for a
lot of the stuff that I talk about
which sometimes is great because I love
making her laugh and cringe and shake
her head at me
and when I was talking about different
coping mechanisms she actually told me
about her grandma who during menopause
was sent into a mental institution to
work with counselors and psychiatrists
and at that time because she was like
sad and withdrawn she had depression at
that time the treatment was regular
shock treatments which we don't have to
deal with today unless you choose to and
I mean it's nothing like trying to cure
your depression by shocking the hell out
of you no we have better options people
talk sarcastically about safe spaces
when making fun of Millennials but I
think the majority of people don't need
safe spaces in the and the normal
thought of how those safe spaces work
but it's nice to have somebody to be
able to talk to you hopefully it gets
chosen I put in a a workshop for
derbycon
if any of you go is going to be like a
mental health workshop where we go over
exercises and there are let's just make
quiet room white noise talks like this
at cetera but kind of like that just
like super chill a place that you can
talk to people that you trust without
being locked back then you couldn't
really talk about mental health at all
just like you couldn't talk about
divorce teen pregnancy and yeah I've had
all three so not can you talk to people
in your field about your thoughts you
can talk about top two psychiatrists
therapists psychologists whatever that
not only will listen to you but will
help you through any thoughts that
you're having from a professional thing
that seems right that's what they went
to school for you think most of you
didn't go to school for psychology so
that's not your forte your forte is tech
security whatever you know you wouldn't
want the psychologists configuring a
and IDs so you shouldn't handle your
mental health on your own so back to
getting all doped up the last 20 in the
last 20 years we've seen a 400% increase
in the use of antidepressants with an
estimated 1 in 10 adults using them now
well we don't want to devalue people
suffering we don't all we also don't
want to be quick to throw pills at
things when there's better non-medical
things that you may be able to try first
which are free I mean it's great that
people are meditite meditating
exercising eating right learning and
doing whatever to relieve some of the
stress and a lot of that is because it
increases the dopamine levels
automatically without the need of
anything clinical when I was first
prescribed zoloft I was the first
anxiety and a depression method medicine
that I was on this is kind of the
explanation that was given to me that
it's just a simple simple chemical
reaction in your brain that you can fix
with some medication while I
wholeheartedly took that as a possible
as gospel because logically on the
surface that made sense something
biological isn't quite firing right in
my head and I'm gonna put the chemicals
I need in my body to try and fix it
during my research I found out that this
isn't necessarily 100% true what I found
in medical journals and articles they
really have no clue why some as medicine
works which a lot of times I mean people
will jump back and forth between
different different types of medications
to try and fix whatever specific issues
they're having because it's definitely
not a one cure Fitts off which okay I
get that science is hard the studies
point out issues also arise from faulty
mood regulation by your brain genetic
vulnerability stressful life events
medication medical problems all that
kind of things
and a quote an American Psychological
Association article this year we do not
dispute the possibility that no
transmitters and other brain chemicals
play a significant role in the etiology
of depression however we are also is
concerned that the chemical imbalance
explanation may not reflect the full
range of causes of depression it may be
given greater credence by both consumers
and practitioners than is supported by
sound research and/or may be understood
in an overly simplistic manner but
really what part of medical science do
we not receive in an overly simplistic
manner right I mean if you go and you're
diagnosed with something unless you're
you have a very very thorough physician
or you're asking a lot of pointed
questions they're going to give you the
easiest answer that gets you the
information that you need so I didn't
started taking Zoloft about six months
before the end of my marriage and it was
amazing I wasn't sad anymore I had
energy
I was just it was just great but it also
kind of made me a zombie it was great at
propelling me through jobs change house
move divorce another to have change
because I honestly didn't have any
emotions at all it was the best thing
ever at the time another pop culture
reference which I I suck at pop culture
reference and so I don't know why
there's so many in this talk if any of
you ever watched The Magicians there's
an episode where they have like a spell
that will put all of their emotions on a
little bottle it's exactly how I felt
everything was just like dead on the
inside looking back probably the best
way to be and that's that's why I ended
up going to something else so
okay so after the major stresses died
down I switch to something else I
realized it would be kind of nice to
feel some sort of emotion again other
than trying to fill that hole in me with
other very very non healthy things you
know it's always great to self-reflect
so I change to old boot rim with
occasional xanax which for me works
fantastic as long as I'm gonna take them
so I'm not saying that everybody should
be medicated but it worked for me and I
bet you there is a good amount of people
that either should be doing that or
coping or coping in healthier ways than
they currently are so one of the coping
mechanisms are there to possibly organ
even properly medicated mental health
can be a struggle sometimes I listen to
a podcast called the hilarious world of
depression during one of the episodes
that guests talked about dealing with
her anxiety by giving it a name she
called it Steve and then she imagined
Steve as this dumb friend that comes out
and gives her a shitty life advice all
the time she could just say Steve cut it
out you don't know what you're talking
about I'm Way smarter than you are and
that helped that helps a lot of people
that I know
once they thought once they figured out
like that was a thing and a lot of child
counsellors will give that as something
that children can do right they can name
it because I mean that's kind of like a
fun game that you can play to kind of
cope with that other times crying even
if I haven't chosen to do it helps I did
not really want to give this talk two
days ago because I was I broke down on
because I mean II and I'd lack of being
able to do things and whatever broke
down and freaked my kids out and cried
on my kitchen floor but so there's
actually a tear expert which is cool
he's a biochemist his name's dr. William
Frey at the Ramsey Medical Center in
Minneapolis
he discovered that reflex tears are 90%
98% water so like because of pollen air
or getting like physically hurt
something like that
but emotional tears actually shed
hormones and toxins out of your body
which accumulate over time during stress
additional studies also showed that
crying stimulates the production of
endorphins which is our body's natural
pain killer and they and feel-good
hormones crying makes us feel better
even when a problem persists in addition
to physical detoxification emotional
tear little emotional tears heal the
heart you don't want to hold tears back
he said that his patients sometimes say
please excuse me for crying I was trying
hard not to it makes me feel weak I've
definitely been there I'm giving this
talk three times prior with different
versions of it and the first time I was
scared to death I was gonna cry on stage
like I was looking like methods to not
cry in front of people online hate
crying in front of people like one of
the tricks I guess that you're supposed
to tighten your ab muscles to keep
yourself some kind but I feel like that
would have bad consequences many faiths
so my heart goes out when I hear that
kind of stuff and he talks about how he
hates the whole powerful men don't cry
and rejects those notions the new
enlightened parroting it I can't say
that word
what cuz if he's a powerful man and
woman is sometimes who has the strength
and self-awareness to cry so see here
yeah here we go I personally use
breathing exercises by neural beats
which you can find on YouTube and our
best with headphones because it's it
goes you know like different things in
different years and other videos made
for anxiety on YouTube I'll fall asleep
too a lot of times and
there's also a technique called the 5 4
3 2 1 coping technique and I walked
through these feel free to do them even
now just to practice if you want or to
try something new and here with me
so 5 is acknowledged 5 things around you
that you can see however big or small
just recognize 5 items you can see with
your eyes for acknowledge 4 things
around you that you can touch don't go
getting all handsy
unless it's consensual maybe it's your
computer that you're sitting on fabric
you're wearing your badge classes cup
you're carrying whatever 3 acknowledge 3
things around that you can hear air vent
I mean obviously you can drink right but
any other things that you can hear go
outside see if you can hear birds or
traffic or you know car going by
anything like that but listen to like
the ambient things you wouldn't normally
turn into to acknowledge to things
around you that you can smell I hope
you've all had your shower and it is
like the first talks in the con so you
should be fine
you can see how your neighbor smells
again that should be content consensual
but if you can't automatically sniff
something out go to the bathroom you can
add its thinking soap but I might not be
a good idea there coughing your cup that
detergent on your clothes perfume you're
wearing all that and the last one can't
go to different ways I've seen
acknowledging one positive thing around
you that you can taste or acknowledging
one positive thing about yourself
considering where we are and the fact
that your neighbor not only might not
smell good but they might not taste good
either I don't know I anxiety can leave
us feeling inadequate or silly that
we're getting worked up over nothing
this happens all the time but taking
time to feel to acknowledge your
feelings is also an accomplishment
positive thinking can help bring about
positive feeling in your
and you can always do that throughout
dicks exercise was wrong so now we've
covered a bunch of my personal baggage
and different coping mechanisms how do
we look about how we can treat other
people that might be struggling our
loved ones family members co-workers as
I said before I've talked to an amazing
amount of people since bringing this up
and learned a lot about how other people
help their loved ones and I've had a lot
of people ask me how they can help their
loved ones not only are there a lot of
resources online which I'll share as
well but also I'll tell you a little bit
about what you can do to help get them a
little bit better the best thing that
you can do is open communication there
are a lot of efforts out there to try
and make it so this isn't so stigmatized
and people can actually open and openly
talking about it without being judged
since I trying to talk about this stuff
openly I've got few huge range of
responses from people I can tell now
when I have an anxiety attack coming on
and I have a handful of people that I
can talk to about it usually when I feel
an anxiety attack coming on I can't talk
so there's like code words I use I
obviously is Porcupine because for
humans my favorite animal and the two
most common negative things I've heard
people say or have been told before is
that they're overreacting it was
definitely a big one and I'm not the
only one that happens to for sure I was
surprised at how many people told me
that that's the response that they get I
get that a lot especially it's from my
mom and I truly do have so much going on
for me I have a wonderful family a great
career published author great group of
friends I'm fairly healthy gainfully
employed how could I be depressed I
don't have the right to be depressed and
a lot of people think that but you know
what I've caught myself saying the exact
same thing to people that have told me
that their that they're depressed I'll
say but then you're amazing and we love
you that doesn't that doesn't help no I
did the wrong thing it was the bottom
one or to try thinking happier thoughts
all things that you should not say I
only wish this was possible
you can't just will yourself to be happy
you might have a chemical imbalance or
other potential reason that your brain
is firing a certain way it's really easy
to put the happy face on on the outside
but that doesn't mean that any of the
inside issues go away a good majority of
mental health issues come with their own
physical symptoms like as we cover
earlier even if it's difficult for the
everyday person to see sometimes we
can't even see it ourselves and we don't
attribute those things as being
connected and you can't just tell
someone to make more of an effort
another I only got in the pit the
positive and negative stories from
people are on mental health but almost
everyone that I've talked to over the
last few years have surprised someone by
telling them how they feel on a day to
day basis
bringing up bringing up your inner
demons is never really easy to talk
about no matter how many times you do it
and in a few cases I've been told those
people were just shamed into thinking
it's their fault which definitely
doesn't help some things that you can
say sometimes you just have to listen
you don't really have to say anything if
it's somebody that you're close to and
you care about you can you can create
signals maybe it's like I do and I have
the code word but you have to know what
works for that individual person and
it's gonna help more than you know know
their hand and feel of people I can go
to that that I know what to say
a lot of times you don't just don't know
what to say so it's best just just to
listen
um my issues happening a lot after big
conferences because work from home all
day I'm around my kids in my cat and I
don't ever go anywhere and then I'll
show up and be around hundreds of people
with constant human interaction bad diet
lack of sleep I'll forget my meds and
just everything compounds on top of each
other and then at the end of like two or
three days it just freaked out but now I
actually remember and make a concerted
effort to remember my medications and my
medicine and have been eating healthier
and boy what a difference it really
makes when you have some someone's of
the routine that you normally have
secondly another thing that you have to
understand about people too is sometimes
they just might not feel like going out
so they shouldn't be forced the thoughts
of crowds in closed spaces public
restrooms loud noises whatever it is
that might cause them issues is not
something that they might want to face
that day and I find that true to be no
matter the issue being crazy really
takes a toll on your social life and
sometimes there's nothing that you can
do to help but that communication is the
backbone for all of that there's a great
article a friend sent me sent to me call
this is how you love someone with
anxiety a lot of points were super
spot-on for each of us in different ways
and talking about it was was interesting
to see different person's perception on
how that stuff works in his life and I
think my favorite quote is still
silence kills anyone with anxiety it
creates problems in their mind that
aren't even there
it ends in apologies that aren't even
needed that pretty much describes me to
a tee I can make super wild speculations
over oh my god what did I just send that
may they never talk to me again it
happens way more than it probably should
and that's five thousand times worse
when I just opened up about something
you know more personal
so even though I suffer from this myself
I still find myself at a loss for words
one that are when other people are
opening up to me I try my hardest to
remember the things that I should say
and maybe I just say the same like
sentence over and over again I don't
know but the fact that somebody is
willing to tell you that kind of stuff
and trust you with that part of
themselves really really means a lot
it's okay and how can I help are
probably the two most powerful things
that you can say and obviously nothing
beats a blanket fort which I might try
and actually do if that workshop gets
accepted is have real blanket for its I
don't know if that would go over well or
not there should be 30 sweaty people in
a blanket fort so not as only is it
difficult to talk about in the beginning
but other things may come into play that
make you want to bottle it up and force
it to go away I want to show you a
couple things that our communities
already doing one is I Ronan calm which
Jason Street started up it's great for
like getting an InfoSec and differ
mental health talks and talks on
imposter syndrome and a whole bunch of
stuff on that site that's ir0 ni n come
also talks about the semi-colon project
and has a lot of really great resources
and next is this video from move X which
I hope my sound works
ah many of some of you may have seen
this before but it's about hacking
together and it really drives home some
of the points I'm trying to make here
anybody know if I can get audio Oh was
we're good okay well I thought you were
just like hearing it for my laptop all
right I've been in Java floor and I'm
hacker now every single one of you
watching probably has a different
definition of what that might be but I
guarantee not a single one of those
definitions includes race creed color
religion sexual preference or anything
usual the hacker community is filled
with human beings people from all walks
of life in our community like any social
community there are people among us
grannies acquaintances comedies that
have problems but many of you might not
even know they have we have lost too
many of those friends the suicide drugs
alcohol depression and crime many of us
go into the world of computers and the
internet because it was a place of
acceptance but there's a dark side as
well it is too easy to disconnect to
risk those markers when all you see is
what someone tweets for I am you can't
see when you first try there are many
ways to help us that need it and are
afraid to ask because one of the biggest
biases we still have in our community is
showing weakness but you can let those
around you know you care that you are
there for them and this door is opening
anytime so one of the best ways is just
to be around each other hang out go to a
movie have a good time
talk about your day be a true friend not
just another face a lobby of it if you
wish to join me in this fight please
take a video or just tell your friends
your Khan buddies or your acquaintances
that you just see it that Lobby Khan
that we are all hacking together so I
like that that's pretty cool pretty cool
video and I mean that's coming from a
marine that used to blow up for a
living so if you can talk about that
stuff so maybe you so let's do some
hacking together my door my phone my DM
all the dams aren't really open but come
on slack about whatever's on your mind
a lot of times if you're feeling lonely
or disconnected or if I'm feeling a
little disconnected I'll tweet out like
a Google Hangouts link just so I can
like talk to people face-to-face even if
it is over the computer I can talk about
projects that you're working on my kids
will come on and say hi sometimes I'm
I'm here I'm out there and there's a lot
of other major nationwide organizations
that we can count on as well I think the
saddest part of the survey results that
I sent out was have you ever felt like
that you weren't worth much as a person
over 50% of the people said yes and over
40% said that they thought their life
wasn't worthwhile I feel like having
more of an open dialogue about this and
killing it as taboo will help a long way
towards fixing it I told you a lot of
crimes do let's me more compassionate to
others and work together even if you
don't like each other
life is just a life as Rob said we've
already lost too many
yeah the World Health Organization
states that over 800,000 people die a
year via suicide and it's the second
leading cause of death between people 15
and 29 years old um there are
indications that for each adult who died
of suicide there may be other there may
be more than 20 others attempting it
here's some really amazing institutions
or associations that you can use some of
them if you don't want to talk to
anybody on the phone like I need to talk
with people on the phone you can chat
with online and they have super
compassionate people on the other end of
the phone line to talk to and I like to
finish up with a picture of a cute puppy
because I know how to pressing the
sockets so recapping things that you
should remember you're definitely not
alone to get hope if you need it there's
always options out there and 3 be
compassionate to one another and
communicate we've all had our struggles
in life some more than others but you
never know what's going on in someone
else's mind so thank you for listening
[Applause]
I've composed myself as anybody have any
questions all right I'll be around today
and tomorrow if you have any questions