so welcome to held hostage this is a
ransomware primer we're going to talk
about a couple of things today we're
gonna do an overview of what ransomware
is a background on ransomware and then
where we're seeing ransomware and then
we're gonna do some case studies these
are real-world engagements that I've
worked and we're going to talk about
some common threads within those and
some not so common threads I am going to
attempt to do a live demo of a bit
Paymer infection so we're gonna play
with some live malware and then I'm
going to give you guys some tips for
protecting your environment that you can
take away and help secure both your
families and your company's networks so
let's talk about ransomware and one of
the questions that we often get is why
is ransomware so popular and the answer
to that is that it's a good attack it's
cheap and it's effective the level of
investment required by an attacker to
deploy a ransomware attack is very small
compared to the return that they get on
that so what is ransomware besides the
pain we define ransomware
as malware with encryption so not all
malware is ransomware but all ransomware
is malware it's mostly non-destructive
it started out a non-destructive we've
seen it take some destructive trends in
the past but primarily it's
non-destructive it's virtually
impossible to crack using RSA 2048
encryption it would essentially take you
until the heat death of the universe
using the harness power of every
computer on the face of the planet to
crack one hash so you're probably not
going to get your data back and then
your ransom is paid in crypto currencies
so primarily we see that in Bitcoin we
haven't really seen a step out into a
theory a more like coin or anything like
that but the ransom is primarily paid in
crypto currencies and so how did we get
here so way back in the dark ages before
most of us even used computers 1989 we
had a little piece of malware called PC
cyborg and that was the very first piece
of ransomware and we'll talk about these
more in depth here in a minute
but if you fast-forward from 89 to 2005
you get to your first modern ransomware
which we know as GP coder and then in
2008 we had the scourge of fake AV which
ten years later really has not gone away
you have your Locker variants in 2011 so
Locker Winlock revit on in 2013 you get
into your modern crypto ransomware
so that's cryptolocker crypto wall tesla
crypt locky all of these things and then
2017 we have everybody's favorite
marketing and headline didn't want to
cry and then the not Pecha or Pecha
attack however you want to talk about
that but let's take a step back to the
Jurassic age of ransomware and let's
talk about PC cyborgs and just as a note
I want to say this is literally the only
image of PC cyborgs I could find on the
Internet so it's fairly rare and I
couldn't find an installer for it
anywhere but it first appeared in 1989
and it was distributed on five and a
quarter inch floppy disks if anybody in
this room knows what those are so we
have one hand but a replace autoexec.bat
on a system and it was used to count the
number of system boots and so once we
get to ninety boots it encrypts the
system and demands 189 dollars in ransom
for 1989 that's a fairly steep figure I
haven't done the conversion to modern
money for inflation but it's fairly
steep and it relied on symmetric
cryptography so this is not something
that had a call home feature or anything
like that it's literally very simplistic
in that it counted the number of boots
and then once it's up to 90 it locks
down the system and then we start to see
a change in this once we get into the
future once we go to 2005 we start to
see your first modern ransomware so your
things that have the help how to decrypt
your files and these maintain
persistence via run key and then it
deletes itself upon successful
encryption so after it encrypts the
system it then deletes itself and you
wouldn't be able to detect the installer
and again we're seeing
variance here using symmetric key
encryption so if you had the wherewithal
you could have actually decrypted these
on the local machine we didn't get into
asymmetric encryption yet we get into
around 2008 what we call fake AV which
is not quite ransomware it uses the the
same distribution methods in terms of
social engineering pandering to people's
fear that they have something on their
systems did not encrypt data but what it
did it was really scare people into
paying for it so you would see one of
these where it would find that you had
30,000 infected files on your system and
then it would ask you for just a measly
29.95 and will take care of all that
when actually what it did would detect
stuff like text files and call those
infections so it's really working off of
fear uncertainty and doubt or flood as
we like to call it
in late 2012 early 2013 we start seeing
the Locker variants
these are Winlock revit on don't know if
anybody here reads Russian but primarily
they come out of Russia and as we can
see here we do have a lock screen and
what these were were distributed via
exploit kits so they would lock the
desktop making the system inaccessible
and they were known to impersonate law
enforcement so if you ever had an
instance where you had a customer or an
employee that said I've got a pop-up
screen that says I have child
pornography on my system and very
obviously you would hope that they're
not pornographers but we'll see things
like Revit on would impersonate those
and use that fear to get them to pay the
fear of having people know that you may
or may not have done these things and
then what we get into in modern days are
our modern ransom wires so locking
crypto wall things like that
modern ransomware uses RSA 2048
encryption and aes-256 that encryption
is performed server-side so that
prevents local decryption so it's
asymmetric encryption those lock screens
are written in every directory where
encrypted files are present and then the
time of encryption can be determined
from the right times on those help files
what we often find
now is that the ransomware will actually
replace or will not replace the right
times on the files it encrypts so it's
better to use the right times of the
files that it drops to determine a time
of infection and then last year actually
right around this time we have
everybody's favorite marketing the
headline want to cry this is a worming
ransomware
that spreads via unpatched windows
installations uses eternal blue and to
take advantage of the MS 1701 Oh exploit
the ransomware aspect is really poorly
designed as really not the newsworthy
part of it the news where the aspect was
the warming capability because what was
the last real worm that we dealt with
was probably conficker around 2009 so
you had essentially an eight nine year
period where nobody had seen a worm in
the wild and a lot of people got caught
unprepared one of the other things we've
noticed is ransomware as a service and
what we have here is a screenshot of the
github page for hidden tear and you can
actually go out to this github page and
download proof of concept ransomware and
essentially what this means that a large
number of cyber criminals really don't
have to develop their own ransom where
they can go grab an installer off of
github distribute it and then make some
money that way it developed even further
with the Satan ransomware where the
developers became shareholders they said
we will help you develop this and
distribute it you give us a 30 percent
cut so it really reinforces that malware
and adversarial attackers while they can
be political they are also business
oriented so malware is a big business if
you have great morals you know maybe you
want to drive a Mercedes building
ransomware I don't recommend that but so
how do these infections occur we have
primary methods of infection and there
are three of those we have
vulnerabilities email and unpatched
software with your vulnerabilities your
families of crypto wall and Tesla crypt
really tended to use those they would
exploit the angler exploit kit and the
nuclear exploit kit which took advantage
of Flash and Java and then we also had
want to cry obviously that took
advantage of Windows for our abilities
one of the things that we often try to
do in our recommendations is say you
know try to get Flash and job out of
your environment we
we stopped doing that after we started
getting laughed at on wrap-up calls when
people in the banking industry that have
you know long term applications that run
on a version of Java that's at this
point probably 15 years old
can't really get rid of it so we had to
come at that from another point Lackey
is a campaign that really loves to push
email and we've seen this really in a
resurgence around Christmastime we
actually had one in December of 2017
they love to use fake invoice
attachments so your fake FedEx UPS
notices people still haven't caught on
that that FedEx and UPS don't send you
PDF files that are actually executables
and then Word docs that have macros in
them and those Word docs will reach out
grab the malicious executable download
it and install it and then we have your
unpatched software so things like Sam
ass use it used the unpatched JBoss
instances that happened really about two
years ago but we still see those once in
a while and then remote desktop is
another one if you've got 3389 exposed
to the Internet you are probably going
to get hit at some point with a
brute-force attack if not with
ransomware so where are we seeing these
there are actually two answers to this
question the short answer is everywhere
and the long answer is no really
everywhere but we have three primary
verticals where we see a lot of
ransomware attacks and that's going to
be in healthcare because you have your
hospital's imaging centers clinical
offices these places that really may not
have visibility into what's running you
have your financial services
institutions which are especially
vulnerable during tax season and then
oil and natural gas because you have a
lot of remote workers that are often
maybe not on managed systems but have
access to file shares and things like
that so you could get an infection out
in the field and that can jump back into
your environment let's talk about a
little bit in the trenches and the
tagline here is how much data got
encrypted because that's a question that
we asked on the phone with one of these
and so before I get into the case
studies I'm going to talk a little bit
about the analysis tools that I use so
this
is not an endorsement of these tools
this is simply what I use I am ence
certified so I primarily do a lot of my
forensic work within in case we were
using IEF we've moved to axiom from
magnet forensics your standard shell
bags Explorer jump list explore all the
places where you would look for file
traces for memory analysis we use
volatility and redline depends on if you
like command-line interfaces or you know
graphical interfaces
KooKoo sandbox is great for detonating
samples in a safe environment this is a
github link to the cuckoo that Optive
uses internally it is a break off of the
actual main cuckoo sandbox but it works
pretty well and then we have a list of
just other tools a and JP Triforce is
fantastic for MFT analysis so Master
File table if you want to find out when
something was written the MFT doesn't
lie event log Explorer is great for
looking at remote desktop connections
just metadata is fantastic because you
can throw all kinds of IPs at it if you
take a list of IPs
feed it to just metadata it'll feed you
back all the who is the geolocation data
all that stuff so it's great for
building heat maps of where your attacks
are coming from threat crowd is great
for making pretty graphs for executives
for reports you can look at associations
from Mt 5s as well as URLs domains and
then all the near soft tools browsing
history view and when we get into
network analysis we like to look at
Wireshark and things like that so again
not an endorsement these are just what I
use maybe give you some ideas when you
do your own investigations let's take a
look at our first real-world example
this is going to be a healthcare
environment and while we're looking at
these I want you guys to kind of get an
idea of these environments and look for
some commonalities and maybe some things
that aren't so common in these we have a
surgical more surgical provider here
with multiple remote care centers so
there's no dedicated on-site IT staff
all of that IT work is done remotely or
with temporary on-site visits so
essentially what happens is that when
these sites don't have IT on on staff
what
looking for is when they get these
infections they have to report that and
then you have a delay time between the
time the ticket goes in the time that
attack is dispatched but what we had
here was a workstation infected with
crypto wall and that infection occurred
via an exploit kit delivered through a
malicious ad on a gaming website so
somebody wasn't adhering to the
acceptable use policy decided to go play
a couple of flash games unfortunately
they weren't using an ad blocker
internally so any ad on that site could
have been compromised they came across a
compromised one and that ended up with
the local workstations and the shared
folders on the server getting encrypted
so let's talk a little bit about crypto
wall this first appeared in early to mid
2014 as version 1 still present today is
version 4 when cryptolocker was taken
down in 2013 as part of Operation Tovar
which is a which was a multinational
effort to take down the botnet behind
cryptolocker crypto defense arose from
the ashes of that environment and then
crypto wall is an evolution of crypto
defense the current versions use RSA
2048 and AES 128 cbc to encrypt that
data communications are routed via i2p
and the Tor protocols so if you're not
sniffing secure traffic on your
environment you're probably not seeing
c2 traffic from ransomware so you
probably want to take a look at 443 if
you have the capability so we have
another healthcare example and again we
have another imaging provider with
multiple remote imaging centers these
guys have no dedicated on-site IT staff
all IT work was done remotely or with
temporary on-site visits we're starting
to see a pattern here
the workstation was infected with the
locky ransomware and this came in
through email so we had a word document
on a fake invoice when the user opened
that doc it asked to enable macros they
enabled it the macros connected out
downloaded the ransomware binary game
over you had a locked workstation and
shared folders on the server got
encrypted so talking about locky
this first appeared in early to mid 2016
as version 1 and is still present today
as version 2 in version 3 there are
multiple variants including thorin
Osiris so we have developers that are
fans of mythology
and then the current versions use RSA
2048 and aes-128
ECB to encrypt that data again all of
that key generation is done server-side
and then C to communications use a
hard-coded IP address and then if that
gets blocked it uses domain generation
algorithms to build out domains that it
can contact so if your hard blocking its
IP addresses it can detect that and then
build domains that it'll talk to outside
of that so our third example here is a
petroleum and natural gas industry it's
a multinational and they have a
combination of on-site and remote IT
workers they have a high visibility and
many tools in place to monitor that
stuff so essentially we're seeing a
change here instead of there being
remote IT staff it's a combination of
on-site and IT staff and a bunch of
tools this user system was infected with
Tesla crypt the infection occurred via
the angler exploit kit during the
browsing session and that workstation
was infected along with an 80 terabyte
Sam and the entire thing was encrypted
so when they got on the phone with us
they had us in one ear and EMC in the
other ear and they were screaming into
both phones so that infection occurred
on a Friday leading into the weekend and
the tools that they had in place did not
alert on that infection and as they were
not tailored for ransomware and so what
we had happened was that infection was
not identified until a day and a half
after the infection and encryption so
that ransomware essentially had a day
and a half to run rampant in the sand
there is a happy ending to that story
they actually had hourly incremental
backups on that sand so they only ended
up losing a day and a half of work but
if that had happened on a Monday and not
a Friday it could have been a lot worse
so test your backups but talking about
Tesla crypt this first appeared in early
2015 as version 1 and remained live
through 2016 as version 3 it was
delivered via the angular exploit kit
and it uses RSA 4096 to encrypt data
because twice as good as twice is better
and then tor for c2 communications so
again we're seeing the use of
symmetric encryption and secure traffic
4c2 communications the developers
actually shut down the Tesla crypt
project and issued an apology in around
December of 2016 it was very kind of
them and he said thereafter released a
decryption tool so if you actually do
have a system that was encrypted with
Tesla crypt and you want to get it
decrypted those keys are in the wild now
so you should be able to decrypt that so
let's take a look at some common threads
all - all the tools that we had in place
in these environments were reactive IT
personnel really had no clue something
was wrong until it was too late and by
that the encryptions weren't identified
until users couldn't access their data
so essentially somebody tried to access
a shared CSV and they couldn't get to it
that encryption began at the perimeter
at the workstation and worked in words
towards the shares so we're gonna do a
little test here a little live demo of
some ransomware and hopefully this works
you always know how live demos go in
conferences but we're gonna talk a
little bit about bit Paymer
this is distributed via remote desktop
and this is a sample that I recovered
from an engagement that I worked so this
is a live sample it uses a yes to mask
it's running process so when you
actually run the malware essentially
what it does is it spawns an alternate
data stream that doesn't share the
processes name so it's really hard to
detect in memory if you're looking for
specific process names it hides in app
data and it uses an auto run key for
persistence so it is fairly
straightforward fairly simple but let's
make sure this works so we'll come over
to our VM here all right so I have
process process Explorer running here
and we'll just move that over to the
side just to give you an idea of what's
running on here we have a couple of
files here we have our standard end-user
License Agreement for process Explorer
just have it here as an example we have
our friendly neighborhood slowpoke and
our friendly neighborhood spider-man and
I have these in here just an example of
files that you know maybe would be in a
user's directory or something like that
and what I want to show with this is not
specifically how to do an analysis or
anything like that but just how fast a
system will get encrypted once
ransomware is in an environment so we're
just going to take this binary we're
gonna run it we have the ADF stream pop
up and there you go you now have an
encrypted system and so what we have
here is this is our original JPEG for
slowpoke and this is our readme file and
so let's just pop this open and notepad
oh our networks been penetrated
so everything within the host
environment has been encrypted with a
strong algorithm and then here's your
onion address and a nice protonmail
account for decrypting that so
essentially what happened in this
environment was somebody penetrated the
network via remote desktop they gained
access to domain administrator keys and
then ran rampant so they had domain
administrator access disabled the
environments antivirus protection and
then deployed this unfortunately the
endgame for this was the customer had to
entirely rebuild their environment
because it was compromised from the top
down so that's just a simple example of
how quickly ransomware can encrypt a
system and then as we see it's no longer
sitting in memory so if you're not
monitoring memory if you're not doing
process detection on endpoints you're
probably going to miss that spawn
so how do we protect against things like
that and what we've come up with is kind
of a conglomeration of items to help
protect your environment we're talking
about patches backups file integrity
monitoring endpoint process visibility
security awareness training email
extension filters and then AppLocker
software restriction GPOs and network
segmentation and these are not in any
specific order these are all of equal
importance so let's start by talking
about patches backups and file integrity
monitoring so patching systems is
imperative we saw this about this time
last year with wanna cry if you can't
get rid of Java and flash or if you
laugh at consultants that tell you to
get rid of them please make sure they're
updated as well as you can
tested backups are the cheapest and
easiest mitigation against ransomware
and a backup is really just data unless
it's tested so if you have a disaster
recovery plan if you have a business
continuity plan you don't test it it's
about worth it's worth about as much as
the paper it's written on and then file
integrity monitoring helps identify and
revert changes ransomware makes so what
we call these are the canary in the
coalmine so if you have a piece of data
that you're using to test within the
environment and it triggers and you
notice it you can actually help to stop
that infection before it occurs endpoint
process visibility is great it's
critically important that you know
what's running on your systems endpoint
monitoring software can alert on those
process spawns like we saw with bit
paper here those solutions can provide
one-click hash banning so one of the
things that we've noticed about
ransomware developers is that they're
not very creative they will send out a
bunch of installers that all have the
same md5 hash which is why you know
traditional AV works so well against
ransomware but then again you know we've
also seen that they actively develop
these things so they may flip a bit and
change that md5 as soon as a detection
comes out we like to use virustotal to
monitor binaries so do the bad guys so
understanding what is running is on a
system
is key and we'll talk a little bit about
app Locker s RPGs Network segmentation
there was a question earlier in one of
the presentations about how effective is
whitelisting one of the things that we
noticed is that whitelisting is super
effective but you're gonna need one dude
work in 40 hours a week to keep
everything appropriately appropriately
white listed it is free with full
documentation from Microsoft and that's
app Locker and software restriction
policies app Locker works the same as
software restriction policies but app
lockers for 1 7 & 2 K 8 r2 and higher
and SRP SR for lower systems it will
stop most ransomware and malware in its
tracks but it's super intensive to
maintain so there's a trade-off for it
network segmentation is beyond the scope
of this talk really but you want to use
a network architect and build out you
know your Fort Knox so all of your
critical systems need to be protected
and really at this point if you're
worried about endpoints and protecting
them it's probably more effective to
just wipe and rebuild a system if it
gets infected and focused that security
on your your goldmine email extension
filters we see a lot of ransomware come
in via email so what we recommend is to
block attachments with both common and
uncommon extensions on your basic list
is zip JSA XE because nobody should be
getting those through email
if you're feeling saucy you can block
all the office stuff but that's probably
not going to go over real well in a
perfect world you would use a secure
transfer solution so where nobody gets
attachments you just go to a portal and
download them and your ransomware and
malware campaigns use email attachments
because it works so they wouldn't use it
if people didn't click on it we'll talk
a little bit about security awareness
training you want to train people to
know if something looks suspicious it's
a learning experience not a shaming
experience please don't have the wall of
sheep for people that have clicked on
the phishing email and even security
folks get compromised and we usually
know what we're doing
but I can count on more than one hand
the number of people on my team that
have been caught up in fishing awareness
so just remember at the end of the day
good security hygiene starts with the
basics
so what you really want to do is is
cover as much as you can with what you
have and if you want to reach out to me
my email is up there and my Twitter is
up there I'm not very funny so if you
follow people on Twitter for them to be
funny that's not me I am a managing
consultant with Optive Enterprise
incident management stuff and I
appreciate your time today does anybody
have any questions yes sir yeah so that
was back on the email extension filters
yes so the question is do you have a
specific question you just want to talk
about that a little bit ok so just as a
as an example at Optive we as proof
point and again not endorsing this this
is simply what we use internally when we
get attachments that can come in through
Proofpoint it's automatically virus
scanned it's automatically scanned for
exploits things like that then we have
to physically go and download that and
then run it rather than it just being
something where it comes in on an email
and you can just click on it because as
we saw earlier I believe last year there
were exploits in the wild where you
didn't even have to click on something
in a document you literally just mouse
over it and that can go out and trigger
a malware download so having it come in
through a portal it gives you that extra
layer of defense so things are scanned
prior to them ever seeing the end user
mobile ransomware that's a fun one I was
waiting for that question I was waiting
for the question of have you guys seen
ransomware that likes to sleep before it
encrypts so mobile ransomware is is
interesting we tend to see it not as
much as your standard when
those ransomware because you know when
you're dealing with mobile devices it's
it's they're less pervasive than then
windows in an office environment there
is some mobile ransomware out there we
don't often do much with it so I
couldn't really speak to that but it's
not as predominant as some of the other
ransomware strains so sorry it's
probably not the answer you were looking
for but yeah it's it's not as
predominant and you know to speak to the
ransomware that sleeps before it infects
systems it's out there but we don't see
it as much again that gives the bad guys
more time to get caught when you do
something like that because as soon as
some of that stuff hits the the web it's
already being uploaded by researchers
being torn apart things like that so
yeah it's not as predominant as some of
the strains that I talked about here but
it is out there yeah yep any other
questions thank you very much
[Applause]