some of you may be familiar with
miyamoto musashi he was a Japanese
swordsman in the 15 and 1600s not this
guy this guy he wrote the book of five
rings which is about the way of strategy
now in infosec many of us have no
strategy at all or if we do it's to be
stuck in a rut but not this kind of rut
this kind of rut we're stuck in a rut in
our job our career we don't seem to be
moving forward there's no opportunities
or options available to us and so we
become apathetic discouraged
disillusioned disenfranchised disgusted
disgruntled frustrated maybe even angry
and we blame the job we blame the
company we blame the career the industry
society or even the government after all
they're spying on us right so we get to
a point where we're fed up and
frustrated and we just jumped ship
looking for something else not always in
a good way but there's a distinct and
subtle problem with our approach with
our lack of strategy in this area and
that is that in infosec we have this
really bad tendency when we jump ship to
do so to the exact same job just in a
different company now we justify it we
say it's a different company it's a
different title there's different roles
and responsibilities that go along with
it and to an extent that's true but it's
also not true we end up still being
frustrated because we didn't actually
change anything we didn't get to the
root cause of the issue as important as
we know that is and we didn't change
anything with our overall status the rut
goes on forever and the party never ends
so we get to a point that we're so
frustrated and fed up that we quit the
industry as a whole we say that we're
burnt out and we just need to take a
break from infosec so we look for
something else to do we look we try but
really the problem
is part of Newton's laws and that is
that objects in motion or at rest tend
to stay in motion or at rest unless
acted upon by an outside force now my
hope today is that I can be an outside
force for you all and no i'm not a
recruiter and no i'm not hiring John
Turner however is so you can talk with
him I say this because it doesn't have
to be that way the future isn't written
in stone people it can be bright we can
wear shades we just need to embrace the
way of strategy and we saw she wrote
that in order to become the master of
any one thing you need to become the
master of all things and in addition to
being a master undefeated swordsman he
was also a sculptor a poet and author a
painter a calligrapher and the list goes
on and on he wasn't a guy that just
talked the talk he also walked the walk
speaking of which I'd like to introduce
you to Shelley Giesbrecht last year at
the summit Shelley gave a talk titled 10
ways to rock your sock in it she
discussed 10 ways or things that she
felt he needed to master in order to
improve your security operations and
that wasn't even her dream job she has
since leveraged that experience to get a
completely new different job with a
completely new different company doing
completely new and different things that
she completely loves and that is
completely also so before you get
frustrated bent out of shape and quit a
job company career industry in a huff
realized that there's a way that you can
avoid the risk of rut and burnout know
the ways of infosec know the ways of all
professions look for things that you can
do where you are right now that you're
passionate about that excites you that
interests you and in ways that will
benefit both you and your employer I got
into digital forensics because I
couldn't stand working in technology any
longer I would say that I was burnt out
but I had a couple of bosses that really
encouraged me to
something in that area that I did enjoy
and since I wasn't looking for a career
with the hacking team I found digital
forensics and I've never looked back I
will also say in all honesty I don't
care that much for infosec it's it's not
that exciting to me it's a job that's
okay though there's benefit in that when
I moved from consulting into corporate I
saw an opportunity to bring with me the
things that I did enjoy digital
forensics incident response even
e-discovery and in doing so I've been
able to save my company literally
millions of dollars that's good for the
company I've also gotten visibility and
recognition up and down the stack in our
company that's good for me but more
importantly I've had the opportunity to
learn and to grow in new ways that are
completely outside the core competencies
of dfi are and that's been incredible
now every job every situation every
person is different so I will say and
I'll finish with this quit your job if
you must alyssa is going to talk about
some of that a little bit later but i
would urge you don't quit your job just
to talk about me just to go to the same
job at a different company that doesn't
serve a purpose be strategic follow a
new way thank