so I talked a little about tour and used
to stand for the onion onion router
doesn't anymore they change that few
months ago so let's talk about how it
works first of all well it's pretty
simple when you access the Internet I'm
not going to talk about how it bounces
up all these mountains everything else
but it's and wants to sniff your traffic
browsing your site that's my ssl it's
pretty straightforward people don't like
this idea so what do they do well be the
SS on the website or pickle couture and
it also complicates things some material
necessarily but protection it offers so
what it does is that you get three what
a cool knows you get entry node you get
no and anything that you can get after
the exit node is going to be completely
unencrypted unless L but it encrypts
everything back from that place so
anything you intercept traffic between
the exit nodes on the site you know what
they trying to get but you don't know
where that's going back to so a bit of a
problem
there's also this other complicated
issue the dark web told me they hit that
term I talk was about so the dark web
has got these nice little things called
dark websites where you don't actually
come out of the Tor network to actually
come out the Tor network in order to
access information these are web servers
which is set up specifically so that
they cannot be these track the traffic
cannot be intercepted fun times the most
common way that people will access or
there's actually two common ways as a
bootless you can use the most common way
is to use the TPP the tor browser bundle
that thing is locked up tight okay they
bring out new versions every few weeks
and they fix patch all kinds of stuff
they have consists of a modified version
of Firefox it also has a couple of other
extensions in there too no script is one
particular note anything well that's
fine no script has a list of sites
already that i can run scripts on there
by default
config file in this so this way it works
it caches nothing drive you still get
nothing what you can find is things like
visit to the tour website where they
downloaded it they ran it and execute
installed and then we're able to
continue to run it after that so you see
we've listed a few here different things
you can look at what else is there well
tours got an interesting of TVB's got
interesting couple of little things it's
got the state file which will tell you
the last time that tall was run it also
has the tour see file which tells you
where it was last run one from so you
may already know that because the
default installations already listed
there but it might be useful to know is
there anything else well no history
history is just not there okay and even
I know less than a year ago what the dfi
our summit that was held in Prague
someone gave a presentation on this and
they found or talked about the HTTP
memory only PB thing which you can
search for which is private browsing for
Firefox which is located in memory
doesn't exist anymore it's not there
which is a huge problem because that
means that the only thing you can get
from a computer which is not currently
being used is very very little you know
it was installed you know it was used
the good thing though is that most
people are stupid well
let's say not technically adept um so if
they think oh I'll 101 tour this is
great but wait a minute I can't access
pornhub so I want to install I want to
install flash so they go on install
flash which is great because then we go
all these Flash cookies and everything
else and and traffic and get intercepted
that's not encrypted wonderful and then
I think or crap all these stupid things
that keep popping up saying I can't
access this so I can't do this I want to
go and visit this site well no you can't
do that either so they turn off the
settings or because these websites dark
web sites have like hugely long
complicated URLs where'd our onion that
you can't remember those so they
bookmark the mr. which is really helpful
and then there's also the attack vectors
to so you get away from the actual dead
box computer itself and if you work for
the NSA and if you do I hate you too um
there's plenty of attacks around so you
can own a whole bunch of tour nodes
there's only six thousand there in
active use so if you suddenly flooded
the Tor network with a bunch of nodes
you can pretty much decipher where that
traffic is coming from then there's also
stuff like all the cisco routers which
you can use to do you do attacks on to
try and do a symmetric stuff but yeah
that's pretty much it