I think the expectation levels are way
above the roof now okay so I'm here
today to talk about some forensics you
already introduced me some skip that
part and we'll go straight this from so
what exactly is from this is something
that as David mentioned I've published a
paper on this it was published earlier
this year in the Journal of digital
investigation and I won't be covering
everything that's there in the paper
today but you can go and read more about
it later offline so let's dive right
into it since we're running a little
late so what exactly is from from the
acronym stands for system resource usage
monitor this is a technology that a
feature that Windows introduced in
actually Microsoft introduced in Windows
8 and ever since it's been there it's
been there in Windows 8.1 it's been
there as for the last Windows 10
technical preview that came out it was
still there and pretty much the same
shape and form so what exactly is this
it's bundled as part of the diagnostic
policy service and it's a technology
that's actually tracking all of your
processes all the services all the
network data that's ever leaving your
interface ok so that's a scary
introduction but we all know Microsoft
and Big Brother that being said it's not
so scary
in fact it's a as forensics folks we
actually love anything that tracks and
monitors because we can then use it in
court so this is a part that really gets
us interested from maintains a database
of all historic activity and for those
of you who were just here for the last
start by Sarah a newcomer that she was
talking about a historic database in OS
X that tracks all of your activity this
is somewhat similar a little less scary
actually so what exactly does from track
or what does it record so five things
essentially first thing network
connectivity any time you connect or
disconnect from a network
Windows is logging that information
second thing network data usage any time
any data is consumed by a network
interface by a Wi-Fi profile it's broken
down by network interface and by Wi-Fi
profile and by application so Windows
knows exactly which application consumed
how many bytes of data how much was
uploaded how much was downloaded in what
time frame third thing is application
resource usage every process every
service every Windows app formerly known
as Metro apps everything is being
trapped so these are the low level
statistics things like context which is
number of flushes number of i/o bytes
that kind of thing the fourth item that
Windows tracks is push notifications
every Windows app or not every Windows
app but most of the Windows apps have
the ability for the server to push out
notifications as you all know in Windows
8 the new start screen is all tiles and
windows apps and those tiles keep
updating by receiving push notifications
for the most part so every time the tile
updates every time you know you you
receive new weather information new new
stories new pictures on there all of
that is being locked and the fifth part
is energy usage can anybody guess what
this is
battery yes that icons are really that
giveaway but in case I see a lot of OS X
systems I see a lot of Mac system so in
case you're wondering if it has anything
to do with the Mac equivalent of energy
if you open the Mac task manager it's
called Activity Monitor I think then you
have this energy tab where it shows you
how much energy each process is using
this is not that in Windows it's purely
battery information so if you're if
there ever interested in seeing the
charge discharge cycle graph on your
computer just take this data from some
throw it into Excel and draw a chart off
with it it can be interesting to look at
sometimes as you can see most important
from a forensics perspective is going to
be the first three pieces of information
network connectivity
usage and application resource usage
push notifications not so much so oh one
more thing
Windows is tracking all of this but at
the same time it is not recording any
user data it's purely metadata purely
metrics okay so none of the user data is
going in there Windows will not tell you
what you'd uploaded or what you
downloaded but it will tell you how many
gigabytes were uploaded or downloaded by
a particular application or interface
same thing for all of these so in case
you're wondering does Windows actually
show any of this information to the user
is the user made aware of all of this
tracking that's going on partially yes
if you've looked up your network
connection in Windows 8 you click on
that little network icon and then click
on the network that you're currently
connected to if it's a Wi-Fi network
you're probably familiar with this
screen if you haven't you can click on
it right now and it'll show you
estimated usage usually it goes back to
60 days the GUI shows you 60 days but in
the database it goes back to at least
three months so it's 90 days but by
default you're only going to see 60 days
if you're an Ethernet then you're likely
not going to see this information
although the information is there in the
database and you can only see this
information for the network that you are
currently connected to so if you're not
connected to let's say your office
network right now there is no windows
built-in way of actually viewing that
information you have to go to the raw
from database to get that so let's talk
a little specific about what exactly is
being tracked in network connectivity so
this is a table in the surrounds
database and some of the items that it
tracks are the interface type the
interface ID when I the interface type
meaning it can either be Ethernet it can
be something else I'm sorry that's
that's the network profile the network
profile ID
is never mind I'm totally confused today
interface type is basically Ethernet or
Wi-Fi or ATM or 3G 4G whatever you use
and the next thing is the network
profile ID network profile ID on a Wi-Fi
network is typically identified by your
SSID you select one of the SSID for the
network's you want to connect to and
then you enter your credentials and
windows creates a bunch of entries in
the registry and tracks it by network
profile ID it also in this database
table it notes the time that you were
the time that the connection was
established and how long did that
connection last that part was pretty
obvious this is something that was added
in Windows 8.1
so the original schrum from windows 8 if
you have a default Windows 8 install
you're not going to see this information
this was added in 8.1 and it exists in
Windows 10 also so where can we use this
information on a on a recent case I I
used this information to draw out a
little chart here and you'll need to use
some data visualization or analytics
tool to do this because excel excel
falls short of drawing this kind of a
chart so here we have a user that's
connected to four different Wi-Fi
networks and over a period of two weeks
we can we just grab this from data I
mean we drew out this graph and we can
see at which date and time he's
connected to through which networks the
first one on there in orange that's the
corporate network this is this is the
employees corporate laptop that's a B
Corp the second one you see there is his
home net home Wi-Fi network
that's Netgear boot by the third one is
Hilton guest Wi-Fi and the fourth one is
a t-mobile 3G connection so in this case
this was actually related to sexual
harassment dispute and
we had to as part of that one of the
things we had to prove was that the
person was or wasn't in the office at a
certain date in time and as most of you
are familiar you do a lot of these cases
and you figure out that we have all the
records but they don't have the rest of
the records for the time period that you
actually care about so you have to do it
using other means so they didn't have
office records to show when this person
came in and into the office during this
this two-week period this makes it
absolutely clear where the person was
because laptop is always with the person
so it's the means of also tracking
physical your physical whereabouts so as
you can see all the way from late
Tuesday night all the way through
Thursday he's somewhere out of town at
Hilton connected to Hilton guest Wi-Fi
on the other days when you look at the
period May fourth through seventh you
see the typical balance of the laptop
connecting to the whole network during
office hours during and then the 9:00 to
5:00 office hours he's usually in the
office in this case it was pretty simple
he we had to prove that he was not in
the office on the 30th there isn't a
Hilton anywhere near the office world on
a 15 mile radius there isn't a Hilton
near his house so this made it pretty
obvious that he was somewhere out of
town and he wasn't in the office on 30th
April another thing this case then went
on and the guy said no no I was in the
office and so they questioned him okay
do you have any proof of you being in
the office and so he shows up a bunch of
emails that he's replied to to his
colleagues in the office and he says
look I'm doing work this is during work
hours and I'm replying to my colleagues
emails on issues so we've been back and
we looked at the next artifact which I'm
going to show you which is the network
data usage
we were able to prove we were able to
look it up that during those those
emails that he showed us they were in
Outlook we were able to look at the
storm artifact for Outlook and we could
see that Outlook was basically consuming
data and it was within that time frame
where you see those blue bars on the
first day so from basically told us the
story clear-cut that outlook you
uploaded you know five megabytes of data
and downloaded three megabytes of data
on the 30th of April you know between
12:00 and 1:00 and it used the Hilton
guest Wi-Fi to do that
it's clear-cut it gives you all of that
information right there and after he was
confronted with all of this
he basically with all of the claims just
went away this is what I was leading up
to this is the network usage data this
is what we showed him this is a goldmine
for all forensic guys especially the
Internet
especially the Incident Response folks
and it's a security nightmare for a
privacy advocate so here you have in the
database it'll tell you which
application was consuming the data it'll
even tell you which user launched the
application so you have the user state
associated with it you have the
application for path you have the amount
of bytes uploaded and downloaded you
have interface type interface ID as well
as the network profile all as one line
item as one row in this database makes
it extremely easy to see what's going on
on the machine again like I said it's
only metadata it's not actual data so we
don't know what was uploaded or
downloaded but we do know the volumes we
do know if we don't know the endpoints
so no IP addresses no ports no protocol
information and we don't have specific
data but a lot of times metadata speaks
volumes just by the NSA wants metadata
everyone wants metadata
this is a third part that's more
interesting to us most interesting to
forensic folks is the application
resource tracking this one tracks
low-level process information so it'll
track CPU cycles that your application
used context which is IO bytes read and
written a number of read operations
number of write operations so all of
this
io is actually it consists of disk IO
Network IO
and any other device IO usually console
IO is not part of this and all of this
is further broken down into background
and foreground processes so there's
background CPU cycles foreground CPU
cycles this information is sometimes
useful most of the time you're
interested in network connectivity and
network usage also what's captured is
the SID of the user who launched the
application or program or service again
it's metadata so you don't have
information about memory threads which
of those CPU cycles was kernel mode
versus user mode none of that
information is being locked yes sir
it does and I will show you that data in
a minute so I'm full of that data so
again in case you're wondering Windows
is doing so much tracking is is the user
of air of it is this shown anywhere to
the user the answer is yes and no some
of it you can see if you go to task
manager and you go to the app history
tab you can see all of the processes by
default you're only going to be seeing
the Windows apps they're not gonna see
desktop apps nor services if you want to
see desktop apps or services it's a
simple option you need to turn on go to
options click on show history for all
processes this then shows you everything
however when I say everything it's it's
just humility of data that you're seeing
here it's not broken down by networking
face or it's not broken down by
timeframe or anything it'll just tell
you within the last month chrome used up
500 gigabytes and 200 was uploading 300
was download and so on for all of these
processes that's all the information
that the task manager gives you if you
want the real guts of the data you have
to go to this rom database a particular
interest in this is this highlighted
item that's uninstalled processes and
that is has nothing to do with the
uninstall feature of a program it has
has no knowledge of installation or
uninstallation what it is is simply
whenever task manager reads this from
database and populates this to show you
this data it's going to double check
it's going to read the executable full
paths go back to the disk and verify
that they exist on the disk if it finds
that any X see an application does not
exist on the disk anymore it bundles it
into uninstalled processes so every
application so it's it's great for
scenarios where a person downloaded
something to the desktop ran that tool
then deleted it that now will show up
under uninstall processes in the task
manager GUI however you cannot it's not
a tree so you can't really open up and
see what's in that you have to go back
to the database to see all of those
applications and a funny ironical thing
is that it's called uninstall processes
but every time you install a program
you're gonna see more entries created in
uninstalled processes anybody anybody
think why that clip is simple
correct so anytime you install a program
your MSI or setup dot exe will basically
decompress files into your temp folder
it will install your program from the
temp folder and then delete the files in
the temp folder so ironically anytime
you install a program uninstall
processes gets pumped up ok I'm going to
talk a bit about how this data is being
collected essentially srem is a
framework and it's a framework which
have
with plugins or extensions and for each
of those five things that reminders
there's an extension for each one
there's a gooood associated with each
extension each has its own DLL and runs
its own code all of this data is
continuously being monitored in memory
and maintains its counters and it's
continuously monitoring all your
processes and data usage once every hour
the SRAM main process comes around and
pulls each one of these extensions takes
that data and writes it to the date
database
and those counters are reset and then
they start collecting data all over
again and the next hour the process
repeats in Windows 8 this used to happen
30 minutes past the hour so you would
see this from database being written at
2:30 then 3:30 then 4:30 and 5:30 so on
in Windows 8.1 on the machines that I
have been looking at it's it's now on
the hour itself it's no longer 30
minutes past the hour so it's now at do
at 3 at 4 at 5 it doesn't change
anything it's still the interval is
still one hour so every hour you're
gonna see entries populated what this
means is when you're looking at the
database if you see an entry from 4
chrome dot exe that is the usage of
Chrome within the last hour that's all
that this means because it's being
collected once every hour and then that
counter is reset if that made any sense
I think ok where does the data go it
doesn't get directly written out to the
database first it goes into the registry
and that's the location where you're
going to be seeing this data if you were
to open up Windows 8 machine machine
software hive if you go to Microsoft
Windows NT current versions from
extensions you're going to see under
there there is a there's a key for each
extension under there there's some
record sets and those record sets
contain the data I think Microsoft
designed it this way because it's a lot
quicker to write to the registry than it
is to files because the registry in
Windows is always persistent in memory
so registry rights are extremely quick
and the format of the data that's being
written in the registry is the same
exact that it's going to eventually
write out to the database so if you look
closely somewhere down there you're
gonna see us column count Co L count is
seven and then you're gonna see zero one
two three four five six or seven items
that go into the seven columns of the
database it's it's pretty it's following
the same format as the database it's a
direct right there's not much
interpretation to do I'm not gonna talk
about this in detail right now you can
read the paper for that but we'll move
on to more interesting things there's
from database on the disk this is where
data eventually ends up this is located
under the system32 folder in a folder
called SRU
it's called SRU DB dot that it's an ESC
database for those of you that are not
familiar with what ESC is it's
extensible storage engine it's the same
one that Microsoft uses for exchange EDB
files for Windows updates for Windows
search Active Directory over the years
Microsoft has been moving everything all
of their internal databases to es e
format and from is also an ESD database
the latest thing by the way to move to
ESC was the Internet Explorer history
files which is no longer indexed at now
it's also an ESD database is also that
the database tables are the goods that
represent the database table names are
going to be the goods that represent
each of those extensions so again it's
straightforward to read no cryptic names
let's take a look at the raw data now
this is the data for the network data
usage table in here you're gonna notice
there there's if you just pull the data
out of the database and you put it in
Excel it's requires a lot of
interpretation before we can make sense
of this so there's essentially but it's
not difficult
actually a few things that require
interpretation and the rest is as is
first thing is this time stamp filled
then that's in column B in column C and
D you are going to notice just numbers
these are foreign keys so there's a
string table which actually tract keeps
a list of all the application full pads
and the user SIG's so these are just
lookups into that table so these are
simply foreign keys in column C and D
it's just a straight look up what
requires interpretation is columns E and
F this is the interface Luud and l2
profile ID and the last two columns are
also straightforward bytes sent and
bytes received so let's look at what
this is these are the fields that need
conversion inside of this run database
you're gonna notice that the time field
is time stamps are in two formats this
one that we just saw was an oily format
it's a 64 bit for my fortunately
well-documented
so we don't have to do any reverse
engineering on that at some places other
places in the from tables you're gonna
find it in the normal file time 64-bit
format file time is the also known as
win date some people like to call it
that it's the one that windows uses
extensively throughout everywhere in the
registry and in NTFS the next column
that we talked about
that's column e interface Luud quick
search on MSDN will tell you that this
is nothing but a net Luud Union and from
this we can extract out the net lu ID
index which i would simply call the
interface index and then the interface
type that an interface type can be
either Wi-Fi or Ethernet or ATM or a
list of there's a list of other types
that are defined for us the most
interesting thing is the interface type
because we want to know what it is this
is the third thing in there l2 profile
ID
and l2 would be layer 2 and l2 profile
ID on a Wi-Fi network is typically
associated with your SSID network
profile so how do we associate it to
recognizable SSID to do that you need to
go to the registry and unfortunately but
this is supposed to be its Kiboko
machine software microsoft WLAN service
interfaces under interfaces you can
actually see interfaces right there
under there there is a for each
interface on your machine you're gonna
see one or more goods I don't know why
sometimes the same interface has dugu
it's on my machine it does have two
goods I don't know why Microsoft does
that and both are actively used I don't
know why but there's two goods sometimes
there's multiples under each of those
interface goods you're gonna find a sub
e called profiles under profiles you
click on the profile GUI that you're in
and whatever Google it is those are
profile 2 it's click on it and you're
gonna notice this thing called profile
index hey that number looks like the
same thing I was looking at was called
l2 profile ID by from so how do I
associate this with an SSID pretty
simple this key has all the answers this
registry location actually so you just
click on the next sub key which is
metadata go in there click on channel
hints look at the binary data for
Channel hints and that will tell you
that this is associated with Netgear 93
that's my SSID so this is how we've
associated profile index with a network
SSID and you can go ahead and just write
a little script that actually runs
through all of the profiles and lists
out a table of all profile indexes and
their associated SS IDs so if you're a
forensic investigator and you want to do
this on your own how do you go ahead and
do this it's a two-step process
unfortunately I
made it a one step process first is you
use Libby se DB or you use another tool
to interpret the ESC database take us
are you DB dot thus from database use
Libya CBB to convert it to a CSV file
and Libya c DB is an awesome tool
written by Joachim it's the guy who's
written another dozen libraries for
forensics really awesome guy this will
give you all the tables in CSV format
take that and then I've written a little
script which you can download from my
website this basically does all of what
I just talked about so resolving those
foreign Keys parsing those interface
Lewis timestamps parsing the network
profiles from the registry it'll do all
of that clean up the database and give
you output which then looks something
like this so this is the cleaned up data
not cleaned up just interpreted data
here you have timestamps here you have
the full application packs the user said
associated with that application that is
the owner of that process followed by
interface type all of this right now is
I Triple E 802 11 that means Wi-Fi
interface ID l2 profile ID if you look
at the last column I've added that so it
interprets l2 profile ID to that SSID
and the second last column is column J
is app name that has also been added by
me manually it's not there in the
database it's simply the same as column
C which is app ID it just takes the full
app path and just gets rid of the path
gives you just the application name
makes it easier to read so you can
interpret this very easily if I'm
looking at the application Chrome which
is the first entry in there then this is
telling me that on 20th of April at 8:00
p.m. there was a strong checkpoint and
the Chrome Exe process
sent 554 bytes and received 392 bytes in
the past one hour so that is activity
for one hour okay that looks really
small that's because Chrome wasn't
really lost it was just there on the
side doing its notification thing
however like I said sometimes you have
multiple interface IDs and they're both
active and this is what's happening on
my machine so you'll notice that there
is yet another profile ID one ending in
fifty-seven that's also associated to
the same Wi-Fi and Windows
sometimes logs it under one sometimes
under the other so if you want to look
up the true usage for Chrome you've got
to add up the values for both the
interfaces the second one I think is
line item it's about halfway through
Auto increment ID 451 there you see a
lot more data for chrome dot exe under
bytes sent and bytes received another
thing I want to highlight in here is
those those two rows that are
highlighted in yellow right there these
are what Windows shows you as the total
bytes consumed by that Wi-Fi profile
remember a few slides back I showed you
how you could view that information on
any connected network it shows you
estimated usage for the last 60 days
Windows is taking all of that all of
these entries that are highlighted and
for the entire month for all the
throughout the you know 60 day period
and showing you the sum of that since it
says for the entire interface you're not
going to see an app ID or user ID
populated there that's what that one
means so if you see that entry with an
empty app ID and user ID that's not some
ghost process that represents the entire
you know all the data that the interface
received on that Wi-Fi profile if you
add up all the application consumed data
and you look up the data that was on the
interface they will closely match they
won't match exactly because the data
received at the interface will always be
a little larger just because there's
always going to be protocol overhead
there's going to be drop packets at the
interface there's gonna be more data
that the interface receives then that it
forwards back to the applications but it
should closely match if you don't have
network problems that is okay that being
said I'm going to talk about some of the
forensic uses of this data what can we
do with this data and some of the
immediate applications off from in our
day-to-day investigations so first thing
and pretty obvious is the user to
process mapping you're doing incident
response you want to find out which
process was launched in who launched it
user process relationship is clearly
given to you in two tables and some
application resource as well as the
network data usage both of them tell you
who's the owner of the process network
statistics again pretty straightforward
data uploaded and downloaded broken down
by four interface or Wi-Fi profile or
process super artifact and I'm going to
talk about where I use this in a recent
case third thing is deleted uninstalled
an external program tracking so we use a
number of artifacts to actually try to
figure out which programs were actually
run on a Windows box you know we use
shim cache and prefetch files and
various mru lists in the registry and
trying to look for anything that would
give me you know what what application
was run that I cannot see on the disk
anymore from is one more one more
artifact which you would add to that
list of artifacts that you would check
there's anything that consumes CPU
cycles would actually show up in srem
under the application resource table and
if it used data it would also show up
under the system data usage and the
fourth item here is application run
times estimation we're going to talk
about this in a little detail whenever
we talk about applications or processors
the first artifact and most important
artifact that we use in fact the only
artifact that tells us the start time of
a process is prefetch files but prefetch
powers does not give us the duration
you know how long did it run did it run
for four hours three hours three minutes
I don't know
so it's rum if an application ran you
know longer than an hour then you have
some kind of estimation that you can do
for it how does this work so let's
assume that a user launched the
Microsoft Word application and the word
application was launched at 1343 ran for
almost three hours and then it exited at
1640 so the forensic investigator comes
in after a few days immediately pulls up
the prefetch files okay I know this was
started at 1343 but I don't know how
long it ran and there were no more
prefetch entries after that so you start
pulling up this ROM data now so you'll
get a strong checkpoint at 1400 hours
another Strom checkpoint at 1500 hours
another srem checkpoint at 1600 hours
and there's one at 1700 hours all of
these will and then there will be
another one at 1800 hours also but that
one will not reference windward because
windward was not running at that point
of time so all the I've only showing you
the from checkpoints that actually
reference in word dot exe in the
application resource table if windward
was running using CPU cycles
communicating out to the Internet it may
or may not it would show up in one or
more tables in from so this first
checkpoint actually tells me the
checkpoint at two o'clock tells me that
between one and two
I saw windward Activity the checkpoint
at three o'clock 1500 hours tells me
that I saw some activity between 1400
and 1500 and so on so using this
information I can sort of estimate that
it's very likely that I could both the
artifacts together and I said I know for
sure it started at 1343 and it probably
went
till 1700 this is my estimation for the
Windward process and I'm able to do this
using this Rome artifact inside of this
estimation again I can say for sure that
Windows ran from 1343 to 1600 and then
that lasts one hour I'm not sure of when
it actually exited did it exit you know
at 1601 or 1659 since rum has a
periodicity of one hour we don't know
when within that hour it exited but we
do know it was running sometime within
that timeframe within that hour so we're
a lot closer to estimating time duration
well with three facts we had note our
estimation we can do some amount of
estimation using
schrum and prefetch put together here's
another thing brief fed files only
retain the last eight start times in
Windows 8 okay in Windows XP and Windows
Vista it was only you know you only get
the last time the process was run now
you get the last eight times but for an
application like word which is
frequently used any other application
that's frequently used it's unlikely
that if an investigator comes in a week
later he's actually going to be able to
see any of the start points because
they've all been overwritten with newer
data the last state start times are
going to refer to this week and not a
month back so if you come in a month
later and you try to do the same thing
you don't have any prefetch files you've
got min word it ran it exited it's been
a month you still have some data because
from data typically goes back the
network data goes back at least three
months and the application resource data
I have seen some data as old as five to
six months so I'm not exactly certain as
to what Windows cutoff period is but I
have seen data as all the six months in
this ROM database but definitely task
manager likes to give you one month old
data so windows guarantee is one month
data and a funny thing is if you
if I go back to that slide you can
actually see that there's a delete users
information if you looked closely on the
task manager it says these are all the
process statistics for this one month
and then there's a belief usage info
button right there if you click that
it's supposedly well it's supposed to
clear out the database but in all the
tests that I have done it actually does
not clear out the database even after do
you delete that user information a lot
of it is still here so it's very likely
that if it's a month old there is going
to be some data in there and you're
gonna find your some checkpoints for
Windward again you're gonna make your
estimation this time your time into
expands because you don't have the
prefetch file to point to the start of
when this activity occurred this is your
estimation one possible duration for
windward dot exe I could say that well
some possibly ran and I'm sure it ran
you know between 1400 and 1600 but this
is only one possibility
this isn't accurate you know why take a
guess anyone this may not be accurate
because I don't have any prefetch files
I don't have anything else that tells me
whether word was run once or twice or 20
times within that time frame it's
possible that it it was started and it
exited you know 50 times within these
four hours all I know is that in each of
these four-hour time frames or it did
exist did it exist for one minute was it
started and killed did it exist 50
instances hundred instances or just one
instance that spanned four hours I don't
know
so from if you don't have prefetch files
cannot actually estimate process run
time however it will tell you that
windward was definitely run between 1300
and 1400 on that day it was definitely
running between 1400 and 1500 it was
definitely running between 16 and 1700
we don't know how many instances or how
long it ran but it definitely ran so
that's a definite value add for
okay I want to talk about another case
that I helped a friend with it's a
typical data theft scenario this has
existed ever since USB drives have
become you know popular employee leaves
a company and during the last few days
he downloads a bunch of data and takes
it with him pretty standard thing should
not happen these days because we've seen
these cases for I think seven eight
years now maybe longer I have seen them
at least seven to eight years back and
they still happen so one such incident
happened again and in this case the
employees laptop was a Windows 8 laptop
so what we did and he was a smart guy he
went ahead and used some tools and
deleted a lot of the forensic artifacts
that were interested in wipe some files
did a lot of covering up of his tracks
but he did not know about shrum so we
went in there we pulled out his from
data and with Excel we were able to take
that u data usage table and plot it out
and we can see the four-day usage over
here and this is for three months over
three months you can notice the last two
weeks there are some huge spikes of data
being consumed lots of data being
uploaded and downloaded and that last
day actually it's the one day before he
left on the 20th of June you're gonna
see about 1.9 gigabytes of data
downloaded and about 100 megabytes of
data uploaded that right there tells me
that something happened that's not the
average pattern of usage for this
employee that should not have happened
now
like I said some doesn't track what was
downloaded what was uploaded or what IP
it went to but that right there is the
biggest red flag that you can have what
else did we have
we took Dropbox activity but it wasn't
Dropbox but it was one of them
services I'll just refer to it as
Dropbox we took Dropbox activity and we
drew up the same chart and guess what
Dropbox was installed two days before
and parallel to this bar you have one
point nine gigabytes downloaded Dropbox
1.9 gigabytes uploaded well what do you
know and on the same day and by the way
I haven't shown you the breakdown you
can break this down by the hour so you
can you know that between 1:00 and 2:00
p.m.
about 1.2 gigabytes was downloaded and
between 3:00 and 4:00 300 megabytes was
downloads so we can narrow it down this
is really great for data theft scenario
is really great for you know any kind of
data exfiltration scenario you can go
back a few months so you so picture this
you're you find a Trojan on your network
and you know it's some kind of apt
something that's stealing data from your
network you've identified that but you
also know now that it's been running in
your network for at least two to three
months or longer go back to all of your
machines and then pull up these graphs
and see how much data and how much
network usage that trojan is actually
doing ok with that I'm just gonna recap
all of the uses that we have for some
data if you want to investigate program
usage with shrum first thing that it
gives you is it gives you I tells you
whether an app was run or not at a
within a particular hour up to a few
months back you can estimate in certain
cases the approximate run time you can
identify the user who launched that
program you get network information
amazing network information you know
broken down by our interface for Wi-Fi
ID for application and for user the same
application is used by three different
users it's cracked in three different
rows in the database and last but not
least is the CPU statistics which is CPU
cycles context which is that kind of
thing which we don't have too much of a
use for actually
so I do have a couple of minutes so I'm
going to talk about the CPU cycles thing
this is something that can't be used
very often but sometimes with certain
programs you can use this information
for doing something useful and I've
written about this in the paper so what
you can do is I took s delete
everybody knows s delete from
sysinternals it's a program in you just
run it s delete followed by file name or
folder name it'll just go ahead and
basically override all the files with
random characters and then rename the
file to some random characters and then
delete it so basically you can't trace
data for that file when you run s delete
you're gonna notice that Esteli it uses
a hundred percent of your cpu it's a
very simple program it basically just
opens the file and starts flooding it
with data there's no weight cycles on it
it's not waiting on the user on a
program that uses a hundred percent of
CPU that means that the CPU time is
going to be roughly equivalent to the
runtime okay only for that program that
doesn't wait for resources this doesn't
work for most programs that we use most
programs simply open up the GUI and then
it's just going on a weight you click on
something on most programs you can run
the programs for hours and the CPU usage
is only going to be a few seconds at
most but for something like s delete
where users of all of your CPU you can
sort of do this estimation it's not
perfect but I ran some I ran some trials
with it and I was getting very very
close results so I took the CPU cycles
you take the CPU cycles divided by your
processor speed and your processor speed
is in Hertz quarts is basically cycles
per second so if you divide cycles by
cycles per second then you get the
number of seconds it will give you CPU
time and like I said if it's using
hundred percent CPU CPU time is roughly
equivalent to a user the time that the
application actually ran so I had Esteli
run for about five minutes and then I
pulled up the stats
from and that was also whence I did the
math dividing the number of CPU cycles
by my CPU speed it roughly corresponds
to the same amount so with certain
programs you know these these things can
be useful but again it's it's very
limited applicability I hope that made
some sense and that's about it we're
almost out of time also if you have any
questions the happy to answer yes sir
so what will happen is if you're doing a
local copy it's not going to show up
it's not going to show up as data going
off of a network interface so what
you're gonna see is the application
resource usage and application resource
has items in there like number of i/o
bytes read and written you're gonna see
those counters go up however I haven't
had a whole lot of luck with that just
because it doesn't separate the i/o it
doesn't separate disk i/o memory i/o
device i/o in two separate categories so
it's all mixed up which is why I haven't
been able to pinpoint that this is you
know two gigabytes written out to a file
so I should see two gigabytes consumed I
didn't see that one-to-one correlation
in my experiments
no as of now nobody knows about Sarang I
have not and it's I suppose you're gonna
have to change some hard-coded values in
somebody else yes sir by default from as
part of the diagnostic policy service so
if you turn off diagnostic policy
service then it's not gonna do any
monitoring but by default it's on yes I
have not seen any ones in particular it
I have not seen anyone yeah
so what happens is data is continuously
being monitored and every hour it's
being written out to the registry and
then periodically from the registry it
goes to the database I'm not certain of
that period it usually happens you know
a few hours so so what here's what I did
if you want to force a write to the
database you shut down the machine on a
shutdown that triggers a full right so
everything that's there in the registry
will get pushed out SR UDP got that or
you can or you can look up the data in
the registry because it's this you will
not have data in both places it's
basically a move operation and I have a
script that specifically goes and fix
that data from the registry the second
script specifically goes and fix the
data from SR UDP so I have run into
those situations where sometimes you
know you've been dose crashes blue
screens or whatever other reason the
diagnostic policy service fails and then
you cannot for some reason Windows does
not say move that data from the registry
to the database so you're gonna have to
get it from both places to get the full
picture yeah III don't know I've not
done that level of experimentation
I have not looked at Server 2012 its I
was on my list of things to do but I
have not looked it up
no this this does record it and probably
for that reason also it minimizes rights
to the disc you know by putting it in
the registry anyone else okay thank you
okay
yes you were on Facebook the other day
turn this off