next up certainly last but not least is
Tanya from she hacks purple talking
about purple is the new black
so she hacks purple specializes in
software and cloud security Tanya's the
founder of that she's also consults
part-time for Iams research her her
background and her obsession as she put
it insecurity stems and starts from
running her own company and running a OS
chapter for over 4 years in Ottawa she's
in Vancouver Victoria now and she runs
the Oh ostrich Apter there as well she
is involved with groups like whoa sec
which hae is a partner of us and in
again in her words has been a
professional computer geek for over 20
years
hi everyone I am Tanya Tinka thank you
so much for coming to my talk today at
besides Halifax I'm really really
excited that we're having these high
telefax because when an access icon was
canceled it I was really sad I'm really
really happy that we're still able to do
something as a community so I'm going to
talk to you today about so the title of
the talk is purple is the new black
we're going to talk about purple teaming
we're also going to talk about how to
modernize application security and what
more modern ways are oppressed
approaches problem because all of the
tech is changing dev ops everyone is
changing and that means we have to
change too okay so first of all let's go
over just some of the things we're going
to talk about today so you can make sure
that you are in the correct talk so
we're going to talk about red team and
by red team I mean offensive security
I'm gonna go into this in a bit more
depth we're going to talk about blue
team which is defensive security we're
going to talk about purple team which I
consider collaborative security we're
also going to talk about how lots of
people see hackers like this
they see security people dangerous and
criminals and badass like they see lots
and lots of I just see lots of negative
connotations but we are also going to
talk about how I see them protecting
others helping people a noble profession
this is what I see when I think of our
industry including hackers not malicious
actors for people who tinker with things
and play with things and takes them a
pair and put them back together again so
we can figure out what all the security
problems are and so you're gonna see a
lot of this positive bias essentially
throughout this talk so with that let's
do the mandatory about me slides so
speakers through the side so that you
will feel that we are qualified to give
our own talk so let me tell you a little
bit about me I am Tony I'm Gingka I like
punk rock I'm also known as she hacks
purple and I am a proud purple team I'm
totally obsessed with ojas the open web
application security project I'm one of
the many people who founded woolsack
women of security I'm a huge fan of bad
you have a chapter in Halifax I believe
they're meeting virtually like the rest
of the chapters you can still come and
hang out um and I'm a trainer and coach
at XI X purple dot dev so hopefully
you're like she's alright
also I'm originally from Ottawa but I
live in Victoria now mm-hmm okay
so this is the outline for the talk um
if you have questions you can put them
in the chat and at the end I'll just go
through all of them and answer them I'm
going to cover a lot of material I feel
like I should apologize in advance for
melting your brains because all day you
just saw awesome content starting with
Anna manly I saw her speak at it when
take 2nd last year she's incredible like
all the talks all day really awesome and
so now you're gonna end with like way
more way more information so get ready
okay so approaches from modern
application Security's so four parts to
this talk the first one is collaboration
empathy and advocacy
and so you might be thinking Oh Torah is
getting soft on us and I am a little bit
but there's good reason there's like
business reasons and you'll see we're
gonna talk about all the types of like
modern apps and then how we secure those
because we have to take so some things
are the same as always and then some
things have really really changed and I
want to talk about all the new things so
I'm not going to talk about like all the
standard old stuff I'm gonna talk about
a new modern cool new stuff I'm going to
talk about automating boring things
because that is why we work in IT we
don't like doing something twice and
then I'm going to talk about how you can
continue to learn because besides in
Atlantic ii only happened once a year
and you need to learn oh you're if you
want to keep pace with all the things
that your dev and ops and the rest of IT
people are doing that you're trying to
run after them scaring okay let's get
purple okay so I'm gonna start with a
couple quick definitions because I want
to make sure that we are all on the same
page so this besides is covering many
many topics not just software security
so some of you are like oh I already
know that Tanya but it's okay because
there's a lot of people that don't know
these things and I want to make sure we
are all on board together before we
continue on to the brand new stuff so
definitions first what is application
security and why does shkolu app sect
it's because it is a mouthful that's why
I hate I'm so application security is
any and every activity that you do to
ensure your software is secure so that
could mean Oh
that can mean hiring a penetration
tester or someone to come and do a
security assessment of your applications
it could be performing a secure code
review exercise and reviewing all of
your different security functions to
make sure they're secure
it could be hearing on a podcast that
this certain version of this free mark
is insecure and then upgrading it so
that you don't accidentally like end up
being attacked and being vulnerable to
that vulnerability anything that you do
even like if you find out that this
function that you used to use that
totally used to be fine but is not fine
now
is insecure and so then you just rep
through all your source code like doing
the search and then you find it and you
replace it with the more modern and
secure option for that function
anything you do it counts it all counts
to you fighting the good fight with us
so people are always asking me well what
is steps tech ops and it is application
security adjusted for a DevOps
environment and my friend
Imran said that and basically it's about
us as application security professionals
adjusting ourselves and our activities
so we have the same goals that we've
always had but maybe we need to figure
out how to use a pay Klein or figure out
how do like how do we work with
infrastructures code so it's us
adjusting ourselves so that we can still
secure the modern stuff using the
methodology that the software people and
operations people are using okay
so that's a lot what is red team so it
is offensive or attacker style security
its adversarial the idea is it's
security testing that is against
production system so that you know what
real risk is you'll find actual values
it's not a paper exercise so penetration
testing writing exploits or attacking
production systems with permission
Allah is considered part of reg team so
it's offensive style security Blue team
is defensive security so they are our
protectors they're the people who
implement our defenses like they're the
people that put the firewall up in the
first place and make sure that it's
effective and it's working properly they
are monitoring logging patching bug
fixing creating you know adding shields
so that they can defend us against abuse
so what is purple team they're going to
be a few slides on this because there is
not a hundred percent agreement yet in
our industry so I call it collaborate
empathy and advocacy but there's
technical stuff too so it is a bit of
doing red and blue I do agree because I
still have to do security testing but I
still also have to help the developers
defend our code as a knapsack
professional I still do I have to
collaborate between the two teams lots
of teams I have to cooperate all the
time
active you'll love the communicating
because sometimes the rest of the
security team isn't listening to the
developers and as that aspect person I'm
read a little I'm teaching and providing
tools
I am enabling the developers to do their
jobs securely and I'm a helper basically
they're like I don't know how to do this
migrate I'll come home make sure you do
it securely um often known as the bridge
between security and the developers I
believe that purple team is application
security as a whole well red and blue
team both overlap as part of app SEC um
so when I talk about purple team I mean
the duties of a fully functional
application security team so they do
blue and they do red you're not going to
have a good app SEC team if all they do
is contest and you're not going to have
a good app SEC team if all they do is
secure coding exercises and they never
actually test anything you have to do
boats so what do purple teams do what is
their work they have hold consultations
with developers they provide guidance
assistance enablement sometimes they
write policies they'll give developers
tools or even make tools they will write
documentation that actually makes sense
that's written in software developer
words instead of security words you can
use security where it's to talk to the
security team but you need to use
software developer words to talk to the
programmers so you can't say session IDs
must be ephemeral because that is vague
and they don't know it's a design after
but a security person is like oh yeah
short lived got it great so you have to
communicate clearly and the other thing
that they do is they
the Kate for security and developers
we're gonna talk about what advocating
means in a bit but essentially purple
team must advocate for both sides so
they need to support what the security
team wants what their priorities and
goals are and they need to also support
what the developers need to get done and
what their policies and goals are and so
you'll have to support both at the same
time which means you have to be really
good at listening
um so purple team is a modern approach
to application security we used to have
the security team over here and used to
have the developers a way over here and
mostly they just talked like that and
now we have an area of the security team
just dedicated to helping developers
make more secure software and this is a
more modern approach we did not always
do it this way okay so I said I was
gonna explain what advocacy means and so
advocacy is showing public support for
recommendation of a particular cause or
policy and that's Wikipedia speaking but
basically it means that you are like
working towards and making sure that
this goal happens and so when you're
doing advocacy for security within the
developers you know you might be giving
a lunch and learn about the new secure
coding guideline and teaching them
everything they need to know and if you
are advocating for the developers with
the security team you may say to them
like listen this new policy is coming
out but you know these three teams need
to be grandfathered in for the first two
months and then we can do this and this
and this because these things are
happening so like yes we can comply with
your standard but first we have like we
need some accommodations if you want to
be able to advocate for security there's
some principles for success that I want
to go over so like ways that you can
make sure you're getting your message
across so that they're picking down what
are they're picking up what you're
putting down we want to make sure you
actually get what you
in the end which is more secure software
so let's look at the principles that you
can use to make sure that you advocate
successfully for security whenever
possible you want to allow independence
and by that I mean self-service so if
you this is the best ever if you're a
software developer I don't know about
you but I do not want to have to wait on
anyone I always want to be able to do it
myself
so for instance if you want them to
always use updated like you want them to
run scans on their images before they
release them great give them a tool show
them how to use it let them use it
themselves or if they want to be able to
run you know it could vast scan a
dynamic application security like web
app scan in their dev environment set it
up so that they can do it themselves
like train them and then just give them
a safe place and let them go do it
micromanaging does not work well it's
important that we have confidentiality
with them they need to know that if they
tell us they've made a mistake
that they can trust us now that does not
mean if they break the law we're not
gonna tell obviously not but for
instance if someone's like I did this
and it said I'm proud and I need to fix
it I need your help they need to know
that you're not going to you know run
until the rest of their team and make
fun of them and shame them that's really
really really important we want to make
sure we're doing a human centric
approach I've worked at up so I used to
be a pen tester for web apps and so many
times so many times I get called in the
very last minute and I you know I'm like
pew pew pew pew I find so much stuff on
and then I'm giving them a report like
two days before they go like and then
the software developers are totally
sweating it out left escape only it
can't fix all the things super stressful
like what if we did it earlier what if
we did some of the tests earlier what if
we didn't put them through hell every
single time so that would be a human
centric approach like remembering that
people need to rest it sounds like
really obvious but you would be
surprised how many people don't consider
that
I worked somewhere once and this woman
made a plan for everyone to work over
Christmas Day and a New Year's Day
because that was more convenient for her
and I take okay so that's not happening
let's make a real plan empowerment and
so software developers are really smart
otherwise they would be X software
developers because they would have been
fired um so if you give them tools if
you create processes that work you give
them the knowledge to do their job
he will go create secure suffer for you
so if you can empower them it is so much
more likely that you will end up with
more secure software at the end I
believe it's important that everyone has
access to the security team I have
worked before at places where they only
wanted to teach the senior developers
about security because according to
those senior developers the junior and
intermediate developers are to don't
want to learn my gosh I don't work for
you I think that you need to teach
everyone or at least make it available
as an option to them maybe not everyone
is capable of learning or ready but
giving them the opportunity so if
there's a junior developer that's really
really really excited about security
like maybe give them borrow them blend
them a book or take them to a meeting
etc I believe in accountability if you
have a service level agreement and SLA
with the developers let's say you know
critical bugs must be fixed within 48
hours of being reported I think maybe
you should have a service level
agreement like we will get back to
emails within three business days
because like they can't just wait on you
all the time if you're like expecting
them to not make you wait it's really
important that you hold yourself
accountable too because that will create
better results with them especially if
you admit fault on the last one is
making security accessible for everyone
and so there are lots of people that you
work with that might be dyslexic or have
ADHD or be neuro atypical etc if you're
going to give a whole lot of cream
maybe someone would be better being able
to do it from home or maybe someone
would work better with an audio book etc
if you put it out there that you know
you'll try to accommodate people if they
have special needs you will not believe
how much that matters to people who need
a little something slightly different so
that they can learn or so that they are
able to accomplish their job at like 100
percent skill level so if you can make
security more accessible in any way so
for instance like we're in Canada so
offering some of your stuff in French
even if most your office is English but
if you know you have some francophones
ask them like do you need this in French
because I could get it for you that
would make a big difference okay
empathy 8min so the soft skills are life
skills but not everyone seems to have
them and you are going to be an awful
application security engineer if you
can't understand where the other side is
coming from empathy is about
understanding where other people come
from and if you sit there and look at
the developers and you're like listen
and made the secure coding standard and
it's going into effect next week and you
all just have to comply that has no
empathy and that means no one's gonna be
a compliant you haven't given them any
time you didn't teach it to them when
you do things like that like you just
facepalm down like you're not gonna
succeed you're not going to do a good
job and I mean not having people like
you at work it's probably not important
to every person however if people can
get along with you and they get that
you're trying they will go the extra
mile for you and you are trying to
convince at least 100 developers for
each security person to do a thing that
you want like they're already winning
there's way more of them than you if you
are giving them no sympathy and no
empathy and not seeing anything from
their side like you're just gonna feel
really miserably and so if you have no
empathy you probably want a different
job because you will find this job
okay so I want to talk about idols and
our ridiculous obsession with hackers so
some people tell me that we're not
obsessed with hackers and that's in my
imagination and it's just on my mind
because it's the place that I work or my
job but that's not what I see I actually
see like it appears that lots of people
are really really really idolizing red
team and hackers and I if you're
thinking this isn't true I ask you why
are there not this many movies about
accountants right where they're not this
many movies about all the other jobs in
tech there's so few people that actually
do penetration testing there's actually
very case however criminals like
compared to how many software developers
or project managers that we have but we
are totally obsessed and in my opinion
is really damaging our industry I feel
like a lot of people they see all these
stereotypes or like people in the black
hoodie extreme arrogance breaking a law
and people think oh I don't belong there
I remember when I was asked to first
train security I was like oh I don't
think I'd fit in I just was like I'm a
nerdy little dweeb that codes in my
cubicle and the person who became my
first mentor just like telling me how
he'd be really good and you know I
clearly it worked out but I feel like
we're repelling so many awesome people
away with the stereotype I'm also seeing
security models we can't afford because
people think that pen testing is the
only thing that's important and so then
they're spending all their money on that
when they're not doing any of the bare
bone basics before that like calling
someone in at the end that is the most
expensive way I mean it's the second
second most expensive way the most
expensive way is to have an actual
security incident that would be way
worse but it's much better if we start
security earlier we do security the
whole way through and we support the
developers for the cost of a pen test
you can do a lot of app sack
I don't mean we shouldn't ever do them
that's not what I mean so there's this
guy people are always asking me like if
that's who I work with I don't know
about you but I don't work with this guy
and I run this thing every Monday he's
to be called mentoring Monday and now
it's cyber mentoring Monday because the
hashtag got so big everyone started
using it and then it got we got drowned
out so now we have our own hashtag cyber
mentoring Monday and when I first
started this people just only asked
about becoming a pen tester but all
anyone asked for the first six six
months and so I wrote an article about
all the different types of jobs in
application security and it turns out oh
I want to be an instant responder oh I
want to do forensics I want to do so
they just didn't know those jobs exist
so part of our problem with like
constantly glorifying only one job is
that people think that's the only job
they can have like I became a pen tester
having no idea that I had the option of
doing at SAC lab SEC it turns out that's
where I'm meant to be and if we don't
tell people about all these different
types of jobs like we could miss out on
people who would be amazing instant
responders right and all the other types
of jobs and we need people doing all of
them okay so now I'm not going to talk
to you about Lois I just love this
graphic this really amazing artist
Ashley Willis made this for me with
permission from a wasp and it is so
gorgeous and when I don't know what to
do or I'm lost I I tweet it that I'm I'm
asking help from Oh ass and just all
these people from the community come and
like help me solve my tech problem it's
super amazing and I was joking with her
that I just turn on the bat-signal and
then she made this beautiful image and
it's open source so you can like print
it and stick it somewhere if you want to
but what I'm actually going to talk to
you about is modern application security
so modern apps need modern approaches
and this is basically what the purple
team does all day so I'm going to talk
about a whole bunch of different new
Tech and then what we have to do to
secure it so I'm gonna explain what each
one of the tech things are so even if
you're like I don't work with software
it's okay
you could still learn about like what
server lissa is and all of that so don't
run away just yet okay so zero trust so
back in the day when security started
what we would do is we would just put a
giant firewall around everything a big
wall and not let people through and you
know our apps would stick edge people
could see the apps and that's it and we
would just trust everyone inside if
you're inside the firewall we just
assumed you were good and what this led
to is first of all insider threats could
do whatever they wanted but also if
someone managed to get in past your
firewall they would have access to every
single thing in your entire org and so
someone came up with the idea of zero
trust which was popularized by Google
and the idea is is you don't trust
anyone ever always verify so you know
they say like trust but verify no trust
no trust just verify forget that and so
this could be in your network design but
this could also be for instance between
applications like if you have a server
with sap that calls another server lasat
it still needs to authenticate right
because I could be a jerk that's broken
into your network and then I think I
call it all right
so between your applications within your
application the way that you set up your
configuration so for instance like we
used to just leave all of our ports open
like well I might want to tone that in
some day know close everything unless
you know you need to use it and then
just open it when you're using it and
close it after okay and the way you
design your network is where zero trust
is is seen the most but basically only
trust after you have authenticated and
authorized so hand-in-hand with zero
trust is a sane breach so this means
designing things in a way where you
assume that you have been breached so an
example of this
it means design and react in a way as
though you have been breached so
if for instance you have a critical bug
reported to you and you're running a bug
bounty program an assumed breach tactic
would be that you run your entire
incident response protocol as though it
was an event and you're not sure if
you've been breached and go verify that
you haven't because that security
researcher might have been the seventh
person to find that problem right the
person that reports it to you it could
have been in like people could have been
exploiting that for a year you have no
idea and so that's the assume breach
mentality and if you do those two
together
things are just locked down nice and
tight another new so a new type of tech
is serverless and logic acts so logic
app is a trigger and the only thing it
does is call serverless apps so logic
apps are generally in the cloud so if
something an activity happens in the
cloud and it senses it then it logs it
triggers the logic app which calls the
service app so let's say someone has
tried to log in 10 times in under one
second so that's probably not person
that's probably a bot and so it could
trigger the logic app and the logic app
it's like I know what to do we call this
service act a server this app is an app
that does not sit on a server all the
time that's why it's called surplice it
is dormant and then when it is called it
explodes a container
runs itself to completion and it could
mean installing software running updates
doing a test spitting out the results
into a report and then once it's done
wherever it's supposed to do it
self-destructs destroys the container
and gives back all of the resources that
it was using and this saves tons of
money so if you have a server less app
and it only runs nine minutes a month
like if you were running a virtual
machine that might be 50 bucks and the
cloud for the whole month but if you are
just running this container for nine
minutes it could be like I don't know
any less and pretty exciting and so
there are some things that we need to
know about server lists and logic apps
so first of all do
forget AB SEC so all of the same things
apply so if you have a circle as app it
still needs to authenticate two things
you can't automatically trust it right
and it needs to be authenticated too as
well so if it is supposed to connect to
an API it needs to know like if
something calls it sometimes when we do
new tech which is totally for everything
at the window input validation why would
I do that
you still need to always validate input
no matter where it's coming from and so
please don't forget yourself but on top
of that okay so some of the things that
you should do that are not brand new
like you should log and monitor your
functions people forget that a lot so if
you have a server let's have a logic
happen if I'm an incident responder or
you've had a big incident and you don't
have any logging omona during setup then
that means I have nothing to investigate
and as an instant responder I am pretty
upset if you use secure coding
conventions for your application code I
know you should use them you don't stop
um and also you want to encrypt all your
data in transit and at rest sometimes
people just forget those those three
things specifically but improvements
modern improvements would include use an
API Gateway as a security buffer so
don't let people call your server less
apps unless they're going through a
gateway monitor and log your stuff but
then like a newer thing which has been
possible for a long time but people are
starting to do it is send those logs to
the sim if you have a security
information and event management system
a sim sending the stuff from your apps
to it it's not just for networks it's
for everyone all of the tech toys can be
like if they can log the sim can absorb
it um if you work if your logic app or
so that was a poor gonna use secrets
they should not be stored inside your
server list they should store it in a
secret store and access programmatically
um you should deploy functions with
minimal granularity
so basically a serverless app should
just do one thing it shouldn't do 500
things it shouldn't be like a full giant
application and you shouldn't be calling
like five hundred times a day in which
case you need a regular uh-huh
and lastly maintain isolated parameters
or parameters and isolated function
parameters means basically zero trusts
so what happens a lot is that a service
app will call another service app and
we'll have no identification or
authorization and if I am a bad person
now I am on your network I'm gonna try
to call your service apps and if they
don't have a tenth occasion or
authorization that means I can and I
could do all sorts of things to them
even if I just call them on a script
over and over so that you can't use them
it could be damaging okay next
third-party component in library
management software supply chain
security some are tweets somewhere
between 60 and 80 or 90% of all the code
in your app is not code that your team
wrote it's actually libraries or
frameworks dependencies components
anything anything else that is code that
you didn't write it's still risking you
are accepting and that can be quite
problematic and so we call that your
supply chain so it's all the things that
you use to make up your software like
the things you use to build your
software so all those things need to be
secure as well and so some people call
this open source security
however the dotnet framework is not open
source its proprietary I still care if
it's secure the old versions of the
framework have lots of vulnerabilities
and so you still want to make sure
you're on the right version that's most
secure I suggest using multiple tools to
verify if your components are known to
be secure because each team like each
security company gets the information
from a different place so I suggest you
scan your repository regularly like
maybe once a week
to look to see if a component has become
vulnerable and you didn't know so people
know if you're using framework bla bla
bla point three people may have been
looking at that for three years and
maybe after two years they found a
vulnerability and then it is exploitable
and you're still using it and that's
disconcerting another thing you can do
is there are IV e plugins so the IDE is
the place where programmers program all
day and there are plugins that will
proxy between their package management
and their IDE and only show them the
packages that are known to be secure
like pre-approved one so this means they
can never using insecure one in the
first place that is awesome sauce
another thing you can and/or should do
is if you are releasing code in an
automated pipeline see ICD pipeline scan
there it is a super quick scan because
it's not actually evaluating the code
it's just looking oh they have version
3.1 point two of this oh yeah that's not
known to be vulnerable good to go it's
very quick check very high accuracy and
it's yeah it's really really hopeful
okay
whom Crown Jewels online storage must be
tickets at the water you're on
storage holds your data and your data is
extremely valuable it is so we
definitely want to so if you're using
the cloud and you're using online
storage you can create in all of the
major public cloud providers you can
create templates and policies so that
every new container or online storage
bucket or whatever you want to call them
is locked down by default all of them
now like so Amazon was the first public
cloud there are lots of you know jokes
about oh they have an open s3 bucket
etcetera so Amazon learned from that all
the cloud providers learned from that
and all of the defaults containers now
are secure at the start so you have to
peel off the security so if you have a
template that everyone follows you can
have it be even more lockdown than that
if you want to and then it's just
effortless right another thing I feel we
should do is classify our data so say
like this is public or this is private
or this is confidential or this is you
know top secret if you do that then
incident responders again can either you
know freak out and meltdown or breathe a
sigh of relief oh that information is
not actually sensitive at all so I mean
I still have to take this seriously it's
an incident but I don't need to follow
all of my hair another thing is you
should monitor access to these so online
storage generally only be accessed by
computers and software and other systems
human beings shouldn't be fiddling
around in there generally so you want to
make sure that you are monitoring it you
turn on file integrity monitoring as
well if there's ports nothing happening
you need to have automated alerts at the
very least and those alerts should be
going to the sense cuz someone sees it
immediately and if you can you could add
an automated response so the cloud
allows a lot of automation responses I'm
oh yes and these containers are storage
buckets and should only be accessed by
service accounts so service account Oh
as
service account is basically an account
used by computers to talk to other
computers so it's not Tanya's account so
that means like if I quit it'll still
keep working because you know like app
ABCs service account is talking to you
know the storage account for app ABC but
if it's Tanya's accounts and then Tonya
leaves that's a problem right also if
you see Tanya's account trying to access
it in the middle of the night you know
there's probably something wrong with
Tanya's account yes so containers and
orchestration is next
so containers are really really really
small operating systems we used to have
giant physical servers we call it bare
metal and you would have one operating
system run on one server then someone or
a whole bunch of people invented hyper
vision and the idea of virtualizing
servers then we had virtual machines all
sorts of virtual machines so you could
have let's say four or six operating
systems running separately and
independently all on the same server
totally awesome then came containers so
an operating system is huge like Windows
is huge it's like two gigs of hard drive
space and two gigs of memory
Gigantor but container only contains the
absolute mandatory parts of the
operating system that you need in order
to run your app so if you're running a
little tiny script you really don't need
that much to run it so instead of being
to Gay's it could be four Meg's it could
be much much smaller and that means we
could run hundreds on a server and when
you have cloud and you have all sorts of
servers all working together like you
could just take out this really small
space and run hundreds of things however
if you have hundreds of containers
someone needs to manage all that and
that's where orchestration comes in so
orchestration systems what they do and
the most famous one is cuber Nettie's I
usually try really hard not to like name
lots of products but kubernetes has just
totally taken over the market um but the
idea is it manages all of that for you
so it launches new ones it managed
memory it it shuts things down and it
just like if you imagine an orchestra
it's like the director running
everything and so that's what containers
are little tiny operating systems and
our constriction the thing managing all
the containers guess what you need to do
keep doing security that you would
always do for some reason people are
like oh I made a container I don't need
to close the ports or do anything like
that
yet you know all the same security
things that you would do for a VM you
need to do them for those but on top of
that there are a few extra things that
are different and so because you know
containers and orchestration are
different there's new configuration
rules that you need to learn and then
tools that you need to learn but they do
that they check the same types of things
right they're still looking over your
configurations they're still testing to
see that things are closed that should
be closed there's new types of
vulnerabilities to watch out for so for
instance if there's a container of
course someone's gonna try to escape it
if there's a virtual machine of course
someone's gonna try to escape it right
but it will be a different vulnerability
let's get to pay attention specifically
with containers and orchestration the
biggest thing that you want to watch out
for is protecting who can create or edit
containers you really want to make sure
that you lock that down that is theme
it's the crown it's um it's the keys to
the kingdom really the only the only
mark important keys are the keys to your
cloud instance I'm still be very careful
with who can do that with basically it's
a very similar approach we would take
two virtual machines so scan check your
config patch regularly or just
completely replace it with a new version
that is secure and apply zero trust to
your configuration and your design I
know that's easier said than done not
saying that it's not hard work but I'm
saying you kind of have to do all the
same things but with new rules and you
can do it so API is and micro services
so an API is basically a web app with no
front end there's just no GUI so it has
all the back stuff that runs on a server
and then it gets cold sometimes it gets
called from a mobile app sometimes it
gets called you know by a web app front
end sometimes it gets called by other
api's and basically an API can do
everything that the back end of a web
app can do and a micro-service is an API
but it just does one single thing so
let's say I'm writing an app and it
looks up addresses based on postal code
so I'd probably use a micro service to
look up the postal code because all the
other people where I work they probably
also have to look up addresses and
postal codes so then everyone can use
that API not just me and all I need to
do is go the database and say okay so
this postal code just send back their
address right so then all of us can use
it instead of just us rewriting that
same functionality over and over again
in each app ok so api's web apps with no
front end no GUI micro services tiny
tiny tiny api's they just do one single
thing okay so yes
gonna say you still have to follow all
the same best practices in regards to
application security you still need to
sanitize your input you don't need to
encode your output because you don't
output to the screen you still have to
do basically everything else that's like
the only way that's the only one that
you don't have to do stuff about so
don't forget all your best practices I'm
mentioning it because many many people
do I do you still do pen test then oh
gosh but there's more there's more stuff
that's very specific for api's um so
there is a thing called service mesh um
I have for the win
beside it it's a service mash remember I
talked about orchestration you know it
manages and does everything for all your
containers well serviced mash does this
for api's so it manages things it
manages it also encrypts everything so
it's a layer of infrastructure and your
apps go through it and it just protects
everything and manages them and it's
pretty great standardization and
templating I have seen so many places
where each API is slightly different no
you should all follow the same format
for calling your API so that's easier to
test and it's easier to make sure that
things are going correctly if they're
all different that is that sounds awful
strict linting of how your API is are
called
so linting is like grammar police for
your code so it does not allow what is
the word it does not allow for like
poetic license so for instance if you're
supposed to define you know this is a
string some programming languages it can
just tell
but lynching won't allow that because
uncertainty is where we end up having
security problems and so ensure strict
lensing so if someone is going to delete
something they should call the delete
function right and they should use that
call in HTTP they shouldn't use a put
because then you don't have the
protection of the delete HTTP request
and so if you initiate linting it will
just check for all those things and make
sure you're following the rules and
there's no one being creative with the
way things are being used modeling in
bruisers Kota which is something that I
believe service match or API gateways
can help with basically throttling means
slowing stuff down so if you know
someone's trying to log in and they keep
failing and they keep failing on the
keep failing well maybe you should slow
them down and then resource quotas means
when you hit a certain number just cut
them off you don't want people abusing
your API so you don't want them calling
them over and over and over again
because that is a disaster and that's
not going to go well and it's gonna be
expensive
um I crossed on you to authenticate and
then to authorize so make sure first you
know who you're talking to and then go
check what they are allowed to do
because if you can't figure out who
you're talking to
there's no need to go any further in
your code hi Dwight you Kenny so by this
I mean so like a a lot of apps and
especially api's will say oh you pulled
us wrong you're supposed to do this when
you be able this extra information you
are giving that to hackers you're giving
that to malicious actors or security
testers who are looking at it and trying
to exploit it a computer calls correctly
that's what happens it always calls the
same way it doesn't make him escaped or
a typo and so if it's calling it
incorrectly and you're like oh no this
is the format don't give some before
that make some guess make it painful
um and lastly you should wait lists so
this goes for all apps but if I throw it
in here um wait list your approved HTTP
methods or votes and then block the rest
so a lot of people use post and get and
sometimes delete people don't usually
use tracer head if you are not using the
other HTTP methods block all of them
don't let anyone call those things
because you're not using them and
therefore zero trust it don't allow it
boom okay so I'm going to have a little
bit more water and then I'm going to
tell you about a whole bunch of
different modern tooling options I know
this talk is long I just couldn't cut
myself off I was just like no but I also
need to cover this and I also need to
cover that I'm sorry if your brains I'm
melting okay some modern cooling so this
is a list of some modern cooling that I
just want you to be aware of that it
exists
I'm not telling you to go buy it or that
you need it but if you don't know what
options you have then you don't know
what opportunities that you might have
and I want you to have all the
opportunities ok so I asked
Interactive's application security
testing so this is a stub that goes into
your application it's a binary and it
interacts with your app as people are
using it and so it only runs over the
parts of your app that are actually used
by your users so if you could run it
during quality assurance testing or a
pen test that would be great it's a mix
of dynamic and Static application
security testing like it looks at some
code and it looks at like how your app
runs but then weird of this is that it
basically it's a binary it's in your app
and that it only tests the parts of your
apps are actually used so there's a lot
onslaught of code that never gets run
and act and so it won't test any of that
just test the used part the next one is
rasp runtime application security
protection again it is a stud of a
binary that goes in your app and it
usually calls out to the cloud so it is
a shield for your app the idea is it's a
bit so it doesn't work at all the way a
web app firewall a laff works like the
same concept it's a shield so it looks
at all the input coming into your app
and then evaluates us if it looks like
an attack or not and so while a what
half a first generation of this type of
tool would just use tons and tons of
regular expression and it's way way out
on the web server so it's far from your
app it will create a fair amount of
latency and sometimes false positive
well a rasp is rate inside your
application it's a binary it runs very
fast and then it calls out to the clouds
sometimes and they say they have AI and
I know and those are really important
buzzwords for marketing so it's supposed
to be a lot more effective
Kyle integrity monitoring which goes
hand-in-hand with application
whitelisting
so file integrity monitoring is making
sure that the files on your system do
not change specifically usually the
system files and application
whitelisting means only these apps there
on this approved list are allowed to run
and the idea of using them in tandem is
that if if malware gets onto your
computer like onto your server the first
thing it does is it tries to start
itself and it won't be on the approved
list of apps so the application
whitelisting will stop it and the second
thing it will do is it will try to
change its name to like a file system
name and the file integrity monitoring
stop that and then it's just dead in its
tracks I gave a hard drive once so we
had done like a security investigation
for something that happened and we had
to like there was a bunch of people
infected and so he gave them all the
stuff to the team to look at and one of
the hard drives came back and they said
hey so um you know like because the they
weren't in fact it turned out was fine
it's a long story but anyway the point
is is there I go this hard drive has a
Trojan on it
so you need to firm at it first it's
infected with malware I'm like okay I
thought it was fine and they're like it
is fine because you have file integrity
monitoring and application whitelisting
it's hopeless I can't do anything but
we'd like you to format it you know even
though it's helpless like just in case
something weird happens and I said oh
cool it worked cloud native controls so
these are software or services created
specifically and optimized for the cloud
they don't work on Prem some of them are
created by the cloud providers some are
created by third parties but the idea is
there a specific
for public cloud adding security tools
to your data pipeline so this should say
regular application security tooling
that has been optimized for pipelines be
careful with this one because a lot of
vendors are singing that they're
old-school tools are totally adopted but
they haven't changed anything and
they'll break all your stuff and slow
everything down and make people unhappy
um but some of them have reinvented
themselves and then there's lots of
really cool new devops tools coming out
from security companies really really
cool things coming that aren't quite
ready yet so I can't put them on the
slide things like automate at least
privilege and I'm trying to think of
also like Princeton's chaining a whole
bunch of security tools together but
just having it run as one place and then
like having it HTA honestly run all the
other tools for you on your Kobe's like
there's lots of cool things coming from
a lot of really cool companies
customizable alerts automated responses
if you are in cloud you can organize
things like this with your cloud
provider and they have system setups
that you can make your own and
application inventory tools so this has
exploded in the past a year and a half
it is really hard having accurate and
current list of all of your apps and so
there are companies now making tools to
help you do this and that is
ridiculously cool because when I did
that sexual time that was like the
hardest thing in the world
modern tactics so these are different
new ways people are doing things so
adding security tools to your pipeline
taking unit tests and making negative or
abuse case unit tests breaking security
activities into smaller Sprint's so if
your developers are releasing code every
three weeks making sure that your
testing takes less than three weeks and
that you can get them results in that
time turning penetration test results
into unit tests to make sure that those
problems never come back I realize that
tuning tools for automation and
efficiency should be really obvious but
it appears that people are doing it now
more than the
- automated or posit or a scanning
that's nice your coats just sitting
there you might as well run every
security test on it that you can because
it doesn't do any harm there's so many
modern tactics and I would be here old
egg
okay so def sec ops my favorite topic
this is application security in a DevOps
environment there's many parts to it so
adding security tooling to your pipeline
ensuring fast feedback from the security
team making everyone when a teaching
moment I actually talked about this
quite a bit so this is a little link to
another long extended talk where that's
all I talk about I just wanted to make
sure that you know that I'm skipping it
on purpose because otherwise we'd be
here all day
okay so cloud security yeah you can't
just talk about cloud in every talk I
know but some apps live in the cloud and
I feel that it's really really important
that you as an app set professional make
sure you know a bit of cloud if you're
going to work in a place that's using
cloud otherwise I feel you're not quite
doing all of your jobs and life will
this be easier if you know what's going
on okay so this is a summary of this
section and then we have a little bit
left I'm sorry I'm going slightly long
um but we started 10 minutes early so
we're not like yet okay so now I want to
talk about automating the boring stuff
this is the last part we learned a code
because we did not want to do things
back under times right you don't want to
do things manually we don't want boring
work we don't want to have errors we
want to make everything faster my friend
Steve Moravsky made this slide he's
awesome and he taught me about toil so
toiled toil stinks the idea of toil is
that it's manual repeatable automatable
tactical it is devoid of enduring value
and it scales literally so it means like
if it takes me all night to do 10 that
means it's me and my friend all night to
do 20 as opposed to if I work heard all
night to automate it
then you never need anyone to do it
again and so that's our automation comes
in
you should automate every single thing
you can the timer takes you to automate
it will be so so valuable for you
because you will have reduced errors
they'll make your table more enjoyable
so you're not doing boring like manual
chores but you'll just you'll be able to
get so much more done in the rest of
your job so options for this are you
know using pipeline soft water if your
dev and ops team are using them creating
your own pipeline where you run lots of
security tools that take a long time to
run but it doesn't actually release any
code anywhere you can do infrastructures
code and security is code so if they're
doing infrastructures code you can add
all your security configurations and
things to it and then test their code
for security and anything you can do to
automate security for developers is good
when you automate as much as possible
you get to do more fun work I mean if
nothing else like the psych living money
and saving errors and stuff this means
you get to work to prevent incidents it
means you get to upgrade some of your
security defenses or add new ones
it means you spend less time cleaning up
messes because you've made less manual
errors
automation is the key it makes life so
much more better so now I'm going to
give you some ways that you can continue
to learn so you know this conference
happens once a year but you need to
learn all year right so the main
takeaway in this section is that every
moment is a teaching moment so you need
to keep teaching even when it's not fun
so the moment we stop learning we are
left behind even if something bad
happens that is a great a great time to
make a lesson or if someone does
something awesome make a lesson of that
it does not have to be super formal
training like you could give them a link
to you know cyber e and send them off on
one of those courses it could be a Lunch
and Learn it could be like an email and
at the end you about cyber tip
developers and ops folks are going to
keep
a new tech whether we like it or not and
they will just go around us if we're not
on board you can create calendar bought
books for self training so I've done
this with my teams before where you know
every Tuesday from 2:00 to 4:00 we have
a learning block and we're all supposed
to be doing self based learning and I
know some of them just sit there and
answer emails but a bunch of them
learned a lot I used that over the
course of nine months to complete three
university courses and I remember my
manager was like whoa but two hours who
I was actually getting one hour but it
just it really worked out job shadowing
mentoring on-the-job learning sharing
information with other teams metric
space training so you know measuring how
things are doing and then making
training based on like what's going well
or it's not going well building your own
training was specific for your
organization that can be super powerful
okay so I have a quick story the time I
invents a DevOps it--it incentive house
and so one of my friends went to see me
give a talk well know one of my friends
told me someone came back from San
Francisco after seeing me speak and she
said yeah so apparently you invented
DevOps I said what she's like yeah I
seen your tech guy win he hadn't been on
training in over a decade and he saw her
talk about Deaf suck-ups and then he
thinks now that you invented it he
thinks you invented bops
as a whole he thinks it was you I never
said that and she's like yeah guys in
charge of projects and design issues and
he's never heard of DevOps before last
week when you told him apparently he
thinks you're really cool the point of
the story is that we can't not go in
training for a really long time because
we will end up with that guy and
although I think it's awesome that one
person in the world thinks I invented
DevOps
it's not really actually very good and
so if you feel you don't have enough
time to go for training and you haven't
gone for training in a long time you're
probably really billing it to prioritize
that
okay so conclusion little tiny reins
I am wicked tired of people thinking of
this guy when they think of our industry
I don't want them to think of this guy
this is what a hacker looks like this is
what a hacker looks like look in the
mirror I don't know if you can see other
people's faces on gotowebinar but that
is what a hacker looks like looks like
anyone it looks like a person who cares
a person that wants to help a person
that wants to protect others I feel if
we don't open up our idea of what our
industry looks like we're going to miss
out on amazing human beings that could
really help us take it to the next level
so that we actually start winning so
that we stop getting emails from have I
been combed all the time so I beg of you
to try to keep this in mind that this is
what a hacker looks like and this and
what you look like because we really
really need to open things up if we're
gonna have enough people in our industry
and one more please be nice to software
developers they are our friends in fact
all of IT are our friends we can't do it
without them I've seen so many security
people need mean to software developers
because they you know have bugs in their
software or like went around something
please be nice to them we need them we
need them on our side without them we
are so screwed and so that is the end of
my rant and now I'm going to give you
free resources so you can keep learning
so I believe Halifax has it an OS
chapter that's like sort of half started
so if you someone wants to restart it
but you can also join all of the tons of
virtual meetings online Ottawa and
Vancouver are both having lots and lots
of online meetings right now they're
open to everyone you could learn a ton
of cool new things I was probably a
better time slot for you than Vancouver
be pretty late for you but definitely I
love a loss I can't say enough good
things about them if you are a woman or
identify as a woman
well Seth welcomes you there is a very
active chapter and you can eat Karen and
Megan and yeah so we we welcome you to
join us group
and Cybermen Monday every Monday if you
have worked in industry for two or more
years you know enough to be a mentor
there's someone who wishes they knew
enough to do your job sending them a
book recommendation or a blog post or
having a virtual coffee with them like a
zoom session and talking out what
they're looking for and just sending
them off in the right direction these
are the things that will make people
join our industry and I cannot tell you
how much it means to someone a newcomer
to have someone take time for them and
try to help them along and if you are
trying to get into security or you need
help use this hashtag there's also ask
InfoSec if you just have a specific
one-off question I'm but I retweet this
all the time there's a whole bunch of us
that answer questions about this each
week so please come join us on Monday
and the last resource is me I have a
website I kept training I have blog
posts and videos and articles and like
all of the things I have a youtube
channel I have lots and lots of stuff
and so please follow me I'm biased but
me and my mom both think I'm super cool
my mom follows me on Twitter you should
too
but yeah I share a lots of stuff and do
lots of stuff like this because it's
really important to me that we further
the cause so what did we learn today we
learned about purple team we learned do
we have to collaborate if we want to be
good at apps heck and we learned modern
tools and practices for the win with
that I would like to thank you for your
time and attention today thank you very
much if you want to see my slides that
link at the top the bitly link it's not
a hack it's actually my slides are there
any questions all right I see some oh
there's a job section see them in there
I do have the questions all queued up
all ready to go Oh perfect yeah I can't
see them
okay no problem a lot of them were
filtered in through the destroyer
Channel we had going at the same time a
lot of good conversations going on
around your talk so that was great to
see as well so
the first question that came in was
around code do you have any preference
between having code signed as part of
the build pipeline versus a tool that
constantly monitors get for changes and
scans so I've never used code signing at
any of the places I've worked but not
because they did a great job of security
but because we were not that organized
before I switch to security I think that
monitoring gets really important I think
you could also sign your code I think
like you should be no one should be able
to be changing or checking anything and
to get that isn't an approved person so
that would like be disconcerting if you
have other people changing your code I
guess I'm saying I don't have a firm
opinion because I haven't had a chance
to use code signing and see what its
value proposition is based on that
person's protecting github instead fair
enough all right when we move on to
containers Japanese recommended
resources for learning about container
security or even just containers in
general what people hear about them a
lot of people think they know they do a
lot of people think they do and have no
idea actually what they do so on Twitter
I follow
Ian cold water Ian's really awesome and
knows a lot and shares a lot I'm also
I'm part of the wasp dev slope project
sloppy DevOps and we're an education
project we also build stuff too and
basically we're for nerds who just like
to build and break things together and
so we've had several different videos
about kubernetes about containers about
how to secure them we have like a bunch
of good content where basically we
interviewed and then got demos from like
a lot of famous people so whenever I
really want to learn something like I
show and then they keychain for free um
so I would definitely check out the dev
swap YouTube channel and then look up
look up containers because I'm sure we
have at least two or three shows on it
I'm pretty sure we have two or three
about kubernetes as well at least and
then we have a bunch of stuff about like
yeah setting them up in a drivers
I'm up in AWS I think we even have one
rjcp like we have a lot of episodes now
where we go in deep and it's like a
really good introduction for each of
them awesome
sticking with containers with them going
up and down so fast can you how can you
keep an inventory management on it or
detect if malicious one slip in a note
and so I think they're talking about
service is that what they're talking
about or containers what's mentioning
containers containers okay so if
someone's bring other containers into
your system the aren't supposed to be
there that's disconcerting if they're
bringing them up and down without your
knowledge that's disconcerting I'm
wondering um if they're talking about
them disappearing a lot if maybe they
meant circle is cuz serverless kind of
turns off and on like usually containers
are on most the time because it's
running your web app or it's running
your API like all the time that makes
sense yep totally but you should be
logging them and there are systems that
can help you organize them like service
mesh like to make sure that they're not
disappearing on you yeah I feel like I'm
a bit confused with the question I hope
that my information was helpful whoever
asked that if you want to like kind of
clarify a bit and the chat I would be
helpful excellent and with DevOps
pipeline where do they live in the
software development life cycle and what
gateway sorry miss reading him and what
gateway do they enter graciously is as
it's written okay so when I say a devops
pipeline I mean a CI CD pipeline so
continuous integration continuous
delivery and potentially continuous
deployment so basically we used to we
used to publish our code by like right
clicking and pressing publish or by
manually copying like files onto iis or
like onto the web server or whatever and
then we started coming up with like
systems to do it for us
and then eventually someone came up with
the idea of well what if we have a
system that automates that process and
so then they said well what if we have
it so it you know integrates the code
with the other code so if you have you
know ten people all working on the same
thing and you know I'm working all day
you're working all day we need to merge
our code and make sure that works we
used to do that in the code repository
and it's kind of messy and janky and we
wouldn't run it to see if it worked
but a CI CD what it does is like it
merges it but then it also like runs a
bunch of automated tests that you design
to see if it actually worked and it will
put it on to a test web server so you
can see oh like it's actually running it
does compile a sanity check checked but
what we want to make sure more things
run and so then both of us can keep
checking things in all the time and it
continues to integrate it and make sure
the pieces all work together and you can
add security tests in there and not too
many because you don't want to make it
really slow and piss everyone off but it
is a great way for you to be able to
automate a bunch of your security tests
that are the most important to you for
instance to make sure there's no secrets
that got in there like a username and
password combo you don't want that to be
and your github repo perfect that looks
like all the questions that we had come
in one thank you very much for taking a
time of your data kind of close out our
conference here is greatly appreciated
thank you thank you I really appreciate
you having me and thank you so much I
hope that I see you next year it's
perfect thank you very much you bye bye