thank you so I'm Thomas Watson
I'm a wyvern area stat VM ray and I'm
going to talk about the evolution of the
current car brands over and I lost the
signal
okay so first I want to say vice
interesting first of all it dominates
Durant's of our market currently it's
basically the only ransomware as a
service this year the second thing
that's interesting about it is that has
it has an edge I like development it
implements frequent and quick changes
and it started out as the most basic
possible runs over in January and now
it's more interesting it uses multiple
exploits and tracking it gets more
challenging because of the frequent
updates also it's uncommon for a
commercial my work to use exploits they
are Marvel authors are usually software
developers and that hackers so even if
there's an existing POC they are usually
not able to implement it in their own
mother that makes it even more
interesting that in August it burned a
zero day so they found zero day in a in
an antivirus software driver and they
managed to crash it we'll talk a lot
more about that zero day it's will try
to analyze it a bit more in detail to
find out how advanced the group really
is so the topics I'm going to talk about
is the business model that they use
ransomware the service I'm talking about
I'm talking about the delivery methods
that they used to get get the infection
to the victim talk about the Packer and
the evolution of the payloads over the
year and finally I will analyze the zero
day so to get you the
morning kind of driver exploit analysis
so the business model is ransomware is a
service this is a specific version of
the library service which is usually
used to distribute my work is this it
the business model separates the
developers of the malware and the
attackers the developers create an
easy-to-use service where the attackers
their affiliates just need to use web UI
and they need to click around to launch
attacks they don't need to be technical
at all or the technical development is
on the side of the developer this has
been our really successful and often
used business in the past few years but
it's slowly going out of out of fashion
this year partially because Ganz crab
took over the whole thing so you know
it's being distributed in a Russian
forum where they are trying to get you
affiliates and they are huge stars there
there's a line waiting to be a member of
their little Club and the attacker would
get a bad panel like this where they
need to click around they have a bunch
of information about their victims like
what is their IP what's what operating
system they use did they yet start dear
has the encryption yet started or have
they paid yet there's also a support
system where they can get support the
attackers can get support from the
developers or they can provide support
to the victims so if their victim wants
to pay but doesn't know how to purchase
cryptocurrency then
they help them out so the next thing to
talk about is the delivery method at
this point the attacker has the marver
but they need to need some way to get it
to the victim machine reliably these
delivery methods are achieved through
alliances the authors of the malware
don't create the delivery methods those
are created by some other developers and
they make some alliances with these
other groups so the most common way to
deliberate was yeah we are email
attachments they attached various
downloaders to it in JavaScript docx or
sometimes encrypted talks sometimes more
convoluted ways to download the axe' but
usually using attachments they also used
drive-by download via Web browser
exploits and more recently they mostly
switch to brute forcing RDP which is now
the more trendy way on the on the
underground forums so simple document
downloader would look like this when the
victim opens it it s ask them to enable
macros and when the macros are enabled
it executes this 800 Ryan VB script
which is basically just a string the
obfuscator it like changes the case and
advance them to each other reverses it
and does it in loops it for 800 lines
and finally comes up with a powershell
one-liner that downloads and executes
them are so more
tricky way to deliver it is just by
encrypting this dog and providing the D
password inside the email which is
useful if the victim has an email
appliance or something that scanning
attachments because the encrypt because
the attachment here will be just an
encrypted blob and the email appliance
won't really be able to extract the
password and decrypt it before it
reaches the before the victim open C so
another common method was browser
exploit kits these are also separate
services which have been around for many
years developing different strains of
Marber an exploit kits a browser exploit
kit contains already known browser
exploits on the server and when a web
server makes a request when a when a web
server gets a request then the user
agent is parsed and based on the user
agent it decides which exploit to
deliver these exploits are usually
expressed for outdated Internet Explorer
or outdated Flash Player so they
shouldn't usually work if the browser is
properly out updating but in some
environments the browser refresh pair is
not out updating so they are still
around this exploit gets a steer around
just much much fewer than a few years
ago and there's even a new one this year
it's called fallout so one of these
popular exploit kits was Rick on my
execution it used a known Flash Player
exploit which is use of the free runner
ability inside flash players DRM
implementation so it needs an SPF file
which is an ActionScript inside and this
it was weird because it was partly
obfuscated but the relevant part was not
associated and it also used debug
symbols so the part that loud
the use after free vulnerability was
just called UAF generator and the
currently common method is RDP they are
looking for open RDP process and rule
forcing them which is it enables them to
do more targeted stuff so they can
target some organization specifically it
allows them to ask for bigger ransom but
fewer victims it's currently the more
trendy method of delivering around
somewhere
it's partly because they are hoping for
bigger profits and also because they
like to feel like hackers but they don't
really know how to properly to any kind
of hacking but they can do a simple
brute-forcing on an RDP port so it's
interesting how they are getting the
open RDP ports they are probably not
scanning scanning the whole internet
themselves but they are likely using
shodhan which is a search engine for
security related stuff and if you search
for remote desktop you will find 2.5
million
open RDP ports which you can then brute
force and so I also want to talk about
the backer
now that the now that this sample is
delivered it needs to evade antivirus
and it needs to make analyzes of it
harder especially automated analyzes and
for these marvered uses packers so I
want to I have no time to analyze the
whole Packer but I want to highlight
some techniques that it uses this is a
technique called API hammering it's a
sandbox evasion technique in a sandbox
sample would get launched inside a
virtual machine and it would run for a
few minutes and
the sandbox would analyze the results of
what it what behavior it executed inside
the VM so one way to bypass it is to
wait so try to reach the timeout but if
they would call a simple sleep function
that would be mitigated by the sandbox
and the sleep wouldn't have been
executed which is why they are trying to
just do a long loop where they are
calling a function or incrementing a
variable over and over again many times
but mitigation for this also exists
because these unnecessary loops
unnecessary loops can be detected and
automatically skipped so what they
implement here is that they try to
obfuscate the the condition and also do
a single useful function call inside the
loop so it cause causes loop 20 million
times but in one of the iterations it
also loads a library so this library is
neat later so if the library is not
loaded and the model won't work so the
loop cannot be skipped easily simple map
method it uses just the post occation on
the stack it moves the opposite it
coding for byte chunks of the stack it
adds and subtracts constants from it to
get the final payload and in a more
recent version they added a simple anti
disassembly trick right they this is a
van known trick that is a method of
control flow food station the cool
instruction just jumps to the next
function the next instruction and also
adds the address of the next instruction
to the stack and then it can be
incremented so when Delphis gated it
looks like this it just it changes the
address on the stack it pops it into a
X and jump stir so this is a pretty old
technique they probably find it by just
googling anti disassembly and this is
the first result that they found so it
makes sense that when is figured out
that is complicated to ACTU Packer that
they try to hire someone else to do it
there are already commercial Packers
available and they wanted to find out
which one is the better this one
so they made a competition so whoever
gets them the best Packer it will get
recommended to their affiliates and
that's a constant revenue for the
authors of the Packer
and it will get more revenue for the
attackers themselves so it's a
profitable alliance for them and that's
basically the Packers current state now
that the the sample is delivered its
unpacked it might have bypassed security
products and now it's time to execute
the actual ransomware payload which
evolved a lot since January and I'm
going to talk about its evolution now so
it's starting point is basically what it
does is basically a constant through all
versions with some minor changes first
it collects data it this is the data
that's displayed displayed on the web
panel that the attacker uses it has it
called X the domain host name processor
named Windows version and collect
currently running antivirus software
world software's and also the number of
drives and the free space on them it's
more interesting that it queries the
public IP address from an external
service like what is my IP this is
easily detectable and it's interesting
that it's also carrying if
keyboard is Russian it's specifically
looking for a Russian keyboard it
queries the keyboard language compares
it to the Russian constant and stores it
as a boolean instruction or not so then
it does check into the command and
control server it uploads all of this
data and then the server can decide
based on this if they want to encrypt or
not so if they want to encrypt they need
to send a response if there's no
response and then the encryption won't
start in the initial version this is the
drawback of this for the attacker is
that if the server goes offline then the
encryption won't happen so if there is a
response from the command and control
server then it kills the processes that
it needs to like these are processes
that would hold an open handle to the
files that it wants to encrypt
so if worked holds a handle to a doc
file then it can't decrypt can't encrypt
the doc file so it needs to kill word
then it encrypts all of the files based
based on an extension list and then
finally removes Windows is shadow copies
which can could be used to restore some
of the data it's interesting that to
remove shadow copies you need
administrator privileges and most
ransomware just doesn't try to escalate
privileges adjusts it tries to remove
the shadow copies even if it int if it
doesn't work that it doesn't work it
doesn't care so after all of this it
puts a ransom note which is which has a
which has an onion link and the
instructions to have to download tor so
when the user download it or they can
browse to the page where they can pay
the ransom and they needed to pay it in
- yeah so I want to talk about the
specifics of the first version it was
released in January it used a yes to
encrypt
and the command-and-control server was
on dot beat TLD domains which can be
resolved by windows directly so in so
they needed to resolve the domains
themselves and they look used nslookup
to do that which is also a dead giveaway
so it's easy to detect and for the first
version they could maybe - only
development in February in the end of
February was that Europol released the
Decrypter for it which the victims could
use to get their files back a week later
the authors of the ransomware admitted
that their infrastructure was hacked
so that's likely the source of the
Decrypter and they added a new version
which for which the Decrypter didn't
work they also change the extensions of
the of the encrypted files to make it
more difficult to track and they and
they started looking for clairemaude ad
components in the next version they
added that the change in the wallpaper
they generate this image dynamically and
they personalize it for the user so it
contains the username and they also
change the user agent which also makes
it a bit harder to track in the next
version there was a bigger leaf right
they changed that encryption algorithm
from a esta salsa it's likely because
they want it to manifest an encryption
of many xx files they if the encryption
takes too long then the victim I just
realize what's going on and stop the
process then they also start encrypting
Network shares and they remove the
ransomware after it's done encrypting
everything
for later it's important taste that they
started using these log files they put
these files with dot lock extension to a
folder to signal that it started being
encrypted and they change the extension
again it's interesting that they removed
the connection to their
command-and-control server and they do
not create the public hyper IP address
anymore so the country completely
removed everything that's network
related which makes it stats here it's
more difficult to track and detect but
it also removes features so if there is
no comment and control connection then
their users are not getting the fancy no
data which is which might be bad for
their business because it's a missing
feature so in a few days a
command-and-control collection was back
and this time they moved it from their
own domains to hacked WordPress sites
and they started using a URL generation
algorithm to generate a list of which
whereas the contact so if you remember
the log files from two slides back they
are put in a folder to signal for the
ransomware that that folder is already
being encrypted and not to encrypt it
again this allowed an anti-virus company
to create a vaccine for it they put a
log file in one of the directories and
the ransomware will not look in
subdirectory Stan and what encrypt
anything so this was pretty short-lived
for four days after there was a new
version that defeated the vaccine and
that day later there was a version 2 of
the vaccine two days later there was
again a new version against a new
vaccine and they probably realized that
this doesn't really make sense so
vaccination is good if if the
development cycle is long if they would
if the Marberry authors would have taken
once to deliver
the new version then it would make sense
but if it's taking a date and the
vaccine is useless so they didn't
release a third version of the vaccine
however a few weeks later the canticle
butters released a new version which had
which had a zero day for the antivirus
companies drivers and they didn't really
use it for any function they just did it
as a retaliation they included a string
inside the marver that's a message to
the antivirus company it says that they
they even the score and they they found
denial of service one regret in it and
they think that it might be developed
into a privilege escalation it's
interesting that they also added a link
which is a link to the POC it's of so
it's a link to the source code of the
exploit so they did this more as a full
disclosure naturally as a as an
exploitation we'll talk about this later
towards the end so the newer version is
version 5 and they added some privilege
escalation exploits which allows them to
remove shadow copies and encrypt files
that they wouldn't have been able
otherwise these are known exploits one
of them is from a full disclosure
somebody will released Blewett
escalation Windows exploits on Twitter
as a full disclosure and a few weeks
later they implemented it in in there
and somewhere which is basically what
happens if you are doing full disclosure
and they also fully randomized the
extension this time another interesting
development is that there was a
decrypter again released by bitdefender
which decrypts the extreme victims files
it's based on a
the graphic arrow that's made by the
ransomware routers so but twelve hours
later there was a new version which
fixed the fixative vulnerability so in
its current state
there is no descriptor for the knot
somewhere the file extension is
randomized and comunicados server
connection is less obvious and and it
also has some chance for privilege
escalation so that's basically the
current state of the of the marver now I
can talk about the zero-day that is used
it's the vulnerability the exploit kit
sub-b sod it makes a blue screen of
death because it's crashing a car driver
but it doesn't really get code execution
that could be used for privilege
escalation so in its current state it's
not really usable and also the exploit
works on its own but the scenes but they
put it inside the ransomware and the
ransomware is detected by the antivirus
so it never really reaches this code and
it's interesting to see why they did it
because and acidotic costs a lot of
money so it's very unusual to burn a
zero-day and even when they even when
they burn it it has a purpose so they
don't just burn money for no reason and
they transfer routers before the release
contacted a new site and told them that
it this is a retaliation and they were
expecting it to be a huge reputation
problem for the antivirus vendor they
basically really overestimated the
impact of the exploit that they found
they thought that this would like bring
down the company or something in reality
it didn't really make the news it's and
it's not really that relevant because it
was fixed really quickly so really it's
a
increase the reputation of the antivirus
vendor because it shows that they know
how to handle my liberty so I should
show how how it happens I don't know if
I have the fire ok thank you ok I
successfully language the video so first
I want to start from the POC that was
released that was linked inside the
marver No so it contains a bunch of
Russian folders but the part that we
care about is the POC that CBP which has
a preamble that they say they claim that
they are the author of the exploit and
was and target of the exploit there's a
run POC function which is important to
us it's it just does three things really
it acquires a handle to the driver then
it sends it to device IO control
functions if you're in user mode that's
how you can communicate with the kernel
driver by sending it a device IO control
function with a specific control code
and the control code defines what a
function will run inside the driver so
this control codes the one of them they
called IO CTO set address and the the
other one is ioctl trigger so we see
that there the control code a in
hexadecimal form a start with an 8
means that these are custom defines
control codes by the driver and that
Windows is predefined ones so to
understand them we need to reverse
engineer the driver but first I want to
try if the PLC actually works this is
the antivirus and when I lounge the PLC
it should crash and it crashed it's not
visible yet it just assets everything is
interests in responsive windows will
make memory damp and reboot it okay so
the reboot happens the exploit worked
I've tried to save us some time okay
so after the reboot we can windows
generated dump
I'm already dumped so we can open that
memory dump it windbg and it will
hopefully give us some useful stuff that
you'll get us started
ok so it's I got first in the video but
it give us a stack so on the stack we
can see that it's that it's calling this
this strawberry and we see the offset
and we also see that in the final final
call if we call this this anti function
which will finally caused the crash ok
so now we need but now we know which
file and that velocity is causing the
crash we can open it in either and look
look at what happens there
so this is where the crash happens it's
calling that a function that we saw in
the in the memory dump and and we can
see that it's calling it with with that
with two parameters one body one
variable and one other parameter this is
for acquiring resource you need to edit
a pointer where to acquire the resource
from so if we change this variable into
something that's not a not a valid
location then it will crash the driver
which is exactly what they did so we
need to see where this variable is set
it can only be set at one place now so
we follow follow this location up we
follow it up first I named it right
ma'am then I follow it up the stack and
we arrived at a large switch case where
the ioctl control codes are defined the
it's defined what to do with each i/o
city a control code and we can see that
this is the Osito control code that they
use for the i/o city or settlers so this
is how they are changing this variable
into something that's a pointer to a
non-existing Wow so it does we don't
really need it that much so they change
it into a variable that's pointing to
another non-existing address and they do
the i/o city a call to set the address
all right
they do one call to set the address and
they do another call to read it and it
crashes a driver and we want to know how
advanced they really are because it's
really uncommon for someone to for a
group like this to find an exploit it's
usually done by nation states or
something that's someone that's more
resourceful so you see that this is very
simple and they probably just fast it
and if you analyze it further we'd see
that turning it into a code execution
would be pretty difficult because it's
not really doing anything to write the
death location so based on based on the
analysis we can make a profile for this
adversary the first thing that we saw is
that this big Russian they post in
Russian forum and they have special
handling for a Russian local which could
all be false Flags it doesn't
necessarily mean that they are Russian
and it's honestly not even that
important the nationality is not
important from a defenders point of view
it's more important what their
capabilities are and based on the
analyzes we can set upper and lower
boundaries to their capabilities so we
see that they have pre-existing
experience with marketing ransomware the
service on the specific forum they know
how to handle that forum very well they
know the they know what their users want
so it's likely that this is not first
and some of the service that they
marketing got marketed on this forum or
a similar one we also see that their
development is organized in a enough to
react quickly to changes and it's the
reaction times are getting quicker it
was one week for the first Decrypter and
it was 12 hours for the most recent one
oh but they are not organized enough for
all releases to work properly is
sometimes it is non-working versions or
versions that only worked on specific
operating systems so what do the
releases are quick they are not
organized enough to
always deliver a proper release which
makes missing everything that they are
not really doing proper agile they just
implemented the quick development part
we also saw that they are capable of
implementing excavators based on POCs we
saw this with the privilege escalation
exploits and they are also capable of
finding a simple exploit via fuzzing but
they are not capable of developing a
more complex or more complex exploit
that would get some good execution that
they didn't need and they are also not
capable of casting the reputation impact
of an exploit which leads us to believe
that this might be their first try they
are not experienced in vulnerability
research and that's basically all of
what I wanted to say thank you
thank you very much for this every
comprehensive study we have time for a
few questions yes thanks for the
presentation I wanted to know if you
have an idea of the improvement of the
random quit Oh run somewhere as an
impact of the I dunno diffusion anti
viruses why people want to do several
versions I didn't really say so why
people were designing one somewhere I
want to do several different version
what is the impact of the first v1 on
the antivirus is on the second one and
so on so what impact it has that they're
racing quickly yeah right so it creates
more work because they need to track new
versions and if there's there frequent
releases then it's more difficult to
track another question
yeah I'd like to know what kind of file
size are we dealing with here are the
size requirements of the file is to be
very small or is it several Meg's what
they Marvel itself or the encrypted
files for the email attachment for
example the inner attachment is small
because it's just a dropper and so it's
pretty small and then the whole virus to
download afterburn mojo so the
downloaded Marvel itself is like a few
megabytes okay that's someone else I
have a question for you why did you
choose this family is it representative
of a new trend of foreign somewhere it's
not new in a sense that it's ransomware
has been around forever but it's new in
a sense of that it's developing more
quickly than usual and it's using
exploits like it's not usual so let's
thank you the speaker again thank you