okay are we ready to go check check
everybody well Josh blog of Mars and he
could speak about the back
I thank you for the introduction
that's how everybody my name is Joshua
Clark I work with the check marks
we are you how many folks have heard of
check marks
ok maybe a third of the room ok so what
check marks is just a quick and short as
Clark checkmarks you basically we build
products first static application
security analysis what we do is were
basically code analysis
static code analysis we never basically
an engine that scans numerous
programming languages
how we support many different platforms
and we'll be talking about some of that
today but the purpose of my talk today
is I'm sure some of you guys are
probably interested in the the plan
words here because this is a very
familiar with Game of Thrones and
hopefully everybody right so that's
that's kind of the the title that we use
here to kind of get the get the interest
and hence the honey pot thing that we
basically built to get people to come to
our site that gather interest
so just a quick a quick briefing on me
and my background I've spent
I like to go i don't really have a title
check marks that kind of just make it up
as I go but I like to come up with this
one today jack of all hacks masters
nothing
many people say jack of all trades
master number i do all kinds of hacking
a both black hat the black packing a
white hat in grey hat that the whole the
whole gamut over my short career in the
industry i probably spent about five
years building stuff in the last five
and a half six years
breaking stuff so I got you no
experience in both sides in the last
five years I've worked for a bunch of
big companies HP IBM i'm working with
checkmarks work with all many of
different tools both in the
we'll call it the black box tools and
white box tools
- sassed grass below the whole the whole
gamut and what I'm here to talk to you
today about is a game of hacks the
monitor the mother of all honey pots and
basically what we're going to talk about
today i'll give you the quick agenda
I'm basically how we're going to spend
our time over the next 45 minutes
typically how you like to do talks five
minutes on a quick intro overview spent
about 20 30 minutes of content and 10
minutes for questions people he said .
questions at the end and basically this
is the agenda we're going to talk about
what is game hacks
what was the purpose of game of hacks
what was behind it you know why we how
we came up with this and where we you
know how we how we came up that the
third point here
i'm sorry i'm just going to tell me real
quick okay
were you ever now and ok alright thanks
so on now go ahead I like that yes and
no background music for all I just like
listen to myself talking just you know
that puts me at ease
ok so back to the agenda here at third
part of we come over and not so wet a
typical we have it
you know where my venue will do it wet
t-shirt contest yeah I like those those
types of events but anyways we're gonna
have a not so wet t-shirt contest for
all you folks in here so we have a
little contest we have to pay attention
you can't sleep I don't know anybody you
know make sure you do have your mobile
phones and your laptop's because there's
going to be interactive session
it's not going to be a typical one right
to sleep here in lecture you're actually
be interacting and answering some
questions so pay attention all the
slides that you know
pay attention keep going to have a quiz
throughout and it'll be pretty pretty
fun and then once we get through our
little contest they also have a given
giveaway so I have a surprise appeared
whoever has the high score gets a prize
and then after we get through the
contest
we're actually going to get into some
some more content with no Jas so
potential risks with the node.js
platform how many of you know about no
Jess
ok like six to eight people raise their
hands okay well according to this talk
it will is about no Jess so if you don't
know i'm going to explain what no Jas is
kind of give you the what's what and
who's who got no Jess so you can
actually learn about it and understand
it so security implications and why you
should care about the platform and then
finally we'll just talk about some quick
take away and leave the rest for some
Q&A
ok alright so interesting slide that we
have here take a quick look at it
this also is kind of interesting because
today is we're doing the you know we
have the lobby we have the vendors from
the vendor space
I know some of the attendees come up and
look at the the board that we have set
up there it's very similar to just a
different different code snippets but
it's different
basically same thing folks come up and
they look at the code and they sit there
and they ponder and they go boom
what was that one ability or you know
what is that what is that code that's
basically how this is the idea came
about a few my colleagues attend
attended a black hat and they had walked
up to a booth and they saw some code on
up on a board and said they were
pondering you know what what's wrong
with this code or what security
implications other in this code
how many of you guys have attended a
black hat or def con conference
some couples okay well that's kinda like
the the industry staple of your
insecurities like black hats kind of
like that
the de facto standard for for security
conferences held in Las Vegas every year
think it's coming up in the next month
so if you're interested try to try to go
out there and check it out
but anyways that's where this idea came
from basically and also if you ever see
a lot of times you go to these
conferences people's shirts
where they have like different times of
light snow everywhere like binary or so
we have some code under sure we actually
have some teachers that we give away you
attend the conference some of those
t-shirts that have code no code elements
that basically try to debug or try to
figure out what the security
vulnerabilities and source code so
that's basically how this came about and
so taking that idea
taking a step forward basically what we
decided to do with this
this idea of grabbing source code was
too
I mean with that idea in mind the other
the other big concept here is how many
of you are familiar with us
ok so many of your mother's ok so you're
familiar with the wasp as you know
there's typically serve as they they've
given out and over the course of time
basically these surveys event told the
couple things one of the most important
things with respect to application
security is that basically what it comes
down to is security awareness for
developers
so there was a survey that was sent out
basically two different to see sales
across all different industries and
basically the net of it was that
developers are just you know they're
they're not really security folks they
don't really have any security awareness
they don't typically get security
training and that's basically the whole
kind of made the major point here about
around this whole game of hacks
illustration in the demonstration is
that developers
you know the primary use case primary
thing that developers with most focusing
on and I can attest this case to be a
developer was I was writing functional
code i just want to write some code get
it to work
push it and ship it out I wasn't really
focused on i mean when i first started
writing writing code I didn't really
have a clue about and what sequel
injection what's cross-site scripting
what's HTTP response splitting you know
what what are these concentrated no
clothes and I grab some code of ok i
guess you get some background background
music for ya
anyways a long story short here the
whole bed of this is that developers
typically are trained on security
concepts
typically they learn how to learn a
programming language in the University
and you know go to university learn how
to do coding learn how to write some
application code talk to me and pull
some data from a web behind on the web
page and then you put that into a
database and you know click on the forum
button right some JavaScript and
go on to the next piece of code there is
really no cutting no no
we'll talk about security and it's it's
it's more it's more prevalent today
because every day you know on the news
there's a new hack it comes out of me
that's kind of why we're all here to
learn about and security topics and
whatnot so it's kind of finish up here
with this point about game of hacks in
the honey pot you know this is this is
another big piece of piece of it is that
also with this this concept that we come
up with is that you can use it as an
educational tool right
so think about your own organization for
a minute you have your organization you
guys all have domain specific code right
if you're working in healthcare and
healthcare domain specific code you work
in government you might have domain
specific code you can use it as a tool
for the concepts that we have here with
a map packs and his honey pot too kind
of train your developers in the code
that you have a particular maybe
particular of problems that you find you
know over and over in your code and
train your own team of developers on how
to write better code and so right now if
you want you can actually go out to on
your mobile device on your laptop if you
want you can go out and go to a game of
hacks com
and what you'll see is you actually go
to our website you know we own the
domain and we basically we launched this
in august of 2014
and since then we had about I mean to
this date I just check the stats
yesterday we got about a hundred twenty
thousand i heard her and 20,000
participants people that have actually
logged on ran through it and actually
tried to you know sit go through the
question because basically what it does
I'm actually just show it for everybody
so if they don't have their machine up
i'll go ahead and just sit here so
you - Jessica space well I'll display
here we are - place you can see it
so you should be able to see my screen
here
so game of
max see how good you are you can go in
there you can play single player you can
challenge your friend and basically what
you are able to do here with gamefaqs
click single player you can pick your
your difficulty level you can pick
whether you think you're a beginner
intermediate or advanced and they can go
out there and for example you know Sam
start playing and go out go out now
start the game up and it's going to ask
you some code SQ would security run a
business in this code block and you have
to go out there and answer it and that's
essentially what are you know what our
whole you know this whole talk is going
to basically be about as a demonstration
of this
okay so me go back here to the
presentation him just to kind of talk
about
we're going to go a little bit deeper
than just with the game covers but the
net of it is not only do we get a
hundred twenty participants but in doing
that we also did something else anybody
else see what else we did with with
setting up a site like this and and kind
of doing something like this any other
ideas that you could think of in the
title of the talk so title
honey pop right getting people to come
to the site and getting them to you know
getting them submit their information
basically collecting you know trying to
get people to come to our site and get
information from them get them to upload
their information to our website some
other statistics about our game of hacks
website was not only do we get over a
hundred twenty thousand users to our
website
we also got over 500 code submissions
right of different code fragments from
different teams and different variations
think about that's basically like free
you know now also if you think about our
business right we're doing code analysis
right want to see different types of
code
we just got 500 or like 500 three
different types of code snippets across
multiple different languages and which
could or could not have security
vulnerabilities in them so kind of like
free security testing uh just by setting
up a honey products think about it and
then also a total amount of games played
is over we had over a hundred twenty
thousand unique visitors and over 200
30 thousand games played so people
definitely been utilizing our our site
and kind of playing around
so pretty cool stuff there with game
hacks and so again just to kind of talk
about those kind of key elements behind
game of hacks and kind of what it was
was meant to do
there's a bigger the number one thing
here with the with being that it was a
honey pot was that we also went out
there and Google into some particular
hacker forums and just like with
anything if you know any of the
different type of hacker forms that out
there
the folks that were playing the game
we're actually talking about it right
so they were actually out there
commenting about different types of
vulnerabilities they were finding within
the game now we knew about that
you know setting it up we did that
intentionally alright so we knew people
going to try to hack just that's the
kind of the whole game the whole purpose
of doing a honeypot to kind of set
people up that you know they're going to
try to hack you and then you try to try
to hack them or try to capture the
information and so as you can see here
some of the comments here from this
this gentleman he basically put on your
and said hey you know it tries to teach
security but it fails that security
because it has no basically has a
vulnerability in it
and ironically the you know the game is
easy to hack
he is an easy game to hack about finding
and security bugs and basically we have
like that we assume the game would be
hacked
we might as well learn from it learn
from what what folks are going to do it
because we were rebuilt this the
platform that we built it on
i was  second  at the time
when this came out was it was around to
the new platform which is no Jas I had a
mongo show you the architecture here and
also the vulnerabilities that we found
from the the users that were hacking are
basically hacking her honeypot basically
use those to enhance our product right
because we have a code scanner product
and this is kind of with things that you
didn't
if you look here basically it's a
client-server architecture you log into
a browser or mobile device
you hit the the know Jas front end
basically it's a server sitting on a
Roco instance with the MongoDB database
basically people log in you place a
single player or you can share code as
it said in the beginning
basically that's kind of the
architecture of what we set up for this
impacts game basically once you login
you know I did you say i can show you
some of this already but basically talks
about getting the score level the type
of question that you have more than one
of the answers and then you get the code
snippet and then you get to you can get
to . and kind of play against your
friends so typically don't know how many
of you guys used to be developers for
our developers
ok maybe a couple or used to be mostly
developers are kind of like eating
I'm just saying I i know i would kind of
wasn't as a developer I always wanted to
be you know compete with other
developers so it's kind of a lot of
developers and they play this game you
know they want to compete against each
other so that's kind of why make a game
and then they compete and then you kind
of the best guy win so it's kind of fun
I mean that's that's kind of the whole
essence I think that's why this headset
so was so successful when we created it
because developers always want to know
so every developer wants to be the the
best in the developer within your team
so it's a kind of interesting in that
regard so so we actually play another
game that I haven't told you about yet
so I do want you guys to get your
devices
what if you have phone got your phone
your mobile device or iPad or you know
whatever whatever kind of ice you have I
want you to go to a website this website
here called dub dub dub
Kahoot that I tea ok
I want you
there you're going to need to enter a
code now once this loads up here
go ahead and do player versus player see
it started here so that
pin so once you go ahead and punch that
when you go to complete an IT punching
that a hat pin code and it was going to
ask you to put in the username
now put in something relatively unique
to yourself to your nickname or whatever
we come up with something uh something
interesting got 10 players 12 13
remember there's a prize you participate
and you do happen to win
there's a price so more more the merrier
here will give it a look at it
excuse me I can't hear you saying
yeah yeah - yeah yeah go ahead and login
we're going honey pot you steal your
credit dr. device
huh we'll give it another minute here
and then we'll go ahead and start the
game and you can you cannot just
remember the pin
that's the pin to join
ok yeah this is this is a funny little I
great gap video here in the back this
dam is go if it just keeps going on and
kick any other goats it's pretty funny
all right let's go ahead and just play
this game here so we'll start this guy
up
there's ten questions
ok so basically you got 10 seconds to
answer
so go ahead and go off and uh the answer
to start popping over here as people go
through
ok so we had all right so some people
are comfortable this is it was just a
question just to see if if you are
comfortable in your seat
ok so we gotta go to get you get seven
small ok you guys still see all right
great
so it's just a sample questions and
hopefully a suggest you get it right
all right let's go ahead question number
two
this is just a test to make sure that
you guys are all pretty smart here
all right great
everybody got that right so - I promised
the other ones are going to be actually
hear about security is going to be math
problems for you want to become so we
can also see who's in the right that's
the picture and then you're here
let's go to the next question
alright so using the original leave here
cool chain saws all right we got mac aod
hey
alright so here we go now what your
vulnerability is exposed in this code
block is probably can't see it
well I guess we can't can't blow it up
anymore but uh for those of you that can
see it see it on your phone
can't do much with the the imager
cool
so how many you guys got a right for all
right so yeah basically
the problem with this one we look at the
code here
basically we have a response here that
we pull in or basically pulling the
request and we use that to build
basically do a basically a uncontrolled
format string in this case
so again you validate input in this case
but pretty straightforward here
all right let's go to the next one so
hey you're you're in the lead
all right another code problem hopefully
this images bigger to you since it or
you can be able to see it in your phone
you're playing phone all right basically
deaf read file reader request in and
take that then we have another method
here called are not object request we
have the response and then you say
request I get read that file then
finally open a file loop over it you
write some stuff out
what can we do here
path traversal so six you guys got it
right
all right guys are you doing okay
I don't know we'll see who's using the
leader hey hey still up there so we'll
find out who that is hoping that they
they wind up with it
all right next one here's a chance for
extra points for those folks that have
been happy to get the code once right
yeah it was pretty easy this one you got
a system that you got a 50-50 shot on
this one
so hopefully uh so we can get this right
there you go ok so i guess somebody in
fact it
so you guys didn't watch them and Jerry
when you guys were kids but that's okay
how the cat is is Tom just so just so
you know I couldn't watch some some
loony tunes and saturday morning or to
revisit that one
he's having he's having fun anybody
having fun yet
yeah ok cool right ok yeah so hopefully
it's more fun than somebody stuck but
alright next one here back to that oh
hey you're still on top
the only up and top by 40 points self so
eltron yeah it was 40
okay you're close yep alrighty l-tron
let's see if you can do it got four more
left here what vulnerability is exposed
in this code you have a PHP block here
to start a session you check to see if
some values are set and we go file DB
new PDO do a prepared statement we
inserted basically do prepared statement
insert into an object we do some
parameter binding
who most yes I thought that was sequel
injection
no there's binding that's being done so
it's not a problem with that it's a
problem with cross-site request forgery
how do you guys know a cross-site
request forgery is ok I guess only four
people per day something that hurts
there for people are just lucky
but anyways basically what cross-site
request forgery is it's a little harder
to determine basically there's an
operation that securing but it could be
occurring on the perhaps you could get
you could get somebody else to execute
that on be on your behalf so say i'm
logged in in my session and I click on a
link and i execute an activity
somebody sent me a link and i execute an
activity I'm not they get me to do
something on my behalf that I'm not
supposed to do so basically getting you
to do something and when i'm logged in
in this case that's what that will do is
create do to make it basically making
some kind of data operation on behalf of
someone else
ok l-tron hey you got kicked off the top
Ultron's the pop only by three points
though this is getting close
all right here next year so question 7
so here's one question think about the
game that we're playing right now right
client-server what limitation might we
run into if the client randomizes the
answer order for example these answer
orders
what's what's impossible it's a possible
problem with this one
somebody was asking about background
music I think we got it
the game so yes this is up you guys a
seven you guys get this right that's
good
basically this one the server won't know
which ones they wrote the correct answer
in that case the client does a even
randomizing
the order of the answers ok I'll try
yours
you're still top have you got a pretty
good lead oh oh oh yeah that I come up
alright so in this case who should be
validating answer correctness client or
the server
this should be it again 50-50 shot on
this one
trying to give you guys a quick easy for
you here
so again and in the concept of this game
right
this concept of this game we're playing
here right so the unlucky person here
that pic the client it's not the clients
the service service service should
always be validating which example the
server knows which answer is correct so
it's you know how to validate which
answer is correct
ok cpus process for that
that's better alright so I'll turns up
there your mom is getting up there is
getting close
all right hey you back in your clothes
get two more left
now what is the problem here with no Jas
this no Jess could not only a couple of
you know no jazz so this might be a
little bit more difficult but it's
pretty simple code base here it's just a
job
ap eyes are you know it's basically this
could be any language doesn't have to be
no chance to Java C sharp jump anything
ok so the problem here with that code
block was that the client can answer the
same question multiple times
basically it's if you have that image
here right so user response is a
response to save him there's no way for
it to know
in that case which which one is the the
right answer
ok so let's go back here we got one more
left see see who's a so hey you're still
the top I'll try on your clothes your
mom you're only about a hundred less
than hundred points off so you have a
chance here the last one
all right drum roll but over all right
let's do it
so last one here which item in the score
calculation and the formula do you think
while based on the hackers that were
packing our money pot which cut which
value do you think they were able to
hack the quickest
my guess is 60
alright so
ok let me you guys got a right it's good
yeah basically in this one
yeah that the client can can modify the
the time to answer they can basically
modify that value on the client and
change the value they were able to
basically specify a value i'll show you
this here in a minute let's see who our
winner is
hey hey you okay so who's hey how there
you go hard so I got a surprise for you
ready for this awesome price
ok you have just received
I'll hub USB hub now we can give them a
positive
so any of you guys all the other losers
in the room if you guys want to stop by
the booth after you come by and get a
free a USB drive for your participation
in today's game
so thank you very much for playing that
was a somewhat fun and enjoy it so yeah
thank you for playing here
this is this is a fun little game you
can also use this for young
if you're interested up i find to be
pretty a pretty useful little game here
we doing presentations but any go
the code that i provide early the pin
that I've tried it
um so yeah the code in game hacks we
don't provide that that's not provided
but the would you asking about the
desert code rocker
yeah you can use that pin but that's
only gonna let you ever play that game
so you can you play the game a bunch of
times if you want but you know who I t
is that so it's this little site that
allows you to create create your own
games but anyways game hacks a lot of a
lot of cool value here with this but
let's get back to the presentation here
see we're doing there now
ok cool we got about 20 minutes left
with you get so let's take a look here
at a just kind of
back to some of the elements of of
answered questions so initially users a
initiated
basically what with this gentleman here
that the guy that uh basically hacked
your application with the the answer
question elements basically allowed them
to submit the answer multiple times
until they get so if you had enough if
you have any other hand the timer
basically what you could do is if you
ran basically a script in your browser
app that send answers
you could send the answer multiple times
to the server and it would it would you
can do it until you got it right
so you can just go right a little quick
loop and say submit all the answers
you got the right one enough time you
can do that in the JavaScript console
window in the browser and I get the
answer because we didn't have a flag on
the server side to say hey this question
is already been answered
right you can keep submitting the answer
until you get it right
we didn't have a flag and the code to
prevent that so that's the solution is
to prevent that right actually have a
flag that's just kind of more of a not
really a security I mean it's not really
security she's more of a functional and
if you're creating a game engine you
probably want to have a flag in there
and say hey to answer is already been
the questions have been answered
don't let them answer again that's one
one piece
the other available component here game
hacks in RM - these are also specific to
our our game of hacks that we that we
created was also the timer so the first
version we let that the timer was
handled by the client so the client said
code that was executing was basically
that answer plus the time spent to the
server
so any you know militia any no hacker
that Daniel was installed there could
have actually went out and just change
the value to extend the time
right so the time time spent could have
you basically just change that value to
a big number and then they could have
take as much time as they want to try to
figure out them the question
right and that's basically be able to do
that by modifying that the JavaScript on
the client side and then again our
friends and the hacker forms decided to
you know like that I didn't get to think
about hackers and a few days agree with
me but i'm pretty sure you probably do
you like to kind of a you know blog and
talk about what they do and say show off
and so
Hey look at what I've done you know this
is a you know this is basically what I
did and this is how I did it
so here you go so okay so let's keep
going here so in a printed version 2 of
game of hacks time is not computed at
the server level with a little bit of a
impact and latency but not too much
so that's basically what we did we
change the second version we included a
timer version in the name of an
explosion - okay so what else what else
could be an issue with the timer the
ideas
well this
this is one
and out through again through the hacker
forms basically you're using an iphone
if you played on iphone you can pause
the time or by holding your finger on
the iphone screen
it's pretty a pretty interesting little
hack
now we didn't even know that but again
our friends here in the hacker community
they did and they they posted about it
so something fun some things that you
know kind of a pretty interesting things
that you can come up with you know you
in the wild as you kind of put these
days honey pots out in the wild and let
people kind of go and play with them and
they post a bunch of their you know
their experience out on the web for Rita
really see so many questions about game
of hacks any general questions about
what we've done there i mean i got a
whole another 20 minutes here have some
more technical and for them and walk you
through but at the impacts level of you
get a chance go out and play the game
you can also go out there when you can
also submit your own code if you want
you can go out there and play against
your friends
it's pretty cool pretty cool game it
really tests your your skill level like
if you think you're you know like I'm
all I know application security and you
know expert go out there and try to play
expert in a good try to try something
coats
it's pretty interesting to see how you
do see how you fare ok so with that any
questions about the game of tax game
okay all right well let's go ahead and
talk about
we're going to go into more know Jas I
want to get into kind of talk to you
about what no Jas it no Jas is the
platform talk about the database talk
about all the implications with building
platforms on know Jas and that's
basically how we build game of hacks so
it's kind of whether they're not
correlate here so no Jas is architect
basically this is the architecture of
know Jas it's a single-threaded
architecture and so that basically one
thread for every know Jas process
basically what you have here is you have
an event queue with events
there's a constant loop here it's a
single through the loop that listens for
these events basically pop off and they
can do specific operations might be a
file system
the file system I oh when you talk to
the database rights under the database
you might do a network call any of those
types of operations basically registers
or call back and then that callback goes
to the queue and then it gets triggered
as it kind of goes in the loop here now
that's pretty a pretty technical
technical overview of the the the
framework here
um but uh what I like - I like to use
this example I think it's a little more
straightforward folks that in the past
and restaurants basically think about a
fast food restaurant
you got you so you going to McDonalds or
my favorite burger king
you go up to the register and order some
food
there's usually one guy there take your
order you can think of that as a single
thread
he processes your order and the order
goes off and you got the little event
handlers with the workers they kind of
go off
make your burger go off get your fries
let's get a drink
boom there's your return that's
essentially kind of the how the
architecture works with with no Jess
ok so with that there's some pros and
cons to with every architecture there's
a pro account too that basically with
with the architecture for know Jas the
positive side of using architecture like
this is it's very good at doing
I Oh intensive for input operate input
opera up
I Oh intensive applications database
crudities applications with high users
thorough parts are usually typically web
apps right you need to process a lot of
things relatively quickly
it's pretty good at doing that that's
why a lot of companies have migrated
their platforms to the know Jas
architecture away from other types of
architect
a
there's conditional operators that they
will actually execute against the
database in this case there's things
that like a dollar sign greater than
about dollars and less than those who
actually execute inside that JSON object
right when it when it gets parsed and so
you have to be careful here because if
you run this am I
it's goodbye i get this to say greater
than one course
out demo here isn't working right
but Lawrence
this one is here we'll see i'll try to
get one more shot and then all will call
it but basically what i was trying to
illustrate is that you can execute those
you can actually execute those
conditional operators greater than or
less than if it evaluates to true it
will essentially give you
you can basically bypass the greater
than here you can basically a bypass the
the check so greater than a dozen of
them
I don't have the value that with the
anyways . . being have the script
somewhere on my machine but can't find
it right now
basically those operators there's a
couple operators you can check that the
mongodb uh documentation specifically
for but basically what it's doing is
it's those those values values operators
will execute and actually if i use the
regular expression one is another
example of the of another operator that
execute against the mongo DB back end
ok so basically here
this type of for that this type of
injection and a typical work around
would be to do a comparison against a
potential candidate password if you just
did up there look up here you can also
there's also another type of
vulnerability and oj s not only the
operator the operator overload basically
that are that are happening in the using
those also if you run a regular
expression operator which is very common
people do regular expressions all the
time
if you use that to do a lookup you could
also overload the the process and
basically right you get a regular
expression in our service which
then again basically what i have here
and so I will try this one and see if
this works
see this
my shame I love
change is always so much fun is copy and
paste in there is kinda guess we're
going here
we'll run this and basically we weren't
able to log in and basically kind of
blew up on us in this case so yeah not
not working there
but anyways be be aware if you're going
to be going to work with an oj s at
architecture remember your we'll go
ahead and jump here to these uh to our
to our takeaways here for this
these types of vulnerabilities that I've
been able to demonstrate here so up back
to Game of hacks just to kind of take
away here
the gamification education piece again
you're building a one of the key things
with with no JR with the game of hacks
was that knowledge is key to help
deliver secure code you can get folks of
all ages to join retained this
information anytime you have a chance to
make morning more fun specifically if
you're going to be writing code you can
do that it's a really cool kind of
demonstration that you can use
I've seen we've actually had some of our
customers actually take this and kind of
build this into their kind of like
center of excellence they took game of
Game of hacks and kind of custom
tailored it for their security
department so that they could so that
they could use you can use game hacks to
basically trained their developers on
how to not make the same type of coding
mistakes and be more security aware kind
of you achieve some of those problems
that the CC shows that were surveyed in
the beginning and address
ok some key elements to think about when
you're when you're writing code
specifically for platforms like no Jas
or any platform for that matter
always make sure to validate your input
make sure you validate the structure
make sure you have a permitted set of
characters that you that you allow
another big thing that I've learned over
my you know kind of career going through
kind of app sec is that each coding
language has its you know has its
pitfalls right
java.net you get done and get sharp TV
java you got driving at c++ every
different coding language out there
there's several different coding
languages on each coding language could
have its own variation of its own own
vulnerability type now to take away from
what we talked about and learn today
particularly with no Jas
we have a new platform that's out and is
very popular things like sequel
injection are still still apparent but
now there are just specific to the no
jazz platform and that's why they're
there still still problematic
it's just you know like I like to like
basically i say here under the OGS
architecture
you got a new platform at the same rules
apply with respect to security
ok and then some of the vulnerabilities
that we addressed at that
I tried to demonstrate here and no jess
was obviously didn't have service worked
pretty straightforward
I think it to show you the week rip
crypto demonstration because our rainbow
tables down at the moment
um but we actually is a pretty slick
demo and basically what it meant to do
is that basically what we were able to
do here with no Jason single process
no Jas the core architecture uses
google's v8 engine inside the the
process and inside that process it uses
a site a random number generator
ok in the sight of random if you guys
take a look at our little role that we
have outside and that site around number
generator that Google v8 uses its
basically uses map that random
okay Matt that random it's not really
it's known that that particular random
number generators been known to be
hacked made it back back like 2009 by a
security guy actually had a long time
ago Google knows about it and just I
don't want to go too much in the details
but the problem is that's that's inside
of the OGS platform so something to be
aware about within each node process
that that
Matt random being used don't use the
default map that random chatter number
random generator inside know Jas because
you can have week
there's a vulnerability for a week
crypto you want to use it like a an
open-source third-party known
saito random number generating ok
other vulnerability types that I
couldn't I couldn't show off but Jason
sequel injection definitely
vulnerability out there and then also
regular expression analysis and many
more
and if I had more time I would I would
love to share those if you're interested
in kind of a note security project
I point to note security I oh it's kind
of an open source project that's open
for do a node node security
so if you're interested you can
contribute enjoying it but uh with that
i think i got about three of three or
five minutes left here i'll leave the
link the rest for a couple questions
I kind of think you a you guys have any
general questions about kind of what we
covered today
now great you guys have fun
all right well hey thank you very much
for joining and I have any questions
step down