we talked about hacking the next
generation and the cyber front here
so with that obviously has to come a
little bit of Star Trek and the card
face palm yes
you corny we get it and use the word
cyber so writers and getting a little
upset about that but I promise you they
won't be any more of the star trek kind
of me more references really just to
kind of get that out of the way but
forgot them
so my generation of attacking people
we can remember in order to do something
with computers
it had certain minimum requirements
those requirements for things like
reading those skills also included
typing patience and a lot of that's
changed
specifically because of things like
mobility and the consumerization of IT
there's a whole nother generation now
who don't have that requirement at all
night
- okay I want my -
is it okay to show you answered with
people I'm sorry what'd you say
yeah yeah
it's okay to share your password to
people so that's some Benny the
destroyer
he he got that nickname by giving
mommy's iphone a bath
he thought it needed to be washed and
that was a 279 dollar lesson for mommy
but then he's also destroyed many other
things in the house and continues to do
so but a couple years ago he barely
spoke just very few words and when you
got a tablet and started using it and
then sort of verbalizing his pass code
it took about a good year and some few
extra months before we kind of like
retrain him on
why that's really not a good idea
the no 1492 big deal there's nothing on
there is a kids tablets
you know youtube for kids and some games
and stuff but there is really a much
deeper problem where parents are sharing
their mobile devices with their kids and
could be a corporate own device or even
if it's a BYOD enabled device
there are many types of sense of data on
that device there can email documents
with having the applications and they
hand it off to their kids because it's
become the electronic babysitter and and
because of that low bar to entry for
kids to be able to use these devices we
created a new pack for kids and a part
of that
it's really kind of an incentive based
program to teach kids cybersecurity
Internet safety and best practices as
well as stem part of like when I grew up
and I played Dungeons and Dragons
right on i would spend hours memorizing
the the tables and the matrices because
it made the game play that much better
we had kind of pause and look things up
it's slow the game down and made it less
interesting less exciting
there was an incentive and that's what
we do it had four kids we provide some
kind of incentive for them to want to
learn really complex technology
I mean mobile devices are pretty easy to
use but behind it is a lot of complexity
and i'll explain a bit more about how
we're hacking the next generation
through hack for kids but before you
know when do we come up with this idea
to create hack for kids
so back in early 2013
I saw your tweet by some hope you see
there i was getting washed out by the
light
what they wanted to have a kids based
conference in Chicago have to see that I
was like this is awesome
since then i published a book for kids
I've been active with my kids teaching
them technology and scouting and it
seemed like this was my calling
inside of me was this
kind of Ember spark it was just kind of
smoldering and this kind of started to
fan it a little bit and I contacted them
and said hey you know I'd love to help
out in any way
there's a really early stage want to
jump in i didn't want to do any kind of
leadership or anything I just wanted to
be there to help and they were like sure
so thrilled so now that ember is
smoldering and it's starting to get
bigger and hotter and then the board of
thought on decided they didn't want to
do a kid's event which was perfectly
fine because it was being really kind of
run by some people from the thought on
board and then all of that like
excitement because we already had a
couple calls we started the plan all
went away and then it's kind of like aa
glum head and while just kind of you
know doing my day-to-day stuff in 2014
you know we launched their first half
for kids thought about it
what to do how to do it who to do with
never ran a conference before I've done
other types of organizational activities
but never actually ran a conference and
not knowing what's involved with that
so work with some other folks and we had
a good showing about 40 kids total of
about a hundred and six people including
pan parents the kids
volunteers everyone you can see here on
this just kind of some opening comments
and one of the staff is really busy on
his mobile device which really kind of
tells you the the ear that we live in
because mobility is everything nowadays
I work for mobile company site feel like
personally a constant basis but we we
have a pretty broad age range we have
kids that are we first were eight to 17
because we wanted to give high school
students an opportunity to learn more
about technology they're probably doing
it already but they might wanna have
done something with ethical hacking and
we want to make that available to them
but also we have any is there and he saw
this homemade hack of some guy took a
galvanized steel garbage and and he
turned it into a robot
put like some more tea what do I see
that and all ok
arduino controllers and then you look at
this thing it was bigger than him but
his incentive I don't you can see it on
the left is a clear bucket of candy so
that helped me overcome this fear
through the incentive of something sweet
but we have changed to seven to 17
because we found out that some kids were
being homeschooled
actually we're kind of going into the
third grade they sometimes are a little
bit more head of public school systems
and or private school systems and we
wanted to open it up to them
we also do things with like you know I
trouble either snap circuits and if
you're familiar with them
there are a lot of fun i'll tell you
more about them a bit
we also did some stuff with 3d printing
last year and this one actually was kind
of cool
a lot of the ideas I wish I could take
credit for it is really coming from my
kids and my kids friends one of them
mom we've got an arduino showing the
blinky light and my son was like well
it's kind of cold blink and you make a
blink Morse code is right there
raising the bar on that yeah sure so it
took him to set through it started to
create different types of functions for
. - and then the alphabet making it
easier to read and he was learning the
whole like how basic programming works
which you've never really been exposed
to before and that kind of got it
I'm excited and then we started to put
messages and was very clear to read SOS
or whatever and one of his friends said
well can we do a scavenger hunt
so we do is we marry those two ideas of
the arduino blinking Morse code but it
was also a part of a scavenger hunt
so we made some little hack of nine-volt
battery connectors for the Arduinos put
them in some 3d printed cases and then
kind of him throughout the event and
then to go find you know the blinking
light and then we have a sheet and they
had a scavenger hunt which they had a
great time doing they were running all
over the place
taking selfies with the different things
that we had hidden in the venue which
they got from the Arduinos those are
some kind of fun things
who here knows morse code like knows it
not knows of it
yeah like I know about five or six
letters right it's it's kind of lost
skill
unless you've been in the military and
the kinda banged it into you and it's
their most people don't know it
and most of the kids nowadays don't know
of it which is the reason why we
introduced it
this one here is pretty fun
one of our volunteers on one of our
calls which is trying to against
brainstorm for some other ideas and she
said well I like to go to goodwill and
get really inexpensive old tech give it
to her son and you haven't taken apart
because he started taking apart things
in their house
so before he got to the microwave she
thought it would be a good idea to
here's a router
here's a telephone has a remote control
here's an old radio and it's a low cost
investment but the education is very
high because now they're seeing
not this little piece of magic
electronics that just kind of does
something but they're seeing how its put
together inside there
the magic kind of goes away but the
curiosity level rises up very high so
here are one of the tyros which is what
we call the kids that attend attack a
hack for kids event
she's taking apart some tech it looks
like an old router or something like
that
kinda you sure but yeah they love it
they love taking the techno party an
idea we all thought would be okay
you know we don't know how it's going to
be received it's one of our most popular
activities
so now what exactly is the entity of
hacker kit so you kind of understand you
kind of how we came about but what is it
it is a public charity to 501 c 3
charity registered with the IRS so um
you know putting the event together it's
a big challenge but it takes funds so
you know you feel compelled you like I
just got this thousand dollar bonus
check from work
I just don't know what to do with it i'm
gonna donate it to hack for kid
we appreciate that thank you but reality
is whatever you want to donate that's
fine
and we work with other organizations
that are very very helpful like even the
folks here at converging and besides
Detroit hugely helpful in providing
venue and in donating the space and
other things in order for us to be able
to do this and we work with other
organizations at the partnership and
it's easy to do that as a charity and it
also kind of projects are intent we're
not looking to make money in inhale
commercialize or capitalize on this
stuff we really are just promoting
education that's really worried about
we've partnered with other events like
circle city con if you are in
Indianapolis
about a month ago we had a village
they're kind of like we're going to do
here tomorrow
we also their big part of ours were also
doing a second one across the pond in
Belgium with the folks of rhukaan which
is actually pretty cool and they really
adopted a model we're looking for work
we go in we educate them we enable them
let them know kind of what would work
and what wouldn't work and how to work
with the kids and then they kind of took
the effort initiated or they're like
already have like a long list of
different things they want to do some of
them little far-reaching but others like
look really possible
and we love that because the only way to
scale this is for other folks that are
experienced organizers to want to be
able to have an event like this with
their event and actually that kind of
that symbiotic relationship between an
established event and a hacker kids
village or another day dedicated has
been a really successful model kind of
Chicago's like the only one where we
actually have just a day who would you
have for kids
everything else has been a partnership
including York on appointing to Chris if
you have not been a jerk on you really
should be completed cara con not just
because you're in the room
it's probably one of the events that i
think i can say i've been to every
single one and I've never missed a
single gurkot a lot goes on there but
we've partnered and i think i actually
nagged you for a couple years for some
emails about when you're gonna do kids
event even before we advocate and then
he finally he gave in and we had our
first one last year and it was it was
very successful me he gave us plenty of
space actually almost fifty percent
larger than the room where now and we
had a lot going on a lot of and even
people that are speaking here and people
are volunteering here and people that
are organizing we're helping us
so you can see this big community
pulling together because we all believe
in the mission
so definitely tomorrow we're doing a
happy kid to converge and / besides
Detroit by now
I don't know if you kind of feel that
ember inside of you and you're like hey
I want to do one of these two or hey I
know someone that runs an event in
another city
maybe they can do one well we are
looking for people who kind of have that
ember in them there's a Google Form
don't bother writing it down this
present is available online you can just
click on the link from there to fill out
the form
get in touch with us and we can figure
something out there is a lot of people
that come up to us and say we want to do
an event in their City find when you get
back to you and that kind of ends the
conversation unfortunately
so kind of having that information in
advance when do you want to do it where
do you want to do it
what other event do you want to do with
in conjunction on the same day or
another day is very helpful information
up front
um forgot to tell the joke before the
punch line
we take security and had four kids very
seriously because one of my kids playing
a video game and I put a little joke
behind it but it actually is one of the
things that we take very very seriously
but we do a fairly good job of kind of
just integrating it not making it so
obvious it's not like you're walking
through TSA and make whatever jokes you
want it's an obvious thing you're going
through a metal detector
but because of you know the nature of
kids and risk and all the risk that
comes with you know creeps out there
oh you know my kids go I want to make
sure my kids are say I know chris's kids
go
I want to make sure he's getting
everybody else's kids are safe so some
of the things that we've adopted because
I'm I don't know the term Scouter it
means an adult leader in boy scouts of
america program
I'm a Scouter now for about five years
so I adopted some of the practices from
the BSA and one of them is we never have
one adult in the room with one or more
kids there's always going to be at least
two adults and has a variety of reasons
it's not just to protect the kids if
it's to protect the adults right
never we don't want anyone ever to have
to defend their character even know
they're there to help and we want to
make sure everybody has a good time and
everybody learns so we don't take
volunteers off the street either so you
come up to me after this and you're like
hey I want to volunteer
I get emails from people i want to
volunteer and even some people in this
room right now they've asked me like how
do you know how can I bet you do you do
something with scouting because i know i
have to do training with them every two
years it's a requirement
I've done stuff with is C squared is a
partner of ours and they do background
checks especially for the safe and
secure online presentation
there's other things like with athletics
if you're a coach in your say soccer
coach
they make you go through training they
do background checks if i can get a
letter or something that states
you're you're safe to be around kids you
know we still accept that with a grain
of salt just I have a lack of trusting
nature but if you know if you know
somebody on the board of directors and
you know them more than like hey you
know I met Bob at this conference and I
see Bob every year past three years
Bob's a good guy
that's not enough you need to know the
person we also take photography very
very seriously
I'm sorry with the my keep moving and
keep moving the audio but what i mean by
that is we state before the event like
during the opening comments if you want
to take a picture of your tyro
and there's another tyro in the frame
politely ask them they can you either
you wait or you ask them to hate and you
screwed over her second I wanna take a
picture of my kid and um you'll keep
them out of it and it was going to post
the social media
we don't want people posting other
people's kids online because maybe that
parent doesn't want their kids for the
online for it only they can do it here
on one of our photographers that one
staff they're instructed that if they
take a picture that's front-facing only
I keep control of those anything that
gets public like this would be something
that's from like a side shot or that
when you can't really identify like I
don't know who this is i honestly don't
know this kid but you know he's doing
something there
he's playing with some snap circuits
he's shooting a propeller into the air
the arduino scavenger hunt boxes there
he might have been working with that
and so we know but this the picture
tells you a lot about what we do but no
identity is being revealed
and in photography even extends into the
restroom to tell people you know what
put your phone away Carrie business
don't take it out when you're in the
restroom male or female
doesn't matter and if somebody of the
kids in there by themselves
turn around and leave wait for them to
exit
we always want that two to one ratio to
adults 21 kid
and even if you're on your phone just
like having an awesome time and had four
kids and tweaking it out there
you don't need to do that in the
restroom somebody else might think
you're doing something that you're not
and again you have to defend your
character
we have to confiscate your phone make
sure we delete pictures and even then
forensically could be recovered with all
of that we don't want to do that
we want people to have fun here's
another example like there's a picture
of a tyro gender
I don't know I actually do know this kid
gender is unknown so these are the kind
of photography that we use all you see
is there's like a big hairy arm so I'm
assuming that's pateros dad and they're
putting something together in the
building something
last year
I'll get this and last year we want to
do that first year we had paper badges
kind of first-year try to figure it all
out quick and easy last year i think it
was about 370 some odd hours of 3d
printing in my bedroom while trying to
produce a couple hundred i think of
printers about 250 badges and different
colors so yeah a lot of noise at night
each page took about 15 minutes the
print 58 minutes to pray excuse me
yeah there they were not like ninety
percent solid but they were you know
pretty solid because we want to make
sure that they were durable especially
the clip we don't want the tops to break
off but and they were reasonably thick I
mean they're probably about that big and
we made different ones for different
locations so when we went to Kirk on
there was one that's a dirt on when we
were broke on said Luke on we try to
really customize and spent a lot of time
doing this
you can see the gliders on there and
then this other symbol like the arrow
pointing down actually
we created a simple called the tyro
symbol for them
so this way like the badge it was
pointing down but when they held it up
it was facing proper direction for them
to be able to see it when they pick it
up with the tire symbol is is that arrow
is on
if you ever seen the Nordic runes
there's one symbols like an arrow called
the tire
tyr and the circle completes the word
tyro with the circle also and all the
tire symbol is like strength and warrior
and then the circle is representing the
unity of the hacker community
don't laugh Chris and yeah and the
hackers never ending
I first request or question knowledge
like once we figure something out and
you're like oh cool i change it like you
keep changing it pushing it further we
don't stop
so that's their symbol why and where had
four kids so why there are other events
out there
this was not a unique idea there are
other great events out there i should
say like roots asylum formerly known as
def con kids and there's also on their
weather was hack hit out of san jose and
what they both have in common is a very
west coast base
I live in Chicago originally from the
east coast but I've also met a lot of
friends in the info tech community in
the northern Midwest as you can see it's
a pretty big community there's a lot of
folks it's also pretty small community a
lot of people know each other and in
because of that we were able to have
events in places like Chicago and grand
rapids and now Detroit and Indianapolis
so we're really kind of looking at this
bit more globally at least northern
hemisphere and in the end even root ,
but now if you can see sect or you know
we got the green light on going to
canada which is actually pretty cool as
i know some people over there and have
been very excited about or very eager to
go to Canada to do a hacker kids and now
we're doing it in conjunction with
b-sides toronto and Sektor which is
phenomenal
we're hoping that's going to be a really
nice huge event but you know we
go to other places we want to do more
but it's hard to scale so we need to
find the right people in the right
places to do this we want to get further
south in this country we speak when
spoken to people in Atlanta and Dallas
and Raleigh and again just it doesn't
always pan out
it takes a time investment on both sides
they want to do it but they got also
getting involved in help
so and move on so some of the things
that we do we have a three types of
activities we have a speaker track
we have activity stations and we have
workshops now activity stations are
really designed to be 15 to 20 minutes
or more
they want to be there longer but to
teach them something they haven't done
before
give him some exercises give them some
challenges and if they've done it before
kind of take it to the next level
especially with some of the older Tyros
but if it's not something of their
interests that we did a a Python for
kids activity station and they might go
in there or their parents might kind of
push them in there in that conference
room and now they're like oh
coding is really not for me i like
hardware so this year we can came up
with a hardware badge which is actually
pretty cool
the hardware it was pre assembled but
it's fully habitable and inside of it is
like an 80 tiny which they can treat it
like an arduino with the breakout pins
and drop the sketch on there and run it
which is actually very cool and some of
them with the help of the the vonage
manufacturer was able to change the
badges or change some of the stuff that
like the speed of the the encoded
message because each one of them has a
different try to see each one of a
different color has a different coded
message on
so it was actually pretty fun and you
can see the pretty badass
and then you could even like adults are
like the parents got one too
they were like loving it and you can go
back home because a lot of the parents
that come to these events are ITR
infosec people there are few accounts
and and and you know just stay at home
moms and whatnot but
the detect people were just like
salivating
because this is just a fun thing you
can't go and pick up at best buy or buy
anywhere else is very very custom but
yeah we we did that
i'm going to talk about that a little
bit when we were talking about the badge
with the workshops so you know the
activity so i would throw out the Python
for kids workshop
some of the kids loved it some of the
kids just did a little bit and moved on
so that's kind of really what we do we
had one kids sit there all day and
Indianapolis doing crypto challenges
he never did crypto before in his life
he discovered how to like decode binary
and base64 and wrote 13 and then we even
had some other ones with like you know
or bash
raise your hand if you know what are
benches it's okay all right
it's the language of Star Wars so the
very first Star Wars movie
yes yes i know i'm with you you should
know that I'm sorry so yeah you have to
leave now
so in the very first Star Wars movie
little history um you can see unlike
their display in the x-wing just some
characters that came up that was
completely meaningless was all random
and then somebody actually created the
armor visual language that could be
converted to like a ski and then
somebody has a website where you can
type in english and it converts into
orbit
so we had a challenge that was orbiting
the kid look at it goes
that's from Star Wars and he kinda
worked out from them spent the entire
day just working on all these challenges
and that's great him his dad you know
he's like I am I son have fun and
everything wrote this long email on how
he impressed us because he found
something inside himself that he didn't
know he had it with a passion for
mathematics or more advanced mathematics
and you know he didn't really commit
like how many you kids how many folks
out there have kids that tell you
everything about what they've done and
communicate yeah had a really great time
today and we did all this stuff with
advancement know you ask you what you do
today it's one nothing
and that's the end of the conversation
unless you push them a little harder but
and you know that his dad was very happy
to get the kind of feedback and now he
knows that something that he should be
able to support with the Sun when it
came to Chicago we had more challenges
for and he's come back he's been at
least we had four kids now he's about 15
he loved so workshops are kind of like
an extended version of that so i can
give you a raspberry pi
I could show you how to log on to it i
can give you a Python script
I can make you turn a servomotor but
when you're done looking at that and you
really have no other interest you kind
of move on but if you have an interest
what we've done is like a whole unboxing
workshop / it was about three hours on
Raspberry Pi from taking it apart
no hdmi monitor no USB keyboard
you have to figure out what your IP
address was so you can xrdp onto the
device and the kids had to get into a
router and we we take this for granted
but they've never done it before and now
they're like wow this is pretty cool and
they were on there and they did all that
stuff i just described in this workshop
instructor was teaching them
web application pending but we called it
web hacking exposed the bounty hunter
edition threw up a copy of Boba Fett
sold out there is no more space in that
workshop
it's how you package it we have other
things like spider-man but if we say hey
you want to do some advanced
mathematical cryptography
you're not gonna have anyone sit down at
the table when you put a sign on the
wall of his spy math they're either
they're all day so
tops of the workshops are really more
like two to three hours sometimes for
and we always do a safe and secure
online presentation because that's where
we're teaching anti cyberbullying ethics
and Internet safety and best practices
all the other stuff like you know
there's some cyber security and it but
everything else we're doing is really
around stem and ethical hacking
so we make sure that this is a part of
the program now I'm the speaking talks
with speaking track
not every location has one is it's
really kind of sometimes difficult if
you're running a very like an adult
conference to fill of speaking track
will call quality speakers when it's
it's kids we want a lot of kids to speak
we don't have any age discrimination you
know it doesn't have to be kids we do
encourage kids we have a mentor program
but the that you know anyone that wants
to speak on something but it has to be
age-appropriate we had something to talk
about biohacking in Chicago but she came
in there and she had a nice display
she had on phosphorus and bacteria and
then when she kind of covered in a black
box
it was like hack for kids and bacteria
which was actually cool then smell very
good in there but it was actually pretty
cool
that's no good at all but that's kind of
what we're talking about so if you want
to talk about something really advanced
and interesting like that but you can
bring it down the level we're happy to
have you there is a speaker last year
this is ruben call i don't know if you
heard of them he's actually been pretty
pretty active as a keynote speaker at
the age of nine and CEOs own company
I think he's now going into 4th grade
maybe fifth grade
he spoke there he is our first keynote
we were very happy to have them
anybody really talked about during the
keynote is in order to be a really good
whitehat security professional you need
to learn the Black Arts and he put it in
the context of Star Wars apropos for me
and it was well received because they're
looking at this guy I mean they were
like teenagers use me they were
teenagers in the audience watching a
nine-year-old present to them about
cybersecurity
so in that
kinda invokes this kind of enthusiasm
that they may have may not have had
before they might have a curiosity but
this really kind of get some going in
there like he can do this I can do this
and along the same thing out of you guys
ever heard of austin Valesky he was our
keynote in Chicago this year you know I
never really heard of him either but if
you ever play the game
impossible rush couple years ago it was
like the number 16 most popular game in
the Apple I of App Store
he and another teenager without pain
14 to 15 when he created it they just
saturday afternoon the other kids cinema
video here's an idea for a game
Austen wrote the code published it
within a month
a hundred thousand downloads some
marketing company came up to them
we want to buy this from you so he's
most adults would like dream of that but
for teenager it's kinda gobsmacking
because you just don't expect it and you
kind of excited that people are using
your app but then when someone wants to
buy it you're like what we do is you
don't have to negotiate that has stuff
and then once it was in the hands of the
marketing company
it took off and since then
you know I think Austin is now 16
he's still in high school and he gets
like consulting jobs for web UI design
he flies to Israel he's been flown out
to google and apple headquarters and he
gives keynote presentation is not just
for us that's how I met him he was at
some other student and technology event
in illinois and like this kid is awesome
so the idea behind having him present is
not just because it was awesome it was a
really nice polite
kitty was like very cool very cool kit
just hearing his presentation I wanted
to make I OS apps and I've done a few
little hacks here and there but like I'm
like god this is all I want to do this
if you could do this I can do this
so then I like to put myself in other
people's shoes and go would have fun
like a ten-year-old watching this
presentation because they were 10 year
olds a lot of middle school hit
11 12 and what if they wanted to learn
how to make an Iowa SAT but they go home
the parent ones windows you can't run
xcode on Windows you can try to make a
hackintosh but it doesn't always work
you're really not too many choices and
all of that inspiration and passion just
kind of flies away and then they get
bummed out and computer stop until they
decide to play clash royale or something
but or pokemon go then they want to make
an appt again but they don't know how to
and their parents don't know how to do
what we did this year in Chicago is
Austin gave his talk in the morning and
then after lunch he did to our workshop
on how to just build a calculator app
you have to start somewhere
but they loved it because it really kind
of reinforced what he talked about it
gave them an opportunity to learn and it
was very well received
so that's kind of some of the stuff we
do we like to talk about and then do it
how many times you guys go to a con
you watch somebody talk about a tour so
I can't want to use it and you never
really do i know that happens to me
every kind of it so we want to be able
to give the kids the opportunity to do
that we do that also in Chicago every
year activity
station a debriefing on this here
it was a stem project to build a
catapult out of popsicle sticks glue gun
paper plastic spoon and rubber bands and
all we gave them with a picture
no step by step instructions here's a
picture and some of it had some build
challenges which were kinda obvious
created by the back of the picture
because you couldn't see couldn't rotate
it
it's just two dimensional and they had
to figure some of that out like if i
glue the crossbars on how do I wrap the
rubber band around the crossbar and
attach a spoon if it's already glued two
posts they have to figure that out first
and then glued a piece on but not all of
them did but that's okay you can still
kind of get around it and what i thought
was really awesome was a lot of them
built their project and then had
competitions on who could send like a
ball of paper
the furthest and then they would tweet
their project a little better to have it
send something further now while that
sounds very academic like very base line
what are we teaching them teaching how
to build like a little RND test and then
go back and do a little more R&D and
that's what engineering is about it's
not your building and works the first
time you know you go through Lego kit
who's ever built a lego the first time a
complicated lego project and they didn't
get like a piece backwards you have like
reverse it
very few people but this is much more
complicated and a lot of them did a very
good job and they had fun with it to
others
that's the stem station and because of
the scouting party i'm also uh uh no the
stem / program it's just part of
scouting another way to have more stem
involved with scouting just the kids did
the project and they get some credit
towards that
but this is what that looks like
workshops talk about that Python for
kids and before you saying hey isn't
that early copy written by no starch
press their sponsor of ours and a
supporter and I did get written approval
to use that arrow
so yes I follow the law I'm by the way I
don't really do an introduction of
myself during this talk but my
background is not only a 19 infosec but
it's also counting and a little bit of
law so i usually kind of check things
out make sure everything's above board
before I do it because I don't like the
fallout I like to keep everything like
to sleep peacefully at night
so here on we do the Python for kids and
we took some these exercises right out
of the book because we have the books we
give them away as prizes but we wanted
to just begin with basic stuff there's
hello world and some lists and just
doing basic input like what's your name
and printing it out just very very
rudimentary things and then we started
to give them challenges like the dizzy
turtle basically a for loop just to kind
of go around and draw it but then they
changed the speed or they try to do
different things that were fun which is
cool and then the favorites kind of
build two lists and merge them and then
Fibonacci series
that's hard for some adults but um we we
put that in there just to see if there's
anyone a bit more advanced they really
wanted to kind of push themselves and
create that algorithm
so what
do you look a little paltry we we have a
library online on our website
h4 k.b kiidz com go to libraries a lot
of this stuff that I talked about we try
to get it up there
we have like we had the first year how
to build a minecraft server we wanted to
teach them linux and they wanted to play
minecraft
boom bring a vm or vm host spun up about
13 guests have their own box
they built the minecraft server and they
played Minecraft when they were done
those notes are right there you can that
link still works all the instructions
are still current
and you can your kids have like a vm in
the cloud running linux whatever
cento is about to have them build a long
arm minecraft server each of them to
install java you know fun stuff like
that and all the crypto challenge not
all oak a lot of the crypto challenges
they're just images so they click a link
will have the image do that
intentionally because i don't want to
just be able to copy base 64 and drop it
in the decoder one of the appetite and
write or type it out in some presents so
we need to update some of what we've
been doing the shooter part of the
incentive product borrow the idea of we
talked about incentives earlier have
them do things reward them rcts is
really participatory based and as long
as they're doing a lot more activities
they receive an opportunity to win a
prize at the draw in a drawing at the
end of the day
so for example we just kind of like a
little hacker his business card hole
punch it
whenever is teaching them something
about a raspberry pi or snap circuits or
whatever and then that's the number of
drawings they get and have a private
python script that puts like you know
Bob 66 chances and then it goes and
randomly grab them and everybody gets a
chance to win once
so this snap circuit kit was donated by
the company called alinco that created
snap circuits fortunately they're nearby
there in Wheeling Illinois which is very
close to me so I got to go check out
their warehouse which if you're into
hardware and soldering it was like
paradise
this place was phenomenal
um but they donated a bunch of kids
which we have here for tomorrow and some
prizes in this right here was like about
a hundred seventy dollar retail and that
was a prize when you consider what we
charge 40 43 dollars for the kids to
enter about 25 for the parents
you know if you win no complaints
parents like thrilled actually was
thanks by the parent when his kid picked
that because he's like now I don't have
to go buy that from my kid
this is awesome because you play with
the snaps are gonna be like I want it
and that when you can build into an AM
and FM radio which is actually pretty
cool
no starch give this book so we donate
books
we also have coupons so if you pick up
any of those flyers are still out on the
table
get a discount also on some books not
just kids books they're doing nose like
we like to get that hardware so we like
we have a conic kid
so now the full pies raspberry pi 3
khana khate or we've been other hardly
knows you know the condo kit which is
the bigger one with the keyboard and the
speaker and like your own raspberry pi
computer
we've been giving those away as well we
just don't have her tomorrow
but like to give him some hardware if
it's tangible it feels like you really
want something i'm speaking of that
who knows what this is one of my
favorite Holies
it's the DC darknet badge so if you go
to DC dark dot net and now it's actually
probably a pretty good time to go
that's right before Jack on usually
about a month before they they
reactivate the demon and if you like
these kinds of challenges I mean even my
10 year old he started doing these a
couple years ago and it's just basic
stop right it's just decoding something
that has like a simple Caesar cipher or
converting hex to something else and you
build points but they also have in their
hardware hacking village the DC darknet
bad about twenty-five dollars and it's a
solder kit
this is the one that i put together and
it's it's lit up on the top but they got
some like Ellen led SNP's that you just
kind of solder put on the back but if
you look at the bottom
there's transmit and receive leds and
those the band just talk to one another
which is pretty cool
and that was a part of the challenge
because the more badges you associate
with the more points you get
and the USB connector at the top you
supposed to plug that in and then figure
out how to get that off and enter those
flags
so it's a pretty cool kit but even that
um it's like an Arduino due in manova
chip that's there that I see and that is
supposed to have a sketch on there for a
TV be gone
so you know to see if you don't know
what a TV begun is it's basically you
push the buttons at best buy and you see
the TV go off
you kind of move position in the store
wait for them to turn them all back on
and then turn it off again
you know just kind of little trolling
harmless fun for you not them it's
basically teaching them to just
deactivate the IR on the TV
no but the kids were all like I want it
they they kinda like the idea the
trolling but it also was like when a
idle state it was blinking a message in
Morse code
it does a bunch of things on the back of
it behind the the battery holder was
like another encoded message that's a
bunch of things on there
they still have them very hard to get if
you go to DEFCON try and get it on
Thursday because if you wait till
saturday
there's going to be no more and they
donate them to us donated probably
around 12 or 13 so far
the kids love them on to pick them up in
their parents like one response to it as
a parent some don't some of them had a
solder
so take them to DEFCON or take them
someplace where there's going to be a
hardware hacking village and then have
them solder it up but yeah it's it's a
fun prize talked a lot about that sorry
gift cards to not very exciting as far
as a picture but we usually have some
who doesn't like - so you know we do
stuff with with that as well
like we're going to do a super bot
tournament tomorrow because we're going
to build some super bots battle
whoever wins the most battledore gets
the most points by the end of that
session
look at 25 I'll gift card you can go and
buy some pokemon backpackers
something'll come on go
I am i doing on time i'm doing alright
so i talked about the safe and secure
online home
sorry this this section is how do we
know what you know what we're doing is
working
it's really hard to know we we do
surveys
I'll show you that in a minute but with
the safe and secure online presentation
with the anti cyberbullying
I gotta tell you my oldest son he SAT
through eight or nine of these
presentations
since he was about six years old he gets
it
but even he fell prey to online cyber
bullying from his friends friend on a
minecraft server and it wasn't
necessarily him it was my middle kid
that was being picked on in the
beginning
did you show each other's creations
that's how they troll one another the
grief that sly in Minecraft and my older
son made me proud was defending his
younger brother which is what we teach
them you know kind of take away the
audience of the bully and then the bully
has no real reason to bully anymore
because they're doing it because they're
want other people to make them feel good
because they pick on someone they laugh
they feel that they picked them pick on
the more they laughed more and that
makes a bully you take that element out
they have no motivation and my son was
trying to do that but for whatever
reason they started picking on him and
he overreacted punched his display and
completely cracked his laptop display
so you know not not good
so we're teaching them the right things
but even when they get very frustrated
their heat of the moment they get angry
it's it's hard to know how successful we
are and a lot of times we don't get that
kind of feedback so we were trying
it's very hard so we do a lot of surveys
surveys are hard to and trying to get
better at this
but in this particular case I hope you
guys can read that
so that first one right there how many
hack the kids attended including this
one circle one
so when I asked my eight year old at the
time
9 he said that means how many hackers
you want to and just circle number is by
then we've only had three
you know that when my wife she read it
she read it as well how many people you
bringing or how many people are tending
had four kids I was like am I should
have you read this first because i had
people literally right in the number
four and circle it wasn't a choice they
made it a choice
so the data normalization is a big
problem because they're now filling out
a survey for for kids who had four
different opinions but it's one response
what do I do with that I don't know how
accurate it is is it an average I don't
know
um unfortunately nobody put anything for
gender they all left
male female they didn't add anything
they're special that is good but even
other problems on here
I'm crazy like this is these top two
we had two workshops you can only attend
one I had people fill in both
what do I do with that which was right
I can't hunt them down because they
don't want their name on it because we
want to keep it anonymous
all right so it goes on and on and on
some people just kind of filled in 45 45
45 / that doesn't help
so we moved to like survey monkey which
you probably like why don't you just do
that in the beginning
well when you put a piece of paper in
front of somebody and say fill this out
and then when you're done many prizes
there's an intent but if you send them
an email
hey answer these questions you know even
i know it's a week later
can all the answers you get I think I've
had six people so far respond from our
chicago event which was two and a half
weeks ago so it's like what do you do
with that data
it's a smaller representation of the
population you try
now this is really my weak attempt at
creating an infographic infographics are
cool
so who's behind looking back at 2015
kind of give you some numbers had 53
kids registered 53 kids showed up
that's pretty cool that is really cool
our first year we had 40 registered and
we had 38 show up
now if we made it free like the state of
Illinois wants us to do in order to be
recognized as a true charity and
actually you know making a charitable
effort to the community we would get
probably a hundred and fifty two hundred
people registered and still probably
have 50 people show up but we would
order 200 sandwiches we would order 200
shirt we would get 200 badges but there
is no state of Illinois saying well
we'll make up the difference
so it's
something we have to do nominal fee it's
below our costs but you can see the
attrition is very low
I'm gender breakdown so of the 53 that
attended 39 were boys you can tell by
the color blue
maybe i should use pink put the girls
are 14 that have previously attended a
hack for kids the first line with 36
that was their first
so last year our second year doing this
in chicago we had a lot of new New
attendees and participants the two and
two
that was their second time attending a
hacker kid and the one boy was obviously
my son
maybe not so obviously who went to every
event with me and he went to three
just got interesting in the age range
because this is another hard thing
it's I see some of these events that
there for 5 year olds and six-year-old
that takes a lot more one-on-one time
because of my four-year-old and I and
even when he was three and we're using
on the game called robot turtles
it's basically teach programming and
kind of logic and flow control like
stuff like that is a physical board game
he loves it but it's a lot of one-on-one
time so it's kind of hard to do that
with what we do so we kind of play with
that and we want to maybe reduce the
older aid like we want to make it maybe
8 to 13 and then we can have more things
kind of gauge in that range but we still
get enough kids that are teenagers but
our sweet spots really like eight to 12
8 to 12 years old so late elementary
school and middle school
now the activity station i mentioned
before I kind of just mentioned a couple
of the most popular was the technology
destruction village where they get to
take take apart and look at it but they
don't just get to destroy it and move on
they have to identify components if I
that's cool
other people have the idea well why
don't we have them take the parts and
glue gun and build something new which
is fine because then I don't have to
take it to a new recycles plant which is
great for me but you know what else
could we do with it and we avoid mercury
but
hold that the most popular was the
technology destruction village of the
most attended the lockpick village who
doesn't like the pop a lock
one kid in the survey only pop handcuffs
and nothing else
which makes you wonder what their future
career might be and not law enforcement
so in the LP v we had 20 kids actually
go of the 53 of that we had
what is that a 12-12 pop five pins super
686 pop six pins which is really
impressive
I don't think i could do six pins and I
know I can do five and then nine did
cuffs the colors of the individual kids
really don't need a living in the
network security section which is
wireshark and comparing telnet vs si Jin
HTTP HTTPS we had seven of nine kids do
all the exercises and then another seven
actually tried to do the hidden file
challenge which was essentially reading
through the the traffic and a pcap to
find the link to the image
pull down the image and then there's
your prize congratulations you can you
know was very simple for you know people
doing CTFs but a challenge for someone
who's never ever looked at wireshark
before Python for kids we had 10 to 10
and of the ten all of them did all the
exercises or sorry to exercise it up to
number three
- completed the challenges of the two
nobody was able to do that bonacci
series probably will need another word
for bonacci they just stopped
I don't know but it's those metrics are
hard and kind of going back to surveys
we want to try to change the model to a
way that we get more this information
like did they go to Fibonacci series try
to do it and then what happened
like you know why did they stop to as
educators we need to know this cell and
then spy math 12 kids attended seven of
the eight
sorry
that's seven did seven of the eight
challenges and to actually did proves we
had 28 year old so the person the
teacher teaching them on this
they were learning more about how to
prove mass which was really not a part
of the program he just kinda took the
initiative and he's like let me show you
how to prove this out and they got it
and he was like oh my god - what these
kids proves i proved they were eight
I'm like awesome what kind of gauge it
because not all of them are ready for
that
but the guy's a math genius and he was
super thrilled technology destruction
village 14 kids attended um and what is
that five kids identified seven
components because they got to go and
look this is a resistor this is pastor
and look like all of them identify the
capacitor some of the comments to on
those sheets and we got back you can
read this for yourself
you know while we might argue in the
industry
there's still a gender bias and there's
not an equal number of people and gender
everyone has their own opinion on that
we don't have an actual split but you
could see 39 and 14
what is that like 75 the 25-percent
maybe 60 40 something like that and I
don't think it has really anything to do
with gender I think it's just awareness
because i went to my second graders
class taught them
of course I like half our history of
computers and let me answer some of your
technical questions and then I handed
out flyers literally that day one of the
girls went home gave it to her parents
and she was registered to have four kids
so I don't I think there's an interest
I just I don't know I don't know why
that I think it's just a matter of time
like everything else lastly we hit the
top of the mountain
if you're interested go to the web site
maybe we can organize one in your area
hopefully you got something out of this
about hacking the next generation
here's some twitter handle something
happen to the bird oh there it goes
links to like roots asylum and and had
kids and I c squared and the link to the
page with the form and i also want to
thank MobileIron my employer for
sponsoring my travel is it makes me able
to come out here and talk to you nice
folks
but if you have any questions I think
you're anything i could take some
question
yeah we we don't really believe in
having a structured program like they go
to skool skool tells them what they have
to learn
we want them to learn the way they want
to learn and we want them to do it
however they feel comfortable so for
example they walk in and they're like oh
my god has eight tables to choose from I
don't know where to begin and when they
actually look at the table they might
see snap circuits and just go
so they get to choose and there's
somebody to kind of take them through
the exercises and challenges or they
might just see somebody sitting there
with a laptop and these little tiny
computers raspberry PI's a little servo
motor and they might that looks kind of
cool
tomorrow we're doing it a little
differently just because we can get
involved here's we're actually going to
go more through series kind of
traditional classroom style
just because it takes a lot of bodies do
that but yeah it's it's really up to
them and with the laptop we do have an
online CTF so CTF the hacker kids calm
even if you're not a kid you want to do
the challenges that's fine you got to be
present to win and if you go there I one
that's me and you're like
over the age of 17 you're disqualified
from a prize
you can still brag that you want and you
beat a bunch of kids that's a few
yeah the top guy that put your next
question
I'm gonna break this down for the next
speaker but i can't a question