hold on a Mac ready all right
I had on the way everybody get you candy
cigarettes man
alas happen oh yeah yes
yeah so - I work for towel
I'm one of the threat research for them
and today we have an example want
oh how we got a television
the objective here today is not that I
you for your pet odor or would like to
learn to build in mind that approach to
things like that
maybe take back your analyst for your
belt in your organization that's what
we're talking about here today
ok i am always open for questions
I just have to try to raise your hand
and I'll try to all right hand with the
best possible try to fold our question
of the energy making it look like i'm on
we will try to get you everything then
answer questions at the end of part
so a little bit about the story
um i was working at a thought that a
company had a lot of friends there and
choir to me
starting work there of course i would be
to knowledge of NBA that let me have an
organization of life and what's right is
right
probably here for infrastructure
services i provide an intercept course
ok you know there's always some bad guy
out there that doesn't like the fact
that an organization
he doesn't like is using your your
company services right you most your web
there were right you provide the
infrastructure we don't like you
whatever so we're going to that
kind of a little motivation so when i
was working at they have the same
problem with anybody else and you have a
bad guy that had been doing some pretty
awful things that and then what I and I
took a personal
I mean he made a personal actually let
you don't attack me and my friends and
my family and my job with my family
right
and my organization with my livelihood
right so i think the personal to agree
and we got off my back cool if like your
dog shit lift and step to be you right
so I left them that I ended up going to
dallas to do dedicated full time threat
hunting and research and sharing about
the threat something that we do and and
so now as my full-time job not just
things stock analysts and yelling with
incident but a full-time job getting
some bad guys in backing the internet so
when I left my other company i couldn't
take it in my research we could take any
of my data i mean i had gigs and gigs of
data and research that I had done
they're all I can take with me what was
trapped between my two years so I've got
talent
did you know i'm pretty sure that bad
guys been doing bad things while that
isn't haunted by himself
i'm sure you probably fuck that thing on
earth cisco customers bosses it okay if
I see if i can go find this guy doing
bad stuff to people like back and he
said don't do with any of the data you
know I was like I don't even have copies
of it i just i know i can find them he
has habits
PS patterns he had behavior I have come
to know more difficult for me
and so one of the things that started
with was on a domain
ok just fucking stuck in my head so I
way tonight
i called up this domain and I said you
know I know we use this domain that you
backing up wonderfully different that
this is going to do bad things better
sure not here uses them and do bad
things against other people look all
over parts of lemon tree and I was like
okay so where I found it wasn't fishing
he uses domains in a phishing email now
look
suck it Wonder officially now and it
really depended me because it was
targeting women
I was like the audience for the fish was
specifically one picture face
that's not all it's a great time I look
into this
so let me start to look at now that I
found his domain in this fishing an
email when I started looking to see what
other phishing emails there were related
to that and then I just said oh my god
that first off I didn't realize that
this whole action out there and practice
over the world email you can imagine the
volume data that had available to me now
first when i worked at a small company
all I saw was our evil right so now I'm
seeing tons of the people's email and I
started seeing like wow he's not out
there doing this by himself he's
actually part of the bigger picture
because i had to sing email was being
sent with different things
now I went in looking for one great
right when I step back and realize that
it wasn't i found the great but I have
also found the entire wine that had all
of the great
so this same email was being used to
fish women still but there were a bunch
of other domains in it so I said well
who owns these domains
well he had jack and John and bill and
bob everything will
how did Jack and john and billy bob all
happens then to say me know from four
different countries like okay cool so I
said started documenting rose at that
started with the ones we have a campaign
had 31 email
what you're seeing here is just seeing
my mouth to go diagram is that you had
to grow little by little I started
looking at different aspects
oh he attacks one spam campaign
thirty-one-year-old I went looking for
one filming there i ended up being sick
too
I kept going and domain kept rolling to
the main maybe add right
I started with one guy and you're off on
your brother and I was like okay we'll
wait a minute there's a lot of
cooperation going on here
and so I actually decided it's time for
me to just now that i've done my cursory
search
I need to develop a plan and I need to
start following you know an actual
investigating a possible and that's what
i'm here to share with you guys about it
the pot and change the answers you get a
walk go
yeah so first we start with what you
want to know what I hate
I you know what the bad guy i know that
you know that right
and then I'm going to know how big with
my threat I had 25 it so i had to define
what was bad food and I got my trusted
resource in this case was the Tama tree
that we had my company outright
sometimes truck source might be open
court virus hole is a great open source
trusted right
open ya trust me
you're right Wow degree right so I pride
in my organization i will show you are
right
start your own data and then I started
to ask questions are putting it together
ok well i went and looking for 1i one
email right that began with fans
I think okay but what's important and
what's relevant
how are they related I identify the
relationship that almost the same line
for all fishing
great the bad guys are smart enough
Bobby Jon to the second word
the one day had work and they need to
put an exclamation point Tom he can hear
you haven't felt the same word that was
almost the exact line
let me try to go over there they go to
HR and so by trying to help people who
are all don't want to be bold grow hair
and I didn't like that
how to roll back later h AI r and I go
for one like that okay with you well
their relationship to the one with the
eighth
are you cheatng well my Lords long
what might that line
how should i knew i had to get people it
was marketed it
I read our people - my I'm it don't
happen
yes I back w got plus give me everything
right so anyway I had an analysis right
well the problem is that we going
everything in an answer to a question
you want a white rat I'm gonna crack the
Moorhead all that fire
how many fire prior appt
wait you're fighting fire eating up the
fire of network
you're flying part of the whip you're
right , entire race believe you can get
an answer but i will tell you about in
mind talking about ready to tell master
key practical on how I'll even after
mouth at all
yeah that does not help feeling that
only 13 to get in
ok so after a little bit of aggregation
and lightning
I want to create them get to design
profession but what what really happened
that I go adding analyzing I hope and I
have to go back to my so what does not
represent it on the fly in this cycle
here
this is a process after you research
your over every Google answer
I caused you but you didn't get more
answers and working
ok
you don't want to avoid all the ocean I
can sometimes you have to start the
ocean before you can start right fish
right know everything yet you get a
bunch of data that
no fish crap
let you don't want lot that means you go
get it or whatever
I have left start trying to hold on the
country
oh that's no you don't know
hey you know what you have to do you get
your hands back and second and
third-order that question so you get to
the point you out watching okay after
you think you should call your network
whatever we met her on your network
we actually look at all that you get
your laptop for the tubing of pressure
whatever and you're developing at the
end of the day you need to be at your
well what about watch me cheat
I did all of it today what do I know
what you want to do not know and what
you want to achieve all that but I don't
know if they're in there any high-level
action item not your story in fact
order that they're there
you know how do your research and how
you look
yeah I'm gay
I how we find out
I got to the gate and don't break your
foot and intelligence lot and equal ball
a ball that should be a lot because what
you will get
but you forgot your funny for a moment
it's a report that I get you will get
will baby
how do you know yeah right like look
good and reports and that bullshit call
me assure you that quick
we have a lot higher developed and
repeatable bot framework
hello great you got a friend here has a
specific questions
arial i wanted to know who mine what do
you mean with that was the question I
decided what I want to know I want to
know who tellin jokes
you'll be all right all right now let's
add a lot of bad guy
I i need to battle a little bit bigger I
need to get the perspective and what how
how do you fight a guy in 45 countries
all the email your little bit of both
we really got off and happy
it's okay
hey thanks a lot like five
yeah here is one for every other week
that email over for that so i had to
find that and i had to go get my data
I wanted to know that Syria that I
decided this application that read
investigation
the criteria might not work you have to
find back and what you will do orange
time in this case i know it is small so
beginning
they're done it already
right here is ready at you'll be broke
not been knocked down
mark God bought their domain gotta love
living in a wheel or more delicious then
I wanted to know how many email email
address they have for registration card
. download
how many different countries with a
threat reporting in
how many IP address how many is he or
helping the big we create that I and now
i'm going on me
they only name that I be shared or I was
trying to get metric metadata about my
name right
so then I decided to take a look at it I
asked me back for collecting the data .
but I have a right to work on
if they ask your question and then when
they get fucking out
you have a roof committed Oh what about
this
look out about anybody
probably a little or none of the main
school building and registering you'll
know that you're a lot but actually what
I tried in the more I look at it in
another pot anymore so I went and
grabbed the data about that you got out
of was highlighted in yellow right
what's unique about the yellow and red
ones and relationship right now and I go
44 right
what is this you know why what's
important about 40 and 42 person they're
small they're small in a relationship
now breeding with one for the job right
it's larger than I am right
yeah I'm all right I what an animal
perspective I want her
all right can you imagine my trying to
analyze 23 ID a girl friend
what's hard wood turns and complications
and a concentration when I've already
had been there six divided into the
warmer
you're right
so what you are about to meet you find
that
we find that happen
we're meeting today we want to look at
right now it just actually let me more
questions for all you
retail be her special training every
part of the country are small numbers i
have a small number of actual data where
else to go back at it so I did that for
my final look at the three questions so
I asked okay that this theta my other
question was why he'll be right i
guarded with my question is why why why
do so i can look at you look at you
sorry hey narrow it down
he steal means that i thought it looked
like a child because i had got a cursory
analysis of mine and email right now and
even want to either a I thought had
getting Valerie like you're getting
fatter is really up there if you're
sending somebody to . that you reduce
bag
you got a fish described got top my
homework
who eat . angler you got
I hey you know that made
so that when I want when I what I was
told that he community contacts in my
other . so effing analyze everything is
great you don't work you need to share
with you if you're working on
you never have to deal with relevant
information
wall street oh I had enough
you need to come together and we want to
meet me so I and normal little bit of
structure on the right
yeah we were at and we have a happy
where i'm going to have it is finally
putting the team of the great do when we
find it interesting that we will make a
ticket but we're going to look into this
are we going to get hurt and sometimes i
have a doing this as I w people and
things i found other stopped to eat and
get it i wouldn't use that contract that
only you
what why didn't he registered with that
IP what is he doing that name is cool i
wonder it or maybe that's another cold
out phishing email had and we do that
all the time and we've never answer to
the previous question what we're finding
all this other cool stuff to go look at
anything needs to be looked at
but not all of it needs to be looked at
now so i'll make a ticket for something
or in other teams
I used to like literally give my team
color light on the sticky notes and i
have i'm going to look at the later wall
and we decorated a whole wall sticky
notes and when times were low we go grab
us to eat and find something to dig in
right
sometimes you have to do that but back
to the topic at hand and ask i define
what was bad i decided the criteria that
I was going to use to narrow down my
data set
I narrow it down my second question I
wanted to answer was
why these ceilings why would i look at
it still needs and then I went and
looked ready
he's been charged up here for a variety
of criteria that did that some of them
or ones that i have used previously
others were there because of reputation
be almost all of them were there because
they offered one or more of the TLD
previously backed up with one of my
requirements units group pics you have
to belly
one more so hot quick
why did they choose a higher pitch
how many do you think would because the
lateral we're actually don't care
quality
how do you think it's a bad pic yes
how many of you guys pick them think on
the term surf and guarantees that they
got in a class back
how do you think that's bad i think i'm
sure they're popular service but what of
business reputation reputation . gonna
wait doesn't that guy there are really
good person to go register at good guy
bad guy never will come over here and
mr. right
so there's reputation on both sides of
the fence where the action is
that's why they added I come to that
conclusion
I looking at what the price of he'll be
four and the volume of a bit better
your belly in right so all right for
either one of them with the domain of 49
less four of them were selling my pics
of them were selling them between a
dollar dollar fifty for the other nine
the bad guy and who fishing and i'm
going to run fishing campaign how fat
you got it pretty quickly rate
so if i wanna on a lo how a lot of that
tight in my arms right
i buy a lot of time sheet and this is
why we call this off
well we're magnet what i have done this
I was actually able to have actionable
intelligence seeing now have the data to
prove my theory which was window means
go on this house all the bad guys
migrated to that register and people
thought I was crazy like you know their
children but we started noticing one yet
she is going on with the TLB wait . have
taken away a member when it went just
off the chart
all that top that top 40 that's a record
low
that's healed up for fat guys forever
work
we're going to be using that means to
redirect
ok so we have an actual piece of
involvement
so now IM 28
where the bad guy might be one
I become aware that this rental car
companies fail
alright so i can start looking for
incoming their IP face or increase in
traffic coming from their IP face right
now but it start knowing I had a hunch I
have to figure out how to sew up
I don't want to know we do I have it I
have you guys
I'm going to get a constitution that I
wanted to do that
right hello my question
buy them if I need to figure out right I
mean it's great to know that probably
want to migrate to the next time you
fail and right but i want to know if
you're trying bad guys
you can I thought I the training people
so i wouldn't have happened
angel the ability to track registry
that's what I get in the yard where I
swear
now and i didn't know what i was going
so i TLD i wish i had taken my criteria
Oh what was bad and / or / 9 greater
than or equal to mine for a very common
to build a school
IRA I don't let you guys know that you
guys might stop
I should get more beyond who is but it
was an opening at all
half benign hungry or I and well but in
short day love and they are coming these
people register
ok so how do I get it
I wait when I use my partnership to pull
down you know break it in
for more than 90 and all those other
pills
I pull that right and what I found was
it same register where it always
different registrar's a problem for it
summary starting out a hundred domains
that other rich are they have 600 and
another is sure when I have full nobody
coalition a reseller and your week
trying to your rental in peace
come on in and get you going to do that
so anyway you know alright so as for our
black with the rest out
all right let's see what they're doing
happen
one thing I didn't have time to answer
the question of how long did it take
this person to get it
great the guys actually top hundred and
I like her
yeah hundred and I guarantee down the
matter with you at all and I go okay
who'd or what an email back
I've been oh you'll never even know it
actually 750 and should be calling back
more than happy that you opened it and
the in the body of my email
no way it was registered the name was
registered to you and give me so I
started to get going to be back
monitoring them and I was like okay guys
we did three of three and then come back
to the order in which you put them in
the dryer
my eyes are tired you know right three
two main three in the body of the email
it to people and I said okay I can't go
on
come May all right you going on that day
that day with the other guys i just
turned 30 and down and take a nap
hello the information that we are going
to this person without I monitoring them
they were doing and I had a metric
all right so I said okay I've got a
hundred forty-two email like Richmond
email addresses for . llamo over 9000
bad . down your arms for greater than
equal right
ok they're well more than 9,000 doing
but 9 out at that
time to edit this for greater than go to
your fish back deliver to people that
hurt
I about . coming straight for that date
and . they did this is something I've
got all that any ok if you pick
something and it's not right and which
block or why you don't know if I trying
to tell me with free and i have work and
intelligence investigation
look at that you know that that little
while after you have your loss
creating a row I had any way to blue
you all got half
you already look for you or X hire a
good time for all that
no you don't find what you're looking
for and doesn't fail and one percent
confidence when you do find something
that a lot of or actually I've done for
you like it
well not so much here is how the world
cup
well well we start monitoring their
change this special
well why well because I would prevent
this business and none of these and eat
and that only all 15 different
explanation for why love
I looked at each other and not look you
get my not saying it like that
the resume before we talk about the tool
you can go out and they take your time
out your captures your everything out
the route or board and getting the whole
century and so
you can go out and you say why can't we
eat tuna
why because well I've been eliminated
not left this matter has got to be one
of you
ok so when i'm developing red gelatin
ventures and I this by the way I look
now or influence there's nothing there
but there's not enough time after that
so I took a look at the matter
you know what let's go look at emails
coming in this car riding and I thought
it was the one-man campaign money
well you know me and I'll register and I
think ok and let's do it again
go get a URL this man was research
domain
look at the detail find the main branch
that actor
check your family to me and I think this
over and over and over and over
also I didn't all right
each guy right here
I have however many registers and I
can't apply only one you've got right
here are the top three bad guys
Claire yeah you are you your personal
address is not eight is behind the
station
unfortunately people
it's going all you know added 40 it is
all go right through the heart and the
bad guy here so I'm saying that guy in
the back and registration I'm not saying
that you're like that guy
i'm talking about the people at giving
you register domain but I did it over
and over
I love this surprise that look
colleges or garden Sam and equal to or
elliptic an hour later and the why am I
gotta slide
why am i what
II about threat intelligence what is the
word rat you're a rat here
rat
oh my god Josh mission
so why you be back
whatever issue
yeah
hey matter here for you should care
right
hey I blew his stack blue people and
you're going to you about
no because you're bringing people you
care about people making great with that
right that you let me know and i are
feat because this market hit the road
it's looking for people who have horns
it matter up to you by the way
maybe not bothering me at all now you
after you
they get here long
what I the island
everything that I've done here the
problem is me and my organization
ok so I kept looking you doing that with
people pop over and over and over and
her dying wish was worth a thousand
words and i started known as thing and I
don't know if you can see you down here
you guys see that little circle it
around ok ok i got a blue dot here in a
blue dot here and a blue diver from the
domain light blue . when i started using
mouse you got a diagram that double jump
out to make it right
so we end of it
what I already built a little bit as
each morning I you know all I can move
on
it won't be because all right
by the time that I talked about around
whatever the Seelie was shielding one
register
there's my bag of ice cream
and the polar bear well then I have a
halloween after and i actually would
after an ad for mr. polar bear with it
no no he wants and she'll be too right
mr. polar bear did not care about you
all a very good night for but what do
you notice about the day and you're
right i have more data over that same
bad guys
more like this multiple you know me but
I didn't know it when I started I didn't
load look I don't know one guy had been
happening some people i had no I hit
that right edges start to ask questions
you're going to get more question great
so I that different questions may be
bigger than what I was one guy and
targeting certain party woman with
particular Russia and then over an
entire organization
people are blue local people that I
walking out whether it was is all great
tools we both watch later and it's our
core mission by thanks to Chris you know
now
so after i had done all this and I
finally draw this conclusion and
identify the group i was able to say
yeah well now I can take
now i actually had a threat and i feel
like if i have a little working popular
there were any got my house
Papa what you're going through but all I
did not marry all five countries
I and wet and cold by the way that it is
hard to find help them
did you hear me your phone number your
address and laugh very hard but i was
able to actually have to start small
let's start small and I want me there
was a legitimate reseller out there and
he was just trying to make use of a good
discount so that he could register
domains and resell them right
he could be a bit a good guy
it's not up to no good and he's
rebounded the main but he's caught up in
it that on it
okay in here is possible that she can
find you a fast
yeah companies do about your weird mole
and I black
yeah you laugh and their pride
you have a level of impact anybody here
black eye contact
black it great
you have practice and play you some
trusted black black with by accident
ok fine because I don't have my back
from being having a little bit so i did
go out with four people are people that
I mean like fighting young fish domains
had been used a little malware like . we
are you wish this you know on your
website for all the livery lot ransom I
our company that's wrong
sorry but they fishing
wait for sure right it feels like
forever
it hardware after all know that they
don't need because we all the time
I
so small but very smooth and I actually
get right back
they're doing and I don't want them for
a day or two
and sure enough for our red string and
it was in my tool amatory next day . of
the guy redshirt 300 most if not all my
three of them of course coming unknown
and you know customers go however they
set their email filters with the
automatic course not
domain coming in and any other already
categorized by Omega right so now i have
verified my suspicion that there
what they're registering your back and
edit that right
you read it bad guys
I'm going to market bad and Michael for
can go to your site for the two weeks
that was gettin on which bad guy away
from them they get violent
yeah completely bad you're not allowed
to go like the automatic fish
traditional but i will now that i think
about it what do I want to do i
recommend you take her lesson the
stricter action when possible in funky
that got a lot of that you have once you
have confirmed his suspicions are
natural areas you have you have to be
stronger and let lighten up later on
what kind of threat you're right
you want to analyze your data
you got a question you going back to
your data you have a question you
married it down right now
now you got me about but what
hey that's a whole nother what was the
point of that
and we're you able your organization for
ain't taken action based on information
hell not efficient and let you and I got
it
yeah I don't know hey are we blocking
mad
oh no what a great time and what
yeah hey but whatever the case may be
what you have you got back together and
then you take a look at it together
how I at least have a week and it's not
the top analyst there together
you got it you got it you got the abuse
to all of you are going to get one
what'd you get what'd you come up with
your piece of intelligence
I promise you everybody
all right so that intelligence is an
integrated profit
you know I want it done and the latter
i'm on her tongue
all right all right
I garden I kept an eye on block right
blah almost there traffic did I now find
you
now that I've gone black all right there
was a fight which meant that you might
be a bad guy and all together we have
been the one lion guard register and we
going right
just because he allowed us the best
right
yeah okay
we find my jacket
I encouraged you to light on a dry erase
wall
what time to answer every day going to
work with the question you're trying to
answer with that it will walk you're
doing fine and not probably got out
rabbit hole
then he doesn't need to be Lord Shiva
not or now or by you
you don't have your coworker and i will
put it you put it on put it on the wall
the side of it if i remove layers that
but make sure that whatever you're
working on it trying to
the question right now all right
don't be afraid to change direction I'm
one card from my book one but you might
be exactly what I know you have but i
just write me a ticket you working on
now because of the money pit may not
know everything you look at it is going
to yield an answer but what does it help
you more
happened about right or not we in your
time and from research to roll
not that perfect oh ok
put a section of weight and you like
network
yeah I might take after that morning or
maybe you might want to the mall
whatever you want
oh haha whatever action you take a
little bit of measure at times
yeah just what it does it so i have
about two minutes for question yet
I always liked it
oh I was doing
straining under the tree all right all
right all right sheet like my data
so I you're out why were you here and
all that money is a little off but it
may be equal
I like that and I added my period right
I have five great
and that's my help
yeah a job