is he going to do
ready madness are out he learned to
worry about hazards in the same
whoo all right but also a bunch last
minute of folks coming in but thanks
guys for coming today uh spending your
post launch coma with me a yeah I will
no doubt exceed the expectations of
letting you sleep through for the next
hour arm but thanks for coming out to
converge right this is 34 converge at
six year for be sized Detroit are
this is Detroit premier security
conference in case you haven't heard
that repeated over and over but if you
see Kay toward & Falk a walk in coral
leg
Ryan harp anybody wearing a red shirt be
sure to give them a great big hug
make it awkward let them know that you
appreciate the hard work they put in
because it really wouldn't have been
possible without all the help
before we get started talking about how
I stop worrying and expecting pentester
mistakes me ask a couple questions the
audience who here is a blue team member
who in the audience gets paid to defend
corporate networks
there's dozens of us all right
dozens and where are my red team dies
and who's getting it pay to to attack my
networks
ok good so go tell the the majority of
the last time you gave this presentation
there's a entire platoon of folks and
they might want to go watch somewhere
else we're gonna make fun of red team
folks a little bit last question
who here has heard the adage that pen
testers you're sorry defenders have to
be right a hundred percent of the time
attackers only happy right once it's
pretty common we keep hearing this over
and over and today I'm going to share
with you the teepees and the IOC's say
you can expect and detect those pen test
the mistakes that way you can win how
these engagements
before we get into all that Who am I
some of you in the audience know me and
for that i apologize you guys a sufferer
those are you don't on the other lovable
Jeremy nielsen a long time I sec member
i have been coming to my second meeting
since 2012
I guess that makes me an old hat around
here are a lot of you may know me best
for my trolling on Twitter and an IRC
but I love security operations i love
digging into the packets i love watching
tcp down by love
watch my ideas to learn to my sim alerts
a lot of stuff going on there's a lot of
great information
I really love to be digging into it and
inevitably
i'm looking at a screen like this
somebody's gotta walk make the comment
that looks a lot like the matrix right
and I don't even see the code anymore i
I just see blonde brunette redhead apt1
shine up
Russia going to go through and doing my
threat hunting and I'm digging through
the ids alert kind of here what's going
on my network
I tend to feel like this guy right now
is cool hunting for his prey
I feel like a real badass hey I'm
digging in there i'm doing what's going
on i'm chasing those people are breaking
the policies
that's really kind of cool yeah it's
exciting
my teams may tell you I'm a little bit
more like this guy right the Gordon
Ramsey of security operations and
yelling at him for you know messing up
how they're responding to malware or
something is not going right now
I don't know that I deserve this but it
did make a guy cry once I don't see him
in the audience who just won this one
guy cry
I asked them to come in and stop circle
facebook so much but the view of blue
team
the review of security operations that I
hate the most is the view of a when a
red team guy comes in and says yeah I
spent five minutes on your network i pop
domain admin drops the 50-page report my
crops and walks out right
it gives the view that the blue team
guys were just standing there like
Walmart greeters saying hi welcome to
our network
please don't steal anything you know
those Walmart greeters right here i was
trying to leave and they want to look
what's inside your packets so I hate
that view
but the entire impetus for this
presentation all started with a phone
call that our security outer that our
service desk received on a monday
morning
I executives admin assistant called up
the service that said hey my phone's not
working
would you guys mind coming up and seeing
what's going on
and anybody that's worked in any size of
an organization knows you do whatever
you can for the executive admin is right
they've got the ear of the people that
matter they know what's going on I know
who's
who's doing the right thing so of course
the service desk monkey goes running on
up there was darkness brownie points
he gets digging around under the
admissions desk and Edmonds heavies
these huge phone systems they have these
multi-line consoles they have these
additional biol pads and there's cables
going everywhere right
service desk guys looking around under
the dads and kind of weeding through the
cables and try to figure out what's
going on
you can't make heads or tails of it but
some of them looks unplug and if the
cable is unplugged that's a network team
job right now our cables never guys so
now we're guy goes up there to plug in
the cable
he's rooting around after a couple of
minutes calls up the security operations
center comes with the sock and says hey
guys on this this phone issue
yeah there's there's a device that looks
like it's plugged into the network and
it's not one of ours
so our incident response plan looks a
little something like this
it's a little slow i apologize for that
but everybody's running around with her
hair on fire and oh my gosh what's going
on is this an incident is it a pen test
what's going on oh my gosh we got to
know what's going on everybody is lit up
so we send a security operations guy up
there to take a look
and in his best wisdom unplug the device
unplug it from the network and brings it
back down
probably shouldn't have done that but it
is what it is right so we're looking at
thing over
we're not quite sure what it is this is
exactly what the the device look like
we're looking at over to try to figure
out what the heck it is we're looking
for some sort of asset ID trying to make
sure if it's one of ours
looking for some sort of stickers are
thinking that there might be one of
these or are looking for a logo and let
us know what the Pony Express maybe a
fresh sticker but we're not seeing
anything right
it turns out as we dig into this it's an
intel knock some new unit of computing
and it is micro form factor pc he had
some laptop memory
you had a hard drive had a couple of
dongles traditional network adapters and
gsm modem
right but as we're going through the
same were like well it's kind of hard
drive
what's on the hard drive what's in the
box what's in the box
so are one of our stock analysts used to
be a service desk monkey
he had a few adapters managed to get one
of those we can mount the drives got a
fun kid after a month of driving we find
out
sure enough it's not encrypted if you
drop a box behind enemy lines and you
don't encrypt the data
okay fine so we're gonna get through
this thing and right away we find
identifying information all over this
thing we love it we let us know that
this was the pen testers box
we recognize the name of the company was
somebody that we were expecting business
with I and so that lower the threat
level right away okay we know this is
not an incident this is just a pen test
of some sort of threat level reduced
we're digging around
we've got all their tools we've got
access to all the cords that their use
it which is great for us because then
that gives us a platform to play with
later but we've also got their logs
we've got bash history
so we're digging through the bastard
file and seeing all the commands that
they're running through and we managed
to see that they're trying to
troubleshoot the network connection
okay to run an act bypass scripts and
some running some mac tools they
obviously did not get onto our network
we see in the long as you see in the
past history there trying to figure out
what's going on around 3am they gave up
and then of course the next morning the
executive admin finds her phone's not
working because they're plugged into one
of the dial pad is that it actually into
the network
as we get through the logs in bash
history
we also noticed that they were
communicating back to a command control
host and they were clever
they weren't using passwords right they
were using ssh keys that they managed to
leave on the box
now what happens next is a bit
contentious we're not entirely sure what
happened but somewhere of the next
morning the guy who sets up our pen test
engagements get some secure text
messages from the pen testers say in
their command-and-control host which is
also the mail server was completely
bombed
you have no idea what happened they're
not able to get the thing but-- they
have no IP addresses they have no
information at all but something went
wrong and it's obviously our fall right
I love this adapter through
I love it
premier security conference
alright so offended
you're pissed right and i'm going to say
that I can't blame them right i mean
they're there to test our security
good they're there to pawn off they're
not there to be the models of security
I mean he was absolutely ticked off
they they they just couldn't wrap their
mind around the fact that they had been
owned that they have totally lost
control of the engagement and so they
ended up storming off storming off the
engagement a rage quit they're like
we're out here
we're done League I was we had enough
that it was unrecoverable right so I I
can't say that I blame them you know
they lost unencrypted sensitive data
behind enemy lines that in segments are
trusted an untrusted networks that are
communicating with a box is part of the
production network they had allegedly
had their credential stolen and used
against them
you know they had no detection for an
incident occurring on their network they
had no incident response capabilities of
their own and their box stop working and
they they were unable to proceed with
their pen test right so
ah I don't blame them for being pissed
off you know it in the end nobody ended
up messing up to own in the pen testers
they had no logs the IP address nothing
to show what happened
so last time I gave this presentation
the platoon of pen testers in the back
like oh no you did it
how dare you and in fact there is a
comment on the YouTube video on iron
geek site you know where you know
company be unlawfully hex legit
companies be company as machines you
know of course they walked off the pen
test the well that's not the point of
this right and while this is this entire
presentation is a vehicle for me to be
able to share this story and really make
fun of these pen testers the real point
that I'm trying to drive across is that
I my first pen test engagement
I learned that we don't have to be right
a hundred percent of times and the
pentek don't have to write once they
have to be right a lot as well
they're going to make mistakes and we
can expect them we can detect them and
then we can win on these engagements
right and that's the point
it's not about the reverse hacking it's
about detecting the pen testers and you
guys coming out as a blue team members
with a positive light after the
engagement so i'm going to share for
simple use cases with you guys so you
guys can help detect pen testers on your
network first going to talk about
detecting the common tool to pen testers
use it
this is actually really great there's
gonna be a lot of IOC's in there they
can use their talk briefly about
detecting road machines on your network
we're going to talk about detecting pass
the hash attacks
I'm not just because pen testers use
those but it's a common lateral movement
from any type of attacker
well talk briefly about detecting brute
force attacks because it's rather boring
we're going to wrap up with talking
about what do you do once you find pen
testers on your network how do you do
incident response there
so for each one of those you know and
Stimpy I have a song right what roles
downstairs alone or in pairs was over
the neighborhood neighbor's dog his logs
right arm every use cases going to
divide a different job depends on what
we call these are dependencies
you've got a lot of great information on
your network if you're not pulling logs
and looking at them regularly you're
missing out on a treasure trove of data
is going to help you better defend your
networks and of course it's really hard
to use all those terabytes along unless
you've got some sort of sim right hole
and have a log aggregator pulling those
logs into a centralized system have a
tool that allows you to write simple
alerts so when these things pop up you
can get alerted rather immediately
rather than having to find out when you
get a pen test to record a week later
I'm a little partial arcsight it
it is that you need a a whopper class
machine in order to run it but once
you've got it up and running is
fantastic so everybody wants to talk our
site with me afterwards can find me
I love that tool but i think the big
takeaway from this isn't just taken away
the IOC's that i have here because
eventually going to get to a pen test
where these these are techniques are no
longer valid
the IOC's are no longer valid to keep up
with red team presentations on iron
geeks aight i'll look at the tools and
techniques that are being developed
figure out how they work
figure out how you can use them on your
network practice with them look at the
red team reports that are being
delivered to you and ask the red team
members
don't make fun of them and don't do it
after you hacked back of the machines
but work with them to understand how the
attack works and how you can recreate
that attack that they used on your
network
look at the logs look what Jack gets
generated of what you can learn on later
on because this will get you so far as a
lot of gimmicky stuff in here and it's
only gonna get you so far so I continue
to learn continue to hunt for new ways
that you're going to be exploited and
then my slides are not actually going to
be online and i actually forgot to bring
the handouts with me so i will post the
actual IOC's you guys don't need a
furiously right all this information
down but we will post the slides for the
the IOC's that you want to use online
some place so we might as well get right
into it right
pen testers love their tools they really
love their tools
it makes for a repeatable process right
they can go from client to client they
can reuse a lot of the same code
a lot of the same techniques and this
also gets pivoted because more of the
unscrupulous companies can become
pentest puppy mills
we never secure our networks were all
vulnerable to msoe no 67 or whatever the
the
the harbinger of the day is you want to
offend our networks adequate we don't
patch those vulnerabilities and so they
sure enough have the right tools to
exploit that and then they can script
for a junior pentester send them out
drop the 20 page report and they are
done making built boatloads of money for
this use case you're going to want to
have proxy logs proxy logs are
invaluable just normally if your proxy
doesn't provide security relevant
categorization letting you know about
malicious outbound sources or hacking
computer security categories you can use
those to build rules around with the
categories being popped in there
we got to have some sort of proxy locks
if you don't have any type of proxy log
shame on you
i recommend blue coat but you can at
least pull dns logs and if you're not
getting papac's logs have to do is log
sorry if you got windows dns servers are
your admins are going to complain that
it's a resource hog and chewing up
resources
turn on the bug pull those in your sim
you got to do it there's a lot of great
information there
so probably the the tool that pen
testers are used most I think every pen
tester is going to touch cali backtrack
at some point in time it's universal
right the tools already pre-installed
they work out of the box i don't have to
to mess with it there's no muss no fuss
so it's not surprising you're going to
find this on your network and Kelly's
got the slogan right the quieter you
become the more you're able to hear
I find this really funny because kali
linux by itself is actually very noisy
so Kelly linux is really a noisy during
installation so when you're installing
this in a vm hear a song that's on a
hard drive
it's making all sorts of calls out after
the first boot
it's making calls out to to check for
updates anytime you install a new tool
anytime you do apt-get update
it's making calls all right let's not
forget that Kelly too . no implemented
automatic updates on a weekly basis
it's going to be calling out and looking
for updates now it's worth noting at
this point the live CD doesn't appear to
actually check for updates so if your
pen testers are going live
it's less likely going to find them
through these methods
there's other ways but not this way so
needless to say if your pen testers are
seeing this on their machine and they're
on my network I've detected them right
dns and HTTP logs proxy logs and EMS
lost so what we're looking for are just
three IOC's here right
you're looking for calls out to http
that Kelly door security that Kelly that
org and archive is some number i usually
see archive dashboard and Kelly that org
you may see a number between one and
nine so look for calls out to this
somebody can go to www.healthcare.gov
not trigger your rule but any app get
any installation
anything that gets updated holes
directly from these repositories
so look for calls out to those that's
going to be your harbinger of death
now i also found that during the
installation of cali it ask you to
select the time zone once it's like what
time zone you're in me to call out to be
in that pool that ntp door now we've got
a lot of d behind a network that might
be a big false positive
but you've got about primarily windows
network keep an eye out for that
shouldn't be there
one thing that shouldn't be there unless
you're running on unless you're building
network cards
there's a weekly update after the first
boot about a half an hour after the
first boot and then weekly after that
there's some app that gets the mac
oh you I database so you can identify
probably through air crack or something
what the network card is that you're
dealing with
so it downloads this like 40 Meg file of
all the macro you is from standards that
i triple e door
that's going to be rare on your network
look for that happens regularly pen
testers don't turn that stuff off
we're going to come on your network
they're going to think I've got a
pre-installed
but then middle of the week is going to
update the macro you I database and
you're going to find them
now some Panthers use metasploit a lot
of a more junior pen testers use
metasploit some of the older ones
that's our script kiddies right but at
some point I think we all use metasploit
on the network
perhaps somebody's breaking violating
some sort of policy may be trying to use
metasploit - boy doesn't update when you
run it but every guide that i look at
from a pencil securities - boy guide
I all the way to the hacker playbook
always says before you run msf
council-run msf update
who's going to avoid guidance like
they're right so in kali linux when you
update metasploit it pulls from the
repository HT to http that Kelly that or
there's a sub you are I that specific
matters boy whom look that up but if
you're just looking for HTTP that Kelly
that org going to be fine
other versions I think like samurai WTF
and other installations actually pulled
directly from updates that matters . com
so take a look at both of those and
you'll find those guys when they pop on
your network
now I love web application assessments
I love digging into how a web
application works and get a toy around
with the actual request that are going
in there when you open up
burp suite on cali for the first time
even if you tell it don't send amount of
its usage statistics
it makes connections out to perfect it
upward swing . net and pro that part
figured on that every time that you open
it up afterwards thinking calls out to
ports figured out net and I see this IP
address on there
during my testing it didn't actually
make a dns call before i started going
to that IP address and may be hard-coded
in there
or maybe I just screwed something up
with my dns cache
either way that may change in the future
but it might be a good indicator there
are hosting at amazon AWS just keep an
eye out for it but somebody is loading
up burp suite
it's checking for updates and in their
developer forums pen testers have asked
him
we need the ability to turn this off and
developers are like okay thanks bye
they're not going to do anything about
it so look for because that's never
going to change
look for ports figure that out on your
network now since we're doing talking
about web application of 7th also like
Nick donate or give me some basic
information about the web servers that
I'm looking at it doesn't update
automatically you have to force it oh
who doesn't right
you might as well look for WWE not
certain that now when you look at that
in your logs
my first inclination is that some sort
of computer incident response team
maybe us serve carnegie mellon sir right
maybe just a lame but take a look at it
right
if you see calls out to that it probably
shouldn't be there and since you're
looking for Nick go anyway
look for user agent string that contain
the word make oh now you're not to be
able to do anything when somebody's
attacking your external website and
you're seeing that in there but if you
see this stuff sourced internally
somebody's doing something that they
showed it right so just keep an eye out
for it but actually you're more likely
to see a nap antacids melty go
LT goes gray right gives me a the
ability or gives the pen test is the
ability to gather OS sent to pull
together a lot of information on an
organization to display it to be able to
use that to to help and aid in their
exploitation
so in kali linux when you open up
melty go for the first time
you get the standard hi welcome to melt
egos mean when you get to this screen
you have already transmitted 1500
packets to perturb that , my network
by the time you get to the end of the
setup screen you can communicate 30,000
packets to perturb on my network
there's a lot of great stuff in there
that you can use to detect them if
somebody's use a melty go on your
network and then after one of my
presentation
somebody asked about core impact I've
never seen core impact use but i
understand there are some teams that
will use this for doing vulnerability
assessments so just in case one of those
companies make a local Detroit company
is using core security on your network
just look for update coming from impact
of course security com
so I'm giving me a lot of gimmicky basic
tools that pen testers are used in many
ways to detect that but think a little
bit broader think about the tools the
pen testers need to do their jobs penosa
just like the rest of us they need food
they need water they need hugs
they also have to file their TPS reports
they have to file their timesheets they
need to check mail and understand what's
going on at back at the office
you need to get yelled at by the boss
right so they probably got to connect to
the VPN someplace they probably got to
connect a webmail owa got some mail that
something that they're checking into so
if you know what company or pen testers
I come from if you know what company
your boss is going to be outsourcing to
whether its rapid seven or whoever it is
do a little bit of reconnaissance on
them before the engagement instead of
pools
look for their mail for example rapid7
not to call them out without an
engagement their meal
are there are VPN servers or mario and
luigi to grab at seven calm and they've
got some script that run that was
running on a network
look for for weird things going back to
weird rapid 7.com sites right all right
let's talk
out detecting road machines on network
you're going you got contestants that
are an engagement
they're coming in and dropping off boxes
like they were trying to do it and at
their engagement with us
you're going
scary boxes dropped off on your network
that you don't know about and they're
trying to hide
you're going to want to detect those as
early as possible so during another pen
test engagement we had folks that were
sitting on our network we detected them
early on because we detected metasploit
and Kelly be calling out we were right
on the first day we detect these guys
are only out we knew it was pen testers
we knew it was going on we ignore the
alerts are being generated we just let
them do what they wanted
because we wanted to work with them
right we want to understand what are
vulnerabilities are so we just let them
run and have fun and being the exciting
and exhilarating guy that I am I spent
my Saturday's threat hunting i go
digging through the same i looked for
active channels in dark side and see
what's going on and that weekend I
wanted to see you
we have been keeping track these pen
testers what what were they doing on the
network and we had some alerts we had
some IP addresses but it looked like
they were changing their IP addresses
how do you keep track of pen testers are
changing their IP addresses so after a
little bit of thought it became obvious
there's likely they're changing their IP
addresses but not their mac address
right
so for this use case you want to pull
your dhcp logs and you don't point your
dns logs gonna get the host names out of
the dns log they're making requests and
you want to get the the host things out
of dhcp logs as well as the mac
addresses can be a bit of pain in the
butt but this is this is kind of an easy
win your guys now as a bigger through
are trying to find the pen testers i
started with an own IP address
management see these guys were used in
vmware and when I started digging
through some of the other IP addresses
that are being used
ah i saw another mac address sure enough
I pull up a list of of virtualized
virtualization mac addresses online so i
created a rule for that went through and
start digging through the older to
manage to see all the times that they
were changing their IP addresses not
only I had a trail that i can go from
there hostname and IP address when they
change the hostname not a big deal when
they changed their IP address
not a big deal now have a trail to go
with
because i was looking for the mac
addresses now it's easy enough to to get
a new address right eh client eth0 on
linux right ipconfig / release renew our
windows
it's pretty easy to change the mac
address in vmware you just go into the
options right put pen testers don't seem
to do this
and since you're looking for mac
addresses you might as well look for a
joker as well so what I ended up finding
as I was to get through the mac
addresses was actually we had one guy
that was using vmware we have the other
guy that was using virtual host or
virtual box and add some isn't going
through and and diagramming out where
they were going on what they were
hitting it became obvious this was two
separate people
I think it was the older guy that was
used in virtualbox but as I'm explaining
this to the rest of the team
it became easier just to refer to these
guys thing one and thing two right so
attributions sucks when you're trying to
figure out whether it's China or Russia
is pretty useless but at least for
understanding what's going on on the
inside of your network attributions
actually pretty reasonable things that
can identify and separate out different
actors on your network do it
and so there are you looking at mac
addresses and got a list of host names
when I think it one step further right
monitor all the mac addresses on your
network look for new things that are
popping up
look for new host that shouldn't be
there now we all work in large
organizations everybody comes in every
day you've got 1,500 knew I you know
discover and request and you know you
you've got all sorts of dhcp logs are
coming in
you're gonna think it's impossible to do
start with your net standard naming
conventions start with the things that
you know are good right when you're not
being attack when things are low start
looking at what supposed to be there
will commonly shows up right
look at your standard naming convention
look at the things that follow whatever
it is that you use all of our companies
use standard naming conventions because
it makes it easier for service desk
folks but it makes it easy for us to
so if you see things that stand out
right if you see iphone if you see
Android see some weird printer address
in there right
you see some vendor KPMG's on your
networker file . on your network and her
showing up as vile . com
and then maybe okay fine that somebody's
got Kelly that local domain because they
didn't change
VMware's dhcp settings the set of
different hosting and if you've got a
box that you're not quite sure about it
looks like it means to name any standard
but maybe it's a little bit different
usps log in right you can of course go
into active directory losers computers
and try and find the computer name and
you're gonna stumble around searching
for this thing
no just from your computer reach out PS
login to whack whack whatever the
computer name is and even your standard
non privileged user credential should be
able to query SMB on the box
if you don't see your user ID reflected
back to you
probably not part of your domain if it's
not part of your domain what you doing
there is your way to investigate let you
know something is valid and out
now after the last time i get this
presentation a red team guy that made
the suggestion that if it's potentially
harmful if it's potentially malicious
you want to send your credentials to
this box
maybe not right so you're going to try
this
be careful do it when it's not in the
middle of an incident do it when it's
not the likelihood of having somebody
have a potentially bad box here and in
any case have a canary account right
have a token account that you can set up
that you've got an alert on elsewhere
that this thing shouldn't be used very
often and when it does it let you guys
know
so if somebody's capture that credential
some is capturing that ntlm handshake
and cracking the password and we're
using throughout the past
throughout the network you can detect
that so be careful but there's ways
around it
let's talk about it
pass the hash attacks passion has
attacks are pretty common there's a
variety of potential attacks right
Active Directory attacks we got past the
ticket we got golden tickets overtaking
we've got kerberos right
contestants love using many cats and
windows credential editor and there's a
lot of good credential attacks out there
you can read up on but I think past the
hashtag is common enough and something
that you can actually detect and spend
some time preventing you just turn off
until and we never turn off any alarm so
i better that we can detect these
attacks when they attempted or
successful and the way this works is I
mean penthouse has got a basic foothold
in your network
I see hinge back there I learned
this from him from a couple years ago
when they get the basic foothold in the
network
they're going to look around dumping
credentials hoping that somebody is log
into a box with domain admin credentials
or some sort of elevated privileges that
they can then use to put it elsewhere in
the network or maybe get into your
domain controller to start taking
control of more stuff
the dependencies here you want to gather
windows security locks from as many
machines you possibly can
I'm not an advocate for log all the
things i think that the ways the time I
think that's a waste of space
I'll but windows security logs going to
want to get as many of these as possible
and if you have limited space if you
have limited eps on your sim at least
get a representative sample at least
focus on your critical machines but
pulling those windows security logs now
pass the hash is an easy attack these
guys to rock out to get access to a
machine
they dumped the Sam to get a hash and
they can replay that hash
I using something like PS exactly
there's tools in madison . they're going
to use that hash and bounced from server
to server
I've seen it used where on one of the
pen tests they were remotely starting
power shell with a base64 encoded
payload that was launching a reverse
shell connecting back so they're going
around the network rather than than
pivoting around an hour here just pop in
box after box and have a connect back to
the central management so that they can
use at a later time
now if you
oh how pass the hash works are several
guys out there that talk about handling
and attacking pass the hash
so if you need some background I start
with Microsoft's guide on mitigating
pass the hash pretty good guide and gets
a little technical I was very limited
the NSA also has a guide and reducing
the effectiveness of pass the hash
attacks again it's it's okay well i
really like I think every pen test every
blue team should have a copy of this
printed out distributed around your
network have it on your bedside table
have it in the toilet wherever you go i
love this guide spot in the adversary
with Windows Event log monitoring not
just focusing on pass the hash attacks
look at all sorts of credential attacks
and other attacks going on Windows
domain and how you can detect those and
things that you can set up a very
vendor-neutral so it's just showing you
from the windows log point of view
what's going to trigger when certain
attacks along again and see people take
a note so I'm leaving now
leave it up there for a moment now
specifically for pass the hash attacks
you're going to be looking for events
like this
- now I know this is an eye chart you
guys aren't able to see this will blow
us up here in a moment but every attack
because we don't turn off and tell em I
every pass the hash attack starts off
this event ID to want 4624 4644 are
successful login
you can also look for - 6:25 to my case
a lot of false positives for that for
some reason for some legacy apps you can
look for 4624 4625 these things are
network login is right there not
interactive their network basis all SMB
and he like multiplication
we're going to look at the logon type 3
you're going to look for the account
name being not at all
now its twenty sixteen since as far back
as the year 2000 everybody's told been
told to turn off all sessions and the
windows domains
some people do some people don't you're
likely to see if you haven't turned off
in all sessions a lot of ntlm no session
is going on in a network you can read
those out
we can turn it off at least when you're
detective or pass the hash the account
name is that going to be empty so look
for something that's a their factories
some of the attacks that I've seen in my
logging system the account name is
actually been really weird that it's not
actual ah it was like random letters as
well as popping up it may have just been
our site screwed something up but and
then lastly you look for authentication
package and he liked the alternative
here's curve rose and it's not a
kerberos attack is an anti-islam attack
we can just mitigate this if we all
turned off ntlm and we know that
executives don't want to bring down the
network and everybody there's that guy
who sits in the corner and you can turn
off until I because it might it might
break something we did we get to someone
to do that right
turn off that Hill I never breaks
everything so if you're building a role
in our site
that's just what the rule looks like a
pretty simple pretty straightforward and
once you got the rule set up the pen
testers start popping on the network if
you get a lot of a particular device
this is going to light up like a
Christmas tree gonna get a whole lot of
alerts you to find out where these guys
are at and chase them down this
flea about detecting the brute force
attacks the common headache on networks
a lot of sim tools come with
pre-installed rules
inevitably one of them is some you know
port scale attack on my external
interface
I i was speaking with a gentleman and an
auto supplier there
mssp for sending them critical alerts
and you showed me a bunch of the
critical alerts and one of the critical
alerts was you know an external ports
can you know critical alert deal with
this now
you can't do anything with that it was a
waste of freaking time
so everybody with a reasonable amount of
of sense
turn that off right they turned off the
rules report scans it there's nothing
that they could do about it
there are
things that you can do with this the
dependencies for this use case are going
to be firewall logs you are pulling all
your part of all along anyway right
pull your firewall logs . windows
security logs going to show you the user
logins and pulling your linux this long
as you let you know about the user is
trying to log into your system as well
pull in from as many devices as you
possibly can manage
so I break this down into there's four
basic types of brute force attacks
now I mean your break is out of the
subcategories and in the end he probably
end up like 30 or 40 of these but I
break it out into four basic brute force
use cases
the first is used in casting right we've
got the same source trying different
usernames that probably using the same
password right
this searching for a foot hole you're
going to
to the user names that are being gassed
these things legitimate did they
actually exist on your network are they
just going through am San and Santos and
tom l smith m smith and smith and they
using , wonder are they just casted
they're probably looking with easy
passwords i worked at a large pizza
company where pizza 1 2 3 was not
uncommon to find as a default password
but your organization probably isn't too
different right
we're no longer in spring people
probably change your passwords or
service that is giving new password as
summer 2016 and maybe there's a list out
there that somebody's riding through
with compromised credentials so there's
a lot of good information that can be
seen from an alert like this arm and a
lot of organizations you're gonna get
over ran with a lot of brute force
attacks but someone is going through
different usernames from the same source
that's a bit odd right take a look at
that point a bit more common and quite a
bit more false positives come from
somebody from the same source
the same username right , type of brute
force attack but this is also a lot of
your stupid users and i'm going to call
the user stupid but you got the guy who
can't remember his password three days
later comes back from vacation and needs
to have his password reset right so he's
going to be the one that's popping these
alerts most of the time but keep an eye
out for it anyway because it's going to
be the pen test was trying to get in
ah oui
being in with all the other stupid uses
now how people that disagree with me
that port scan isn't really a brute
force attack
we can argue about that later i can do
that over beers tonight or whatever but
when you think about it its most basic
level you're going through port by poor
to see what's open what's closed
you're going to host by host to see
what's what's available where where you
can move to next right
your brute forcing going through every
sixty five thousand words on the machine
to see what's there now as I said
earlier people turn off this rule
because they're getting bombarded with
the external scans that they can't do
anything about it was somebody's inside
your network and port scanning probably
shouldn't right
we don't have a network game that does
this and that's common you know you can
follow up with them i would not exclude
the network team but follow up with
these things they shouldn't be happening
daily they shouldn't even be happening
weekly so turn it on
look for the internals you've got
critical machines definitely be looking
for those right
I work for again large pizza company
that had a lot of pci data
it makes sense if someone is going to
try and numerate in your your pc I range
your segment pci zones
that's a bit creepy so if you've got
critical servers and get things that
you're sensitive about at least look
they're right and then a bit different
from a port scan is an address can
this is where somebody's got a
particular port they're looking for poor
137 and looking for the vulnerability
there are para running an exploit to
take advantage of SMB or their port 1904
something with ssdp but they're blowing
through every IP address that got that
that vulnerability lined up there just
looking for the right target to pop that
thing on
and so we're going to go address by
address looking for what's vulnerable
for it
your pork skins likely not going to
detect this right because it's looking
for on a single IP address 10 or more
hits in 60 seconds or whatever it is
this is a bit different look for
different IP addresses on a single IP
address
well we're going to talk about that
briefly i know i was incredibly boring
once you've found pen testers on your
network right whether it's that you take
to the tool on the system you found the
road machine
maybe you just figured out that the guys
are there what do you do next right now
before we get any further
typical disclaimer is usually comes at
the beginning of the talk more relevant
here
I'm not your manager right I'm not going
to be able to say do this
and thou shalt not have any consequences
right I'm not your mother i'm not going
to wipe out after yeah
so some of the things here may be
illegal depending on the states that
folks come from
I'll so you see they put your job in
jeopardy usual
judgment so let me start with a story
one day sake
this sitting there watching the console
and he gets one of the largest detects
the tool is a Kelly outbound hit right
he sees it go out of the few of those
and wow what's going on right so it goes
to the guy who sets up the the pen test
engagement goes you know we'll call him
Ron Ron hey is it is this you is this
you doing stuff around being the shady
kind of guy that he is like maybe
because that little smirk right so the
sake let's take that as a yes and closes
out the alert doesn't document anything
goes about his day until about an hour
later when more alerts get generated
goes back to Ron and mom
see more of these alerts is everything
all right everyone everything good
oh yeah don't worry about not going to
just close out right
so a little while later he sees a
printer may get a call out to cali that
Oregon that's that's a little bit weird
he calls me over
you know let me know hey I've been
seeing these things going on of course I
get a little irate
why why we documented this why didn't
you let me know sooner if Ron is doing
this show we know what they're doing
should we be tracking this
the answer is yes so we dig into it a
little bit further mean he adds a little
weird that a printer is making a call
out to cali . heart
so we go chase down every guy hey what's
this IP address Matt back to you
ok maps back to this IP or this mac
address I mac addresses on the sport
what do you want to do we're looking
around like shot it down
sure why not right we are doing weird
stuff whatever they're doing isn't
supposed to be there so if Ron is doing
some weird stuff
I'll shut it down five minutes later I
get called into a conference room where
of course we got to turn the port back
on and and they let me know about the
pen test going on and got to the port
back on as soon as we turn the power
back on five minutes there's another
cali hit going out like okay that
can't keep a straight face on this one
that gives up but in that story we had a
quite a few screw-ups
just four more security operation side
right now they're not even talking about
the penetration testers are tools that
kept going out and calling out and
trigger in our alerts so I want to talk
about the good the bad and the ugly ways
of dealing with the pen testers or
anybody else once you find them on your
network
now these are the good things right
these are the things that you should
always be doing right
use your incident response plan
that's what it's there for you got an
incident the red team members are called
and probably to test your incident
response plan not just to find all the
cool vulnerabilities on a network but
use the incident response plan that's
there and then once you've engaged that
and you've let whoever know your boss
their boss whatever you're into the
response plan says to do
stop the clock go to the person who sets
up the pen test and say I found these
guys because now that change that
conversation from how is the sock doing
two more of a conversation around how
can the red team help us get better at
detecting a war are responding to events
later on right so it's no longer testing
you
no longer testing your your sock is
testing the network now as part of your
is a response plan
I don't call this out up here you really
got to have a few key things right
have it tested i had a time haven't
defined ahead of time the worst time to
be looking for
how do you respond to this stuff is in
the middle of a crisis because you got
30 things going on you got a whole bunch
of alerts you want to investigate the
last thing you want to do is oh my gosh
what do i do - I turn off the port way
now turn off your food white owl right
so have a tabletop exercises ahead of
time if you've got it
if you don't have an incident response
plan and you haven't run through a
tabletop exercise you should not be
doing
anonymous or on unannounced red team
exercise
I mean just point blank right but it
happens and it happens all over the
place where people bring in the red team
penetration testers
have somebody that's a defined incident
responder was recording the notes write
all their job is is were defined
I keep track of everything that was
found all the systems that were touched
everything that you collect all the
artifacts
I keep track of the information have
somebody else who's assigned as the
incident manager
it doesn't have to be the sock manager
it doesn't have to be the vp of
information security have somebody who's
going to coordinate and distribute tasks
because last thing you want because
everybody's hair is going to be a
firearm is running around
oh my gosh what's going on it's an
incident last thing you want is 50
different people telling your stock
analyst
hey check this out and he did you think
about looking over there know all that
should come through a single chain of
command right
that should be the incident manager so
have all the stuff to find ahead of time
right
as part of your incident response plan
should be tracking down all the machines
that were touched
you've got the logs hopefully you've got
all the logs peasant hopping through the
network for pivoting they're getting
credentials track all that stuff down
right
collect all the logs you may not have
all the logs right
they're going to be touching machines
end . we don't get a large man . maybe
use carbon black maybe you don't
collected
large as you can for everything else is
hard on access layer switches but if you
can get a span port and you can put a
sniff around there
nothing is going to be better than
seeing the actual packets that are going
across the network letting you know
exactly where they went
and what they did now going back to the
story
one of the bad things that we did was
shutting that poured down early
we look like a printer printer should be
making calls out and that's right anyway
right so it's no big deal
so shut down the fort except that during
an engagement pen testers can pick up
there more laptops walk out the door and
nobody knows where they were
whatever do it they can go back tomorrow
and try again and we've lost all
opportunity to attract them for our
network so don't shut down the port
before it's necessary to do so right
don't unplug devices 15 years ago when I
was going through training for this
it was told isolated keep this from are
extending past where they've already got
into right now we're as soon as never
gets on a box shut that thing down right
the wisdom now is we can get memory cap
or memory dumps
we can take four and six image of these
things that we don't want to tip our
hand to an attacker where they change
their their their tactics because we've
detected them and they know that we've
detected that right so don't unplug
devices you can lose a lot of valuable
data and then during that same pen test
on protesters are pivoting through the
network they were using metasploit the
other shells they managed to tap in to
the microphones and cameras so that they
can see what different people are doing
and one of my stock analyst are that
they were doing that on his machine
he got really ticked off and so at the
end of the day it's like six o'clock
he's going around trying to figure out
where on the third floor that they were
at trying to figure out what happens
from there in he was really upset about
this thing I you want to use talking
about like / in the tire
leaving some president for these guys at
the conference room so I mean I gotta
warn ya
no matter what don't come from the pen
testers is not going to lead to anything
positive nothing good is going to come
out of this but maybe
why not plug them right if they're going
to listen in through meterpreter to your
conversations if you're going to hack
your email
if they're going to listen in to your
phone calls by hacking voice system or
just packing capturing the VoIP system
why not listen to what they're doing put
a little bug in the conference room
where there and figure out where they're
at the start listening in to them
port scan their machine right on our
networks we have free rein around
vulnerability of vulnerability scans
that should include the user subnets
right so scan their machine and see
what's open
Callie is a little bit lock down these
days
use their own credentials against them
why not right they're going to use your
credentials against you
we're going to use your credentials
across the network how funny would it be
to log into their email system and so
their boss an email saying hey this this
this place sucks i'm quitting
I'm out of here I'm gone or maybe mimic
thousands of homes across the network to
ports poofy make it harder for them to
do their job right
so be creative and be careful right when
I got to this point of the kind of the
presentation before I must have
triggered the platoon of of a red
teamers you know they were they were
antsy the feedback they basically gave
me was why don't work with the pen
testers might not work with them on the
engagement and I mean a typical pentest
engagement
these guys are adversarial there
listening in to you they're there
hacking your machines right there
leaving middleware make an adversarial
back right so just a recap and all these
things are kind of gimmicky but we talk
about detecting the pen testers tools
I'll keep an eye out for cali door
secured a dark alley door
we talked about detective road machines
on the network for dhcp logs we talk
about printing off this guy right
look for 4624 4625 events to detect ntlm
pass the hash tax
we talked briefly about brute force
attacks and detecting those and we
talked a little bit about in a response
to what you do
the good the bad the ugly ways once you
find them on your network
so with two minutes left
any questions yes sir
in my experience I have not so yeah
possibly yeah i mean it
I don't know anybody that's going to
agree that shirt now you've got the get
out of jail card just as they do right
yeah that's a good idea
fair enough there was a box on your
network though
yep
but yeah exactly so the question was how
do you know that it's really a pen
tester as opposed to a real attacker or
just the zombie machine right arm that
mail server that was being used for
command and control
I mean we knew about it because I while
you belong to the pen testing firm that
we knew was contracted so in that case
we get away with it but yeah how do you
know it's not a zombie machine how do
you hack back or counter-attack
I guess the machine that could be a
zombie as part of something else you can
be careful in that area but you have to
question this hurt
sure we wanted to do that
I at the previous organization we have
that where I'm at now
so a lot of those engagements tend to be
a bit more hours Bob you know the more
you know type of slide where these guys
are the ones testing the tools and
seeing how the tax work and then working
with us to figure out how we could
attack what rules we could write so
there's a better relationship there then
and
it's a good idea to have adversarial in
that kind of a situation as well
they're going to do their things and
announced and i'll be detected and what
do we do once we detected right so yeah
it was
there's a lot more variety you can do
that when you've got a good team
internally
yeah absolutely
and there's a lot of great benefit that
can be had from having internal energy
use and i don't mean this to be
disparaging too much to the red teamers
because the external penetration testing
is very positive in a very important
thing to have on your network but don't
I get tired of the presentations where
I've totally pulling the blue team and
all my gosh these guys are are are
stupid they're idiots they don't know
what they're doing and whatever else it
is right because we've got a lot going
on
we've got a lot of logs to dig through
and we don't have to be right a hundred
percent of time we can detect these guys
being foolish as well
so with that I think I'll clear the
stage for the next guy
thank you very much