Robert over from to get food and water
to him
okay okay well thanks everyone so today
we're going to talk about threat
modeling which is actually one of my
passions in particular what I do is as
was mentioned there i'm an independent
software security consultant
I'm an architect of a trainer I've been
doing development of some sort for now
almost 30 years which is crazy because
thinking back right out of high school
and so forth to do a lot of this stuff
development architecture project
management leading developers mentoring
developers all that kind of stuff about
12 years ago I started looking more and
more security
now that was a time when it wasn't as
popular it wasn't seen as much you don't
talk about it as much but what I found
was that we need to think about it we
need to talk about it and so as I've
done along one of the things i also
learned way back when was how to do
threat modeling and then again that was
a thing that just Microsoft and others
we are talking about
and the last few years it seems like
it's coming back into play again because
it didn't hear about it for a while but
now it's starting to come back into play
and just had a curiosity
whatever
the car
client directly into your database right
that's how you fix it but it's still a
design issue it's still something built
in an incident is still in there today
you have to be aware of it and
understand your tools and understand how
do I build around that in a secure way
another issue that's come up in the the
news
we've seen is the jeep cherokee hack
everybody heard about that one right
you know they say that what is it three
and three out of four Americans have now
forgotten about this but four out of
four carmaker certainly have not right
this is still a big deal and we still
hear about it sometimes in the news -
about different issues with cars and and
now you know being the fact that they're
all software
what happened here was it last year if
you remember of crystal second and
Charlie Miller presented at blackhat
where they were able to find a flaw in
the design where it's jeep cherokee in
the entertainment system that you could
subscribe to that allows you to to be
able to say watch movies in the system
it turned out that you also not only had
access to the internet and maybe cool
things down but you also have an IP
address and so what was your able to do
is somebody could come in and find you
through that IP address
make your way through the entertainment
system into the rest of the car and take
over certain operations
now you say well you like the window
window wife Susan's wipers weather and
so forth but you could also take control
the brakes you can take control of the
car in terms of moving it and that's
what they did in that and their demo
which was you know amazing things so
again a design flaw
who had the idea that it was okay to
make this available so that somebody can
take over a bus that perhaps we could do
harm to people
another one not software specifically
it's more of a system design but the
target breach was something also in the
news in the last few years
again a design flaw design issue where
we had network access given to a third
party company in this particular case it
was an HVAC company being able to come
in directly go to the system to the
network
no segmentation involved and so by
attackers going through the HVAC and
basically having full access to
everything
of course they also had full access to
the point of sale systems and you know
there's some issue there and so on and
so on i mean we can talk all day about
this but again at a design issue in this
case a system design issue
so this is where it matters thinking
through these things matters and where
you make those decisions where you make
choices about how you build out system
really matters and so I talking about
that well how do we solve that and
that's what we're going to talk about
the day is essentially taking a look at
threat modeling and how it can help you
with secure software design in
particular
so we're threat modeling will to me it's
something we already do it our personal
lives you know when we lock the doors to
our house when we know lock the windows
and when we lock the doors to our car
we're already thinking ahead about what
could go wrong where essentially you
know we don't leave those things open
because why
well you know more than likely or
possibly somebody's going to come in to
my home
take something if I leave things in my
car just out in the open somebody will
come by and see it or if i leave the
door to door unlocked or window open
somebody might take it so we're already
thinking about these things in our
personal lives we may not realize that
we may not necessarily put a name to it
but it is a kind of threat modeling in
the sense that we're thinking about what
can go wrong we weigh the risks and act
accordingly
well actually what we want to do is try
to apply some of those same thoughts to
how we design software how we design
systems we want to think about and think
ahead
what could happen here i think the
number one question I here and and one
of the things that I do in my own work
in consulting is I help customers think
about these things and in particular one
of the questions that I here often
is when we talk about user interactions
so forth is well why would a user do
that you've heard that before but why
would anyone do that but that's the
point they would and they may and so
then you have to think about it so just
talk really quickly about what are the
things that that money can help you do
to me it are it helps you breathe some
gas for example between the builders the
breakers the defenders it helps the
builders focus on the security features
you know the developers the people who
are putting together secure systems
it helps the breakers know where the
critical attack surfaces are so the
people that are doing the the pen
testing the penetration testing it can
help them understand you know they don't
have unlimited time but if they spend
some time to think about the design to
think about the actual threats to the
system that can help them in locating or
localizing their attacks for breaking
into the system and the defenders it
also helps them understand the patterns
you know what is it that you know
attackers may be looking at our system
understanding the threat model of the
system can help you do that as well and
I think it
it's in many ways it helps security and
business understand each other because
threat modeling is actually ultimately a
business decision as well
what are the threats and how does that
impact my business and how I build my
system
so where does it fit it's one of the
security tools we already know about
these penetration testing buzzing all
those a lot of automated tools threat
welding on the other hand is really a
process
it's a way of thinking and if you've
been in security for a while
again we talked about you know some
things you already think about you don't
go anywhere
probably anymore and and see things the
same way right once you start thinking
about security
you see an open door you say well you
know what if somebody came in that way
or I see an open port on a device and
you think you know what if somebody
decided to plug into that you can see
what's happening with the protocol
that's coming across
so it's a way of thinking and ultimately
as will take a look at it's a tool
that's useful for secure design
so here's the official an official
definition it's a process of
understanding your system and the
potential threats against her system and
I like to think of you know when I'm
creating a threat model I want to have
these particular elements as a part of
it so and understanding or a diagram of
my system what is it on building
what is it that we're trying to to build
here in our system whether it be a
software or an infrastructure anything
identify threats
you know what are people wanting to do
or could do in the system and any
mitigation so as we go through what
we'll find is requirements will say okay
we have a threat here
has anybody done anything about this how
do we counter it
so those are your mitigations and then
priorities by risk and I think this is
really important because sometimes if
you find all kinds of problems in your
system for example people will chase
vulnerabilities like crazy i've got 520
boner abilities
okay what are you gonna do with that you
can't fix them all at 11 time and so
threat modeling another aspect of threat
modeling is risk management where you're
trying to understand okay now I know
this about my system
let's prioritize it figure out what's
the most critical thing and fix it
accordingly by priority
so those are things that I think
essentially come together with the
threat model a couple of coats I have
this is from Michael Howard it at
Microsoft the road secure code to dev
team with awesome complete accurate
threat model gets my operation and not
much of my time because essentially they
don't need it and i found that as well
as myself in my own experience that
companies who are starting out with
threat modeling thinking about that in
their design thinking about that in the
requirements are already ahead of the
game
another quote by brookstone field he
wrote a great book that came out last
summer on threat modeling and on secure
architecture as I practice it threat
modeling cannot be the province of a
tech lead but instead its best own way
all the development team and and what I
take from that and and I like that idea
as well is it's not just the security
people that you want to be threat
modeling
you don't want to just say okay you go
to the threat modeling and come back
with what you find
but instead my approach and and Brooke
as well is that we want to try to get
everybody involved
everybody thinking about threat modeling
and everybody can contribute to the
design of systems
so talk about some definitions of a
threat agent is essentially someone or a
process that wants to do harm to your
system so that can be an attacker
it could be again a process that is
running on your system
the threat is the goal it's what the
adversary wants to do
for example I a threat maybe that an
adversary wants to take your credit card
information
that's the fret how would they do it
well it turns out the way they do it is
typically for vulnerability and there's
a distinction between these two a
vulnerability is the flaw in the system
that helps the thread agent realize the
threat
so for example if i have a website and I
perhaps have a sequel injection
vulnerability
well because of the presence of the
vulnerability the sequel injection an
attacker could then realize the threat
of obtaining off my credit card
information or change in my database or
dropping my database or tables and so on
so on and so on but with out the
vulnerability
without the sequel injection being there
then really i don't have that threat
so there is a distinction some people
try to use them interchangeably but
they're not the same
at least I don't see the same and many
others do not as well there is a
distinction so the vulnerability helps
make the threat realized but understand
that the threat itself is something that
you could happen as a result of the
vulnerability being there
the attack is essentially the thread
agent taking advantage of that
vulnerability and there are a couple of
things here that i like to point out
usually it is related to a motivated and
sufficiently skilled threat agent so
motivations can change or or vary
depending on who's doing this so for
example years ago there used to be where
we are called get the script kiddies
so usually like teenagers and say hey I
got us I got some kind of script i'm
going to throw it
this website see what happens do I know
what it does
absolutely not I don't care it's just
fun i want to face it or something and
all the way up to a motivation of a of a
criminal of a state-sponsored attack
where you know they want to ultimately
typically is money
personal information other kinds of
things that order to ultimately obtain
money that's typically what the state of
Texas doing or subvert nation-states
sufficiently skilled i already talked
about the script kitty who may not know
what he's doing all the way up to the
nation-state attacker who is absolutely
skilled and they don't know if you've
seen it but there are criminal
organizations that basically have a
DevOps and they have check-ins and they
have project managers and they have all
that kind of stuff
just like in your own organizations
mainly because it is if it's something
that they are serious about and they
need to spend time on and and focus on
so you have all kinds of these people
but ultimately various motivations
various skills
the thread agent taking advantage of
that vulnerability produce the attack
assets something of value could be your
credit card information can be other
kinds of things that it varies but but
the key is and I know in some for
example the fair approach will say an
asset is anything that you don't you'll
lose money on you know basically I I
it's a loss of some sort
this is a threat modeling vocabulary
this is this is a nice graphic by john
stevens digital and these slides will be
available afterwards if you want to you
know follow my Twitter my foot
sorry follow my twitter all i'll post a
link to it but this is where he is
relating all the threats the attacks the
risk and everything and how they they
work together all those terms
so that's a that's a really nice slide a
document are sorry of a visual talking
about poses a threat on there are many
different ways to do this
my particular approach is typically
software centric and that's what we're
talking about the day
that's where I focus on secure design
look at the data flow diagrams
another one is more asset centric where
you may use attack trees essentially
work flows through your system
so for example if I've got a website and
i want to be able to exploit an xss
vulnerability
how were the one of the ways that i may
be able to use excess in order to do
something for example the threat maybe I
want to grab your session cookie
and how do i do that so that may be an
attack flow that you might go through
and then you would at each point
determined that you have the right
mitigation in place to prevent that
so that's one way to do that another is
attacker centric and that was what i was
talking about a moment ago where you're
focusing on the profile
you're focusing on the various patterns
so for example as i mentioned the script
kiddie will do one thing very different
than a nation-state hacker
perhaps in attacking your system
the the bottom two there a lot of times
we'll apply more to network or
infrastructure but the way I see it is
you know when you're doing threat
modeling a lot of these things you can
think about
depending on your system and and what
makes sense
so when you do threat modeling well
ideally its first
you do it first so i typically we should
come in the requirements and design
phase so I have their in this diagram
threat modeling as part of your design
and could also become part of your
requirements and actually threat
modeling will also uncover new
requirements as you go through the
process you will typically find
oh there's something else for missing we
need to put that in place if you are you
following the more of an agile
methodology
you can make it a part of your sprint so
there you can see we're in the story
you're building out your story you
define what's our threat model or as
you're iterating through
yo various Sprint's you might you put in
there and say okay here's a new feature
what's our threat model its associated
with it
so along with that you can come up with
user stories and attacker stories as
well so if you never did threat modeling
and I remember earlier I asked you if
you've done threat modeling are you
currently doing crap modeling but the
reality is it's not too late to start
for the most part just realize that it
will be more difficult to change major
design decisions later I mean if you
already
you know picked let's say haha
you know if you if you pick some
framework that is inherently not secure
and then decide okay now we need to be
secure than you know revamping the
entire thing is going to be a lot of
effort so you want to do these things
ideally of front early but i'd say do it
anyway
go through the process go through the
the stages of trying to figure out where
are you in your system
how secure are you still do it
so let's talk about a typical threat
modeling session and what i described
this what I'm talking about is let's say
that you've never done threat modeling
before you're looking at your system you
want to go through and try to figure out
how you know where are we
here are some things that I found to be
very useful to get started so first
thing is you want to gather
documentation
you know who built the system when was
it built
what was the purpose why do we do what
we did and you know that can also apply
to some new things but especially for
for things that are existing gather your
team again don't make this one person's
job have lots of people involved if you
can developers QA architects project
managers stakeholders people who have an
investment into this system in making a
secure making it a productive making it
will generate revenue I mean those
people count because all of this stuff
ultimately can affect your bottom line
understand the business goals and the
technical goals and sometimes you know
they may not necessarily match what your
security goals are for example i worked
with a client where we talked about
putting two factor authentication in
place and their goal was yes we want to
do that but not for everybody we have
some users we don't and some
administrators we do for now
and you know my recommendations we need
to across the board
I said no that's not our goal right now
so you have to be aware of what your
goals are and why you do what you do
the other thing about this is also
understand your technical goals know for
example why did you choose job as your
framework
why did you choose . net why did you
choose that open source library why did
you know those are important things
because all of those things can impact
the security design of your system based
on on those things that you
you chose
meeting dates and times agree on those
and then I like to say I only said one
to two hours
focus session don't make this a whole
day thing and the reason is because
ultimately it becomes almost a code
review and it's not a code review we're
not talking about looking at your code
and getting that far down we're talking
more of a high level view about the
architecture and the various data flows
and things like that so make it very
focused on understanding where the
security issues in the system and then
most important and this I've learned
through trial and error working with
teams is be honest ligo the door and no
blaming it's so easy to when you're
looking at security and especially in a
system that's already been built and
you're missing things is to say oh what
did we did that you know who didn't do
this
oh and then to find out you know as an
architect well i know we set up our
authentication process this way and the
developer comes back and says well
actually no we didn't we
you know look in depth different half
that day because it wasn't too difficult
or whatever and you find out those
things
the key is you know this is discovery
its understanding so try to leave those
things aside you again be honestly we go
the door no blaming some simple tools
that you can use a whiteboard just to
draw your your application your system
you can use visio for the diagramming
you know word or excel to document one
thing i like is Dennis Cruz simple
threat model one page template and
concepts you've been working on this a
little while
that's a link to it but essentially it
looks like this
these the latest i think in about a
month ago or so I pull this off his
sight but essentially it's a page where
he's trying to keep track of your
diagram various entry points assets and
threats in this case based on strike
just to keep track of you know what is
it your system on the back he has these
concepts so
what is stride with you know the
vocabulary and so on so that's something
that he puts together I think it's
pretty cool
what i like to use this worksheet which
is just keeping track of the risk level
with Brett's description countermeasures
and so on and then of course the
follow-up which we'll talk about later
as well so simple tools keep it simple
there are some other tools out there but
don't look at these until you understand
the process because if you jump into
these as I said there's no automated
tool out there at all you can't just say
you know . to my system and build one
it doesn't work that way you have to
think through
ok how's this built one of the things
that are moving between the various
pieces and then the potential security
issues that might be represented
once you understand the process and some
of these tools may come in handy
lately I've been evaluating friend
mother it's a very interesting web-based
collaborative tool from my app security
at you know take a look at that one
the free one from Microsoft is pretty
good but it has some limitations
it's a free tool but you know in terms
of upgrades and so forth not sure
and then there are a few other options
there as well but and I'm sure there's
some others out there but the key is be
familiar with the process for start
simple because it is a thinking tool
first and foremost so as you start to to
get into doing the threat modeling
session itself
one of things I like to do is review
security principles the basic security
principles for example securing the
weakest link the pen in depth of feeling
security economize mechanisms simply
simply keep it simple
these privileged not sharing mechanisms
for example don't make authentication be
your authorization to don't make
authorization work like your
authentication that's very key be
reluctant to trust promote privacy
security usable we talked about that
earlier
so there's a lot of things that we go
over it would go over what great
document to take a look at if you
haven't already is this one from the
Tripoli computer side society center
/ secure design they wrote this for a
couple years ago a bunch of companies
got together and wrote these top 10
software security design flaws and
essentially what they were trying to
talk about is you know what is the
difference between a bug and flawed and
a bug is essentially an implementation
level software problem
someone forgot something someone missed
something or they miss type something
and now you have a bug in the system
very different than a flaw a flawed on
the other hand is where we made a
mistake in the way we made a decision so
for example a bug is that I I didn't
quite I didn't put the right
I didn't put the right number of
characters and password let's say the
flaw is I've made the wrong decision
about how i'm storing that password for
example shot one don't you shot one
that's it that's a design decision that
you've made that now is the flaw that
perhaps could be exploited
so that's very key out of that document
you'll find there's there's ten
different things that they they have
described as flaws
cryptography comes up all the time you
know they always say don't roll your own
that's obviously a big flaw but for
example one of the things is yet
neglecting to authorize after
authentication
some people say well you know I'm
pathetic ated and then we move forward
without doing the access control so some
very key things and then of course the
recommendations are just the opposite of
that
you know earn or give never assume trust
always use cryptography correctly and so
on and so on so these are things that
you want to you want to review with your
team and make sure everybody understands
the difference between what's a bug and
what's the flaw
now that everybody has you know that
basic foundation then let's talk about
the actual threat modeling process
itself
so this is what I've come up with and
others have come up with maybe five six
of these seven of these I've tried to
pull it down into 24 and even in this
there's
you know some some stuff that that comes
out of this but I'm trying to make it as
simple as possible
first thing is draw your picture
understand your system and the data
flows that that go between your parts of
your system identified the threats
determine the mitigations and risks and
finally which i think is one of the most
important things that the follow-through
don't just make that and exercise that
you know hey we did it
great let's move on but something that
that you continue to revisit so drawing
your picture
let me just ask you anybody have an idea
what that is
make a guess
anybody so whatever it is we'll head
back and you've probably seen this
before right
free to your web app we got a browser we
got a web server we got a database
server but when you look at this just
drawing this out
you don't really know a whole lot about
it right you don't know exactly what's
going on you especially don't know
what's going on inside the web server so
this is this is a start but it's not
enough
what you want to do is you want to get a
little further into the processes that
are happening inside that web server and
so a good way to do that is to use and
this is an example of using data flow
diagrams now you can draw a pretty much
anything and no make sure you want this
is just a recommendation or you know a
lot of people do this and threat
modeling but to represent these various
parts of your system to enter these the
processes the data stores and Trust
boundaries boundaries is kind of an
interesting thing because that's where
you're going from ok I'm not
authenticated and now i am or I'm not
authorized and now i am and that can be
really key about well what do those mean
in my system essentially so what we're
going to do is understand the logical
and the component architecture of our
system and the communication flow and
valuable data moved and stored and the
reason why we do that is it turns out
that when data is moving back and forth
let's say I
- two things that never talk to each
other not so interesting
if the database is over here by itself
and nothing ever touches it ever
it's it's it's not very interesting but
when the data starts flowing whether
it's a network connection of some sort
holding back the data storing the data
it turns out that that app that
connection
how the data is moving back and forth or
between components and then getting the
database and so on is much more
interesting to an attacker because
that's where you particularly in could
be most vulnerable and so that's what we
want to know how the data moving where
is it moving - and and how's it being
authenticated and authorized and so on
so for example just to start off with we
might look here at building out
ok users and admin hitting a server to
into these are two users and the kinds
of of data that are sending back and
forth which quest responses
you know perhaps the admin is is setting
up some things on the server and the
admin is reading in logging data and
there's a boundary between those users
and the server we're outside i don't
have the right
authentication authorization and inside
my request is now authorized it can do
you know what it needs to do
going a little further into the system
that would be what I would call a
level-one a diagram this is more like a
level one after level 0 this level one
where I'm a you know the finding a few
more things in my system
so here I am I'm again documenting the
data flows
I have the users in the am unix admin
again I have the web app and I have some
services authentication service audit
service
I have some files data files credentials
i also have this management tool and
then I want to define some kind of trust
boundary where the users are able to go
from let's say from outside inside and
or maybe around that user and everything
around that user is is either not
trusted and now trusted
so you can find some of those things and
as you do that
you're you're one to document what you
find
and so you know where my users why it my
you know the entities that I i
determined my processes very services
the data stores the data flows how does
data flow and so what I would typically
do is try to have a diagram that matches
you know what my system looks like at a
high level view and then try to
understand okay you know what comes here
what we're going to be using here and
ask some questions
so for example in the request to the web
app
what are we using are we using HTTPS are
we using HTTPS inside the system
anywhere
you know I see a lot of companies that
don't do that you know they they do a
very good job of guarding the outside
but on the inside you notice that candy
bar the the crunchy outside and the
Chilean tonight
never seen that before now so those are
good questions to ask you know what are
we doing we're sending those requests
how are we are dedicating you know what
kind of what kind of mechanism what kind
of protocol were using so those are
questions that you would ask about your
system from a security perspective of
how this is working
so once you've done that go through that
through that exercise you now have a
diagram and understanding of your system
so let's talk about identifying the
threats which of course as you can
imagine and threat modeling that's the
most important part
what we're doing there you know there's
a few ways you can use the attack trees
we already talked about that you can use
some some libraries that kind of help
you think about the kinds of it attacks
that are well-known a peck a loss top 10
you can use checklist a loss has a
couple of really good ones
a SBS and the proactive controls where
basically they say okay here are the
things that we know or or questions that
you can ask your system
have we done this have we done that you
know and so on you can use use cases or
misuse cases those are great because so
many times we build systems we think
about well how does this work from use
case you know the workflow
we don't always think about the misuse
case and again remember I asked that
question why would he use ever
do that well that's a misuse case and so
it's good to think about those there is
a there's a couple games out there that
kind of help you through those things
this is from 0 wasp this cornucopia game
where they have various areas
optimization session management and so
on
where you basically play a hand around
rather and let's say I've got two of
cryptography and you have something to
read
say well does this apply to my system
yes or no
and at the bottom of a card it will tell
you well this is found in a lost top 10
this is found in the mcat back to the
founding whatever and so it's a way of
helping your team understand about
threats as a way of understanding about
some of the the top types of things that
are out there in a system
another way to think about threats or or
to find threats and this is probably the
most well-known or threat modeling is to
use stride stride is a and it's
essentially it's not categories it's a
mnemonic
so they're not a bunch of spoofing type
it is basically helping you understand
well here's a kind of of a way of a
threat in your system
spoofing is you know pretend to be whom
you're not tampering is changing the
data repudiation is saying hey I did
something or you can't prove that I did
something information disclosure
you know making you know some sensitive
data available in all of service of
course means I can't you know user your
application your service and elevation
of privilege
the most dangerous we're basically if
I'm a user and I have the ability to get
into your system and subvert it without
you know authorizing properly or access
control
you know I can be an admin without
having to go through the process of
being an admin you know elevation of
privilege the way to counter those in
authentication integrity non-repudiation
which usually is through logging you
know some kind of monitoring logging to
verify that you know users are doing
what you think they're doing
confidentiality availability and
authorization or access control
so this is a way it again a way of
finding threats and it's a it's a very
easy and simple way and a lot of people
start there
I think it applies really best to data
flows but that's not all that you have
maybe in your system so there are some
other things to think about will talk
about the moment there's also this game
elevation of privilege game which
basically another game that kind of
helps you think about threat modeling
using stride
pasta is another method which uses
stride attacks and also uses risk
analysis part of pasta is that they may
include the actual simulated attack as
part of the threat model
what I like to do is also look at the
functional areas and ask questions
accordingly so I asked questions about
configuration management sensitive data
cryptography and and so on and so on
those kinds of questions I might ask is
you know who would be interested in this
application its data who are the threat
agents where the goals the assets where
the methods that they're using
are there any attack services exposed
you know what are we missing
how the authentication handled you know
and and when we say okay we've got a
vindication a specifically what kind of
authentication
what are you using for authentication
what are you using for access control
so it's not enough to just say you know
you know where we got a password
yeah well okay how's the password store
how does it retrieve how that you know
those are kinds of questions you need to
ask about the system we sending data to
the open and so on
I'll one of the best questions i found
very effective anything giving you up at
night
is there anything in this system that
you built that you would rather nobody
ever know or you forgot about it still
out there and you know I better go and
fix it
so that's a great one task as well so
flipping through here i want to take a
look at a scenario configuration
management back into our web diagram
here if I narrowed it down to where
would I find configuration management
problems
i'm looking here
our data file such a configuration files
for web
well what's a problem with that well it
turns out that the reality is in that
system we have files its input into our
system has anybody ever thought about
you know what if somebody change the URL
in that configuration file what would
happen
what if somebody was able to get it my
configuration file with the connection
string to a database and change that to
another database what would happen
so some of the security principles to be
aware of be reluctant to trust and
assume that secrets are not safe knowing
that we can then ask the questions you
know how does this app users
configuration files
is there any kind of validation on the
data in those configuration files or
it's just an implied trust and we are
jumping ahead of it but some of the
possible controls and mitigation are you
know set permissions on those files
don't just let anybody read those are
right to them but make sure that the
process that's reading and writing those
configuration files has you know the
right tackles imply applied
another thing is you know validate the
data that's coming from those files use
testing but testing to ensure input
validation so those are some things that
you might find as a result of doing a
threat model against your configuration
management
so here we have some threats that have
been identified
let's talk about the mitigations and the
wrist so there are a few options that
you have once you identify some threats
one is it just simply leave it as is
if you find that you have you know let's
say a sequel injection problem now
hopefully you don't leave it but you
could you could say you know I want to
fix it later or have other things that
I've found I want to leave it as is
we already know it's there it's low risk
perhaps
let's leave it you can remove it from
the product
ideally you can remedy it with a
technology countermeasure the other is
that you can also warn the user now this
is where you see the CSL a CL C essays
and support where or agreements that we
all you know come up and say you agree
to this and you scroll through and read
it like everybody does and click OK that
may say you know there are certain risks
if you run this application so that
so the question is you know what's the
risk associated with things that we find
and that's where risk management comes
in you can apply the fair approach which
is a very drawn-out process you can use
what i like is just that a high medium
low which is essentially applying two
factors ease of expectation and business
impact so he's of expectation is you
know how how easy is it for someone to
be able to exploit our system so if an
office users can exploit it
more than likely this is a high-risk if
someone has to know it very well and are
strong programming skills then maybe
your risk rating is low if you're at the
other good business impact if all users
impacted that's high at a low number
low and then you combine those together
and now you have let's say for example a
medium risk threat this is on related to
csrf back to our configuration
management
you know if we own the box perhaps
medium if we're on the cloud
hi and the reason for that is maybe
because we don't own it and so on
so following up a document what you
found
file bugs verify bugs
if we missed anything review it again if
there's anything new review it again
and so then what you have ultimately is
a living threat model a living threat
model
so what a finishing up here secure
design before new features
drive your testing and other review
activities and understand the bigger
picture
I have some resources here a lot of
great books again I'll make these slides
available so you'll get these links and
so on
and now we come to questions and I just
want to zip through because i'm i'm
running out of time but I want to leave
some time for questions so many
questions on that whole process we've
got about 5 10 minutes there
good question so as I mentioned and a
brook points out that the developers
should do that and I've had questions
about that myself and you know I think
it depends on the organization
if you've never done this before the
more than likely the security group is
going to be the ones who started in and
start driving it and bringing into the
organization but ultimately I think what
you want to try to do is get each of the
groups start to own some of this
so you know one way that I've seen and
what I'm actually working with a client
right now where they're starting from
the security group and they're trying to
help different teams get the skills and
the training they need to do threat
modeling so that more or less a a way of
duplicating the effort so that not just
one person does this but several do that
and so that you know the small things
like for example there's just some
things that you should have in your
application regardless right
I should have proper authentication I
have I should have proper authorization
those are things that should already be
done before it ever gets to a group to
say let's ask those questions
so try to move that down into the basic
questions can we get those answered and
then the bigger design questions
continue to move forward up so I i think
the answer your question I think
ultimately you want
a lot of different groups own their own
threat model but it may start at the
security group and the security team to
start you know showing hey this is what
we're doing and why and what it helps
you do and ultimately it's helping you
design better and secure code in and
secure systems
good question anybody else those of you
mentioned that you've done some trap
money what are you using any of the
tools out of curiosity
microsoft too late buddy
okay so yeah anyway
other questions yes
sure sure
so the question is how do we go where do
you define and how do you define trust
boundaries and that's a good question
because that can depend on the a lot of
things about your company and about your
application and what you're what i see
it is again
typically the first place i started
where do we move from not being a
dedicated to being authenticated where
do we go from not being authorized now
being authorized but that can also vary
depending on the process it can depend
on the user
so you know that's where you have to and
also in my internal and external am I
you know all those kinds of things may
vary but that's my cum my rule of thumb
where I start
where am i changing the state's it's
more like a state issue where my
changing my state of security being
authorizer authenticated
I'm sorry I can get authorized and then
moving from there
specifically how I start trying to
understand trust boundaries
you think you can be used for him . or
it can be processes and the reason I say
that is because you want to be very
careful I don't know if you interview
guys are doing microservices these days
which is the rage
be careful about them because there's
have you heard of the confused deputy
problem is that familiar everybody heard
of that essentially i have let's say i
have two or three microservices and I i
have a workflow so one calls this one
which calls the third one but what
happens if I am somebody else who calls
the second one but i don't have the
right
authorization do it but I'm not checking
it because simply i know that if i call
this one and bypass this first one I'll
get it to do the things i want and that
second one microservice may not know and
not realize who's calling it all it
knows is
I call this third thing which isn't in
it which is a privilege operation but
because i'm not doing the correct
checking
I don't know if it's this one calling me
or this one calling me but I want to do
the right thing which is called the
privilege microservice so the confused
deputy problem is that second one is
going to do what it thinks is right
thing but if I don't have the correct
trust boundaries to find the correct
authorization in place to do the right
thing the next thing that calls then you
know I potentially have just introduced
a security issue in my system not
understanding the importance of you know
all the way through not just users but
all the way through microservices
calling other microservices it really
matters how the secure design is in
place
does that make sense yeah well and I see
that I mean that's a pic the common
thing I keep saying with microservices
with when I get called in somebody
talked about API design
nobody's thinking about that enough yet
I think ok any other questions
ok right thank you