so little bit of history and background
myself and Ava author the social
engineer toolkits and and then a lot of
stuff after my career but what's
interesting in the reason why i like
this talk so much is that you know I my
whole career has been primarily focused
on offensive and you know kind of
growing up as a kid I suppose you know
early on in my career you know breaking
stuff was always the best thing for me
always win the company's I smash them
you know God domain admin stole their
intellectual properties to all the
credit card data and I walked out
high-fiving thinking I was the greatest
that you know thing ever
and when I started to realize you know I
guess I got a little bit older is that
you no offense and defense very much
work together and some of the things
that i'll be showing you today are
things that I learned offensively by
going through and looking at what i do
is an attacker and figure out how do I
stop myself and so a lot of these
patterns i'm gonna show you the reasons
why we're getting breached inhale my
guys here is this is not a clown this
time it wasn't planning to do
I've seen pictures of where this is it
Ben and i'm scared i'm terrified factory
care of high did I got iced teas you see
this
I they got a whole 88 leader of or 8
fluid ounces of ice and how it goes
around come from talking to a time right
that pepsi so terrible
thanks Jason Jason Street everybody and
aquatech time that was awkward that
dinosaur whatever the heck that was
better anyways so doing a lot of the
stuff offensively i'm getting a good
mind defense will be what i need to do
so i'm gonna show you today is a lot of
what we see as far as breaches occur the
same techniques that I use to attack
organizations go after them everything
from you know targeted attacks to
fishing
what are the indicators of compromises
that we typically look at me look at the
industry today I think what we really
focus on is a lot of the the noise so we
look at commoditized things like malware
you know ransomware things like that
which are still things that we need to
protect against but if you look at what
actually causes a lot of implications
are most damage it's the attacks that
typically go on so i'll be talking a lot
about that today and how to best defense
against you know essentially me also a
little history of i started to companies
so trusted sec is a security consulting
company out of cleveland ohio and i have
a lot of great folks that work there and
also start another company called binary
defense which is a 24-7 security
operations center and we also have a
tool that looks for attacks and things
like that so a little bit the intro here
and I be if I start mumbling a little
bit because the past two days I've got a
combined total amount of hours of two
hours of sleep so I'm running on
caffeine and now diet pepsi and smirnoff
ice which I don't know if that's think
it's bad
we'll see we'll see how it plays out but
a brief intro you know a lot of what I
talked about on the defensive side you
know I get to work with a lot of
different companies in different
organizations and see what they have in
place I get that you know test a lot of
different tools and technology and
products I get to look at different
things that are coming out that the new
next-generation stuff for the new
artificial intelligence that's going to
stop you know all hackers in their
tracks
I get to play with all those different
tools and techniques to see you know
what does it do what is it good and what
is not good at and ultimately you know
looking at this from a large corporation
perspective is enlarged everything i'm
going to talk to is going to be
applicable to kind of all different
sizes of businesses but it's also
something that we all share consistently
consistently and that's really the lack
of detection we put all of our baskets
in our perimeter defenses and a little
bit into our actual detection on end .
and then from there we have these big
seems that you know conglomerate all of
our data into central information is so
much data we don't we're doing with
and so we start to build a little bit of
rules around things and hopefully we're
staying ahead of the game when it comes
to what we're actually seeing out there
but in most cases when if I can
compromise the machine
let's just say through fishing and I
compromise that end user and moved to
different systems in your environment
and most of the time that stage right
there to the stage they get access to
systems that need go undetected and so
what I'm going to talk about today is is
those steps there and how do you
actually go about looking for those
patterns environments to actually going
to stop it
most if not all attacks are detectable
something you can detect and why I say
that is we as attackers try to emulate
legitimate traffic we use PowerShell we
use you know Cee scripted w script to
run the author to your wretched s430 to
use methods that might are built into
Microsoft we try to emulate legitimate
traffic i mean all of our shells are
based off of RFC compliant traffic we
use HTTPS and HTTP protocols in order to
communicate in and out there are a lot
of times our proxy where the type of
things that we do are very atypical
environments so if I you know bobbin
sales as bobbin sales ever talk to Mary
over 90 sure those machines ever be
touching in any way shape or form of
communicating and in one anyway should
performer
first of all should you have your entire
network allowed to communicate the rest
of the network in the first place but
look we'll get there someday perhaps
something but are those normal behaviour
in your environment is you know Bob and
sales is he ever been a dbo in a sequel
server a simple administrator in any
other way shape or form in your
environment before
no those are very atypical patterns here
in your organization you don't
traditionally see now the problem is
there's a lot of patterns that we use
attackers and finding all of them is
very difficult however there are things
that we do all the time that are the
same lateral movement is the same
techniques of getting two lateral
movement different so for example let's
just take it local hash on a box and
there's a local admits the same local
and another box
I'm gonna move that one system to the
next and the next until I get access to
the admin it has access to the server
then out there
but that might not be every single time
I might find you no are you no I might
see Group Policy preferences and use
that or i might try to go attack a
different system and move from that and
then go to different system but I'm
still going to move from system to
system that's not typical behavior until
I get access to a domain controller or
something that I had elevated
credentials with the kerberos token or
something like that and i can use that
to expand the rest of the network that's
atypical behavior is not something
that's normal in your environment is
gonna be very different and unique that
isn't going to be the same unless I
pappadeaux made a man like if your head
if you have your helpdesk it's running
as a domain admin on internet explorer
you deserve everything that you get we
fish somebody like two weeks ago that
was the case and I was like seriously
easiest test ever i'm like you just you
just write the check now it's done it's
over with you know but it's getting
really do it so attacker behaviour
abnormal and so we have to look for on
the defensive side and by the way i want
to give a round of applause for the
folks aren't even rated for the
defensive side give you the round of
applause because you're working much
more army hours and i am so defense has
the hardest job in the world you have to
go to meetings you have to go to change
control what you know our meetings you
have to go to other meetings and on top
of you have to defend the entire company
and hopefully you don't have one fall
allows an attacker you have a stupid
you're not stupid user using are stupid
they just don't know what the deuce
right i take that back was an accident
slip them on user click on things and
all the sudden now you're supposed to be
the one that's guarding the entire
organization right and so you have a lot
of things to deal with
now there's an interesting in Egypt in
Jeremiah talked about a while back and I
like this one because you know Jeremiah
was saying it said an adversary just
needs to find one vulnerability to win
to do that they need to find just one
system the target they didn't know they
own the system that you forgot about
that windows XP box that 2003 machine
that's out there or that apache tomcat
that installs because one of your
developers was putting up in a weird
version of xampp or something and you
haven't you know the fitness system that
you didn't know existed all those
vulnerabilities right in Egypt had a
good . and i completely agree with this
and this is where we need to be on the
blue team which is counter . once you're
on a system the adversary Rolf lips blue
only need to find one indicator of
compromise the cast already know that
something was wrong
and so as defenders we need to look at
that and say well can we put pieces of
technology or detection capabilities are
ways of getting ideas into what abnormal
behavior looks like this start to detect
these things because i only have to see
you once if you're moving from system to
system i see that one time you got
access to marry and it's-- box then I
can shut you down you make it in another
way but hopefully I got detection that
way as well so we have to get better at
detection on the blue so talk a little
bit understanding attack patterns now
one big disadvantage that the blue team
typically has you don't understand
boss's office and by the way I'm
understand also that you folks do a
defense as well so there's just two
separate industries in the security
industry right we have the offensive the
defense they shouldn't be separately
should be very much like this right we
should learn from one another and that's
what we call purple teams looking at
purple teams a combination of
understanding office and defense I'm a
huge advocate of this out when I sit
down with the blue team and Mikey I'm
doing this exploit right here and doing
this attacker you see it no no but but i
think i can see over here let's figure
that out then boo now they got a
detection capability
okay wanna try to circumvent that doing
this well hey I think I context you
doing this is back and forth working
together understanding what we're
actually doing
it's a much more beneficial role in fact
honestly I think as as a industry we
should probably kill just the normal
pentest i'm probably boot for that and a
bunch of pentesting really ticking me
but honestly we're past the point now
where we're doing the covert assessments
where you're going to try to have your
blue team attack this because every
single time we get in every single time
we break in every single time we still
every day and then you guys feel
horrible afterwards because we just
owned everything so I I pitch more so
the purple team approach and everything
and understanding of everything that's
happening out there but understanding
these attacks
let's look at some stats from just are
companies that we see eighty percent a
compliment or a hundred percent of of
what we evaluate a two percent of that
were due to a breaches reduce and .
compromises eighty-two percent
your highest probability of risk . is
going to be the end users everybody
agree with that everybody's again we all
we've all had a deal with ransomware and
everybody's machine or you know going to
machine that got infected with a fake
one or even the ads now the ads are
getting good look at your machine has
been infected and you got grandma
calling you like I'm infected with
ransomware grandma is just an ad don't
worry you're fine just hit X ok cool and
wasn't i'm not speaking from personal
experience running around my grandma I
love her to death but you know it is
there anybody here the IT person for the
family right yeah all of us right so
you're kinda like the designated person
to go to for anything right away what
antivirus need to get or what you know
shot by a mac or you know a windows
machine or so for the surface or which
surface which version right you're that
IT person and it's kind of like the King
role that you've established your family
or the king or queen role you're
establishing your family right here that
person my grandma knows this but yet she
spent two hours on support with
Microsoft because her subscription for
antivirus field and she gave her credit
card like Grandma call me before you
give a credit card out two perfectly
good stranger right anyway sorry long
story of any um 40-percent perimeter
compromises perimeters still a very high
risk and high probability still need to
do the things to defend it but I think
overall we've got a lot better on the
perimeter it's not like we're finding
the basic stuff that we did
traditionally find on the outside
anymore you still there but it's not as
bad but if you look at the end .
compromises this is a higher return on
investment i can buy an EK or exploit
kit on the market for a couple hundred
bucks for fifty bucks on that in the
coming ones and then pop an organization
based on a predefined fish that was
already inside the EK and then use that
to exploit an organization to get access
to right or from decent i can use you
know another tool or open-source tools
whatever i want to you to craft fishes
offer go through organized by accounts
that already compromised or whatever I
want to do but the endpoints end up
being the most challenging one for us
because you know the users themselves if
I let you save it . population of 500 ok
five other people i send a fish 22
people doesn't work watch them do more
and send it to more than intended to
more until I get that one person to
click a link and what's great is there
so much information available already
know most of your defenses problem even
going after you
no one here I'm sure is puttin linkedin
their experience with their organization
right okay i am
our site admin and when he hears and you
know we I did a whole implementation of
our site two years ago so now I know
your arse implementations two years old
which means that really not exist
because our tastes like 400 years to get
working so we got class because we all
know we all been there been there too
I know the pain is to have here at that
point my hair back but on so you know
you look at that and you say ok I can
know what levels of maturity and
organizations and hey i just switched
from this antivirus product and I'm i
went to this new next-generation
solution you know so now i know that you
have all this stuff here that I need to
get around to get around the link is a
great example but going after that's
really great
now one thing that's interesting is how
do these specific attacks work and
that's what i'm showing I think it's
important to understand and show you
some of these attacks and i'm sure some
of you already seen me present on some
eight attack vectors let me show you the
other side of it of what is actually
there and how do you actually defend
against it so these are the attacks work
that's my presentation ever thank you
alright so i want to
after an organization the first thing to
do is do my homework then if I'd like to
talk about LinkedIn little threat model
was my easiest way of getting into the
organization is it through its
subsidiary you know branch office
something remote homework home employees
you know partners that could have
potential access into environments a lot
of ways that we can look at attacking an
organization then step 3 the attack and
then next is persistence in next level
and here's a better model right here and
hope you can see it to look at here this
is kind of a life cycle of an attack and
uh if you look at at at these steps you
know with her every step but you know
essentially just talk about defining
your target doing your homework going
through building and testing test for
detection appropriate fishing deployment
of your command control infrastructure
now here's where the hard part is at
right here looking at the initial
intrusion all the way up to the cover
tracks and maintain foot hole that
period of time is a very small window
that we have as defenders you're talking
usually anywhere between hours to days
there's a great study i think the
verizon database report and I don't like
referencing them a lot as a lot of its
anyways so you look at the present
report on what they did is they looked
at and analyze how long it took
attackers once an actual breach occurred
to get access to the data they needed in
most cases they found that happened
after a few days so we have a few days
as defenders to detect that initial
breach or the movement in the network to
get the systems that have the data or
else we're screwed right then we're like
six months later right now the
industry's at anywhere between six
months to like yeah right now right
mmm is it 2013-2014 right not find stuff
for a few years right
that's where as an industry so we have
six months to a few years how to get
better and shrink that down to a few
hours or a few minutes or a few seconds
or as it happens now I'm a full advocate
of protection or defending and I think
there's a lot of layers that we can do
for your protection
most companies don't have the luxury of
really building a sound secure
infrastructure because already been
there for like nine hundred years so
changing that's very difficult if you
have a flat network architecture didn't
have been through a complete network
recall where they had a like new network
segmentation as not nice right as not
fun
you're a lot of late nights and people
are young you all the time
look at people yelling at me when I did
like four years ago so anyway so how do
we get better at the initial intrusion
how do we get better when the
command-and-control happens how do we
get better at lateral movement is
already know a lot of movement is moving
from one system to the next the next the
next using some sort of information on
the box to get access to it
how do we get better persistence hooks
and maintaining access into environments
and how do we get better when they start
to exfiltrate the information and
covering the tracks that's what I'm
going to focus on is kind of this now
some of you already seen this before I
apologize but this is what my favorite
ones that I did for CNN and it's it's
it's a good example I didn't have any
information about this company is going
after I knew nothing about them at all
actually it was one of our customers
that gave us permission to do a live
social engineer on CNN as long as we
didn't reveal the customer names later
blur out or remove the sections where
that happened
so this is a lot of social engineer that
i did about a year ago at DEFCON and so
hopefully find interesting but this is
how easy it is to get that first
compromising and by the way this is IT
helpdesk it typically have elevated
access into systems
Yeah Yeah right usually over endpoints
right over the workstations themselves
so they can remote in and do all the
good stuff there right
that's beautiful for us man that's
beautiful love it but when I say the
word hacker some creepy dude in the
basement
well that's a misconception of you by
the way yes I told you there's a class
of hackers who don't just have social
skills they have more digital
intelligence than anyone you'll ever
meet David Kennedy is one of them
he's what's known as a social engineer a
little hacker his craft is to dupe you
into doing things and sharing
information you probably should discover
your credit card number some use it for
illegal activity in David's case
companies Pam to find out if employees
are leading the company vulnerable he is
game shows how it's done step one of his
number so it looks like he's calling
from inside the company and then call
tech support
hello there hello i can grab was
wondering if you cannot take a look at a
website trying to get to its for a God
big customer think i'm working on for
monday and i can't seem to get to the
website for my computer
sure thanks man really appreciate the
help I mean it could be a stupid thing
i'm i'm i'm really suck with computers
but so it's a it's it's it's
www.searchtv.org is you are veiy dash
pro . com
yeah I but open and i'm at right now
here's what the IT guy doesn't realize
by clicking that link
he's just given David full access to his
computer okay that's weird i just hit
into work seems like it's working fine
now
awesome i don't know what you did man i
really appreciate the help
no problem view that was it we're on
this computer now you are able to take
take over this
this guy's computer within i would say
like under commander two minutes yeah
under two minutes to go over the entire
computer and and think of it as not just
his computer but it's pretty much a doll
involvement so I say that the entire
down holding company house phone by the
way you never know when it's gonna work
like i did a one like a DEFCON a few
years ago and kevin Mitnick and I didn't
talk i think is like DEFCON 22 or
something like that
I remember which one but we were on
stage and we had a list of people to be
called customer same customer allowed us
to call on you know different different
people you never know when you're doing
a live demonstration in front of an
entire on it's like 5,000 people are not
going to work
it's like the first person we got wasn't
better off as a second person we got
hung up on us immediately the third
person we finally got we hook the Miami
we compromise and everything on it like
super comic like social engineering live
on stage in front of 5,000 people and
got access to computer shells and
everything was amazing
one of the highlights of your life and
you like a little to your time to think
about that moment but but why i say
that's the entire downfall the entire
company is because that initial
intrusion if i don't get detected in
this point and I established a command
control from there the information that
i can gleam off that machine whether
it's local admin accounts for the
ability to move to different systems or
if its IT helpdesk person the
permissions themselves you know can I
use that information to move to
different systems the network usually IT
helpdesk folks have local admin other
boxes do you think any of your on folks
that are our domain admins have ever
longed to enter like hit right click run
as administrator for their active
directory tools you know that launches a
kerberos token that we cannot person in
our domain and we can move the different
systems right so you know finding that
token or something that we need to move
to different systems and have access is
the point in time where if I don't get
detected here we have a big problem and
so how do we go and move to that system
how do we get a little better than i'll
talk about that so still to this day
main methods of exploitation are still
predominantly executables about from
what we can sell based on the malware
analysis and droppers and communication
infrastructure 93% is still executables
executable to this they are still a
problem and all those are non-code sign
so if you have a good environment where
you can say i'm only going to allow code
signed certificates which is none of us
by the line but um wish someday along
with network segmentation so if we get
to that point where we can actually have
executed that are signed by certain
certificate authorities I think that's
going to reduce the footprint
significantly that's what I'm a pretty
big advocate of application whitelisting
you can do application whitelisting on
your environment that's a pretty good
indication you can drop it shrink about
ninety percent of your overall exposure
that you're going to have from your
users and their focus on that seven
percent 7% a lot easier to handle than a
hundred percent right but now you have
executables flying all over the place we
allow an unsigned code to be executed in
any way shape or form and that's how all
these are still traditionally happening
now we're seeing a big move to
powershell that's been happening over
the past few years and you're seeing you
know I'm like antivirus products in
next-generation product is that starting
a little bit better at detecting
powershell but it's still pretty far
enough sheep ashes on their diets out
there either post on my facebook that
there is a /a target
well where the new windows 10 preview
had a update for a boon to I'm like well
when would I ever thought that Microsoft
have an update for a bunch of it anyway
let's take a look at an actual attack
this is using HTML and if you're not
familiar with what an HD is on it's
essentially so a few years ago ICU job
apples all-time exclusively because Java
applets awesome right because job
applicant everybody had jobs installed
and just co-signed it look believable I
still works very well but why not just
use something that's built into windows
that everybody has no matter what right
so HDA files are something that are
inherently installed by default you can
remove its high content files that you
can't be you necessarily within a web
browser that requires excessive
permissions and so you can do inside of
a web browser you can say hey I need to
launch this HTM file this HTM file
contains code that is going to prompt me
to say to you are you sure you want to
open this what you think users do that
can click on a fast enough right and
what's funny is a it was about a year
ago we started messing for two years ago
started messing with HTS quite a bit and
uh Justin one of our guys LZ was like
this stuff works so good like me and no
one is ever gonna believe that he like a
hundred percent accessory like all right
I'm gonna eat my my words in this one
and i've been using ever since it's
fantastic when the best methods to use
for for compromising the endpoints HD is
a great socially demo that real fast
something so this is the new version
not released and hopefully to be done in
about another week or so mrs. 7474 I'm
interesting enough everything powershell
so arm Empire def cons I remember the
difference in trouble or 16 I think I
you with another person named josh kelly
gave the very first powershell security
talk never liked the history of powerful
security which is awesome is called
powershell msg and during that period of
time we showed ways of getting around
the execution restriction policies and
stuff like that which at the time were
toddlers kind of like security features
that has since been changed quite a bit
but we also show that you can take code
like a long list of code and condensing
him and put it into an encoded command
get around things now coated command is
used all the time now
ah it'sit's a use all the time now to
get code executed powershell a lot of
tools out there in fact if you're from
the metasploit never used the PS exact
module the old method for that used to
be the drop executables now it's
actually fully converted to powershell
as a method for droppers vs executable
themselves so what I've done in this
version is there's actually 12 different
ways of using a code command you know
that abbreviation and things like that
Jake and dashing cody command dash a and
C Dash and see you know I at the spell
oh you know you can be abbreviated
everything my favorite one now is dashi
shrinks everything up you can use dashi
now four encoded command to get around
most stuff interesting enough on the
last version of set was getting flagged
by symantec and mcafee and all these
other ones Michael that's weird we're
flagging my powershell stuff or
something we got to like write my code
or whatever and so I have a tool that
basically chunks of my code and then
submits it looks for with the portions
that are actually getting flagged by
antivirus and so i can actually see my
and my double and environment and all
that wasn't was getting by with no
problem until I pass it a dash and see
something
ok well what if i do dash E and got
around all of my okay that's good
so actually works fine for now i'll
switch around 22 but Dashon coated
command the full one also works as well
they're not they can get rid of that one
because that was being used by everybody
for it so what this attack doesn't buy
the new version of 74 incorporates a lot
of new application on power show which
is fantastic so I'm gonna go to the
social context number one on and by the
way a funny story on the SMS spoofing
that way
it's really well now by the way I was
just that I was at MIT yesterday just
wanted to give me sleep but they had a
lot of my government officials and stuff
like that
I called one of the folks up on stage
and I'm like hey what's your first and
last name and what county do you live in
and he gave me his first last name i
think it was but something that won't
give us last time out on a new account
and so I have a way a little magic trick
on stage for folks but i have a way of
pulling like a full social date of birth
you know their wives names and kids
names and home addresses and phone
numbers and everything so I did all that
on stage he's freaking Isaac when I go
check this out
let's move the phone number you know
from his wife is every has Wi-Fi
networks like hacking into that tube
I'm gonna let me give information by the
way got a waiver on and so I spoke by
phone number her phone number to him and
said hey there's an emergency call me
now and so you know he's looking into a
freak guys like okay I'm Donnie tapped
out which is really cool but that's the
best roofing works really well on into
the new version but actually removed it
a few versions to go and then it was
shown mr. robot and so everybody kept
sending me emails like every week like
words SMS spoof module that is almost
robotic so I rewrote the whole thing
over a weekend my car SMS will be back
in there now it's actually pretty cool
so so go to the website attacker number
2 i'm gonna go to the HD eight actor
which is number eight
ok so that's number eight on the social
engineers will get so hit number eight
nobody the cyclone ER and was going to
close and trusted second common example
using my IP address i'll call that real
fast
useful for three and I just an
interpreter shell and what this is going
to do is kelowna website automatically
create the hd2 actor now the method that
uses for infection is an HTM file
coupled with a powerful injection attack
ok so it's using powershell as a method
of compromising now a cool technique was
introduced a couple years ago by name a
really great security researcher on my
favorite Matthew graber at the greater
figure out a way to inject shellcode
read into memory through powershell
without ever touching disk now why
that's important is because we're never
touching this great stuff that's purely
memory resident is very difficult to
actively go and detect upon unless you
have something written specifically for
that and then after that I'm it's very
easy to go and do all that stuff we're
getting shells people um so you know
when you look at that that's one of
those things that will be actually
taking a peek at when we actually gonna
do this but we're not touching disc at
this point i'm so that my Windows
machine go to this website 172 29 we
gotta think now you can see an open
prompts a second
it's a little
prompt sure those the website over here
we are shell it is building over
those windows 10 you just saw it there
so Windows 10 windows 8 windows 7
windows XP any version you want to you
don't have any software installed now to
do anything updates or anything crazy it
works on all versions and platforms that
have power Sean's thought you could drop
executables and stuff to works fine
that's great is it doesn't get picked up
anything so I'm application whitelisting
is a good example of that is application
whitelisting going to stop this
no right why the memory right so in
memory not executing and powers powerful
DXE waitlisted application
sure usually you're blocking be awesome
um so you know this method we have full
access computer now let's talk a little
about the techniques of this work in
actually looking at the technics so what
detecting attacks powershell injection
is one of the topics ones because with
power with powerful v8 version five
highly recommended has some
significantly advanced logging features
in it
I'm so you have the ability to look for
things i'm a good one to look for is
abbreviated coded commands right on
anybody ever using my carbon black for
example anybody know one okay so carbon
black will take things back and you can
actually developer called watch lists
off of things right with those watch
list it's very easy to circumvent those
because they're very finite type of
rules that you put so you literally have
to get like every iteration of things
like dashi dashi and destiny and you're
going to pass after that if you want to
look for things like encode command
basically for commands on kernel32.dll
being run is at normal in powershell
free to be running that from the command
line oh right Mimi cats have normal
never be running from partial oh right
on
so all those things are things you can
look for i'm actually going to publish a
blog after this i have this talk with
all the things that i look for are you
know for suspicious commands for that
out invoke expression is another one
abbreviated commanded that is IEX so if
you see any of those and I'm happening
environment on which is basically going
download and execute on those are all
things that you typically want to look
for and this you have the logging
available for you automatically on your
Windows machine so get those to your sim
or whatever you're using and have those
actually go back now says little
difficult when you have tools like
invoke expression done and phenomenal
tool by daniel did an awesome job
I really said 30
on and invoke obfuscation i will
basically take your power shell code and
mango living daylights out of it to make
it look like it's no longer there
anymore are malicious code anyway so no
moves everything is just everything at
pax it looks at around so that's a
really good tools if you're at pentester
running avoca obfuscation is a great one
so I talked about in this the encoded
command one is a good example you know
of being able to circumvent that based
off of shrinking and everything else but
i'll publish a list of those on the
defensive side a good method is honey
tokens be familiar with this so when you
compromise a machine and you get access
to this machine will typically happens
there kerberos tokens on systems that
attackers look for so i'm an admin on a
box i can usually in person that
kerberos token and from there move to
rest of the network right so we can do
honey tokens is there's this great API
and colin is actually talk show you the
power shopping powershell but it's
create process with login w what's great
about this function is that it will
allow you to create a fake username and
password and memory or a fake token
memory what you can do is on your domain
controllers create a user it's like
super domain admin dash 1 or whatever
you want to write give it a super long
crazy past like three thousand character
password lock it in the safe and and you
know only two people have the key to
whatever you wanna do right so it's a
super secret account right now what you
do is you run this command in in and
I'll show you how to do here in a second
you get if you know the username of that
domain admin the domain of that you have
your domain on that password but make it
a fake password this shoots it into
memory so i use a tool like me cats are
going to pull double digest and I'll say
oh there's a domain admin login this box
let me go and try it if you ever see a
field login attempt in that domain admin
account you got a problem in your
network right as a great example of a
way to mess with a actual attacker only
an attackers only ever going to see that
there's a good example the the 46 48 and
here's another one on every anybody use
the tool responder yeah that was
actually pretty difficult on to detect
kind of with responder what it works is
that there's just two methods local link
multicast resolution protocol RL NR and
is also on you know
a few other methods uh escaping me right
now balancers thank you ms thank you
looking for that so those two methods on
you know essentially if you want to know
how it works is you know if you let's
just say I'm trying to connect to a file
server it will grab its local cache and
say hey is it cash to have the IP
address this if not then I'll broadcast
it out to my local sudden and say hey
pal survey are you there a responder
work says yes I'm file server a password
credentials and it sends usually an
internet and v1 and v2 hash of of that
user account that was being actively
used what you can do on and there's a
couple tools to leverage this on the ben
ten when the guys at work trust a sec
with us on ben ten releases a tool under
powerful defense and you can run this
tool as they are like a scheduled task
in your environment and will actually
send out fake I women are broadcast
across your network fake usernames and
passwords again make a domain admin make
it super complex password if you ever
see those credentials ever going across
your network and you have an issue but
there's actually a really cool way of
detecting this in your environment even
half the way for the username and
password failure you look for event log
46-48 which is explicit credentials you
use to log into the remote system should
that username and password ever be used
in your environment that log into remote
system that password invalid anywhere
know if I have a fake username and
password somewhere i'm logging into
remote system that's responder saying if
I'm good password credentials and get
those crowds are good we know that
something's not right there so you can
detect respond directly over the wire
real-time just by that specific event ID
and so you can go to that site
github.com been 0 then 0 XA / powershell
defense and it's also the one that
automatically does their the create
login process w that one is a tool that
you can use its it's a powershell tool
you on as a scheduled task and that's
from fuzzy security so get help calm /
high security is a powerful speaker is
called invoke run as broken as well I to
create those fake credentials in memory
there's a lot of cool things you can do
directly power shown runs as scheduled
commands and running across your entire
network as an attacker i compromise one
box i see a domain him along w think I'm
going after right
hey i'm on the network and I got
responder running or invade which is a
windows version of it
you think I'm looking for right so I'm
gonna try to find those types of things
and those are some of the main methods
that you can do now this is a cool one
I've never released this before so one
thing that we do at BDS do a lot of
research because we have a tool that
looks for indicators of compromises and
. softer look for it
what I like to do is release a lot of
that research on that we do on based on
how to find things now when we first
looked at pat detecting pass the hash
environments
this is a really difficult one there's a
lot of papers on pass the hash detection
none of them work especially in large
enterprises none of them work so a lot
of will tell you to look at the ntl MSP
accounts anybody ever tried looking at
the end you'll MSP account happens
everywhere across your entire
environment all the time so your
sharepoint accounts used for
authentication owa uses it all the time
print servers use it all the time we
found this out because we have over
4,000 points are like hey let's try it
out
whoa that's a lot of false-positive crap
right so when you have those many false
positives you have to look at what how
can i detect pass the hash better
environments that you can detect that
reduce that the way we started looking
at it is well maybe the NLCS is P is a
good way to go is there deviations and
patterns that happen inside pass the
hash that are unique and different
things that aren't gonna happen the rest
of your environment and how do we
minimize that
so the way that we looked at it is well
where can you actually get hashes from
we're the only two places that you can
get either LMAO ntlm hashes and
environment just think
whatever so so where they store that
we're the only two locations they're
stored at on your on your in your entire
organization the pcs or domain
controllers so only two places that you
have in your environments that have a
lemon NCM hashes that can be used for
pass the hash i'm not talking env2 or
cash credentials can be used for cat
pass the hash you crack and then use
them to do that that's a different
different story but only two places you
could actually pass the hash our local
accounts that are stored on the pc so
your local admin accounts they may be
the same across the board right or
domain controllers so we started looking
at and say okay well let's take a look
at the Intel message p accountant all
said which is the current method of
doing it looking environments got
thousands and thousands of false
positives but also the deviations ok
well let's limit it just local accounts
and domain controllers
ok let's take those two and and build
those in and see what we get
ok we're still seeing some false
positives for example on if you remote
desktop into a system it's still a
network login type three remote login
right whether you do it via RPC netbios
or w my or whatever or rdp it's still a
network login it's going to be our the
second remote logging never type 3 and
so we had false positives with rdp so I
rdp to a system and hit X and I went
back into it again and i was already
logged in the system it would use cash
credentials and then look like pass the
hash of the network how to reduce that
one too
so here's what we did and we figured out
you grab
log 4624 login type 3 look at the login
process of ntlm sp1 bhopal publishes on
a blog post so all of you that are gonna
take pictures to its fine
yeah security ID null said what you can
do is to like meh display for example i
will randomize the hostname so we can do
is you can create a baseline based off
your Active Directory computers you
compare those interesting to say oh hey
does this you know the machine is
authenticating a domain machine and it's
coming from a hostname that is not a
domain that's one way of the technique
but that's not a hundred percent any way
shape or form i would even rely off of
that as a main method because you know
if somebody's administrators probably
pants are not necessarily you know
state-sponsored adversaries trying to
take down everything your network great
so you know that part's not really
really reliable however those of value
inside of your event law called key link
and his key length is what negotiates a
session key for encryption with an
actual authentication occurs rdp will
always use a key length of something i
usually hundred twenty-eight so with the
key lengths of a hundred twenty-eight
bit you know that's going to be already
penis not pass the hash so the way that
you look for this is you say one is it a
local machine a local admin accounts not
a domain admin accounts 246 24 log
network login type 3 login process and
SSB security ideas and all said and then
you take the key lengths to make it zero
you can't combine all those together now
you got your recipe for detecting past
hash across your network and it works
very very well so congrats you know your
past has detection lot of cool things
you can look forward to a suspicious
file execution extensions or someone
that we look for SCT files
seriously like go to your content
filtering firewall parameters your web
blocking software start blocking foul
tips you don't need you ever need a CT
files to be running on the outside
no other ways around that Gracie what
was a subdeacon i think came out with it
so you can use reg SVR 32 on to
communicate and it's a proxy aware
executable microsoft will allow you to
communicate out grabbing sec filing get
remote code execution bypass application
whitelisting stuff like that
the problem with that is that it doesn't
need to be named ICT so you can still
does download a regular file not unless
you're doing inspection look at the see
if it has a file format RC file of the
cts on that will be a little bit
different but you know these are some of
the things you can definitely block you
know from your from your firewall like
do you really need HTS on the outside
no no one needs HD and no one uses the
season outside know what you're using
job in the outside either been
persistent hooks one my favorites on a
long time ago
there's a way of doing a very front of
the whole stickies attack right you know
if you're not familiar you can reboot
machine and you could rename set HDD XC
+ util mandate you seem to like command
esc when you reboot the computer the
shift key factors in the command prompt
pops up and yet system access to the box
right away that you always reset
people's password hacking boxes whatever
now it's funny story i was talking with
my friends I so if you actually start
looking for sticky keys or is a tool
that a dentist came out with a camera
the name of it the name of the tool at
this last defcon but actually sweeps
your network looking for sticky it's a
great tool just look up the defcon
sticky to find it on but what's
interesting is you will find these on
your network like almost all the time
like I've searched in the past ten
pentest and half of them iphone stickies
on boxes before it's like a developer
like I'm and lost my password reset
using sticky like you can literally get
access the boxes and only based on and
developers doing
no interesting thing for admins what was
interesting as those required reboots
right
not necessarily and if you ever saw the
blog post that musics in awhile back I
think about Chris gates also did as well
if you just read these you can put a
specific process in debug mode and will
do is it will say okay this image file
execution options said exe I need you to
replace it every time its run with
community
sexy it's a simple registry command that
doesn't require a reboot you can get
persistence mode very easily without
having to reboot the machine and have a
back door to assistant to be community
so you can be your payload whatever you
want to do so you can have that run
every single time you run it is that I
probably look for in your environment
that's just a good example of a
persistent working environment should
never have registered he's like that
change service creations so there's I
don't know this by the way but we start
debugging like what group policy logs
and what doesn't and going through like
what information you need and you know
whether or not i need to use like ewo or
hook an API or record with driver or
whatever I gotta do in order to get what
I need to start going through a lot of
these on the event logs and it realize
that Microsoft stores all of your audit
logs and event logs your settings and
csv files you guys know that I didn't so
the csv file data stored in my corset
initially totally messing with that
right now so i can do that but we'll see
um but if you look at this event log
4697 have to configure advanced options
we can do increase group policy and
that'll get you service creations know
what you can do is baseline what
services you allow and the flag on
anything that's not normal so more of a
baseline application whitelisting
approaches you ever see services like
for example metasploit will use commas
back to install a powershell service in
your environment you ever see that in
your environment
no you know you've been owned at that
point I'm write a lot of cool things you
can look at on just specifically office
service creations application
whitelisting phenomenal
I'm a big advocate that because again
reduces the noise about 93 percentage
and you have the rest of it to worry
about and that's that's more manageable
remember giving a talk like seven or
eight years ago when I was a chief
security officer of a fortune 1000
companies diebold after came after party
machine
um so when I didn't talk there
you know I did the same thing on
detection I tried to eliminate the noise
on detection so I said well if any port
scans we just automatically Shawn and
Carrie bottom eliminate the noise the
folks that are really trying to go after
i want to see that percentage the same
thing for protection eliminate your
noise portable executable files are
executables are the noise right now
that's miss Bennett noise since like the
AOL days right
remember like in fact and remember
somebody affecting somebody with no
malware with an exe back in the old days
the BBS days
so some mitigation that work for me
randomizing disabled admins are familiar
with laps maps a pretty decent tool but
it stores the password in clear text and
group awesome you can restrict that a
little bit
there's also an open-source tool that we
released one of our guys jeff releases
called ships the shared host integration
password server it was originally chips
but then we can figure out a good
acronym for chips because we're eating
all the chips the time when we thought
ship sounded kind of paradiso we made it
parts so ships a good one but a
randomized all your password across your
network so you know as an IT admin know
hey I need to get to this box okay
here's the random local admin pass they
need to authenticate to it
oh you can also disable local admins now
good story about this do you like group
policy setting it says you know disabled
local admins that doesn't actually
disabled and unless you have another
local admin there that does you no good
if you have another local admins the
same across the board cross everything
machine so we can do there is you can
actually run scheduled tasks to disable
your local an across-the-board if you
need to get access to just run a
scheduled task to re-enable it on or if
it gets too strong for the domain you
reboot the machine and safe mode it will
automatically enable the default sit 500
so it's going to your local minister
account automatically be unable to still
do administration if it's for some
reason you can't communicate the domain
controllers that's a good one lower
permissions obviously that's a pretty
big one not having enemies running as
local admin like and stuff are user
countering local admins are removing
excessive account usage formerly
management is a big one basic binary
types and powerful execution and .
visibility my favorite one to configure
my absolute favorite one totally jacked
me up you can put this in your
workstations and servers and put the
local admins group is part of this deny
access to computer for the network local
administrators tonight local
administrators access network that
totally jacked me up as an attacker like
literally jacked me up so bad and the
reason for that is if I compromise a
machine and let's just say you have the
same local and passes across the board
you don't care because I as a local
admin I can authenticate remotely to
another machine that has a local admin
boxing because you have a group policy
setting in place so that shuts me down
and almost instantaneously across the
board with that specific policy
obviously need to test it on
but this one here really really messes
me up on as an attacker so i highly
recommend placing and last but not least
we all need to be purple times it just
like that's cool i actually had 15
minutes i got like two minutes so we all
need to be purple as an industry that's
one of the most important pieces that I
can relate you know it's a lot of the
things that you saw here are very
detective nature based off of the
attacks that i use I'm gonna publish a
blog post allowing all this at binary
defense you go to binary sense com i'll
show you how to attack pass the hash and
like it's tough on everyone at least
here I should have it out hopefully
tomorrow after i get like eight hours of
sleep i'm not gonna happen a private
tonight but we all need to be purple on
and what we do now in memory is
definitely harder to detect one thing
that ben ten released all right if your
pen tester
this is totally dirty everybody mess
with NPS and pas is not powershell an
executable that runs powershell without
ever calling powershell ever don't know
haven't got that far yet I'm workin on
it okay
nothing my next talk on a second ps2
memory I don't admit that I'm like old
man i can figure out you know when
you're not using a code signing start
right it's like well then i'm just going
to write this thing here which is
invoked memory MPs and so downloads and
uploads executable directly members you
can run powershell directly memories out
of her calling powershot they seem like
i'm working on that next right it's
always a back-and-forth of the guys over
there obviously one of the things that's
also hard to detect the physical text i
just want to show you a really funny
video real quick and then I'll wrap it
up all day that a funny note but going
into buildings like we've been trying to
progressively get more and more
ridiculous with things that we do to see
how like far we can push the envelope
and so this is whatever guys Paul Burke
nickname Biebs you can take justin
bieber and so-and-so beads going in
there and we had to dress up in a nice
suit and tie and with a with a whole
thing of balloons for birthday serious
beats going in the building who
we can all awesome then we have a camera
behind them and then you can see here
create distraction and we walk into the
building just walking past or locked
inside of you
hey now we're inside the building was
awesome
another good one if you haven't seen
this by the way on this DVD and I like
to show that even when this one makes me
laugh more than any other video I've
ever seen in my entire life before and I
get this picture like I can just picture
I don't even really well if you don't
know me is one of the best like lockpick
guys physical security guys that I've
ever met my life and deviant and i can
just picture him like walking down the
street drunk one day with a single
whiskey in his hand he's like oh there's
a sense of their let me just blow
whiskey through to sleep and get the
door
a student is all dapper was a rack
sensor they're making everybody