well thank you everyone for coming to my
talk I know we're up against lunch so I
appreciate you for going lunch for a few
more minutes
this talk specifically is entitled
becoming a cyborg kind of my first steps
into implantable technology it's
something that i started to research
over the last several months to years so
and i kinda want to share my beginning
steps with you I work for a company
called Sikich basically we are a IT
consulting firm we do everything from
penetration testing forensics work two
implementations so kind of a
one-stop-shop as far as IT consulting
goes so if you need assistance with that
you know give us a call look us up
they're paying for me to be here so
that's that's the shameless plug a
little bit about myself i am a
penetration tester by day I also
currently run the mini partner project
we checked over from my good friend
Kevin Baughn kevin and i also run a
youtube show called mayhem lab where we
do really stupid things with electronics
so if you have time to waste you can't
really look that up so kind of a real
quick agenda today we are going to talk
about biotechnology about hacking come
what is it
look at the different types of implants
what people are doing with these
implants and kind of talk about what you
would want to think about if you're
interested in getting an implant I do
have a demonstration of i've got a video
on how I was actually implanted and then
how it actually works and then talk a
little bit about the lesson learn i was
like to throw the disclaimer up here
that we do have some corn quite
disturbing images because we can talk
about biohacking without getting your
hands a little bit dirty
so if you're squeamish you may want to
know about your eyes
not every slide so according to
wikipedia which is the definitive source
for absolutely everything biohacking is
basically a social movement of people
trying to use medical grade equipment to
introduce technology with their bodies
right i like to sum it up as it's an art
form of modifying the human body to take
advantage of technology so how can we
integrate the two
unlike the last talk which was extremely
interesting nanotechnology we're not
talking about that sort of integration
we're talking about putting something
under your skin or on your skin
something like that that would then
become useful to what's interesting is
if you guys have watched the implant
implantable technologies movement over
the last couple years it's kind of
starting to get a little traction
it's not a new phenomenon it's actually
been around for a long time there was a
program in 2004 called the very chip
bigquery chip sure I pronounce that but
it was a program started by hospital
systems to implant a basically an RFID
tag and either your right shoulder your
right elbow region thought process was
you go to the hospital in your
unconscious you can actually get scanned
when you enter into the emergency room
and that ID with in reference to make
your medical records so the implant
itself didn't actually host your medical
records but it was just a way to look it
up if you were say unconscious this died
out relatively quickly and got about 300
people the best I can figure out the
main concern was that the implants were
causing cancer so you know it's probably
bad for a hospital to give you cancer so
they stopped doing it a little bit
different types of implants as I said
we've got rfid or is everyone familiar
with RFID radio frequency identification
tags right we all have one little white
badges to get into things NFC is
actually a subset of rfid so near field
communication works specifically on the
thirteen point six five megahertz range
so it's actually a subset of rfid in
this shot you can kind of see how big
these how little these impacts of plants
are they're about the size of a grain of
rice if you want to take a look at one a
little bit later if you can see this but
I have one of the implants taped to my
business card so it looks very small
little device
basically the same thing they come in a
little strange little needle that it's
very simple to inject into your skin
under your skin will see a little bit
later the one that leave his name is
alex at cyber eyes . me which is one of
the places you can get these that
information at the end is working on a
thermometer so it's interesting about
this you can implement the thermometer
under your skin and you have a
proprietary device that he came up with
that you can go ahead and scan that's a
monitor and get your temperature at any
given time the downside is works on a
little bit of an odd frequency so 34.2
kilohertz and you do have to have the
proprietary device right haven't really
been able to figure out how to use it in
other ways yet so this is also an
interesting one
it's called tritium so it's the same
substance that if you if you have a
watch that's not a smartwatch and
actually has dials on it if you ever
notice got a little green tips on the
one hand the glows in the dark
that's basically what this substance is
so it goes under the skin
it's a strictly aesthetic so it's it's
referred to as a firefly tattoo because
you can you know go the Raven light up
like a firefly guess don't but that's
what type of implant people are doing
this was really interesting as well
these guys from grindhouse where they're
very interesting group of individuals
haven't had a chance to meet them in
person but you can check out their site
they do a very interesting work they've
got this device called the North Star
currently they've got version 1 and to
my knowledge these are the only
individuals that have it basically it's
a small disk little puck that they've
sliced open their hand and then inserted
it and it in close when you you know
chicken or get close to each other
it's completely aesthetic has no
practical purpose its battery-powered so
someday it will die and have to come out
kinda sounds like a lot of phosphor not
much but they are working on version to
say it's going to be rechargeable and
guessing that means wireless charging vs
uh having a USB port on your hand made
sure but they're also talking about
building in some kind of technology to
control other things like rfid or NFC so
not a lot of information on that yet but
another interesting thing so this is
very interesting
Gabriel Gabriel decided to give himself
night vision so basically what they did
and you can find the formula online
didn't want to be responsible for
ruining anyone signed eyesight so I
didn't put up here but yeah they worked
out a chemical formula and put into a
strange it's based off of what's called
ce6 but basically it's something that
you could find in a type of fish
I believe that's lives in the deep sea
they can squirt it into your eyes become
basically black you look like a you know
like a sci-fi creature and you can go
ahead and go outside and see in the dark
it's not really scientifically proven
you know he did it to himself or had
somebody else do it to himself and
there's no real scientific data that
shows that you're going to actually get
night vision does wear off after a
couple hours
this was pretty big when it came out
last year therefore what again what's
interesting is this isn't really new
either they've been experimenting with
this sort of Technology from 2006 in
mice rats so we just decided to do it to
ourselves as far as humans go
so then magnets we all like magnetism
right what a lot of people are doing for
implants these days is putting negative
your fingertips they have kits that you
can buy online either do this to
yourself seen videos of people doing it
to himself I'm not sure how drunk they
actually work
um I don't think I can do this to myself
but you know yourself take a scalpel
slice open your fingertip insert a small
three millimeters by one Miller
millimeter in size so very small magnet
you put one in each fingertip and people
can actually detect magnetic fields you
feel a little tug on your your fingers
when you're around magnetic field people
have reported for instance i read an
article about a gentleman holding a
vacuum cleaner cord you can actually
feel the electricity pulsing through the
back and record things like that it's
kind of interesting i'm not quite sure
what the practical use of having a
magnet in your fingers
I like practical implants but I guess if
we come up with a practical use for
magnetism this guy is probably one of
the first legitimate implants that I've
been able to find back in $MONTH 2004
kneel here had an implant put into the
back of his skull
there's no information on the procedure
the doctors remain anonymous
it was one of the first time that they
never done this but basically he's
colorblind
so what he's able to do is actually pick
up images through this camera which
converts it to sound and he now can hear
color through this special device that
he wears looks like kind of a little
antenna that skips over his head
so some of the stuff has been around for
a long time I think that's kind of what
i want to get you know take these points
to is it's not new i know a lot of
people have talked about the last couple
years but it's relatively old stuff
we're starting to see it kind of more
mainstream Oh a little little bit more
interesting stuff so you have to select
your implant and why do you want an
implant what do you want the implant to
do as you've seen so far most of the
implants are aesthetic in nature a lot
of those like the firefly tattoos or the
North Star things like that people have
LEDs and planted on their skin obviously
a big one is you know all your friends
are doing it that's how i got started it
because my good friend kevin was at a
conference and he emailed me a picture
inside check out this really cool
implant kid I just got so about five
seconds later i said i want one
um so he brought it home and you know I
had my name planted and he sadly never
did make sex that but what do you want
to do right so we're talking about some
little different chips that they have
out there you know NFC vs RFC I think
it's the biggest debate right now what
what information do you want to store on
your chip and what is it that you want
to actually do for you
there is a we're talking at der beek on
a couple of weeks ago to an individual
and they're looking at NFC chips that
have a little bit more storage and
actually storing like your pgp key on it
so you can imagine signing your
documents literally with your fingertip
or palm of your hand or something
instead of actually pulling it out on
USB Drive which would be I think pretty
cool very useful right so a couple of
different ships are I wanted to look at
these there's a lot of them out there
there's the ones that i have a little
bit of experience with so we've got the
mayfair cards those are your typical
wristband key fob sort of thing and
we're like a disney world is doing it
now a lot of the other theme parks you
get like a little wristband you walk up
and you know you tap on it and make his
headlights up or whatever and you can
get on your ride
that's NFC technology in fact our hotel
room doors right
Arzo is a Mayfair kind of clone there's
a couple different sizes out there so if
you're going to look at getting
something like this implanted you want
to be aware of how much data you need
one chip isn't necessarily the same
you'll notice there's a quite a range of
sizes when it comes to capacity
you know 48 bits 228 bits universes 224
bits up to 4k so look at the chip
understand what it is that you're
actually getting because you might
actually find them online for thirty
bucks
and it sounds like a great deal and you
get it and it's much smaller the data
capacity is much smaller than you
anticipated so just be aware of that
when you get down to the NFC ones which
are the bottom to the ATA 5577 is the
most common ship that you can get from
an RFID implantable scheme so that's
what comes in the little syringe that
you can actually have implanted that one
will mimic a hit card and she'll say the
PM 410 will also make ahead card we
found that one actually in an RFID ring
that we got it was just off amazon for
20 ish dollars and since since Kevin
couldn't have his implant we got a no he
got a ring instead so we can use you can
use his ring 22 badge into the office so
reading and writing these things this is
where kind of gets very interesting you
guys ever heard and get familiar with
the proxmark so the proxmark is a little
tool about this big effect is just about
this big
this is one it's about $300 so it's a
little bit pricey
oh ok but it's what's needed to actually
write to these and if so are these RFID
chips the little thing on the right-hand
side of the screen is like kind of a
Chinese knockoff reader-writer what's
interesting about that is it's fairly
cheap there about twenty thirty dollars
but they write a password to the chip so
you have to use that reader than to
rewrite the chip the proxmark doesn't do
that so sounds like a great deal just be
aware that you're going to need that
writer in the future if you ever want to
reprogram there are ways to brute force
it because the key spaces in that big so
if you can get ahold of the proxmark or
know someone has it you can go ahead and
brute force that key out and kind of
clear that password so something think
of
we specifically use the proxmark for all
of our experiments because we had one so
if you're not familiar with the proxmark
it's pretty simple you by the device you
download the software extract the
software of course plug the products
market is a couple of real basic
commands and see if I can look at a
demonstration for this a little bit but
these are the basic commands what you
want to do obviously search to see if
you can find your card so i have a head
cart
I'm gonna need that ID off of this and
then the first thing when you get the
implant actually completed so here's
your injection needle actually get this
implanted in you
the first step is it's not set up to be
a hit card yet it's just kinda like a
generic chip so we need to reprogram
block 0
ok so to do that commands on the screen
so the proxmark has the ability to write
to the t-55 series of chips so you're
right block 0 with that particular code
and you write that a couple times just
to make sure that it's read it correctly
now it now it thinks it's a hit card now
you can go ahead and actually program it
as a hit card right so that's the big
first magic step is make sure your
program block 0 first without that it
won't work
trust me we tried for Republicans think
I'm right in saying this slide took us
about four days to write of time so it
seems simple but it wasn't at first just
a quick example you do LF search left by
the way is low frequency we're working a
low frequency range with these RFID hit
cards at 225 kilohertz so we do the
search we find a tag we get the tag ID
you'll see right there is no 987654321
then simply again we're a block 0 and we
write the actual ID to the cart right
right to the chip it's really that
simple
so you see if I can do this successfully
let's see if i can make a little bit
bigger
okay . well it's not going very well so
let's go ahead and try to program this
card now this particular rig that I've
got up here is just something that we
threw together as a demonstration
it's got a hit bad reader got off ebay
for a couple bucks Arduino is the brains
and some resistor excuse me some voltage
regulators and and switches so this card
right now is a clone of my actual badge
which unlocks the door
this badge does not unlock the doors
just a big batch right so because i'm
not actually clinically insane i'm not
going to actually program this with my
real ID I'm gonna take my reality off of
it so you'll see my real ID because then
i have to be reprogrammed and that's
just a pain so I do my let's search my
badge put it on the proxmark finds the
ID I apologize it's hard to read but
it's hard for me to read
there it is
there's the tag ID right just store that
in notepad real quick
I know how to computer so just steal
this string real quick and then what I'm
going to do is take my sample put it on
the antenna and basically you can write
this as many times as you want i
recommend doing it at least four or five
different times just to make sure that
it's picked up correctly what we can do
is do the LF hit clone command get the
ID from the last step
there it is its interests
about the proxmark is you actually never
know if it's successfully has written to
take or not but hopefully this work was
locked so I've unprogrammed this is my
passion . it is someone else's bench
right that was that was anticlimactic
so again I've got the rfid tag in my
hand just some of the things we've
observed playing with it is is it secure
is not secure the question for us
obviously if you use a practice mark
being a penetration tester one of the
things that we do for social engineering
is try to gain physical access into
organizations i see a lot of people and
I just love them when they have their
badge hanging off the belt
those are my favorite kind of people
because I can just walk up to them with
this in my pocket this kind of grades up
against them an excuse me sorry i've
captured your bad idea now I can go back
to my car wherever program me up a badge
and now i can walk into your
organization right so that's that's one
of the main uses for the the proxmark
we've tried to do that same sort of
thing with the implant in my hand we
find it extremely difficult if not
impossible to read it
main reason being is approximate works
at 5 volts because it was powered off a
USB these things are up to 24 volts so
need a lot more power to read the
implant the antenna inside of the head
card that you have in your pocket is
much more powerful so the real quick
video of us doing this and this is the
ultimate case of ask for forgiveness
because we did this at my office okay
and then we have this meeting every day
when we talk about what we did yesterday
and my co-workers like yeah i injected
Michael with this chip and our boss just
kind of looked at
like don't don't do that anymore so it
went pretty well it's pretty
straightforward process it is a little
bit of a needle poke if you're familiar
with giving blood something like that
the needles are a lot smaller
this is a 14-gauge needle so it's much
larger if you want to take a look at it
I do have one up here i highly recommend
not touching it is it's a needle sharp
as I poked myself as i try to put away
the same forgetting to take the stop out
there we go
that was fun and that's pretty much it
it's a pretty straightforward implant
was also very interesting as well is it
has actually moved around its migrated
through the body wasn't supposed to
apparently but it did there it is
insert see it right under my skin right
on the top actually an x-ray done
there's the there it is now you'll
notice the difference much closer to the
top of my hand now it's much further
down towards the center of my finger and
thumb area so it has migrated self a
little bit makes a little bit more hard
to use used to be a lot easier so quick
demo I've got that's the schematic for
this particular device if you're
interested the code will be up online
soon as I said we've got hit cards don't
work so yeah and thanks and i did a
thing
sort of a last minute hey we got a
working finally that was that and real
quick lessons learned is probably the
most important stuff
it might not work right away oh by the
way you can't you can't program it while
still in syringe
oddly enough these are medical grade
stainless steel so you can't the radio
doesn't work through this figure that
out the hard way after about a week and
it may not work right away so after you
get injected is very probable that for a
couple of days or a week you're not
actually going to read it that the hit
readers aren't going to pick it up
because all the inflammation around the
injection site so it didn't work and it
didn't work that one day I'm just like
you know what I'm just gonna try it on
the outside door and I tried it and I
was just a static because i got my
office with my hand one thing we were
just recently learning that these chips
are so small the way that the antenna is
wound and the way that the magnetic
field comes off of the hit readers the
orientation of the chip makes a really
big difference you'll notice I was kind
of controlling my hand to get it to read
because it's sort of in an awkward angle
inside my hand so when you have been
implanted if you want to have one of
these implanted make sure you kind of
understand where you're going to be
using it or in a good orientation that's
gonna be easy for you personally if i
was going to do it again I'd probably
put it on the back of my hand so I could
walk up to the door sort of like this
instead of all twisted around obviously
make sure that you get one that's
rewritable they do have read only ones
so unless you have a really gracious
employer and you can walk up to them and
say please make my ID this which not
many places do that so make sure you get
one that you can reprogram or and oh I
found it extremely difficult to find
someone to implant me I went to my
doctor I went to piercers tattoo artists
Wisconsin apparently is a very
conservative city because i couldn't
find anybody which is what we ended up
doing in my office is like I can't find
anybody my buddy's like I'll do it
ok
for smart as we are not that smart
so the big question is is it worth it do
you want one you want to do this sort of
thing I guess it depends i like it i can
unlock my office doors i'm building a
rig like this that I'm gonna actually be
able to put in my house so I can walk up
to my home and so I have a key i canjust
badge in my cup at my office right so
handy stuff people have written up to
their cars motorcycles things like that
so some of the resources the the code
the main code that I've used was off at
github by the way these slides will be
up online so i have to frantically write
down the big long urls and i'm going to
put the code out that actually runs this
rig as well out on our page just mayhem
laptop net questions I can't breathe
through their real quick but i think i
have a few minutes know if not slides
will be up online if anyone's interested
absolutely absolutely