not as good as he is armed
this talk is also not one of those make
you feel a certain thing inside talks in
fact this is the closest thing I have to
slide this entire talk is a demo i am
going to show you the tools that i use
to find vulnerabilities in android
applications but i'm going to give you a
little bit of history first how many
people here have heard me speak before
I've never been to this car like no one
here has heard me speak
this is insane okay i guess i should
have gotten out my demo so I know we'll
certainly speak but he doesn't have
raised his hand so um so my name is Bill
SEF and I'm a developer out of columbus
ohio arm i have been in the computer
game for so long that my first 30 or so
programs were an assembler I my first
significant hack was teaching an apple
2e to use two modems so that i could
dial into BBS's at the same time between
the time i got home from school my
parents got home from work so I could
download more stuff which engendered me
the handle Hydra which I still carry to
this day because i have the heads
everywhere arm i have done just about
everything in in the computer industry
but i ended up in software development
for some reason arm and I think it's
largely because I'm really good at
translating business requirements into
arm working processes and I'm a good
technologist those two things go really
well together to be an enterprise
software development but I get bored
super easily so i got a reputation for
being the person who handles the
problems that nobody else wants to do
which is traditionally performance
integration and security are there any
programmers in the room people who check
out code the morning check it out check
it in the evening that's it oh just a
handful of your cake is gonna be
interesting that arm so for 425 years i
wrote code for living arm and and that's
a bit of an exaggeration because i'm
still well I'm kind of writing code for
living now arm
but about five years ago I was writing
about eight years ago now i was writing
primarily javascript code for a living
after that I never want to write another
line of code again so I reached out to a
friend of mine and said dude finally
something to do in the security industry
because I've been the security guy on
the dev team for so long maybe I can be
the deaf guy on the security team for a
while and hook me up with the company
arm who had some projects but being
required me to move which would to go on
site which I couldn't do with time so i
ended up doing
I he said I would like to work with you
could do some testing for me and you
know i'm i'm a damn right I'm thinking
like QA like write unit tests what are
you talking about here is like not do
security assessment i didn't even know
it was a thing I've been doing that all
along i use Paris proxy 15-20 years ago
i learned to use that I i had a burp
license
I've been testing software along i
didn't know that there was a formal
process for vulnerability analysis at
that time so I learned it and um I ended
up with them kind of good at it because
it turns out if you made all the
mistakes and software engineering it's
really easy to find them and oh my if I
made all of them are in fact what got me
in the security was a sequel injection
vulnerability on a website that i had
written allowed a bunch of german
hackers to take over my buddies web
server and Phillip full german porn when
the hard drive filled up i got a page
like eleven o'clock on a saturday night
and then up spending the rest of the
weekend in his basement rebuilding the
server from scratch on that was an
interesting weekend but i wanted to know
how they got in this is a 97 by the way
so this was very early on anybody know
when sequel injection was invented or
discovered a year anybody you gotta no
no
74 on one of ems are 74 is how long
sequin sections been around anyway so
fast forward a little bit um i'm testing
applications which is is I mean for a
developer if I can't get up a piece of
code to work i end up staying up all
night fix it so that i can do . the next
day right in a vulnerability analysis if
I can't get something to our I get
something popping just going to reports
way better way to live your life so I'm
very happy there but about about past
two years ago now arm somebody called
said hey can you test the mobile
application i was like i don't know i
guess i can give it a shot
um why don't you send it over and i'll
give it a try and i took a little extra
time and learn some stuff and found out
there really wasn't much of a tool set
out there to do mobile testing and not
many people with that there weren't a
lot of people with the requisite
combination of skills and I've done some
mobile development arm and I'm familiar
with java so on the Android side was
very comfortable iOS was significantly
more difficult i'm gonna do this talk in
iOS next year if everything goes well
armed but on the Android side I I had I
had a very strong understanding of the
underlying operating system for android
which is linux arm i have a very strong
understanding of the software platform
that's used to develop android
applications which is java it with with
alec and i had a strong understanding of
application vulnerabilities analysis so
those three things combined together
made it so that i actually did an okay
job at this arm but they're still I mean
there there are some things out there
but there aren't nearly as many armed
full-range guidance on how to get kicked
off because the environment is
everything
other lots of things written down
there's more tools now there used to be
but really how the hell you get started
and that's that's where this top came
from this this i'm going to show you all
the stuff that I used to make this even
possible
um and hopefully we'll make a little bit
of sense so my name is Bill sent you to
find me on twitter i like Twitter a lot
of an ir
see person for years and years and still
am actually on IRC a lot if you hang out
on on my sec the the IRC channel on
freenode wherever it is my hangout their
arm and but I like Twitter because it's
lower barrier to entry so the
conversations little bit more global you
feel free to find me there ask me any
questions anytime about anything
security-related you'd like
so this when I say there's no slides I'm
not kidding i literally have a arm i
literally have a text file with my
outline of everything i'm going to talk
about so first let's talk about mobile
vulnerabilities for for a few minutes
arm there is a project of an
organization called a loss which was in
Kevin's talk i know he mentioned he is
heavily involved in a loss i'm sure some
other people have mentioned here it's
the open app open web application
security project mobile applications are
not web applications they are different
but they have a couple of similarities
on the primary one being that the middle
tier of ninety-nine percent mobile
applications are web services either xml
soap web services or rest in in Jason
web services on which are hosted on web
services and have all the same
vulnerabilities as web applications arm
owasp has a series of projects that they
manage that some of which are
documentation projects in some of which
are code project we're actually going to
use several of them today and one of the
projects is very famous as the loss
popped n the law stop 10 is a marketing
piece is a something that you is a
security professional can wave under the
nose of your CC little staff and say
these things are very important we need
to teach our developers about them now
it is not an application security
program and you can't build anything
with it but you can explain things with
it the mobile top 10 does a pretty good
job of doing exactly that
so we're looking for switch looking to
start with these 10 things and then go
from there
so what are the 10 things interestingly
enough the first of the ten things
is actually um not a mobile application
it at all it's entirely about our the
server-side week server side controls so
those services which do very well that
fall into the loss banner our number one
on the list
absolutely insecure data storage is m2
and that's referring to keeping secrets
on the device now there are secrets in
there are secrets is the users social
security number of secret
absolutely is it potentially acceptable
to store that on their device
well it's their device if somebody has
stolen the device you know all bets are
off anyway I'm sure that their social
security number of other numbers that
are important are stored in other data
mechanisms anyway but your servers
private ssh key for instance is not
something that should be stored on the
device the passwords are keys for
license services that the application
uses should not be stored on the device
without proper without proper army and
encryption other protection so that's
insecure data storage insufficient
transport layer protection is once again
a server-side piece this is
communicating back to the back to the
server back to the mothership not using
TLS which at this point I think we all
know that no application community /
communicating over the Internet should
do it without the benefits of TLS before
is unintended data leakage
so this is leaving data some place it
shouldn't be not necessarily secrets but
data that isn't related directly to the
the person who is using the application
had being leaked to them for
authorization authentication is m5 the
most common flaw i find in mobile
applications barn on is arm putting in
my username and omitting the password
and pressing submit and being allowed
into an application if i put in the
wrong password i get an error but if i
put in no password it lets me in this is
due to a fluke and some very common
template code that people use for login
pages for android applications arm and
it was just a very convoluted exception
management example floating around
somewhere in in the in Google
documentation the people regularly copy
and paste and if you implement it
without changing it will allow you to
log in without any password at all i
don't know if that one sample is the
reason this is my five or not but none
less than five and six is broken
cryptography this goes on both sides of
cryptography both using inappropriate
ciphers for armed symmetric and
asymmetric encryption right either via
TLS for storing data on the device and
also we caches you know using md5 hash
or something of that nature to arm the
hash something like for instance the
session that but me percent collisions
ah so client-side injections m7 this is
basically exactly the same kind of
injection you would expect talking about
a web application are either a some
nature of cross-site scripting or
command injection armed security
decisions via untrusted inputs so you're
using the headers of the service call to
make a security decision whereas i will
show you the attacker is not actually
going to be using the mobile device to
attack your services so that is a bad
idea
rm9 proper session handling exactly what
you would expect using using the users
ID as its session management instead of
a cryptographically random unique such
an identifier and m10 is really the only
thing on here that's very much specific
to mobile devices which is lack of
binary protections so this is the mobile
application itself not protecting itself
against reverse-engineering modification
and redeployment so that's the mobile
top 10 and this is about as close as we
get to guidance for testing
there is also a cheat sheet for both
Android and iOS their separate projects
on arm on the office website and if you
have to do mobile application testing
advice looking those up as well they
have more detailed advice but it's still
very scattershot there isn't a
comprehensive test plan really anywhere
for
mobile it's a little frustrating so the
first thing you're going to want to do
is have some kind of a test device
alright so in order to make a test
environment you have to recognize that
your phone needs to be off-limits for a
lot of reasons you need a test phone the
best way to create a test phone is to
create a virtual test phone in android
remember we're not even talking about
iOS here today
this is this is not possible in iOS arm
create a virtual device and use a fake
gmail account or google account to log
into it
alright we're going to do a lot of
not-so-great things to this device so
you do not you want your account
anywhere near it and you do not want any
of your personal data on this phone when
we're done with this phone is going to
be very insecure so I discovered there
is a arm emulator in the Android
developers toolkit so if you go get the
developer what the developers used to
write the applications you can press the
command key and it will pull up an
android emulator for you and it is so
slow
you can literally go to lunch and wait
for the boot on my you know octo
processor 64 gig of ram all SSD mando
workstation at home
it takes it like 18 minutes just fully
start so there's a solution
it's called genymotion genymotion is a
wonderful tool built on VirtualBox which
is an open-source son product or used to
be a son product that you're still is
armed and they have a bunch of free
unlocked bootloader sample arm roms for
phone
that you can just do area are so here
they are different versions of Android
different devices is the actual roms
unlocked so you can root them right arm
and then install things that would get
under the covers of the operating system
normally routing a phone and unlocking
it is not something i recommend doing to
your day-to-day device it makes it more
vulnerable to both malware and flaws in
the operating system because updates are
less likely to take even if you do
manually run them that's another reason
why we use a virtual device for the
majority of our testing genymotion is
great for this so we have a nexus 5 here
oops that we booted up and it's just a
normal phone
it does everything that a phone does um
it has all the same settings files
this is a surface book so i have a
touchscreen i can actually use the touch
which is really nice on my main
workstation at home have three monitors
my left hand monitors the touchscreen so
I booted up in there and I can actually
use the the gestures which is excellent
if you have a way you can do that i
strongly recommend its way nice so what
we're going to do when you when you boot
up an image like this
um it automatically sets up your arm
your your your Wi-Fi as a wired Wi-Fi
it's very strange but it reacts just the
same as a normal wireless connection so
we can for instance go in here and
modify the network
so that we can use a proxy and the
reason we're going to do this we're
going to proxy all of our traffic
through an attack proxy in this case
burp suite
you could also use that arm if you
prefer that attack proxy which is the
free like beer open-source olas project
which I probably really should be
demoing instead of birth . i do this but
I'm so used to doing burp I just do it
uh maybe we have time to look at that um
you can proxy all the traffic through
here so when we go let's do this let's
go go back here and we cancel here and
we go here we go here we load the packer
news and we refresh and there's there's
the request and response pair to a
spring fortress here's the request see
it's just a regular get and here's a
response all that data and Jason exactly
what you would do if you were doing
analysis of a web application right you
go in and you use foxy proxy or some
other add-on for your browser teach it
to use your arm your your built-in proxy
on your machine all the web traffic goes
between the web browser and the server
gets recorded by the attack proxy now
I'm not going to do a demonstration of
burp here today because that's not the
point of all this if you want to do that
we can do that some other time arm but
the the point of all this is m1 because
no matter what and it's true it's the
way I found as well most of the
vulnerabilities involved in mobile
applications are actually found on the
server side so all the same attacks that
you would do to a website using an
attack proxy like this you want to do to
their web services web services are
tricky
they don't respond the same way they're
often stateless figuring out where the
session management is it sometimes
extraordinarily demanding they don't
return HTML to you so it's very
difficult to find things like cross-site
scripting it's not
usually arm rendered in a way that's
useful also remember we're rendering on
a mobile device . a web browser so the
ability to inject client-side code is
very different we may not have access to
JavaScript then again we might so it's
it's a little bit more involved it's a
little bit more thinking than attacking
a web application in my opinion arm but
it's absolutely something that should be
done so in order to do this we need to
set up a special proxy on burp so that
it will listen on any interface i'm on
my own network up here but if this were
armed
this will open any of you could use my
IP number and proxy through my burp
right now and then your traffic would
show up here arm the reason we've done
that is because if we just do uh 2300 at
one then it its expecting that
everything is going to be resident on
the same machine right
realistically that virtual machine is a
separate machine with its own IP number
so I needed unless i'm going to go in
program every device i want a proxy from
I need to just say listen accept it
accept all except all commerce right
star except all interfaces I'm gonna
pick a different port number so it
doesn't pick up traffic from my local
machine where there might be a web
browser open with a proxy on it that
make sense to everybody
ok let's go back to the list here and
see where we're at
ok so this is why I've got these notes
there's a lot of details to this and
this is all up on my blog too so you can
go
remind yourself and also it'll be it'll
be radians recording it so it'll be up
on YouTube probably like in about 20
minutes
I think the last time I gave this talk
he actually had it up on youtube before
i was done with it i'm still trying to
figure that out i'm not certain arm if
you're on a Windows platform i didn't
get my windows speech after my window
speech next if you're on Windows
platform remember that the azure bits
that's not know not as you're ever
hyper-v the hyper-v bits interact poorly
the hyper-v bits interact poorly with
virtualbox so virtualbox is airing on
you in Jenny motion so genymotion just
as I can't do it
go look at virtualbox you open
virtualbox it's entering to go look at
hyper-v settings in windows because
every major update windows turns them
all back on and you need to turn them
off if you're using hyper-v you're not
gonna be able to do both of these are
the same time
secondly genymotion must run on the
metal you cannot set up a vm install
genymotion on it and then run android
apps inside the vm inside the vm arm it
would simply will not let you do that
tells you that like line one and
documentation so everything has to be
straight on the metal now you'll notice
i'm running windows 10 and I'm
supposedly a security analyst right and
then you know all security people hate
windows right well I don't I was a unix
guy in the day arm and I had a mac on on
system 7 and was when I would I just
really kicked off my my professional
career and I logged into units boxes via
terminal 2 to do my work but when
windows 95 came out and they started
firing by ass i said this is going to be
the platform for mid-level business
writing intranets which I was doing at
the time and pearl arm
hey I said this is this is where its at
this lightless mid-level scripting
language something like the vbscript
this is where things are going to be at
so I hold moved i sold my Mac I
the body-mind build a windows pc i
became a windows guy I went to the
windows 95 launched at osu arm and I've
been windows guy ever since so and i'm a
dot net programmer i'm still very much a
windows person but I really thought this
would be better done on linux and I have
a on the metal in Xbox to python coding
and whatnot it's much easier and
networking and analysis and stuff like
that
software-defined radio all that's easier
on the next is on Windows but I
discovered that despite what some people
tell you my experiences most of the
tools just don't run great on Linux
Android developers video isn't available
yes does it run well absolutely not
genymotion isn't available all armed
there's another tool that i'm going to
show you later called virtuous 10 that's
a decompiler and yes there are other
ones that are available for Linux and
command-line tools in you know we're
just using me back like a real
programmer arm but the fact is is that
the tools that i'm showing you either
work poorly on other operating systems
or are available at all so honestly i
use a windows box for this arm its
that's been that's been Maya my thing
okay so um the one other thing i managed
to forget to tell you was that you will
need to teach your teacher win your
Android machine to trust burps
intermediate certificate which you can
get at that it's now there's a video of
it on port swingers website i will just
let you watch that rather than walking
you through it because i always forget
where it's at and people in the crowd
have to remind me so i will just tell
you you'll need to do that and it will
leave this mark on your machine another
reason why you should not use your
personal android phone for this you want
to you want to have a test machine and
since we can virtualize not right and
you have dozens of these two it's great
and you can kill them and delete them
and take snapshots in virtualbox and its
really very cool actually don't think
advantage of nearly as many of these
things i did so are the one other tube
it is uh my fake account that i have
here is actually i also used for like my
social engineering stuff so it's a it's
a real thing account
arm and it's a very very popular word in
gmail i was one of the first two or
three thousand people to get a gmail
address arm so about my last name is
gone already
so I got a very common word and people
have used it incorrectly a lot of times
in fact most commonly my email is filled
up with these banks bank statements that
peter som something solution i shouldna
said that um there's something similar
to my email address that is a bank and
people send their financial statements
to it so i have just like hundreds of
thousands of financial statements toward
my gmail account but also people send me
messages on google talk so when that
happens I'm sorry about it and it does
happen occasionally ok so when you test
services you can exercise the mobile
application and then arm test from there
but also let me recommend another tool
to you called soap you is anybody ever
heard of it
this is a developer's tool arm but it is
a really really nice arm has a very nice
project model for certain services
apparently it's gonna take forever to
load for some reason I was probably
trying to call home
oh it's also am a spring app so it is it
doesn't do my scaling very well-armed so
you probably can't see this all but you
can just go right here and say I want to
make you rest endpoint and it will start
you with where the endpoint is and then
it will go and do its own research and
find whatever it needs to find about the
the the logic that's available and then
you can proxy this through burp and
exercise the exercising services even
more fully than you came with the
application itself so this is a great
way to get one of the more of those m1
bugs
so one thing I recommend you do if you
want to take this seriously is write
some code learn how to write android
applications because one of the core
attacks you can do methods whistling arm
is you can fire up a application learn
how it works then change the screens to
do what you want to do and then put the
application back on the device making a
a true truly like weaponized version of
an application to prove the expletive
vulnerability so I recommend you get
android studio when I do move my stuff
run again
Oh for crying out loud
ok anyway get android studio it is free
get an android developer account it's
like 25 bucks a year and it gives you
are the ability to write a simple app
get up in the store see what it's like
see what that process is like you much
greater insight into what can go wrong
and application if you know what is
possible in an application so take a
weekend there's tons of beginning pieces
out there to teach you how to do this
right some code and and and get started
alright 25 minutes or three minutes late
android has a built-in bugger it's
called a DB say time mr. yeah arm right
yeah when you fire up a Jenny motion it
automatically registers itself with adb
so we're automatically connected to with
the debugger I don't remember if the
roms have debugging turned on
automatically
I think they do arm if not you can just
go and look and turn them on
so here's what we can do then now we're
logged onto the device
this is the actual machine and were
logged into groups were logged into this
machine analytics prompt so anything
that the application stores on the
machine all of our linux toolset tools
are still going to be valid to help us
with the analysis but to be honest with
you more often than not I just pull
things down and use the tool sets
unfamiliar with on Windows but if you're
more familiar with linux you can get you
can get right in here
and do the work on the device at the
prompt using a command prompt are
absolutely key way to get things done
there is a unusual set of structure of
folders in android that this isn't a
forensics course i won't get into i will
tell you that most of the application
specific information without special
privileges the application can only
store its settings and internal bits in
seed in indy data so here are all the
applications that exists on my device
obviously most of them are that comdey
android namespace those are android
applications com google obviously as the
the google branded android applications
because you know that there's there's
android open source android then there's
Google's special android right and
that's why we have to get roms we can't
just download build and deploy is
because Google's closed a significant
amount of the winter it works and these
pieces down here are little bits and
pieces of applications that arm that i
have installed separately right so
there's your party for instance an
application that I'm working on right
now so we can log out of this and then
we can use another atb command lady pull
ok didn't get anything but that then
after you exercise your application with
download all of the settings files and
bits and pieces that that application
changed for you to go and look for in
secure data storage dig through that it
saved keys and machine is there a
password that it's using to access the
services that it's maybe hashing
encrypting locally before it sends
through but it's storing on the device
is it storing anything of the users that
really shouldn't be left on the nice
maybe something of the users thats
related directly to your application arm
anything that can be used to further
attack all of those things are pieces we
look for by looking in the settings that
the application leaves on the device now
let's say there are far more
sophisticated ways to get access to the
internals of what applications do there
are actual hardware devices the plug-in
the machines that give you memory level
bit level access to what's going on
inside the device there are also four
thousand dollars a year everything I've
shown you thus far as free so you know
you get what you pay for and it's true
that those tools are very good but
they're probably more than you need for
android assessment i know they're more
than I need framed or assessment arm 44
ability assessment and they are quite
expensive that said if you need that
level of access
that's that you can go get it does exist
so yeah yeah that's true in most of you
being security people you're probably
more familiar with the underlying linux
operating system than I am on you
probably know interesting places to go
look for things as well one way to do
things just to go get everything before
you install the application and go get
everything after you install the
application and compare the two stacks
find out what that application change on
the device i have done that before and
found all kinds of interesting things
especially if an application requires a
certain privileged from the phone that
allows it to save its settings elsewhere
give it more advanced access into the
operating system then you're definitely
we're going to want to go dig around
look but that's a little above we're
trying to do here pull a copy of the
host up so all of this said in order to
do this we need to be running this app
on our phone to get things rolling I
should have said this before but in
order to do that you're going to need
the APK alright so this is the example
APK i'm working with just for messing
around here believe that anymore do we
don't need him anymore arm so to get an
EPK now is way easier than the first
time I built this a player i built this
presentation are now there's a ton of
neat little ways to get APK that
interact directly with the store and
also apps you can install on your phone
that will get the APK for you arm and
then there's instructions on going and
finding on your phone as well and
getting it manually which were may
require doing some description magic and
stuff so I advise you the tools are
available but if you go to the Play
Store and search for APK finder they'll
did you can just download an app to your
device and it'll it'll take the APK and
put it on the Downloads folder you can
login with ADB and get it to your
machine if you're handed the APK file
okay say you're doing ok not to any of
you do an illegitimate test but if we're
going to test like a company right where
the developers give you their their
hockey account they let you access to
the hockey account and you can go
download the latest build and test that
you're literally given an APK file all
you need to do is um uh download the
application and then drag it to the
phone and it will just install
that's it and install the app armed and
secure bank right here so that's
something super simple that genymotion
gives you for free and that's so that's
how you get the APK and how you put the
APK on your device
now now that you have the APK there's
other interesting things you can do to
let's talk a little bit about the pc
test environment once you have the APK
there are a bunch of scanners out there
and they are some were downright need
arm but none of them are perfect people
are building new ones all the time in
fact i started publishing up some of the
script that I use and I get home and
hopes that one day I'll be able to
either wrap them into a larger scale
active project or roll project of my own
someday
oops you might ask my super secret
password
why not secure secure password
what the heck
wow that's new this is my cali box right
all right that was the last one
well I understand do this before I mean
I literally just had it up
well it's that is really secure don't
you know what's closed it its power of
the Machine and i'll have to be a little
bit of a pain but i'll reboot it in the
meantime let me restart it and see this
is so at any other people in here give
presentations and you know how they
always say don't do live demos and then
what fucking idiot am I gonna give a
talk that's nothing but one hour long i
am I demo I mean so but i'm a dev and
this is what I'm used to doing ok so
this this is what you get
I do have some boring with slides but
nobody likes those arm so sometimes
things are going to break and that's
just gonna be the way it is i will tell
you that that that work just perfectly
sitting over a knack for kids an hour
ago
so let's let that let's look at bootup
and i will show you the other side of my
environment so this is virtuous 10
studio so virtuous 10 studio is the Zen
reason why arm in my opinion most of the
Android tools run better on Windows than
anything else because most of the
android modders out there the people who
make modifications and skins for android
applications are 14 year old boys using
their moms old windows 7 laptop and I
kid you not that's who originally wrote
virtuous 10 with that they weren't
really 14 but I mean just to basically
kids are building a toolset to moderate
to make mods to android apps as it turns
out these tools are awesome for static
analysis of the APK files and I'm not
going to click and show you the reverse
generation process but there is a
there's a tool out there called apktool
it's open source and it's designed to
reverse-engineer arm the bytecode of an
APK into the intermediate language which
is Smalley arm and that's that's what
virtuous can use and you can do it all
from the command line in be fancy if you
want to but it is
whoo easy-to-use virtuous 10 and
actually have an ide to work with its
it's insane and again it's free you can
pay for license the only thing you get
rid of this little flag at the beginning
that says it's there and actually I
think I i paid for license and sent in
the form and everything i have never
heard back from them so i'm wondering if
they just don't care anymore what the
deal is but doesn't matter they're still
operating tools and that's what matters
to me
so once um something you should know
about the internet PK it's really like
all of these armed app type environments
it's just a zip file doesn't matter
whether you're talking about an iOS I
IPA file APK here arm a Windows 10
Universal application
they're all just zipped you can change
the extension to the IP double click on
it to open windows and then you can look
at the underlying file in fact i gave a
talk at black hat several years ago
about Europe about arm Windows 10 in the
vulnerabilities that I discovered doing
analysis of Microsoft's Windows 10 apps
for instance they left all of their arm
it's just JavaScript under the covers
right and they left all of there are
keys like to access their own weather
service's their keys are sitting in the
JavaScript files rather than using H Mac
like they should they just saved the
keys in their arm and so I mean you
could use Microsoft's Microsoft's own
key to get weather from being in your
app if you wanted to
I got a phone call from Microsoft after
that talk was a little stressful i was
sitting on my deck is like six o'clock
at cigars Scotch phone rings seattle
number
cool maybe maybe somebody's got some
work for me answer it they didn't have
work for the most important file in here
is the manifest file the manifest file
will tell you all of the privileges the
application asks for now this isn't
really a security vulnerability per se
but developers will tend to just keep
adding privileges to their app until it
works and then never take anything away
which is not only very rude
it does set you up for failure so making
sure that these things are actually
really what the application needs should
be one of the things you do arm it lists
all the activities these are like these
be pages in a web application right arm
you can then find the activities down in
the res folder arm it lists arm
ah yeah that's pretty much on this one
but there's there's other pieces that
are in there that little this certain
assets and and external pieces the
android operating system if it needs
them armed and in other stuff like that
also this is often a place where
developers will store things like
credentials arm and you need to look for
that that's something you definitely
don't want kept on the device because
this is obviously something anybody can
look at then once you get past here you
can do things like talking about
insecure security insecure arm
photography you can go and look at the
certificates that are stored with the
app to make sure that they meet your
organization's requirements for for
encryption and then most interestingly
you can start digging into the the
activities themselves the shapes of the
activity are all written in xml and the
code behind the activities are
originally written in java the
intermediate by car code is called
Smalley and that is here and you can do
static analysis of the application in
intermediate code and there are lists of
things you going to offsite you can find
list of things you can search for that
are potentially dangerous if you don't
know how the coding platform works i'll
give you some basic stuff to sit and
look 40 and then I didn't keep it up
here nope no just second so i have armed
my own framework for pentesting are some
of the pieces you searched for here and
then all the other bits that I i do
search for most of this is just out of
the OAuth cheat arm but these are the
things i start with the what 40 items or
so then I checked for that I start with
and then we go from there
uh but working in burp working in
genymotion working in virtualbox and
working the spreadsheet that's how
that's why wrap this all together into
one piece
let's see if Callie's up
there we go unfortunately how this
preset up so I'm gonna have to remember
what I did so park is a scanner written
by linkedin is on arm github and it's
actively maintained and they take pull
requests arm i know one of the dyno two
of the guys now I met want to recon who
wrote it
they're really cool and the other stuff
it's written in python and it's just a
static analysis analyzers all it is
um notice that it's qar k not quar k
that is a very different thing i have
five minutes left arm so you can tell it
you have the APK provide a path or you
can pull it off the device are you can
say this is where i'm going to forget
Eva beta . APK oh jeez temp Eva beta
okay no okay i'm not going to look for
armed the UH it will just run static
analysis a little runny beak a tool
little digest the Somali and it'll sit
and run through all the Somali code and
look for a set of pre it's just like any
other static scanner right it's looking
for pre-established patterns that
represent vulnerabilities it'll tell you
about things like arm you're you're
starting activity is unprotected
therefore any application can launch
this application which leads to tap
jacking it will tell you about
unprotected buttons for top jacking it
will tell you about um missing a
cryptography it will tell you all kinds
of cool stuff and it prints out a really
spot-on HTML report you can include in
your final analysis which is really cool
so I like it a lot on if you want to get
involved in this i think this is a great
place to put your code if you've got an
idea about vulnerability is a great
place to put proof of concept for it
there are others out there i just don't
know them all so feel free to hit me up
on twitter if you know 1 i'm running out
of time so i will just tell you one real
quick thing about this um hopefully so
sometimes you have to have a device
ok you arm have something that uses the
camera you have something that uses the
bluetooth you have something that uses
the gps and you have to have the device
itself even connected to it so there is
a build arm would see that ok there is a
android at cyanogenmod of version of
cali called net hunter and it is a
penetration testing tool kit for like
doing network pentesting so you can take
the phone in and run your pineapple up
well okay that's good . um run
uh let's see is that hundred net hunter
and then you know hid attacks . Connor
and maps can hear we can do an epic
scale on the network once we connect to
the Wi-Fi all those things you can do
right but we're not interested in any of
this
what's nice about Callie is that it's a
very secure platform upon which to put
an application on the hardware that we
can then go and test and you can do the
same exact thing with this you did with
your virtual phone you can set up the
proxy trust the burp piece arm and then
not use it as your main phone gives you
a great excuse to buy a gadget to fun
toy it works great on the nexus 4 5 6
and 7 but the phone I like the best is
the one plus one which is a
extraordinarily inexpensive very high
quality phone it's actually currently in
version 3 they only have an image for
one though I carry the three you can buy
a one used for 90 bucks and it is a
great phone still today even three
versions out arm but if if you if you if
you need to test on a device for
whatever reason that's how you go about
it you get a 1 plus 1 you install the
cali net hunter uh build of cyanogen on
it and then you are you all the same
crap to it that you did your virtual
machine you can still proxy it through
burp the traffic still going through
burb arm and then you can you there's
all kinds of fun tools you can use for
that um I'm out of time I want to be
nice to the next presenter there's more
stuff but but we go as far as we can if
anybody has any questions I'm actually
largely a knack for kids my son is here
are and if you don't know had four kids
you should just stop by and see they're
all kinds of stuff my son took them
spent the morning taking apart an old
toshiba laptop and experimenting with
the bits inside of it
I don't even know where that's going to
end up arm but feel free to find me
I ask any questions or hit me up on
Twitter of the matter hope you enjoyed
it thank you very much have a great
restaurant