that in the future when we talk about
stand it's going to include something
very near and dear to all of us
i am david schwartzberg on the senior
manager of security privacy and
MobileIron I'm also the president one of
the founders of hack for kids my running
mate could be aries out now right I
think he's in Iowa trying to also spread
the the good word of stem Christmas
drunk he's unavailable but he that you
can get him on Twitter
he's a consultant fire I and use one of
the organizers for besides Jackson in
Mississippi but like any good campaign
we need to have some kinda slogan you
know makes them great again is good but
i also think no child's email should be
left behind and they all should have
their own server
why did you just do that it did not like
graphic you guys hit something over
there
that concludes our presentation for
today we hope you learned a lot makes
ingredient right
yes every time you leave something
happens with the frequencies and the
signals all get Jack Chris he wants to
build a firewall and make iit paid for
it makes get a great again is chris is
one of the skater guys that we all rely
on so he does a I think of Bill Clinton
voice when he does that so it sounds
pretty good
what is the part you know a big Patriots
Oh USB USB USB that concludes the funny
part of the presentation so you probably
heard of stem raise your hand if you
never heard of stem before right
what are you trolling or seriouser ok
good he wasn't rolling so stem is an
acronym for science technology
engineering and math it was created in
order to help make the United States to
be much more competitive globally along
with other nations that were ahead of us
in these different disciplines
because our students our kids weren't
learning these skills and then we're
going out into the job market and they
were important really qualified or they
weren't able to compete with lower labor
costs that were international but a lot
more talent it was created back in 1997
during the national science foundation
that's where they first used it and they
just said this is what we're gonna . and
then they started to kind of spread the
word throughout education it's not just
early childhood education is also a big
part of any of them higher education as
well then you can see that there's more
and more type of IT courses but there's
also stem courses now stem doesn't know
we think I I personally always embraced
ends being something that's mathematical
technology and engineering related but
there's also the science right you know
a lot of technology it's all applied
science so keep that in mind during the
presentation in 2010
someone said you know kind of left out
our need more art so they created steam
it's a nice acronym I have nothing
against art I love art I think it's
wonderful but you know so it's not for
everyone not you can't be good at
everything right you gotta pick a few
things and kind of focus then 2014
there's a Huffington Post article which
the link is there available for you that
said now we need to have stream let's
include reading in that acronym and it
just kind of gets longer and longer and
longer and and that's all good stuff not
saying that we don't need these things
but I i want to focus on them and so
does obama obama definitely believes we
need to expand and there goes an
anti-obama guy right there see you later
good luck
the allocated millions and millions of
dollars to different types of grants and
programs in education focused on stem
and even in some cases including cyber
security which i think is also pretty
phenomenal because now there's
organizations out there including maybe
your kids school your friends kids
school your relatives kids school arm
can get these grant funds and start to
have stem programs because it always
comes down to cost everything needs some
funding and one of the things that Obama
said was going to read this directly so
don't misquote is it is an approach it
is an approach to the world a critical
way to understand and explore and engage
with the world and then have the
capacity to change the world
hmm a shine like to you hack the planet
pain so how do we come up with this idea
Chris and I we're just kind of goofing
around and some hang out or something
and just kind of joking around like hey
we need more you know hacking and
stamens I don't think of yeah you can
read that
so we try to come up with a new acronym
write and understand steam and stream
like how you put the H in there the last
time the H is silent or modify the
continent so we like how about like hi
folks out here unfortunately having your
crashed on us so we lost audio and
David's talk until about the
seven-minute 47-second mark sorry for
the inconvenience
and challenges who here began in IT is a
hobby kind of nearly unanimous except
for the apathetic person that's holding
their head in their hand that says I'm
not doing anything but sitting and
listening and leaving on board of you
the the hobbyist turned it into a career
i remember in college I was able to take
some programming courses but there
really wasn't anything networking are
tcp/ip and kind of understanding all the
switching and how that work or even like
web servers kind of started getting
stronger and stronger presence there
wasn't a lot but then go write some code
but who's going to maintain the box that
was missing
um so really kind of the idea too is you
got into it because you like to play
video games
let's be honest I like to be a gamer and
take a break for a while when i try to
find a white and started to have a
family but now that my kids are bigger I
get to play overwatch and clash Royale
with them
life is good you'll get there but the
the gaming you wanted to kind of tweak
it right you wanted to win you wanted to
beat the developers and you're willing
to do whatever you had to do on one
person that I know I'm not going to name
them buddies a big supporter pack for
kids and he's speaking about some of the
things that he did with diablo 2 who
remembers playing diablo 2 and then
there were some duped items and you
might have bought it from the auction
and then your account got deleted
yeah are you feeling the chills like I
am he did that because he wanted to be
the game and they came up with creative
ways to do items and and that was not
something that they felt was malicious
he and his brother were teenagers they
wanted to just win and they were smart
enough to analyze the code and trick
people out of their account information
and do other things he didn't quite
realize he was being like a criminal
he just thought he was being mean but
that's some of the things now he works
for good he works in the credit card
industry
he's trying to keep our daily safe and
some major cut layers and grocery stores
so
you know that's a really good example of
somebody who broke the rules but
understood how things work but then kind
of really use their powers for good
instead of evil like these gentlemen so
you got like uncle Kevin right there
he's running a big company he's sitting
on that the Iron Throne and then you got
Uncle Dave right there
does he look like a hacker to you looks
like an accountant to me would you agree
maybe a bookkeeper low-paid so now it's
become this career right so you go from
this hacking Joe to this hacking pro and
a lot of times and we all know this is
like people come up you know you're
doing it wrong
well what's the right way to do it you
figure that out or they might have a
solution but it kind of works for them
and sort of does it doesn't work for you
and that's part we want this to work for
everybody
it's really very important to us not to
mention its increasing the media right
they twisted that word that beautiful
sensual ever so important word hacker
and twisted into something meaning
cybercriminal this one article right
here it's so fantastic
it's hackers can turn your home computer
into a bomb from miles of way away how
ridiculous is that we know you can't
really do that you can turn it into a
bomb if you have physical access but not
from miles away is the questioning this
was back i think in two thousand earlier
they might still have your computers
back then but the the concept of the
media is kind of creating all this false
height there's another 12 on Fox News or
some hackers broke into a damn's those
damn hackers kind of interrupted on I
get some services for some people with
industrial controls and you know that
hit fox news write this stuff is all
over the place it's constantly in our
face who doesn't watch mr. robot
alright brave souls brave souls so I
figured I'd get your review than asking
the question the other way and in this
really stands out because you know you
saw the movie sneakers you know that
they did a really good job of kind of
showing some of the tools and how they
work but then when you watch like the
movie the net you kinda moaning groaning
like we go again roll your eyes and mr.
robot if you don't watch in or if you
haven't heard they use real tools they
really speak the language and they have
really good technology consultants on
staff to make sure that they're using
the words properly and it's not
Hollywood sensationalized there is a
reality to it were you know doing
certain things intact you kinda like all
right I'm gonna be this image and walk
away get some coffee and come back and
hope it's done some very exciting to
watch it on TV so it takes 10 seconds
that's no you got to do that but they're
the reason using real tools and commands
it's actually pretty actually really
amazing if you haven't seen it highly
encouraged but it's important so that
the kind of the message there is now you
have somebody who's got an interest for
their hobbyist in IT and now they watch
mr. robot and they download set and they
do phone call text message and they
trick somebody now their hacker right
you can answer or not but no not really
not really they're using a tool so the
important part there is as a community
we need to make sure that these people
who have an interest really start to do
it the right way it's kind of obvious
but it's easy for them to do with the
wrong way and then just start to make
the community not look so you know
aboveboard and again like the whole work
shortage on CS online they put an
article out 0% cybersecurity
unemployment there's 1,000,000 jobs
unfilled now I know some people an IT
that are either looking to switch jobs
or
they're just an employee is theirs so
unemployed people out there for whatever
reason they're not able to get a job and
it's unfortunate considering that
there's a million unfilled jobs so now
you think why is that
is it them is it the qualifications like
way up here
I remember on somebody gave the talk in
Chicago about how I think I think Ali
was out for a year and one of the
requirements on the resume was minimum
five years cali experience possible
I mean maybe they meant backtrack right
but it goes to show you that the people
that are creating or defining
requirements to be qualified don't
understand them
how do you reach their expectation if
it's unrealistic so um speak with a geek
swag they were out in Vegas during
infosec summer camp and they were
interviewing a bunch of people and how
do we solve this problem how we gonna
fill these 1,000,000 on positions that
are out there and i encourage you to
create a bit ly because they're linked
was like ridiculously long but i
encourage you to check out the video
it's a few minutes but it um the the
answers that some people provided i
don't want to spoil it for anybody there
somewhere like really good and others
were like the answer was I don't know i
mean almost kind of metaphysical their
philosophical right now how we gonna do
this I really don't know something to
think about
now let's talk about the kids for a
minute because well they're a big part
of it
we're all hackers were pretty much grown
up i see that there are a couple of kids
in the room maybe teenager college
students but the younger ones think back
remember when you were to you ask your
parents why a lot and even when they
answer your question you asked why again
and you kept asking why until the elder
you
yeah couple of people snickering they
just naturally want to try to understand
things
and and that makes him really good
hackers they also like to question
authority
no one of my mom got three boys / kid 0
kid wanted to to being the youngest so /
0 he likes to be very persistent when we
he asked for something and then you say
no he asks again we say no when he moves
on to the other parent and same kind of
experience so he's his persistence kind
of taught him a little social
engineering so he would not even ask my
wife and come to me and say hey can i
buy that that purchase inside of clash
Royale I'm like well you know we don't
really like doing that with your mom say
I'm trying to play the game back on here
oh she said ask you don't need to check
there because I don't think she would
have said that so you know the they get
clever they're trying these little
things and these are the same kind of
tricks that we use if you do physical
pen test to get into a building or get
information from people who are calling
them up on the phone
very clever he's on he also did another
one on my wife he took in our house got
all kinds of screens but do your
homework you can go on screens you get
grounded
do your homework you read a book or
something else you don't get to go on
screens and my wife would sometimes let
them borrow her iphone well he won hate
when he was allowed to be on screen he
noticed that in order to register his
fingerprint required passcode right with
touch ID and what happened was um he had
to unlock the phone and was messing
around in there and then said mom I lock
the phone again can you please type in
your passcode she's got a very technical
person so she just was like sure punched
it in $YEAR and registered his finger to
touch ID
so when he got grounded he crams her
phone authenticates and he's on his
screens and she's like wait a minute are
you grounded how'd you know anything
yeah so you know from figuring how the
technology and then a little social
engineering he got his bonds that was
the motivation and the incentive and
with a little bit of knowledge he had
success so they're pretty innovative got
plenty of these stories but I don't want
to make my life look too bad this is
being recorded so um kind of going back
to some other stories right there was
this 15 year old boy played his dad's
xbox and you know if you use Xbox
nowadays right you gotta log in and kid
was home dad was at work had the control
just mashing the buttons
he seems like fuzzing the xbox any
perform like a buffer overflow which
then got him in and its really cute
because this video attached to that
website with the news like ya gotta play
the games he found a ball and xbox and
his dad being an IT reported it to them
and the kid actually got credit because
if you look through the release notes
you'll see you know like instead of like
a research kind of lab or something it's
like individual and it's this
five-year-old it's pretty cool so
there's there's the desire to get
something at any means and will try
anything to get their kind of part of
the hacker mentality right i have
another one for you it'll be audio work
that's you going with me
09 count
ok I one front nine tail is it ok to
share your password people
I'm sorry just say yeah yeah it's okay
to share pasco to people that was kid or
/ kid to use two years old back then we
took the video i thought was just kinda
cute at the time but it actually dawned
on me some days later little slow that
this is a systemic problem or should a
systemic problem scuze me he can't read
he can recognize numbers he actually
just started speaking kind of regularly
of you maybe a couple months before that
but he knew the pattern to unlock the
ipad or the tablet because he wanted to
watch videos or play a game goes back
again motivations and incentives that
was his reward
so he memorized the pattern but again
you know he's too doesn't quite
understand you know I'm
stimulus-response or consequences or
risk or any of the things that we learn
about to protect data so he thinks it's
fine
yeah anyone can do this is great
fortunately there's nothing on there and
it took us about two years them to
change the passcode because he didn't
want to do and we didn't want to make it
hard time you know difficult from to get
back in there but now and I think this
is really cool is he understands he does
look when we change the passcode
no one knows it but you know kid too and
myself
he won't even tell my wife so you ever
want to have fun with your spouse it's a
great way when you kind of start to get
the kids to do things and they don't
want to share and they start to feel
like all but it's important part is he
now gets it he's getting that this is
something it's just for codes keep it
simple but he's gonna continue to mature
and understand the important
of us importance of a secure password I
to stuff with scouts and I teach them
it's called the cyber chip first thing
we cover is good bat passwords and
badass words let's go over that and we
covered by the time they're done they're
coming up with some really strong
passwords that they can remember some of
them are a little too ridiculous but you
know use the word but a lot but it's
okay i don't know if it is but in the
dictionary i think it is so still
dictionary attack that one now Chris um
in my running mate his son also very
curious and does some really fun things
he learned how to use scratch scratches
a MIT project for kids to write code
name
Lego kind of block style UI and if it's
a syntax error instead of it going
together and throwing an error it
actually won't let the pieces connect
and then those values and variables that
they can modify so Christmas son wanted
to make a pong game so he builds pong
game and when he does it
he's like well every time the ball gets
hit by the paddle make it bigger gets it
on the other side gets bigger until take
off the screen and play a sound and
change colors and you got this like
psychedelic noisy cottony going on and
chris's was like what the heck is going
on in there and that's kind of fun the
other one was like kind of make the
paddle smaller and do all these other
crazy things right instead of just I
have a game and this is the game and
that's it and I'm gonna play it this way
he's changing it is making his own he
wants to see what happens when he goes
beyond the boundaries being a
nine-year-old this was the night the
title of the app apropos but hey we're
no better
there's all these organizations i
mentioned some before that are focused
on stem and hoping that they adopt stem
with a nature stem or something like
that and in fact for kids which very
near and dear to me came about and it's
not a unique idea there's other groups
out there is like DEFCON kids became
with this island that was kind of I
guess the switch that one off in my mind
like yeah we need to do this as a man i
live in chicago in the Midwest because
it was all very west coast focus and
those had kid and san jose and if you
don't like the silence in Las Vegas as
well we have to bring it to other people
too so why don't we kinda like partner
up with other conferences like no lacan
he's fallen asleep you go and Kirk on
and do a hack the kids with them and
we're actually doing one tomorrow so
that concept and we've done other like
Detroit other areas well kinda get ahead
without the Belgium were also doing one
in were working on 21 Toronto next week
so this is really taking off and it's
great but there's also like interrupt or
cyber boot camp which might be near you
you should look into those so there's a
lot of other is a lot of different
programs and there's a lot of i should
say there's some online programs and the
one caution that I have to offer to you
is when you look at the price and you
look at the education that the student
would be getting you got to see if
there's value because some of them are
like two hundred fifty dollars for a
year just to learn i think some basic
like intro to java it's nice to give you
like $MONEY a year to do that but is it
really worth 250 dollars you can buy
yourself a nice book for forty fifty
sixty dollars and have that perpetually
it's just me
unlike that I'm accountant by original
education into itune cybersecurity but I
look at the value of those things but
that's kind of an important message is a
lot of these organizations are doing
stem with an h today and you should look
for one near you that I tell you some
more stories so again a cricket's being
near and dear to me I can
talk directly about some of the things
that we have seen there and i'll tell
you about Bob so in $MONTH 2015 we did a
hack for kids in indianapolis now Bob is
14 years old and has an interest in
computers and plays games just kind of
like we did and kind of internal use
other apps and wants to write some code
but when he came in and showed him the
room maybe quarter the size of this one
he just kind of looked around and he saw
this sign on the wall is it crypto
corner because i would check this out
what is this is sitting there and he was
learning about converting binary and a
64 and some other like a location
ciphers and stuff like that simple
things you can do with the computer and
it's done in seconds but he was doing it
by hand we had eight challenges there he
didn't leave only that spot the entire
day even when we went on break
robert wagner right there is a board
member of hacker kids we go to lunch and
we came back in $YEAR bob was standing
outside the door waiting to continue to
let him and he SAT right down and I'm
getting chills thinking about this but
it was amazing because this is somebody
who's never done this before and found
within himself a passion for math that
he didn't know existed
it was fun and I think what ten makes
this story even better is when i emailed
his father say oh we know what about
think of hacker kids but yeah you know
he said it was good have fun so apparent
right my kids go they do something they
go to camp or but I was it would you do
nothing would you learn nothing nice
talking to you but that's kinda like you
know that's the parent-child
relationship sometimes and that was what
happened Bob and his dad so I wrote this
email explaining everything is dad about
how impressed we were with his focus and
dedication to solving these problems and
that we've never seen anyone do this
before
there's something inside
him that you should nurture and take
further and his father . but gobsmacked
I had no idea i did not know he like
this so much thank you
alright this is what we're trying to do
for changing lives slowly but surely in
bit by bit but it's also that communal
effort right um so then Bob's dad said
we're going to hack the kids in Chicago
and he was asking you guys gonna have
more of these challenges and he said
yeah we're going to make new ones we
actually did one in Arabic are best for
him
ok only two people got that over bitches
the language from Star Wars there's a
translator online if you need to know
the story of it briefly when you look at
the first Star Wars movie and that his
character scroll up they meant
absolutely nothing but somebody
collected all the characters and made it
into an alphabet and we use that as a
way to create a secret message and gave
Bob some more fun
so since then Bob's been 24 have four
kids and we always intentionally do new
things for him like a 3d printed board
in Braille so he has to like figure out
the Braille and kid loves it so that's
the story Bob so that is the story of
Alice now so you could appreciate this i
have to give you a little bit of
background about Alice we met her this
year and besides Detroit where we did a
hacker kids there and what her her mom
told me was about 12 and she came from a
background of her biological parents
wanted was an alcoholic and other one
was a chemical abuser
so for Alice growing up certain things
that most kids have like expect for a
luxury so she had a really rough start
in the world and eventually she went to
foster care and her adopted bomb who i
met the gave her some time to kind of
adjust and get used to going to school
regularly and all those things and then
she started to show more of an interest
in computers so she said I've never had
a hacker kids and we're likecool
so she did this super robot contest now
this is somebody who's never done this
before never took the controller on the
easy for controller and then build a
robot and then battled it against other
robots after kind of doing the R&D and
the tweaking on the power and the speed
not only does she have a great time and
learn more about herself she took first
place she said she got first place and
she got a $25 gift card for that because
of that mean think about it
her life is changing $25 to a kid might
as well be a million right it's not much
to us but it's a ton of money to them
and then she did our online CTF where
she got involved with some crypto she
did some of our simple and coding and
even some of the more complex and coding
and you might think well she probably
got some help from mom and maybe she did
but one of the things that we really
focus on communicating with the parents
is not to be like that helicopter parent
kind of overseeing to make sure their
kids successful by doing the work for
them
not judging but there's a lot of parents
that do that we use a phrase it's very
simple
do you want time or coaching and we let
them being controlled what happens in
those next few minutes and if they want
more time you step back
they want some coaching we give them
some hints and suggestions and how
they're approaching the problem so they
learn well she did really well with the
crypto she did really well with the
information-gathering which is like
being a pen tester
she also did really well with the
lock-picking she got all the way up to
from a single pin lock to a 6 pin lock
and the handcuffs so she swept the
lock-picking challenges them all and
then we also had am a badge challenge
which once live this badge had a secret
message scrolling across that was in
Braille and again some coaching in time
for her mom she was able to figure it
out and she got that when the other ones
were kinda tough but we just wanted to
see what you know what they know and how
far they'll go and it was really kind of
cool because you know she's all
like excited that she was doing so well
in the super robot contest and you know
you can get that prices so she gets
first prize for that at the end of the
day and then she tied for first place in
the CTF that was really cool of course
at that point she gets to pick of all
the different prices we have the table
what she wanted and she went with a
conic it so now she has her own small
personal computer at home right doesn't
need to use your parents pc or laptop
for mac so these are just a couple
stories I could tell you more but you
know you can see if you haven't gotten
chills i didn't do a good job I've been
getting chills telling you the whole
time I'm kind of pad kind of told you
some of this information already so i
might just skip it but what kind of
impact we making so since 2014 we
started doing this we had 40 kids at our
first Chicago event and then since then
in $MONTH 2015 by the end we had about a
hundred 115 kids in all the different
for events that we did that year and
then including up to the last three not
tomorrow we're at a hundred and
sixty-six and we're hoping between all
the events we doing October will be
changing another hundred lives for the
better
now what happens after all this what's
next well as they get older they could
become mentors after they learn how to
be mentors from us we should be their
first mentors we also should be teaching
them leadership and and what does that
mean does that mean yelling at people
and what they're doing wrong
what does that mean hey I see you doing
something i did before to in coaching
your time and let that person who needs
help be led by kid who's already been
down that so many other things that
we're doing like just different activity
stations like raspberry pi talk about
the crypto we've done stuff with a
Python for kids so thank you no starch
press we have permission to use that
term that or that title of the book and
they always donate books to the events
for us to give the kids so one of the
prizes we give aways a virtual minecraft
server so if you can get this
book two company that learn to program
with minecraft like a win-win right they
got their own server they can write code
on and then we do this ETFs and that's
the URL for the server it will be the
server's up with the game is off right
now we're going to turn it on tomorrow
morning if you want to feel free to make
yourself an account poke around even
answer a couple questions but it's
really for the kids so in there they're
like you know let's just say answer them
all you get the most points i'm not
gonna give you a prize if you're in
adults but if you're a kid yeah so but
it's open we're very focused on on
inclusion we don't want anyone ever feel
like they can't do anything or benefit
because they're probably some adults
that might take a shot at this and go
man some of these are hard and actually
a couple of them are really hard
we just want to see what these kids are
capable of doing you remember the
Reading Rainbow you know if you ever
read 2600 and $OPERAND people like
writing the letters i love the letters
hey I'm gonna get the hacking what I do
we read some more when you get tired of
reading read some more when it hurts
read and when you're bleeding out your
eyes keep breathing
it's like you don't stop and and that's
what we want to do is that kids are
learning through videos in youtube in
some ways it's good in some ways it's
got to remember to read to and we need
to be that role model like crack open a
magazine or a book and read the books
maybe with your kids if they're not too
technical if you could get your kids one
of the kids programming books or
something and do it with them and when
they see user using see you using the
books they're going to copy you keep it
hands-on we already know that it
reinforces the knowledge but don't have
them read a chapter of a book and then
go do something I'm trying to see if i
can get kids 02 become a plus certified
and the first thing I go is booked a
thousand pages let me know when you need
help i made a huge mistake she read the
first page goes I don't know what the
heck's going on in here I can't do this
so we're we're having a plan now we're
going to go through paragraph by
paragraph we did together
what didn't you understand let me
explain it to you you want to see what
that looks like it's in my basement in a
bin it's got dust on it but you can
still see it and then using that
methodology will reinforce it and I'm
hoping in a year or two that you know
before he goes into high school will be
a plus certified released stretch goal
for that's the best case before he
graduates high school to be a plus
certified so we can even get a job and
you know make some money in college and
then the community I mean we're here
right
we believe in the community or trying to
there are some people out there that
make it difficult but we got a shrug
them aside focus on what we know is
right i meant to say this sooner but I'm
going to tell you were all mostly
technical people here so you probably
never heard of Russell a cough
he's a well-known economist he said and
the paraphrase when we do something
wrong right the wrong girl we become
what we do something right wrong
the writer we become it's okay to make
mistakes if you doing it the right way
there are people that tell us in our
industry were doing it the wrong way
without coaching or time to do it the
right way we need to do it the right way
wrong so we can get better at it and I
think we are a little bit but we kind of
all pulling in different directions kind
of bring it together and then mentorship
i mentioned this before but i don't
think i can mention it enough we need to
mentor one another and we need to mentor
the next generation
otherwise they're going to be inheriting
all of our problems that we've created
all the problems we can't solve and in
some cases these kids are becoming
really lazy because if they don't get
that immediate gratification that a
problem solved
they lose interest we like what we do
because of that gratification
we need to show them it might take time
but you'll get there
don't give up
another little case study so i talked to
mainly you know what we usually do stuff
as a kid 717 but what about these other
kids kind of going to college so we
approached me on the Internet
not too long ago and said hey why don't
you guys start up like a scholarship
fund to send some kids going into
college to DEFCON sound like a good idea
kind of tweeted about it some people
didn't think it was a good idea but
meanwhile right in the heart of DEFCON
his roots asylum
it's not a bad thing it's a good thing
but sending some kids off to you know
how all the things and drink all the
booze drink all the booze and have all
the things you have to drink enough you
say backwards
um we didn't want that and we didn't
want them to be there to think that for
their parents to think that were we were
encouraging them to be cybercriminals we
put out a application and the responses
we got were from students who were
leaders in their school they were doing
things with extra activities some of
them were active in sports some of them
were playing music and a lot of them
were all like focused either an ITR
infosec or both as a career
so one of them that really kind of stood
out the most everybody reviewing we did
like a double-blind review right so
you're not familiar with that term the
reviewers they get the information they
don't know who they're revealing and
they don't know what each other saying
about the individual people being
reviewed nobody can influence anybody
and this one kid he not only is like
rockin it in high school is also an
Eagle Scout he would you familiar with
the program that's a major
accomplishment he was also on active in
cyber Patriot so the first year he
joined he was on the team figuring it
out the next year his team I think
placed third and then this year he was
the captain of the team and they took
first place in their national division
with cyber Patriot I'm getting chills
saying that I'm so impressed by this kid
and he was cool to hang out with you
picture you know the teenager just kind
of full acne and glasses and Matt agree
see here was actually pretty fun to hang
out with him we were doing stuff and
kind of going around then you're
introducing them to different people in
the industry and they had a great time
and everything rolled up their
experiences and we're kind of reviewing
them we want to scrub games for privacy
reasons but were going to release their
experiences publicly so that you guys
can see that people because without
people making donations to this and and
providing the funds we could have sent
them have never been a Def Con this year
the band was 240 dollars and to show you
my dedication i want to CTF and guided f
combat didn't donate directly to this
because i believe that was important and
not that you know gave me but it's like
you gotta give you gotta give and you
get back lost you guys yet still there
there's a lot of challenges right now we
know that hacking is viewed to be
something negative in in the media light
the more we do to make that different
even if work we're doing it right but
wrong will start to get it writer
there's a lot of lack of funds and and
maker spaces and hackerspaces like I
know from Christian giving this
presentation with me in Mississippi
there are no hacker maker spaces around
anywhere for him he was saying that his
libraries are just gonna start to get
funds for 3d printers which i think is
pretty cool and that's going to get kids
interested in doing this stuff and just
even things in rural areas so there's a
role tech fund website if you want to go
and make a donation but none of this can
happen without some kind of funding
little bit helps and even measuring
metrics I tell you these stories but if
I never see Alice or Bob again we don't
know the actual success level we reached
with them we do take surveys we do track
their progress especially stuff online
with the CTF but it's very difficult
wheels
teach things like auntie cyberbullying
how do we know if they reacted the way
we taught them when they were being
bullied online or if they properly
diffuse the bully picking on someone
else rather than being a participant in
laughing along because they don't want
to be the victim
it's nearly impossible to measure and we
send out surveys we always send out
surveys after the events we do get some
good data and commentary for people but
it's a tricky thing more reporting
baselines this is kinda some of the real
dryer stuff in the talk with we're
thinking of doing some more of this
online because when you're online you
get a lot of metrics you can see
information about the person in their
private profile like their age you can
figure out for example if they try to
challenge and didn't finish it right
somebody goes with the lock-picking
table
we're not watching they try to pick a
lock and a walk away we don't know if
they tried 10 seconds or 10 minutes
right so they might have needed more
time more help but if you're online
doing some of this stuff you can see
exactly how long they tried or oh wow
they're going through this really quick
they really bright or someone else doing
this for them so you get a lot more
intelligence and none of this can really
be done without you folks we need to
remember is my political campaign that
makes them great again and it's the
community
you gotta participate you don't have to
sit down at a table with the kid or
somebody and be a mentor but maybe talk
to some people in your area that might
be more comfortable about just small
things just maybe having a meetup and
like in your house whether like you know
maybe one of the other parents are doing
it with you kids just build a box
install linux in the cloud get a
raspberry pi and learn how to unbox it
will turn into minecraft server all that
stuff so in conclusion this is very
exciting and in time very exciting times
and there's a lot that's emerging super
exciting because we're part of it and we
as a collective our steering its
direction and it's always something
emerging I mean I don't want to go into
IOT you know you
don't know about what's going on there
and autonomous vehicles to make the
nervous kind of cool but scary at the
same time
what are the risks well until we have
one we don't really know how to break it
but there's sure there's some weaknesses
and these these small changes in their
life make a huge lasting impact if
Alison Bob I hope they come back and be
a mentor had four kids because it's a
great story continued like the value of
like Steam and stream remember art and
reading is important but you also want
to include hacking there's still plenty
to do and on a final note you know how
we need a theme song
so instead of up you know going to drink
all the kool-aid and we're going to have
all the things
oh yeah Chris college so get out your
ballots check for stem checks them off
with an h remember it's important that
you vote this year and makes them great
again thank you