good afternoon everybody
thanks for joining me it's a great to
see that i won out over the beer and the
food so thanks for joining me
oh yes people brought their beer in the
room so yeah we got the part covered so
I cool so thanks for joining me we're
gonna be talking a bit about how do you
get started
what do you do if you're in the middle
of your career kind of post and really
kind of why cats started this is I went
through a lot of kind of I guess so we
say reinventing the wheel learning how
to do these things first time and
there's a lot of difficulties that I ran
into that I think that if I'd known it
would save me a lot of heartache pain
and time and really what it comes down
to is first off this is about you guys
this is about me so I'm gonna be sharing
information about my pass but truthfully
what I'm hoping is that you guys are
gonna come away from this with the idea
of figure out how to avoid a lot of
mistakes that I made
I also think that is a community it kind
of strength of this all because it's not
really about having a one or two guys
that are just kind of like those ninjas
that really just figured out a bad asses
you know what kind of call on them when
those problems i think that the more we
are strengthening the community you know
we just reunited and stronger in general
you can have to help each other out you
know and also inspire you guys if I can
have you guys come away with just one
thing that helps you out from this
options kinds consider that a win so
kinda helps to start like Who I am I
mean it's are you guys know I'm just
some guy up here giving a talk so I
figured it gives a little bit of bad be
kind of a little bit of help kind of
like a background about Who I am what
kinda gone through and whatnot before i
start saying hey you should do these
things is from advice standpoint self so
i guess uh oh yeah by the way so I love
moving around and the fact that i'm
tired of this kind of driving me nuts a
little bit like to engage more with you
guys and all that so I to bear with me
also my heuer I don't mind trying to
intend to offend anybody so uh but i try
to do in contact so just keep that in
mind
so by the oldest marry whomever is this
movie
alright who actually remembers when the
movie came out hey not much your hand
so I know this until years later but
apparently when this was on TV my
parents said I was always glued to it I
was like 23 at the time but i had no
idea years later i'm doing hacking but
who would have thought so who here
actually knows what a record player is
ever seen one
okay cool alright for those of you who
haven't ever seen a record player before
I promise you there's one in this
picture but I kind of grew up being that
kid that was really kinda just be
exploring creative and all that kind of
self and my sister had this like a
record player one time and i promise
she's not in this picture so and it was
one of those types that uh I guess you
had something plug in the wall and some
that didn't but I'm thinking our
whatever just a record player you know
it's got a motor inside spins you know
music comes out of it as you love this
thing she'd played like the same like
winnie-the-pooh record all the time on
it one day I happen to be going by and
I'm like there's a light inside that
record player and I'm like oh my gosh i
need to figure this out something the
older brother i'm kind of going hey
Heather
there's a light on inside that we should
figure out what's inside there of course
being the fact that I'm her older
brother and she's been through the stuff
that ripped apart before she's only
going on the defensive freaking out you
screaming the mom to protect a record
player
unfortunately at one point you know she
did pretty good job of protecting it
until one day she left it unguarded and
leave those to say that they go into
pieces i just find out what was inside
there
so anybody in here want to give a gastar
to what they thought that light was that
was inside the record player back
youtube exactly so yeah that was kind of
my first at least when I remember my
first time actually really going into
stuff figuring out how stuff works and
ripping apart the thing never worked
again i'm sorry to say it but whatever
so later along who remembers these
things
ok I'll if you've never seen these
before what you will really want to take
notice the fact that there's no
grounding plugs on these and as little
boy someone thought it was a great idea
to give me a whole bunch of these and
I'm thinking how can i tinker and make
these things you know have fun with it
so I'm in the basement one day and I
like three or four these things i plug
them together so that this long little
line you know stacked out for each other
i got nothing to plug into him just like
playing with them i plugged into the
outlet and
thing and all right well what else can I
do with this I happen to have this new
little nightlight and the old two-prong
job I'm like hey i can plug it in the
end of that and you know I'll have
something that actually works
I'm pushing it in there it wouldn't fit
because you know these things were
really exactly designed to be like you
know unified standards and my finger
slips and the next thing i know i'm
coming to you like 10 feet from the wall
i'm going what the hell just happened
and just trying to take it all in then
the headaches set in and I think it's
because when i flew across the room I
smacked my head on the concrete and I
just was like oh my gosh what the heck
just happened so I had an interesting
life childhood growing up so there's a
somehow I survived my childhood I don't
know is a miracle and I started doing
coding and magazines at some point in
the past when magazines I don't even
know what magazine it was but they give
all this kind of cool qbasic code and
whatever and you can program in whatever
so I haven't had one of these things
growing up called a TI 1994a and that's
a you know the exact thing right there
and by the way I can't believe I think
my parents must have known that rip
stuff apart because more recently I
found another identical copy in the
exact same shipping box and everything
I've never been touched so I think
they're expecting me to rip apart the
first one and have a backup for you know
when I damage that oneself so ya gotta
qbasic started programming with that
stuff and who remembers this stuff
yeah here who's in the audience yeah so
there are two really big games that I
think I'll launched with qbasic i think
it was it was on my computer at least as
guerrillas and nibbles and the gist of
it is uh it's kinda like tanks and worms
nowadays but you got to gorillas and you
put into out angle velocity that you
want to throw bananas at each other and
they explode when they hit your detonate
on the target and whatever it's a fun
game wherever i realized that i could go
into the code and change the detonation
of the the bananas so I was playing
around one time and I got the detonation
so big it basically wiped out the entire
screen so you think like a chocolate
tired hard to explain what i'm talking
about it but it that was the first time
I realized I can start playing
manipulating self that already existed
and I worked
this is fun i think i've had probably
cool is that I'm like literally like you
know like 10 years old he comes home
secure copy of borland c++ in your
compiler I'm like sweet
I fire this thing up and I didn't know
what the hell to do it all I didn't
really have any guidance i'm like no
other program stuff I had no idea what
like a main function was all this stuff
but it's just incredible opportunity
that I feel like I just a little bit of
guidance
looking back I I don't know where I'd be
today maybe i just would be an
antisocial person completely because i
was between writing code but you know
it's funny when you look back at your
life and you know some of those
opportunities that are either became
something or didn't based upon like
nurturing so I mentioned that to say
that you know if you have kids or you
see other younger people just giving
them that little push to make all the
difference in the world except i've been
able to just write one main loop or just
a little bit would give me that like
that foothold to kind of take the next
step in the next step
oh yeah okay cool alright so then is my
life can continue going on a kind of
them . start doing a lot more tinkering
in developing by this point I was
ripping apart computers and this is back
in the days before that you know even
had the UH we want to call it the the
color coding on the board so you can
easily reversed in and hook up things
wrong all that and then there's one time
where my own computer was down for some
reason and my dad is like hey I've got
this laptop i used for work you should
use it to do your your school project
Edward perfect 51 or whatever it was
like alright sweet and uh I don't even
know if I actually did the report what
happened to go inside of wordpress and
realize i can open up all these other
files
well i found that there was a calm
command . exe file that can open so open
it and we're perfect and of course it
was gibberish and made no sense and I'm
like oh I must get out of here but I
must change the character to inside
there because uh uh as soon as i exited
it gave me this message on on the
command line basically saying please
insert just system disk or hard drive
and I'm like all crap so I reboot the
system is booting and in the first line
please insert system disk to continue
home like a whole crap
fortunately i think i had a system this
floating around i stuck in the system
didn't like that it was stuck in a loop
like consistently my dad was not happy
it cost over eight hundred dollars you
get that thing fixed
I still don't even know how to fix it
because it was you couldn't get to a
command prompt to get into like install
so he never let me touch his laptop ever
again until like 15 years later and then
of course she's coming to me for
everything to fix his stuff so yeah
funny how that kind of looked around
yeah exactly like dad stop stop asking
me for help but yeah actually I should
have had like a built-in mic i paid a
hundred dollars back man i'm done so so
later on I mean again I'm still around
like 12 years old I got ahold of IRC in
again I don't even know how this
happened but it really really changed my
life
um a lot of stuff I didn't realize until
i was putting this presentation together
to realize what really happened so I'm
like whatever
somehow I got on some IRC channels and I
found myself in that channel that was
talking about hacking and I think a lot
of these guys were probably college and
t1 lines because i'm on my you know
epica 33.6 baud modem you know people
are sharing files it was pretty cool
because i think it was my first real
experience kind of connecting with the
culture but up met some cool people too
and I don't even know if there was new
was a kid or not but next thing you know
I'm like yeah hook me up with all this
cool stuff and I'm getting myself mail
bomb on AOL so basically in short a
one-point had a limitation on the amount
of files that you can our emails in your
mailbox and they just flooded me into
this day I don't know if they're trying
to like you know actually mail bomb me
or be funny because they send me
everything i had everything from like
AOL hell all these like crack passwords
things I was my first exposure to uh was
it the Anarchist Cookbook in the
terrorist handbook or something I forget
the inversion of man you're 12-feet like
this is the coolest of avraham
explosives so the disciplines you know I
get tones awesome fun stuff and I'm
thinking I got 336 modem I don't know
what to download and I'm like oh Duke
Nukem so i just downloaded do can i play
that all the whole time instead of
taking advantage of all this other cool
stuff that I had really known you know
from tools her hand so basically alcohol
was a pro
MW two Friel access you just keep
generating new accounts that were good
for 30 days i think there was something
that allows you to school for to pretend
to be like a system administrator or
whatever it's lots of fun stuff but
again i had no clue that the wealth of
knowledge with my fingertips of course
then this came out it still holds a
special place in my heart you know I
don't know why it was you know that the
hacker culture all that are in fact that
Angelina Jolie was anything that was
right on that certain age and of course
also really would change my life to you
was goin to Beaver in aliens and of
course Victoria Secrets oh yeah alright
so going post-high school that's when I
kind of started my first business and
I'm thinking all right I can do this I
got this yeah I can run my own business
starting my own things solo started out
doing a lot of just building computers
writing software programs Microsoft
founded transition into doing more like
blue team defense security too but I
didn't really know what I was doing it
was just kinda like self-taught self-pay
alright so let's use ssh you know let's
just do whatever we can encrypt stuff
for communications but this was just
stuff that I can learn is my own there's
really no formal training with this at
all
I finally got a bachelor's degree in
computer science finally I say that
because working full-time and also going
to school doesn't work well on your GPA
really panic takes a hit so if i if i
should look back on that I think that
kind of really focused on my degree and
I'll kind of explain why on that a
little bit better later but was also my
first real experience to realize that i
could do hacking is a profession and it
was just so incredible to me taking a
graduate level class it was kind of a
stripped-down CH of semester class but
it was incredible some like oh my gosh
I've been doing this stuff have been
having fun but people get paid to do
this stuff so is it really excited me
and it really kind of help leverage me
or push me for my career but going
through school they really they were
really giving you any kind of guidance
truth be told like even taking the class
a practical you sign up waiver to make
sure that you are going to use this
stuff for malicious behavior
at the end of the class the most
dangerous thing we did with you like a
port scan I'm like you guys got to be
kidding me
but it still gave me the tools and that
in the end enough direction figure out
where to kind of go next and kind of
brush after that I was working with up
with a software development company and
they did a lot of web hosting training
programs and then we're going bankrupt
and I was like hey all right I've run a
company before i'm going to start a web
hosting company and i'll just take all
the clients sit back easy money i don't
have to do anything but maintain a
server and i'll let you know that didn't
really work out too well as i was hoping
and I hey
yeah whatever but the good stuff that
came out of it is that I got to see a
lot of real real world at taxes they
happened and they're coming to me asking
me for help
so there are some sites that had a lot
of high-level traffic on it and they
were well these people weren't exactly
designed you know but try to keep the
code safe and all the stuff so they come
to me for help so it was a great
opportunity to see in all kinds of stuff
in the wilds just play with your kind of
reversing reverse-engineering exploits
seeing bots watching them actually
behave when instead of being in a
controlled environment i'm going to
watch the school stuff happen at the end
of it realized what I really don't want
to do was really not system
administration has really pushed me
forward more to kind of go on that tax
out of it a little more that arm
I don't remember where exactly was in my
career realize but protecting people was
really everything to me i don't really
know what that revelation came in but I
started really shaping that driving for
my future is going to that kind of
continue insulting but its when I really
started connecting with security
conferences i think Kirk on was one of
the first conferences I ever came to and
I I know I kind of keep saying a lot
about a game changer and stuff like that
and it changed my life but it really
made a difference and then was really
fun as I started dealing with criminal
cases two people kind of doing hacking
and getting involved that that's so kind
of falling start work on the Michigan
cyber around 2013 that was awesome
because I gotta do a lot of heavy
development writing computer code but uh
the thing about it was I was little
write code that was doing offensive and
defensive stuff too so building tactical
exercises helping people playing a game
environment so
you got the typical here this type of
exercise you get the red team and the
blue team they're doing self but
someone's gotta make an environment
right so this is about building that
stuff up so people complain it captures
the flags uh training of writing custom
malware roocase bubble all that kind of
stuff but then leadership this was my
first time really getting exposed to
being a position where I've got a guide
and direct stopped because the projects
we got so big that I could do stuff
anymore so we can't really kind of
miller team bigger and all that so oh
yeah by the way so i'll shout out to you
don't know if they're in here not but
figured he was shot out i love working
with them over there it realizes but I
actually happen to capture a photo of
them i work on time and forget to share
this with you guys so damn hard work at
the office so and then most recent
venture this is incredibly just stare at
it forever so like what is going on here
so I the most recent venture started a
company called vector rock and then
focuses on during testing so it's kind
of getting back to my roots in helping
people make their their systems a secure
yes i'm kinda quoting myself here but to
me securities a whale life it's a
mindset and heart set
it's not about saying alright you know
this is this is just one piece of facets
everything is really encompass you and
become really who you are you kind of
eat and breathe it so who in here a
throw to questions that you guys hear
what you guys think to shout them out
what the the greatest challenge is for
security professionals in our industry
right now
ok ok so I actually tend to go and I
actually look what a little introverted
with us that ego is actually greatest
challenge and I think that more for
ourselves because we're gonna get stuck
in our comfort zones we like to stick
with what we know we feel that
comfortable there
you don't necessarily to be wrong and we
just feel safe there so until we can
overcome our egos yeah it's the same
question what you guys think the top for
reasons other people get into cyber
security
water break stuff
curiosity technically challenging jobs
yeah I so these aren't necessarily in
any particular order haven't done any
research on these but this is my
experience of what i've seen so the
first one actually has money have you
guys seen a lot more people are going
wow there's a lot of money in this
internship i'm gonna dive into it and
get the big bucks second curious they
want to explore be creative understand
how this stuff's working just have fun
I think that / protecting people you
know kind of like police you know we're
trying to do it daily our dealers keep
citizens safe i think there's people
that get into this to protect people and
cyber also again we come back to our ego
power over others
so if you don't talk about with this you
don't really get the relation with this
think about when you go into a
conference and he got the security guys
and their the you know at the conference
doing security and walking down the
hallway like yeah I'm awesome
get down off there get out of the way
whatever they're not there to
necessarily protect people keep people
safe if they're there because it gives
them a sense of power so that's why I'm
that I relate that who are industry as
well so so that I've code totally kind
of trash on that a little bit of show
hands here who is considering becoming a
security professional in the process of
building that and kind of going that
awesome cool yeah weather on the tech
side of the policy side so i figured to
give you guys a little look into what
what this might look like for you on a
daily basis if you're going on the
technical side of that so that's kind of
close but I think it's probably more
like this
yeah right sighs you got the red team
and the blue team smacking down the
defender of death kill here
yeah yeah flying around our blue guy
gets angry
what is going on it's angry writing
guide take that Alright yeah so now if
you're going on the the policy side of
the house I forgive you guys a taste of
what I think your daily life is probably
going to look like so if you haven't
noticed I'm more of a tech guys in a
policy guy so he's about right now thank
you yeah it's okay moving on uh I am
going to focus a lot more on the text
out of it is policy side is more my
background is what i try to who as far
as what I could remember the time air
down the different areas where I think
that people can really pursue sorts of
areas of hardware hacking application
hacking networking encryption physical
security social engineering i think i
might be couple others but I think
social engineering is a huge area that
people overlook because we focus so much
in general about ok i hack this
application or that that it's really a
big need and in our industry because
what's the weakest link in security it
alright so i think the biggest misnomer
that we want to make sure that if you're
coming into the industry gotta realize
is you don't have to know anything
everything there's nobody that knows
everything and truly it's impossible
that shouldn't be something that you've
got to feel afraid about or that it's a
challenge that you've got overcome it's
just a reality try to figure out where
star right well you look at those
different areas it just just pick
somewhere just start having fun to start
playing there's no really no wrong way
to do it
so even example for me I i started
actually want true hacking when i needed
i started playing with Wi-Fi networks
when I was living somewhere in needed
internet which which by the way I found
out later
I think it's still the case that might
be that hacking wireless access points
in the state of Michigan is considered a
felony
I don't have a phony and don't worry but
I was like oh my gosh wow that would be
helpful to know you know little while
back and then I started doing
application hacking as well but it
really comes down to learning the basics
the more you understand how something
works the better going to be able to
hack so take wireless for example if you
understand what frequencies these
wireless networks are talking are how
they communicated the fundamentals is
going to help you break anything better
understand how these attacks work you
don't have to reinvent the wheel either
i think there's this concept of people
get out there like all right well I'm
going to build a program are going to
write a port scanner but why there's
tons of applications out there unless
there's a particular reason with
something exists
don't waste your time you something
that's already out there don't feel like
you've got to improve yourself for
making . start with what's out there and
build off it so some ideas of things you
can do with that reaching out to peers
other people in the industry's other
people's research even classes after
taking that class at a college and I was
like alright just whetted my appetite to
figure out more i knew was based off
that certified ethical hacking class and
I went out and took it that helped me
just get a broader of knowledge of all
the different areas to help me get
started even more because if i try to do
all the stuff on my own it would just
been a waste of time to a certain degree
but we try to go with this you know what
to what end it would you want to get to
you
what are you shooting for with your
skills in any kind of particular area
well i believe is this you want to get
to the point where when you're looking
for information trying to solve a
problem you know googling it is going to
be futile because you know so much about
it and the problem that you're trying to
solve the so complex that you're just
not going to get any kind of hits the
best example I could think of to share
with you guys was i was working on
building a solution one time that was
pretty cool because we had several two
computers that have to access the same
data up really high speeds at black
level without having to worry about
overriding each other and stuff but if
if one system was accessing it we want
to make sure it was locked for the other
people so I ran into something called
gfs2 global file system too
and it was a lot of fun it was open
source stuff started playing with it but
that was a point where I just all the
problems you know it's it was one it was
so kind of under the radar that people
didn't know about it that you really
kind of had to just figure the stuff on
your own so it was taking other people's
stuff figure out how to tweak it fix it
and play with it that's really where you
want to get but again you don't have to
do in all these areas just pick an area
that you liked it loved it just kind of
run with it
we're trying to get you to the point
where you what I can think outside the
box so on think i did have another good
example of this but the idea being or
something is meant to use in one way and
you figure out all right well I can use
it this other way
what helps with that is one feeling that
you know you can just have the freedom
to try and do whatever you're not
constrained you're trying to do
something the wrong way you know it's
okay to make no mistakes and do
different things but also that it skip
my break I always think outside the box
is a good thing
also one time I was at the conference
and i ran across this guy that was
talking he seems like an incredible guy
I'm like oh my gosh i need to get this
guy's advice up to this day I still
don't know if it was really good advice
or not but you know this is a hacker and
get up sharing all the stories I going
to afterwards like do tell me what I'm
just starting out what do i do you and
he tells me to go get an MBA that was
very confused like this why would I go
and get a masters of business
administration
I still haven't solved that one yet but
i figured i'd still pass that on because
when he might have an idea or light bulb
moment with that so shifting gears
interpersonal skills i believe that
that's something that we majorly majorly
overlooked as an industry I think it
actually can make or break your career
makes the difference between if you end
up being the guy that you know with this
stapler down in the basement nobody
wants to talk to al vs the guy that's an
STI soo the company number one thing to
listen I don't think we listen up at all
once heard someone say or share that
when people are conversing back and
forth are having a debate
the person is listening to the guy
that's doing the talking spend more time
trying to think about what he wants to
say and refute next to the guy that you
know what the guy that's talking stop
talking so i think if we were to step
back a second and actually listening to
what the other person says that not only
you come across a better listener but
you know you you feel that there's more
of a dialogue you can make progress in
your conversations are also difficult to
process feedback from others a personal
example with this is actually kind of a
painful one
i started working with this business I
came in as an engineer like level 2 or
whatever and I'm just like yeah I'm
awesome you guys are noobs I don't know
what you're doing and I was promised to
do security work with them but i ended
up doing some some simple application
stuff with them and i'm just looking at
some of these guys going why is it
taking you three months all this when I
can do it in a matter of days and as a
result i started burning bridges i
started alienating people they turned
out a lot of the project managers want
to stop working with me simply because
you know I'm remove it
ensure i thought I was better for with
everybody as a result that didn't end up
well and i ended up losing my my my my
project and work with them but looking
back you know i had so i could either
gone to one one of two things i could
either said all right well you guys are
stupid on whatever or i could said
alright what actually happened here and
what can I learn from it so that's what
i'm talking about this this uh
processing feedback and kind of like
with self reflection on stuff to figure
out let's focus on the problem or a
let's face it being willing together and
learn from it so some thoughts with this
could be facing the same problem again
and again and again when you go into a
meeting you say something people are
giving us our looks again and again
chances are something that you're doing
and you want to look into that
so if you're having issues with that
figure out problems talk with somebody
you trust ask them for feedback but also
don't shoot them down if they give you
the roster opinion to go forward looking
at communication i couldn't think of a
shorter way to put that one down on the
slide there but what did i do if you all
the information in the world
but you know how to communicate it
somebody was trying to help somebody
let's say you know that somebody going
down this way you're building a program
this way is bad
well if you can't explain to them Howard
batter wise bad well you're not being
effective you're not really able to do a
good job with that maybe I really care
about that maybe you're just having a
debate with somebody and you know you're
right and somebody else is wrong if you
can't communicate that concept is
somebody again uh that's not helpful in
our industry I think we've got this
concept everybody's really good
technically but we talk technical right
and then we talked with people and
non-technical that non-technical they
just don't get it i found that there's
this is it's just like a rate of what
black a better way to put it people will
pay top dollar if you're able to
communicate technical information to
non-technical people in ways that the
understand it is like gold also proved
yourself or with your worst people in
interviews you know I mean you're worth
something you're worth value and you've
got to be able to convey that or
convince people of this also getting
that raise and promotion if you're not
able to communicate what you bring the
team how are you able to take that to
the next level a good story that one
time I was interviewing this guy and he
got to the point where we brought him
into the office and we want to see how
he's doing still I so you know he
doesn't mean all that but I start
talking with him to figure out all right
well do we want to bring this guy in how
does he does he work out and he started
going off like a new seals car salesman
and I'm like I you know she might have
known as stuff he might have been
actually good but during this interview
that way use cumin conveying
communicating really he didn't sell
himself at all and we enter choosing
somebody else so building connections so
we talked about what you know your tech
skills are talking about interpersonal
relationships up for yourself but i also
want us to focus on building connections
in the end that way with with people
around us so well why you might ask the
world is much bigger than you realize
what you know is very small compared to
what everybody else knows
think about it if you as you been here
listening to other people other people
talk before just before here there's
John
one up you're talking about defeating
those capture systems and you know when
you listen to people talk about their
engagement in their different talks
unless you spent the same time that they
did on the stuff you're never going to
hear about it so incredible uh you know
when you really get yourself out there
and you realize how how much is out
there at the same time the world is a
lot smaller than what you realize to and
what I mean by this is over the past
couple years is that going all these
conferences around the world you start
to see these same people that's
important because you gotta realize that
you think our communities really big but
in reality it's really small last thing
you want to do is burn bridges because
you know you make one guy angry and you
might be looking at the project you want
start working with it but he knows you
and he tells me no don't go with this
person because they're jerker whatever
with the same time you got a good
relationship with that person and
there's a couple people that are trying
to get this project and because this guy
knows you and you know he trusts you you
say hey i know this is a person to go
with you should go with him
I'm I brown-nosing to the point where
you're trying to suck up but you're
getting to know people on a real level
really connected with them to make a big
difference also Goulding snowing solo
doesn't cut it did that for many years
of you waste a lot of time a lot of time
with that web hosting company i spent a
lot of my time running invoices and
stuff like that that sucks i want to
write invoices I sure our patch updates
on servers one thing but you know you
want to focus when your passion is not
responding to people's emails asking why
their emails watching can't really
respond to people's emails saying why
their emails are now but you know
communicating with people who want their
problems are with their servers or they
do next
it's not you know you waste your time on
these little things instead of focusing
on what your strengths are usually
doesn't end well you know I spend what
two hours trying to make an invoice for
a template that somebody could do in
five minutes
they're five-minute was probably better
than mine and what i do i want to use
theirs and it is wasted and something
that looks kinda like crap and it's like
I said inhibits you from focusing on
what you want to do because really at
the end of the day you only have so many
hours that was actually probably the
biggest lessons I learned working with
Michigan cyber inch
is that you know you only have so many
hours in the day if you can work with
others and collaborate with others
amount of stuff that you can do
potential eyes is just incredible also
burn out
been there done that sucks not cool as
much too with the fishes average i learn
more about collaborative and
collaborating and communicating working
with the Michigan cyber range in those
two to three years at all 15 years of
the I think of past work experience
putting that together because I was not
doing things on my own I was willing to
go places that feel uncomfortable having
conversations were difficult just push
myself to that the actual limit
conferences obviously you're at a
conference you get the whole conference
think that's a great thing that you can
do to start leveraging those you they've
got them all over the country i think so
the ones at least come to mind right now
you got whatchu con of course eager con
um shutters Snow about besides Der Beek
on death was a dot-com yeah black hat
you got you know b-sides Las Vegas all
these three conferences meetup groups
even your local area great way to meet
people start connecting all that stuff
this is probably the biggest ones
letting your ego who in this room has
issues letting there you go go
your hands yeah right yeah those guys
not raise your hands they want to like
let your ego that you have issues with
your you okay cool so I think it's the
first challenges are being able to admit
when you don't know something kind of
challenge but i'd rather work with
somebody that can admit that they don't
know something and somebody friends
pretends like they know something i
really don't just mean you respect I'd
much rather work with that person I can
respect to work with its gonna be honest
with me and the guys just going to
pretend that he doesn't really know
what's going on I think it's also hold
two because when you're able to let you
go
able to get past those hurdles of
personal things that are preventing you
from going forward so
alright let's say you're not really good
medicine . but you pretend to be well
until you can admit that you're not
really going to be able to kind of go
that area and kind of get better or you
know in certain areas we just you know
don't want to go there because it feels
hurtful in our existing we kind of feel
sensitive at so that's kind of where
we're talking about that it's also you
know it's helpful to make friends you
know you let you or you're gonna be able
to make more friends more personal
because we all know you know there's
nothing uh oh I want to file together
there's nothing harder than trying to be
friends with that person who basically
thinks they're better than everybody
else so I was also thinking too I think
this may be the first time ever is a
never ending first time anybody's ever
quoted a Bible verse in a security
convention but as a ok whatever I like
this especially pretty good so it goes
go to the animal sluggard observer ways
and be wise which having no chief
officer ruler pairs for food in the
summer and gathers for provisions in the
harvest
how long will you lie down the sluggard
when will you arise from your sleep a
little sleep little slumber a little
folding of the hands to rest your
poverty will come in like a vanguard in
your your need be like an armed man
alright so what are we talking about
with this thing first always talk about
setting goals for yourself you want to
dream big if you don't really start
going anywhere or kind of have some plan
to go somewhere you're not going to get
anywhere so all right so what goes look
like are so mine
world domination right so always a
little kid I'm like yeah I'm gonna have
some huge company that's so big that
I'll be able to kind of take over the
world you know and yeah I don't think
upload making it their can check back
with me in 10 years and you know be like
told you so
so the goals don't be afraid to take
risks
I think that it stops us a lot of times
where we don't want to get outside again
of our comfort zones truthfully making
mistakes are ok
I give you permission to make its
mistakes is completely okay to make
mistakes don't let that stop you from
moving forward think about like this if
someone told you that you're going to be
a multi-millionaire but first you have
to go through a hundred mistakes when
you lose everything
would you rather have all those hundred
mistakes in the very beginning at once
would rather stretch that over 20 years
pretty obvious right i mean wouldn't you
wanna make all the mistakes first and
then live the rest of your life you know
is this multi-millionaire so it's okay
to make mistakes because it's going to
help you get farther help you succeed
and progress faster so this is
incredible i actually tie myself that
this is going to be like a 70 minute
presentation so I went faster and now
it's much more than I expected
so before I actually are ask four
questions I want to take this time to
kind of we're not this time already
leaving here don't you think about these
things to reflect on first take time to
invest in yourself it'll pay off
you really don't have to know everything
you really want to get outside his
comfort zones and lastly you know here
to dream big
what kind of questions do you have in
the back so invest in yourself great
question what do I mean by investing
myself so I'm talking about taking the
time to instead of you know maybe
playing video games at home you know
when your off time that you're spending
time doing research or just spending
quality time going into these media
groups doing things that are helping you
get your goals so if your goal is to be
somebody that's may be awesome in Python
well do stuff that helps you know spend
time doing this Python classes come up
with reasons to program stuff in Python
did I get my MBA no i did not get my MBA
yes you tell me the first four yes let's
go back to that not the victoria secret
one
I wish man whatever the world that will
be my backyard
yes
yeah that's a great point so on so for
those who who didn't hear that general
sharing about his experiences he's been
in the industry for what 30 something
years
yeah yeah and we're discussing arm the
motivations and yes 2.2 I think that
once you get entrenched in this industry
and become more about it that those
people that are really successful
they're really focus on the areas of you
know the curiosity and kind of
protecting people the money kinda flows
with that but uh I find that people that
are just getting into the industry their
motivations the people coming in just
for the money or that power trip they
really don't succeed you know they kind
of get a wall and maybe they got to make
a choice
where r is the money the motivation
because we know at some point that's
just going to leave you know you see in
every industry after X amount of years
it's a high point but then they kind of
gets out I think for us it's going to be
a while because the fact that there's so
few people that really have good skills
in that regard up but yes yes I think
that's my point with this is to say that
be the person that is curious and want
to protect people and the rest will come
flow naturally
ok so the question was regarding our
building up your skills and yet there at
some point in the future these automated
skills skills will replace us
that's why I think interpersonal skills
really make all the difference because
at the end of the day some of the
attacks do change right i mean we're no
longer using d common watch I guess we
are still using decom exploits to take
over this windows boxes that haven't
been updating like 20 years but yeah the
the concept of the attacks to say the
same although the specific attacks do
change so uh I think that's why
interpersonal skills are the most
important because you can keep up with
it
the deeper you understand stuff you can
translate it and explain all that stuff
that's happening but do I really think
we're going to ever truly be replaced by
automated tools i find that I find hard
to believe in this is my reasoning why
humans make stuff right and another
human figures out a break it and these
automation tools are built by humans and
it's an arms race just like back in the
day you know we went from sticks and
stones bows and arrows swords you know
huge machines of war an hour talking
about doing attacks over a the ether
it's an arms race so there's always give
me that battle kind of going back and
forth so someone can always build a
better whatever you know office defense
so the question was up if you're looking
at getting into social engineering where
do you start hiding involved so thank
you for bringing that up because i was
firing through my slides because I was
concerned we're gonna have enough time I
skipped over in an important point
personally I believe that are women who
are trying to get into cybersecurity
have a huge one up maybe probably a 10
up over guys especially feel the social
engineering how many people want to see
a guy a girl have an issue say oh I'll
help you I'll give you what you need
so I think they're just as now
so inherent sensitive when they're
looking to get in cybersecurity attack
that own that you know that's a great
way to get started getting into cyber
security because what 99% well I don't
think that's a little high but not
ninety percent of all the people in tact
our guys
yes of course we want to save the day we
want to get that date whatever you know
so going back to your question yourself
because you're obviously not a woman
unless you are in
ok so I how to get started with that
that's a great question because
personally myself I haven't done a lot
with social engineering
I know there's a lot of workshops in
places i think at DEFCON where they do
social engineering itself one of my
co-workers was sharing me that I think
it was this past year the year before
we're in real-time the social engineered
comcast and got the guy at comcast the
tech I to not only give all this
personal information away but give the
browser that the guy was running the
version of internet explorer of the
flash plugin that was running and
everything that he needed
oh and convince the guy that that he was
going to send a PDF that he needed to
open with information so uh it was
incredible how people are able to kind
of T this up but I don't that helps you
so there's resources out there is place
the sicko
I don't know if I really can answer that
too well
oh man ok so what type of burnout have
experience of what can i do to prevent
it
so i'll start with preventing of it
first and i think that is realizing what
your limits are realizing that it's not
all on you and it's not your problem to
solve
realizing that working together as a
team makes all the difference in the
world
so when I first start working with
Michigan cyber range just before first
engagement we there's three of us and we
did 36 hours straight nonce one day just
because we want to make this event go
off and they're still all officers
challenges of stuff we needed to deal
with being able to sit back and say
alright let's plan this out let's let's
figure out how we can all do this skill
wise and let everybody go and I try to
control everything and make sure that
it's done the way I wanted to was a huge
game changer for me in other areas where
everyone's bitcoins all that right yeah
okay nobody raised your hand while no
one knows a bitcoin is alright well
anyways so there's these virtual
currency stuff that's floating around
and I was huge in that scene for a very
long time
uh there was some hacks that happened
that I pulled it and I jumped in and I
want to kind of help save the day and
this is also while working full-time
doing stuff with the missions average so
I even took vacation time off to
basically stay at home and code and work
on the stuff and again I was this is all
about my ego truthfully and putting this
on myself trying to get it done
not really sitting back and saying you
need to relax you know it's it's not
something that you have to solve and
come in and save the day on so i think
the biggest thing was just realizing
what your limits are
that's you know again you only got so
many hours in a day where you should you
really spend your time and trusting
other people
haha why not Bitcoin anymore well in
truth I was involved since I think
ownership like that at the end of the
day the community is a community just
left a very sour taste in my mouth
they always assume people were thinking
the worst that everybody's out to get
them and you know there's a hack came in
and I'm like all right i'll come save
the day I'll help you know Gotye it's
like three guys one was like in Brazil
you know there was another lens of is
around the world and we're trying to
make this stuff happen and all the
feedback we got was negative negative
negative negative you know you guys are
scamming you guys are lying all the
stuff so i just got a community so any
last questions we're gonna wrap this up
I will thank you very much for your time
you guys have been a great audience
hope you have a very rested