hey everybody who that's loud
thank you for coming to my talk so I'm
gonna go ahead and get started I guess
I'm so this is so you've inherited a
security department now what this is me
my name is Amanda or info sister online
i've been doing blue team related things
for about ten plus years I've worked in
healthcare ISPs higher education but
bunch of different places doing you know
jack of all trades sysadmin network
security that kind of stuff
hmm so the the premise of this talk came
i had the idea about a year-and-a-half
ago I had just started at a higher
education job walked in and they had
absolutely no idea what security was and
and just the frustration that comes with
walking into a place like that and
having to start a security program from
the ground up
I mean the other engineers their new
about security too but nobody outside of
the three or four people knew or cared
about it so I wrote a blog blog post
about you know this frustration and like
all right well there's so much so much
you can do for free that so many
companies aren't putting in place that
maybe you know it would be good to write
something to give to somebody that was
in Mike my shoes walking in that didn't
really know where to start so i started
working with O'Reilly and this is
is a book that I'm writing with Lee
brothers didn't and he's out of Toronto
and he he kind of has been in the same
boat right he's he's done consulting for
a while a lot of lot of like linux admin
stuff like that so I like all right well
all these things that we know to do but
other people don't maybe we'll just you
know consolidated all put it in a book
fill a gap that's out there so this book
was born
it's not it's not out yet it's not
printed but it's on its way it'll be out
in March it's broken up into three
different categories we have the free
and easy things that we can do and this
is how that this talks going to be
broken up to
so free and easy free and not so easy
and then all the expensive shit that you
do afterwards so I'm going to read you
part of a quote that i really like so
many attacks on the internet and network
systems have no particular target the
attacker simply sends a large broadcast
a large broadcast that uses any
unprotected system as a staging point
for to launch an attack so like botnets
shit start using computers without basic
protections like firewalls antivirus and
user education not only affects your own
business but many other businesses as
the virus is spread on the internet so I
mean fix your low low hanging fruit you
want to be more secure than the next guy
just make it that much harder
so step one work with your stakeholders
you're not going to just walk into a
place or start a new security program
and not tell anybody you could it's
probably not the best idea you can
present your research so work so with
those stakeholders so you're going to
have you know your dba's or people &
finance or sea levels you
all you need some kind of task force or
team or group of people that you need to
let them know how important security is
right
otherwise it's just going to be you in
this massive sea of not non-secured
environment and you need you need a
group behind you
tactfully explain you're not gonna walk
up to them and just start ranting and
raving about you know the status of the
network your you you need to present it
in a way that they're going to take that
information and be able to do something
with it around you know after you've
done that those people are going to be
able to work with you to create a mock
create milestones you know project plans
whatever just to kind of get the ball
rolling and then you're going to let
them know how much you can do for free
that isn't already being done
usually you know see top sea level execs
really enjoy it when you can tell them
you can do this stuff for free and
you're not walking up to them and asking
for a million-dollar budget to do what
you need to do so I'm a huge proponent
of asset management it nobody doesn't
management right like if I if I could
find somebody that knows exactly what's
on their network and we're please let me
know how you've done it I've not found a
single place that that knows what's on
the network there i mean i i'm really
anal about that kind of stuff so i would
want to know you know if if somebody
plug something in my network i wanna
know I wanna know what it is I want to
know if it's ours or if it's you know
something they're bringing in from home
you can't protect against what you don't
know
so take-charge there's i'm going to go
over a couple different things you can
do for asset management that are free
and most people don't want to do the
asset management themselves so it's a
good opportunity for you to do it in
your own have one source of truth
there's I just talked to a company that
we're trying to find out how many
endpoints i had and whether these other
domain controllers were like well we
think we have six domain controllers but
we also have this other domain but we're
not really sure where those reside
well we have this list over here in
sharepoint and then we have this excel
spreadsheet and and I don't have access
to that sub domain so I don't really
know if those are how many DC's on that
one
that's a problem I mean you're your
domain controllers or something that it
should be really high on your priority
list to secure right so have one source
of truth don't have you know the
spreadsheet in the sharepoint and then
whatever you need to keep it all
organized visibility into your network
that sub domain you know know what you
have visibility into if you don't have
visibility to it that's fine you just
need to know you know if if it's another
company whatever you know that that's
stuff that needs to be documented and
then automation you don't want to have
to do all that stuff manually and don't
forget the cloud not just because you
know your websites hosted somewhere else
doesn't mean that you're not responsible
for the security of it
you're late and there's a lot of
different methodologies for asset
management that are out there this is
one of them so assessing planning and
implementing so let's start with the
free easy no sense to open source
intelligence e this is free right this
tool is pretty cool it'll tell you like
all the different websites are our
software that's out there that you can
use to do person do it on your own
company
you can do this if you're I mean if
you're looking to move jobs right i
should have in hindsight done my
research on the company before I took
the job because they had was it like for
/ 16 and all of them are on children
you could see their printers you could
see their sequel servers like all
accessible from the internet that kind
of stuff that you do you can do
beforehand or as you're working there is
also going to la help you out with asset
management you know what can the
internet see that you have now you can
see what your public-facing technology
is so filled with will actually show you
what your websites are made out of right
is it running Apache is it a microsoft
server running is that kind of stuff
freakin ng another two free tool it's
like multi go so multi go is a a really
really fancy super expensive tool that
you can use to well find that ocean out
on the internet about companies people
whatever reason angie is free kind of
the like metasploit so he run different
modules little print your reports but
it's all coming online as opposed to the
gooey but it's free it's pretty good
tool the harvester a Python script is
included with Kelly you can just
download it individually i actually use
this put together a user education by
fishing at the healthcare healthcare
organization that I work for this is
going to scan facebook google linkedin
whatever for all email addresses on your
domain super easy for an attacker to run
this against your domain and Bumi is a
list of email addresses that he's going
to target those are probably going to be
the people that
you're gonna need the most user
education because their email addresses
are out there and you know that with an
automated tool like that you don't need
to even put any thought into it a really
good defensive mitigation our way to
monitor this kind of stuff is you know
if you have a public-facing web site put
a honeypot email address somewhere on it
right just some random email address
that you're never going to actually use
nobody's gonna you know email it on
purpose right monitor that email address
and you can know when people are are
scanning your website trying to you know
actively fish don't you don't have to
worry about you know customers seeing it
and you can always put you know it in
white text on a white background
nobody's gonna actually see that when
they when they browse to your website
the skin automatic scanning tools will
pick it up you can also do like um like
fake linkedin account stuff like that
shodhan was created by John mad early it
does like pretty much scans for a good
amount of things that are out on the
internet on unnormal ports so I think
he's up to like 40 or 50 ports maybe
that he schemes for automatically across
the entire internet if you're working
for a place and they they know that
showed it is scanning them I've had
people say all right well we just want
to block all the show an IP addresses so
it doesn't show up
okay great that I mean now it won't be
unshown but doesn't mean anybody else is
not going to scan you
it's still you're not you're not fixing
anything you're taking information away
from yourself that you could be using
some more free easy stuff that you can
do get a trial vulnerability scanner
vulnerability scanners can be expensive
depending on how many and points that
you have and how often you scan that
kind of stuff if you want to prove the
bang for the buck
go ahead and get a trial first scan a
subset
network scan something that you know is
probably insecure and there you can give
the report to those top executives and
let them know hey we have all this stuff
let them know the free stuff that you
can do more stuff that will talk about
to mitigate some of that and at the end
when you realize that you need to scan
the rest of your network or have ongoing
vulnerability scans you'll have all that
information about back you up when you
go to actually ask them for some money I
best practice group policy objects such
a huge windows nerd for a while I did
you know that make it
mcitp I did going back to me being super
anal about things I actually printed out
15 of our group policy on pieces of
paper so i could cross-reference citizen
and make them all like my idol redesign
it all so that was that was a nightmare
but if you're if you're creating an
image or you want an already locked down
group policy so you don't have to go
through all five thousand settings that
are in there missed . gov actually has
group policy object like templates that
you can download you can put them you
know locally on the machines you can
import them to your active directory and
and so you don't have to build those
bikes from scratch as few as possible
domain admins how many places I i said
in Dave Kennedy's talk in great . you
know the whole whole fucking helped us
his domain admin that that I mean they
can pop up box just like that because
they're not supposed to be using that
domain admin unless you're doing domain
admin ahead you know activities with you
know you know anything get taking those
permissions away is difficult sometimes
we had a lot of like application support
people that just had domain admin
because it was easier you can install
their software they could run a service
as it and everything would just work
right but it's not definitely not the
best idea i'm getting rid of open chairs
so their scripts out there I'd like
everybody write this down so yeah that
will scan your network for open chairs
another thing that you know if you have
an open chair out there with any type of
data is a huge vulnerability right and a
vulnerability scanner will necessarily
find this this is from net and map
there's on that was you know there's
also one written in powershell that you
can do some more frizzy disabling telnet
and other insecure protocols there's a
lot of devices seem like old Cisco
devices old mainframes that kind of
stuff that you can't you absolute you
can disable tell me that they don't give
you an option for ssh alright so if you
can't disable it you can switch to a
more secure protocol you can alert on it
you know with with I mean spunks not
really free but there's you know other
other pieces of software that you can
set up that will alert on the login / /
that port ensure web logins use https so
this was a public-facing firewall I did
the SEC tf2 not this defcon at DEFCON
before and frontier was the company that
I had to find all those and information
on all of their f fives were HP there's
like 30 or 40 of them throughout the
united states that we're all just plain
HTTP located locate and destroy
plaintext passwords this-this-this talks
full of horror stories that I've
efficient and encounter
a the place I worked at the healthcare
organization when we first we got our
first pen test one of our network admins
had all passwords for the organization
in a password-protected excel
spreadsheet
ah so they had domain admin within five
minutes
no open Wi-Fi same place we gotta i was
actually working at the helpdesk at that
point got a call from a lady and uh her
Wi-Fi wasn't working and it was part of
our job to you know go up to the patient
room help them with whatever device they
have trying to get them on the on the
free Wi-Fi
well that Wi-Fi had no password no way
of authenticating you whatever turns out
that she was on the next street over
using our our Wi-Fi as her internet and
she just wanted to call and let us know
that was down $PERCENT disabled ports
that are unused and setup port security
i did a lot of network stuff for a while
one of the biggest pains in the asses
were we're turning off all unused ports
we had no idea of knowing what ports
were being used unless we physically
logged in each each switch and you know
did everything manually
well there's a net think it's a couple
slides ahead abroad program called net
disco that you can actually set up and
it will tell you what ports are being
used with the last mac address was on it
that kind of stuff you don't want
somebody to just be able to walk in
plug-in you know sit on the floor sit in
the corner or whatever and boom there
now on your vlan1 that you probably have
all your servers onto so disable ssl
that's a no-brainer
so thirty-three percent of all https
servers are vulnerable to one of the
below mentioned
manam exploits so artfully poodle the
block one you can use ssl labs to see if
your websites are vulnerable for it and
not necessarily mean you don't just
worry about your external websites you
don't worry about your internal ones as
well and on alaspin Sands has you know
different tutorials on how to disable
and switch to TLS right for whatever
type of web server that you're running
so centralized login so you don't want
one of your network admins to leave and
have to go and delete their account on
all of your switches and all of your
routers and everything else right we
just want to be able to not let you know
in in one fell swoop just disable their
account
who knows if you do if you end up
missing something right use that locker
and endpoint encryption especially I
mean especially healthcare or something
where you have a lot of patient data
that's on that's a media nightmare
somebody you know breaks in your you
know nurses car and steals a laptop if
you don't have that encrypted or you
can't prove that it was encrypted
I mean you'll be the you know the next
big Hospital name in the news right not
only backup your network device
configuration alert on changes you know
if you have you know depending on the
size of organization some people have no
change control so that can be a little
bit messy people can be just making
changes whenever they're awake but maybe
i'll make sure you know not everybody
has access to those backups don't put
those on the open chair i'm patrick
linux boxes gets a lot of people forget
about those if you know w setup for all
your windows boxes and
you have this little linux box running
for the last 20 years in the corner that
has never rebooted because always just
works
you're not gonna remember to update that
always and yeah so remove unneeded
software nobody knew well I don't wanna
see nobody there's a lot of really
shitty apps out there that need it but
everywhere you can remove java you know
all the other software that isn't needed
but is automatically insult I've seen
porn popups on servers so dont let
browsing from users happen log
successful logins you know if you see a
bunch of unsuccessful logins people
normally log for unsuccessful against
right because that's what you want to
look for but if you see a whole bunch of
unsuccessful and then a successful you
could get a little bit more more
information from that so and i love
settings and password so like dal HP
servers right we'll have lights out
cards that will let you control the
physical hardware from you know from
remote without actually being on this is
really it they ship with really insecure
protocols and a lot of the times they
ship with I mean they ship with default
passwords and that's not something that
you normally think of theirs on there's
a Metasploit module out there that will
scan for HP and dell i believe and we'll
kind of let you know if that's a exploit
that can be run on that that protocol
and your dns and DC server should be
just that
so the nice old lady that was using our
free open Wi-Fi also so this this is all
been fixed but at that particular place
we had a DC running sequel server
well that sequel server was the bat back
end to our website our public website so
and that was doing home so you could hop
on the public website box everything was
open in between that in our domain
controller which was also handing out
dhcp to that open Wi-Fi so you can go
full circle out the open Wi-Fi back in
through the website and just you know
disabled and stone transfers that that
will give people more information about
the inside of your network the kind that
kind of stuff you only want your domain
controllers to know that kind of stuff
already covered that restricting access
to backups closure open mail realize you
don't want you know there's a whole list
open your mail relays out there that you
could send email as whatever you want to
whoever you want you don't want your
mail server to be one of those and a lot
of them are exchanged turns out people
just install exchange just by default
and think that they're completely fine
so this is pretty cool
can you tell where the ransomware start
encrypting ship you're going to be able
to alert on this without so this is this
in particular spunk right I do a lot of
spunk work at her in labs this you can
easily create an alert on you're going
to know that when that when that's a
that ransom was happening is just an
example of one of them but to know that
you have to have four sided you get the
force advanced auditing on your windows
boxes that can be really
resource-intensive so it doesn't always
work for everybody but it does help in
the long run if you want to detect this
kind of stuff and this is what I was
talking about before so this is a
screenshot and that the net disco
tells you the different ports which ones
are up and down the vlans you know what
what always been connected to it the
port description will tell you what iOS
versions are on your network on this is
great free tool i haven't seen anything
close to being this comprehensive for
free other than this one
I mean like I think solarwinds can do
the same kind of thing but I mean so
that was pretty damn expensive
this is super easy to set up and just
run
I don't forget your printers everybody
remember when we've printed out a bunch
of Nazi stuff to printers all over the
internet because people leave their
printers open talk to that as as i'm
writing the book and as I'm writing
these slides i was talking to a bunch of
red team friends that I have because I I
think I'm really shitty friend teaming
but like all right well what are some of
the top things that you run into that
makes it super easy for you to do your
job like oh well people never secure
their printers they have like
administrative credentials on them
constantly because it's super easy to
put those credentials in the printer and
you can just like scan the director is
right and you can email to ever you want
because those credentials are always
going to work this is you know what
happens when you do that I'm some so
some software that we can install for
free so you are all scan will screen all
incoming requests for like is reverse so
so some of the things that it actually
protects against is max URL it'll it'll
look for people trying to scan your your
website / you know different directories
that kind of stuff failed today and
schedule log files and automatically
bands them that's a like a linux apache
thing
modsecurity is the web application
firewall for linux microsoft baseline
security analyzer is a free tool for
Microsoft that you can run against your
images that kind of stuff and we'll tell
you you know when the main things on
windows that you need to not secure lock
down and I'm it kind of will protect
against zero-day type behavior on
windows free tool is great we
implemented this and only had a couple
issues like some weird microsoft access
it would it would block and block other
I think someone told me like it would
block photoshop sometimes trusted that
has a good blog that will tell you how
to automate the rollout of this we had
to do it by hand which on 2500 endpoints
was a huge pain in the ass
so after after that came out I wish we
could have scripted that out instead the
thing they have to watch out for Emmett
though is think with new arm it will
with the newer updates i think it will
break
oh well forget that i can't remember
so and ir a bug-out bag it's totally
backwards so when the show
it's the fan you want to have a good
idea of what to do have a plan
have-have you know run through this kind
of stuff in your head work with that
team that you've been working with this
whole time to to talk to the different
stakeholders and and figure out what
your steps should be you know if if you
know your data center explodes or you
know someone steals your domain
controller and and you're just screwed
you want a good list of stuff that
you're gonna have to do what you need to
do front for ir there's a really good
book
oh it's a defensive security handbook
know that shit that's my I know there's
one on ir that does all the lieutenant
inside the blue team and book that does
incident response that's great a great
tool will give you different things to
run down the list of if you have an ir
issue as opposed to just calling
somebody so now we're onto the free and
not completely easy some of that stuff
we talked about before isn't completely
easy like taking away demand that domain
admin creds depending on the you know
how how easy the rest of your department
is to work with so start to purple team
not this this was a huge step for me
just because I have always thought that
it i'm sitting at red teaming doing in
your own organization though you have
less risk because you kind of know you
know the the layout we know that who
talk to if you break something but it
doesn't take a genius to do some of
these uh purple team things so user
education also not super easy
there's a mean some people think user
education isn't worth it
I've seen it be worth it we we put
together so it's all the words based
user education if someone would report
on like a fishing exploit that would
come in or phishing attempt that would
come in they would get in put in this
monthly drawing we saw our time for
reporting fishing go from either never
reporting it all to think we were able
to see we stopped a an actual
professional and test team from getting
in
in three minutes we had somebody called
right away we were able to you know
block them and stop them and in doubt
those three minutes without user
education that would never happen
there's there's a tool out there that
you can actually run that will change
all your local admin passwords makes it
a little bit more difficult for an
attacker to hop from box to box if they
have to get the new password every time
something the police privileges so you
don't want Kathy an HR to be able to you
know rdp to your to the finance server
application whitelisting also not very
easy
it's free but it's not easy at all a lot
of people going back to asset management
not only did they not know the devices
they have on their network they also
hold a software they have on the network
so it's it's a little bit more difficult
starting there but that better than
application blacklisting you know you
can you can either i complete
special hip-hop sorry i'm just going on
to the next one
just pretend like that last 30 seconds
and happen i had a rough night
yes whitelisting good huh
shit alright so canary in the coal mine
set up a sequel server that you're never
going to use that nobody's going to ever
run queries against that nobody's ever
going to log into an alert on that it's
going to be different in every
department in every environment maybe
you don't have any life sequel servers
probably not true but it you know
customize those things to you to your
network and holy shit egress filtering
know like oh so many people don't don't
duh filter upon traffic because I mean
all the attacks come from the internet
right there's no way anybody's gonna
bring their laptop and from home that's
already attracted that that won't happen
and we're talking about purple teaming
so right you don't have to be super
league red team or I totally am NOT but
so you can use responder there's a bunch
of a bunch of talks out there about
responder that you can I mean this is
super non-invasive you can do this on
your network and let me just learn about
it you know you're gonna the more you
know about how the red teamers then the
attacker stank the better you're going
to be able to defend your own
environment
ah so do this one carefully
I have accidentally brought entire
network to their knees by doing a mass
can turns out some enterprise-grade
next-gen firewalls don't handle mask and
very well fire up medicine plate play
around with it
great books and forums and this huge
community around metasploit that you can
really really learn a lot from and
you'll find more shit on your network
that those vulnerability scans aren't
going to find so r is pretty cool will
scan your network for port 80 and port
443 and will give you this nice little
report and print out of all of the
websites that finds and we'll just do a
screenshot really great for attackers to
just run this and like oh you know that
that website doesn't really seem like
it's a lockdown or hey this one looks
like people really use it a lot i'm
going to smooth that one
I'm you set so when I did the the whole
fishing thing set is what I used to you
know spoof the email addresses and and
send out that kind of stuff and it'll
send you back those credentials that
you're capturing in real time you can do
it has a whole bunch of other stuff too
but i think one of the easier things to
do is use this for those fishing
exercises so these two links everything
in the first link so it's the top five
ways spider lab . domain admin on your
internal network so they write responder
but they have you know a great list of
things that you really need to protect
against not by Olson lnr is you know
pretty high on that list last time I
brought up the slide like half the
audience left
shit we don't listen about compliance
nobody does but pick a compliance
standard and stick to it there there's
so mom so much you can get a car bomb
accomplished if you say oh no we have to
do this because hippo said so it better
than just a checkmark right you can
actually affect change by picking a
compliance standard don't just worried
about the compliance if you but if you
do security and you do security right
that compliance is just going to fall in
line so probably the top three
segmentation that whole you know website
that was due home that you can access
the DC from segmentation and a dmz would
have really really come in handy they're
setting up feelin's you can't put a
firewall everywhere right
it's just not i mean that's not really
possible
I mean not great for costs but you can
segment with vlans and i'll put all
depending on the size your network
either put all servers on one VLAN or
put all web servers on one VLAN and you
inside access controls in between the
two as opposed to putting a firewall
between everything and Active Directory
delegation of Rights so all of those
domain add domain admin account that you
took away from everybody that didn't
need them you can give them the right
set of permissions as opposed to just
walking around doing their jobs for them
and you can do that with Active
Directory delegation so you can you know
say you know the helpdesk can only do
these certain things as far as the
domain goes like moving pieces two
different use that kind of stuff so now
that we've done all of this free stuff
there's also i mean all those blinky
boxes that are out there now you should
have a budget if you've you've done your
due diligence you worked with
them as a group you you know spent the
last two years implementing all the free
stuff that no one ever nobody ever
thinks about you're like look at look at
all of the stuff that we've done now
could be pleased have these advanced
tools so get a real vulnerability
scanner at that point you know you're
gonna outgrow the free trial
it's only good for a little bit anyways
you should be doing vulnerability scans
full-scope you know you don't want to
just forget half of your network because
they think it's a good idea that you
don't scan that part and do it month
i've seen people do it monthly quarterly
some people say they do it weekly but
that's a horrible idea
there's no way you can make enough
change from one week to the next that
you need a vulnerability scan every week
I'm a semi dsi PS I'm you know I want to
say get sprung and you can buy from us
but other other ones out there that are
free but you know to get a good one that
has advanced reporting that kind of
stuff is going to cost a little bit of
money get a professional pentest not one
of those places that sells vulnerability
scan as a contest right you need to know
the difference
you need to you know if they're giving
you stuff that you already know based on
what you've done evaluate vulnerability
scan on and you're not getting the money
you know you're not getting the value
for the money and not only two factor
authentication but to off two-factor
authentication implemented correctly so
we had a not gonna say the name of it
but protector our software that instead
of giving you a code or you know having
having a fob texting you push up or
whatever it would call you and all you
do is hit pound and they would lock you
in that with technically on paper
compliance you know you work you're
covered for two vector off
what would happen is you know the the
pen testers fish steps and credentials
it was using two-factor off but they
used it called the person and they just
hit pound because I mean that's what
they always do when they get a call from
that number as they hit pound because
that that's what we train them to do you
know that's all the software works
technically it's two-factor off but it's
definitely not implemented correctly and
then you can get the next-gen cyber
buzzword boxes after that and get
organized iPads management software
password saves you're not going to
getting all those plaintext passwords
that you have found your going to need
to put them somewhere you can just
memorize all that stuff you need to
there's some what is a psychotic has a
really good product that I've used
before that you can give certain people
access to folders within it secret
server
thank you yeah it's a really good
product incident response to tabletops
and drills so tabletop is going to be
where you just think about what's going
to happen a drill is going to be when
you actually physically make something
happen
I've had people do the tabletops and
then a week later get hit by the exact
thing that we did the table top on and
they still fucked it up
so what it wasn't as bad right i mean
they each time you do something like
that you're going to learn a little bit
more about your network you're gonna
know who to call in what situation
you're gonna know you know if you have
to send out something media related or
your or you know turn off certain things
or called different organizations that
kind of stuff
each time you do that you think of
something else and when it happens
you're a little bit more prepared you're
not always going to get it right but you
know that next step is just how fast
you're able to recover from that
incident and a run book where you keep
all of this
you're not going to want to just you
know printed out you're not going to
want to have it just not a website
somewhere or the share drive because if
something I are related happens and you
lose that then you just trying to go by
memory and then user education and I
just like to hit on this again because
you can do everything you need to do
technically but that users always going
to get fished the weakest point hands
down
haha other than me fucking up a couple
times thank you
if any questions
yes my favorite vulnerability scanners
I'm partial analysis is necessary for a
while
yeah i mean it has no different
different levels where you can you know
like advanced reporting and tracking
vulnerabilities from month to month
whatever but yets I like it a lot
get it right oh that one work but you're
going
make me talk about application
whitelisting when I set up here first
good site
um I don't know i'm not sure we use the
built-in microsoft one
yeah correctly now offer asset
management using several those tools
right so that disco is going to be your
1 source of truth for your network right
dms for everything else I mean eating
having everything in dns most of that
just populate automatically right so
using that is your 1 source of truth for
endpoints is is good thanks