so yeah that's definitely one of the
best security conferences around I think
anyway I hope you agree especially in
state of Michigan and you know although
I i love they have my converge and
besides and everything else and fit
those endearing the air around the
Detroit side of town and there's
wonderful people my sack that actually
linked up with but i'm dr. dr0 it's
funny name but on at one point I worked
with people have multiple doctors
Doctorate degrees and I said I will
never get a doctor great so that's where
the name comes from on i have a history
and I'll talk about that but this all
started with an idea and the idea and
the concept is that we were going to
make an automotive certificate program
at walsh college and that's where i
worked at the time and they're still
going about and you're still doing it
which is awesome and it's hands-on its
offensive and what the way we go about
it is that were including people from
different parts of the automotive
industry and me bein more like the gray
hat that grew up into like operational
security type of person are decided that
hey you know in these conversations and
as I was talking to people that work for
automotive comp companies that actually
do try to secure their automotive
vehicles but they can I felt a little
bit out of place you know I feel a
little more comfortable in this type of
environment with people like myself so
on
that's where this kind of came from so
we're talking about the culture crash
and there's a couple of things that I
deserved along the way
well i was going to some of these
different vendors and you know the
suppliers and automotive people
organizations and talking to them about
possibly linking up and join the forces
to help with certification so along
those lines basically I felt like whoops
there's little bit there I felt like my
associate is trying to say is that our
new brake pads are really cool
you're not going to believe
it like um let's say you're driving
along the road with your family and
you're driving along I was that all of a
sudden there's a truck tire in the
middle of the road and you hit the
brakes whoa that was close
yeah now let's see what happens when
you're driving with the other guys brake
pads you're driving is driving a lot and
I was done the kids are young sexy
I gotta go to pick up and daddy not now
damik four-tire hey I can't stop
there's a glare that's when your firm or
spiritual and your family's agreement
oh my god were burning alive
no I can't feel my legs it comes to meat
wagon and the Medicus out and says oh my
god you guys in the corner puking his
guts out all because you want to save a
couple extra pennies that send to me it
doesn't get out now do you validate now
ok thank you so I kind of like that you
know because that's one of the things
that you know in the security arena we
often get sold as hey you know you know
what's gonna cost is actually you know
it gotta you know there are trade-offs
should we eliminate this or should we
just accept the rest we just keep on
moving forward on and on
yes the decisions that we have to make
but what we have to do here is taking a
step back and basically what we have to
do is try to our best to define culture
just end through this cut through this
conversation to this presentation we're
going to talk about stereotypes of
similarities we have between people and
corporate culture and people that are
true traditional hackers people that
actually work in their own workplaces
set up their own different boxes and try
to attack those boxes to try to better
our own understanding of security on
what are some of the countermeasures and
the cultural clashes that go with that
and hopefully we're going to look at the
case studies i also believe a lot in
history and we don't want to repeat that
so that's the kind of caucus is it's not
very techincal from that standpoint but
I'm so if you're expecting a more
technical talk then you might want to go
to something else a little bit more
technical but so about me I have 18
years of experience and operational
security and I worked mainly at a
college level and i was one of the guys
that they kind of look to when they had
security breaches and stuff like that
and say okay well how did this get out
and I would do a quick google search and
I find like document that some media
posted out there and exploiting our
information so her posting information
on the web basically a i spent six years
teaching cybersecurity i'm a big fan of
scotus and what he's done it sans I
think they're doing it right it's it's a
bit expensive so i was trying to build a
program that was basically competitive
with that and i'm a past full time
faculty member at walsh college so the
views of my that I have in this
presentation and things I talk about
I've obviously my own and that of my
employer so when you talk about culture
we have to realize that 1952 somebody
wanted out some sociologists route and
her after anthropologists went out and
they try to define culture and then
basically 50 years pass and they had a
hundred sixty four different definitions
so on
by the 1990s somebody finally drew line
in the sand and said well this is
probably one of the best ways that we
can define culture and its culture is
the consistence of derivatives of
experience more or less that have been
learned so it's it's so it's a learning
feature it's part of us and we learn it
through others and that are around us
and it's a team effort that's what
culture is basically so it kind of
sounds like some of the meetings that
have participated in though when you
don't have a decision just keep on going
on are the hacker culture though I think
we can you know when I want to speak
about the hacker culture this is what
comes to my mind that were noble
explorers for protector guardians of the
interwebs
there's also divisions within that
hacker culture there's a bike at first
the defcon are obviously that can
support more the eff group
a less expensive for that
yeah def con definitely a less expensive
than the black hat culture where you pay
a lot more for you in the same pretty
presentation is pretty much the week
before and there's the ethical versus
the unethical and where do you draw the
line in the sand with that there's many
shades of grey
there's the hacktivists first law
enforcement and then there's also the
subject you know when we talk about that
it's very deep and wide so due to
diversity and experience the views of
this may vary and we could probably
argue about this all day so we class
with classify hackers or at least it
when i classify hackers I think of more
like the defcon you know the traditional
hackers people like myself I grew up
testing security controls and I didn't
really realize it until I got a former
for formal education and then I started
realizing like hey wait a minute i was
actually like 10 testing a lot of this
stuff and wow I didn't really think
about it you know from physical locks
all the way over to websites and stuff
like that arm and then I started to
realize some of the value of my ways the
black hat actually represents more the
corporations and there's a few people
like much that actually can make the
crossover from the the defcon to the
black hat and so on so forth and consult
with the Pentagon he kind of represents
a lot of us and helps out with the the
hacker community as well armed cultural
clashes basically these are the ones I
think that we have we have media versus
the hacker vs corporation we have a huge
one which is basically should we go
ahead and have open source for
automotive vehicles versus the closed
source argument one side believes that
its information share and the other side
believes that we should have hands-on
there's the unbound of people which is
more the hackers versus the corporations
that have very strict boundaries of what
you can and cannot do and what you will
say what you want say or you won't have
a job so there's a communication
response
there's the hacker tools that are out
there that are different
and obviously the corporation has a lot
more money spent on tools where we
develop our own and we pull some to
various websites to make them available
for people that wanna play with them and
we have the testing of different
concepts and legality concerns and
ethics so cultural crash number one so
it's the media versus the hacker culture
basically this is a this is a screenshot
of what people think about hackers in
general we don't all wear hoodies first
and foremost but this is the stuff that
they put out there you guys all know
this and then there's there's a little
bit there's ads and stuff like that long
wait says you know how hackers and car
makers of battling for control of your
ride
well when the average user reads this
they think that you're trying to break
into their car and that's not
necessarily true for the most part and
we're just interested in like trying to
figure out we might want to plug into
the can bus of the vehicle it might be
your own vehicle just to see what we can
do what we can make work but we can't
work for makers and from that sense i
mean that's that's what we do
so does immediate to portray the at the
culture of the hackers like is being bad
absolutely but they also betray the
corporation's is being bad as well
depending on what the flies in their
vehicles on and you can find different
types of you know different types of
examples for that so Henry Ford
basically he's he's one of our original
hackers and he's from around at the
auditorium metropolitan area so we all
know about him if we grew up around
there but he talked about failure is
simply the opportunity to begin again
this time were intelligently and that's
the way we all have to approach it from
that standpoint is first corporation
it's like if a hacker find some some
kind of flying your system then that's
actually a good thing because now you
know it exists now you know there might
be something that you have to address at
that point is it's something that we
have to address and you do a risk
analysis on it and you can move on arm
so we talk about media versus hacker
culture where is the media wine we
actually look at military and when we
look at the law enforcement agencies and
stuff like that that are out there
they're hackers as well and I've
actually had the pleasure of training
people that have been ex-military that
our military that are actually law
enforcement agency agents along the way
in offensive and defensive technologies
this with as it relates the computer
security and they're pretty cool people
but they think a lot like like the
hackers the homegrown hackers that i was
at one point which is pretty cool arm so
we are the makers breakers and builders
and we do have a law enforcement among
other us as well and you know that gets
more along lines of the black hat versus
the defcon conferences and stuff like
that
obviously if you're familiar with Def
Con you know that law enforcement isn't
really welcome to DEFCON but arm media
versus a hacker culture resolution
stereotype and really doesn't help any
of us so we all don't chuck cars down on
busy freeways we don't put we all don't
mean we might test in our own garages a
craig smith actually got to meet him had
breakfast with him he's a really nice
guy in fact he comes from like a
different like the same type of
background i come from as far as working
for education and in an information
technology and doing security work their
arm
not every corporate person is born stiff
ok i met some really cool people that
worked with us at actually are in the
corporations that know a lot and the in
fact some of those people actually
helped out over at besides this year arm
and and they were supporting like the
hacker challenge and they came up with
all the various different challenges so
they are among us
believe it or not now they may not come
out and say and here's a problem with
this too is that is hackers we like to
find a hole in something and we kinda
like say you know you know
WTF you know what's up with this like
this hole in this this product and why
isn't this fixed and then we like to
point out the organization say god you
guys want to be stupid but arm a lot of
times with that said there is it comes
down to somebody did a risk assessment
or they might have known about it but
they can't speak about it and we've seen
some of that recently as far as ok Peppa
something anyway so basically what we
have to think about there is is not
totally distracted
where was like arm but anyway yeah that
totally distracted but thank you it was
a pleasant just a distraction anyway but
on what we have to think about is like
basically parent myself with the
corporate environments and like how to
work with them and in a constructive way
so corporations stone all address the
zero-day disclosures in a timely manner
as we would all like to see and it's
never been a cool thing to the public or
the hacker community and the reason why
this is and this is the same in cars as
it is in any server or operating system
that's out there is because we just want
to see it fixed
ok and the reason why we like go ahead
and we just go put things out there and
to the public and we say okay well
here's here's the vulnerability is
because it actually like to fire any
somebody's bomb and they're . they're
what they're what we have to realize
their employees that are in a corporate
the care about the security concerns we
have like with the example and that's
what i was getting too before I was
interrupted was a yahoo recently there
they had a very good security expert in
over there okay and he finally came out
and said look we tried to secure this
stuff a couple years a few years ago
before this all happened we tried to be
you know in the forefront as far as
security in yahoo but basically what
happened was they decided not to you
know they decided the cost of spending
the money on the counter measures wasn't
worth it
ok so he ended up
moving on and he's probably getting paid
pretty good for it and maybe his less
stress but that's like the stuff does
happen so so anyway media versus the
hacker culture in the resolution age you
can see here is like there is like one
way that I was looking at this like its
first like the the hacker and me is like
bunches fix the damn thing
ok and that's on the outside but when
you look at it from a back pack you and
as I'm sitting in these meetings in a
meeting with these people that are very
intelligent it just is every bit as
intelligence me and totally understand
and be able to hang with me and my
conversations I was like wow these guys
are not all ideas these guys actually do
know what they're talking about they're
actually in our community they're doing
a lot of the cool stuff that were doing
and we have to realize that perception
is something that we all make up and
this is like psychological and it's like
you know at that point it's and I always
like to think of it like this it's like
it's it's just like a culture but it's
made up in your mind something that
you've learned ever since you were a
baby and you and you were born and you
carried it through and my perception had
to change at that point that was like I
said that was a paradigm shift in thing
arm and go into a lot of conferences
I've heard a lot of hackers kind of bash
you know the corporations and stuff like
that for not for not fixing things right
away but there is a resolution for that
so this bonus of terms of contributions
so there's teamworks the 1i want to
think about is like how can we go ahead
and contribute contribute more to the
actual corporate environments and the
one thing is corporate environments are
now welcome on us and and one at the
time when i came up with this this
conversation they weren't as much so
welcome and us and to go ahead and have
their stuff and try to welcome us
forward into vulnerability management
programs so obviously you know GM was
the first start they came out with a
vulnerability disclosure program but
that was a big step when I seen that I'm
like wow things are actually changing
maybe for the better
ok the disclaimers
talked a little bit but you know a lot
but but anyway on that they want to put
in in the reason why I say that is
because they want to put constraints
around the hackers member unbound we
don't like boundaries so when you try to
put its constraints around us corporate
then basically what happens is you
really turn us off we don't want to be
like how liable for something that we
want to disclose to you to try to fix
your product because you probably should
have thought about in the first place
what we want to do is basically go ahead
and you know help you out and just get
it fixed
you know that's that's the that's the
mentality on and you know there's a
certain pride and it depends on the
person's depends on the motivation might
actually be like hey look i did this it
was me that actually found this problem
and they can actually they fix that I
think that's where the pride really is
with the hacker community and I think
that's what's got to stay so we can
definitely go ahead and make you know
build bridges it in in terms of that arm
but you know I also understand the
legality side of the corporation that
they don't want to be held liable for
something that might actually cause
death or harm i got knows already have
teams of lawyers that they go ahead and
employ a full-time so realize when
somebody talks to media corporate vs
hackers sometimes the message gets
edited to so i actually did uh you know
I did channel 50 there was a street beat
this this year I talked about hackers in
general I talked about some of the
security concerns we have on that's a
different topic as far as nation-state
and what we have to be more aware of but
in those conversations like you know you
have to meet you realize that sometimes
when you say stuff on TV and media and
for those unless they have actually been
media trained armed sometimes they might
get edited or cut down and then also it
doesn't it doesn't sound right
so you have to realize that happens to
corporate to arm so this place a lot
into the perception of overall public
and as well so media is kinda like one
of those things it's like I don't
necessarily believe that every time I
see it so arm and that's the point of
that slide but you know that's what I'm
saying is like you better to take it
back to the to the hobbit to the person
actually talk to them and try to find
out what they SAT and try to get
clarification if you don't agree with it
that's one great thing about this
conference is like everybody here like
wants to help everybody else out but arm
you can always cocoa up to somebody and
talk to them like i have conversations
about building you know my classes and
stuff like that I'll go out and I'll
reach out to chris Roberts and stuff
like that i mean this is the best thing
thats why i love this community I love
this 7 as far as that is concerned you
want to talk about building an
educational program then come talk to me
like 18 years experiencing but you know
open source so in order to contribute to
open-source both parties need to have
trust with each other
the hackers in the corporation obviously
the trust isn't there when you actually
have some kind of sign off you know
you're signing your life away you know
just case something happens and the gm's
bug bounty program like I talked about
was a step in the right place and
Charlie Miller was like the first voice
out there and hopefully we all know who
he is but he's one of the guys that
hacked the cheaper made it like stop go
off the road a crystal acid is the other
one arm and basically with that said I
he blasted GM right when it first came
out because he read it he read the terms
of agreement and then he actually talked
to general motors guy is said here so
you have to follow up with something
like that and realize that arm you know
he's actually like the person on the
inside is actually really pretty cool
person like when he sat down to talk to
him
it's because he's not that much
different than Charlie ok they seen
eye-to-eye and this is case in point
ok so the human they have families to
feed and again you know with what the
people i know they actually are afraid
you know they have to make sure i don't
say free but they want to make sure that
they don't say they don't say something
that's going to get them in trouble and
cause problems so hackers an open-source
we tend to be more willing to share
especially in this community it's like
hey I wrote some code you know you want
to check it out and see if it were
works and maybe have any input on I know
I sit down like when I was making this
presentation I talked to a couple people
so what do you think about it you know
how can i improve about it i actually
did that again last night it's all about
Sharon and saw so we all learn and are
the exceptions of when money is the
motivation factors 200 days basically
the unethical zor maybe even the
ethicals white have a good day that they
don't want to publish to everybody
because they know they could possibly
make a lot of money on it so my whole
back on it so this depends on their epic
alignment their financial situation
obviously if you're not making bank and
you find an oday it might be like wait a
minute I got a guy kinda gotta feed my
kids there might actually be some
ethical choices you have to make their
hopefully make the right ones but with
Def Con for example the his parties were
people are all up all night Sharon
working together back in and helping
facilitate each other's education and
that's that's the greatest strength of
this community that's what I love about
it the most and that's why I teach
security because it's fun
I mean I just want tonight I seen a nick
jacobs stock and basically what's cool
is i don't is it anybody in that five
nights at freddy talk was there
ok Nick Jacobs is actually one of my
former students which is kind of cool so
I'm proud to say that because I see a
couple of here and actually I'm actually
yeah I'm hooked up and I'm hanging out
with another one all conference which is
cool so it's fun when you have a passion
you can share it and I think we all have
a passion we can share and that's why
I'm up here so open sources a theme for
the most part b sides cons etc are clear
examples of that arm you know with the
cultural clash though it's like it there
is an exception on this obviously
there's something that there's there's
couple manufacturers out there local
mordor's wiki speed and some others they
actually believe an open-source they
published their different products that
are out there so people can review it
actually look at it and say whether this
is a good builder it's not a good build
for their cars there's any kind of
vulnerabilities and that are you know
what should we do with that I but you
know as far as like GM Ford and some
other other
ones they tend to be more tight-lipped
about what they're working on and that's
more apparent like you know what I want
to some of the facilities like you know
I thought I talked a lot about physical
insecurities when you go into the is
anybody ever gone into a corporation
like for GM or any of the big three
automotives around here
yeah when you go in there it's like you
going through your first mantrap you're
like wow they're really really serious
and by the way I tried to like talk to
people and see if I can sort of like
kind of socially just let them get no
that wasn't going to happen they knew
that they could lose your job so it's
very serious but i was thinking like
well maybe it was nice this guy he would
let me and so I want to have to wait
here like 15-20 minutes with somebody
come get me and it didn't happen so they
are very very security conscious and uh
so there's there's codes for can boss
they're not published requires using
techniques like buzzin but the g-pack
shows that husband works in essence of
Charlie Miller and Chris classic
actually got their data so high codes
only slow down the attacks but it
doesn't really stop it
overall and you know and think maybe
that's a strategy that the corporation
likes to have and maybe that's why
they're not so big on open source but
you know attacks are going to happen and
people are going to find their way with
surround systems this goes back to the
conversation to realize that before I
even accepted a job as a cybersecurity
full-time instructor at walsh college
which i'm not there anymore arm that
basically that was my choice but arm but
basically i was sitting down at a bar
and i'll send across from somebody and
that person later i was going to be my
contacts so I the the cool thing about
it was my hacker my hacker side the of
me actually was more social and i was
able to make a contact with an
automotive company that was able to get
land us a meeting which was pretty cool
so that's something that definitely have
gone for us but I the overall
conversation the reason why I bring this
up is it's very much about open source
and clothes stories is he told me that
he was basically working for major
automotive company and this is like
he's been through a couple different
automotive companies and what happened
was he he got placed over at this other
is this one he's working it now and he
said that all I said what he didn't know
my background which is funny and I said
what we what do you do and you know that
kind of conversation comes up and he's
like why you know this is what I do I
were confirmar for automotive I said all
what do you think about the local
hacking all that wasn't you know people
don't know one off there there's there's
no way hackers going to be able to do
anything with it like three months later
so it's a corporate mentality
three months later charlie miller was up
on wired magazine they had a video that
they showed that just proves everything
that we just said was wrong so there is
that facet still in the corporate
culture that hey we don't provide him
the codes they won't know and all this
other stuff but we figure it out because
that's what we do we don't mind spending
hours and hours and by the way you know
there's tons of ours that Charlie you
know Chris you know props to them had to
go through just to make that work you
know and that takes a lot of skill and
dedication obviously arm disclosures you
know we talked about you know the you
know the hacker mantelli you know who
wants to go out there and just like you
know just make a disclosure public like
right away and basically Benjamin cons
be disclosed on july seven two
vulnerabilities they were in the BMW
ConnectedDrive vehicle
ok but let's go take a look back in
February he actually want you contacted
the BMW corporation and he said that hey
these these vulnerabilities are in there
and the client side cross scripting
vulnerability is also on your website
and on they didn't do anything about it
so he sat on it for months and nothing
ever happened from that so we're going
to talk about how to fix that hopefully
if there is not any corporate people
that walk out already but arm all
technology blueprints and patents should
be available it sounds like a fantasy
but there are companies that are
actually doing that
it's just not the major players in
Detroit so this vehicle has 10,000 out
area ten-thousand-dollar car concept
there is Tesla obviously open up patents
or open that opened up patents are more
experiment and creativity is going on
and people are learning how to work with
the technologies that are in these these
systems and actually how to break and
fix them more innovations from third
parties that's what it means there's
good thing that there are smaller
alliances that are out there and
actually major automotive players are
part of those alliances salt and we're
talking about Ford and GM and stuff like
that so they're artists as there is an
alliance out there such as the open
automotive Alliance for android wear the
major manufacturers are out there so to
shift your paradigm a little bit
it's not like it's totally closed like
we think it is so they're the are
sharing a little bit and that's another
reason I want to get up and have this
talk because you know again dealing with
these people I found these things out
and for my own research you know just
google on and check it out
however being completely open to the
public of the world will attract top
talent as pointed out by the head of
Tesla you know what the other thing is
maybe you'll find somebody that's like
really geeky like a hacker and like he
wants to learn this stuff and when you
see these jobs right now there's a ton
of jobs posted out there for automotive
security but they want you to know can
bus they want you to all these different
things and how do you break into that
field well you know the more you mess
with this stuff the better you're going
to get so are hecka tools vs legality
well Charlie Miller he goes out there he
talks about you know there's a lot of
people out there right in their own
programs i'm like how to read campus why
would I ever need to use any of those
programs when I vehicle spies you know
and vehicle spies like one of those
tools that are out there that's
available to people that make big money
you know arm or work for big
corporations so when I found was in
conversations through in this isn't just
like Charlie Miller sand that's like and
Twitter that's not where i get this
information it's real world in the
meeting rooms
we're talking about
uh we use canoe for campus sniffing I
and we were talking about that and then
I'll son one of the people from the
corporation was like what are actually
they use canoe and then I and I said
well we use kayak which is kind of a
play on words because canoe was actually
the bigger more paid for his more
feature-rich and they're like three
thousand dollars or something for the
program where kayaks free you know so if
you can imagine the difference in those
two but there's a big difference between
what we use hackers and what the people
using the corporations which is also
something that could have a limitation
if you're looking for employment and
they want to actually have you have
experienced just this one thing but you
can say hey I for the kayak and maybe
you know that would give them off the oh
I know what kayak is they know these
tools they know the free and open-source
tools to so like I said they're not
stupid arm the vehicles by you know this
that's something that Charlie Miller
prefers sharing information
automotive tends to be a little bit more
responsible than shutting down a vehicle
on the freeway obviously they do it in
closed environment so that they don't
hurt anyone on this creates a struggle
both legally on Capitol this
that's the other thing is like I've got
friends in low and high places and and
some of those people actually had to go
on before capitol hill and defend what
Charlie Miller did because because it
was in all perceived as irresponsible at
which you can fall down because somebody
could have got hurt and on and so
there's that legal struggle on Capitol
Hill that goes both ways they want to
take a right away for testing on
vehicles and testing on different
technologies
well where do you think they get these
ideas from when they see stuff like this
so there's that that long gun mentality
out there but also if it wasn't done
who would ever take it as a big
perceivable threat so there's that other
side of the coin and it's like into me
and almost seems like what's happenin
and this is my humble opinion is that
we're getting pushed into the corner of
making these horrible decisions because
nobody's going to listen to us unless we
actually do that
so more solutions to demand respect you
must need you must gain respect and in
the corporate culture that's definitely
more true than that so it pays to be
professional when you're dealing with
these people I didn't have the Tommy Boy
meeting because I understood that ok
that's what's going on in my hat
what's the crashing and stuff like that
and the burn your car is going to do
this and that unless this you know you
actually get our help on but rants are
good but solutions are better i think we
started off a few years ago we used the
rant about security now we're all
talking about solutions so we have to
have clear lines of communication when I
talk about this is a corporate has to
have clear lines of communication with
the hacker culture the hacker culture
also needs and wants that communication
if remember we talked about the BMW
vulnerability it's my humble opinion
that if they were communicated to think
about this if your corporation and
somebody comes forward with a
vulnerability to you and says hey you
have a problem in your system then they
become your client in a way you should
manage that connection this person
actually cares about your product then
you should probably let them know where
it lands that are you going to do
something about it
are you planning on it maybe you guys
could be able to move this fast enough
for whatever limitations resources you
have at that point but you don't have to
tell them all the all the details but at
least communicate to the hacker
community to let them know that it's on
your radar
yeah you know things you wrote wrote to
me about a month ago
we're still looking at it but if you
manage those communications better you
probably have lost dachshund of
information out there okay because all
we want to know is like hey are we gonna
make the difference
are you going to make the difference
because if you're not then i'm going to
go ahead i'm going to release this
information to the web
and somebody's gonna have to do
something about it and it's gonna be you
and well-armed bug bounties you have to
give closure to those people that
recorded them if your cyber ninja 17
inches are those are most of the hackers
communities in this most people in this
room so in and that's definitely me
somebody could do a lot with just a
little bit arm if you actually have
people working for you there's a good
talk a lot of year or two ago and are
basically it was talking about how the
care and feeding of a cyber ninjas thats
a list of doing that that's that talk
about it and that's so true
it's like you don't want to piss us off
because we're just gonna walk away you
know because we know where employable
and we're gonna find something somewhere
else and you know but for the most part
were also dedicated i work for a place
for 18 years
so let's say about me I don't just walk
away from things i like a relationship I
like family you know and you know if its
corporate family and great but our
corporations need to recognize and give
those at 50 days by fixing those issues
and given the hacker pops that's the
only thing is like they want to know
that they want to be able to say look
what i did i had i found something any
effects and I think that's really what
it comes down to arm most importantly
realize that we have a common goal and
that's hopefully create a safer
technology safer future for everybody
and I think that really is a comical so
we need to break down barriers we need
to learn from each other and we need to
listen without prejudice we need to
speak with the commonality nobody really
is better than anyone else as far as the
corporation's versus the hacker culture
we're all in this together we're all on
this to fix things
the human mind is a wonderful thing will
help us actually get through this very
easily the barriers of stereotypes will
move us ahead there only to stop us and
slow us down
conferences ok but action is much better
at the end of the day so there there's a
conscious concept of internal hackers
that I kind of came up with a while ago
and it's kind of cyber ninja vs i'm
interpreting over vs entrepreneur
entrepreneurs . people this is an older
term from when I was going for my be a
long time ago but I it behaves like an
entrepreneur but inside the company
you're actually taking it and you're
making your own business you take a lot
of pride in your work and I think a lot
of a cyber ninjas do that take a lot of
pride in what we do and we want to carry
that forward so you know if it sounds
familiar it's because it is familiar
so here's a little quiz anybody know who
these guys are
there's a guy in a left and who's the
two guys on the right
anybody know this is a second this is
like the last part of my talk here
what's well I probably already just said
it just went forward til it's Roger boys
really physical engineer which is which
is on your left and charlie miller and
Chris plastic which is on your right so
I got my night directions messed up here
but on what do they have in common
basically Roger came out with a
vulnerability that was in a vehicle sort
of chris and and our and Charlie Miller
and the perception of roger was much
like Chris and Charlie at the same time
they have messages liver but the action
was either slow or too slow or in denial
arm so in keep in mind charlie Crist
again they did not go out to the
Chrysler and sail chrysler are you know
we're just gonna go ahead and release
this now they gave chrysler sometime
they didn't get the response that they
thought they should have had and then
they release that ok
arm the perception was pretty bad
corporate culture does play a big role
in this and it's hard to recommend for
corporate culture has a so large to
change arm but people focuses on
differences more than not and those
differences often hold us back
and why is this important because Roger
member memo in january $MONTH 1985
concerning a faulty design and the in a
vehicle
I'm sorry for my presentation people
skipping forward arm but anyway the
rocket boots
hers was was a problem in the Challenger
and in January 28 1986 by the way he
didn't come forward and just release
this information of public but our
january twenty hate 1986 30 years ago
this year and that's why I'm doing this
presentation is Challenger actually
exploded
okay why does nobody know anything about
it they just kept on pushing forward arm
so these are the kind of problems that
some hackers may have issue with what if
they have our ability was still in the
systems of for the automotive systems
and also we can just go ahead and mass
shutdown vehicles or stop them on a
freeway and all you need is five and you
have so many accidents will be crazy arm
me cataclysmic and this is already this
is you know communication have a car's
horns honk and stuff like this
this has been the already done by
insiders it's been proven that they have
the capability to do this in mass to
multiple vehicles at once but it could
be more devastating than the Challenger
ok
r-roger testified and found himself shot
by his colleges and managers so much
that he actually resigned
so here's here's an ethical talk where
roger actually speaks I just want to put
this up there before it it actually goes
ahead forward before i start i want
first remark i'm going to show you the
NASA state video launched that was pipes
through all the contractors on the
program
I have to tell you this the first time I
actually sorry launched from my facility
i didn't even know it was available
ability i was about doing the business
on the program the whole trip and this
is the only one I actually saw from my
points but before I show it i want to
press upon several things and although
this may sound like a craft statement
it's not meant to be so but the
challenges story and used as a case
study to help students understand what's
going to be coming up especially it's
not about the death seven acid and I
know that sounds horrible but it's not
about that that was a horrible horrible
combination of the event itself seven
exceptional people for their wise such
irresponsible losses
it's also not about the loss of over two
billion dollars with the apartment what
it's about it's professionals in the
system prevent the authority and
responsibility and fiduciary interest to
do the right thing and they advocated
them they advocated that because they
were pressured to do itself by the
agency called mass as you here is three
foals so the reason why obviously the
reason why I play that is because we
can't advocator rolls
no matter what they are whether we're
inside the organization or whether we're
the at actual ethical hacker and we're
interested in trying to fix something so
that's why we have to learn to work
together little a lot better than
sometimes we do so what happens when we
have that big pileup vehicles because
somebody actually got in and something
did happen and identical texts or
corporation does seem to care a lot
about money so that obviously hopefully
i'm hoping to god it never happens and
I'm religious guy so arm
you know as far as hackers themselves
one doesn't have to look far to see
different types of hackers that are out
there and Henry Ford was one we have
Roger boys really use physical engineer
because a hacker he knew how the systems
work inside out he knew what was going
to happen before it even happened
he predicted the future the dodge
brothers you know Tesla we have Charlie
Miller crystal astok you know we have so
many different people around us that
actually can inspire and hopefully help
to lead us into making the right
decisions and in the end and hopefully
those right decisions involve ethical
decisions and something that we can work
together on because it's about bridging
that gap so what actions will you take
you know can hackers be heroes
I know we can I however stunt hacking
may not be the best way to achieve this
but it often gets the point across so
it's hard to argue against that even in
my own mind i have a moral conflict with
this because I understand how important
this was because you know what soon as
this heard it started happening if you
follow this wire you know we're still
talking about it and still up here
talking about at a conference when you
follow stuff like this you start to see
the chain effects we actually have our
ability programs that are getting
released out there
corporations are actually in there is
anthony's infinitely infant steps in
trying to reach out to us and trying to
get some kind of program does it is it
gonna get better
absolutely it actually is going to be
better ok they start out small okay if
you're not getting the response and
they're offering only so much their
credit increase rewards
ok that's a way that Tesla started out
they were small and then the increase
the rewards so if you look historically
at what's been happening and we actually
can be here also observations we may we
talk about culture we talk about
stereotypes differences we talk about
similarities the culture clashes various
different countermeasures how we can
work together and it's going to take a
lot from both sides we talked about the
history vs today stuff that happened and
again vehicle systems well
it's a camera system in a vehicle or
it's an actual rocket booster I mean
each may have its own cataclysmic affect
in any death is is one too many
so any if you have any questions
Dave Shafer dr0 mom let me know i am
open up to questions yes right now you
can you don't mean clap when we get back
okay thank you it's nice having you here
today
yeah so the question is how do I feel
about unlocking vehicles potentials
through automotive cars and he gave an
example of a navigation system
I i think that you know if you if you
could personally I feel that that's cool
i think that we should investigate we
should explore
however i know for a fact that
corporations don't feel that way for
obvious reasons but yeah I think that's
awesome it's like going out by an ass
why shouldn't you go out by an ass and
go ahead and try to see how to get tell
that to it and try to issue different
commands to it absolutely do it any
other questions
okay well obviously there's no
competition but i gotta repeat the
question so i got this little magical
gonna arm and uh it's basically how can
the corporation's compete with with the
dark web you know with otays that are
being auctioned off for like hundreds of
thousands of dollars and stuff like that
obviously they can ok that they can but
they can you know it's it's one of those
things it's not a Chrysler willing to
pay and there is the black market is
always going to offer even if they paid
a hundred thousand dollars the black
market is always going to offer more
it's a nature of things so you know
again arm you know how do you compete
there's you know definitely you know
ethically trying to reach out to people
making them realize that there is
another choice
this is the best way they can compete
try to combat that and maybe people if
they offer the right amount of money
maybe ten thousand dollars it's only ten
percent you know of what in there not
even offering that some programs which
is which is kind of horrible and I've
actually I've actually talk talk to
people and said we're just starting out
small because again i have my contacts
it's not like I'm just come up here
making this stuff up
I actually talk to these people and
organizations were just starting out
small and you know if we don't get a
good response then we will increase it
more likely you know in the future you
know but they have to start somewhere
and on you know and if you give somebody
$10,000 or hundred thousand they may
actually go for the 10,000 just because
it's the right thing to do as opposed
because you want anything hits the black
market you know day you never know what
for government or whoever is going to
use that you know because that's what
people are going to pay for that stuff
right
yeah could be our own government to so
we have a history
anything else okay thank you very much