good afternoon jerk on you guys are
still awake
everybody's work out the hangovers by
now hopefully perfect
there are extra credit points for
bringing beer especially when you bring
one for the speaker but and no one's
done that yet so that's alright so
welcome to what's in your top ten
intelligent apset prioritisation my name
is Tony Miller you guys have seen me
speak before this is going to be a
little uncomfortable for me i'm not used
to being tied to a podium if you see me
before you know that usually I'm all
over the map but hey we'll make things
work
so this is who I am I'm a principal
security engineer I lead the program
services practice at aspect security i
mention their names because they were
the folks kind enough to sponsor my time
and my expenses to be here
they also do this really cool thing of
depositing no unsolicited amounts of
money in my account every you know half
of a month or so I who I am I spent 11
years in apps at application security of
prior to that I spent an additional nine
years as a software developer and some
large financial institutions and so
forth all sorts of fun stuff I've got my
twitter handle their i will give you
fair warning if you decide the hand to
follow me I will probably be one of your
more boring follows on twitter but go
ahead add me anyway you know i'll call
you back
you've also got my email address up
there if after the talk you've got
questions or you want to chat some more
or you just want to tell me men
you suck hey you know I'm here for you
i'll listen up
so what are we going to talk about today
Oh see now here's a man with a plan
we've got beer we're rockin and rollin a
round of applause for this cap
alright so far so good so what we're
going to talk about today this this
nebulous thing I put out there i was
going to tell you all about intelligent
application security prioritization of
what in the world does that mean right
so we're going to talk a lot of all
threat modeling and how we use
that to plan out our security spend and
really focus where we're going to put
security efforts within our
organizations
I know it's late on the second day but I
need a little participation here how
many you guys out there work for say a
decent sized organizations maybe you got
a hundred 200 500 systems you're
responsible for ok pretty unwieldy when
someone says hey you gotta test all that
stuff every so often blah blah blah
right now we're going to test five
hundred things every year something like
that so we're going to talk a little bit
about strategy how we do that we'll use
some threat modeling and some risk
analysis to do that and i'm going to
hopefully show you how to make it real
simple i'm going to talk about why we
should be or why we do threat model for
those of us that you any of you out
there have threat modeling as part of
your security programs today
12 alright so and and that's not a bad
thing I mean that's not uncommon threat
modeling is one of those things we've
been talking about for a long time but
it doesn't really happen all that often
so we're going to talk about why we
don't do it will also get into some
idealism of threat modeling versus the
reality of threat modeling and we're
going to talk about this whole idea how
do we ensure all is not lost you'll see
what i mean when we get there and then
of course let's make it simple right
so keep it simple stupid so why do we
threat model anybody red Adams textbook
pretty good book the same one guy who
does threat modeling is one person read
the book if you're interested in threat
modeling i strongly recommend that book
it's 500 some pages you actually don't
need to read it all at once the first
half is really good to tell you how to
do threat modeling the second half is
all reference for when you're doing that
modeling good book i say that now
because I'm gonna probably beat up on
him a little bit not Adam personally but
the book just there's nothing wrong with
the book but there are some things i
think we can do a little better
why do we do it
first of all it's a way for us to push
security early into the sdlc right we
hear this all the time where people talk
about
hey we gotta do more things early on in
this in the development lifecycle couple
more security there we gotta design
security and our applications
how do we do that threat modeling is one
way that we can start to do that threat
modeling allows us to recognize issues
in how were designing our apps the ideal
threat model that will talk about a
little bit allows you to proactively say
hey if you're going to build an
application that does this you need
these controls to make sure you're going
to keep that application secure before
you ever start developing anything
that's pretty cool
okay um another thing threat modeling
those forces it brings that business
context to our security structure so
we're going to talk about building
security into an application we really
want to understand what that application
does proactively instead of the typical
pentest get handed a nap and okay maybe
we find out some information about what
it does
maybe we discover some information about
what it does just by doing some
reconnaissance this gets us a little
more intelligence from the business side
which can be very effective when we
start talking about what kind of
security controls do we need and then
finally we understand if we're talking
in a large organization now how does
that application contribute to our
overall security posture within the
organization so that's why we want to be
doing throughout modeling that's what
threat modeling was intended to provide
us with but now let's talk about why
don't we
there's a good book out there called
juggling elephants it's one of those
high-level management books that I don't
normally read but this one actually
kinda like the reality is for those of
us especially those of you that said hey
I've got 500 systems are responsible for
we are juggling elephants everything is
a priority we've got all of these
systems each one of them in the owners
mind is a critical priority to the
company in addition just within the
security space we've got all these
conflicting things that were told we
need to do all these security activities
that were supposed to be doing
we're supposed to be doing pen
this was supposed to be doing code
reviews people are telling us we're
supposed to be doing our scans are all
this stuff we need firewalls we need wax
we need this we need that all these
dolphins up in the air
how do we pick the ones that are most
important if we drop any of them they
land on our head
we're done so that becomes a major issue
now we start talking about threat
modeling because now threat modeling
becomes yet another baby elephant that
we want to throw up there and give our
security folks and our development teams
to juggle another problem threat
modeling is what is it really
most people don't really have a clear
understanding of what threat modeling is
in addition if you go out and you try to
research what is threat modeling aside
from again the Shostak book which is
kind of become like the Bible for threat
modeling there's about a thousand other
resources you're going to find and not
one of them agrees with the other one is
threat modeling okay it to it means
something to ever to each individual
person go out there and look at service
companies like my own consulting
companies that offer this is a service
in what you're gonna see is everybody
talks about a little bit differently
everybody offers their own flavor of it
so what that means now if I've got an
organization says hey you know what I
want to push us dlc security
I want to get this threat modeling thing
that her all about into my sdlc because
I've been told that that's an easy way
for me to push all the security farther
into the sdlc the cost of entry is just
astronomical because just trying to
figure out what you're going to do
leaves you searching and searching and
searching so it's time to come up with
your own methodology and are you going
to do it right are going wrong
what is right and as we're going to see
what's right isn't always the same for
each organization and then finally the
reason why organizations don't do threat
modeling today because we as security
folks don't do a good job of
establishing why it's important we talk
about this nebulous idea of hey we're
going to push security over here left in
the software development lifecycle
layers one of those cliches for you want
to push everything left
all ok great i can kind of see as a
manager why that's important but you
know what I've got all this tactical
stuff I've got to worry about i got
people trying to attack me every day I'm
worried about getting firewalls and
keeping them running I'm worried about
putting web application firewalls in
front of my apps I'm worried about my
sim and what's it telling me and how do
I react with all these things I've
already spending maybe millions of
dollars on penetration testing and so
forth now you're telling me we need yet
another security activity
why so we throw this out there as a
threat modeling is this great wonderful
thing we don't really put any context
around it so what we need to do a
security folks is first understand the
value of threat modeling ourselves and
how we can drive that value within our
organizations and then we need to be
able to communicate that and really
display that to our management so they
understand better so hopefully some of
the tools i'm going to give you during
this talk today are going to help you
with that will talk about as we get into
this now some of the ways that we enable
better share of information between
information security and developers how
that saves us money than in the long run
in development and we'll get more into
that as we go on
so for the one person who red Adams book
and for the rest of you who haven't
let's talk a little bit about I the
ideal threat modeling so this is really
according to what Shostak talks about in
that book and this is also what you'll
find most people kind of get as a
general concept the ideal threat
modeling happens during the concept
phase of any application lifecycle so
for building a new application or we're
thinking of bringing something in from a
third-party whatever it is we do threat
modeling at the point that hate we need
this system to do XYZ we're not
designing it yet we're not doing
anything
the intent is we kind of talked about
what is this system going to do what
kind of data is it going how's what
other systems is going to talk to and
then we think about all who
wants to attack that system so and then
from there we can say okay based on this
you need to make sure that when you
build this system so as you're designing
it putting these controls that are going
to address those threats those actors
who would come after us to do us harm in
all these various various different ways
the problem with this many DevOps
developers out there anybody doing
continuous integration
there we go we got a couple kinds of
phase isn't really much of a phase is it
it's hey I got an idea what's right it
there's no time to sit down and stop the
development process for something like
this even if you're in a traditional
waterfall and agile shop oftentimes
things go straight from concept into
design in a heartbeat when we do this
another issue with trying to do threat
modeling that early is we've got no
design context at all so yeah it's great
we throw threat modeling out there we do
it nice and early
hey we're gonna be really proactive
we're going to figure out what the
threats to this system are before we do
any coding and then they can design it
can make sure it's all secure it sounds
great in theory and I see you shaking
your head already and I think I you
probably on the same boat i am maybe
that the problem is without design
context there are design features that
implement new threat or introduce new
threats so if I'm not considering what
that design is going to be there are
potentially threats that go unnoticed
the intent is that we do a lot of this
threat modeling which includes building
you know some data flow diagrams and all
these wonderful things understanding
where the state is going to flow is
going to attack it and we're supposed to
go back and validate that later we're
supposed to do other activities that
we're not doing today to go back and
validate that hey all these things that
we said during our threat model are true
and correct and accurate
so now you're talking about a security
activity that lives on through the
entire lifecycle if your microsoft and
you have the ability to do that kind of
thing in your huge and you're writing
software that's going to be used by
millions
yes you probably have the time and the
effort and the money to spend to do that
the reality is for most of us that's not
something that's going to float if we
try to sell that to our management in
the end if you get threat modeling going
according to this ideal program what you
end up with is what we insecurities
think is great right
security drives the architecture going
to use the technology that we're going
to use and it drives the design of our
applications
sounds good right how many of you work
in any organization where that actually
happens one you work for Microsoft ok i
did i bring that Microsoft is very good
at this and it works for them the
problem is for most of us that ideal
never occurs right
infosecurity does not get the
opportunity to dictate design new
technologies come up all the time that
are driven to be used within our
organizations because they offer some
new functionality or something new and
sexy that somebody wants to add and we
are stuck from a security perspective
having to react to it so the reality is
we don't usually see that ideal the
timing was perfect on that
my friend stephen a smith hey let's be
real here
ok let's talk about what the reality is
what we take more for mag pragmatic
approach to this and realize first of
all we're probably not going to have
much of a concept face where we can
really slow development down if we're in
a DevOps or continuous integration
environment it's just not going to
happen even for an agile yeah we're
writing is writing those stories were
putting them out there maybe maybe we're
gonna have a chance to do this but what
if we push something a little bit later
if we make threat modeling part of our
design phase for some of those more
traditional methodologies or even into
coding if we're talking about you know
continuous integration or so forth or
even god forbid i know this is you know
a horrible thing to say but even maybe
after post-production right so we've got
a continuous integration of our we put
something we have coded that's part of
continuous integration but we still
wanna go back and look at that right and
maybe there's something that threat
modeling can provide us that our
traditional pentesting doesn't it will
look at what that is
by doing this what were able to do as I
said before we can leverage that design
context so now we've got an established
design at minimum or working with our
developers as they're going through that
design and maybe we're talking to them
about some other design ideas
what are some of the things they want to
do what are some of the things that
they're planning some of the
technologies that they want to implement
are they doing single sign-on what type
of provider the using things of this
nature we want to understand those and
the threats that they are going to
potentially introduced so what you get
now is you get security requirements
that are being derived from that
architecture from that technology and
from that design and we'll see how the
speed back loop is going to get set up
and it's going to start to drive us
toward maybe getting to that ideal state
where now we can do this we can
establish security earlier than the
design phase finally
if we're able to do this this becomes
something that's repeatable when we have
redesigns often times I've seen
organizations they're not many out there
that do it but there are some who do
have an early early threat model
methodology they do it once when they
create a new application and it's gone
that's all they do
by pushing a little later into design
phase now if I know I've got a major
rewrite or we're gonna replace an
application with something else now I've
got a repeatable process that i can use
that fits into those spaces as well so
let's delve a little bit deeper and I
promised these are going to get less
textual and a little bit easier to read
as we go but let's talk about what we're
looking at when we do this architecture
design first of all by doing this threat
modeling as part of the architecture and
design we are able to identify design
patters what are the common things that
were doing it for implementing single
sign-on that's a design pattern
hopefully hopefully there's a standard
way that we do single sign-on or we can
start to define one do we have specific
providers that we use are we a
siteminder shop and we're going to
always implement site minor or do we
have specific implementations for things
like off those types of things we can
pull in as specific design patterns we
identify them and we can start to use
our threat modeling to not only pull
those out but later on as well see we
can use the threat modeling to actually
enhance those design patterns when we
start to identify these patterns we can
also start to refine our threat models
and make the threat modeling better by
linking those common threats that we
know are part of this particular design
pattern back to that pattern now we see
that pattern in our threat model
hey were able to call that out we may
have specific strategies and specific
diet design guidance as will see that
goes along with that because we have a
design hopefully we have some concept of
where security controls are so as ice
to identify threats I'm also able to
look at some of the security controls
that were planning to implement and now
we determine if I have them but how
about their relative strengths and their
type those are things that are going to
be important that helped me better
define maybe changes that are needed or
improvements are needed within that
application design and then finally as i
said this design for this activity
drives are proactive design
specifications that so we may have
design in process now I have a way that
i can affect that design that's
intelligent is based on the threats i'm
going to see what cakes into account
some of the things that have already
been done in the work done by our
development team someone to talk to you
a little bit about the methodology and
this is ok literally how are we going to
go about this threat modeling so I I've
thrown a lot of ethereal stuff at you
this all sounds really well and good but
what are we really doing so we come down
to a threat model this is not dissimilar
from what you would see if you go out
and read a book on threat modeling one
popular and I've talked about a few
times the first part of this really is
just to capture what is that design now
depending on your development shop what
type of methodology they follow maybe
they've got some type of design work
done for you maybe this is something
you're going to create but the best way
to do this is simply and this is
something that you this is something
that is a common theme throughout threat
modeling is to get together these
whiteboarding workshops where you can
sit down with the stakeholders and walk
through that design understand what the
design looks like and then start to
document the data flows so if I
understand what data is in there i
understand how it flows this system
doing this is a collaborative session is
very important
what you start to see as you do this and
you're working through as I said you've
got developers you've got systems
architects and application architecture
building this they start to ask you
questions as a security engineer
hey I'm thinking of doing this what do
you think of this idea or what I need to
be careful if I do that and so more so
than even just your threat model now
you've started to build this
collaboration between your security
people and your development teams your
project teams now have that open line of
communication and this is a vast value
add to this process this is the type of
thing that now you can start to
establish real returns from the activity
you're doing that extend beyond just hey
we're going to this threat model this
application so what does this look like
we've captured the design we've captured
the data flows it ends up looking
something like this
now what you see when you get into
threat modeling everybody's got their
own different ways that they like to
capture this stuff
certainly you know there's a threat
modeling tools out there that draw their
own does their own diagrams in certain
ways
everybody's got their own methodology
this just happens to be the one that I
use that aspect
ok so what you see here the key part so
that you'll notice that go beyond your
typical threat modeling data flow
diagram is that we've got actual
components of the application
represented here you can see things like
road load balancers in web proxies so
things at an architecture level that are
being represented we've got different
constructs within the application itself
UC web servers and other things those
are all things that kind of get lost if
we do threat modeling too early if we
don't have that design context
those are things that we lose you see up
here as well specifications as far as
the different communication paths you
see we've got sequel and HTTPS and all
the different protocols labeled and so
forth
capturing these again that's context and
oftentimes maybe we define as part of
the threat model but isn't there for
doing the threat model before any design
works been done
everything we do the rest of the model
is based on what we see here so this is
why it's important to get this right
this is why a collaborative session
where we're doing things on a whiteboard
and working with developers who can
immediately see how we're understanding
what they're telling us and can correct
what we're making mistakes on we may
even have the architects help us draw
those types of things they may put their
own spin in there
this becomes a valuable valuable piece
not only for the threat modeling that
we're doing but obviously this type of
documentation for any system a lot of us
don't have this typically in our
projects today so now we've got
something that's additional value down
the road for that particular application
so now we've got the dataflow the next
thing we want to do is talk about where
are the controls that are already
planned what are the intending to
implement what type of authentication
what type of authorization what type of
logging features are they looking at all
of the different security controls that
you can think of break those down into
categories and start to represent those
in our diagram what are they doing to
protect us against things like
cross-site scripting so do they have
controls for input validation and i'll
put encoding things of that nature
once we have that general idea
now we can start to look at threats now
let's look at who are those threat
actors what are the things that they're
going to look to do to our system
what's the data they're going to be
after where are they going to attempt to
take over system or potentially
denial-of-service what I cannot really
want to attempt to deny service
ok so this is where we start to think
about you people who are you guys her
stride before stride ring a bell to
hopefully if couple 123
alright so we don't want stride we're
talking about just categories of attacks
right we've got spoofing and tampering
repudiation so forth
this is now where we start to draw that
in and so what you can see here is just
one way
that you could potentially represented
the way we do it here is you've got a
number of different threat actors
represented and the relative risk
rankings in terms of likelihood impact
and overall risk of each of those
threats so we start to identify those we
show the the attack paths which are
denoted there with red so this is the
type of thing that we're looking to
understand at this point now we start to
see okay here based on how the system is
architected and the technologies that
are at play
now we have a better understanding of
where they attacking us how are they
attacking us
so where do I either need to validate
that the controls we have designed are
sufficient or where we potentially
missing controls that need to be added
to this environment so as you can
imagine the last pieces that controls
analysis so now that we understand who
are threats are where they come from
they may be internal they may be
external we understand the different
types of attacks we may see we
understand where those attacks are
targeted now we need to understand the
controls that we have in place the
controls here are represented by
triangles again
your mileage may vary whatever works for
you is fine but we're trying to
represent here is the relative strength
of those controls and their location
within the system so that now we can
visualize how those address the attack
and those threats that we identified
earlier in this case the colors are
important you know colors aren't always
the greatest thing i will say i think
it's something like twenty five percent
of the population is colorblind so you
know you you may not want to use colors
to represent but in this case blue are
strong green are sufficient and so on
and so forth
there's no right up there but if I had
any controls that were outright missing
those would be represented in red again
i put this up here not to break that
this is like some great wonderful thing
that we do so well but more to spur
ideas for you on ways that you can
represent this again you'll find if you
search the happy interwebs you'll find
plenty of information different ideas on
how to draw a diagram similar to this
but hopefully this provide some context
for you
I'm talking about so i said i was going
to talk to you about this site this
concept of ensuring that all is not lost
if we look at traditional threat
modeling we have that ideal hey we're
gonna put this early in the life cycle
we are discussed why that doesn't happen
if i go out and look at say different
organizations who offer threat modeling
services will see many of them sell
threat modeling and just like the way
they would sell pen test or anything
else it's this one time I come in I do
an assessment boom here's your threat
model is and your report the key to
threat modeling is ensuring that we get
more out of it than just hey you need to
change your design of your application
this one time and make this one design
better in these following ways right we
get that from pentest all the time right
we do a pen testing is my application
i'm gonna spit out reports got a bunch
of hey you've got this moment is
literally this vulnerability fix it this
way this way this way that's great it's
really prescriptive it gives me some
actionable stuff but then it goes away
and once they start making changes to my
system that pen test is no longer valid
and it means very little going forward
for pen testing may conduct in the
future so what we want to do with threat
models we don't want to sit out in an
island like this threat modeling is not
something that becomes a one-time
activity we just do and it's done as i
said before as security experts we want
to drive more value we want our
management to be able to understand why
this is so effective and what it's going
to mean from a larger sense i'll use one
of those cliché terms we wanted to look
holistic I shudder at the word but
because it gets overused far too often
but the fact of the matter is we want
something that's going to impact our
entire application security program not
just be this one-time event so we're
gonna look at ways that threat modeling
helps us effect change in the sdlc there
is a loop of feedback between the threat
model and the sdlc the obvious
is the threat model providing that
design information things that we need
to change about this particular app that
we just threat models but we'll we'll
see some more strategic ways that we can
use threat modeling to better our
overall software development we can also
use threat modeling to drive better
security testing whether those be
application pentest vulnerability scans
code reviews whatever it is that we're
doing today from security activity
perspective we can use threat modeling
to give us a better overall coverage and
rigor within those activities and then
as we kind of mentioned as though the
title of this talk suggest how do we
plan our security going forward so the
last part of this will look at how can i
use threat modeling to help me build an
overall risk picture of all my
applications so i understand not only
what applications are higher risk for me
but maybe what types of threats are
common what types of data are common
where does that data exists which
divisions of my organization and so
forth so start by looking at how we feed
the sdlc so the sdlc ties into threat
modeling as we said we're going to look
at initially how do we tie this in from
the design phase onward and we're going
to go out we're going to do this threat
model going to get all this wonderful
information but we do with that
information really i mentioned before
that we're looking for design patterns
right so as I'm going through and I
start to implement a threat modeling
program within my organization one of
the things we're going to start to see
pretty quickly is that there are common
design patterns across our applications
some of you may already be aware of some
of these today you might have specific
implementation guidance that pertains to
certain design patterns
this enables you to expand on that or
created if you don't have it today so as
we start to see these different design
patterns now we can start to identify
and document on
and provide reference architectures and
implementation guidance to our
development teams for how they execute
these design patterns if you're going to
deploy say an application into a sure
what type of authentication do we
require as an organization
maybe we tie these back to best
practices but we want Taylor to what is
important to us if you read the abstract
on this talk
one of the key things you what secure
for one company is another company's
disaster right depending on our needs
depending on our risk posture depending
on our risk tolerance this can vary so
we want these design guides to fit what
makes sense for our organization now the
feedback from that on the flip side is
the sdlc can now provide us information
back into the threat modeling
methodology specifically emerging
technologies as i said before if when
we've probably all experience this at
some point you get out there and you
know that technology is changing new
technologies are developers going to use
it all the time maybe we're in an
organization that is never seen no Jas
before and suddenly that's what
everybody wants to use because it's new
and sexy it's not so new and sexy
anymore but it was a couple years ago
arm
those are things that now the sdlc
starts feeding back into threat modeling
that now we can consider as a part of
our threat models going forward
additionally yes we're going to provide
this great design guidance and some of
this you know these recommendations as
part of our are different from model
activities but developers are pretty
cool right
they'll see something lot of times they
no way to do it better or they may come
up with something that we hadn't thought
of from a security perspective that
addresses it in a different way that
maybe we like a lot better so now from
the sdlc we can start to drive those
design improved design patterns back
into the threat model so that our future
threat models take into account the
lessons learned
from previous cycles of software
development when we look at security
testing so let's assume for a moment
that we've got our threat modeling
program in place and we're doing this
we've also got a pretty robust program
for doing our code reviews doing our
application pentest and so forth threat
modeling can help us refine that and
actually drive some efficiency there
throughout modeling one of the things we
can do is very easily identify test
cases so we're gaining quite a bit of
business context into that application
we're gaining quite a bit of technical
context into the design of that
application as we document these things
these can start to drive very targeted
test cases when it comes time to do a
penetration test we're talking about
those specific controls that we
implemented within this application
that's great information we get ready to
start doing a code review where do we
want to direct our efforts in a code
review
yeah maybe we're running some cool
automated tool to do a lot of that
static analysis but maybe we put a
little extra manual time to look at that
single sign-on that they implemented or
that you know funky authorization
construct that they decided to use so in
the end threat modeling gives us that
ability to now refine the security
testing and ultimately make that now
more effective more efficient as well
on the flipside coming back security
testing certainly will potentially
identify new threat vectors for us maybe
something new technology has been used
and something we didn't consider when we
went to the threat model gets identified
through security testing now we have a
lesson to be learned right we can take
that put that back into the threat model
future applications that use a similar
design pattern now can learn from the
lessons that were taught in that
previous design
additionally we can improve that
implementation guidance again i said
before developers are really cool people
are really smart they come up with a lot
of neat ideas that
security people didn't even think of
I've been there more than once in shit
no threat model where you sit down and a
developer throw something funny and it's
like you know what I never thought to do
that that's pretty darn cool so we can
use those as well this is a great way
that now we've enabled
information-sharing from may be
completely separate development
divisions within our organization and
now we're able to leverage that combined
knowledge and that combined expertise in
new ways that hey you know what we we
didn't have that before because maybe
those developers aren't talking maybe
that information didn't get shared
before now there's a conduit for that
and then finally this concept of
security prioritisation so we've all
many of us at least myself included have
been in those organizations where we
have an overwhelming amount of systems
and applications and such that we need
to make sure our secure we have no idea
how this all ties together we may not
know where the hotspots are sometimes we
have a general idea just through tacit
knowledge we know that hey this
application over here pretty much stinks
it's a steaming pile we know what these
guys over here do something really good
but what if we can provide a clear
picture to management on where the
problem areas lie where certain
divisions have more risk to worry about
or more vulnerabilities and more threats
to worry about then maybe other
divisions now you've got a way to
justify the money you want to spend when
you go and you say we need this in our
application security program and their
first question is why now you have the
answers so one of the things we drive
out of threat modeling or we can drive
out of threat modeling is this idea of
an application risk rating and in
literally 10 minutes couple
easy questions that you would ask the
threat model anyway you can start to
establish the risk rating for these
applications that now leverages the
information that you're gaining through
your threat model its transformable so
that you can provide it to
decision-makers to look at any different
way from Sunday whether they want to see
it by divisions or by operating systems
or by no pci data or whatever your
concerns are there are ways to melt that
the feedback then from that is that your
security planning can refine your
methodologies whether it's in threat
modeling security testing or otherwise
based on those risk levels maybe we've
got low-risk applications we say you
know what we're not going to pay some
consultants sixty thousand dollars to
come in and do a two-week dynamic
analysis and code analysis on this
application
it's low risk maybe we have some
automated tools that instead we can
enable our developers or security
architects to run and provided a certain
level of assurance for those low-risk
applications
that's a little less than what we want
to do for our high-risk applications
that oh yeah by the way are the crown
jewels of the organization and need that
extra attention so what I'm going to
show you now is a a tool and I'm doing
this because I promise you if you read
the abstract that this is what i was
going to do was show you a tool
this isn't meant to be something that
hey here go use this run it this is
again meant to be an example of
something you can do what you're going
to see is something that is built in
Microsoft Excel now it's in Excel
because it
excel is easy it's portable and
everybody has it arm ideally you'd like
to see this be in some type of database
or some other robust system maybe a web
application something of that nature but
to show you how quickly and easily get
something like this spun up i'm gonna
show you this in microsoft excel so
we're going to hold
then pray that the monitor still reacts
the way it did before because this is
when i was ten and god only knows
ok so what you have in front of you here
is what I finally refer to as the as
role or the application security risk
level this is a tool as I said built in
Excel that allows me to capture
information about an application that i
would be capturing anyway during a
threat model the difference here is that
I'm capturing this information and it
pertains to risk as much as architecture
as much as security and by capturing
this information i'm able to define a
scoring model behind the scenes that
then develops for me a risk level now I
break this down into five risk levels
again your mileage may vary
maybe you want to establish more maybe
you want to establish fewer that's
entirely up to you but what you'll see
here is that there's five risk levels
and what we use this for is now I can go
out and I can do that prioritization i
can say hey you know what
here let's break this down into
applications and that within a specific
division i can see this set this
divisions got a lot of high-risk
applications divisions got a lot of
low-risk applications now I know where I
need to spend my attention from a
security perspective so before before I
get too far into this questionnaire i'm
going to show you just really quickly
the way this is all driven and i mean
this this is actually kind of cool and
usable so I've got a section here where
I can define my business lines which
then gets pulled in later i can define
business systems so I talk about
business systems i'm talking about
high-level this might include multiple
software systems multiple applications
multiple groups of people so you see
things here like vendor payments and I
you see sales leads and accounts payable
and so forth these are your business
systems things to find a business level
the heart of this is really the
application inventory so here's all the
applications that i know i've got within
this organization that fit into those
business systems that are within those
business lines and as you can see this
is all tied together each of these you
know in this case is kind of a cool
little excel all these are tied together
these are dropdowns
that are generated if i select a
business system here if I couldn't say a
new application will say the marketing
portal
I can almost type and then you know
through selection it will assign the
other pieces are not terribly important
again this is just to give you some
ideas of what you could do with this
in this case its software base so now
from here I resource the applications
that generates my happy macros yes for
using macros in excel dangerous scary
stuff but I trust because I wrote it or
well someone in my organization wrote it
I won't claim responsibility for that
event now I've got this new application
and I want to complete this as role and
freaked out on me that's ok we'll use
the one that's here so we look at this
application and you can see it's got
things in here basic stuff we about when
it was profiled and so forth but right
away we jump into starting to understand
the risk you know what's the
classification of information being
processed or transmitted uh you know how
large is the user population what's the
applications primary architecture type
things like that so we capture all these
we break we've broken them down as you
can see they're actually all you know in
this case again to make its coral and
auto and very automated they're just
simple drop-down list and what that ends
up giving me is then this profile report
where I've got some basic
transformations you can expand this and
certainly we typically would you can see
that can break it down by specific
business lines i can go even into
divisions and specific business systems
and start to get a view of what's out
there within my organization you ask NEC
so go out there and hand them something
like this and say I can tell you across
the organization where highest risks are
from an application perspective from
security perspective this is a CISOs
dream so again really simple tool here
implementing something like this of your
own is a great way to leverage what
we're doing in threat modeling
to really enable us to take it to the
next level and start to build that
prioritization like i said before from
here now you can see I've got a 05 which
is our highest risk all the way down as
well three
now I can start attaching different
levels of application security rigor
different activities and perform based
on the risk level of these applications
so with that um I'm going to wrap things
up because we are getting down to the
end of time I just want to make sure
that i left a few minutes here for any
questions if there are any from the
group so yes have my published a
template anywhere for which the the the
diagrams or the the tool the spreadsheet
no not at this point like I said it's
kind of more it's one idea arm I it is
probably something I can share with you
though if you want actually let me go
back to the top of put my email back up
there you guys can contact me
I'll see to if there is a good way to
share it arm because yeah I mean it
would definitely be helpful something
you can build off of
so that's a good question any other
questions
okay all right well you guys continue to
have a great khan hopefully always
something the drawings tonight
appreciate the beers or you are awesome
as always
hopefully we'll see you next year and
i'll take care we'll see on down the
road