okay welcome back we're going to resume
with Aaron policy 2014 Nash to improving
a thoughtful NT flip language and point
out that we have an hour and 20 minutes
to get through these so history
january2014 than policy proposal build
our only the long the Shepherd's the
policy text you have in front of you in
online same questions as always is this
fair and impartial technically sound
that's supported by the community
problem statement current language
suicide peace within the Arab region
must not have received a transfer
allocation or assignment of ID number
resources for marrying for 12 months
prior to rule of transfer for us this
tradition is not applied to a man a
transfer so I'm going to have a extra
nettle to Chris me i'm going to have dan
get up and do this so I hit the morning
so the gist of what the author of this
proposal is suggesting is that when the
the anti flip language was originally
incorporated into the the transfer
requirements the intent was so that
people wouldn't obtained an allocation
from
then turn around and sell it and then go
back for more but what they're
suggesting is that the current wording
poses a problem in that large companies
with subsidiaries and and that our
collection of organizations they can't
transfer blocks within themselves
because they run up against this in time
flipping language so what they had
proposed as to add the red text to the
existing section to exempt the transfers
within organizations and their
subsidiaries and that is the gist of the
change
so the questions become should an
organization you fired from from
transferring an existing plot to another
rir as part of a reorganization just
because they've received assignments or
does the chloe clause and its
subsidiaries open this policy language
to abuse and based on your opinion if
you have any suggestions for alternative
worry sorry thank you for being so
succinct and trying to get back on a
track invite if anybody in the room
would like to comment on this I see mr.
Howard standing thank you sir Lee Howard
fulfilling my regular role can you
actually flip back to the proposed
language it's only one sentence this
looks to me like the intent of this
proposal is to affect organizations
rather than blocks and my understanding
of the anti flipping licenses is that it
would affect block the idea is if you've
been able to convince somebody to
transfer a block of addresses to you
then you shouldn't be able to flip that
same block of addresses that should be
locked down for 12 months of incidence
and it doesn't affect an M&A transfers
which is sort of implied as currently we
sort of implied a question about in the
in the next slide of ethical questions
so I guess what I'd like to see is a
restriction on transferring blocks of
addresses rather than what organizations
can do so you propose anti flipping
approach which is based on a block that
has been transferred being prohibited
from transfer for a certain amount of
time okay but that's actually not what
the current language says the current
language is the language in black which
simply applies to organizations so this
enhances the current language and the
current approach proposed a different
tack on it which may or may not be
better but is a different way of solving
that problem
find that this is completed a long road
okay by the way is very Susan does this
might now we're good for this trip
George I need to use this one as well
I'll just try for this the multi
participants can't carry let me know
thanks Scott lab ran an errand AC
responding to these comment and the
language that's in black that is
currency was intended to prevent the
case where someone gets has a bunch of
space gets a new block from Aaron and
then goes and sells off their other
space that they already have so this is
based on the idea that IP addresses can
be somewhat fungible if you have dynamic
addressing and such and so just
restricting the individual block that
you receive from them being transferred
out doesn't fix the problem if you have
another block that you can just transfer
it instead so that's the reason for the
current black deck the proposal here
asserts that that is a to restrictive
form of anti flipping and that there
should be a caveat that if you're not
going and selling it off on the market
to someone else but you're just
transferring it to your own subsidiary
that that should be fine now the
language that you're talking about i
think actually might be in the other
side of the transfer policy already
there there may be a individual block
insightful think there are different
types of anti flipping language in
section 8 already this is one of them
and the author feels it is to determine
wants to relax it so that's the part
that we are discussing but i think the
lock based stuff is already elsewhere or
was
to be not good enough when we originally
did a three mr. librarian review on is
that just a community of a view on the
proposal as well that's a comment as
remember the AC I hadn't yet formed an
opinion on this and community feedback
thank you mister Howard you escaped
unfortunately without stating as such I
believe okay oh yes you're quite right
after it is you say that a ring he is
quite correct let me just turn the right
brain again there we go thank you it's
necklace brandon ross network utility
force I am staunchly against this policy
I believe that anything that reduces the
liquidity of ipv4 space trading hurts
all of us and makes it more difficult to
continue propping up ipv4 for as long as
we need you to get fees okay opposed got
it that time for sure as you get it yeah
I got that time I apologize to mr.
Howard again don't all approach the
mikes at once and if we have any remote
participants perhaps hopefully they can
hear what I've been told to switch back
to this mic so they can hear it they
can't hear me too bad for them more
feedback none standing a pathway maybe
again it's been pointed out to me that I
may have misinterpreted the policy so
I'll need to reread it so you can
withdraw my objection furnace so
withdrawn
so we'll close the mics or ask anyone
remotely to start typing seen shaking of
head your homies are quiet I'll need a
moment after that so I think we've
gotten some feedback on this unless I'm
mr. Sweeting you'd like any further
feedback for the AC okay thank you all
for your consideration on this and we
will all turn it back over to John thank
you I remind everyone to speak close to
the mics when you're speaking of ledge
you got a live one andrew dahl comment
this policy proposal makes a significant
change to the ability of an organization
to transfer a block outside the errand
service region until the inter rir
transfer policy was adopted the ability
of an organization to move their block
to another region was largely restricted
thank you Andrew I'll now turn it over
to John again okay we're going to pick
up on schedule next policy proposal is
draft policy 2000 remove the 82 83 and
84 minimum ipv4 block size requirements
okay as noted this is a new policy
proposal submitted in January the
Shepherd's are owned along and built
dark it was accepted as a draft policy
by the AC it is a work in progress and
so the AC is trying to figure out if
it's good number policy is it fair and
impartial is it technically sound and is
it supported I'll turn it over to Dan to
give the AC presentation close to it so
on this one this one's actually even
shorter than the previous one ok
so this one's actually a little shorter
than even the other one in that what the
author is suggesting is in the current
sections of the the transfer proposals
there is a / 24 minimum saying only
blocks of a 24 or larger will actually
be accepted as a transfer what he's
suggesting here is that that requirement
be removed and any size be allowed so
essentially section 8 2 3 & 4 just
remove the sections that remove the
clauses that say a minimum transfer size
of a / 24 so what we're soliciting here
is opinions about whether that's a good
idea bad idea and whether it should be
allowed what are some of the
implications discuss mr. Howard it's
great to remember my name Lee having to
come up and identify myself because
that's the rules Lee Howard this is a
terrible idea please don't do this would
you like my opinion are you in favor
against so this is essentially proposing
that not only deck chairs but individual
components of decks chairs made me
rearranged this is stupid before is dead
deploy these days thank you me what
anyone else like to come a concept here
it's a very simple proposal Scott Scott
library with limelight networks down but
mostly speaking for myself just not in a
seat
um okay for a while viewing there are a
number of organizations that have
requested transfers of / 32 because they
don't understand how the internet works
and they want their IP address I think
there are even individuals who requested
strands of / 32 these may have may or
may not have gotten to Aaron as actual
request but there are people who want to
transfer their IP I don't believe that
our policy should allow such if there is
a good technical justification for
reducing the minimum transfers eyes from
24 to something smaller I might need for
that but eliminating completely is a bad
idea thank you Scott Stacey do we have
any remote participation you got one
Stacy will check her homies I think I'm
slightly uncomfortable saying that I
don't know why that's true we're going
to be closing the mics if there is a no
feedback on this proposal stacy is
shaking your head I will turn it back
then thank you very much for the
feedback and I will turn it over to John
thank you sir ok we're going to resume
with draft policy Aaron 2014 dash for
which is remove the 4 to 5 web hosting
policy
okay another new policy proposal January
of this year John Springer and Andrew
dull are the our shepherds it's in your
discussion guide and available online it
has been posted to PP ml and is a
percentage for the community for
discussion the AC is looking for
feedback regarding whether it's fair and
impartial technically sound and
supported by the community and I will
now turn it over to John Springer to do
the AC presentation thank you John hello
ladies and gentlemen good morning so
this may look familiar this is an item
that is substantially similar to
something else we looked at earlier the
problem statement on this particular
proposal is draft policy is section 4.25
is technology specific language that is
not current with modern network
operation needs and practices we should
remove it to make in RPM clearer there's
the the current wording it's been in
place since july of 2001 it's I say
functionally identical to the last
bullet item of 2013 7 the the differing
problem statement is there the author
has been asked and answered that he
would specifically like it submitted and
considered separately from 2013 dash 7
and would like it considered
independently however I think the AC if
we decide to move 2013 7 to recommend a
draft policy will do something else with
this
it should be noted that although the
draft policy says that information will
be collected and analyzed that it has
not been and that it's not necessary to
do so going forward does the community
see a need for this information to be
collected and possibly analyzed discuss
your shocking presentational thank you
John Springer and I did confirm also
with John Sweeting so yes if obviously
as a clarification of 2013 7 was to be
adopted this would render this null yes
this is the observation but it is
effectively the same change or part of
sorry of 2013 7 so we have discussed
this earlier but I will open it up again
if somebody wishes to bring up a new
issue or comment we did get some
feedback on web hosting earlier today
how's the break and some caffeine
changed anybody's views or if you could
ask staci your homies if they've got
anything
Lee Howard even this will not cause you
to I've just got to give it a little
time in case the remote the snow is
causing some increased latency
unfortunately sowwy yeah well they don't
they don't have to protect it they don't
expect it's no nuts okay calling it once
twice three times close thank you very
much I will turn it back over thank you
John Springer turn over to John turn to
mini John thank you very much okay
moving right ahead next policy proposal
is policy proposal draft policy outer
air in 2014 dash five which is remove
7.2 lane delegations k introduced in
january 2014 stacy hughes and rod seized
from are the shepherds it was accepted
as a draft policy the arid advisory
council it's available in your guide and
online it has been posted to be pml the
iron advisory council needs your
feedback regarding whether it's good
number policy is it fair and impartial
is a technically sound and is it
supported by the community and i will
now turn it back to John Springer to do
the AC presentation if you in case you
haven't noticed these are attempts to do
some in rpm cleanup section 7.2 was
established a decade ago but the audit
function that it requires were never put
in place the author asserts that
lameness and adder in in adder is
orthogonal to demonstrate a neat and
it's in as such shouldn't be in policy
and how to run things like who is
I are our components should not be in
policy there is the policy statement and
implications so generally we try to keep
operational practice out of it in our PM
a question for the community is is there
something special about inner hat or
DARPA that makes it different and if so
does that extend to ip6 DARPA properly
running an adder like the choice of an
upstream provider may affect an ISPs
end-user experience but it is that any
of errands business anybody have
anything to say thank you John Springer
you're all very quiet when it comes to
removing sections interesting ask anyone
online too quickly comment or someone in
the room and like to speak perhaps Lee
Howard shortly how I remember having
this to be was 12 years ago no not quite
this was actually my first policy
proposals a shepherd when I was back on
the AC I remembered well I remember had
fairly emotional debates about how badly
miss was and that it was fundamentally
broken and I opposed this proposal thank
you sir central Mike juice tonight pini
I'm that really care with you do the
same rocks obviously but I do know
however in some recent work on securing
the routing system an alternative
proposal to our pico I actually based it
so completely and it's trust
reverse dns and it was a thing coming
called Roebuck and the idea was it
pushed information in the DNS SEC sign
reverse dns and then pulled out
credentials so if we will walk from this
we're walking away from that as well in
theory so just be aware that some folk
have differing assumptions as to what
the reverse DNS is good for and you
might not find that everyone wants to
walk away at the same speed as you thank
you liked it don't care one way or the
other thank you Jeff no central
microphone my brand question for staff
in community my impression from the ppl
all discussion is that since Aaron
changed to using a per zone per block
model that they haven't really been
doing this per server based thing that
we instructed them to do a decade ago or
whatever long it's been and therefore
removing this doesn't actually change
operational practice however if as Lee
suggested that is something that still
is needed or if has Jeff suggested there
may be other reasons for doing something
it would seem that we actually need new
guidance to Aaron as to what they should
be doing in the new world of delegation
of individual blocks and it's hard to
say this server is entirely bad if it's
just as one block that's not responding
etc etc so i think we either need to get
rid of this or we need to have a new
proposal that does the opposite but the
current status quo is rather silly
because we're instructing to do Aaron to
do something they can't do and that's
dumb yeah in 2009 mark gave a
presentation of Aaron meeting where he
noted that the definition of lame for a
server when what you're testing is
individual zones is somewhat not
canonical and therefore needed
clarification from the community if
folks want to remove this from a dress
policy that's
that clarifies the situation obviously
if folks want us to do something here it
is possible for us to go to the step of
marking servers for blocks that aren't
responsive going to the next step of
actual removal I will say once I
understand what you're advocating we
need to do a legal review because it's
not clear that removal of servers from
records is a fair risk trade-off for
Aaron to do so I what I need is I need
either you guys to remove it or for you
to indicate that you want to proceed
with marking and or marking and
stripping one or the other though I do
agree Scott and thanks to the good
people at Google just for to clarify it
was 2005 that this policy went in rear
microphone speaking of Google the
existing policy that we're proposing to
remove all together already says that
you should remove lane servers so not
sure why you're saying that you need
legal review teresa's you should remove
if the community wants us to strip the
DNS records of lame servers I'd like a
canonical definition of lame added to
this policy because when we do that and
someone comes back and says you impacted
our business I want to say yes we you
y'all you impacted their business and
right now you've not given us that
canonical definition that can be coded
so Heather yes but no as as reported in
2009 we can't and we asked for Clara
definition then so feel free to start
working on it now any other comments
well that was a lame discussion oh come
on I've been waiting since 2005 to use
that no and with that humorous moment or
lack thereof will close the mics if
there is no remote participation Thank
You Stacey do my best field on here here
coming to the audience with the Andrew
dull question for operators to operators
believe that one of erin's operational
role is to brought provide feedback to
operators on the status of their reverse
DNS zones given ret nanog and there are
operators here does anyone wish to
address mr. dolls clothes and Rudolph
question Sentret left microphone you
have delegated the zone to me and
especially at my request to the servers
that I have designated and that sort of
proves to be unresponsive to that for
that delegation then yeah I think you
ought to tell me that I will also point
out that I did do a quick search to see
if there's an existing definition of
lame delegation and I didn't see one
provided by IETF but lack nick has a
pretty good version thank you any other
responses to Andrew dolls question two
operators we have another one and the
remote AV is apparently non-functional
refresh your browser of course you need
to have your AV working you hear me say
that but hopefully they can Stacey well
pass that on
I take no position on this particular
proposal but I would observe that
removing servers for having a lane
delegation pointed to them would be
potentially problematic if someone else
pointed the delegation to them thank you
we're back thank you but with that I
will close the microphones unless
there's anyone else who wants to comment
either on the policy or the question
that Andrew quickly posed thank you all
for your feedback all pass it back to
John Curran for the next item excellent
so we are moving ahead to draft policy
Erin 2014 dash six move section 71
maintaining inadar okay hey hey okay per
policy proposal 198 introduced in
january 2014 rob's eastern and chasey
hues of the shepherds it's been accepted
as a draft policy and posted online in
the discussion guide it is a work in
progress and the AC need your feedback
on it regarding it whether it's fair and
impartial technically sound or supported
by the community and once again it will
turn it over to drown Springer so
another in rpm cleanup policy proposal
the author observes that seven dot one
attempts to dictate operational practice
again for managing in a DARPA and
operational practice Auden ought to be
in the NRP m7 dot one is silent on ip6
DARPA which works fine thus
demonstrating that Aaron staffs
technical judgment on implementation is
as usual sufficient policy proposal
recommendation is to remove 7 dot 1
entirely again operational practice
generally doesn't go in the NR p.m. does
the community feel that there's
something about an attitude r / that
makes it different and if such a
condition exists does it extend to ip6
darpa over here this time thank you John
more more reverse dns more rule leave
you can beat rear microphone 6 anybody
like see me playing ping-pong these
policies so move ian adams put this back
in to policies for the same thing what's
going on stop spinning to enter p.m. for
years and don't we have better things to
do thanks can I take that as non support
I could care less could you a little
closer we're having no trouble here so I
pv policy 654 already delegated ip6 out
right to the recipient if we take Alan
both policies and there's nothing
guiding Jones that's your interpretation
now you said 75 presently does where 656
reverted up 656 seems to be fairly clear
that we delegate responsibility for the
reverse look up zone and that service
providers who do assignments out of an
allocation in turn delegate to this any
organization the responsibility of the
assignee asks it's fairly complete
you're saying it doesn't work without 70
I suit you're saying right I see it's
the fall it would be nice i guess to
have language that actually relates to
reverse lookup in the ipv4 policy to
make it clear and that's probably a good
clean up if section 7 goes away thank
you I would read it parallel is a
parallel construction of policies makes
sense in this case and I would like that
too to include reverse addressing that's
if your authoritative for addresses then
you want to be other words
for the zone thank you well there's a
sight for sore eyes haven't seen you in
a while Leo victa all farsighted
security could you go back to the party
second yes I just wanted to take issue
with the bottom point while I do not
have a top of my head the exact
statistic for how much ipv6 has been
deployed I will quote Geoff Huston
roughly earlier that it is a barren
wasteland on the edges of the internet i
think is how he phrased it I'm not sure
that taking the current state of ipv6 as
representative of well anything is a
good idea so I that bullet point just
struck me as all kinds of wrong and no
view on the proposal just that's a
comment or I think I think Martin kind
of touched more on my general thought I
think Aaron needs somewhere some policy
on amader DARPA it is quite clear to me
that there are many policy proposals
attempting to adjust that in multiple
ways and depending on which was which
are passed or do not pass we could end
up in a really good or a totally absurd
place and so given that there are so
many I don't know how to take a position
on one your point is taken thank you
will close the mics if there's no
there's no more participation oh there
is Ramon sorry i thought i saw a shaking
head there I'm call it of course at any
time Stacey user Andrew dull at this
time I post I am opposed to this policy
while I agree the text is out of date
and probably should be updated I don't
necessarily agree that the section
should be removed reverse DNS is an
important part of the services that
Aaron provides to address holders I
believe that is wholly appropriate for
the N RPM I got you Andrew to contain a
section describing how it Aaron should
implement our DNS services to address
holders Thank You Stacey thank you
Andrew and thank you everyone for your
feedback
on this thank you John Springer and
remember to john curran I think we've
caught up on time yes we have so back on
schedule here we're going to move ahead
to draft policy Aaron 2014 dare 7 the
section 4.4 micro allocation
conservation update very good okay
history was submitted as Aaron proposal
200 in january 2014 Andrew dull and Rob
see strim the Shepherd's the policy text
has been put online as in your
discussion guide it is a draft policy
that has been presented for community
discussion the AC need your feedback
regarding whether or not it's fair and
impartial technically sound and
supported by the community I'm going to
turn it over to Dan now I think yes Stan
very good and he'll give the AC
presentation hello again so in this case
the suggested proposal is that the the
current wording of the policy for
getting an allocation for an IXP is that
to operator at a minimum of two
operators get together to justify an
allocation from Erin with the suggestion
that was raised was that this this
presents possible situations of abuse as
the free pool gets depleted and that may
it suggested that maybe that bar is set
too low so what the policy statement
suggests is that the minimum requirement
be raised from two to three two
hopefully present that prevent that
potential for abuse there is actually a
fair amount of discussion on the the
mailing list about this so for those who
enjoy that reading
yeah it'd probably be a good visit to
the to the mailing list the two sides of
the discussion of kind of settled around
a number of people agree that this the
bar is too low and that it should be
raised one point that was made on the
other side was for smaller countries in
the Aaron region like the Caribbean who
have a difficult time possibly getting
three people together that this could
cause issues for them so they're there
is two sides of this discussion and
we're interested to hear more points of
view from those in the room last policy
of the agenda here is some vibrant
debate hopefully bring us some vibrant
debate Brayden Ross network utility
force I'll just reiterate what I said of
mailing list which is that if you're
going to fade to companies you can just
as easily faked three companies so this
does nothing to prevent abuse the tiny
amount of address space we're talking
about will do nothing to preserve the
free pool for more than a few seconds
therefore I am against the change policy
is that a good start
no one other this is dan one other point
that I'd offer to the room as
information while it doesn't suggest
future behavior just you know
information for consideration is looking
at the the air and websites there's less
than 70 allocations that have currently
been made you know for this purpose it's
like to give you an idea of scope Thank
You next speaker mark Hannigan open IX
Association among the board of directors
I'm not necessarily expressing an
opinion of the membership just one of
the point to the fact that there is an
association that is tackling what is
apparently the third world condition of
IXPs in North America which includes the
arm region there's a standard that the
community develop culto ax1 and there's
a definition of what an IXP is and it
was fully debated within the community
there was a consensus process there was
public notice and all that fun stuff
related to open is a transparency that
said I'm going to shift hats and what
does was did the since you mentioned
that did relate to this change they're
saying then that policy that really
established before this policy was
entertainment no my question being you
brought that up as does the policy speak
to the two or the three the standard
started the standard my apologies one
specifically states that an i excuse
defined as three part that's why I
wanted to clarify thank you go ahead and
so now I'm going to shift that just
going to speak Martin not representing
anyone so though I am the author of
Basel
the purpose of the proposal wasn't to
combat abuse it was to encourage
conservation of the slide 16 and we have
reserved for future growth and I XPS as
I previously mentioned the Stata by XPS
is unusually broken in North America
when you compare it to other regions in
the world and we're working very hard to
improve that situation as you probably
are all aware of a number of IXPs of
announced service in the states new york
virginia there are public plans with
respect to chicago we have a new entrant
Omaha we're working closely with a
number of parties or we're also or I'm
also going to work with parties in the
Caribbean to help them to establish a
minimum of three participants and bring
the tomatoes to the soup so to speak and
bring some content in fact we're
actually doing that the purpose of some
of this work is is to help people to
establish these exchanges not to thwart
them an observation that I have when you
use for example the PCH nap directory
and you go through and actually check on
the entries in that directory that the
vast majority of the entries that are
listed as two participants or even dead
or the space is being used for personal
or person that's being consumed
personally I proposed an alternative to
this policy on the list I so won the
underlying text I suggested that because
there's already text like that in in the
purple in the existing policy don't
really care if that goes away or not if
that's a per view the staff of the wart
that's fine by me secondly I think that
the alternative is that Aaron
immediately or we move to and this is a
big step for me modify section 12 and
start to conduct audits of people that
get this space and if they don't
actually use it for its intended purpose
or succeed and again success is key I
don't think we
with science base and in you know what
what pending exhaustion to people that
are not going to succeed we should help
them to succeed we should do things like
develop programs on for example there's
a pen there's a pairing program being
developed and Oakland annex to help
people fund these things and get
certified and and you know meet those
minimum standards that the community was
pulled on that said that this is what we
want from IXPs and granted the Caribbean
is what this seems the objection seems
to be about and it is unique and and I
think that a lot of people want to help
them make things succeed but I think
that we need to start with some
realistic criteria and I think that this
has come this is fairly reasonable and
simple and that's a and you're
supportive of the text that we can't
afford it again it's not about you know
shutting down IXPs per se in Caribbean
it's above using the resources properly
and getting some successes thank you sir
go ahead sir like Joseph Google I oppose
this policy first tackling the latter
portion first I believe that the
existing for foreign language oversteps
the scope of the NR p.m. and i believe
that the underlying section here further
oversteps the scope it should be the
proper domain of the board to determine
how organizations are classified for the
purpose of payment of fees and to
explicitly call out the taxable status
of an organization in the NR p.m. to
determine fee structure is in my opinion
wholly inappropriate particularly
considering that the errand service
region may include countries in which
the NRP the proposed enter p.m. language
is not not applicable so I think it's
important that the board have the leeway
to develop the most appropriate language
and policy for determining the fee
structure for critical critical
infrastructure and
XPS honest on the first portion I don't
I'm sympathetic to the the abuse concern
here I could certainly see some
potential for abuse so I would be
interested to hear staff opinion as to
whether or not they've seen any abuse of
this policy to date but I can see also a
potential chicken and egg problem you
have your first I XP participant and you
want to give them addresses but you have
to tell them to wait until somebody else
shows up before you can give them their
their addresses and I can see that being
a problem so I'm not sure that it's
necessary to change that for three but I
would be interested to hear static
experience on this point okay don't run
away first first john curran sorry too
two questions first with respect to the
the scope issue regarding whether this
Texas within scope for the NR p.m. I
believe that we can in the staff
assessment make sure we address that and
figure out the right way to phrase the
intent there is a certainly a
distinguishing organizations for
purposes of whether or not they qualify
for resources and whether or not they're
treated as end users or is BS is
perfectly appropriate in part of an RPM
I agree the fee question is done in an
hour p.m. issue but we'll pick that up
in the staff assessment of the policy I
was adjusted nonprofits that is why not
being in Turkey and as you either
understood unless it unless it affects
what resources parties are entitled to
because the NR PM has allocation or
assignment policy that directly is
germane to one or the other it would be
foolish policy that's a different
question it would be in scope foolish
policy okay but I the fee question I
understand the second question you asked
about abuse I don't think abuse we see
much of with respect to this but
recognize there's a difference between
abuse and aspirational use and a party
that gets an address block and then
doesn't fulfill
their goals and dreams is not abuse but
its fulfillment that didn't happen and
we do have quite a bit of that one
question I wanted to ask is if we back
up from the idea of the difference of
two and three being a matter of abuse as
I already tried to clarify that the
three it here's more to an industry
acceptable definition does that do you
have an opinion about that um so first
of my the larger portion of my objection
is about the the second half of the text
but concerning that the first portion of
the text I would be comfortable saying
that there was an intent to have more
than two participants but that
withholding the space until the third
shows up would you contention a
problematic I'm not sure how to best
capture that in policy and I don't take
a strong position on the two versus
three them thank you
Heather shell or Google Fiber so on that
some of those as a policy is written
mostly because of the second statement
that's been added about my excuses
nonprofits in regards to the two versus
three um there's a total of like 66
current ixp allocation so we're not
talking about like a huge number of
allocations that I think will have a
significant impact so not I mean it
raises the bar it but barely yeah i
think someone on the list that raised it
to five or something else means that
that's fine with me too but the part
about IXPs formed is nonprofit so
there's far more at least grammatically
the way it's written all others will be
considered ISPs in context of the larger
4.4 section implies that the see a bomb
the folks who get a critical
infrastructure space for non isp
purposes would be considered eyes peas
as well and so there are far more of
those allocations than there are 0 x XP
allocations and the far more of them are
currently end-users and would be
adversely impacted by becoming isps
Elvis financially impacted so I think
that that that policy board is more
implication for the non IXPs than it
does for XPS whether they're non problem
you talk about the fact that just says
all yes nbk so you only see this section
the one part of section 4.4 which is
part of a larger piece of policy I don't
think you have the entire statement and
so the 4.4 is the entire my craw
allocation section which that my other
micro allocations are made for other
types of critical infrastructure like
operators and so the way that it's the
way that is written that it implies that
that part applies to GMs operators as
well and my point is just that there are
far more of those type of allocation
yeah the Heather is correct that you
know it's on page 32 of your book that
the section 4.4 actually has other
paragraphs that aren't here so you might
want to consider that both the AC in the
membership communities all right last
comment will close the mics if you're
going to speak on this item please
either start typing or approach a mic
otherwise we'll close it up after this
gentleman starts speaking perhaps name
and affiliation please have the
rosenthal form is prime thanks and
perhaps a better way of looking at it is
not for initial allocation but perhaps
looking at it as an audit if over the
past year of activity I know with you
know some exchanges that we've been
looking at that are launching now you
know there's a number of participants
talking about joining every single one
of them are content I'm a Content
company we're interested in joining but
there isn't necessarily much value
necessarily in you know in actually
joining when there is you know no
eyeballs on on that exchange that gets
into you know way beyond what you know
your proposal of course but my point is
that these exchanges do not grow
explosively respond taneously they grow
organically and if you you know say you
have to have a minimum of X number of
participants day one it's possible you
will never have that and after six
months you know you'll get a you know a
few people that will join it will
attract others and if the exchange
failed you know take the space back its
out of a special block that shouldn't be
used for anything else anyway right so
so you're not sore would you be
supportive of this or you feel that I on
it I mean that it needs more text I
don't have to be an audit rather than
initial allocation so as it is I am
against it thank you microphones are
closed any remote thank you next micro
so sure the second name and the second
half of it again I'm going on for a
little proposal wind I put it there we
clean up I think correctly to clean up
some existing language so sure clean it
up and I have no opposition whatsoever
dar having that adapted to whatever you
want it to be with respect to the two
versus three re numbering is easy
especially when it's two to three and
there are other instances of the NR p.m.
where we suggest renumber it is easy as
well and again it's not about abuse it's
about conservation and the 16 that we
put aside for DNS infrastructure and and
for exchanges I believe at this point is
going to be fully utilized in around the
rapid manner in the next 36 months so
I'm just seeking to raise the bar a
little bit in by the way if you guys
want to go to five that's perfectly fine
by me too because again Rena Marie is
easy thank you thank you and last
comment Chris Grundmann and i actually
just had a question actually about that
/ 16 this reserve okay Alex I didn't
remember it says the end of the policy
terms was that still time base where it
gets released into the free pool at
after three years or is that / 16
reserved for inspector period he's
asking I don't remember whether the / 16
will eventually go back as the policy
still says 0 / 16 of ipv4 address space
and reserve promote respect as defined
below it at the end of policy term there
is unused address based remaining in
this pool it goes on to say that will be
released but I think that's just hanging
on my text i don't but i don't remember
i dont rember this yeah at this point we
just look fit at the end of the policy
term at this
right at this point we are the policy
term is no longer defined Heather go
ahead you're going to say something
because he asked that last month and um
I thought that what you said was that it
was going to be kept indefinitely right
it was that they didn't have plans to
release it right there's no longer a
reference antecedent for that phrase
Thank You Heather for that clarification
and Leslie go ahead of 2016 I think I
told you that you wouldn't release the
space but then that the current policy
doesn't happen in a term limit it's not
defined enough how much for me at the AC
should take it upon itself to add that
to this policy either to remove the
expiration or set date certain thank you
John and AC can take that in
consideration heatherwood did that
clarify or leak or confuse the matter
thank you so with respect to that
question I actually made that change to
that specific policy as well and I
specifically recall my intent was that I
believe once we dipped into the last / 8
that allocations would come from that
block in 36 months later that whatever
was left in the block
back to the free pool and my intention
when I wrote that was that we we weren't
providing a crutch for people to hobble
along on before forever we were giving
them an opportunity to get started and
then get their asses over ipv6 okay i
think is john curran say that it would
be helpful theae could clarify that
language we had close the mics was there
anything else on just this last point
that if you wanted to address or mr.
Sweeting John sweeting is there anything
that further input you need oh okay
thank you very much for your
participation I'll turn it back to John
Curran thank you okay we're now coming
to the last portion of the policy
consultation and what we have is we have
proposals three proposals that drawn
Sweeting is going to just let the
community know are underway now these
are not yet draft policies that AC is
still working on the text but they've
received them from submitters and so
John if you want to come up and talk
about proposals 193 199 and 201 okay so
193 199 should be fairly quick we
probably won't have what asked for much
discussion on that but 201 we'll
probably get some some good discussion
going ok so I'm proposals and under the
new policy process proposals come in
they go to the AC the AC works with the
author the author controls that proposal
until such time is it's determined to be
clear and in scope and then the AC can
move it into a draft policy status and
that's when it gets posted 2 ppm L we
start looking for input based on the
policy itself in trying to create good
policy so these proposals are still with
the AC working with the author trying to
get clear problem statement and making
sure it's at scope
most likely these proposals will be on
the air and 33 agenda in Chicago and you
should see them probably on PP ml after
our next after the ac's next meeting
which is the third Thursday of this
month so the 193 is alignment of eight
that three needs requirements to reality
of business and 199 is to resolve
conflict between the IRSA and eight dot
to utilization requirements most you
might have seen these I think David
huberman the author posted these two ppl
but i'm not i'm not sure there was a
whole lot of discussion on him the aaron
proposal 201 is to remove sections for
dot six and four dot seven from the
nurple and this is the board policy
suspension action that was taken earlier
this year when it was pointed out that
there was an actual danger to aaron
there if these sections remained in
force and could be used and basically
that was somebody with a any company
with a fairly really large bunch of
addresses could go into aaron and ask
for a really big aggregate to take away
and renumber into overtime which i think
under one paw under one policy it was 12
months under another section for
different reasons it was 24 months so
anyway at this time getting down soaked
so low in the free pool was well what if
a company that had a / 8 aggregate came
in and said they wanted or if they had
all their addresses together came in and
said well we won a / 8 to renumber into
so we have just one aggregate so I
believe that's why the board took that
action it was on the list there was a
lot of discussion
and in accordance with the PDP the AC
had to make a recommendation on that
suspension which we agreed on in our
last meeting was posted to the list and
is still there still can be commented on
it had to be there and take comments for
14 days but the gist of the ac's
recommendation was to continue
continuance of the suspension and we
also submitted a belief dan alexander is
the author of record but it was an AC
decision to submit that proposal to
remove those two sections from the nerve
them so that's where we are with that
and we would like to to hear discussion
on that now if anybody would like to
just since it's it is out there on the
list at wear's we can take discussion on
it I would like to hear that Leo Leo
bicknell for site security I I totally
see why 47 the aggregate is very
problematic so I have no issue with that
going away whatsoever 46 I can
understand from reading the text how
there are potentially some problematic
elements however I can also think of
some not very non problematic particular
potential uses of 46 I believe and I
would like to be corrected if wrong that
for instance if a legacy address space
holder had way more address than they
needed and wanted to return that Andrey
number into a smaller block they may
well use 46 for that purpose and in that
sense while it may tie up more address
space for a short period of time it
would actually lead to the return of
useable address space to the community
and so maybe some time frames and some
stuff need to be addressed in 46 but I
think removing it would possibly include
people from doing that which would be a
bad thing given that that there is a
large amount of address space out there
someone that wanted to downsize into a
slightly smaller amount of space such as
a legacy / 8 holder could say they need
oh the equivalent of 3 / 11 s to
renumber their current / 8 usage that's
still a substantial amount of space to
suddenly lose out of the free pool
aaron's happy to entertain that if
that's what the community wants but it
would be very difficult to handle a
large number of amnesty requests which
brought the free pool 20 and then rely
on being able to get that space back it
could put us in a very difficult because
we have to get the legacy block back to
put us in a very difficult situation so
if the upside is seen as important
enough for that it would be good for the
community to set under what practices
and what circumstances and why it's
desirable we suspended both because both
have risk sure I guess my thinking in
broad terms because then certainly
prepared to offer specific language is
that for instance limiting someone under
46 to being able to get no more than
twenty percent of the free pool
remaining for that purpose may provide
that safety valve that it can't be
instant migraine while still allowing to
the extent the free pool does allow the
exchange of space right and thus
recovering space down wrote it would
it's a net gain for the delay sure no we
haven't had anyone exercise these
policies in more than five years so it's
a it's a great doorway to have for
someone to walk through but i'm not sure
people are actually looking at that wall
anymore I'm hoping that run out makes
some people look at that but I agree
that they are unlikely to walk through
the door thanks leo Lee Lee Howard have
you looked the routing tables for
specifically the address box of the
legacy holders specialist water
shoulders it does not look to me that
the kinds of organizations that leo is
talking about I don't think there are
people who have large blocks of address
space who would want to renumber into
large ish blocks that would be risky for
Aaron and don't have enough space within
their existing block so for instance the
legacy / 8 holder who would need 3 / 11
s has 3 / 11 and can re number into part
of their existing / 8 and then do return
the rest if that's what they would like
to do I would love it if they were to
return the rest to Aaron I think it's
probably more like that they would use
the transfer market the recipe outer
space but you know the opportunity still
already exists and I don't think that we
need to risk the free pool for that
having said all of that I think that in
any any organization that was then to
remember taking advantage of these
policies would not be able to renumber
before the free pool is exhausted right
so we would be giving a free full space
for and then you know maybe getting some
more later maybe so I agree
what suspension with the suspension
board is done and support proposal that
the ACS considering right now and you
know do v6 Thank You Lee any any other
comments bar do you have something on
share oh yeah thanks go ahead mine so
one of the concerns about section 4.6 is
it presupposes it presupposes an
exchange against the free pool but the
other thing it clarifies is something
somewhat to states from that which is
the no penalty for returning point of 46
to the first cause of 462 and
particularly the first sentence of 46 to
which states that Aaron shall seek to
make the return of address space as
convenient and risk free to the
returning organization as possible given
that this has now been suspended by the
board what risks does an organization
now observe in the return of address
space to Aaron and how would returning
address space to Aaron effect that
organizations for their feelings again
so you can return address space very
risk freedom I've worked with a number
of organizations to do that over the
decade and so there's no risks the
circumstance of risks described in the
embassy policy is a case where you wish
to renumber in return and the probe
attend the admonishment and the policy
text is that Aaron should not create
undue timelines or thresholds so that
you're remembering plan is endangered so
you must remember in six months well I
didn't get the equipment I needed I
can't finish a project well we're taking
the block back and have a nice day so in
the case where someone's remembering out
of an existing block into another one
it's aaronus has to have the flexibility
to work with that that also is one of
the reasons why the amnesty approach or
aggregation approach when we re
numbering and some
says I'm running into difficulties it
makes it particularly difficult for air
endeavor predictably know we'll get the
space back that was assured as a result
of the amnesty or the other remembering
request but absent those uses just plain
old returning of address space I can
make that very risk-free including the
subsequent requests including the
subsequent requests absolutely just a
comment from Gary Burmaster while there
may be a theoretical use of 4.6 to
return space I would find it surprising
if any organization actually would
consider doing so the risk likely
exceeds the potential benefit suspension
was appropriate and the suctions should
be removed okay thank you anyone else if
not then I'll turn this back over to
John thank you everyone for coming to we
got the AC got a lot of good useful
information out it is yes thank you John
okay we've got some closing
announcements and just quickly move
through them there we go okay first and
foremost this is good preparation for
our upcoming public policy meeting which
will be airing 33 in chicago illinois in
just a couple months 13th or 16th of
april one more thing we've had
discussions in the past that people get
all excited about all the conversation
that's happened here and they want to
make progress they want to meet with the
shepherds and talk about new text and
all that other good stuff and so we've
arranged for a room if you want to go
from here to another room and work with
members of the AC and further talk or
brainstorm you need to grab them there's
no assurance they'll be available but I
see John and I see other AC members here
the board room on the sixth floor is
available for people who want to do
workshop editing of these proposals but
you've got to find a cooperative AC
member to work with it's on the sixth
floor and it's open now through 5 p.m.
so we'll be doing that after our public
policy sessions so that people have a
way to follow on while the ideas and
juices are still fresh that's it I'd
like to thank everyone for coming it's
been very successful and i hope everyone
continues to enjoy nanog stay safe
there's some storm coming involving ice
but um hopefully that won't affect the
meeting with in here take care enjoy
your day
you