hello everyone my name is Husain lutfi
and
a performance engineering team at
verizon EdgeCast I'm here to talk about
the challenges that we had when we
initially testing our network for ipv6
the problems we found and possible
solutions to those problems since this
is the first time that we're presenting
at a nog I have two slides to explain
who we are and what we do edgecast is a
content delivery network with presence
in more than 40 locations around the
world and it's rapidly expanding we have
a small object and large object object
static delivery platform we also have a
dynamic object delivery platform which
has a lot of TCP optimizations in it we
do streaming and dns and as you might
have heard we were recently acquired by
Verizon here's what my team does at
edgecast we're a bunch of full stack
engineers that look at mountains of
mountains of performance data and we try
to come up with ways that we can make
this CD and faster basically we're up
against what Einstein predicted right we
can't go faster than speed of light
we're coming up with different ways to
deliver the objects faster and what
we're going to do what we're doing is
that we look at the entire stack and
what it makes it really interesting is
that one day we focus on Colonel file
system TCP the next day its application
optimization the day after that its
network in any case optimization and we
have we had several cases that we
actually had to do physical changes in
our data centers to improve performance
and so basically whenever there's a
complex case coming up and no one else
can explain what's going on and it
touches multiple areas its performance
engineering team that gets involved to
be able to address those issues in my
talk you're going to hear a lot about
response times and milliseconds and let
me just quickly explain why it matters
so much there are a lot of independent
studies that measures the CDM
performances and they actually publish
the data publicly and if you look at one
of these benchmarks this is said access
data the difference between the best
performing CDN at the worst one in u.s.
is only 17 milliseconds so
that's why every millisecond counts
that's why we're so anxious to be able
to cut round trips and minimize the
internal latency of our applications all
right so in my talk initially i had when
i submitted to talk to knock it was
talking about patentable problems and
the solutions around it the feedback
that I got from a program committee was
that it's good to explain how we
discovered those issues as well because
there might never be more interesting
the audience to to know about our
experience with testing our network for
ipv6 compatibility so let me start with
that whenever we launch a new product
what we do is that we have a tool set
that we go over the stool set to be able
to make sure that availability is what
we expect and the performance is good
I'm going to walk over all of these
steps and explain how we use these tools
to detect ipv6 problems our target
launch was ipv6 launch day so we had a
set deadline that we had to make sure
everything is good by that normally when
you launch a new platform the first
thing we test is synthetic monitoring
these are servers around the world very
well-managed where we will appear and we
love synthetic monitoring because it's
reproducible it's controllable when we
have a new idea that we want to test
usually the first thing that we still we
start testing is this synthetic test
because generally the random noise over
internet is not pursued present in these
platforms so we can rely on the data
that we were collecting from these
servers we had a lot of synthetic notes
at before ipv6 launch but the problem is
none of them were v6 capable at that
time so synthetic monitoring wasn't
really an option price to this day one
of the platforms two of them actually
supported but there's still not that
good of a coverage so the next tool that
is usually available to us is wrong real
user monitoring is a very clever idea
that what they do at the end of the web
page browse what happens is that the web
page becomes your test platform and the
user browser is going to call multiple
objects from different CD ends and
report the timing back to a central
server
their companies out there who are
basically offering this product you can
you can get the raw data you can get a
lot of analysis from these platforms the
problem again i'ma let me mention the
value of these wrong platforms because
now you get you can see visibility into
areas that you had no visibility before
an interesting case we were getting
reports from one of these run platforms
that our response time in Albania for
some reason is 40 milliseconds higher
than the best CDN in that country and
we're really curious what's going on
there was no synthetic node in that
country so that was the only indication
that something is wrong so we looked at
it and we discovered the GUI p mapping
problem and then once we were able to
fix that we're able to match the
performance of the other city n there
rom just the general caution is that the
data is full of noise so we don't look
at rom data in real time we don't set
real-time alerts on these things we look
at wrong data mainly for trending
purposes what you're seeing in this
chart is one of the TCP optimizations
idea that we had and the blue line is a
target line you can see that when we
applied the to the red chart the
throughput goes up and just to prove
that it was rtcp performance
optimization that made things better and
not any other random effect when we turn
it off we went back to the control set
where we used to be before but again the
problem with the ROM at that time was
that there were not ipv6 capable and
none of the platforms to my knowledge
today are so now wasn't an option for us
we have to skip to the next option which
turned out to be really amazing these
little probes that ripe distributed was
extremely helpful for us ripe I'm sure
they've presented this before and you
guys are all familiar but I'm going to
explain how this probe helped us to find
a v6 problems they have pretty good
coverage around the world they now more
than 4,000 notes they're deployed and
what we really like about Atlas is that
it's completely programmable you can say
you can set your test using IP eyes and
get the results back from the API
they can do ptrace dns ssl certs and
they're doing HTTP taste say in beta now
one of the cool things that you could
you can have an atlas this is not
available to to all at last users and
ripe will be probably really bad mad at
me by telling you this but the beta
testers of ipv6 network had access to a
certain tool that could actually launch
v6 pings and traces from their entire
network and they'll give you the is
mapping and the is graph and on the
graph on the right I'm not sure if it's
visible enough but you can actually see
the failed passes and you can actually
see what was the last AAS that you saw
in the trace before going blank going
dark so it was extremely helpful for us
to detect the to zoom into the primary
assets that we had a problem with all
right a general note is that we need
more at last probes in u.s. it's heavily
Europe centric I guess because ripe
started it they have a ton of nodes
there but when you look at us this is
one of the largest US networks and you
can see that it's very East Coast
centric the problem with this sort of
deployment is that especially for
networks like us that rely on any cast
we need to be able to see the traffic we
need to see we'll be able to see the
performance from around the country not
just the East Coast heavy so if you're
thinking about launching a looking glass
I highly encourage considering outlast
instead it will help the community much
better it's programmable I can do
everything that then a looking glass can
do with way less than risk of a
traditional looking glass but of course
you can't give you bgp lookups which
ripe has a different solution for it all
right so what did we learn from at last
when we tested our v6 which ability we
the first thing that we compiled was a
pop to contrary mapping and it we
drilled down to a s level and subnet
level as Latin as well and we try to
visualize the latencies and then we
uncovered pretty amazing things one of
the examples in this chart is that the
country in the center of that
art is Ukraine and you can see that it's
going to two of our pops one of them is
showing relatively good latency the
other one is has high latency so we
wanted to know why part of that country
is going to a different pub that is not
the right location for it and we focus
on these high latency links first and
then we we untangle the problems there
and this study is actually published by
ripe as one of the case studies of using
at last so we learned a lot from at last
we we wanted to understand our
availability what we needed more data
that's why we launched our own rom to
basically test three different objects
we were calling a v4 object a v6 only
address and a dual stack dual address
just to make sure that to understand the
availability of these three as well as
the difference between the latencies and
we wanted to focus on the most the main
problem areas so one idea was that okay
let's add a control set let's add ipv6
google google com as well to be able to
understand our their networks out there
that can reach to google but what failed
to reach to us over v6 and that was the
primary focus to fix these routing
issues we also did latency calculations
we knew ahead of the time that going v6
is actually in a lot of cases is not
good for the performance because mainly
because of the peering policies that we
have with about all the networks we have
a very rich peering data set with all of
you guys but that's not the case for all
the v6 connections and we knew ahead of
the time that there will be a
performance hit and over time you can
see this is a set random is that I plot
it out you can see that over time we
made it better and better and that's an
ongoing process attached gasps what we
do is we look at these gaps between v4
and v6 and we try to come up with ways
that we can close this gap but it's a
little bit more complex for us I mean
resolving these issues because we run
any cast and this is usually the way
that I explain any cast a cube make made
out of bulky bolts
right and it's a stable system as long
as you don't introduce a change as soon
as you add a new pier or remove
something the whole cube changes the
structure of your routing changes so you
have to be really careful about how to
add a new player into an anycast mix and
that's why it's a little bit challenging
for us and a time-consuming I should say
to be able to fix all of the v6 peering
problems the biggest enemy of you have
any cast is there are your own local
profs I'm very excited to do this talk
here because look at all the that
are present in this room and we either
directly pier with you or only one asla
and in our daily optimizations there ton
of cases that whatever change or perhaps
that you guys have in your no local
networks are actually killing the
anycast performance and I like to go
back to this topic and maybe in another
talk and explain what are the things
that you guys can do to help improve the
global anycast performance all right the
last tool that we use the that we
couldn't use but as actually part of our
used tool kit is a TCP info we
internally we call it the awesome TV
info because it gives the best value of
looking at the behavior of intra that
other global scale what we do is that we
first publicly discuss this in the last
velocity conference in New York that's
what I'm reiterating over that our chief
architect Rob Peters had a very
interesting talk about how we use the
TCP info data basically the idea is that
at the end of the connection we capture
everything we know about that connection
all the packets that were transferred
the latency the round-trip the number of
retransmissions all that stuff and then
we can do deep dive into the global PCP
performance one of the things that we do
with this data is that we map round ship
based on the subnets so in if inside
your network you decide to route one
subnet and a different route than the
other one it will actually show up in
our latency differences charts and we
know ahead of the time that we know in
near real time that you guys are making
these changes countless examples but
we've had cases that you know I squeezed
in Germany they had a problem with the
line card they didn't know about it but
the int latency that they introduced
we're completely visible in these charts
what but none of the monitoring
platforms of that isp picked it up we
also do we started doing some global
internet health studies this is an
interesting slide it's a little bit off
topic I have to skip a really fast but
we detected a lot of a certain anomaly
in the internet that some folks are
assassinating the window scaling bit to
slow down the internet these are
corporates that are not really happy
about users having exponential growth
and their TCP congestion window and
they're actually setting the congestion
the window is gaining bit on purpose
that's the optic at the end of the chart
to slow down the connections and we're
planning to do a stubble talk around
this this is very interesting all right
well let me go back to the actual they
did the track of my talk it this is the
problem that we discussed we found a lot
of sessions that were able to complete
the v6 trace to us but we're not able to
download the v6 object and we were lucky
enough to be able to do some packet
captures and we saw something really
interesting when we sent the initial
congestion out initial congestion window
out only few packets were acknowledged
not all of them we were getting feedback
back from the client but that was only
for you for a few packets not the entire
transmission well this is a clear sign
of a path and two problem because if you
look at the trace again you only see a
sub MSS packets being acknowledged none
of the 1500 bite messages are being
acknowledged so that tells us there's
probably a choke point there's a black
hole in there in the path that is not
happy with us sending the full MSS what
the explanation display is pretty simple
right there has to be a v4 only internet
that cannot route these packets
and someone had to establish a tunnel
between these two points in order to
make a uniform v6 connectivity between
these two but the problem with these
tunnels is that when you send the 1,500
packet out the router the beginning of
the tunnel has to inject its own header
into it when we send a 1500 bytes out
the router cannot inject anything more
into the packet so will actually send
you down send you a message that says
slow down you have to lower your MTU
this is this is a known issue in the
internet and had been had been addressed
before that's why the ICMP packet to big
messages are for so it shouldn't break
the internet and we're curious to
understand we're not filtering the
message we know that the ICMP is being
sent out why the connection is actually
getting black hole so we looked at the
server that was handling the connection
it was in Frankfurt the black hole
session was in Frankfurt we didn't see
the ICMP packet we looked at all the
servers in Frankfurt it was in there so
we launched a global packet hunt for
that ICMP message which is by itself is
a very big challenge at a network at our
size but we managed to run that that
packet capture globally and we found the
packet what we found it in Paris it was
very curious the conde flow was in
Frankfurt but das ICMP telling us to
slow down was arrived in Paris why is
that well the answer is inside the
packet when you send out the offending
packet let's call it the one that is
sending out at 1500 by the size you're
so seeing it from the anycast address
towards the client but when the icy
jacket is coming back it's from a
different source it's from the router
itself and it happens in that scenario
that the router itself was making it was
actually looking into a different
routing table to make routing decisions
for its own IP address it was completely
in a different routing table so we have
different peering policies anycast
behaves differently on there for
networks so we ended up that the actual
is client 20 cash flow was in Frankfurt
but the router to any cash flow was in
Paris we managed to fix that on this one
in
since this was actually a hurricane
electric and we were able to address
this issue with working with them
directly but again going back to the
flow the packet didn't arrive on the
same server it was delivered to
Frankfurt but not to the right server so
we thought that there must be something
else going on there we look deeper and
we notice that one of our systems we
have multiple layers of load balancing
one of the layers is doing is the source
destination based hashing and what
happens is that the load balancer looks
at the source and destination of the
packet to make the routing decision
forwarding decision but the ICMP packet
that is arriving is this is sourced from
a different addresses source from the
router address so we will map
differently to a different path and it
ever makes it to the actual server the
solution to this is different from
deployment to deployment it depends on
what kind of router or load balancing
you're using so I can't talk about
specifics of your network but generally
one of the ideas is that we have to look
deeper and we have to look inside the
ICMP packet to make forwarding decisions
based on the offending packet because
the offending packet is actually a
snapshot of it is including in the ICMP
packet all right so how can we fix this
and how big of a problem this is the
simplest solution is the RFC itself the
RFC says that 1280 is the safest MTU and
the internet in the v6 internet so all
the nodes have to be capable of
transferring 12 messages with 1280 sites
the bigger problem is that this is
happening in v4 address space as well
the same problem that i just explained
can happen in before as well and it is
happening one of our synthetic platforms
is catch point they recently launched a
note in Iceland and it was amazing
because as soon as they launched a note
we received the ticket from them that it
said you know we can't get to etch gas
cannock to get to yahoo we can get to a
lot of different sites and it seemed
that it this is a you know not in first
it happens in before as well and second
of all is that there are a lot of folks
out there that have this issue so the
suggestions that I have for you i mean
the solutions to address to sue this
problem is it's different per
implementation but generally what i can
recommend is that if you have if you run
an anycast network look for these
orphaned icmp packets that arrive
somewhere in your network with no
matching flow there could be sign of an
attack for sure but if they're
legitimate and you have a flow somewhere
else in your network this ICMP packet is
telling you something that that probe
that the initial the actual flow is
suffering from a path MTU problem the
other idea is that you can set up last
mile tests and compare your availability
between any caste and unicast if going
directly to the servers are going
directly to your pops shows higher
availability than going to the anycast
address that's another indication that
any caste routing is basically sending
the package icmp packets to the wrong
place another solution to this problem
is empty you probing this was deployed
in linux kernel a long time ago and
general idea is that they look for black
holing signatures if they see packets
that are being acknowledged in the same
way that i explain what happens is that
these packets the systems will actually
start lowering the MTO based on a set
speed and try out those steps it brings
up your availability but the problem is
it will cost your real response time
because the MTU tables are very
aggressive and you can see this this tcp
chart of that connection it'll actually
takes a long time to be able to ramp up
and deliver the object all right that
was my last slide thanks for your time
I'll be happy to take questions you can
take questions now
Leo McNall Farsight security the root
name server operators have been any
casting for quite a while and there has
been great debate over the years about
the impact of any cast on that service
and they have investigated many of these
probably more focused in v4 than in v6
the interesting conclusions there is
that of course the longer duration of
your TCP connection the more likely it
is to be clobbered in an anycast world
because of instability in the network
causing these return packets to go to
the wrong place and so the general
thought is that if you're going to do
any cast for tcp you should do it for
very short-lived connections for
instance if you wanted to serve up a six
hundred megabyte ISO image or something
you would any cast a HTTP connection
that was a 302 redirect to the server
sitting right next to it that was a
standard unicast connection so my
question kind of comes are you really
trying to any cast all of your content
because that sounds very risky based on
what I've heard are you are you any
casting redirections to the actual
content involved and and have you looked
at any of that root name server research
along with us I looked at with seven
studies for a different purpose because
ripe has a very interesting model for
the announcements and how they because
ripe has global instances of local
instances and how they manage to make
sure that their global instances don't
get majority of the traffic and they can
absorb local traffic into locals ones
looked at it from that perspective but
not from this the general idea is that a
side note is that the performance of
these root servers are not the same the
performance of these nodes are not the
same so it is extremely important to
land on the right cluster it's a bigger
problem with the gtld than what it is
with the root servers because gTLD if
you look at individual gtld responses
they're very different especially the
note that runs out of Japan
it's not a match for the rest of the
notes longleaf TCP connections yes the
risk is there the we do a little bit of
the inside trick on how to make sure
that the connection as long as it's
within the same pop gets the right
server even after the internal changes
that we make to the pop hour traffic
distribution is based on multiple layers
but any cast is primarily the way we're
out the objects in there inside one
region and I agree with you any any
change on over a long live TCP
connection can I can make this happen
but I wish I had that chart it's very
amazing when we looked at the TCP data
and we looked at the total bytes that
were transferred into each connection
internet is amazingly very small when we
give you this the metric more than
eighty two percent of all the
connections that we serve they fit into
one tcp burst so the client never goes
back to actually request the second
burst yes it's as if this is a 600 Meg
file and you expand it over minutes and
hours and any change in the network
happens yes you will end up going to the
right wrong pop but this is surprisingly
a very very small percentage that the
very long tail of the connections
alright since there's no one else up
here I'll make my one other comment
which was buried in the details of why
that packet to big message comes back is
actually a subtle difference in v6 that
I think many people haven't gotten their
mind around yet and that is in v4 we can
send out a packet that is 1500 bytes and
allow it to be fragmented and if there's
a tunnel it will go on its merry way in
v6 there is no fragmentation at
intermediate nodes and so you will get
many more packet two bigs in v6 than you
have gotten in before particularly with
the tunneling since you
which really accentuates this problem it
also accentuates the standard black
holing problem of people filtering
packet too big and stalling and so
studying both of those on the v6 and
comparing to v4 is is interesting i'd
like to see more charts about that
thanks for my information again it's a
good point all right thank you the same
you