look at that it's a miracle
Richard Steenburgen again or Turk Bergen
depending on the results of the survey
from global Turk Bergen Telecom
apparently I'll pre apologize for the I
don't know what the wave means closer
okay I will pre apologize for the lack
of pretty pictures in this because I
literally just finished this during the
QA of the last so what the heck is this
all about for anyone that doesn't know a
jumbo frame in Ethernet technically
anything that is bigger than a 1500 byte
frame according to the I Triple E 802 3
Ethernet standard is a jumbo frame it's
outside of the standard and therefore
not standardized so the question is how
much bigger what what makes a jumbo
frame what what do people want to pass
as a jumbo frame and the answer is no
one really knows because of course it's
a non-standard so the rough guideline
that we're all kind of working on right
now is around 9000 bytes and that's
really a historical number from the
original Altium proposal from about 15
years ago for an even 9,000 but for most
vendors today it's actually a completely
different number but it's somewhere in
that ballpark insert mean picture here
so the goal of jumbo frames there's
three main goals the first one is to
improve high speed transfer efficiency
so if you look at the way most hosts
most CPUs work and most operating system
works they're really not built around
moving 1,500 byte packets or even less
once you factor in all the the overhead
of headers they're really built around
moving data and at least 4096 slot
chunks the size of a memory page the
size of a block writing to disk pretty
much anything is is that type of block
so when you start breaking this down
into 1500 byte packets it actually
doesn't align with that very well so in
in classic days what you had was you had
to wait for the operating system to do
all this chunking and buffering and
waiting for buffers to fill and do all
this extra work
when copying stuff so you did more
copies into memory you did more more
segmentation it happens load the second
goal of jumbo frames is to reduce the
packet per second count so if you go
from your standard 1,500 byte to say
nine thousand that's a 6x increase in
size so if you're ascending all content
you might be looking at one sixth the
numbers of packets per second and again
15 years ago packets per second was a
was a big deal is a big concern that
that was a major cause of the load and
impact on devices was how do we keep up
with all these lookups and the third
argument for it is increasing the
flexibility when tunneling so 1500 bytes
because of Ethernet or really the de
facto standard of the ethernet of the
Internet you really rarely rarely see
packets that are larger than 1500 bytes
go across the Internet
and so that's why cuddling 1,500 plus
tunnel overhead is so hard to do so the
intended use of jumbo frames is a little
bit different than historical so the way
that it works today is pretty much
everyone tries to go up to the maximum
you you take your 1460 of TCP data or
whatever it is - - all your options and
you shove it into every packet and
you're gonna have your packets be almost
always that size and any packet that
isn't is probably a knack for a packet
that was the way that we're proposing or
the way that jumbo frames proposed to be
used is differently instead of sending a
9k packet every time you're really
sending 4096 or 8192
a payload plus whatever you have in
headers so in theory it makes it easier
to support tunnels to support different
media types to support maybe an IPSec
tunnel things like that thus that's the
goal is to not to get to 9,000 but to
get to 81 92 plus something and then
have enough room for that something and
we're now starting to see some
internetwork deployment so until very
recently jumbo frames were pretty much
an internal network only thing you know
if they were ever going to be used
anywhere it was
you controlled your own Network and it
was very easy for you to know what you
set on both sides of a link but now
we're actually starting to see some IX
operators start to roll this out to some
major exchange points there's a lot of
cases where they're using a dedicated
VLAN and telling people what the MTU
number is and they're trying to do all
the right things and this could in
theory eventually lead to being able to
do a greater than 1,500 byte packet in
2n and that's the goal so there's a lot
of people out there who are cheerleading
this effort and there's a lot of
idealism about improving the efficiency
of high speed flows and maybe someday
we'll you know get these beautiful
hundred gigabit flows to people's houses
but I'm here to talk about how that's
all a bad idea so sorry so first off big
problem with jumbo frames is really
picking the number because remember
there's no standard value defined
anywhere nor is there any way to
actually negotiate this for you so
really we're down to manual negotiation
between operators I've got to call up
the person on the other side of the link
and say what value does your gear
support what number do you want to
configure etc but it's not even that
simple it's made harder by the router
vendors because even the numbers don't
mean the same things so for example when
you're on a Cisco IOS device and you
talk about a 1500 by Tim to you on the
Juniper or on an iOS XR device that
actually means 15 14 because one side is
including the ethernet header and the
other is not but it's even worse than
that
because on the side where you're
including the Ethernet header it changes
depending on your encapsulation so if
you have a VLAN tag in there you've now
got to go configure it for 15 18 if your
interface is configured for Q&Q you've
now got to go configure that for 15 22
and so every time you do this
negotiation with the other side you've
got to understand what gear do they have
what number are you actually talking
about and the really bad part about all
this is if you get it wrong you silently
black hole traffic that's where it goes
really bad really quickly so path MTU
discovery which is the mechanism for
detecting mismatch today in a word sucks
the way that it works is when a router
encounters an MTU mass in mismatch it
has two interfaces it received a big
packet over a big interface and it's
trying to send it to a
and it can't fit it will drop the packet
it will send back an ICMP message as was
talked about in the last presentation
and then the host is responsible for
receiving that ICMP message detecting
that there was a problem and reducing
the the packet size on this flow from
now on but that doesn't work very well
so first off if you look at the
architecture of routers and how they
generate ICMP that's not a hardware
performed function that's what's called
a slow path you have to punt the you
have to drop the packet punt it to a CPU
to generate an ICMP message which can
only happen at a certain limited rate so
there might be a cap of a hundred or a
thousand packets per second so it's
incredibly easy to launch a
denial-of-service against this all you
would have to do is generate some some
big packets that come through a big
interface going to a small interface and
you've taken out those this routers
capability of ICMP generation you
probably broke traceroute them in the
process but you you definitely broke
path into you discovery the other big
problem is that ICMP is all too often
blocked or limited by the ISPs the users
pretty much any random person on the
internet who gets a little filter happy
will block the ICMP message and while
there's a dedicated type for it most
people aren't that discriminating and so
that's where you start to see problems
so the only reason that the internet
works today is really because of the de
facto 1500 byte standard if we actually
encountered path MTU mismatch on any
type of regular basis we'd all be living
in a lot bigger world of hurt than we
are today
other problems that people forget is the
larger packet size increase the jitter
so you know a 100 gigabit flow some
beautiful high-speed and in flow is a
very noble cause but you've increased
the the amount of serialization delay by
6 X so now you've got someone on a
slow-speed
DSL or cable link at home even even a
nice 10 Meg link you've added 6.2
milliseconds of serialization delay so
something that people don't take into
mind when they're they're building for
the very large flows is that it's
probably not going to
achieve anything it might actually hurt
the home user the benefits here are
completely non-existent until you have a
hundred percent jumbo enabled into n
path it doesn't help you in any way if
one piece in the middle is bigger and
there's really no content network who's
ever gonna risk rolling this out the
benefits are minimal and the risk is
that they're gonna break some flows or
some customers and not only that but
they're likely to do it in really
obscure ways where some flows go through
the connection starts to open and then
the connection ramps up and it doesn't
go through at all and worst of all this
is all completely unnecessary so
remember jumbo frames are about a 15
year old idea and 15 years ago that
actually helped you you by cutting the
the load factor by 6 X by cutting your
memory operations by making your buffer
page flipping and whatnot more efficient
you were actually able to take your 300
megahertz processors of the day and make
them deliver potentially a gigabit flow
today it's really completely unnecessary
the modern NICs
support was called LSO a large segment
offload so instead of it now the host
having to do all this work of managing
these fragmentation and segmentation of
all these these buffers it'll just hand
the NIC a single here's a big 64 K right
and the NIC will then take care of doing
all the segmentation and offloading and
it does it very efficiently in a way
that it's not causing a problem so
really we're talking about solving a
problem that we really don't even have
so the other argument is that having
jumbo frames will help you with
tunneling so if you now have a link that
supports something bigger than 1500 that
makes it a lot easier to implement a
tunnel and it's an interesting argument
but really I think it proves the point
that path MTU discovery is so
fundamentally broken because if MTU
mismatches actually worked you wouldn't
have a problem tunneling under 1500
bytes the fact that you're having that
problem proves exactly what you're
you're hitting so all you're really
doing is creating more into you
mismatches to try and solve the problem
of MTU mismatches which is just making
your problem worse so then the question
becomes what would it take what would
you need
to actually raise the bar on em to you
what would be required to do this
internet wide and I think before you can
even begin to try and dabble in this
space you've really got to have some
type of reliable and negotiation between
the endpoints it's not sensible to have
operator a call operator B and say what
do you want for this link and then try
to figure out what they mean when they
give a number you need some type of
negotiation protocol so if you think
about what you need its Ethernet so you
really need to support this per mac you
need to be able to support this per her
next hop essentially and if you look at
the way the hardware works on the most
modern routers it actually does support
it that way so if you've got a slash 24
subnet you can give a different MTU
value to a dot two versus a dot three
but that's not exposed in any software
but if you look at the underlying
hardware the capability is actually
there but then in order for path MTU
discovery to ever have a chance of
working you would need to know about it
at layer 3 so the only sensible place
that I can think of to put something
like this would be in art when you're
negotiating between the two hosts you
could negotiate what the MTU that the
the in devices think they're capable of
passing and then hope that your layer 2
device in the middle gets it right and
the problem there is that's a really
dirty hack that's very unlikely to get
implemented getting art changed at this
point is pretty much not going to happen
so no chance of that really happening
but this all comes back really to the
fundamental problem with path MTU
discovery and that's where the whole
thing fails if you think about what
you're trying to do you're requiring the
router to drop the packet generate an
ICMP have that ICP make it all the way
back to the hosts outside of its flow
before the host even knows there's an
MTU mismatch the host then has to react
it's completely unsupportable on the
modern router architecture it's like I
said vulnerable to denial of service and
it really adds latency installs the
performance on every flow if you've got
a wait for you to hit this have the ICMP
generated have it come back that's not a
fast thing and if you look at the work
people are trying to do on the Internet
taking out a couple of hundred
milliseconds of round-trip time from
just the set up of the TCP
and the initial windowing we're going in
completely the opposite direction we're
now adding significant latency that's
tied to the CPU of a router so we want
to talk about customer complaints every
time someone does something to runt the
CP owner router it's a really quick way
to get there and there's really no
replacement on the horizon for path MTU
discovery that's that's the big problem
here so supporting jumbo frames doesn't
really do anything to help you and
trying to use it makes the problem worse
so in short just want to have a
counterpoint to the people who are
pushing this on IX isn't saying this is
this is a good thing my take on it is
this probably going to cause a lot more
harm than good
under the current technology and I don't
really see any replacement technology in
the future so something to keep in mind
questions
yes I'm Darius come on come on isn't a
possible solution here basically better
standardization in that we standardize
on a specific MTU then say routers
implement a single binary flag where
either on this empty or not so Cisco and
juniper can you know work together and
like fix their stupid number whatever is
going wrong there and then the
interconnection Network empty use
becomes a lot easier that would be a
much better way to solve the problem and
the problem is the I Triple E has
steadfastly resisted any effort to do
that they refused it's been brought up
many times and they refuse to consider
putting any other value and I'm not
gonna fight that I Triple E so okay Leo
Leo McDowell far site security two
comments one is on the tunneling I think
perhaps the mistake you have made as you
have assumed that people wants a tunnel
layer three IP packets with something
that looks like a router they in fact
may want to tunnel their two packets
where there is no way to send a packet
too big they may want to tunnel non IP
protocols they may even want to tunnel
layer three without having the tunnel
look like a router that could send back
a packet too big message so I think
you're being a little too dismissive on
the value of being able to move a
greater than 1500 byte packet for
tunneling purposes the second comment I
have on the ARP thing is I agree that
perhaps changing the actual our protocol
is not going to ever be possible but I
am fascinated that no one has made an
attempt to negotiate a layer two MTU
because it seems to me like a amazingly
trivial problem you assume everyone has
a 1500 byte MTU you send an ARP and if
you get back a ARP reply followed
immediately by the hi I'm a new thing
that knows much bigger MT use and well
whatever else you want have stuff in
that packet then it can send bigger
packets I mean yes there's some details
there but I mean I would be shocked if
that was a 10-page RFC and more than a
couple of hundred lines to implement so
I don't know why people haven't gotten
on
fixing the layer to MTU negotiation
problem yeah absolutely so there's
there's lots of ways you can attempt to
skin that cat and that's definitely the
only sensible way to do it really what
I'm trying to point out here is that
we're not ready for primetime we're not
ready to roll this out and have people
try to achieve jumbo frames over the
Internet and there's a bunch of concerns
and this is one of them
so if if people could start paying
attention that and do some
standardization work on it you would you
probably got a lot further configured
far too many tunnels in my day greater
than 1500 byte actually works about
99.99% of the time where it does not
work is to consumer connections if you
want this on your cable modem or your
DSL link or your even your t1 to your
house probably ain't gonna never happen
but almost all backbone providers are
clean bigger than 1,500 internally and
in my experience the vast majority of
p-n eyes are clean greater than 1500
bytes so when I try to tunnel a greater
than 1500 byte packet admittedly like
1600 not 9,000 my success rates like
99.99% and the only place it ever breaks
is when it goes over a public exchange
so I'm not sure I would agree on the the
pni part I haven't really seen a lot of
interest on the pni side for people
doing that and then really the
interesting question becomes how broken
how many broken things are sitting out
there that we don't know about because
we're not trying that greater than 9,000
192 unless the 9216 range and I think
the answer is there's a lot I've run
across that more often than you would
imagine
and as soon as people do start trying to
send those packets you're gonna suddenly
have broken flows and no one's gonna
know why or where to troubleshoot it
way to sharpen my mind networks one of
the things that's frustrated me with
this whole MTU issue is the fact that
when the call for additional bandwidth
has come into play say for example the
transition from Fe to Giggy and get you
to ten is that people did not take
advantage of the opportunity to say all
right we recognize that there are
certain problems in the underlying
architecture the the underlying protocol
and specification design so we're gonna
make this incompatible just the way that
a ds3 doesn't talk to a sonic connection
and make the router reframe it and be
able to take advantages of some of the
some of the improvements that could that
could be had and allow overtime the same
way that you rarely see an EFI
connection on an end device in a mark
they're still out there but they're few
and far between and a lot of time to
take care of solving that little problem
to be able to allow us to get to bigger
m to use the way i look at it is when
you're talking about higher and higher
bandwidth at 1500 by an m2 you tang
giegi hunter Giggy it starts to look a
lot like ATM where you have so much your
overhead being thrown away because of
being because of so much your vamp being
thrown away because of overhead with
these little tiny small packets and this
really big fat pipe that you start to
introduce some enormous and efficiency
since the real cost some some real
expenses real cost losses into your
network if the yeah but commenting
behind me as well that that's creates
buffer problems if the standard spot is
a were to be able to do something like
that in going forward in future
technologies do you believe that that
would have a significant impact on
reducing the problems that you've
identified and perhaps being able to
allow us to be able to do bigger things
with fewer problems well it's an
interesting problem because you know
every time they change the protocol they
make significant changes to the the
layer one side so no one has a 10
gigabit hub that will talk to a one
gigabit device but it's hard to say
we're not going to make a switch that is
compatible with both 10 gig and 1 gig
that's gonna throw out a lot of your
business a lot of what
as a protocol is intended to do so I
understand why they hit that problem in
terms of efficiency I mean do the math
20 bytes 40 bytes of headers per 1500
bytes versus 9,000 isn't in the same
league as ATM it's not quite that bad so
yeah it's it's a slightly inefficient
but the question is are you actually
gaining enough inefficiency to make it
worth all the problems that you're going
to hit and I'm not sure the answer is
yes based on everyone else coming up
with perfectly reasonable solutions to
handle all this load to respond to that
the you look at the increasing demand
for larger and larger and larger file
sizes not just in terms of the source
for us for an on-demand stream but also
in just bulk data transfer to end users
the ability to deliver that is directly
proportional to the amount of data that
you can send in a syn in a single packet
so there is a real reason to want to do
more more data in a single in a single
packet just to reduce the the turnaround
time on a data transfer also true yeah
that's the one of the should've thrown
that as a reason but there are technical
reasons why it's a help the question is
is it worth all of the the suffering or
do we need to do more work before we
start trying to roll it out and I think
that's that's the point that I'm trying
to make is I'm not saying that it's not
technically lots of good benefits but
we've got to solve those problems we're
going to cause more problems than we
then we solve is just to say all right
well let's look at the people who are
defining the standards the people who
are producing their products and say all
right we need help so on IX and on lid
services we have a lot of customers who
have a little checkbox and it says do
you support jumbo frames and you spit
out 92 16 or 91 24 and they go away
happy and we know from stats that
absolutely nobody puts jumbo frames
across and I any of our IX platforms I
have a feeling that applies to the other
is
the room are we making things worse by
having 90-120 4sz MTU or whatever other
people have or a certain individual who
pushes 9000 who's in a car on his way to
Florida to not defend himself are we
making things worse or is that just okay
at this point so the the reasons I think
it's making it worse is while you might
have done a great job of making sure
that everyone that's on your ix is using
the same value you've picked a different
value than another IX and so the the
real potential here the real thought is
how do you cross these points multiple
times and have path MTU discovery work
and the problem is it's so broken as a
technology that once you start hitting
any type of MTU mismatch whether it's at
a single exchange point or whether it's
across two you start breaking stuff and
then the reason that I'm doing this
presentation is because a lot of people
are happy they come in and they say Oh
jumbo frames that sounds like a really
good idea I like better performance I
like you know faster flows and they
don't think what's the downside so I
want people to be aware of that and be a
little more cautious before they start
turning it on and you know there's a lot
of things out there that are gonna break
when they go over those flows as soon as
someone does try to send a big flow
across or still broken light you know
what's the suggestion you all would
really have to be the I Triple E for it
to have any any hope of going anywhere
no man a large frame cheerleader
shouldn't your email address be changed
why wrapped but that's not that that was
my complaint the question I have has to
do with the fact that large frames and
negotiation for large frames or
different framing MT use has been around
for longer than you have been alive and
the mechanisms that we have in place
as you described were for a simpler
kinder gentler time what we have now is
the same problem with two different
vectors pulling on it one of them is the
increased signaling rates on the links
ten hundred terabit speeds right and
it's increasing and if you stick at 1500
bytes you increasingly start to look
like the ATM problem of the 53 byte
cells and reassembly which leads to a
buffer bloat problem in the intermediate
processing and you have that whole back
off problem and all this stuff that
you're talking about question is is do
you do the short-term it's
cost-effective to eliminate any upgrade
and migration strategy to support a
newer different internet interconnection
modality just to make the quarter
profits or do we actually provide
constructive quality feedback on how do
we actually do this if Mike Sinatra
would get up and talk the internet to
community the yarny community have been
doing jumbo frames for a long time and
some serious studies on jumbo frames
it's got to start somewhere
pushing it at AI X's and backbones is a
reasonable place to do it because that's
where they that's where you have the
high bandwidth it will throttle
eventually but it'll throttle close to
the edge and quite frankly you can fix
the MTU issue and you can also reenable
TCP on port 53 at the same time thank
you very much so if we talk about
eventually when we're at one petabyte
Ethernet or something yes eventually
we're in the billions of packets per
second 1500 by Tim to use is going to
look bad the question is is 9000 any
better is is the 6x benefit really worth
it or do we need to find a way to do 60
X 6000 X where's our 64 km to you
all right probably the problem is the
number changes and the number changes a
lot so what we need is a mechanism to
negotiate this and actually make it work
when the MT use mismatch that's what
needs to happen before you can achieve
any of those goals not to say that they
aren't admirable goals but we have to
approach it from that perspective or
we're gonna break a lot of stuff in the
process so while it might be great in
the core as soon as it gets to the edge
and you hit an MTU mismatch and you
break the consumer that's a problem we
have about three minutes remaining let's
hit the last two questions and if we
could it sounds to me like you're not
complaining about jumbo MTU you're
complaining about jumbo MSS which is to
say you don't want the server's to
actually try and use 9000 having it in
the core for purposes of tunneling and
whatever is great as a band-aid for the
other problems that we have I wonder if
maybe the most pragmatic solution here
is to simply have the TCP sax do their
own path MTU discovery that doesn't rely
on routers sending packet to big
messages like if I send a 1,500 byte
packet and then I have another packet to
send a millisecond later and I make that
one a large packet and then accept do it
in the other order do the blood run
first then the small one if I get an ACK
on the small one a selective act that
says I didn't see your big one then I
know that that's a broken path MTU and I
can go back to 1500 it should be random
packet loss or member other yeah but
there should be ways for the TCP stack
to heuristically determine whether it's
likely to be successful at 9000 bytes or
not and do that in a way that doesn't
degrade performance because you're only
doing it after you ramp up the window a
bit I don't have all the answers of how
that would work but it seems like given
that the problem is the MSS and not the
MTU we should be trying to solve this in
TCP stacks not e'en networks well like I
said we definitely need a replacement
for path MTU discovery and yes the best
way to handle that would be to make it
in band as part of the TCP flow instead
of having the the network try to handle
it I'm not saying that jumbo frames are
horrible there's clearly some technical
advantages and I would like to see that
capability I'm try
to make people aware of all the
downsides and risks make sure that they
don't go then try to enable this on
their host and try to push out I agree
setting an MSS of 9,000 has lots of
dangers yep last question for what it's
worth Paul Baron thought that jumbo
frames were a very bad idea if my memory
serves me correctly jumbo frames were
created by Sun Microsystems in 1993 as
part of the specification for NFS
version 3 and the creation of the so
called fast ethernet standard and the I
Triple E had the good sense not to
include the large empty use in the fast
ethernet standard to me this issue is
all about what that guy yesterday was
mentioning I forget his name about Nanog
versus IETF people in this room know how
to make things work and an IETF they
know how to tell you why they shouldn't
be done and I think that this whole
jumbo frames issue really emphasizes his
point is that there should be more
interplay between
nanog and IETF and their food is a
better anyhow that's definitely a
problem and I was talking about the most
recent iteration of jumbo frames trying
to come back as pushed by algae on
around 2000 with Giggy
but yeah the problem here isn't even the
IETF it's it's worse it's I Triple E so
the IETF actually proposed jumbo frames
and the reason that they put forward was
to support very large as this topologies
and the I Triple E said that's a
horrible reason and rejected it
so even the IETF is on the side of jumbo
frames and didn't really get anywhere
with it yes overall we definitely need
better communication between the
standards bodies and better explanation
of why we need what we need where we
need them there's probably a good way to
handle this but I don't think that
turning on jumbo frames across the eye
X's or across anywhere else and trying
to shove big packets down the internet
is the right way to do it
so thanks Richard
you