good afternoon everyone I'm a nice
career currently with the Department of
Homeland Security Cyber Security
Division the work I'll be talking about
today was done while I was at Merritt so
the collaborators on this project were
with the University of Michigan and
other folks at ed merit what I'll be
talking about is understanding ipv6
internet background radiation and I'll
describe a few interesting things that
we've done in this regard at a very high
level why did we want to do this well
we've done a lot of darknet study in
ipv4 for example we we have been we've
been announcing one large dark net over
10 15 different - 10 15 years and we've
collected lots of data lots of analysis
lots of experience in the value we get
from that and I think 40 of the last
slash aids that were allocated by the
are IRS we did a dark net announcement
of those for a week at a time or more
just to try to understand the health of
the network and how usable or polluted
those Network entities were and that
proved to be very useful as well
some of the some of you who've who are
frequent Nanog attendees might remember
the work we've done on the 1/8 the 5/8
and so on all of them leading to some
very interesting results of the kind of
junk you pick up when you look at unused
address space and the idea there is
really the reason we're doing this is
especially if we start in ipv6 we were
hoping that if we can pick up issues
early on we can help improve ipv6
deployment as it gets started so that
that was where we were coming at from
this problem a quick background for for
those who are not familiar with our work
in the past what our network telescopes
network telescope is essentially
announcing unused address space picking
up junk that gets sent to it misdirected
to it and then doing analysis on what it
is and in slicing and dicing the data in
different ways the kinds of data
patterns we pick up our worm propagation
warm especially things like configured
they pick a random guess
Nation Address try to connect to it we
pick up DDoS backscatter we get lots of
syn ack from DDoS victims because of
spoof source IP addresses we will pick
up lots of random scanning activity like
encore 22 and more interestingly and
this is what we found when we were doing
the analysis of the ipv4 2/8 darknets
we we end up with a lot of
misconfigurations stuff we end up with
misrouted syslog we end up with video
streams for some strange reason people
are sending video streams to unused
address space essentially people have
done something wrong and in their
configuration are in their network and
you can get a lot of value by by
identifying these issues and then
telling people about them so they can
fix it so that's where we're coming from
what am I going to talk about today I'm
gonna talk about the large study of ipv6
on unreachable address space that we did
it covered about 86% of all allocated
address blocks in in ipv6 next I'll talk
about I'll characterize some of this
what are the patterns whether the trends
we're seeing what are we not seeing and
then towards the end I'll talk a little
bit more about what we did different in
this study and and some of the
implications of that in particular the
covering prefix methodologies that we
used in this study so some of the
previous work that has happened in ipv6
there were at least two other
experiments that had been done in this
area
one was a small experiment that ant that
announced a slash 48 they just saw 12
packets in 15 months essentially it's a
small space there's not a whole lot
going on in ipv6 then there was one
large study by Jeff Houston over at ap
Nick where they announced the covering
slash 12 from AP Nick for a period of a
year and and analyzed the the background
radiation that they saw there we we
thought that was a great idea so what we
did was we then extended that same idea
and to all our ARS we went to the our
IRS we said can we do the same
experiment that ap Nick is doing for
your address space and we'll report the
results that we get back to the
community and that's why I'm here today
so we announced the four five sorry 5/12
one from each of the our IRS
we got letters of authorization to do
the announcements we send them to our
upstreams the upstream say no way and
then we say no no no this really is
signed it's it's it's a real letter and
then finally those announcements were
accepted we act we advertise these / 12
prefixes why are merits ASM so we ended
up with two two datasets one is a
24-hour data set it's just one day of
darknets it's all 5/12 and then the next
data set that i'll be talking about in
detail is a three month data set and in
this case what's happened as we've
reduced the the right / twelve into two
chunks the / 14 and the / 13 and I'll
talk a little bit about the reasons for
doing that and and we'll talk about the
analysis of those two different data
sets so quick overview about what it is
what what address space are we actually
looking at what traffic are we picking
up you can talk about random IP
addresses that you see they fall into
four different categories routered
allocated routed unallocated unrouted
allocated and unrouted unallocated now
traditional dark Nets have looked at
unrouted unallocated address space this
is an address space where there was no
other announcement in the network and
you just pick up you just send out you
just set up your announcement to pick up
that unused address unallocated unrouted
address block so in the first part of
the talk I'm just gonna focus on results
for that traditional description I'm
gonna talk about the differences we see
between the different IR IRS the
different trends and differences between
ipv4 comparing ipv4 darknet to an ipv6
Dargan traffic and also whether we see
anything interesting at all so here's
here's the data set over time what
you're seeing is different different our
IRS I have different colored lines on
the on the chart and you're seeing about
20-25 packets per second from the Arin
region and all the other regions have
much lower traffic volumes and in a lot
of these cases why this is happening why
is the traffic variation boils down to
the next few charts which I'm going to
talk about spatial analysis we're
looking at where is this traffic coming
from and
and destinations where what it was a
destined to the red and the black lines
are for a panic and an errand region
specifically so if you're looking at
just the sources chart what we're seeing
is very few sources almost less than a
thousand unique sources are accounting
for over 90% of the traffic for the
three-month data set now that tells you
that there's some very specific event
there that can be tracked down and
perhaps mitigated in terms of
destinations it's even more more
dramatic for the air for the air for the
air in region we see less than a hundred
destinations so this target this data is
going towards specific IP addresses and
specifically less than a hundred of
those account for 90% of the traffic and
for the other two the other two regions
we see much lower traffic volumes how
does this compare with what we see in
ipv4 well first of all there's a clear
difference in volume of traffic just
like ipv4 and ipv6 traffic there's
there's a clear volume difference in
terms of how much dark no traffic you
see in an ipv4 dark net for an
equivalent slash for a for a slash a
dark net in ipv4 you would expect to see
close to 10,000 packets per second or
more in ipv6 we're seeing about so in
ipv6 for the for the most amount a
granade of traffic we're seeing about
20-25 packets per second what is the
difference in terms of the spatial
distribution of sources and destinations
in ipv4 and ipv6 is one more dense than
the other if you're looking at just the
sources for example we see that that
ipv6 sources are much more concentrated
ipv4 dark net sources have much larger
variation so in other words pollution
traffic in ipv4 is coming from a broader
set of actors than 90 v6 in ipv6 we are
seeing a very small set of actors and a
very small specific set of data
unlike I'd be before where it's much
broader if we look at the types of
traffic that we're getting in terms of
protocols or TCP flags you'll see an
ipv4 the bulk of what we get is TCP
traffic and and and the bulk of
what we see in in ipv4 as I as I talked
about earlier is configure scans its SSH
scans all TCP events we see some UDP
events and but very little ICMP now what
we're seeing in ipv6 darknet traffic
remember this is the unallocated
unrouted darknet traffic we're seeing
lots of ICMP probing and not much else
not much else not very very little
activity going on very few systems right
now in ipv6 so very few pollution
traffic this is why it was useful to do
this study early on so we you said well
one of the things that can that
contributes large largely in to Dokken
traffic in ipv4 is probing and scanning
activities do we see any sign of that
happening in ipv6 so we went ahead and
tried to do an analysis on the of the
data and what we find is there's no real
evidence of broad large-scale scanning
we do find some regional local scanning
attempts there's no indicator there's
nothing to indicate that those are
malicious
perhaps attempts to map out small
sections of the space perhaps misguided
or misdirected attempts to scan traffic
one interesting thing that we do see is
we see leak of link local addresses so
fe8 0/10 are linked local addresses and
they should not be routed and should not
be made available to anybody on the
internet but as it turns out people are
not blocking those at the routers and
the dude leaked out into the public
Internet just there were only a few set
of sources that were they were
generating this traffic but they did
account for a very large number of
packets within this data set worm
activity we looked for we had no reason
to believe that we might see it but we
said we should look just in case there
is something going on and as it turns
out there's no worm activity that we
could spot from dark net traffic in in
ipv6 so now let's talk about what we did
different in ipv6 for this experiment
that we haven't done before in the ipv4
remember in the ipv4 we were largely
announcing unallocated unrouted outer
space in this experiment what we did
different was in order to maximize
our coverage area we used a pull up
route pull up route essentially takes
the traffic that was unclaimed by a
routing table and says here you go this
is the unclaimed traffic on the Internet
now that has some implications and what
is interesting to see is this is this
was one of the unexpected side effects
of horror study is we are able to find
that 90 percent of 95 percent of the
packets we now observe are not the
traditional dark net they're different
there's something else they're pointing
to routing instability and they're
pointing to apparent leakage of internal
address space so let's let's go through
a quick reminder of what's what the
different words are right so one is
routed allocated that means it was
allocated address space and it was
routed we should not have received a
packet for the space but we did this was
unexpected unrouted unallocated this is
sorry unrouted and allocated this is
address space that was allocated to an
organization but it did not have an an
entry in there in the routing table also
strange why were we receiving these
packets so let's talk about what these
packets are and where they're coming
from so let's talk about in particular
the allocated and the routed data set we
see 36% of our packets of the total
number of packets we receive from our
experiment fell into this category these
prefixes were largely coming to us we
assume from routing problems instability
perhaps very very small outages we are
not able to confirm for sure that these
are micro outages but we have some
interesting indicator so we went ahead
and did a separate study just looking at
rough use data to see well what is the
stability of an average ipv6 prefix and
is it different from an ipv4 prefix and
as it turns out yes ipv6 prefixes in
general are less stable they are also
less well connected than an average ipv4
prefix and they're originated by a in
general coming from the edges so overall
what we are able to confirm is that
they're an average ipv6 prefix does have
less stability than ipv4 and that
potentially is a contributor to us
picking up a fair amount
this time now if you look at the
allocated and the unrouted traffic these
were once again packets that should not
have been leaking out potentially this
accounts for about 59% of the of the
total number of packets that we observe
in our data set
86,000 unique destinations are targeted
due to this and potentially this is
because of leakage of internal address
space this should not be happening but
it is in we were able to identify
actually two specific contributors to
this to the strap to this traffic one
was a large wireless service provider we
contacted them and they said no this
couldn't be happening we use this
internally and like no no this really is
leaking out and we share with them the
data and they're like oh well thank you
we'll fix it we did the same thing with
another hosting company but that was the
second largest contributor and both
operators you know were we're happy to
have identified the problem and fix
their miss configuration so that was a
good happy ending to that analysis
unallocated and router traffic this was
just strange it's not allocated by an ir
why is there traffic for in the ipv6
internet turns out it's just a small
fraction of it but we do see some
traffic and most of it we identified was
due to some experimental scanning that
was just not being very careful to not
scan unallocated space so we contacted
the three organizations and they said
yep we can do this better and they would
they did go ahead and make those changes
as well
so long story short what did we learn
from this well one of the things we
learned is there is a distinct
difference in ipv6 darkness we also
learned that there's value in in in
doing the study which which can have an
operational impact feeding this back to
to the organizations where the
organizations are able to remedy some of
the situations is is very helpful and I
think getting a head start on this in
ipv6 as we did hopefully will lead to
fewer problems in the future this also
leads to a second research follow-on
research that we want to do is looking
at routing stability for for ipv6
we did not expect to see the level of
instability that we did been
but obviously the there is there are
some fundamental issues there we want to
study those in a little bit more detail
the covering prefix methodology that we
used in this study is itself interesting
it talks it
than a pure darknet study so long story
short we did a large study of
unallocated used address space
unreachable address space in ipv6 we are
able to characterize typical background
radiation and the trends and how it
compares with ipv4 some interesting case
studies for example we found NTP traffic
that wasn't being misrouted and there
was some BGP session connect connection
attempts as well and we spend a
significant amount of time then looking
into the covering prefix methodology
which gives us something slightly
different and we are able to identify
things like routing instability leakage
of address space as well which were
unexpected results and unintentional
results questions
lots of time
we need to unmute the question mics
please Heather Schiller Google Fiber
should have titled your presentation how
to hijack the v6 Internet with everybody
watching
so just because you got eloise to route
the prefixes doesn't make it right
that is not darknet space it's actively
allocated to real companies who are
doing business and actually pushing real
traffic over it and I think that it's
unethical to have allocator to have
routed the slash 12 free tricks it's not
that different than what some Russian
companies who are announcing V 4/8 SAR
doing and when a network goes down or
something becomes unstable you're
getting traffic that you shouldn't be
seeing and I think that we should be
able to have more trust in the routing
system and from you know research
organizations to do responsible research
I don't I don't think that this is right
and we've taken it up with the IRS about
why they permitted this prefix to be
allocated if you want to do darknet
research that's fine but announce
prefixes that aren't actively allocated
to organizations already III think
that's that you make a good point and I
agree with you that there were some
intentional unintentional outcomes
that's not what we started out to do we
our expectation was there would be
nothing else here and we would be fine
now as it turns out this also brings up
an interesting question and and I'm and
I'm glad that this question that is
something that when you discussed here
which is there's but there's potentially
other people who could be doing this
right and have we done something useful
by at least highlighting the importance
of of knew yourself being able to do
this to understand potential leakages
and potential of routing instability in
your prefixes and in the organizations
that we work with that we were able to
identify they were they were happy that
we that we did do this experiment and
were able to help fix some issues that
they weren't aware of so perhaps it it I
think it
to the importance of being more aware
and perhaps doing this more by the
organization's themselves and not by us
so if you're announcing your own if
you're sorry you're talking about
organizations that were not announcing
their entire prefix and you saw leakage
for the pieces that they were using but
we're not announcing so let me talk
about this in a slightly different way
there's a there's an entirely different
experiment than be constructed by
injecting an organization's prefix from
multiple different locations the same
prefix with different lens and then
doing a fire drill what happens if
there's a route hijack of my prefix and
I'm going to try to inject this you know
at some regular interval to see what
happens I mean we have to have an
understanding of I mean organizations
probably so for example network
penetration testing is often done to try
to proactively identify issues that
might happen and things that might go
wrong and perhaps this is something with
the organization's permission yes you
did not go seek the permission of the
organizations that already had
allocations in this nut box
that is correct that is correct and
that's that's what what what I'm trying
to point out is if this were to happen
in the future that would be the word
worship the great the reason this
happened this way was because we were
not expecting this to happen
like how could you not expect to get
trapped like v6 not that different from
before like this happens in before as
well like I don't I just can't wrap my
head around why why it was okay to do
this in v6 like if you did this and
before people would lose their minds and
like you'd be all over the news and
renesis and bgp monde and all of this
stuff but like because you did it in v6
and no one's paying attention it's ok I
don't agree with that I think our
intention was to identify issues and to
highlight them in a public forum right
and and that's that's why we're here
reporting our results right I'm talking
about like how ethical is it to hijack
address space that's in use and
allocated to other people without their
permission but this was whether whether
this was not an I just felt so the
traffic was not hijacked the traffic
that was that was collected was
unclaimed unrouted but but that's
absolutely not the case that is it is
not the case because you did not you
announced the entire slash 12 and so
there are pieces of that that are
allocated to our organization and so if
if something happened where some route
went away or we misconfigured something
it is hijacked because now you're
getting the traffic so rather than it
not having a route and not so we did not
expect that those incidents would
actually were actually taking place we
thought the internet system is the
routing system is stable and then there
will be nothing coming to us that
shouldn't be coming to us you know how
it works it works the same way as before
and you went looking you intentionally
went looking for it without notifying
operators before you did this work I
think we'll have to leave it at that
ok let's have the next next question
please Michel Sinatra yes net I just
want to say that that just put some
little context in on this Geoff Huston
has been routing 2400 / 12 to various
telescope projects that he's been
running for many years
under the auspices of a pan and actually
at one point I helped him out with some
of that too I was very nervous and I was
very concerned about the exact same
things Heather was concerned about so I
certainly understand those concerns I
have the same concerns I would say
though let's not take Manish out to the
woodshed let's instead go to our our IRS
and say we don't want you issuing these
Aloise because they did they issued the
LOA so and they said you can route you
can announce this / well go to the our
IRS and say revoke the LOA we don't want
our address space being used in this way
so I'm just wondering how far and why
did you actually advertise the / Clause
because did this affect everyone
actually are just people behead v6
default routes point it out so we did do
an analysis on the route views and it
the our routing announcements were
visible for the large majority of route
view monitors as well as in the right
region as well so they did propagate up
questions
I think that's everyone Thank You
minister
you