come on
there we are
so uh i have the uh the pleasure of
going through a lot of the
cryptocurrency blockchain and other
stuff with about my team does that
and we run into a lot of things on the
way
and some of the things that we do
i was thinking about
showing you
the reason for
um that we see a lot of problems are
this there's a lot of money in this
business
it's about i don't know how i would say
this but
136 billion dollars
in d5
today which is quite
quite a lot of money so there's a lot of
people trying to get hold of this
what we've done in the work is that we
haven't sort of been able to
do the thing that most psychologists do
to find out who's the scammers
so
who you can trust that's up to you as a
user or as a
customer to these companies
so
no
there we are
a little bit quick for this
and
so
things that we've found so for example
we have a rounding errors
that unfortunately cancel themselves out
because of the way that blockchains
calculate time
so we had a problem with a interest rate
that was 20 off
but based on the fact how they
calculated time it actually was zero
so when the blockchain actually started
to pick up speed
the
interest rate went off
and they couldn't figure out why until
we looked at the code and suddenly
realized okay this is why
so now they look at something else to
have as a time reference instead
this is an interesting one
programs that look and con sort of check
that it's actually itself
so one equals one
okay
so let's everybody do whatever they want
this program that's not too good either
and then we have the the ones that uh
let everybody you sort of change the
parameters on the fly
when it's
saying that well let's change the amount
of money transfer from this account to
another account instead
we have
impossible endless
trust loops
sort of things that trust something else
that trust something else that trust
something else and that trusts the first
thing
and that makes
things really interesting when it comes
to the
how they calculate
uh
the
outcome of this program another thing is
that a lot of these programs rely on
external
information sources oracles
but the problem is that not all oracles
are
still valid and in some cases we have
found programs that sort of set up their
own oracles
and the
[Music]
results from those are quite
interesting sometimes when people start
to tune them
to
game the system which is also something
that's interesting so one of the things
that
coming back to the the
the slide about who can you trust
well
you need really need to go through these
sites if they're going to use them and
look at if they are
trans as transparent at you as you
should want them to be
um
when it comes to programming
well a lot of these
programs are being done extremely
quickly or by people that are extremely
cheap or that
are
called them divas sometimes and they
want to show off and the problem is that
they create extremely complex
programming
[Music]
situations for example we had a
situation where we had four different
layers of macros
the code was really really simple but
when you sort of dig into the macros
there was
millions of errors
but it looked good
yeah and then we have the open source
issue well it's
just for it to be open source and not
it's transparent but not secure
i think we all know that
so
we have seen
teams that have been inspired by the
same code base inspired and
sort of
copied the code
and
when a review suddenly says to one of
the projects that well this is actually
a serious bug in your system
suddenly another project that has been
sort of
using the same code has been
attacked
so it's it's really like being
working in in the wild west
it's uh
fantastic to see all these different
teams sort of competing
against each other
and sometimes not using um shall we say
playing fair
oops
all right stepped on something here
oh well
there we are
uh yeah another thing is error handling
by crashing
uh
people think that there's a really good
idea to just panic the program and let
it crash because the blockchain would
clean it up
it does but it leaves interesting traces
on the environment where the program has
been running like private keys
another interesting things for
forensics to find
and we actually found some interesting
scams where you well the solarwinds
discussions were quite interesting to
listen to because
if you have in this case it was nine
different
sort of things that needed to be
positive
that would trigger something in in the
program to allow the one who owned the
program to sort of
get rid of
or get all the money in the pool
so it was quite interesting and to
sort of summarize about two billion
dollars has been stolen the last
well
seven years
someone's been returned but most of them
has been sort of missing
and to be honest none of these projects
were actually not thoroughly reviewed
they spot checked stuff in them
and
that may be good but if you're depending
on a lot of different things
if one of those things are broken
the whole thing falls apart
and so we usually say this is a perfect
storm with no reviews
you have ex sort of ridiculous time to
market and there's too much money
pushing for these projects to go online
so a lot of the times when we do as a
step into the review
the program is already online
on the main net
with a huge number of money in it
and they
sort of call us and say well there was
something happening last saturday that
we were sort of
sort of thinking about could you please
have it review our code before we get
sort of completely robbed
and
sometimes we have the time sometimes we
don't
well um i spend more or less my life on
this so if you want to spend some time
with me talking about it because i have
lots more talking about it
we have a little booth around the corner
and
well
thanks
you