so we are live here from sexy 2021 uh
stuck and fabio just came off stage uh
giving an excellent talk about some
threat hunting they've been doing some
tools you
developed to figure out how to
be a little bit ahead of the bad guys
right yeah right and maybe a little bit
about how to be the bad guys or
it's all of them right yeah that's it it
can't just be all defense right we
everybody likes to hack stuff but
what i love about this whole thing that
we presented today which was
um
responsive incident response right is
that that's redeeming reverse because
you need to understand all the offensive
tools being used and if you are a good
red teamer it's going to feel natural
for you when you're doing the whole
incident response thing because you
identify patterns and it's like reading
redacted reports that somebody wrote up
and you can see what happens so i think
it's really interesting
yeah and we have the luxury to have both
red teamers and blue teamers into
instant responders that
help doing this with this you know
handling these cases and it's always
nice to have a red team or perspective
when you try to figure out what an
actual cyber criminal did because then
you can think you know from their
perspective like if i were there i had
this type of access i was in this system
and my goal was that how would i do it
and then you can check is that how they
actually did it or not and it actually
helps a lot yeah
and the other way around as well right
what we learned from incident response
you can apply into your own red teaming
because if you know how to find stuff
you also know how to not be found
exactly and i think
also to be a good red teamer it helps if
you work blue team yeah because you you
know where where sys admins get sloppy
and where they uh
sort of take shortcuts and things like
that so uh yeah yeah it all ties
together i think it's a good good idea
to have um to have both sides of the of
the house represented in some response
yeah
i would not i would throw it to the mix
also the monitoring and the sock yeah
because they actually do the the
detection and quick response right so
they are the one like setting the rules
for what to check for uh and uh and
alerting and reacting to that so should
the uh sock people also go into the red
teaming
i think that's awesome and we have
people from our sock that move into pen
testing and red teaming
so
i think that's the best the more
perspectives you can get
and the more you act
uh
effectively yeah
i think for for me one one of the things
i i've worked uh a lot of incident
response and worked in forensics uh uh
in in the before times uh but one thing
i liked about your talk was that you did
the analogy about you know a jigsaw
puzzle that you have to find little
pieces and and and it might you might
not even have all the pieces but it
somehow creates a picture and and you're
you're
keeping that timeline as basically a
security blanket that you're you're
attaching everything to and try to
correlate things so
i i really enjoyed that that's
i am what what do you think i mean you
guys developed tools to to sort of
build into that but but do you think
there should be
like with you discussed in the talk um
[Music]
microsoft's uh
cache for uh remote desktop
do you think that software companies
like microsoft should be more
in terms of helpful in terms of creating
tools to to use that as incident
response or should that be thwarted by
or
i think uh yes ideally yes uh but i mean
if i'm trying to look from from their
perspective uh
they of course want to work with giving
possibility to detect and possibly even
block stuff right and they do it in
their way you know they push the new
solutions and all the you know the new
fancy solutions they have
uh which which you know they're usually
good you know they do the right things
provided that you are in a modern
environment and that you have other
things in place it doesn't make sense to
use the latest and greatest if you don't
even do the basics right but here we're
talking about missing the basics and
this is the stuff we're left with so i
don't know yes it would be great to have
but i i don't see that there is
huge value for a company like microsoft
to do that then again they they are
sometimes very transparent sometimes not
because
but they have tools like you know
autoruns and all this stuff anyway like
yeah i mean that's just internals that's
you know it's it's microsoft yeah it's a
part of microsoft that does those
they could probably just create one
that's the rdp cache explorer
sure right sure in theory and yeah
i mean it's possible it's gonna come up
like but uh in theory they will start to
use the captchas as do the puzzling from
the repeat cache to show that you're
human right yeah you guys can be a great
idea
do that can you figure out how to sort
my mccasting this
or a hydra or whatever wow awesome great
idea
you're happy to explore that one perfect
one thing that i picked up on your talk
was all the different tactics and
technologies that you showed up was a
way of disguising your actual attack
towards the responders right throw away
some some stupid error message that that
will make
the incident responders stop yeah and
look another way oh this is just a
phishing attack or this is just this and
that
but but how common would you say it is
someone goes in goes after data and then
throws out some bitcoin miner just to
see that oh the instant responder oh
it's a just bitcoin miner or a monero
miner person that's after us do you have
any data on that
i don't have anything on my head but i
don't think that's very common among
criminal groups uh it is more common
when you have an apt
that actually has
you know they have a lot of resources
they have time
and they can actually do this and they
actually have value in doing that
but
but it would be quite easy just to throw
up something for sure it would but it
also tells you that it's important to do
with our investigation yeah so when do
you stop investigating
when you're ready to do a full
kick out and
you have a plan for how you were
building yeah because that's the thing
when you want to do a kickout
you need to make sure you do all the
things you need to do at once right say
you have x number of systems compromised
and
there's back doors talking to servers
you know thread after servers
their accounts are compromised
then you know okay i need to clean that
server i need to block
i need to block those ips in the
firewall and i need to reset the
passwords for these accounts and they
came in through rdp for example so we
need to close rdp so they can come back
in the same way and so on so all these
things you need to have found them all
ideally so you can do them at the same
time because if you do one but you need
the other they're gonna figure out
that you're doing that and then they're
gonna hide differently it doesn't really
apply for ransomware cases so much
because you know obviously you've
noticed
your is
so then they know of course there's
going to be an investigation they're not
really in in most cases i guess they
could be but but um
that's more for targeted attacks that
are not ransomware
then you really want to make sure you
find everything before you do the kick
out yeah and that that takes time and i
don't know how it depends how complex
the environment is and how advanced and
extended the attack is
it's easy to say also that you probably
just change the passwords right but you
need to change
all the passwords everything all the
time
at the same time right yeah at the same
time and then you need to have another
cleaned domain where you can start
working with and you know this is
complex stuff and you have people
working trying to take care of stuff
trying to do what they're doing customer
is stressed all the time right and
asking you when when can we start doing
this then losing money by the minute
yeah and so that's also the thing that i
love about doing this work is that when
you enter an incident
in the first stages if it isn't around
somewhere you are
you're getting called in adrenaline is
pumping you're starting to figure things
out and you're
and you know the threat actor is in the
system and you need to figure out how
did they get in and which and how do we
stop them because the system can be
around somewhere at any second because
they don't know you're there so you need
to be stealthy as well doing the
research you can't just start a bunch of
new user accounts in the main naming
them your company consultant one because
that's gonna flag them so you need to
stealth that look what's going on and
then eventually figure out like do we
have backups are we create are we ready
so we don't get that vengeance around
somewhere where there is one yeah
exactly then they do things uh you know
quickly yeah like you know the phases
are usually you take over the entire
infrastructure first then you go after
data uh it usually takes a while to find
the right data and then you steal that
so you have the additional leverage when
you do the ransomware
uh and uh and then you destroy backups
they usually also like uninstall uh av
centrally if it's a group policy or
whatever they just push it out and then
they do the run somewhere ever at the
same time if for example if you catch
them in the middle phase there when they
already have a lot of access
uh but they're still you know they still
need to go through data to steal and
stuff like that and find the backups and
they see that you're on to them they're
probably going to be kicked out any
minute now
you know the quick reaction could be
well okay forget the backups and the
data just
so so that's a very bad spot to find
them or to at least let them know that
you found them how common would you say
is that they go after the backups and
crash that
all the time pretty much also that like
you could go persistent and
just encrypt the backups right
so during half a year you start doing
the
encryption of the backup when you do
read back you do that decryption
so you don't see that there is a problem
yeah
and then you drop the key
i see that but then it's easier to wipe
them and do the brass markings yeah but
then but then you would recognize that
right and then you have that your
off-site yeah okay if you have actual
off-site and offline backups yeah that's
true fair enough uh and it's definitely
something that could
potentially be done but it's very
interesting i'm just going to say
they are so successful already
they haven't even start thinking about
more sophisticated stuff like that
they don't need to they don't need to
yeah
it's an roi thing yeah you know the
delay there is between the first breach
and when they actually start to manually
work in the environment that can be
weeks or months so nobody sees anything
right magic how many companies are
currently breached and they are not
being actively worked with because
they're working on some other higher
priority targets
that can be weeks or months imagine how
many they already gain they're
overloaded with networks they already
have access to yeah they own you create
persistence and then they idle they just
unleash time to harvest one one thing
that i i
really liked as well about your your
presentation was that you tied in the
the importance of threat intelligence uh
to to be able to proactively find when
when things are going to hit the fan
uh could you could you elaborate some
more about that because i i mean i i
guess that's that's a case-by-case thing
you you
gave one example uh where you had a
typical mo for a certain threat actor uh
but
how could you use
threat intelligence in a more
general way to to sort of be on top of
things yeah so there are the the more
technical iocs type of things that are
pretty straightforward like oh this ib
address is a c2 server you can
proactively block that right and simple
stuff like that or you know this email
like this domain is sending out machine
emails like you know there is so much of
that and that can be done proactively
if it's shared people can block it um
then the other part is more of uh uh
uh i guess there are different layers
one is the techniques
like the first example we showed about
the rtf uh that you can talk about we
see this attack that works this way and
this is a relatively generic way you can
detect this type of attack even if it's
a variation of it that's tricky to
define because it really depends on case
by case so i don't have a good answer
for that but then the layer on top of
that i think it's more generic in terms
of
what type of attacks are there even like
how common is ransomware and how common
is that they actually delete the backups
before the ransomware if you have those
statistics if you know that in 100 of
the cases they delete the backups that's
probably gonna put that at the top of
the list if you're gonna handle
something start with securing your
backups and testing your backups right
we do this work when we do like threat
intelligence reports and profiles that
are specific to customers we start with
like the generic landscape and then
narrow it down to what they actually
expose and what problems they actually
have and then we gave recommendations
that are
actually mapped to the threats that are
currently seen in the wild because you
know if you need to start from very low
security there is so many things you can
do yeah right where do you start
right you should probably do most of
them anyways but you need to have an
order
we're doing it where do you use the
priorities start from the ones that are
actively exploiting it in the wild right
now
so we try to do the mapping and give
them a plan that is actually mapped to
urgency based on what's happening but
are you also mapping the
priorities depending on the criticality
of the amount the assets are you
protecting i mean it's it's not just a
generic it environment it could be
production environments it could be like
erp systems etc etc exactly and that
needs to start from the business but
it's a question that of course is
usually asked or is always asked like
what's the worst that can happen
right how would your business die
tomorrow if we don't have for example
the same database or this erp or or uh
for us the uptime is very important for
example and and then you map it to okay
these are important assets what do they
depend on
uh because that's the other challenging
part like they maybe depend on 100
different third-party software that we
have no idea about so what if they get
breached so and do they even know what
they depend on
they usually don't they usually don't
yeah
and it's not easy in their defense it's
hard the systems are complex yeah uh
absolutely looking especially at the
case stuff i mean you're looking at
several layers of dependencies right
yeah yeah but then again
facts in hindsight prove that cassette
was pretty broken and and you know
that's they weren't focusing on that and
people are relying on the trust from
suppliers so it but if you remove that
idea and say okay i got this ip
environment that's mine that i'm the
guard of it's i'm susan whatever and i
have a bunch of things that are exposed
to the internet what i would do
personally is i would i would constantly
just git pull the latest nuclei
templates and whatever and just scan my
environment continuously because that's
where like one day cds come out and see
if it smashes your system if it fits
send yourself a notification in slack
this scp fire falls positive or not like
use the bug mounting methodology and
attack your system externally because if
you don't do it somebody else gonna do
it for you and if it fires at least then
you know and it's 100 better to know
what you're what you're having that's
wonderful than not having it yeah and if
you don't have the capability to do it
yourself i guess that maps to whatever
sort of
vulnerability exposure
type of thing you can put on the outside
right now i i don't even know probably
if there are to be honest i know there
are many uh ideally you have hackers
like stuff that can do that for you
continuously but you know they got that
stuff to do as well
but i mean identifying the exposure is
very important and also be very
uh very quick when things happen because
step number one is inventory know what
you actually have especially what you're
exposed to
step number two is uh be consistent with
the patching level and it's boring to
talk about patching no one likes to like
you know
go through the process of doing the
inventory and check with the perspective
of make sure it's a cash and get the
notification when there is a new patch
available and stuff
but take stats it's
uh it's actually if you look at our own
stats uh from from i think nearly 100
different cases so far this year
[Music]
i think the highest
number on what initial access back to
the use is external exploitation the
next is phishing
and you will see those nice firewalls
with vpns enabled just for the i.t
admins that
they forgot about or that kind of stuff
that's happening all the time because
you do that
the easiest route right yeah but it's on
the internet it's on the internet
yeah and so so no one likes to talk
about patching but it's actually very
important so first reduce the exposure
right if you don't have to have it
exposed don't have it
uh if you need to have it explosive but
not necessarily have to have it hosted
in your own premier infrastructure put
it on a cloud service yeah that's a lot
better if it gets if you get pawned at
least it's not your infrastructure
so
yeah right but still it's a lot better
to have it in your internal network
exactly so i think that's a good note to
uh to end on and um
we thank you a lot for taking the time
to talk to us and um
you guys are done now so you can just
enjoy it enjoy the rest enjoy the sun
and enjoy the show
the venue and have a nice day in
stockholm thank you thank you for
sharing with us on second support
costume fabio
frederick
thank you very much thanks