now let's continue with the program and
actually I'm being always interested in
in wearable devices and also Tizen is of
course also providing something like
that so I've been looking really forward
to this presentation that's welcome
orphan as there are over here and let's
see what this presentation is going to
be about thank you very appreciate that
that's a really great introduction and
thank you all for coming to my
presentation my name is our fantasy art
I am with the Intel security group also
known as McAfee as you can see the
mcafee logo so there it's on my shirt as
well so this is the agenda for today but
i just wanted to also call out the goal
that I have here I wanted to give you
guys enough information about Tizen as a
platform how to look for files that are
related to tyson how to analyze them and
make you dangerous enough so that if you
come across a threat for that platform
you would know what to do and you
recognize it so that is my goal here ok
so kaisan and that this is always the
biggest pronunciation is tyson is eddie
correctly pointed out and it's not tease
on but it it is something that we get a
lot of people asking questions about is
a linux-based operating system for
devices including smartphones tablets in
vehicle information systems devices
smart tvs laptops smart cameras so the
reason for that is this guy so Tyson is
a collaboration of Intel and Samsung but
because Samsung is so big on the
consumer electronics space they wanted
to have a platform to to basically
consolidate all their electronic devices
and in the direction in you know in the
direction we're headed where a lot of
devices in this day and age of the
internet of things are you know they
have we have the neat for one device to
talk to another device this was the
perfect platform for this is the perfect
time for Santa to launch a new operating
system
so as Eddie pointed out it's it's not
just a mobile operating system it's
actually because of circumstances that
arose Taizo was originally supposed to
be launched on a smartphone do you do
some complications that did not happen
it will happen I believe end of november
the first target market is india and
right now it exists you can actually go
by devices that actually have the Tizen
operating system it's the NX 3,000
camera the Galaxy gear s this will be
sold I think starting next month from
what I've just been told if this
actually has a 3 it has a data modem 3G
device so it's actually standalone
smartphone / wearable device and the
smartphone and the the samsung TV
operating system will be replaced with
tyson so it's out there right now and
it's it's something that you guys can
actually take a look and get your hands
on you get start investigating now so
the origins of tyson go back to 2008
where there's roughly about five
platforms here but the liebo which is
linux mobile that samsung was originally
using and planning to replace their
feature phones with and there's moblin
which stands for mobile linux see the
connection that linux mobile mobile naas
and then there is MIMO which was
supposed to be the successor to the
symbian operating system from Nokia so
you know because there's so much you
know similarity between these guys they
were both they were all literally just
layered operating systems built around
the Linux kernel so it just made perfect
sense for these guys to merge with these
guys come up with a Mego operating
system around that same time in 2009
Samsung decided to keep this project
going but they decided to come up with a
new consumable version of an operating
system to replace the operating system
on feature phones called bada now if you
haven't heard about bada it has not
taken off in North America but it's it
does have success in Korea Samson's
native home market and it's an ecosystem
it's got smartphone devices as well as
an app market as well as close to about
four
naps last I checked so to some extent it
was successful so Samson wanted to keep
this guy going and it was you know to
their credit the dibadda app ecosystem
was never violated with a malware which
you know let's just face it even Apple
iTunes or Google Play can't take as a
credit so so they want to maybe set
something that was really interesting
they wanted to keep that going so that's
where Tizen came from 2011 a lot of
these guys decided you know this is
exactly what we want to consolidate take
the attack surfaces of these different
operating systems bring the best of
breed practices and Tyson was born so
since 2011 till today this is where
Tizen stands the first vulnerability for
Tizen was in January first of 2013 20 12
64 it was basically a little issue that
was discovered on the devil's where
despite the fact that you turned off the
Bluetooth setting on the on the dead
phone it really didn't turn off and
unfortunately any device around you
anybody who was wardriving something
that could pick up the thing but then
again it was a depth what I was never
ever meant to be in production so it
wasn't such a big vulnerability the
biggest change after that at this point
in time app developers were encouraged
by Samsung and Intel to look at Tizen as
the platform for web app development the
the html5 platform was something that
Samsung and both Intel were heavily
promoting and they said this is what you
want to if you are planning to be in
this space you want to leverage your
html5 skills your web app development
skills and you want to make a profit
about it this is the platform you want
to do it and it's pretty reasonable idea
if you think about it because not only
are you exposed to smartphone app
developer but you will also be able to
extend that app experience if you're a
developer to to other platforms so
so in 2013 basically actually let's go
back for a second here so bad as I said
you had some good characteristics the
the underlying runtime in the bada
framework was actually poured it over to
the Tizen platform so for the first time
in addition to web apps Tyson also had
the ability to run native apps and the
one thing that was really really big
point for samsung to for developers was
the fact that native apps and web apps
are both first-class citizens they would
be known or capabilities or API calls
between the two so if you're a hardcore
c developer you want to basically
develop what your apps and give people
you know that experience on your native
runtime oh then you can actually do that
or if your web developer you want to
call api set or you know that are not
possible of that so there's no
restriction essentially so 2014 is when
the first phone will be launching
hopefully knock on wood it will be in
november sometime and that's when we
also kind of expect the App Store to be
launched so this is the architecture if
anybody has ever seen any of Dan
Bronstein's presentations about the
Tizen architect the Android architecture
the dalek framework and stuff later
you'll see that there's a lot of
similarities and that's the first thing
people ask me like is this a ripoff and
it's the same thing essentially again
the key concept beer it's a layered
operating system built on the colonel a
linux kernel and then the different
layers actually are depending what
device you're using if it's it's a
smartphone it's a vehicle it's a camera
the different layers would be there and
the three most common layers is of
course the the core system framework
which has all these you know the app
frame with the system based connectivity
the services that are provided by the
device you are and this is dependent on
the device you're using then of course
you have the web framework providing the
runtimes the framework to run the apps
either if you're developing a native or
or web
so Tizen runtime packages a package in
Tizen is nothing wonder the container or
executable content essentially now each
package has a unique package ID and
within each app and within each package
you can have multiple apps now each one
of them has to have a unique app ID as
well as the app name the app name can
overlap but the ID a PI D has to be
unique all apps in a package share
resources of those the privilege defined
at the package level so you can have
multiple apps within a package but they
all have to have they all or to have to
work off of the privileges divine of the
core app level Tyson framework supports
three type of packages web packages
sorry web applications native apps
hybrid apps which is a mixture of
actually web apps and native and it also
supports the installation of RPM
packages and the RPM package the mode I
put in there is that despite the fact
that web applications and native
applications require you to explicitly
sign the application for insulation our
PM packages don't I consider to be a
security issue and the guys that ties in
they also kind of yeah yeah we think it
is they're also going to change this in
the next release so a web application is
based on the w3c widget packaging
specification which is exactly how the
the Firefox OS is dealing with packages
as well and all the apps on Firefox
think they can easily be ported over to
ties it without too much trouble you
know it's html5 again as the core
development engine engine there as well
as the framework people are asked to
develop their apps around a web
application must conform to the
following it has to be a zip archived
and the extension will be wgt so
if you ever see this it's either Firefox
app or it's a ties a nap and this is
what it looks like so the app idea again
I said the app ID has to be unique it's
a ten bite long string it's about four
levels down if you
unzip the file and then when you do you
know you can see the entire content so
reverse engineering or getting this to
getting a black box system running to
basically get the outputs of a web app
or very it's not trivial at all hybrid
and native applications must conform to
the following convention again it has to
be a zip archive the the extension in
that case is tpk that's the file
extension for native applications the
package structure looks like this it's a
it's a it's encompassing of the web
application as well as what what is used
to store the the elf binary so having
said that if you're if you have any
skills on the symbian platform you know
basically decompiling arm binaries your
unlock your skill sets can be users
we're easy to give you compile and debug
elf minor either because they really are
just self binaries and that's where they
are stored so applications security and
access control overview so at the core
of the Tizen security enforcement policy
it's privileged control and application
signing both of this you know taken from
vessel you practice from Android and
Apple which includes process I
installation sandboxing and mandatory
access control this is called smack I'll
talk about this in a minute so some of
the key principles that Tizen uses is
all applications will run with the non
root user ID including system damon's so
nothing on a Tizen device maybe
smartphone camera or anything else
should be running this and there's one
or two exception but they're bugs and
the guys that ties in are working on
bringing this down and again it's
because of the the consolidation from
the you know
it's because of the consolidation will
break here getting all of these guys to
be nice to each other and talk to each
other and getting you know the best of
breed practices you're here is not easy
so okay so an application again in the
sandbox world an application is only
allowed to read and write files in its
home directory and shared media
directory that's it you can't access
anything else and if you do it's it's
basically because you either rooted the
device or you've somehow i exploited or
broken the sandbox privileges now closes
are very similar to the concept of
permissions in android with what little
difference and we'll call that in a
second here tyson provides api level
access control for sensitive operations
and so essentially what it does is all
the api's have been separated or grouped
actually clustered depending on their
security attack surface so you can have
access to some of them depending on who
you are so if you're a plat for a
general public just one-off developer
you can access only a subset of the
entire API set same thing if you're a
partner you get to access more api's
platform is the ultimate you basically
ties in or the carrier you make Sovine
access all the AP is and it's similar to
the concept of how system permissions
are used on Android wear certain apps
can only access certain AP is used by
the system if they're signed by the
system signature application without
proper privileges cannot use the api's
doesn't matter you have the permissions
it's dependent on the signature and the
other thing that's interesting about
ties in application is that whereas on
Android you require one signature on
Tizen there are two and again it doesn't
mentioned before depending on the
signature that you have that is the
essentially determines what is the
probability API proposes that you can
access so an author signature is
basically the author and that has to be
registered with the types of development
certificate authority which is the
tysons
or and the distributor signature this is
generated by the the Tizen Association
of the Tizen store and is usually only
assigned to say large carriers or
somebody who samsung trusts enough to to
basically allow them to either develop
the platform or extend it or you know
somebody who is in need of special api's
or something like mobile like actual
cars the in-vehicle entertainment system
so here's an example of the API that
I've got this documented in the paper
that gives you a list of all the APS for
example I don't know if you can see that
the app certificate I believe that's
what it says can only be accessed by the
partner signature same thing with things
like see let's take a look at your
bookmarks and stuff can only be accessed
by platform and stuff that you know we
take write it on Android for example
changing a system setting that can only
be done by platform so you know if your
malicious app you try to uninstall a
security application unless you have a
partner signature that's not going to
happen so the other thing different in
the Tizen you know security model is
it's something that Android actually try
to adopt with a pops but for one reason
or the other they decided not to go
ahead with it is that you can define
permissions post installations on the
app by the user so in android unites is
a policy of all or nothing so you have
an app that's requiring SMS privileges
or or I don't know connection to the
internet but you're not comfortable with
that app talking to the internet for
some reason or if you don't want it to
be you know somehow accessing your
contact database you can't do anything
about it the only choices you uninstall
the app but on Tizen by default what you
can do is you can basically take that
granular permission level and say you
know what I don't want this app after
installation accessing my contacts
databases anymore or I don't want it
accessing my location information
anymore now the problem you're and the
trick here is that app developers have
to keep
in mind that this is happening in the
background and this is this is something
that the user has an option so they have
to come up with error checking routines
on their own the system won't tell you
if somebody's disabled it so your app is
basically prone to crash if it's not
which is one of the reasons why a pops
wasn't officially launched now smack is
a Linux security module that determines
the process how processes interact with
each other and share information in a
nutshell this is how Tyson basically
achieves sandboxing so the key concept
here if if there are two entities and
they want to communicate with each other
they need to have one of these labels
that basically identifies for each of
those objects you going to have a
labeled so for example I have a label
that says I could talk to her and she
has a label that she can talk to me and
you can get more granular on that and
you can say between 6pm and 6pm and you
know you can restrict it more so that
that is essentially the court here that
is driving smack and the entire thing
compared to like to say selinux is
simplicity is the goal that we're going
for you know I think somebody was
something like selinux was rejected
because of that over smack and of course
smack is part of the Linux upstream so
every app has its own label which also
can be used as a way to identify the app
in addition to the app ID and Tyson's
uses these smacks labels to control apps
API devices functions and everything so
basically not only our apps restricted
by snap smack on what they can do when
they communicate you can actually create
smack policies around two components
within a Tizen device and how they
communicate and how they interact so
content security framework now this is
mcafee or intel security groups
contribution to the Tizen ecosystem now
that this is a vendor agnostic framework
you know what we realized here and
you know it was based on experience of
Android that sandbox operating system
they don't make it easy for a new
vendors to do what they need to do so it
would be ideal to have a platform or a
layer to work off of which actually
exposes hooks so that you can basically
you know if you find something malicious
or if you're planning to write your own
engines to scan files or scan URLs you
would have the ability to to basically
not worried about how would you actually
remove the app and subletter you focus
on what you need to do which is write
the code for the engine and that's it
and that's what semantics I'm sorry well
that's what say a couple of other
companies like this paresky they're also
doing and there's right now to vendors
actually who are actually if i'm not
mistaken will be there available as a
download on the Tison app store when it
launches which is mcafee and kaspersky
so you know that's the other hidden
agenda I have here which is to get you
guys interested in the content security
framework enough to to identify that you
know what you can maybe reduce your time
to market by using this and again it's
open source we have very little control
over this other than than you know maybe
helping you guys have a documentation I
write your own engines to hook onto this
okay so let's face it phones are nothing
without their app ecosystem in this day
and age right so the apple ecosystem in
this case is represented by the Tizen
store again we're hoping that it's going
to be launching around November that's
what the tysons or guys were telling me
now this isn't something that they told
me what we actually figured this out on
our own which is we looked at a couple
of available Tizen phones that was being
demoed at the Tizen developer conference
in i believe it was in june or May in
San Francisco we went over there we kind
of started looking through the device
and seeing how many apps are available
in the App Store so we're roughly the
ecosystems around 10,000 apps or less
and there's only about two devices where
I believe that will be launched so
you're looking at looking at initially
an ecosystem of 10,000 apps and
increasing and there's roughly about 200
apps for the Tizen version of the
wearable device so it's not a you know
if you're looking to get into a new
operation this is the perfect time to do
it so how do you ask get on the Tizen
app store they go through an app
validation process which consists of two
phases now after a nap as a developer
has been submitted to the Tizen store
what the first phase does is basically
run an inspection automated dynamic
glasses it's it's based off of emulators
and there's actually quite a lot of
documentation on this and what they do
is they literally just run your app and
I'm live emulator and they basically see
what are the inputs and outputs they try
to simulate interactions with the app to
see if there's certain functionalities
that will trigger some more inputs or
outputs and based on that they basically
give it a pass or fail if it's been
flagged it goes here I mean all apps go
to hear any of it but it goes that into
the extra note saying look there's
something that flag to phase one you may
want to take an extra look at it in
phase 2 phase two is human in static
analysis that this is something Samsung
and said that they are going to do so it
goes through an automation as well as a
human inspection process and the best
part Tyson has said this is the part
that always causes a little bit of a
concern samsung said that they'll turn
around any app submitted to them within
three days maximum so this entire
process you can send in thousands of
apps three days that's a turnaround time
now again like I said Bardock to its
credit some of the guys behind us are
the same people using the you know who
were behind the bada project in the app
store bought it to its credit we have
never heard or seen any malware on it so
you know I'll give them the benefit of
the doubt maybe they can pull it off but
if the app ecosystem explodes you get
thousands of developers come here you
know I'm not sure of that three-day time
period will hold so against a little bit
more detail about what happens during
those three days the app is analyzed
this actually the opposite so the
dynamic analysis basically brings back
instrumentation of what were the URLs
being contacted you know they have a
reputation on them and they're using a
they're using an array of AV engines as
well so it they try to figure out if
there's any detection on this from any
standard equipment of anything ancient
and when it passes through both of these
things then it gets analysis done to
basically confirm that the permissions
that are being asked for by the app are
the bare minimum of what the app needs
so if it's a nap I don't know just that
doesn't require certain permissions they
will stop that app from being published
it will ask for an explanation from the
developer why do you need this
permission you don't need it for this
app and after that it gets on the Tizen
store so the revaluation occurs when the
app has been updated again that same
process continues from this point
onwards okay third party stores as I
said that there's there's two signatures
so we are Samsung has been a little bit
quiet about this but we are expecting
them to facilitate basically third party
stores it's in around the world so we do
believe there will be third party stores
but what we still don't know about is if
sideloading will be not allowed
sideloading right now is allowed on the
developer devices as well as on the
phones but we don't know what the final
release product will have right now
there's like a half a dozen places where
you can find people who were kind of
anxious to get their develop apps out
and distribute its Emma so you'll find a
lot of you know stuff on github a lot of
third-party sites where you can actually
download apps and and basically you know
investigate them so ties it under attack
now this is the part that I like about
the presentation the most so as I
mentioned this operating system is right
now out there on wearable devices on
cameras in vehicles as the other part of
forgot to mention Jaguar and Toyota
at both signed on and you know they it
makes sense if you think about it right
there a vehicle company they don't want
to be in the operating system business
they would rather leave it to somebody
who's got experience in this which is
you know makes perfect sense a
consumable electronic company to focus
on creating the the value as far as in
vehicle entertainment goes so there's
this was the first one durability that
was discussed in the Bluetooth con man
functionality after you turn the
bluetooth outfit wasn't there it didn't
turn off here's another one the camera
the NX 3000 it comes with the you know
caga reader and writer and by default
there's about several guys out there
who've been you know playing around with
it try to customize the OSI try and see
look for vulnerabilities so one there's
there's one gentleman out there what he
did was he basically found out that the
the tag the device was rewritable so the
functionality was you've got a camera
you basically any kind of Android device
you touch it against the camera and to
create a positive user experience if the
camera has an NFC reader you'll be able
to directly download the app from
Samsung to interact with the camera you
know so you don't have to worry about
setting up Wi-Fi setting out what's the
SSID setting of the Bluetooth connection
you don't have to worry about that but
what they were also realized was you can
actually change that to something else
so instead of going to Google Play you
can actually redirect that to any
package on google play that was that was
something very easily changed and there
was no signature verification or
anything I needed to be done to redirect
this thing so you know the other thing
is that the the tag supports permanent
right locking so if you decided to
create a custom OS and distribute it you
know like i said the RPM packages they
don't have to be signed and they're not
verified on a device so you can you can
be installing a malicious RPM package
with you know in the perception that
it's a clean contribution to the open
source community so so here's another
example somebody actually decided to
take one of the cameras and do a you
know
nmap scan and they actually found out
that the port is open sure if you can
see that they're 4x11 right there 6000
so you know what you can do was it was a
little minute what you can do you I mean
they they kind of did ended up sending a
couple of images to the device the other
thing was that you could also do a DDoS
attack and take out a camera but again
one of the things that you want to keep
an eye on so the other thing that was
you know something that one of a
gentleman who I worked with a couple of
years ago Candace actually found out was
that ties and devices can be routed they
you know this is so that if anybody's
looking for additional customization
example to watch you know they're not
happy with the the fact that in certain
regions like in Japan where it is
mandatory for mobile recording devices
to have an audible alarm you know you
can basically root the device and
basically disable the alarm which is
again kind of breaking a lot but
customizing it and there's roughly about
two currently available rude exploits
that can give you rude access on Tyson
person ok could you roll please
absolutely really there ok so the last
thing one of the things that is of
course a sign that the ecosystem is
under attack malware we've started to
see posts on sites and where we're
actively trying to chase down these guys
where they've actually call that spyware
claiming that it is available on Tizen
devices again the device has not been
released so what we suspect is they
probably attended a developer conference
or are probably using something off of
the emulator to get these abs so you
know we I don't believe I think it
wouldn't be too much of a stretch to say
that before the year is out we can
expect to see the first tizen malware
out there that's it
you