okay if we can take our seats we can't
continue sorry for a bit of the delay we
had to set up the next presenter not to
lose any time and we all want to have a
coffee break the next presentation is by
Mickey boom and neo 10 the broken our
chat kappa also in the just take
it away hi my name is Mickey and this is
Neil we're both doing botnet researching
for Annette today we are going to talk
about one of the most high-profile
banking children but net in the past few
years cat hall for today's agenda I'm
going to give a brief introduction of
wut kappa is then we'll be going to talk
about goals that kept her focus is on
and the aggressive approach to address
them i would also like to briefly
summarize the campaign of cat paw on how
he has evolved over time then i will
hand over to kneel to talk about how
capital works indeed these help focusing
on is to see to network infrastructure
communication protocol and encryption
server request plugins and configuration
file then i will conclude today's
discussion of capo with a few
observation and current state of this
part net we have collected our first cap
whole sample in late 2011 around
november kappa was commonly known as
because his early sample
contains quotes from Shakespeare's
Merchant of Venice as it's easier
capital was well known as men in boys
men in the browser attack which targets
bank websites cap hill has caught public
attention in early 2013 because of his
release of skype spreading mojo noting
that msn messenger and skype surface
merch around that time we have also
discovered that in the later version
kappa copy significant amount of code
from sue's saw sleek kappa had operate
for roughly three years and it has not
been seen on sale on the black market
there were no sauce leak of yourself
this suggests that Kappa was privately
owned and ran by the same poor people
who were actively developing them
so let's talk about three goals that
kappa attempts to address the first goal
is to get new victims the malware relies
on a network of infected websites to
perform drive-by downloads attack as its
initial infection Victor for directing
traffic Stu these sites one way to do it
is through messaging service such as msn
messenger or skype once it is resident
on a newly infected machine it will go
find a specific messaging application
and it will use it to send malicious
link to the victims contacts through the
chat function likewise cap hill can also
spread by hijacking Facebook account and
posting malicious link into France walls
they had also been seen using mal
fertilizing spamming and other Burnett
in distributing the catwalk client the
second goal of kempo is stealing banking
information banking has built sorry capo
has building code and plucking modules
to accomplish this mission such as
taking video of the desktop key locking
installing we NC server hooking up the
browser to upload the browser cookies or
make phishing sites locally available
through the infected browser the final
goal of Kappa is to maintain is control
on a spot net terminal while being
stealthy at the same time cap hull was
designed to protect itself from being
discovered or reversed by having cooked
to detect sandboxing and the debugging
environment it has also tried to impede
the process of reversing reverse
engineering by code obfuscation and
traffic encryption using all the samples
we have collected we has contract we
have constructed a timeline for cap host
build version number against sample
collection date the malware writer has
been actively updating his client for
roughly three years we have collected
our first batch of samples in November
2011 marked as version 1.0 all the
malicious drinks are reviewed once
unpacked
the custom pecker the original clients
also only has a master and slave
installation mode which we will be
discussing that later in june 2012 capo
had a lot of major updates in this 1.4
version kappa has added NT BM mechanism
by checking vm presence in system module
registry register key value or running
processes kappa has also added NT
debugging mccann sorry anti debuff
mechanism by making sure that the first
time the client is run is within two
hours after the client was built Kappa
had been rewritten to accommodate copied
code from Zeus the cote de copy from
Zeus in qu included antivirus processes
detection string encryption and API hash
encryption in February 2013 there was a
version 1.7 capo had added skype message
spreader module as a download it has
finally gained a lot of media's
attention because microsoft has
scheduled skype to replace msn measures
messenger at that period of time in
februari 2014 there was a minor
improvement in cap halt string
encryption algorithm this version had
token out the four zeros which
originally separated the key and
encrypted string this has made the
client smaller and at the same time
making it harder to crack the code using
four zeros as an anchor to apply the
Christian method that will review all
the malicious strings there are also a
few kind of update inclined code through
the whole timeline it is the XML tag in
the configuration file that can be
parsed by the clients we have observed
certain modules that comes with the tag
being introduced in the later version
whereas some other texts were obsolete
are available as a download plugin in
other versions now i'm going to hand
over to kneel to discuss the details of
capo clients
okay now the fun part kaho implemented
multi processes and multithreading
architecture in order to distribute the
workload and to run efficiently it tries
to inject yourself into multiple
processes including Firefox ie Explorer
svchost and so on depending on the
variance to interpret to
intercommunicating in between these
processes it creates an empire and named
pipes using names uniquely generated
from the user environment there are
three installation mode or injection
mold master slave and plug in this is a
typical control flow chart of the master
mode installation the mask process was
mainly responsible for the initial
contact with the c2 server and injecting
the slave process sending initial report
and to get the initial configuration
data once the configuration was
downloaded to local it passed it and
might inject more causes to start the
plugins the slaves and the planning
process also had ability to communicate
with the sea to server pass the
communication file and to load
corresponding options if this may sound
a little bit complex let's just think of
that all these processes will act like a
unity process with multithreading
function here it will help you to
understand the following concepts so how
do you both find its ce2 server to start
an initial contact this is usually I
like the most because for the botnet and
writer the most concern is to protect or
to hide the c2 server infrastructure
almost everybody has its own way of
finding an updating c2 server or proxy
server list so there are some examples I
call the first one is the hard way the
encrypt and hard coded the c2 server
list inside of client binary such as
Andromeda bot so the tongues I is quite
obvious because if the port loose
connection while the server changing the
domain name then the board does not get
the
update hands it's lost forever but
there's the upside of it it is not easy
to track the latest server list if you
don't have the latest spot client and
the next one I call it is a software
such as zebra croydex and Kraken Barnett
the client and the server are both using
the same domain name generating
algorithm with the same seat so that the
generated domain name is actually not
random but predictable by both parties
commonly they use current time in a
specific time zone for the seat
therefore even the server disappear or
lost communication with declined for a
period of time when it comes back home
he still knows the currently active
domain issue register and vice versa for
the choir the downside of doing this is
that once the domain name generating
algorithm is reverse engineered you can
just filter out all these possible
possible domain names in ISPO that
domain name server level to disrupt the
ball net what cabal used for the
see-through server communication
connection is a combination of the two
ways together with the cup with a
configuration updates here in the middle
here's a URL template for the client to
connect the initial domain name were
hard code it in the binary the Cayenne
binary encrypted and the sub domain was
going to be randomly generated generated
here's a the lower parts of ceuta co of
the get prefix the get sub domain name
function it the boat use this function
to generate a random sub domain name
note that the cow random here was going
to generate arbitrary numbers concerned
by the word the variable count the child
can max and use a random see as input
inside this function so the client would
keep trying the generated sub domain
until you could get dns response as you
can see in the Wireshark snapshot above
the boat ride a bunch of subdomains
until it hits the dns query
response so for now it looks like the
ball is shooting a shotgun blindly and
wasting time doing all these milliner's
effort here actually it's not here's a
communication protocol and the
encryption for communication protocol
the botnet use secure sockets layer and
on top of that the post message is
encrypted using our c4 algorithm with
key being the domain name it was
querying with the fixed student
appending to it and some of the very end
uses server IP with the prefix as the
rc4 key for decrypt the photo encryption
as you can see the prefix is always a
part of the cac-40 the idea is that it
was the c2 servers to decide which sub
domain he was going to use and only the
right client with which had the right
sub domain generated could be able to
start initial communication with the c2
server so if you for some reason no the
c2 server IP and try to connect without
knowing the prefix you cannot start a
communication and the message sending
back from the server to the client was
also encrypted using our c4 key with a
different key in the ID value generated
using cpuid instruction and hashing
function how did the server notice I be
this RC four key it is in the initial
request here's a list of parameters and
descriptions of the data are sending to
the server so you can see the there's a
key vendor which is the first one that
the lender key and the ID which is going
to be used by the server to encrypt the
message sending back to the client and
installation mode and also the net the
botnet name and the CMD and the double
here together indicates the message type
for example CMD equals to lock and W
equals to compare informants this
message contains a report of the
infected
house & Co LS means stolen flash cookie
files and eskew but a nap UT means
stolen Bitcoin wallets here are more
parameters the version here is what we
use to construct our timeline and here's
an example of a request beings sent from
a master master install installation
mode process inside a botnet named USA
and requesting for configuration file
and the board collected an extensive
user information from the local host
here's the list of the information
collected most of them could be used for
user profiling and victim selection and
there are some there are some
interesting ones at the list of
anti-malware products and whether it is
running in the sandbox environment if it
found any inside this report the server
might repay reply back your fake
complete configuration file instead so
as an analyst you might be played with
the fake downloading URL and got nothing
now I will handle the rest of the
present heading back to Mickey
as I mentioned in the earlier session
capo had employed a wide range of
strategies to achieve his goal of
sealing banking information a lot of
these functions were not presented in
the original catwalk back in 2011 they
were at the slowly later since kappa
uses named pipe to communicate between
infected processes on the compromised
machine plugins were able to install
using a newer configuration file and
still being able to still being
compatible to capo client that might not
be the latest one so here is a list of
plugins that we have seen being download
bike at all it had a browser cookies
little stiller which extract information
from the browser cookie database and use
the cap host building archive to
compressed it and uploaded the archival
also does the same kind of thing for
desktop screen shot videos there was
also a VNC server which makes remote
accessing the computer available ftp
grabber took the locking credentials
stolen in the infected machine from
certain application and upload it to the
sea to server at this spreader copies
the catwalk line to removable drive or
network shares there was a spambot
blocking that uses the infected machine
to distribute capital klein using
download this band template and there's
a back sock in which is a proxy server
plugin that used the infected machine as
a access point to bypass in Internet
filtering the last plug-in skype
spreader was the most interesting one
which make cap Hall stands out as a
banking children so the skype spreader
first checked for the existence of skype
application in the infected host then it
test for the conductivity to the skype
situ server the URL address of the sea
to server is provided by the cap hull
configuration file which will see be
seeing that in the later slides next up
it disabled the sound alert of the skype
application and send HTTP request to the
sea to server and retrieve a list of
options on how they want to skype spare
to be run let's say by using the weight
away option skype spreader will be
sleeping for and for a hard-coded amount
of time before it's a spamming its
contacts this sky spreader hoped the
skype window using skype control API
discover and skype control API attached
however this will trigger the T sub
communicator window to appear as you can
see here to quickly get rid of this
window the skype spreader will do some
calculation on where the allow access
button was located in this window and
send a left mouse down event to make it
go away with the authentication feature
of skype from out of the window skype
spreader proceed to retrieve the spam
template from the sea to server by
sending a at user HTTP requests then it
will use this information to spam all
the contacts in the infected skype user
like this the last step of skype
spreader was to clean up the Skype
history database of his spam messages
and send all done HTTP requests to the
sea to server I would also like to point
out that ng our bot was using a similar
technique to spread the malicious
software around the same time however
this version of skype spreader we are
seeing here farm of far more
sophisticated seen it since it used it
worked with cap hull configuration file
and it requires to connect to a c2
server the ngr bought skype spreader on
the contrary had everything hard-coded
in his spam time including its Pam
template in there skype module now we
are moving on to talk about cap whole
configuration file after cap hull client
is ran the first time on an on the
machine kapil can inject itself into an
existing process and install itself into
this process under different modes they
are restrictions on how the scattered
process on the pc with the
configuration father as it is indicated
in this table here in each infected pc
there are only one master which must not
be injected into the browser process
such as I Explorer AC or five Foxtrot
Exe the master process main
responsibility is to keep track of the
c2 server information such as URL
updates and capture of other cat hawk
infected processes in the PC the
infected process web slave installation
mode could only be the browser processes
though hence it focuses on parsing
information in the HTTP tagg that
contains information on how to do web
page injection on specific pages the
plug-in installation mode is used on all
the downloaded modules hence these
processes are allowed to parse all the
texts that are related to the extra
functionalities of this part here is
what a cap hull configuration file looks
like it contains the information about
the botnet c2 server the other part of
the configuration file will include
instruction to run the building modules
it also includes information regarding
plugins it's download location or
initial state after installation last
and the most important part of the
configuration file is the HTTP inject
tag the download HT beach HTTP inject
file is another XML format configuration
file encrypted using the same method now
we're going to discuss further about
this file this configuration file is
written to work with the hooked browser
such that it could manipulate
information in the browser based on an
event it's detected such as alert box or
URL visited based on these triggers the
hooks browser will use the configuration
files instruction to either inject
script into the page or replacing
certain string in the loader page which
I will be demonstrating the later slides
the URL visited or event can
so trigger other modules of capital to
assist in stealing user information such
as login to the URL visited grabbing the
forms initiating VNC session and so on
it is interesting to point out that when
the hooked browser detects a user is
visiting the business of domain of a
bank page the configuration file will
enable the back contact server because
the malware operator might think that
the user is accessing from a copper
environment and you will be easier to
send back useful information to the sea
to server if a proxy server has been set
up from the HTTP inject file we can see
that it was trying to replace bank help
line numbers such as credit card fraud
number to their own so that when the
victim tries to call and report
suspicious behavior in the account they
will end up calling calling an answering
machine another thing is that the HTTP
inject configuration file can also
duplicate in Portland input boxes and
hide original ones such that it can use
extra JavaScript to retrieve the users
input information and send it back to
the 2t server if all the key loggers or
from foam grabbers doesn't work on
certain bank websites there was also a
module which captures a PC desktop into
an avi video and upload it to the sea to
server we have made a summary of all the
banks being targeted by kappa from other
HTTP inject configuration file we have
collected there about 23 US based
financial institution 28 from Italy and
27 in UK and there are also mortgage
loan companies credit card services us
retirement saving services and treasury
management services there are also some
unlikely targets being discovered
through these HTTP injection
configuration file such as a library
website a job search surface
an Italian communication company the
configuration file will just instruct a
hoax browser to lock this URL visited
for the case of the job search surface
website the configuration file want to
lock the URL only if it contains the
search parameter which most likely will
be containing information regarding job
search we suspect that this information
could be used against the victim by
sending them better craft phishing
emails or using as use it as a filter to
data-mine victim who might be searching
for a higher paid job in the month of
May 2014 there were 12 see two servers
in the united states and the rest of
them are mostly located in european
countries based on our observation
capital requires two groups of people to
work on some time consuming task for the
botnet the one group will be the
developers who are responsible in
updated for updating configuration file
to compare online banking security
countermeasures or withdraw from
difficult targets building new client to
include the latest active c2 server
domain updating the client with original
code or copying rifle botnets code and
adding new features and plugins there
will be also a group of people who will
be busy data mining for bank and credit
card information filtering out Murphy
victims from special browsing history
monitoring VNC sessions or reviewing
screenshot videos finally I have a few
last word about what happened to cap
hall now a botnet tracker has suddenly
stopped all connections with C 2 servers
in June 2014 after three years of
operation multiple presses has reported
that capital or was taken down
by multi-agency joint effort in July
2014 seizure of c2 server lead to
discovery of Shiloh infrastructure I
guess cat is out of the back by then
last but not least no report of a rest
has been made so far thank you okay
thank you for the presentation we have
like a minute or two for questions are
there any questions the middle oh