okay so let's continue with our program
the last presentation before lunch and
Gregory panaqa will show you how to
abuse zip to deliver malware apps I
think isn't it yeah thank you I'm
Gregory panicle from case on computing
what I will be covering in this
presentation today he is the
exploitation of the zip file format that
forms the base for an Android
application we will be covering a few
handpick cases of Android
vulnerabilities that are caused due to
it zip file format handling oh sorry
about that so will then look at a novel
method to bypass deep inspection of
Android applications by antivirus
software by using specially crafted ap
case we will then see the chameleons if
that can be interpreted differently you
know depending on the application that
process said first a quick look at the
zip file format the zip file contains
automated data related to the files it
holds sorry to both those who already
know this the zip file contains a lot of
you know it condenses handle directly
header that is located at the end of the
file the details in the central
directory header contains information
such as the file names the compressor
and uncompressed data sizes the
compression method used to compress
these files as well as relative offset
from the start of the file were the
local file header for the corresponding
file could be located the archived data
for a particular file follows the local
file header that is located towards the
start of the file now an anarchic
application typically starts processing
a zip file by first look locating
central directory header that is located
towards the end of the file for that it
scans the last 64 kb of the file for
special magic values in order to locate
the end of the end of central directory
header and then it starts working
towards start of the file to locate be
archived data now moving on to the APK
file format the APK file format or the
android package follows a predefined
directory structure that enables the
you know android package manager to
cryptographically verify the whole
package it can it's essentially a Java
archive that contains a android specific
files one being the android manifest map
file which basically describes the
application as well as any permission it
requires the main dialogue executable
that is the classes or decks is
essentially an amalgamated file which is
which you know the all the classes that
are required required for execution are
all mashed up together the epic a will
also contain signing related files that
helps validate the whole package the APK
would contain in other information or
the resources that the epic the whole
land Royd package would require let us
see how the APK is handled by the
android OS for in verification and
installation the android OS on both
starts to services that are relevant to
us one being the install d or the
install Damon it's essentially a
component that's written in C C++ it it
listens on domains or kids waiting for
commands to install an APK to a specific
directory with appropriate permissions
then you have a component called package
manager service that it is a component
written in Java it gets loaded as part
of the system server process which is
also started on boot now this component
validates an EPK prior to issuing
commands to the install Damon to perform
the actual on dis installation the user
may interact with a component called
package manager which you know helps the
user to install an APK interactively
this component would communicate with
the background package manager service
whenever required now as you have seen
you have two components in android OS
that deals with the APK file format the
one that is a returning Java else with
the verification of validation of the
apk and you have the CC purpose
component that extracts and you know the
final comment that is loaded onto the
system it is as part of the installation
now the logic for these implementations
cannot only be different but we mutually
opposite at certain parts in the code
now this means that you have you know
because of the logic difference there is
an opportunity for the attackers to
bypass the cryptographic verification
process of the android OS allowing
progenies apks to be installed onto the
system as though it was verified clean
let's take a look at you know the few
prominent Warner abilities that I've you
know come across we have come across in
the last couple of years the first is
the master key vulnerability of course
the master key vulnerability arises due
to the discrepancy in the way the
android OS handles or the components
that handled the APK inside the android
OS handled the occurrence of multiple
files with the same name within the APK
archive now the java component when it
wants to ala date a particular entry
would pick the very last entry from you
know the multiple entries that you find
while the CC previous component would
extract the very first entry from the
APK now this you know entry would never
have been validated by the java layer
but it gets extracted and loaded onto
the system as though it was verified
clean now this gives an opportunity to
you know for the malicious attacker to
place it as the malicious entry to be
place as the first entry and this is the
one that he actually gets loaded on the
system now this vulnerability of x
android OS prior to jellybean the next
vulnerability is to do with how you know
both these implementation that is in
java and c process try to locate the
archive data now in order to locate the
archive data first is locates the
particular entry within the central
directory header and from there it finds
the offset for the local file header
what you see on screen is the local file
later it contains some variable length
fields one being the file name and the
other being the extra data field both
the lengths are specified within the
header it's both our 16-bit fields now
the vulnerability is to do with how the
Java layer and the sea pusses layer
treats this extra field length field the
Java layer incorrectly treated as a
signed integer
while the CC proposed component is
correctly as a you know unsigned integer
so if one place is a very large value
within this field this means that it
would get treated as a negative number
by the Java let whilst rated as a very
large positive number by the sea pasilla
for you know for example let us say we
place the value F F F D here and that
means when it tries to locate the
archived data the Java layer would treat
it as negative 3 and instead of moving
forward to locate you know the
corresponding archive data it actually
moves back three steps while the CC
prefers component when it wants to
extract the particular data would jump
forward by approximately 64 K so if one
locates a you know you know trusted APK
that has a classic text that's less than
64 kb in size you could exploit this
vulnerability so what you could do is
you could place the malicious classes
dot txt pass the benign entry and you
actually have to merge the first three
bites of the classes dot text with the
last three bites of the name of classes
dot X because in order to account for
the three bites that you are wrong you
know that you're you have to account for
that in that top so what you do is you
take the original trusted a week a
package it back with the stored method
so that no real compression algorithm
gets applied and you merge the three
bites that is part of the file name as
well as the first three bites of the
magic header of the classes dot txt who
so once this is done the what the Java
layer would see is the benign entry and
this is the one that gets validated and
the sea pusses layer would see this
particular the last entry of class or
text and that's the one that actually
gets loaded and the malicious clustered
ex would get loaded onto system the next
one Apple again is to do with how the
both the implementation attempt to
locate the archived data for example the
Java layer in order located you know the
archive data would pick the filename
length that is cached from the central
directory header while the local file
header I mean for the extra data like it
picks from the local file header
while the CC purpose implementation pics
both both the length from the send you
know the local file header itself so
this means that if you have two separate
values from the central directory header
and local file data for the file name
length you could have both
implementation see at two different
locations for the you know archive data
for the classic dot X so yet again with
the you know if you find a small you
know and trusted APK with a very small
class decks that's around let's say 64
kb in size you could place two separate
values in you know the for the file name
length field you can have the valid one
within the send Rec director header and
very dodgy are you specified within the
local file header so the format or the
layout of the crafted APK would be very
similar to the previous vulnerability
and the malicious APK is the one or the
malicious class next is the one actually
that gets finally extracted to disk now
the details for this are you know
slightly wrong in the paper I apologize
for the mistake so moving on now the
android OS to handle a particular APK
uses only two out of you know possible
65,000 fine and 36 compression methods
and one being the store method were it
actually puts the data inside the APK
without applying any compression
algorithm the other one the android OS
supports is the popular deflate
algorithm which has the value 8 so now
the android OS make some assumptions
when handling this compression method
fields for android OS you know kit kat
and above what it does is it checks if
the particular compression method that
specified within the APK archive is
stored it assumes if it is not stored it
assumes deflate while in earlier
versions of Android jelly bean and Kit
Kat sorry Ice Cream Sandwich you have a
reversal of check within the Java layer
who are it checks like the method if it
is deflate if not it assumes stored
while the CC plus an implementation has
remained same so this means that you
know they have actually tried to address
this and be consistent in the newer
version of the operating system however
the awesome
patients are still there that is the you
know what are the different
possibilities of compression method that
is there so this kind of gives an
opportunity for the militia a tracker to
abuse these assumptions and you know we
the security that may be in place now
let us see how an anti-virus software
typically handles a you know in a picket
what they're the put generally more
stricter checks when handling any
particular file format this is usually
done for performance and to handle any
form of you know format abuse while a
nun are coming application or in this
case the android OS has more you know
relaxed checks so if one place is a
value in the compression method field
other than stored or deflate there is
other than 08 it would still get get
treated as one of them by the android OS
because of the assumptions it makes but
the antivirus soft brick because it will
if it is an unsupported compression
method it would try to extract or it
would just skip over the file and move
on to the next file the supported method
it would attempt to extract whatever
data that is given based on the
algorithm that specified which would not
be compatible and it would break again
so in order to test the effects of this
manipulation of this compression method
field we picked up you know potentially
unwanted utility called droid chief it
is a symbol like a hacking utility it up
the reason one of the reason why we pick
that was we notice that most of the AVS
were detecting on closet decks with in
this package and even when you resign it
with the different sign up the detection
was still there so we created two
crafted apks to test the effects and
these are the results the first one is a
control test case to ensure that the AV
detection was maintained even if you
repackage with a different saina so as
you can see the fe detection was minted
and for android 4.3 and below and 4.4
and we had to create two separate
crafted apks because you have the
reversal of checks within the java layer
in the targeted OS where the
installation was successful the av's
failed to detect both during you know at
the time of installation when we had the
real
a competent running as well as when we
did an on-demand scan post insulation
and so was the case with you know the
new versions of the epic a targeting the
newer versions as so the non-targeted OS
because the it was not compatible with
the checks made by the operating system
the installation itself failed and so
that was the results now let's see how
this you know the these crafted apks was
prepared so for the original APK by
default the class adored x got
compressed so that means that the
deflate our algorithm kicks in so which
has evaluate this is the field that we
keep manipulating for the you know
creating the crafted application so for
the first crafted APK that is targeting
android 4.4 and above you what we do is
we change the compression method field
to a value other than 0 or eight so we
pick the next higher value that is from
0 1 which stands actually for a strong
method so we did the change in both in
the central directory header as well as
in the local file header to be
consistent and just with these changes
the APK still installed successfully in
the android OS while the av's which we
tested against which ad running in the
background failed to install our failed
to detect both during installation phase
as well as when we did on demand scan
for android OS prior to 4.3 and below it
was a bit more challenging each
construct and construct the APK because
you have the reversal of checks between
the sea purpose and the java components
so what we did was we laid out all the
files that needed to go into the APK
except for the signing related files and
the first step what we did was we pre
compress the classes decks using a
custom as you know custom return 0
utility it skipped writing the headers
in the compressed data so that it was
compatible with the unzip function that
was found in the c++ handling layer for
the zip within the android OS so we
replace the file within the directory
layer and so the you know as you can see
the file size came down
next step what we did was we in our cave
the whole directory using a standard
zipping utility let's say win draw we
stored we chose the store method so no
real you know compression algorithm
kicked it the files as such was stored
in the arcade and we renamed it to dot
apk and then ran it through through the
jaw saina process what the jaw saina
process does is it extracts each and
every files within the APK our cave and
calculates a sha-1 hash for it and it
places that in into manifest or mf5 and
signs it with whatever you know keys you
provide so now it is it is important to
keep in mind that the classics here is
actually pre-compressed and water shower
is calculated is for the pre compressed
data and not for the final classes decks
that actually would get loaded onto the
system the next step was changing the
headers the first step what we did again
was you know change the compression
method to value other and stored or
deflate again we picked you know one
standing for shrunk method then we
change the uncompressed size to reflect
the very original size of the class of
decks that was above 80 kb this was
because it was necessary because the sea
purpose component actually desk check
this you know the weather the file sizes
matches at the very last step after
during extraction so with just these
changes the APK installed successfully
on to the android OS so what happened
underneath is the Java layer when it
performs a validation would check the
compression method against being deflate
it sees its not so it assumes stored
method and starts calculating the sha-1
hash for we know the raw data and at
this point it calculates a shaman for
classes as well but it doesn't verify
whether the file format that is within
that a peek at that point is of dex
format so as long as the sha-1 hash is
checks out for the raw data the APK is
assumed valid and then then moving on to
when it goes to you know the CPU layer
for installation it has the reverse
check were checks the compression method
against being stored it ceases not so it
assumes deflate
which is correct and once it is able to
decompress the data and it combines the
file size and that two checks out and so
the package installed successfully on to
the android OS it again from as you can
as you have seen from the results the
av's which we are running in the
background failed to detect during you
know both the installation phase and
when we did an on-demand scan so as a
mitigation step even though we do not
consider this as a vulnerability of the
android OS we do believe that most
richter checks need to be placed as part
of you know the android OS code so that
they don't allow installation of such
crafted apks because it just lowers the
overall security of the android
ecosystem as far as you know the other
thing I want to just stress before the
next point is that we have to
implementation of see proces in and Java
that is handling the APK file format so
that always increases the risk of you
know you have difference in code or the
difference in logic which may bring up
you know similar cryptographic
verification process by past as well so
as for the antivirus vendors who are
potentially the most affected by crafted
apks we have a few suggestions oneness
to curiosity click flag any apk that as
an unsupported compression type because
it is a clear indicator of the apk
package being crafted the other
suggestion which we actually do not
recommend is to actually emulate the
behavior of the android OS in which you
are currently installed in it obviously
increases the queue and the development
effort so no recommendation for that as
moving out to the chameleon zip now the
zip file format has turned into a very
versatile convenient packaging format
for a variety of applications we have
already seen it you know as used as part
of android packages and obviously it's
you know being used for Tizen as well
and now the other formats it comes in
the package format which comes up is in
Java archives and you know you have it
in various document formats as you know
with docx and
Metro apps with our you know a PEC
extension as well so this this has
created new challenges for the AV
windows in order to recognize the
correct package type to do context level
passing just based on the continent you
know if you don't account for the
extension also if you have any
automation systems in the back end that
wants to evaluate behavior of a
particular file or a package based on
the you know the type of package it is
there is new challenges there as well so
what what a package type of analyzing
component typically does it looks for
specific files at specific locations in
order to recognize a particular package
type for JA you have the signing related
information under the meta-inf directory
and you have you know one or more class
files in the root for the APK you have
similar signing related information as
well as the android specific files such
as the android manifest and cross don
text for docx you have the content types
as well you know other files that are
related to the document for metro apps
that is epic extension it has its own
manifest file as well as you know were
the ones that holds the hashes for the
various files within the package no no
if you combine all the files that are in
all these various packages into a single
directory you know you could actually
create a single package that could be
treated as all these ones so as you can
see in the directory you can you have
the docx file jar file you know all with
various types together we are given the
you know this amalgamated package the
sobriquet chameleons if so what we did
we just package everything in using a
standard archiving utility and we tested
it out against the various are entering
utilities so what we observed was a
valid APK is also valid jar file because
both of them follow the same underlying
you know verification process so as long
as the hash is for the files which it
doesn't know about like and java archive
wouldn't know about the android manifest
file but as long as the hashes were
present in the manifest at MF it does
not matter
just regular data foil for the you know
for the respective applications so it
installed successfully in the android OS
and the when we invented to dodge jar it
loaded successfully in the Java
environment as for the docx file when we
rename the package is doc Ock's and try
to open in Microsoft Word it throw an
error that the package was corrupted
what we you know notice was even the
presence of a unaccounted file within
the doc Ock's package was enough to
throw off you know the microsoft words
you know like the integrity check for
for the doc expel phase however when we
try to open it with in OpenOffice it
open successfully display the content
and without any you know visible errors
or warnings as for Metro apps it has a
similar requirement that it should also
be validated prior to being installed so
this means that creating a valid apk and
a valid epic simultaneous having as a
package which is both valid may not be
feasible because it requires updating
two separate files with these you know
hashes for all the files within the
package so changing one file which holds
the hashes would affect the other so it
may not be feasible to create both both
valid packages at the same time however
the presence of the files that awful
it's a in apex with the package might be
enough to throw off a package type
analyzing component for concluding so as
you I mean zip file always has been very
flexible format and so it has always
been abused a antivirus vendors are all
too familiar with you know gateway
bypass using crafted archive file
formats so we can we expect the trend to
continue as far as the crafted AP case
is concerned we had tested out with you
know few antivirus products we found
that both their Android versions or
Android products and the windows engines
were equally affected we had reported
this issue to the you know the vendors
whom we checked against some of them
responded acknowledged and promised to
fix the issue by the way we had case and
I rolled out the fix as well
those vendors who haven't responded we
hope that they take it up and address it
from their side there's some effort
going on on the I through bill tagging
friend to validate the top top level apk
and not just the contents inside so it
is being actively discussed and we are
looking forward to that as well as for
the chameleons if we were unable to test
the effects of the package on the
automation system we live it up to the
vendors to evaluate the internal systems
to see you know how it treats these
packages with that I is if myself to
thank you any question okay