okay well good evening everyone I know
everyone is a little tired we have a big
lunch today we have a lot of technical
presentations right now I'm going to
discuss about Bitcoin it's a topic I'm
very passionate about and not only about
Bitcoin but Bitcoin in Latin America and
how it relates to malware so it's a
correlation of everything I don't only
try to analyze samples or show you
technical details or show you why
bitcoin is good or not bow but how
everything fits in the picture together
so when I chose the title for my
presentation I thought about anchorman
will first movie about how everything is
about being so fast and escalating so
quickly so if you haven't seen this
movie see it it's very funny ok let's
start with the presentation well in the
beginning we had Bitcoin here in the in
this part of the graph we see the
different coins that we have at the
moment and as you can see bitcoin is the
top cryptocurrency right now we have
light going we have dark coin we have
dogecoin we have a letter a lot of
cryptocurrencies but Bitcoin being the
first in the market and I discuss these
about in the paper about some economic
principles behind this the first mover
advantage or the network effect it's
very popular nowadays and as I was being
briefed just before the presentation
Bible is now accepting bitcoins the
value is changing a lot these days as I
will talk later but there are some
pretty cool things about Bitcoin and not
only this Intel ization privacy or the
speed at we can do transactions this
also this we can buy the weirdest thing
with Bitcoin I mean I was just looking
at the site where you can buy alpaca
socks with Bitcoin you can buy sweaters
you can
a lot of things that nobody really cares
about but you can do it only with
Bitcoin so what with that but the
community is really strong and they feel
like it's something that creates bonding
so they do these kind of things or slag
to sell so we also can mind the currency
so we can exchange Shore processing
power for money and I consider this an
alchemist stream I mean translating
processing power for money you're
translating reality your electric bill
for money in the past this was effective
this was profitable right now mining the
currency is not very profitable at least
at an amateur level you can do it if you
have an aiesec equipment on a fpga or or
a mining firm then it can become
profitable but nowadays it's not so much
then this is what I want to highlight in
this presentation the Bitcoin it's an
alternative especially in Latin America
where we have strict financial controls
where we have the local currencies that
are being in effect or are affected by
division or evolutionary processes the
inflation that we have so bitcoin is
seen by citizens as an alternative they
are looking for a way to escape the peso
to escape whatever currency they have in
order to have the learnings saved
somewhere else they want to escape the
government and bitcoin is offering this
whether we like it or not what else well
when it comes to security I call this
byob being your own Bank which is not so
easy uses are adopting Bitcoin but at
the same time they are becoming the
wrong banks they have to secure the
bitcoins they need to be aware of the
risks they need to have a valid then it
encrypted and if they are using an
exchange house we know many of the
incidents that happen not only mon gods
but others so it's not so easy being
your own bank
I will talk about this in a future
flight but okay what's not so cool about
bacon well this is a dogecoin sweater
but I wouldn't consider it cool you can
buy this kind of things with the
cryptocurrency what else it's a
nightmare for text agencies and
governments why is that because they
can't control it and they are very
afraid of this because tax agencies
depend on the honesty of the users with
descriptive currencies and as we know
this is not something feasible
governments aren't so keen about it
either in Argentina we are having an
Team honoree money laundering units
being interested in Bitcoin because they
want to learn how the citizens are
buying this cryptocurrency in order to
escape the tax agencies and the
government because it is happening this
is not a prediction it's happening right
now illegal markets they have come and
gone we know about Silk Road ship market
and Bitcoin in conjunction with the tour
PGP and a lot of nice tools that we use
every day it's being adopted by
cybercriminals and illegal markets in
order to sell this kind of goods online
then we have fraudsters and scammers
that are changing their fishing
campaigns in order 12 just a word
Bitcoin inside it we have seen the
Nigerian scam just adding the word
Bitcoin and you can see what this is
still working I mean it's unbelievable
the body of a liability this is
something not cool at the beginning of
the year we were around eight hundred
dollars per bitcoin this week I'm today
we are at 422 the values extreme or
highly volatile but nevertheless in
Latin America volatility is not an issue
for example when i did this presentation
the Pacer wasn't us around eight days
for one dollar today I got a message
from a friend that told me that I was
going to be like in the terminal
with Tom Hanks when you come back that
isn't going to be an Argentine today the
peso was there were 16 pesos for one
dollar so bowl ability is something were
used to in Latin America and then as in
the previous slide storing your own
money is not easy users especially in
emerging markets are learning about
Bitcoin but also about security and this
goes hand in hand but they can deal with
everything at once and cyber criminals
know this and know that they are buying
bitcoins but they don't know how to
secure them ok we have the market
capitalization until we reach the 21
million units that are dean for bitcoin
in the year 2140 is still a while we
don't know what the volume will be at
that time but we know that the market
capitalization keeps on growing and
cyber criminals are following these
trends and not only with Bitcoin they
are following with our cryptocurrencies
for example dogecoin litecoin or dark
coin and why is this I will talk about
it in the next slide but the reality is
that not only Bitcoin means money for
the cybercriminals all the currencies
can be translated to dollars or to other
cryptocurrencies so they are very eager
to follow this kind of market
capitalization graphics and daily values
worthless money there is crime and they
know this and we have seen this we have
evidence about this about the samples
that we are seeing in our lives every
day that they are changing Bitcoin for
dogecoin one day they are mining in a
mobile device the earth day they are
mining in DVR and the other day they are
creating a wallet stealer so they are
changing their approach based on the
value this is not random and this is
what I mean that when I talk about that
everything is related the economy the
psychological part and the malware
everything is related so difficulty
every and number of bloods
bitcoin the difficulty increases so when
mining becomes unprofitable and cyber
criminals resort to other currencies I
mean we have seen as I spoke previously
about mining malware but while it's
stealing right now is becoming the trend
of the norm when it comes to cyber crime
related to VidCon so why is this because
the difficulty with bitcoin is so hard
right now that even with a high gaming
computer you will still wouldn't make a
dime you will have to pay more for your
electrical bill ok rickrolling the block
chain i added this life because i
thought it was interesting how on how
bitcoin changes our lives so please read
this tweet with me yeah rickrolling and
you can find inside the blockchain the
entire lyrics for the Rick Astley song
now we're going to give you up yeah the
entire song in the blog shine but not
only that you can find the stone papyrus
in the blockchain this was detected this
year and a lot of miners complain that
they couldn't use Bitcoin because this
was being detected so no blockchain no
mining we have Nelson Mandela pictures
and quotes we also have WikiLeaks cables
and spy files everything in there there
are even services like cryptography tea
or cryptos crypto secret which are used
between couples to sing like lovers
messages and things like that this is
now becoming automated adding garbage
inside the block chain but one question
I want to ask with you we have already
received reports about people including
child pornography inside the blockchain
what about when you don't load
everything into your computer what do we
stand on these legally
and this is something we need to keep
researching because I find extremely
interesting that everyone is downloading
the blockchain without knowing all the
garbage that they are getting too okay
yeah I know the only guy that could
would roll font from My gods his name
Chuck Norris the rest of them couldn't
withdraw a single cent yeah so we have
many attacks and vulnerabilities that
can be done with Bitcoin Mont God's
blame transaction malleability bug
because of bad implementation on their
software but we also have as I mentioned
previously illegal content in the
blockchain we have the 51-percent attack
when for example mining pools have
enough clients that they can overrun the
network they can choose if to accept or
not a transaction so this is a possible
attack add up though it needs a lot of
processing power then we have denial of
service so for probabilities and of
course malware yeah mont gods this is an
interesting case the first incident that
they reported was her work hong kong IP
accessing one of their sites account and
sterling the selling of a lot of
bitcoins causing a price drop that was
really devastating for the currency
because everyone lost the confidence in
Bitcoin at that time then we saw in
February this year that they blamed as I
mentioned previously transaction
malleability for their demise in reality
and if you read other papers and
research about the topics this is highly
unlikely the realities that we don't
know what happened with mongols but at
the time they were handling around seven
percent of all the bitcoins in existence
and their closure left a half a billion
use USD american dollars stolen so
that's a lot of money and there was only
one of the exchange
is that suffer this type of incidents we
have other exchange houses most of them
suffering these type of attacks I mean
attacks worthy we don't know what
happened or just suffering playing
social engineering attacks for example
there was canadian bitcoins where a guy
just called the data center and told
them hey I need I need you to restart
the server in safe mode and they did and
they stole the bitcoins because they
were able to bypass all security
measures so this is the kind of security
that exchanges had I mean and we go we
used to consider them as banks banks
have insurance Bank have security
policies exchange houses didn't right
now we are seeing a paradigm shift
hopefully for the better but there are
also other things in the Bitcoin
scenario for example we have Ponzi
schemes like a bit conceiving suntrust
which was being managed by a guy called
pirate at 40 before being called that
way he was called the pirate savings and
trust and it promised sever point seven
percent return weekly on your investment
of course this was a Ponzi scheme and if
you were the last to join I'm sorry you
lost your money then the malware I want
to talk about this because of the
relation between the pricing Bitcoin and
the type of malware that we see so if we
were to put the same graphic of the
Bitcoin value on top of these you would
see it correlates when the value of
Bitcoin decreases you would see that the
malware samples start focusing elsewhere
you would see them focusing on dogecoin
or casino coin on other currencies that
are becoming more adopted by the
audience in the same way that difficulty
increases they are also resorting to
cryptocurrencies this was a pretty
simple marwar that we'd seen as
mont goats closed this was just a leak
that was filter andhra online and it was
a client that was supposedly to access
the mongols details that were being
leaked and in reality it was a wallet
stealer and credential stealer and away
why do i say this is very simple because
it was sending the credentials just by
using base fifth 64 encoding and
nevertheless this still work and this is
something that amazes me nowadays we are
seeing these type of things still
working and wow again we've seen when
there is a data breach we see that
someone in based in both these posts
about okay give me your bitcoins i will
sell you the database dump in many cases
this is a scam we've seen also facing
phishing messages even after Mongols
closed they will keep on fishing on the
sides so they were telling the users
okay i know the side died but I need
your credentials to close it definitely
why is that because many users you reuse
their credentials so cyber criminals
nudists and they still like kick that
dog they will still keep on beating the
same thing then other types of simple
scams like okay USA is going to burn a
shot Bitcoin okay click here click here
and get infected for free yeah what
about some interesting stuff okay we
have seen Internet of Things devices
which is a trending world I don't like
it but we have seen for example DPR
equipments or network attached storage
and devices getting infected with with
minors I mean if you know the capacity
of the order processing power that these
devices have this makes no sense at all
I mean when we calculated the hashing
power of this
you would get like two cents every other
three months of something like that it
would pay more for your electric bill of
course if you are the cybercriminal you
don't care about this but still is it
worth to do a mining malware for a DVR I
know then you will have chrome
extensions that would steal your wallet
then yeah mobile applications that would
offer you wallpaper interesting
wallpaper run away and they would check
for your battery level they would check
if the phone was plugged in or not and
would still start mining the currency
Bitcoin in this case then we have other
examples targeting dogecoin and casino
going this was much sad the much said
malware that also was used as a mobile
minor I don't know still affecting the
users but in reality the profits that
you would get with this type of miners
are pretty slim okay and what happens
when the cyber criminals get your heart
and bitcoins okay they are gone and they
are gone forever we've seen in reddit
some people moonlighting as private
investigators they are trying to follow
the money you know you have the
blockchain is public you can follow the
blog China you can see where the money
has been moving and you can say oh look
this guy has my money and they started
daxing people they started releasing
personal information but reddit told
them okay you need to stop this this is
a witch hunt you're releasing personal
information on people that have nothing
to do with this incident your money is
gone accept it and that's it okay as I
mentioned previously when I studied this
presentation or this research we have 10
pesos firm for one dollar the dollar
messy we call it in Argentina 10 for one
right now we are 16 for one so what I
want to highlight is how in Argentina
teyla and other places in latin america
we are seeing a desperate need for other
currencies and people are learning about
Bitcoin because they are forced to they
want to escape the local currency and
I've seen like little papers on the
train station where it says shine the
revolution buy bitcoins you say in
Argentina yeah so we have a very large
market for illegal dollars you know
Argentina has a history with this but
people are resorting to VidCon and other
cryptocurrencies we have foundation
there that holds weekly meetings the
anti-money laundering unit is taking
part of this so this is something that
is happening and this is what I want you
to take out of this that Latin America
is specific or has some characteristics
difference from the rest of the world
all Latin America is different and we
have this type of things happening right
now and if people are resorting to
VidCon cyber criminals are resorting to
beat going to they are following the
money so we know that argentineans and
Latin Americans are using bit going
another cryptocurrencies we need to
follow it closely some people learn
falsely as I mentioned previously mostly
because of around somewhere infection we
have seen cryptolocker then bit crypt
for example included a waltz dealer then
we have the rabbit on run some more
family that included mobile a minor so
cyber criminals are keen or are kind
with us because we don't have dollars so
some of the time they offer discount
rates because they know we can't buy the
dollars so this is interesting but still
I've seen a lot of friends that ask me
what is a Bitcoin and where do i buy one
I have my files encrypted and I don't
know what to do and this is our reality
and people who are learning because of
these
okay so what do I hope for the future or
where are we standing right now we are
seeing that my name botnets are
something that it's not so hot right now
we are shifting to wallet stealing
because people don't trust these change
houses and with a good reason I mean
some of them likes apple in Argentina
that is launching right now offers kind
of uninsurance like a bank but others
are still like a she's behind so people
are served saving their bitcoins in the
wrong home maybe in a USB behind the
mattress or a sofa so this means that
cybercriminals habit really easy and
it's a responsibility for all of us to
provide protection to this type of
malware scams fishing to provide
education and to let them know what the
threats are of using cryptocurrencies as
I mentioned in the first slide of course
you have many cool things about Bitcoin
but there are also risks and we are not
in Kansas anymore this is going
escalating pretty quickly so we need to
be aware and we need to educate thank