all right welcome back everybody time to
find a seat where we're joined now by
Matt Swan now if you're to give Matt a
nickname some people might say like the
cold stone killer or something like that
but I've heard other people call them
the InfoSec mr. Roger is he's like the
nicest guy you'll ever meet but an
incredible role model he's also a great
example of somebody who just gets stuff
done
you know he's rolled out with with his
team rolled out a bunch of incredible
things and oath 365 and sharepoint
online and we're gonna hear about it
today let's give him a hand
welcome to thankfully so my name is Matt
my team's responsible for securing
customer data in SharePoint Online and
office 365 and as we've worked on this
problem for the last five years we've
discovered that we actually we have a we
have a challenge one of which is that
our clickers sometimes don't work but as
our service has grown the scale of our
service has outpaced our ability to do
Incident Response because when we look
at our service the way that we used to
do things no longer works right I used
to run a script across thousands or tens
of thousands of machines to gather data
or make a change I used to run a cosmos
query or an hdinsight query to evaluate
my event logs and track an adversary the
same day that I found him but now I've
got two hundred thousand-plus machines
spread across multiple domains with no
trust between them or sometimes in a
domain 'less environment we're running a
script and assuming that I have implicit
service account trust across all those
machines no longer holds true HD insight
and cosmos has failed me because I have
15 terabytes of event logs every day and
I can't query those rapidly enough to
keep track of my adversary so my team
has been forced to build five
superpowers that has allows that allowed
us to scale our Incident Response
capabilities as our cloud has scaled too
and so I want to share those with you
today so the first one is inventory and
no-nothing makes your heart beat faster
than asset inventory right when I think
of this I think about like a barcode and
I'm putting labels on all my physical
Hardware keeping track of who has it and
where it has gone but I want to
challenge you to think about this in a
different way really the question that
we're trying to answer here is how
confident you are about the security
health of your fleet imagine wanna cry
right all of a sudden it was very
important to all of us to know whether
SMB v1 was enabled or not we all quickly
went to Stack Overflow found the
registry key that told us whether that
was on or not and then tried to figure
out well how do I run that query across
all of my fleet all of my tests in four
instances all of my cloud all my dev
workstations suddenly inventory became
incredibly important so we looked at
this after the fact and we said you know
one of the things that is challenging to
us as you know we we're not even sure we
know how many machines we have but we
also don't know this state of all of
those machines so we built a little
agent we distributed it across the
machines and we said you know I'm going
to give these agents questions to answer
I'm gonna give them WMI queries I'm
going to give them registry paths and
every hour I want each agent to wake up
on a random interval pull down those
list of queries answer them locally and
push them back up to a document DB in
Azure cloud and this empowers a couple
of things one it means that in that
wanna cry scenario my engineers can add
a query wait an hour go back do a query
and find every machine that is or is not
compliant with a standard - this allows
us to build historical models and track
the state of our fleet over time so for
instance if I were to take a snapshot of
this state every hour put it into a
database query that and say show me
machines that have been persistently
unhealthy for the last 48 hours in my
environment I constantly have VM
spinning up and being torn down so at a
slice and time I don't necessarily know
whether that machine is unhealthy
because it's been on the network for too
long and things have started to rot or
whether it's a brand new Lea deployed VM
and it just hasn't finished being
provisioned yet
so I need to be able to look
historically over time to determine
whether something should be cleaned up
or not but the real power here when you
have inventory and when you have state
is the ability to auto heal and so we've
built an auto healing workflow that runs
four times a day
queries our system looking for machines
that are unhealthy and then tickets them
for remediation not to humans but to an
automated system so the if they're a VM
they get torn down paved spun back up if
it's a physical machine all the VMS that
it hosts are evacuated and that machine
is imaged and so this helps us make sure
that our mission our environment is
evergreen that's always healthy and as
we add new health metrics
those accrue to our auto harvesting
system here as well now as someone
astutely pointed out in the OS query
presentation this morning the challenge
with agents is how do you know when the
agent isn't installed how do you know
when the agent isn't healthy so we had
that problem too and what we did is we
taught our agents to scan each other on
the network so we took advantage of a
fact that we knew about our environment
and we said for each agent for each ipv4
address that it's listening on I want
you to scan everyone else in that slash
24 subnet and I want you to do that once
a day at a random time during the day so
if this subnet is fully saturated with
agents we're going to get about 10 scans
an hour and the scans gonna do something
really simple
each inventory agent listens on a port
the scanners try to connect to that port
if it's present it says great the
inventory agent is running on this
machine and the inventory agent when it
responded gave me back the machine name
in the domain so I can build a list an
inventory of everything local to me on
my same subnet if the inventory agent
did not respond I'm going to try three
three eight nine RDP I'm gonna try it
SMB because I want to know whether this
is a Windows machine that's alive on the
network but not running my inventory
agent and so what I get back is every
about 10 times an hour and at least once
a day if there's one machine on the
subnet running my agent a list of every
IP address in my
cool subnet with the machines that are
running the inventory agent and their
names and domains and the machines that
are not the machines that are online but
unhealthy and so I can ticket those for
remediation too as we built this
capability we also realized you know
that list of machines and list of
subnets that are associated with them
the domains that are associated with
them is also giving me all of the
information that I need to configure my
Windows Firewall because now I know for
each slash 24/7 net which domains it
hosts and so I can say hey inventory
system tell me all the subnets that are
associated with the domain that I am so
that I can trust them and so we can push
that information back down and build an
auto configuring firewall without having
to have a master asset inventory list
that is hand curated as things join or
leave the domain so the next superpower
we had to build was forensics and again
the challenge here was trying to scale
to the size of our environment so will
we get an alert we don't want to go out
and to one machine or a hundred machines
or a thousand machines and try to gather
enough context to know whether this
alert is a true positive or a false
positive so we really like agents in
office 365 so we already had a security
agent that's running listening to etw
uploading security events to our cloud
and the first thing we did is we
realized you know I want to know ahead
of time what the auto start entry points
are that are configured on this machine
I want to know all the local groups
local users local group membership I
want to know which certificates are
installed on this machine so each agent
every day is gonna snapshot those and
upload those to our Big Data system so
that when I have an alert I can go back
look at the state of the machine and
build some context so that worked pretty
well and in fact that actually drove
detections because once we had a list of
auto start and few points from each
machine in a system like cosmos or HD
insight it's the most obvious thing in
the world to compare those machines one
with another and even though I don't
have a spec that says what registry keys
are supposed to be set I know that a
deviation in a security interesting
registry key might be an indication of
compromised
but not all information is small enough
for us to feel comfortable just
uploading it constantly so the next
thing we did is we taught our agent that
when it uploads an alert a real-time
alert to one of my engineers that it
should also upload forensic results at
the same time so when I get a real-time
alert I want to get a list of everyone
who's logged into the machine all the
processes that are running maybe the
list of dll's that are loaded into each
one of those processes we call this
x-ray we want to get like a bill of
health for that machine that I can use
to evaluate that alert in real time at
the time it's received so I'm speeding
up some of the operations that my
engineer would otherwise have to do
similarly if we get an alert for a
process perhaps we want to take a
process memory dump and we want to
upload the executable associated with
that process
well my engineers are then going to have
to use a tool like pe studio or Watson
or windbg or strings to try to do some
initial malware triage on that instead
of my engineers running tools why don't
I do that in the cloud why not take
every executable that I decide is
interesting send it through and as your
workflow that runs PE studio and gives
me a list of initial malware triage
entities so now instead of my engineers
spending time triaging each individual
alert and digging into the ones that are
interesting or perhaps not even doing
that level of research or involvement
because it's time consuming that
information is staring them in the face
in the same place but they're already
triaging alerts
okay so we're triaging alerts and we
found one that's a true positive I have
two hundred thousand machines it seems
like the odds are pitched against me
because my adversary can choose to hide
anywhere in that fleet and I'm the one
that has to track him down and I've
started to solve a couple of problems or
at least know that my agent is running
and healthy on every machine so there's
fewer opportunities for him to hide but
I still have the proverbial needle in a
haystack so back to our fleet back to
our security agents the first thing that
we did here is we built an IOC store and
when I CI OCS I don't mean hashes an IP
address
than we get from a threat intelligence
feed I don't mean some subscription that
we sign up for that we automatically
import and push out to the agents these
are I OCS that are gathered during real
incident response so for example if the
red team is in my environment I get an
alert I investigate and I discover that
that red team malware is calling out to
an IP address I'm going to put that IP
and that hostname in my IOC store every
agent is going to sync that down every
15 minutes and the next time Network
activity or process activity occurs on
that machine and matches that IOC I'm
going to get a real-time alert and
what's beautiful about this is that I'm
not gonna get an alert just from the one
machine that tipped me off I'm going to
see every machine as it happens so if my
adversary moves from one machine to
another that will trip a new IP address
alert or a new IOC alert and so now as
my adversary moves laterally I can see
him at the same tempo that he's moving
now not all evidence can be gathered
event by event for instance let's say I
took that malware and I looked inside
and I found that there were strings or a
sequence of bytes that were unique to
this malware I want to know where else
that is inside my fleet so what we did
is we taught our agent how to run jobs
the jobs like a Yara scan Yara is a
pattern matching language that can be
used to look for hashes or sequences of
bytes in a file or in memory and so we
run a Yara scan across the fleet by
defining the signature that we're
looking for we handcrafted this it's
bespoke hipster Yara rules that we
crafted from our malware we put it in
the cloud and we distribute that
question to all of our agents bit by bit
because we know that you are scanning
could be expensive we're running a cloud
service our engineers or our customers
need to continue being able to get their
job done and so we distribute that
across the fleet and if we find a match
that alert gets sent to our engineers
now we tried this in a red team
engagement last December and what we
found was that there's a virtuous cycle
between this IOC system and this alert
system or a job system so we started
with an IP address that we knew was bad
based on an alert that we received when
we put that in the cloud
started to get alerts from other
machines that were accessing that same
IP so we used our forensic capability
pulled process memory dumps investigated
those and wrote yarra rules to bet
pattern match that malware we ran a job
to scan all the other processes across
our entire fleet looking for that
malware found more processes and what's
funny was that those there were disjoint
sets the set of machines that were
contacting an IP address that we knew is
bad and the set of machines containing
malware that was associated with our red
team or with our adversary so when we
investigate those other machines we find
other IP addresses because our red team
knows that they need to have
heterogeneous or redundant command and
control infrastructure and now I take
those IPs I put them back in the cloud I
wait 15 minutes
I have alerts from new machines so this
forms a virtuous cycle where I'm able to
quickly scan my environment and uncover
my adversaries tracks but just like I
need to be able to track my adversary
now I need to be able to respond and
this is really where the rubber meets
the road so I have TTP's I have IPs
domains processes machines that need to
be paved now I need to respond so the
first thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
use those same capabilities I'm gonna
use my IOC store and my job repository
as part of a coordinated eviction
activity I'm going to use my job
repository to run we call an inoculation
job on every machine so if there's an IP
that we know is bad we're gonna add a
static route for it on every machine if
there's a hostname that we know is bad
we're gonna sinkhole it by agra adding
an entry to the hosts file if there's a
process name that is bad we're gonna add
an image file execution options registry
key so that it can no longer execute
similarly we're gonna use our IOC store
we're gonna add I oh C's for all of
things these what we're gonna flip on an
option so that when the IOC matches not
only do we get an alert but that thread
gets suspended or that process gets
terminated so now we're in active
response mode right we're doing this
again as a coordinated response not
onesie twosie as we happen
to learn things about the environment
because we don't want to tip our hand
early but when we're ready to evict we
need it to happen all at once fleet-wide
and when we did this in December we were
overwhelmed with data data from machines
that had started to call back data from
machines that we were doing a vixen on
data from machines that we were doing
forensics on we're pulling process
memory images we're running strings on
them all of that output needs to go into
a st. a single place so we learned how
to put that all in Cousteau Cousteau is
a lot like elasticsearch for folks
outside of Microsoft and Cousteau has
this really nice property or I can query
across multiple tables so I can say give
me everything that is true about a given
process or a machine or username but
then we had another challenge because
our tools didn't know how to speak the
same language okay you know in one
instance I might upload data about a
machine name and I might put the mission
the fully qualified name of the machine
in one column but another tool might
upload the machine name and the machine
domain and two separate columns and so
we had to go through a process of
normalization right so define what is
our schema what are we going to call
these column names are they uppercase
are they lowercase do machine names end
with a period or not we did the same
thing for processes we did the same
things for users and then if you see on
the right you know we have some IP
addresses as well in one case we call it
an entity in another case it was an IOC
match so we know it's an IP so let's
pull those out - let's call those IP
addresses the value of doing this is
twofold one it makes it easy for your
engineers to query across this and
imagine now when you want to find out
your list of assets that need to be
remediated you are a query away right
select star from machine names across
all of the tables that contain my
forensic data that's the list of
machines that I need to hand off to get
remediated or to get paved this also
lets you build intelligent experiences
on top of your data when your data
didn't share a common schema you
couldn't join it together you couldn't
do linked data analysis you couldn't
build a graph but if you're using the
same schema now you can connect together
everything relating to a given user
every
thing relating to a given IP address and
this allows you to go beyond just data
in a table that you're making use of for
forensics but actually building
intelligent experiences so that your
engineers can start doing guided hunting
and exploring your data all the way down
to the raw data as well as incorporating
their forensic results as they explore
so in office 365 in order for us to
deliver on our accountability to make
this the safest cloud we've had to
defend our data with new capabilities
that have scaled to the amount of
machines to the size of our fleet and we
know that if we don't do this it's not
just we who lose
it's our customers who lose and so what
I gave you today is five patterns that
we've proven out that we found to be
effective if you had the opportunity to
see Nix talk this morning he did a
spectacular job of walking through how
os query incorporates these same
patterns how they use them at Facebook
and how anyone can use them it's their
open source and they can be contributed
to if you're here inside of Microsoft
and you like to learn how we're doing
this inside of Office 365
I'd love to chat with you we have a
micro service an agent-based deployment
that has worked really well for us or if
you have your own technology whether
that's Azure security center or OMS and
you'd like to incorporate that as well
we'd love to chat thank you
great job Matt this is a great example
of kind of the difference between basics
and fundamentals where fundamentals are
the things that everybody would like to
have but there's obviously a vast range
of skill so we've got some time for
questions how does anybody have some
questions from at we've got mic runners
at at both sides got a question right
there
so it was very impressed let me just
start off with a little bit of
compliments so it looks like you've
scaled very well how do you work with
teens for instance customer and certain
response teams that haven't scaled as
well that are still operating at a
slower pace good question
so I'll be honest we don't do a lot of
customer incident response the strategy
there is to leverage tools like tools
like Microsoft cloud app security where
they've learned how to present
interfaces that scale for customers so
the analogous version of this for a
customer of office 365 would be to
import all of the audit events coming
out of office 365 out of SharePoint out
of exchange putting those audit events
in a common schema like cloud app
security gives you and then being able
to reason over that schema to say you
know when I see an alert by a user on a
resource what else has happened on that
user what else has happened on that
resource and be able to encode that as
as rules that you can apply and then be
able to configure workflows that take
action so that rather than an individual
sock analyst having to go through those
rules or those policy violations
line-by-line
you're automatically taking remediation
actions so that you can keep up with the
scale of your organization rather than
you know burning down a sock you as as
folks talked earlier about and also this
is a great plug for the next session
Greg Faust will be talking shortly about
doing log analysis and investigation of
office 365 online we've got time for one
more question is anybody have one got
one back there mentioned static routing
black Halling IPS that's pretty
significant it looks very simple it
turns out not to be simple did you reuse
an existing model for that where you've
got some kind of cleanup you know you're
concerned about the maximum number IPS
you might be willing to put in that
routing table or
you know what what are the pitfalls
there that you've encountered you know
we we haven't had the opportunity to
exercise that in a real incident
response we're building the capability
right now I like that you call out the
pitfalls there there are certainly
services that depend on being able to
make outbound calls to given IP
addresses SharePoint is not one of those
customers make a request and we respond
and so the the IP address or dns black
holing should have less of an effect in
our unique environments but you're right
that there should be should be check
checks and balances there so that an
engineer can't black hole say all of the
the ten dot space or all the 25 dot
state space thank you
great thanks Matt thanks for your time a
great session
[Applause]