[Music]
so welcome to the talk we're gonna be
talking about automating creating secure
disposable infrastructure for red teams
primarily using terraform this is gonna
be an interesting talk because I've
acquired the confluence I've been here
so if you hear just random really bad
coughs while I talk I promise you I'm
not dying it's just the con flu so quick
Who am I slide because we got a lot of
content to go through my name is
Michelle Oh I go by pipe leader on the
Twitter's I'm a security analyst at
Black Hills InfoSec and I have a bunch
of other certs which nobody cares about
so let's talk about let's see what we're
gonna talk about this is basically gonna
be a terraform crash course and how to
automate all the things infrastructure
rise at least red team related but also
you could technically use the tool that
we're gonna talk about for DevOps
purchases as well what this talk isn't
gonna be as a basic C to infrastructure
talk so if you don't know what a
redirector is if you don't know what a
c2 server is this might not be the talk
for you
there was another talk right after mine
that covered the basics of this but I
think it was cancelled unfortunately but
this is not definitely not gonna be a
basic C to infrastructure talk so we're
gonna cover things cover some things
that are a little bit more advanced so
let's talk about what's terraform
because obviously not everyone might not
know what terraform is so terraform is
built by hashey Corp the creators of
packer and vagrant and all of those
awesome tools so mainly terraform is a
tool for building changing and
versioning infrastructure safely and
efficiently but you can really ignore
the definition because all you really
need to know is it you build
infrastructure with code and with code I
mean HCl hashey Corp configuration
language so this is a specific language
to terraform and after that there's an
execution plan so when you run terraform
apply for example which we'll get into a
bit later it actually tells you what
infrastructure it will go and create so
you don't mess up creating
infrastructure before you actually
deploy things it also has the concept of
Blissett implicit dependencies meaning
that if you set a implicit or explicit
dependency terraform is smart enough to
know that a certain resource needs to be
created before the other resource that
you specified as the pet that it's the
pendant on it also has a state file
which is I think is probably one of the
most unique features when it comes to
these tools terraform distinguishes
itself because the state file so state
the state file and terraform keeps track
of the created infrastructure both that
you deployed and both that you've dipped
so and we'll talk about that in a minute
as well let's real quick dive into HCl
because there's gonna be a lot of code
in this presentation but it's important
that you understand the code in order to
get a grips on the tool itself so there
are three main concepts in HCl there are
providers logical providers and
provisioners so providers are the things
that you specify an HCl that go and
interact with a remote API so any cloud
service provider be at digitalocean AWS
whatever you want I think I lost track
of the amount of API services the
terraform supports I'm pretty sure at
this point it supports basically
anything under the Sun logical providers
on the other hand are the complete
opposite so logical providers are
something that only exists in the code
itself and you can use logical providers
to do stuff like create SSH keys
dynamically or create random bits for
example so that there's no conflicting
resources when you actually go to apply
your infrastructure
there's also provisioners and
provisioners is the fun part
provisioners allow you to do stuff like
execute batch scripts on the created
instances execute commands locally which
is more useful than it sounds and we'll
get into that in a second and all sorts
of cool fun stuff so how do you get
started with terraform it's actually
much much simpler than you'd expect you
create a directory preferably with a git
repository it is code afterall and
that's if you don't use a git in your
code that's a cardinal sin variables
that TF which is where you put all of
your variables terraform that TFRs which
will basically be your file where you
define values to your variables
and then do that TF in this presentation
will be interacting mainly with
digitalocean just because it is very
simple to understand and there aren't
really special things you need to do in
order to get started but the last file
can really be renamed anything you want
so let's take a look at the code so
we've set our variables at TF file
we've populated our variable the other
variable file and and what we do in the
do that CF file is we define a resource
so the really important part of this is
the digitalocean droplet so that is the
actual name of the provider so you
define the keyword resource you give it
digitalocean droplet and now terraform
knows that you're going to be creating a
provider with digitalocean droplet so
you want to interact with digital ocean
HTTP c2 is just a common name we can
give it in this case we're trying to
spin up a c2 server so this is just a
name you can give that perfect that
specific resource and then we define our
parameters underneath so there is image
which is just the slug name of the image
you want to create on that droplet the
name of the droplet you want to create
region in this case it's London size two
gigabyte droplet that's all good and
dandy and the SSH keys and we'll talk
about that in the next slide then we go
to the provisioner so this is what you
actually use to execute scripts remotely
on the created droplet so the
provisioner in this case is named remote
exec there's a bunch of these there's
also a remote in line which you can use
to actually specify a list of commands
in the actual conviction code as opposed
to running a just the bash script
remotely and you need in order for the
provisioner to successfully connect to
the create a droplet you need to tell it
how to connect so in this case we're
connecting via ssh with the user root
and then we're giving it the private key
which we the
find before alright so before before we
did all that we basically defined a
digital ocean SSH key so as I said
before so there is a resource in this
case it's named digital ocean SSH key so
if you give it a file path it will then
upload that SSH key at digitalocean and
it'll be available to use integer ocean
we're giving it the name digital ocean
SSH key and we're using a built-in
function called file and the file as you
might expect a built-in function file
you give it a file path reads it and
puts it into the public key variable
okay and the VAR SSH key variable here
is something that we've defined
previously in our variables that TF file
so we we've managed to create resources
on digital ocean with SSH keys and
everything but the thing is we're using
the built in function file which means
that we have to manually create the SSH
keys before we want run that script
which is bad because you know we want to
automate all the things so how do we do
this also you can't have multiple
objects in digital ocean or really any
cloud service provider with the same
name because they do not like that so
you need a way to generate randomness in
the name so that digital ocean or really
anything AWS doesn't come back to you
and say hey this is not gonna work stop
it so how do we go about dynamically
creating SSH keys and typing that into
the digital ocean provider to then
upload and then use to then upload that
stuff to digital ocean and spin that
droplet up so the first thing that we do
here is we define the random ID resource
and we give it the parameter byte length
of four so it'll create four bytes of
randomness and that will be used in
order to create our randomness in the
droplets name we then use the TLS
private key resource which as the name
entails will
generate an SSH key using the RSA
algorithm with 4096 bits now this is the
down here is the special part because by
giving the public key variable the the
previously defined TLS private key
resource we're creating an implicit
dependency and by that terraform and
with that terraform knows that it needs
to first create the private key and it
needs to first create the public private
key pair ssh public/private key pair
before actually going and creating the
droplets but the thing is this way we
don't really have our SSH keys to disks
because they if you generate the public
private key pair through HCl they will
be only stored in the terraform that TF
state file in the state file which you
could parse for this data but it's
really really inconvenient so what you
can do is at the end of the digital
ocean resource you can put the local
exec provisioner and what this will do
is execute a local command and the rest
is really just string interpolation so
what it will do when it creates the
digitalocean droplet it will take the
private key and the public key and echo
it to a file in this case data that ssh
data ssh keys so every time we create a
droplet those two public that
public/private key pair will be
outputted to the filesystem which is
great which we can then use to document
and actually SSH the droplet itself
what's also great is we can actually
clean up after ourselves so the local
you do we then define another local exec
provisioner and we specify ondestroy
so when equals destroy means that that
provisioner will only run when we
actually destroy the infrastructure as
opposed to creating it and we give it
the command to run so in this case we're
just deleting the SSH keys which we
previously which you previously output
it before
so we've we've got everything set up how
do you actually spin stuff up with
terraform well the first thing you have
to do is export a environment variable
the environment variable name itself is
you're gonna have to refer to the
documentation of terraform for each
individual CSP digitalocean is pretty
straightforward it's just digitalocean
token and you give it your digitalocean
token you then run terraform in it
terraform in it downloads all of the
required providers which are not
installed by default and terraform so it
has to go out and download them from the
tariff Ward site terraform site you
didn't run terraform plan which will
give you a nice diff of your
infrastructure so say for example you've
already applied this terraform
configuration and you go and change
something in it if you were in terraform
plan again it'll actually create an
infrastructure diff for you and you'll
know exactly what resources are gonna be
changed or not and then you want
terraform apply and let everything loose
and it'll create everything you want for
it so let's recap we can now
automatically generate SSH keys for our
instances we can spin our droplets up or
whatever CSP you decide to use and then
you can run commands and bash scripts on
the remote hosts or locally but the
thing is this is really the system
really isn't flexible the reason for
this is we want to create complex
infrastructure right during Red Team
assessments you want read erectors you
want c2 servers you want Alcorn all
sorts of fancy stuff and the only way
you'll be able to do that is if in this
in this method is if you just keep
changing the same terraform
configuration file over and over again
and obviously if you want different
kinds of infrastructure for different
engagements that's gonna be a pain in
the butt so how do we make the system
modular so that you have to only change
very small amount of code in order to
get very complex infrastructure and as I
said before so as of right now
everything is one configuration file so
the whole system is very inflexible so
it turns out there's these things called
terraform modules and terraform
describes them as self-contained
packages but you can again ignore the
description just think of terraform
modules as functions so
any programming language that you know
you can just think of terraform modules
as functions how do you create a
terraform module
well you just create a subdirectory in
your root folder wherever you spun up
terraform before and at era for module
consists mainly of three files so
there's a main that's he F outputs at TF
variables that TF variables at TF so
obviously the name is pretty
straightforward the main is where all of
your main logic will lie the outputs is
the outputs of the module so thing as
again like referencing it functions that
that's your function output variables
that TF is the module input module
inputs so think of it as arguments to
your function so this is we're gonna
create a simple module that will spin up
a HD PC to using digitalocean right so
how do we do that well we go to our
variables that TF file and we put in our
arguments so we got the install argument
at which is a type of list
we got the count argument which is how
many instances you want to actually spin
up besides the region so basically
everything that we've previously defined
in our single configuration file that we
did before we now have as arguments to
the module and this makes the system
very flexible so that you don't have to
keep changing the code the HDL code over
and over again the outputs contains the
IPS of the instances and the reason why
I did this it'll become clear later and
also the SSH user different CSPs need
different user names to actually ssh
into them so because there's now ansible
support and Red Baron which is the tool
that we'll be talking about in a second
that does basically everything that I'm
talking about here for you that is
needed to actually SSH into the bosses
so we've got everything in a module now
we go back to our root configuration
file and instead of all of the code that
we previously saw before
all we really need is this so we define
a module the module name really doesn't
matter in this case we're just calling
it HTTP c2 the important part is the
source variable and that source variable
is the path is the local path to the
module that we previously created so now
we completely automated spinning up a c2
server securely we can also run multiple
scripts on the created service so for
example if we wanted to install a cobalt
strike everything that we want as an NSC
to server we can totally do that so now
we need to take care of the redirect
there's right because we have our c2 sir
we're not office Kate our c2 servers we
need to create something that can
automate creating redirect errs so this
would be awesome so say we had in a root
terraform configuration file we have we
have two modules we have a c2 server and
a redirector server what would be
awesome if is if we can just feed the
IPS of the of the C - sir - to redirect
our module in order for terraform to
automatically redirect all traffic from
the redirect or service to the C - sir
that would be great right that's like
literally ten lines of code so is it
possible to do that yes it is so in the
redirector module all I really need to
do is define a redirect to variable
which is of a list type so what that
variable will do is it will get well it
will contain a set of IPS which will be
our c2 servers and then basically the
rest of the code is the same the only
thing that we may want to do is actually
use some kind of tool in order to
actually redirect the traffic so how do
we do that well in this case we're using
a different provisional so it's always
remote exact but we're using the inline
argument and the inline argument
specifies a number of commands that we
execute remotely instead of just a bash
script so we're doing it we're
installing a bunch of stuff here the
really the magic sauce is this final
line here which uses so cat to redirect
port 82
see to IPS which we gave it previously
in the actual route terraform
configuration so now we have something
like this which is pretty pretty cool so
we defined in our Reuter from
configuration we define the HTTP c2
module we give it the source which is
the H which is the HTTP c2 module count
so turns out the all of the terraform
provisioners support account argument
meaning that all of this stuff and
theory can scale infinitely so for
example if you wanted to see two servers
and Tenri directors for some reason you
can totally do that
just by specifying the count variable
which is great and then we give it an
install argument which just is just
basically a list of bash scripts that
are local on our machine that we want to
install and in this case we're
installing Empire Metasploit and cobalt
strike because why not we then define an
HTTP HTTP redirect ER module we give it
the source which is the HTTP redirect or
module that we previously created and in
this case we're spinning up for redirect
errs because why not the redirect Q
argument is the most important because
we're basically telling it hey in order
for you to create the redirect is you
need to first create the HTTP HTTP c2
servers right so by specifying the
output the IPS output of the HTTP c2 sir
what we're doing is creating again like
an implicit dependency so terraform now
knows it needs to first create that c2
server before the redirect errs and also
we can specify different regions so for
example if you wanted to just spin up a
droplet and from Singapore and New York
you can specify the regions as well and
every droplet will have a different
region from that array so it would be
great if there's a tool that did all of
this for you right because I just talked
about it now but it would be kind of sad
if you now went home with this and you
have to build it all yourself well it
turns out I did I did most of the work
for you so there's Red Baron which was a
tool that I wrote that does exactly this
and at this point it supports
it's a pretty mature project it has
documentation which from an open source
tool is pretty rare it has an exhaustive
support of all the major csps and also a
lot of examples in the example folder so
if you just go to that github link
there's an examples folder which will
basically all you really need to get
started and it supports AWS digitalocean
has your Google Cloud compute and lie
node at this point the line node support
needs to be revamped just because
there's an actual official lie node
provider now for terraform so we're
gonna I'm gonna have to work on getting
that getting that pushed out also but
also I actually forgot to put it in
there it also supports the creation of
let's encrypt certificates so and we'll
talk about that a little bit now because
there's ansible support too so actually
just a week ago I pushed out an update
to Red Baron which adds ansible support
to all of this dynamic SSH config
generation which sounds a little lame
but I guarantee you it's sort of a big
deal because it's a key saver and I'll
demo that in a second also how many
people have heard of mosh here awesome
ok so you probably should be using mosh
as your SSH client because it is at
least 40 times better than the standard
SSH client it supports roaming it has
feedback it has some sort of algorithm
that I I forgot exactly what it does but
it basically it predicts your typing as
you type which makes things incredibly
faster especially on latency heavy
networks and everything is March
friendly so all the firewall
configurations that it does support
smosh already so let's let's take a look
at how it generates SSH config files we
give it the template file provider which
basically is used to create as the name
implies templates and we specify the
path to the template in the template
variable we then create an explicit
dependency because there really is in a
way of creating an implicit dependency
using the template file provisioner for
some reason
and then all of these variables down
here is what will be replaced with the
the same variables in the template file
so all of these values will be string
interpolated into the template file as
it generates it but in order to actually
generate the template file we also need
to tell terraform when to actually
generate them because it doesn't it it's
not smart enough to know that and in
order to do that we create an OLE
resource null resource is sort of a
weird terraform provider but it
essentially as the name implies does
nothing but it can be used on a lot of
things because you basically can get
around a lot of terraform limitations
and HCl limitations this way so in this
case we're using a null resource to
basically tell it to render the template
that we previously defined on top
whenever a SSH can SSH key is generated
so one of the big main issues that
terraform has is the provisioners the
remote exact provisioners the local
exact provisioners aren't really made to
do in-depth configuration on the host
you spin up so they're meant mainly to
bootstrap the host so that you can then
go in with something like ansible to
actually do in-depth configuration and
take advantage of everything that
ansible offers but I really didn't want
to do that in a sense I just wanted
something that just did everything for
me so there's this awesome github
account called which I think is that one
of the best names I've ever heard insane
cloud posse and it turns out they
managed to figure out how to get ansible
to work with terraform and you do that
by basically and I think this is almost
genius because I could never figure this
out so you're creating again a null
resource and we're telling it hey it
depends on in this case the redirector
code so this will only this will only
trigger when a HTTP redirected in this
case gets created
but also it will trigger if the ansible
playbook changes in any way because what
it does is calculates the sha-1 some of
the ansible playbook and if we modify
the ansible playbook and type terraform
apply it will trigger on that so that it
knows hey you've updated the playbook
and we want to go out and configure
something differently on those hosts and
then in the null resource we give it the
local exact provisioner which actually
runs the ansible playbook command and
this is just again I actually truncated
this for brevity because this command is
that this line is actually really really
long but you can see it you get the idea
where it just there's a bunch of string
interpolation and it gives it the
private key of the host that it wants to
get that it needs to connect to and the
playbook and all that good stuff so demo
this is I'm gonna try to do a live demo
first the internet years really sucks
but hopefully it'll work but I have a
video just in case it doesn't okay can
everyone see that that is way too small
hold on
okay this is gonna look really bad
because there's terraform is very very
verbose but I'll give it a shot anyway
so let's take a look at our main
terraform configuration file okay so
this is sort of similar to the slides
but we have a htpc two module defined we
gave it the ansible playbook argument
which is gonna run the ansible the
specified ansible playbook on all of the
SI toos that you create you could
technically as i said like this
technically scales out pretty well but
right now for just time constraints
we're gonna spin up one server one HP HP
BC to server and I'm not gonna install a
cobalt strike this is an example by the
way of just creating something with Red
Baron in digitalocean
it's in the examples folder so you can
literally just copy and paste this into
the root directory and you should and
uncommon stuff and you should be good to
go we then define the redirect to
argument which waits until the ec2
servers have been created in order to
pass that information to the redirector
so that our traffic actually gets
redirected so now we run terraforming it
okay so when you first run this it'll
take a while especially if you have a
bad internet connection via days it
needs to download all the providers but
from the output here you see Terra for a
minute you got it has the digitalocean
provider external provider null random
template so these are all the providers
that are needed by the modules in order
to actually create this infrastructure
we then run terraform plan and what's
great about the way the modules are set
up to which I really didn't explain
because of time but by default firewall
rules are generated for each droplet and
when you run terraform apply what it'll
do is go out get your current public IP
address and set rich input restrictions
on the track on the track
ethic so you can only connect to the
droplet and no one else so it basically
firewalls everything that you create by
default to four and allows access to
only your IP so this is the output of
terraform plan and it's a lot of output
because like the the modules in self
contain a decent amount of code the
actual route configuration file does not
however but you see here that we have
it's going to generate a SSH config
template it's gonna generate a digital
ocean droplet all of this stuff these
are all firewall rules right here so
it'll basically only allow SSH in from
my current public IP address these are
the SSH keys that we'll be creating and
all of the redirect our stuff as well so
let's see how slow this actually runs
and if anything we could just play the
video so I'm running terraform apply now
which will actually go out and create
all of this infrastructure that we've
set up that we've defined in our root
configuration file and we say yes you
want to create all the things and now
it's doing its magic one thing that you
want to keep in mind if you're concerned
about it from a security perspective is
that the actual SSH private key that you
that it uses is output it to the
terminal there is technically a
sensitive flag in order for terraform to
redact this but for some reason isn't
currently working with the some of the
provisioners so i still have to figure
that out but you can see here that it
generated the SSH keys it generated the
firewall rules and it's now trying to
create it is now trying to create the
HTTP c2 server and once it did there and
once it does verify that it's up it'll
connect to it via SSH and install a
bunch of dependencies that we've set so
now the API the digitalocean api got
back to terraform it said hey the host
is now up so now terraform is
automatically trying to connect to the
instance via SSH
okay connected this is awesome it's
working and now it's basically just
running apt-get install to install Maj
among other things and just basic
dependencies so that we can later
install Empire Metasploit or cobalt
strike
and so cat also awesome so let's all
that it's doing its thing let's take a
look so it created the HTTP situ server
and this is just a bunch of this is the
app this is the actual SSH keys that
help put it to the folder and now since
we defined a ansible playbook to run on
the HTTP c 2 server it's actually
executing ansible now so this is the
output of ansible and the playbook that
it's now executing is just get cloning a
bunch of stuff to the root directory so
it's doing that now it's cloning in
packet CME and again this is an example
that you can find in the actual
repository it's now trying to create the
redirector and it's installing a bunch
of dependencies on the redirector and
it's also going to set up its gonna run
so cat and a team ox instance so that it
will actually persist after terraform
logs out of SSH on the host awesome I
can't believe this worked quite frankly
on this internet so now we've created 15
resources and everything seems to be up
so since we also generated the SSH
config files along with all the all of
these hosts we can make SSH tab complete
all of the created infrastructure that
we just set up using Red Baron so if I
now type SSH and then let's see so I
think that's pretty cool
because that saves you an enormous
amount of typing in terms of just
specifying the config the private key
and everything that you'd normally have
to do when you spend stuff up
and there you go so now we see we've
successfully created a redirector and a
situ server completely automatically
with Red Baron and now to actually
destroy the infrastructure once you're
done with it
so once you're done with your engagement
type terraform destroy it'll clean up
after itself it'll remove the SSH keys
it'll destroy everything that you've
previously created
sweet and we just we've taken we've
clean up everything that we created so I
actually finished this quite uh somewhat
early but I want to give a shout out to
these three people so let me put that
back in presentation mode I was
expecting the demo to take a lot longer
with the internet but Rastamouse he did
an awesome two-part blog post on
initially setting this stuff up in
terraform some basic stuff with
terraform and Red Baron was sort of
inspired by those two blog posts Jared
Hite who contributed at the azure
modules in Red Baron and also a
gentleman or a gentlewoman of the a f00
one that's that's his or her Twitter
handle thank you to her him or her for
creating the Google cloud compute
modules any questions that's a good
question so the question was if you're
on two separate engagements and you want
to create two different kinds of
instructure for to both of those
engagements how do you do that
so terraform has an awesome command
called workspace which is exactly what
you'd expect it to do so you can
basically if I can type it small so
doing this with one hand so you can
basically create separate workspaces and
I'm not showing that you can create
separate workspaces with the terraform
workspace so that your state files don't
conflict with each other and that's yeah
after that you're basically good to go
all righty I think that's it
[Music]