[Music]
welcome to a hack for show report for
dough BB King your presenter this
afternoon I am a tester with Black Hills
info sack I've been working with them
for about four years I've been doing pen
testing since 2008 I started with web
apps
I built a couple of two different
companies I helped to build the pen test
an internal pen testing team and a big
part of that was coming up with the
reporting template and the content for
those reports and at those jobs I had to
live with those reports forever because
I was working with the development teams
and so anything unclear in those reports
came back to me anything that they
thought maybe wasn't really an issue you
know how big a deal is it if we have a
cross-site scripting in the banking
application those all came back to me so
I got pretty good at trying to explain
things clearly in words in the report so
I didn't have to explain them over and
over again in meetings I came to InfoSec
in kind of a strange way and I think
more and more people are doing it this
way I think at the you know the first
wave of hackers was all you know
computer educated or just computers as a
hobby I came from art I have a
bachelor's of Fine Arts degree in
technical theatre so lighting design and
that sort of thing there are computers
involved in that they're not the normal
computers that we use and that was what
was interesting to me about that but I
come at this from a little bit more I
don't know maybe non-traditional view
I'm not quite as excited about the
technical details I think the
presentation is important as well
so when it comes down to it if you're
doing pen tests what are you actually
accomplishing what's when you're done
testing what have you done if you're if
you're building an automobile when
you're done you have an automobile if
you're testing when you're done what do
you have you maybe maybe you have a
bunch of passwords maybe you have a
bunch of accounts maybe have access to
things you didn't didn't
access to at the beginning hopefully but
that's not what they're paying you for
there they're not paying you to to get
access to things that you shouldn't get
access to they're paying you for your
description of how that happened
so that you can help them to stop other
people from doing that the report is the
product the test is fun and that's
awesome and you can have as much fun as
you want when you're testing but your
product is not the test your product is
the report that's the thing that lives
on afterwards they're not paying you to
have a good time even professional
athletes that people talk about oh you
know it would be great to play a game
for a living wouldn't it well you kind
of do if you're a pen tester you kind of
play a game for a living but they're not
paying you to play they're paying you
for a result you can certainly have fun
while you're doing it I recommend that
but that's not the goal it's easy to
lose sight of that sometimes so the
report is supposed to tell a story there
it is the story is the story of the
environment that you're testing and the
report is what lives afterwards so
whatever you did to get the access you
got is awesome if it was a vole 'nor
ability in a system in a commercial
system that vulnerabilities probably
gonna be patched so at some point that's
not gonna work anymore once people
install those patches right because
they'll install patches lickety-split
but that's not that's not the thing
that's nothing at the purpose the
purpose is to create that report so that
you can improve the processes that
contributed to the environment I mean
the reports will sometimes end up as
evidence in a court of law it's never
happened to me yet I don't think and I
hope it never does
but that's that's the level of attention
you should be paying to the reporting
while you're writing it understand that
people are going to pick this apart it's
not just the developers who are gonna
say that you know your this exploits
never really going to happen who's
really going to attack us
there may be actual consequences to that
report you can have to stand behind it
the the and again the goal of that
report is to help people make decisions
so if your report is not clearly
describing the the environment and the
things you found in like actionable
terms
then they're missing a lot of the value
out of that report I've seen a lot of
reports that are really good technically
like I learned a lot I try to read as
many reports as I can friend that come
out of the testing team fph I ask
because I learned a lot from those but
as a technical person has a pen testing
person I'm looking for something totally
different than the people who paid us to
produce that report are looking for I'm
looking to seeing how does that new
exploit work how does that new tool work
I want to see how I can use those things
in my next test but that is not the
point of the report the report of the
report again is to give actionable
information to the people who can take
action then the people who can take
action usually aren't the technical
people there's I think one of the
problems that we get and I've heard this
one mentioned over and over again is
people try in their reports or they try
in conversations or they try at
conferences that they try in CTFs to
prove how awesome they are and I think
some of that stems from this this
impostor syndrome that everyone seems to
have everyone has it you're not an
impostor and I don't think it's a
syndrome to realize that you have limits
to realize that there are things that
you don't know yet I think that's all
fine but trying to show off is
off-putting to people it plays into
those stereotypes people have of
technical people which is well maybe he
knows all about computers but he doesn't
know about business he doesn't know
about people he doesn't know how to
communicate well he's just you know in
the basement 400-pound guy with his
computer John has said this a lot of his
talk he said don't try to impress the
other wizards which i think is great
because that implies that you're the
wizard too but but it's easy to get
stuck in that it's easy to get stuck in
showing how cool the hack was because it
is cool
so the story you're telling in your
report is what does that environment
look like so what was it that you were
testing were you testing a web
application then your report talks about
that web application it talks about how
you as an attacker to see that web
application and your view is different
than the developers view you should have
at least an in-depth view of that
application as the developers do but you
don't have the source code you know how
it works and you have a different
perspective than they have and that in
itself is valuable even if you don't
find vulnerabilities even if you don't
find you know sequel injection you can't
just take over the system it's still
valuable to see how an attacker looks at
a system I can't tell you how many
developers I've talked to when when I'm
showing them how we do pen testing we'll
get you know 15 20 minutes into
explaining how we did some sequel
injection in their in their their
application and somebody in the back
will raise their hand to kind of meekly
kind of you know I'm not quite sure
what's going on call him say what's your
question he says well how could you do
that because the input field only
accepts 15 characters like they don't
know
that that's not a control because the
world they live in is all about that
it's about usability it's about what the
what the device is what the interface is
that you present to the user and they
gloss over all the details underneath
that so even to show them that your
field length limits are in your input
forms don't have any effect on somebody
who's got hostile intent to your
application is an eye opener the the
report should include your failures and
there's there's a couple kinds of
failures one is the the good kind of
failure I think for the customer is when
you try something and they have it have
a control in place that stops you so
when that happens it's important to
document that you did that I tried this
thing and it didn't work because you had
this control in place and then take
another sentence and and compliment them
on that tell them where does that come
from
so think about the executives think
about the the people who have like real
offices with the door what what are they
interested in what processes do they
have in place what sort of things
they know about they contributed to that
do you have a good maybe you've got good
training for your software developers
maybe they're using good validation
routines maybe they're consistently
disabling old features maybe they're
there they're going through and they've
got a good strong password policy call
those things out the people who are
paying you for this test are it's it's
the company sure but the person that
you're working with is probably closer
to your role as a tester than to the
executives role so if you can build that
kind of relationship with them and
acknowledge in the report the things
that they're doing skilfully that helps
them justify their performance to their
their executives and it builds tells a
more complete story of what's in the
environment the other kinds of failures
are things if you're if there's you know
communication failures there's a there's
a maybe there's a way people love laughs
for web applications and maybe that
contributes to to a different kind of
failure maybe this doesn't stop you from
from your attacks but it limits what you
can do in the time that you have perhaps
I think get way too much credit for
being a control bears they're useful
they have their place I think they're
great for like live patching things if
you know there's an issue and you don't
have your buying time to fix it in the
application but those sorts of things
that just make your job take longer it's
important to call those out as well
because maybe you didn't cover in as
much depth as you could have had they
removed that control for you and it's up
to them don't tell them you know you
have to turn the way off or I'm not
doing the test it's up to them how they
want to present their environment to you
and what sort of view they want to give
you into it but call it out if it got in
the way that should be written down if
you've found a bypass for it that's even
better
so every report you've got two audiences
for every single report you have the
technical people which i think is the
group that most of us think of while
we're writing the report because we're
doing technical things the the person I
think I like to imagine when I'm writing
this part of the report
the methodology that kind of a
blow-by-blow this is where I started
this is what I saw this is where I went
with that what was interesting to me
what caught my eye what tools I used I
think about somebody who's like me but
maybe you're behind maybe six months
behind so I explained a little bit more
than I would to one of my peers at work
but not so much that I'm telling them
you know what an IP address should look
like I'm going to include the commands
that I ran so that they can rerun those
things because the as a consultant I
have this wonderful freedom that I
didn't have as a corporate employee
which is when I'm done with the report
there might be some questions and I
answer those questions and then I get to
walk away from it I don't have to live
with that report forever so that report
needs to stand on its own there can't be
questions that I'm gonna answer later
their needs if somebody wants to know
hey I want to fix this problem so the
first step in fixing the problem is to
recreate it right so what are the steps
that take to expose this defect or this
bug and the report needs to include
enough information for that so not for
somebody who never used a command line
not for somebody who's not familiar with
you know the the tears in the
application or the this the parts of the
environment but somebody who's who could
use a little bit of help that's who you
want to keep in mind when you're doing
that part of the report and then when
you're done with the testing part you
want to think about the business people
and the business people are the ones who
are going to make the decisions
regardless of what the technical people
think regardless of whether you think
that's great or not they're generally
making the decisions they can be
influenced by the technical people but
when it comes down to it if something
goes wrong in the company they're not
going to go after the guy sitting in the
sock they're gonna go after the guy
sitting you know with the door on his
office so for this group of people I
picture somebody who is interested in
the environment somebody I assume they
have good intentions I assume they want
to protect their their assets and their
customers but they don't live in that
environment they don't spend time at a
command line they don't spend time using
the computer because the computers fun
they use the computer to get specific
things done they're more in PowerPoint
and outlook than they are
you know burps sweet and Kali the people
like this they've got a different view
their up way higher above all the
details and what they see in front of
them is they see they see different
organizations underneath them different
groups different responsibilities they
see maybe some of the technology they
paid a fortune for they see some of the
consulting hours they paid for to learn
how to use that technology so for them
they've got this big like an array of
levers and buttons in front of them and
what they want to know when they read
your report is they want to be able to
quickly know which of these levers and
buttons do I need to pay attention to
which way does it go and then they'll
figure out who in their environments who
in their organization you know owns
what's behind that lever and now they
know what to work on so no you don't
want technical detail here you want
general things so so your password
policy lets people choose weak passwords
okay that's that's a policy lever I got
that one you you don't have you know
egress filtering on your your perimeter
so anybody can get out here okay so
that's the network guys tell them in
general terms where they can go to make
the changes you think they need to make
so a quick example if in your test you
managed to steal all the hashes from the
domain controller and you took them
offline and through whatever process you
cracked 85% of the passwords you
probably feeling pretty good about that
that's that's it's exciting to see all
the passwords cracking so for the
technical folks they need to be able to
recreate that they're probably not going
to have the actual password cracker in
their environment because I don't think
a lot of organizations see that as a
valuable expenditure so you need to show
them how you got the information that
you needed in order to crack those
passwords so this is one they should be
able by reading this section of your
report to do exactly what you did on the
systems that use that you hit using the
commands and tools that you used so how
did you get admin privileges which
domain controller did you hit what were
the commands you typed and when did you
do it if you don't say when you did it
then they don't have an opportunity to
go look and see in there they're in the
log systems of what you know were their
signs are we collecting information that
we could have alerted on this but didn't
so the more detail you can give there
the better you don't need to go into the
details of password cracking or you know
what formulas you use with hash cat or
how you did the actual password cracking
the important thing for the people who
are going to fix this remember that's
what they want they want to know how to
fix this is how did you do what you did
so that when they make changes they can
go again and see if their changes would
stop you from doing the same thing or
similar things in the future so for the
business people this same issue you
would describe this differently you're
not going to say the word domain
controller you're not going to say the
words hash cap you're gonna say that I
got encrypted passwords for all your
users and I was able to recover the
plain text of those passwords and you're
gonna say that this has something to do
with the fact that your password policy
allows people to choose bad passwords
you're not gonna say your people are
choosing stupid passwords you're not
gonna say I need to educate your people
better you're gonna say because that's
not a problem they can solve they can't
I mean training is great but there's no
training program that's gonna prevent
people from choosing bad passwords your
password policy can do that so that's
the lever you want to point out for that
one and then you also want to point out
that what you did left some traces
somewhere you're your domain controller
shouldn't be talking to the internet
that sort of thing levers focus on the
levers another one if you're testing a
web application maybe you got in with a
sequel injection this one's a little bit
different than cracking passwords
because everybody's heard sequel
injection even the executives for the
technical folks you want to you want to
call it sequel injection you can maybe
just call it SQL I that's fine they'll
know what that is and you want to tell
them that the full URL and the
parameters that you used to take
advantage of that why because they need
to know where to go to fix this if you
just say hey your web apps got a sequel
injection I stole your database okay
well what do I do about that where where
is the sequel injection they need to
know where so they need the full URL and
they need the parameter that was
affected and if they don't already know
how to exploit that kind of thing they
could use a hand so give them an example
show them something that maybe not the
thing that would like download the whole
database you don't need to download the
whole database you just need to prove
that the issue is there show them
something that they can just
run and see the effects something that
when they've solved the problem will
fail or behave obviously differently
that's what they need the business folks
they all need to know about about about
quoting mechanisms and commenting
mechanisms and how you can end this
query early but they have heard sequel
injection and they probably know that
that's been in the OS top ten since the
OU has top ten has been out so mention
it but explain to them that it has to do
with the communication between the
application in the database and explain
to them that there are coding methods
you can use to avoid this completely but
the key to this and I've seen this over
and over in previous jobs and actually I
haven't seen this one here but in
previous jobs the developers they want
to do this they don't want to write code
that's exploitable they really don't and
some of them know how to write better
code but they have they have such
conflicting priorities I mean if you if
you've ever sat down and talked with a
developer who's got a security mindset
and works in a big organization that is
one of the most frustrated individuals
you'll ever meet they want to do or they
want to do right but right they want to
do better they want to be better but
they have is conflicting priorities if
their managers don't make it a priority
if they're not evaluated based on theirs
secure coding techniques and not just
delivering functionality they need both
and they're in conflict with each other
they need support from management for
those things they need to know how to do
it they need to see their manager making
it important they need to be recognized
when they're doing things well when
they're fixing problems and those are
the things the managers can do so I had
a I had a pen test it was it was Web
Apps I do a lot of web apps and it was
just just recently and it was it was bad
the when I talked to the customer
initially the they were what they wanted
was they wanted a report that they could
show to their customers to illustrate
that they were taking security seriously
and your data is safe with us and the
report that I wrote was not that at all
it was it was it was bad they had their
main web app was was three perl screen
that were written in 1998 and hadn't
been touched it was a horrible so this
is bad news they were expecting the kind
of a stamp you know this is this is
something we can show to our customers
and that is not at all what they got
this is the best compliment I've gotten
since I've been at BH is one of the
internal reviews of the report pointed
this out that there was there were
problems everywhere but I tried to
explain them in kind of a neutral way
stick to the facts I'm not calling you
names I'm not saying how could you make
this mistake I'm saying this is the
state of your application here's where
you need to go to fix it yes it's going
to take a long time so the positive
positive findings these are things like
for Web Apps like we didn't find any
input event input valuation problems we
couldn't get any sequel injection you
didn't even reflect any input that's
awesome
point these things out things that
people often do wrong that can
contribute to vulnerabilities when you
find people doing those right call it
out they need that reinforcement the if
they're not getting it from their
managers they can get it from you that's
part of your job you should be you
should be encouraging that sort of
behavior the things that make your job
as a pen tester harder you should be
excited when you see those and you
should call those out so that's enough
about how to the the mindset I think of
the reporting screenshots is another
area where you can you can you can kick
ass or you can really miss the missed
the boat
I think screenshots are critical I think
a report with no screenshots is a really
difficult report to ingest but just
having screenshots doesn't really solve
the problem either so when I'm thinking
about screenshots I'm thinking I'm going
to illustrate something I'm not going to
decorate something so this there's a
vulnerability here and I've seen reports
where this is the screenshot can you
tell what the vulnerability is I can't
tell what the vulnerability is so maybe
if i zoom in a little bit maybe the
vulnerability is a little bit clearer
but there's still kind of a bunch of
stuff here and there's there's something
going on on the bottom left there
that might be related I'm sure not not
sure what usually asking me to look at
here consume it a little bit more and
it's getting closer maybe some of you
figured it out right now and I can
circle it now
and so the vulnerability the vote is
that it's it's clear text communication
there's no SSL here so I so I could do
this as a report now I've narrowed it
down you see the URL I've circled where
the problem is but do you think everyone
who looks at that is going to say oh
clearly I know what the problem is I
don't think they are I think they need
more help than that so if you click on
that little eye it tells you a little
bit more it says the connection is not
secure okay this is better this is
better but what does that mean not
secure aren't you testing the security
the application isn't like aren't there
other problems that are security
problems maybe maybe the login page
maybe you can bypass the authentication
step isn't that an indication that your
site is not secure this also isn't
telling you anything
so remember when the browsers used to
tell you what URL you were at do you
member those days weren't those great
days I don't know why they keep getting
rid of that but you can fix it
Firefox you can fix like everything
still so you can go back into the
settings there and you can tell it the
the protocol is kind of an important
part of the URL and I would like to see
that please now you can see so now you
have a screen shot that's focused
narrowly in on where the problem is the
whole URL is there I've circled the part
that's bad I've pointed to the
explanation of why it's bad and I put
some words underneath that say it again
so there's no way you're going to look
at this screenshot with any knowledge of
how web browsers work and what security
issues are and miss the point you can't
miss that here what was it again this
could be anywhere
so there's two things about good
screenshots a good screenshot is helpful
which means that it's relevant it's not
just a shot of something that happened
near where the issue was it's not just a
screenshot of something that contains
what the issue was along with a hundred
other things
it adds some useful information so you
will describe it in words near the near
the picture but it also clarifies what's
going on and I'll show you some examples
of what I mean by that a little bit
later but bottom line is accurate a good
screenshot is accurate it's helpful by
being accurate it's also clear by being
legible which is to say that if you have
a screenshot of like the entire
application window and you have to
squish it down so that it fits on your
page and now I can't read anything
don't put that screenshot in if that's
the best you can do for that issue
that's not the screenshot you want you
need to find another way to illustrate
that issue and it's it's precise so it
emits things that are not relevant so if
you come from a math or a science
background may be helpful and clear
aren't the words you want may be
accurate and precise are what you want
so accurate means that it's true and
precise means that it's narrowly focused
on what the issue is we want something
that's true and something that's
narrowly focused on what the issue is so
I wanted to play a game I was gonna
write a little script there was this
there was this thing hot or not for a
while and it was also kitten war I don't
I like kitten war better where you see
pictures of kittens and you decide which
kittens are cuter than the other kittens
and into the collects votes across
everybody who plays and you see who's
the cutest kitten at the end but instead
we're just gonna look at screen shots
there is a did I say yes there is a
project on it that collects public pen
testing reports so there's no bhi ass
reports in here because I've learned my
lesson about trying to redact real
reports you're always going to miss
something so I'm not doing that at all
these are all available and we're going
to look at some of them so here 53 you
did an analysis of crypto cat this is
one of their screenshots from the report
their caption is above the screenshot
which is fine stylistic choice exemplary
is not the word exemplary means this is
perfect what they meant to say is
example but what is that illustrating I
can't tell what that what's important
about that there's there's something in
the middle there I think the word evil
shows up so I'm guessing
that's not supposed to be there but if
I'm a developer I don't have any idea
where that came from
what's contributing to it I see
developer tools it's pretty it's
decorating it's not illustrating this is
not a helpful screenshot from the same
report another screenshot this one's alt
text but it was as a screenshot which is
fine if you're if you're using text if
your screenshot is text I like to see it
as text because then it's searchable but
this is fine so this is telling you
what's going on we don't like math dot
random for some reason and it's
explaining why it's showing you exactly
where it is it's got the file name it's
got the line numbers it's got the thing
that doesn't like in bold so there's no
circles there's no red arrows here but
you're not gonna miss what's wrong with
this you can disagree with it if you
want but you're not going to
misunderstand what they're trying to say
they did another one for male fellow
male hope is it's a browser plugin that
will do PGP encryption decryption in the
browser for you and here's another one
same company different tests I don't I
don't know what this means
I think it's German I don't speak German
but I'm not sure that that matters so if
you've done any development or if you've
worked with developers you've heard the
phrase code smells you know a code smell
is a code smell is something that you
see in in source code that just looks
funny
maybe maybe it's not exploitable maybe I
can't I can't tell you exactly why it's
bad but it indicates that your minds in
the wrong place you're taking the wrong
approach to something a screenshot in a
report that's the entire window is kind
of a code smell for me it's not always
wrong but it's usually wrong
here's another one than a test for a PHP
myadmin PHP myadmin PHP myadmin it's a -
ql tool for handling - ql databases it's
a web app this is their explanation for
an issue that they found in there so the
steps are very clear i like the
description they they're telling you
what's going on they're telling you
where you can find what's what the
problem is but they're assuming that you
know where the login pages which is
probably okay they're assuming that you
know how to see what the my PA the PHP
myadmin cookie is they're expecting you
know what CSRF token is and what that
particular one is and and then well i
guess if you found them you can tell
whether they changed or not so that's
all good but it's that step two that
bothers me it's not it's not super clear
and it may be because they're testing
the application and not an instance of
it so in this case maybe there's not a
particular URL that the whole thing is
useful but certainly the path is right
maybe it's on my server and not your
server so the domain doesn't matter but
the path is still gonna matter and this
I think would benefit hugely from a
screenshot what would you put in a
screenshot that would say in one picture
what all those four bullet points say in
words you'd have a screenshot of the
HTTP response for the login page before
you logged in and then for the same
response after you logged in and you
would circle those things the cookies
and the C surf talkin and you would
point out that they didn't change so
this one I don't think this is a bad I
would do it differently I would have
screenshots but this report has no
screenshots in it at all so clearly
that's a stylistic choice that they made
they don't do screenshots and I can
respect making a choice and sticking
with it I think it was I would make a
different choice all right company
called mnemonic which is the word I can
never say correctly they analyzed the
Norwegian voting source code they voted
norwegia with source code
so here's a screenshot from this that's
that's the whole screen so there's two
different screenshots here the one up
left is it's text that's fine
the the caption is a little aggressive I
think it's it's got it's got a colon in
it and it asks a rhetorical question why
would you do this that's not something
you should say in your report you
shouldn't ask questions in your report
you should give answers in your report
so this should point out that maybe it's
an insecure kind of number generator it
shouldn't say why did you do that it's
kind of insulting to the reader maybe
there's a good reason maybe they wanted
to use the other one but they had some
legacy code that wouldn't let them maybe
maybe that rhetorical question has a
really really good answer maybe it was
really expensive for them to do it the
other way so maybe they have maybe they
have what you might call a compensating
control maybe somewhere else they
they're aware of the whole this made and
they've compensated for it somewhere
else but you're the people this this
caption assumes that they didn't know
what they were doing and they just did
it wrong out of ignorance which is bad
this they're not going to come back to
this customer if they do things like
that again and then down here they get
into crazy detail the is optimized
method is a simple routine it's simple
that returns true with 12.5% probability
1/8 maybe I don't know it goes into lots
of detail maybe that's useful for the
developers it feels like a little bit
too much for me I don't know I'm not
going to complain too much about that
bottom one but that that caption really
gets me it's horrible
next one Pro check up a company did a
report that's anonymize so they went
down the road that I was afraid to go
down they took a real report and they
redacted it and they're talking about
the reconnaissance phase so they're
telling the story this test started with
a reconnaissance phase I was trying to
figure out what was available to me
where I was what's going on and we we
brought out they had their own test
equipment so this is not a system they
were provided with they they brought
their own laptop in they plugged into a
network jack and there was a DHCP
service that gave an IP address
that's kind of a finding I don't know
how bad that is maybe that's okay given
the other controls in the environment
but to know that I can just plug in and
get an IP address that's important to
know and they say why that's important
revealed information that allowed other
targets to be discovered and then it
shows you the command they ran so this
command this is beautiful it's text but
it's beautiful there's no color but it's
still beautiful it tells you who the
user is it tells you what host they were
on it shows you with the pound sign that
they were rude it shows you they ran if
config on the first Ethernet interface
it shows you the hardware address do you
say that they've redacted that good for
them but it shows you what what there
there are hardware addresses that's
that's their own hardware address so it
probably doesn't matter to the customer
but maybe it's in log somewhere maybe
they can keep track of what that thing
did while it was there and then they've
made bold the line that shows where they
were on the network while they were
doing their test so that's great I think
just just that bolded line there is
enough by itself the rest of is just
gravy and then at the bottom there that
last thing receive bytes and transmit
bytes okay so what well that means it
was active if they if they just did if
config and looked at every interface
some of them would have zeros there and
show that they're not active so this
confirms to you to the reader of this
report that this was an active interface
that was actually doing stuff this is
beautiful there's no information missing
from this continuing with this same
report they point out that DNS service
the DNS servers are typically domain
controllers so that's obvious to
somebody who runs a Windows environment
it's not obvious to the executives it's
good to know maybe they know what a DNS
server is maybe they don't but this is
the kind of thing where you can you can
just put a couple of words in there to
help people who are new who maybe don't
focus on that area of the network to
help them understand what you're saying
why does it matter well this is why it
matters who cares that you find the DNS
server
well DNS yeah all right but the domain
controller there's a lot of stuff on
that that's interesting and again it's
showing you how they found out they
looked in that see resolved com so after
when they connected with DHCP they got
some information back from that that got
written to this file and this is what it
was
is this a vulnerability or are you going
to lose all your valuables because of
this no but it shows you how they
learned what they learned same report
that kind of fell off the rails here I
think this is one of those things that's
the code smell right it's the hole it's
not just one window it's the entire
desktop what do you what's important
about this they tell you at the top we
got access to this IP address as a local
administrator okay that's good
so the screenshot should prove to me
that that's what happened it kind of
does because it shows on the Start menu
there at the top it says administrator
so ok I'm logged in as somebody whose
name is administrator all right it's a
good clue but it's not proof and the
manager so everything in the back that
comes up when you log in as
administrator so ok
it probably is but why do you need all
that blue space there's so much there
what am I supposed to look at I drew the
arrows those arrows weren't there so
this gives you a lot of information that
you don't need along with some
information that you do need but it's
kind of questionably reliable there's
there's probably better ways to
illustrate that your local administrator
than showing this thing from the GUI so
remember the code smell it the holes if
the whole thing is what your screenshot
is maybe there's a better way to
illustrate it maybe there's a better way
to illustrate this it's good that they
put something in to support the claim
but there's room for improvement there
same report now they're showing the
exiting shadow file so again they're
telling you exactly what they're looking
at they're telling you what machine it's
on it's on a machine called spike and
it's showing you that the root user is
not prompted for a password so star NP
star that's where the password goes does
who just knows just by looking at that
that that means you look in login
without a password who just knew that
hardly anybody I didn't know that for
sure so apparently it's true but to me
this is not convincing but what is
convincing is only root can read out see
shadow so the fact that they were able
to read this file proves to me that they
were rude on that machine so that's
interesting and this is on the next page
they're showing how access was granted
to that system and they just SSH Tim so
this is again this is they're showing
you exactly what they did
so if you get this report and it's your
job to fix this problem and you think no
wait it's like we got authentication on
that box I know we do
well type this and see if you get the
same results and if you do you just
learn something wait a second the
controls I thought I had in place
actually aren't there this is where the
screenshots save lots of confusion lots
of arguing back and forth lots of lots
of pain show them how to do it and then
down at the bottom a neat little trick
they want to show two things they want
to show who am i and who am i gives you
the username and then ID gives you the
the u''t which is different so just
because your username is root doesn't
mean that you are root usually it does
but but they did them both and they
didn't both in one command so they saved
a little bit of space if I did him in
two commands it would've been a little
bit bigger screenshot they might have
had to squeeze it squeeze it some more
so they put some thought into this this
is a really good one this report i if I
have time at the end I'm going to show
you the whole report because this entire
report is like five pages long and this
is how it begins there's a picture and
then it talks about it just it just
leaps directly into problems it doesn't
talk about how they started if there's
no context it just jumps straight into
problems and it makes claims without
backing them up and says this this gem
is vulnerable to state fixation it
assumes you know what that means it
assumes you know what a gem is it
assumes you know what state fixation is
you can set it to an arbitrary value and
then they give you an example of an
arbitrary value but they don't tell you
what state fixation might be so I'm
going to kind of blow through this one
because it's kind of quick
here's that's the number six that's the
entire description of the issue
doorkeeper should be updated because
it's vulnerable to a critical CSRF I
think it might be better to say
doorkeeper has a critical CSRF
vulnerability and there's a patch
available whether it should be updated
or not is kind of not your job to say
and here's this summaries so so look at
the summary using the first two tricks
don't call them tricks they hijacked the
account for users no matter whether they
had Weibo connected or not and then
using two-factor authentication
vulnerabilities that got around two
factor authentication they could steal
people's cryptocurrency wallets
that's pretty Hassan right so they can
steal coins from any exchangers or so
anybody who uses this exchange they can
just jump right in and steal all your
coins and here's their conclusion
overall it's very secure I don't
understand how that follows and then
they take a potshot at other exchanges
yours is really good considering how far
horrible everybody else's is that's not
really the compliment I think they meant
to make so here's another example report
this one I don't know who knows about
Nakatomi Plaza anyone anyone very good
so this one might be fictional but it's
a really good illustration there's a
couple of things from here and then we
may have time to actually look at the
whole report because I think it's a
great example so here's a whole
screenshot right code smell this might
be bad we've got the whole URL we got
the IP address we got well not the whole
URL but it kind of goes off into some
weeds there with some random looking
things so maybe that's not meaningful
maybe we don't need it all right we'll
let it go log off in the upper right
this is this is one of the first things
I ever learned to look for when I first
started testing Web Apps to prove that I
was logged in I don't know who we're
logged in here as but if there's a log
off button then I'm logged on so
including that is critical it's it's a
thing you you're not gonna pick up on
right away people aren't gonna look at
that and say oh hey he's logged in but
if you point at it they'll say oh wow I
guess you're right you wouldn't be able
to log off unless you were logged in so
we are logged in we can see we've got
all this this stuff here there's a good
caption at the bottom if you can see it
the only nitpick I would have for this
is maybe there's something a little bit
more scary maybe there's a big red
button that we could click maybe there's
a an input thing that says add new user
maybe there's a big button that says you
know kill the searchlights some
a little bit scarier but this is good
later in that same report we on the
validation step so validation this is
what the reader of the reports going to
do to make sure that what you said is
true so here's the whole curled command
here's the response and it's highlighted
what you're looking for so you run this
whole thing you get a bunch of stuff in
the response but this is all you care
about
so illustrate with your screenshots
don't decorate don't put them in there
to make it pretty don't put it in there
to make it longer don't put it in there
because you think it's been five pages
since I had a screenshot make them good
screenshots have a good reason for
everyone
make them accurate make them precise
make them helpful so if you've got the
right voice and if you've got good
screenshots there's one last thing that
you should pay attention to and that's
formatting issues it's actually
important you can make it pretty you can
make the computer make it pretty for the
most part here's a place where it might
be worth hiring a page layout person
tell them give them a sample report
that's just got whatever you've got in
it whatever however you report is
whatever information you think is
important in there give them that as a
starting point and work with them to
make it pretty tell them what's
important tell them what you want the
reader to focus on and let them use
their artistic skills there their
attention focusing skills to to direct
people's attention to the parts that are
important and once you've got that
template you never have to think about
it again so we're gonna look at the
sample report from read siege because
it's a good example
so there's a nice cover page you know
who wrote this report it's important
because when they read this report a
year or a year and a half down the road
and they need their next pen test report
their follow-up they're gonna remember
who did this it's good to have that on
there there's a nice table of contents
the stuff on the left I think was added
to explain what's going on so that's not
actually part of the report but there's
headings headings is formatting you know
how to use headings right you can
generate the table of contents just by
using good headings then you've got your
executive summary so this is the part
that's for the guy with the levers and
the buttons right this this is the
summary of everything that's happened
during the test and it's all one page
you can't always make it one page but if
you can that's a good goal make it one
page if you have to go along or go ahead
but try to keep it short like this
there's a pie chart people laugh at pie
charts but they're really helpful
they're there it gets your attention you
can look at that quickly and you can see
okay
most of our issues are green greens
probably not bad and we've got the so
the overview the key finding so this
calls out the the highest severity
issues or the most important issues or
whatever from the perspective of the
person who did the test whatever I
really want you to know if you read
nothing else read these we've got that
and then recommendations this is these
are the levers to pull so implement
two-factor authentication on public
facing systems it doesn't get into the
details of what that is it doesn't say
you should use this particular 2fa
solution it says you should have one
that's something an executive can run
with he can go if he doesn't know what
2fa is you can call in his network ID
you can say hey do you know what 2fa is
we need to get some 2fa can you learn
something about that and help me out
strengthen password requirements I know
what a password is required offensive
coding training for developers that's my
favorite advice they really need that
and and they need to know that it's
important they need to know that you
care all right and then here's our
finding summaries so look at this we've
got color color is good
some people are color blind red and
green look the same to a lot of people
it's more prevalent in men it tends to
be pretty prevalent in technical men so
I'll sue
that people reading your report can't
tell the difference between red and
green just assume that so if we can't
tell a difference in you red and green
why is this still a good example it's
not just red and green there's a little
circle see the circle the red ones have
an exclamation point the green one is
empty so even if you print this in black
and white even if you can't tell your
Reds from your greens even if your rods
and cones are messed up you can still
see this at a glance what's what it's
consistent they look the same they look
similar they fit together
it's pleasant to look at here's an
explanation of what those mean and the
little circles again so color is there
yes but also in the absence of color
there's still obviously different here's
an example of one of the critical risk
findings and how it's illustrated we've
got the same words we saw before we've
got the circled with the bang in it
we've got a screenshot that shows you
where it's happening now the URL is not
in here so at first I'm thinking well
hey that URL should be there but it's
the login page you know where that is
and that shows what it is that shows
where the issue is figure 1 VPN login
form lacking second factor so there's
nothing to circle because it's missing
but it's called out right below here's
the other one with the the curl command
was nice the low severity findings
here's another one another crawl command
so we're running curl again we're
getting us the same kind of response but
we're interested in something else but
there's nothing extra there the whole
body is not present the whole URL is
there it's very focused on what needs to
be done and then methodology is blank
because it's not a real test
there's there's an appendix with some
definitions there's table of figures
depending how long your report is that
could be really helpful so I think
that's a good example of a good report
it's a lot of the things that I think
are important
where did my mouse go there it is
so in that report the reason I picked
that is because I think the formatting
of that report focuses your attention on
the issues it you can tell you know
color or not you could tell what was
important the highlighting and the
responses was good the screenshots were
good and focused I think it was really
good and I think that I think that that
template could have been made by a
graphic designer
and handed off to a tester and now the
tester can get all the benefits of the
graphic design expertise without having
to worry a lick about it it's a one-time
thing there's always things not to do
there's not very many and they're kind
of easy to remember so you don't to copy
and paste from a previous report it's
too easy to get somebody else's data in
somebody else's report and it's bad
because as soon as you've done that
you've completely broken the trust you
have with both customers so one customer
is doing somebody else's data in their
report so now how can they trust that
you're not gonna do the same thing to
them and what if they know each other
and it's it's a whole train wreck of bad
don't ever copy and paste from a
previous report what you can do if you
find you're using the same stuff over
and over again is write it up
generically and save that somewhere and
then take that generic and paste that in
and customize it vulnerability reports
everybody can run their own
vulnerability reports your job is to
provide detail so don't just copy and
paste from the vulnerability scanner
don't assume your audience knows
everything you know cuz they'll miss a
lot of your points you'll miss that
chance to educate them a little bit but
at the same time don't assume they don't
know the basics and don't assume they're
stupid don't say why would you do that
in the report don't say I can't believe
you didn't have this in place or this
was so simple
there's don't do that and I'm running
out of time for to show you the window
windows word things but I'm going to
tell you there are some things in
Microsoft Word that will save you time
if you're writing reports in Microsoft
Word a lot of people hate it but a lot
of people still use word we use word we
sometimes hate it but you can look at it
look it's been spend an afternoon
looking at word and see what you can
find in there that's not just copy and
paste
just select and make it bold look at the
features in Microsoft Word treat it like
a pen test trying to get around and
figure out what you can do in there
there's a couple of things one you can
insert a screenshot directly into your
document without saving it somewhere
else first
it's insert screenshot word Gray's out
you draw a rectangle around what you
want and you let go and your screenshot
is in the report the other is you can
abuse the autocorrect system so
autocorrect fixes your typos you can
create your own dictionary things for
those so phrases you're using over and
over again type the phrase once
highlight it go to the autocorrect thing
type in abbreviation you want to type in
to have expand into that and it's there
some people use like text expander or
things like that to do that system-wide
but it's built into work if you spend
some time it's you'll find it's well
worth it you can also use macros to to
fill in things we do screenshots in
there and the caption has to be a
particular format so I have a macro I
click on the screenshot I run the macro
it formats the the screenshot it formats
the the caption and we move on so I
think the purport is actually more
important than the hacking that produces
the report because the report lives on
and the hacking is just how you get
there thank you for your time I hope you
learn something worthwhile
[Music]