[Music]
hi good morning welcome to our talk
today me and Derek we had a long
discussion about the little guys
supposed to hold it here and a loud guy
is supposed to hold it down here so give
me a heads up if you can't hear it you
can hear us let us know it'd be
fantastic my name is Tim Madine we'll
give you a quick it's very brief intro I
teach with sans mimes faculty and the
program director for the sans master's
program I doing pen testing for well
over a decade now now I have a
consulting company red siege Turk I'm
gonna have to learn to introduce myself
first because I don't do any of that I'm
a pen tester at Black Hills information
security and to thank you guys for
coming to our conference how many of how
many of you are here for the first time
first wild bus access suite nice well we
only have one other one so you know next
year I expect to see you know some
repeat folks but uh yeah like I said I'm
a pen tester or security analyst at
Black Hills and that's my dream job cool
so we have first timers second timers
third great jokes I'm here all week try
the veal tip your waiter thank you so
much for attending our session today so
what we wanted to do is talk through
some of the the sort of the dumb hacks
that we've been seeing because what we
see isn't the super advanced stuff in in
your pen test right how many of you are
pen testers red teamers want to be
either of those things at great six
seven people fantastic great crowd
but what we're gonna do is we're gonna
discuss a lot of me my clickers
networking and I was trying to install
updates that's gonna be great idea score
yeah so what we see from time to time
and time again is we see the simple
stuff works and I would encourage you
when you're doing some of your pen
testing sorry I'm a wanderer when you're
doing some of your pen testing you're
doing some of your attacks and honestly
the defenses as well
so many times the lazy stuff this simple
stuff is gonna be what gets you the most
traction so be lazy be try this simple
stuff first you don't have to
necessarily hack way up here we're going
to show you sort of a number of
scenarios then we'll come back and sort
of wrap it up at the end now whenever
you see a breach there's always a
three-letter group who does the hack
right it's apt what is the a stand for
an apt advance the P stands for I've
always wanted to do that and the T is of
course threat right when time and time
again and you know every single breach
its the apt but if you've ever paid
attention to a lot of the hacks VA isn't
necessarily a thing the P is barely
there in the course they might be a
little bit of a threat the key scenario
here Equifax now they were breached the
vulnerability was released in March they
were breached in May that is two months
with off-the-shelf exploit code off the
shelf after two months is that very a
right I mean it's off the shelf it's
like oh I'm super advanced you know what
I did
I googled for the exploit right and two
months is that very persistent like how
much vacation time do we get here in the
US a couple of weeks like the to two
months that's absolutely a crazy town
and we see this time and time again
where these simple these off-the-shelf
of vulnerabilities that have been
sitting around for a long time are what
ultimately is going to end up leading to
the breach or leading to us get the
compromise in our pen test or our red
team Derek's gonna talk you through now
a real sort of simple way to do a
fishing so what's one of the first
things you need if you want to send a
fishing
campaign to a target email a domain
right so you need a domain because you
have to you know communicate on the
Internet right and but so how many
people run some kind of email gateway or
mail filter I expect everyone to raise
their hands right because even if you're
using cloud email providers you know
they're trying to prevent spam and
malicious you know domains there and
they do that through what categorization
reputation right so it turns out it's
actually really easy to get past
categorization and reputation type stuff
what you do is you go to a website and
find a previously expired domain and
that's already categorized and then you
use that that's not very sophisticated
expired domains dotnet doesn't take a
lot of skill to go create an account and
use that right so I mean you could
create a domain right and be like you
know q9x 3 7 comm and try and get that
categorized or you can actually search
for your term and say I'd like a domain
with some kind of message in there and
just pick one and then pretty much
you've bypassed those categorizations
this also works for command and control
traffic I mean how many people use
something like a Bluecoat that you block
on categorization right
yeah just pretty much out of the gate on
pentest now I don't create domains I
just go find one that somebody else
created and they forgot about it and it
was already categorized and then that
works this is super advanced stuff
just take a quick step back to add more
to that now the reason why the messages
thing is great now we you know use annex
but you're using expired domains it's
kind of cool because it's sort of like a
zombie website someone's hopes and
dreams and building this giant business
has now died and we're resurrected that
to eat the brains of other end users
yeah and the great reason I just thought
yeah the great reason why messages are
so fantastic or message somewhere in the
title is attachments now we tell end
users time and time again don't click on
blank and email fill in that blank links
attachments anything a couple people
look confused like I click on everything
it's fantastic yeah we tell people time
and time again don't click on things in
email we also tell our end users if you
have something sensitive to send you
secure email how many of you have use
any sort of secure email ever I expect
to see a lot more hands but okay
what is in 100% of those secure emails
links or attachments so we tell an end
users okay folks don't click on anything
an email unless it looks really
important and users are like got it I'm
just gonna click on everything to make
it easy right and this is why it ends up
being so super effective
another very sort of a simple approach
actually Derek and I were working on
this together
we had an Excel Excel macro in trying to
embed a some a cobalt strike agent into
the Excel macro we pasted it into the
Excel macro and attempted to save it to
disk and Defenders like nope not going
to let you do it little warning pops up
it's like this is clearly a bad Excel
document so I'm like oh well time to
start reversing Windows Defender which
sucks and we're trying to play like the
high/low game like the top half of this
macro causing the problem is it is at
the bottom half of the macro and then
I'm like you know what
let's go back to the base of tenant of
this talk let's be lazy
so instead copy and pasted the entire
macro pasted it into cell a12 and turned
the font white and then when the Excel
document open we said hey just run
whatever is in a12 now I've had people
after the talk they're like how did you
know to use a 12 did you reverse
engineer it I'm like I so badly want to
say yes but it was like there was
closest to my mouse so I just ended up
pasting it there right so we paste it
there you turn the font whites of the
end-user can't see it save it and
defenders like Oh fair enough looks good
carry on and that worked for a number of
months so again try this simple stuff
because that's often to be the best
bypass so I'm gonna ask another question
how many of you use some kind of EDR
solution some kind of next-generation
apt prevention blinky box yeah it's the
the latest greatest type thing I'm not
saying they don't do something good but
there's still quite a few issues so the
next slide is the super advanced way
that I got past one of these you know
next generation I a PT blinky boxes does
anybody want to guess what I did before
I used n cat like it on the machine that
I was on you know I wanted to reverse
shell from it I went to the N map
website downloaded the binary off their
website and shoveled a reverse shell and
it worked that they're the EDR solution
thought that was right how many of you
think that that's a good idea
like maybe they should have found that I
do I I don't think a net cat reverse
shell is something that next-generation
AI shouldn't find
they say them too loud have to hold it
down lower my bad dude so John has to
come and be my handler thank you John
yeah John's the sound man so Specter and
Mel town you guys how many of you have
heard of Spectre and meltdown keep your
hands up if you totally understand it
all right like one or two hands
fantastic
I suspect - hood meltdown we're an
attack against the processor and their
branch prediction really awesome stuff
like you would execute multiple paths at
the same time and they would have
figured out what your branch would
actually needed to take it would like go
back and collapse multiple universes
together there's like wormholes involved
and dead kittens and like the souls of
virgins like weird stuff happened inside
the processor so anyways where this
vulnerability came out I had clients
come to me like Tim what should we do
about specter and meltdown and this was
like the next day I mean what should we
do and I'm like oh you should change
your password policy and they're looking
at me too like Tim do you understand
Spectre am outside I'm like not not I'm
not really I mean I do I understand how
the execute how it actually works and
the practical implications of it but the
bad password and they're like we went
back and forth a few times I'm like look
you're focusing on the wrong risk right
now how many of you have ever worked the
helpdesk after a holiday yeah he does
he's just like yeah I did
hey what was the phone call that you get
like a hundred percent of the time on
January 2nd what's my password could I
change my password right and how long
how often are you supposed to change
your passwords every 90 days why when
Moses came down from the mountain he had
a third tablet and on that you know
write it clearly not the case right
actually if you look really closely at
the moon the ancient aliens carved into
it change your passwords every night no
the reason is because in the 70s yes the
70s
I'm gonna ask this question I'm gonna
feel old how many of you never saw the
1970s that are still in this room oh
gosh does your mom drive you here how
did ya so in the 70s it took 90 days to
crack a password these days we have
password cracking rigs that can get
billions with it they're sorry trillions
with the T password attempts per second
we have passed the hash we have mimicked
cats we have social engineering we have
breached passwords in brass word reuse
and this 90-day thing of course ends up
working against us now if you've ever
done any sort of pen testing we as the
attackers note the password that will
work this month because the end users
they get tired of calling the helpdesk
on January 2nd and they feel bad and
they look out the window door like man
if only I could look out the window and
realize what my password is and there's
like snow on the ground and then 90 days
later when they call the helpdesk again
you know there's there's flowers and
ninety days later it's in Texas so
people are like dying in the streets so
people use them that season and year so
we had a situation where literally this
gets us in with single-factor on the VPN
so the specter in meltdown this is not
the biggest threat it's important but
you have to properly prioritize don't go
spending all of your resources trying to
fix this when you can get in from the
external on a single factor VPN using
fall 2017 this was me and Derek we're
doing some work together we got
absolutely destroyed and I'm like after
that week I was like there's anybody
need a sales engineer because I'm in the
long wrong line of work
so Derek texted me he's like yeah I told
he got in with fall 2017 I'm like cool
cookies in a presentation he's like
happily lol right cool
so playing off the bad password thing
there's a number of ways that you can
take advantage of bad passwords to get
into an organization so how many of you
are still using an office web app server
in your in publicly on the internet it's
okay you don't have to raise your hands
but if you do I thank you because you've
made my job a whole lot easier so I have
a co-worker who wrote a tool that you
can essentially point-and-click at the
Ola server and take this tool called a
mail sniper and take advantage of bad
passwords now you might be thinking wow
just using someone else's tool tool and
pointing and clicking at you know it's
infrastructure you don't that's not what
hackers do that's what script kiddies do
yeah I mean I think that you should you
know take the time to understand what
the code is doing but a lot of the heavy
lifting is already done
and a lot of cases for you to take
advantage of these kinds of
misconfigurations and we still see all
the time on penetration tests someone
using really bad passwords in fact when
I get into an organization and I see
that there's like a 14 character
password policy there's a little part of
me inside that starts crying because I
know that it's going to be a lot harder
but the point of this is is that if you
if there are tools already out there and
and this is just one example there's
another one by Trustwave called I think
password spray or something like that
where you can just point the tool and
click and you can even do this as a
defender to see if you you know have
users who are choosing bad passwords oh
yeah this one's kind of fun alright so
going back to that sort of a simple sort
of a hacky thing well I guess not really
going back staying with the theme of the
entire talk I so had a situation a
friend of mine in 2012 this January 2012
this actually happened the previous
month but he wrote a blog post went to
Amazon bought a webcam and did some
reverse engineering the firmware how
many of you have ever done
first engineer to firmware it's actually
surprisingly simple with tools like bin
walk now in 2012 bin walk was not quite
as full featured but bin walk does he we
give it an arbitrary blob and it will
look inside of that file for headers and
in this case with the firmware what bin
walk did is it found three different
headers and what we had to do that what
he did is we had to chop it up to get
those three portions of the file now the
new versions of bin walk will actually
do all of the extraction for you really
really really simple but back then we
had to chop it up so he chops up this
form we're into three pieces and looks
at the third piece in the third piece he
sees what looks like a Linux file system
in there there's a directory called
server looks inside a servant is another
directory called CGI bin inside of CGI
bin is another directory called a nanny
guess what a non e stands for anonymous
right so it's anonymous access so within
what he does is he grabs his browser
browses to his web cam slash CGI bin
slash a non e /m jpg that's CGI and he
his authorization bypass okay so he's
got full access to uh to the camera this
is whoops there's a bad words and I
should edit this differently this is
straight from his blog post it's for
science there's so really simple so I'm
like you know what if this dude can do
that so can I so I'm like you know what
I'm just gonna juice click like
literally hack by numbers so I buy I go
to Amazon spend 45 bucks on another web
camera use bin walk to do the same types
of extraction different piece of
hardware very similar type process again
find a Linux file system mount a Linux
file system where's one of the first
places we should look at see password
right now one of the really cool things
with these sort of older devices it's
like going
back in time and hacking all of the nice
defenses that we have all gone so
typically in a your typical Linux system
Etsy password has your user account
information and the passwords are in
like Etsy shadow now with this this olds
this old-school new device the
credentials are in Etsy password but
unfortunately they're encrypted using
this really high-tech encryption called
base64 yeah so basics t4 is an encoding
mechanism so you can reverse that
country encoding and get the clear text
credentials oh my god this is cool so I
look in the web interface and I look in
etsy password I look at Etsy password
the first user is admin in the web
interface also a user admin an Etsy
password viewer in the admin interface
viewer an Etsy password factory test
factory test is not in the admin
interface on the website I'm like huh
well this is interesting so I log into
the device and may or may not have
logged into a bunch of devices in
non-extradition countries just a joke
but now we have authentication bypass
with a back door account super simple
literally followed the directions of
somebody else found this vulnerability
ended up contacting the manufacturer now
this was before the days of bug bounties
so you couldn't be like hey pay me or
else because back in those days we had a
technical term for that it's called
extortion so we had to like do you
compensate for exclusive disclosure of
security vulnerabilities in your
products that may have impact your brand
and reputation blah blah blah blah and
they ended up paying me like three or
four thousand dollars for about a minute
27 seconds worth of work I will never
make that much money that quickly again
I was hoping last week for 1.6 billion
dollars didn't work out but literally it
was following the steps of somebody else
you don't have to necessarily go out and
try to create the brand
newest thing try things that other
people have used it is credibly
incredibly effective one of my other
sort of a favorite bugs is a Cisco flaw
this is Cisco flaws probably about eight
years old earned by now
so with this Lascaux flaw you could log
into a Cisco device you could give it an
SSH private key literally any SSH
private key in fact you all you had to
have is a file that said it was a key
it's like the Cisco device would be like
hey you got a private key bro I do you
want to see it now you're fair enough
you got it and I was thinking I'm like
we ended up talking to the guy who found
the vulnerability I'm like how did you
find this like how did you virtualize
the Cisco device and hook up gdb and
reverse engineer this he's like don't
tell anybody but what I did is he
accidentally over wrote his private key
with his public key and he was still
able to login to a bunch of the Cisco
devices so that was his high tech sort
of mechanism for finding that and he
would think issues like that wouldn't
happen so you would think that that
doesn't happen anymore right
so how many of you have appliances in
your network like some kind of appliance
that you get right and what does that
appliance generally use underneath the
hood in terms of an operating system
Linux Yeah right
so about two weeks ago I saw this
vulnerability come through a Twitter
feed and thought man this is really
great for our talk right so it turns out
now this isn't open SSH this is live SSH
right so it's you have to use this in
terms of making your own implementation
of SSH on your appliance and so
essentially the way it works is you send
if you if you try and authenticate with
SSH you send an authentication request
to the server and it sends back you know
success right well it turns out if you
just send a success message out of the
gate it just lets you in
so and this was two weeks ago it's uh
what CBE 2018 ten 933 yeah so this is
still happening and I think I saw that
on showed and there are about 3,500
devices facing the internet that this
affected another one of my sort of
favorite bugs here how many of you have
children how many of you have children
that like ice cream I I see more hands
than the first time like I don't have
any kids but if I yet they all like ice
cream
that was weird anyway so this is I call
this can I have some ice cream dad so
this vulnerability if you ask the sequel
server enough times it's like fair
enough you're in it's like you know your
kid comes in a series like dad can I
have some ice cream not till after
dinner dad can I have some ice cream
no dad can have some ice cream no dad
cares some ice cream no can I some ice
cream go ask your mother and then I get
about you know 37 seconds to reprieve
mom said ask you again you're like fine
go have the bloody ice cream that's this
vulnerability okay can i authenticate
now bad credentials bad credentials bad
credentials bad credentials are fine
already
just have it also call it the other
soccer trophy a vulnerability you know
you tried real hard you should be
allowed and I don't want to hurt your
feelings if I don't let you in your
self-esteem is going to be squashed
so here's access to the database server
the vulnerability was one in 256 tries
it would just randomly let you in now
the story I heard but behind how this
was found is somebody was using a
vulnerability scanner the vulnerability
scanner said that there's a default
credential for this my sequel server
default credential allows us access so
that the gentleman went back to verify
does this default credential actually
let me in and he tries it and it fails
it tries it again and it fails and again
and he fails and then he writes a script
to try over and over again he like
literally rage script this thing it's
like no no
yes he's like what what though what the
hell just happened and then found this
sort of like lame-o type of
vulnerability so sort of wrapping this
up
you never know too much right like none
of these none of these concepts
none of these techniques none of these
vulnerabilities are that complex but we
see these vulnerabilities time and time
again and they're allowing us into the
organization we're the good guys but
it's also allowing the bad guys into the
organization and when you're trying to
identify these vulnerabilities when
you're trying to do your hacks or your
defenses try some of the simple things
first sort of related to that ask some
of the new people around you now I am
sort of a I consider myself senior right
like I have my own company but it's kind
of hard sometimes to go and ask a new a
person like what are your thoughts on
this right you have to sort of lay
yourself out there and don't go with
like well here's what I know how to do
blah blah blah blah blah and qualify it
and then ask the question cuz you're
already setting them up for failure just
come a time humbly it's like I got
nothing what you got and it gives them
an opportunity to share with you and
they're gonna come back with some brand
new type ideas like literally that last
one with the Lib SSH I might have been
stucked on that ask like a new person's
like what did you try it a thousand
times
hmm no but maybe we should right so use
those new people around you ask them
there's only so many times that new
person is going to come to you and ask
you for help if every single time they
ask for help you squash them and you
tell them it's like well here's a better
way to do that it gets tiring we've
probably all been there right anybody
ever been in that situation we're here
to join your guy and you are excited we
keep talking how we want passionate
people in in the industry but time and
time again we like to squash those
people so talk to the new people get an
outside perspective it's super valuable
to get the input from somebody else
because they're gonna have a different
viewpoints on some of that so learn from
it some of the news now one of the pen
testing courses that I teach with sans
has this challenge
this challenge is literally my favorite
CTF challenge of all time now let's
let's take a step back let's sort of
think of this like a noob what types of
characters do we see here what types of
characters
I hear upper case what else we got
lower case upper case lower case numbers
in an equal sign now there's probably
some of you that sort of went to the
next level and said base64 take the baby
steps it'll only take you a couple extra
seconds but it's happening medium number
of times where I'm like I'm so smart I'm
gonna jump up here and I missed that
baby step base64 and base 30 to look
very similar now this happens to be
base64 but take that baby step so what
we can do to sort of decode this is we
can use my favorite decoder burp so I've
got burp here right and we got my base64
and I can simply just say decode as
base64 now we see these other characters
right and it's this next set of
characters what types of characters do
we see alphanumeric what about more
specifically hex right we got 0 through
9 a through F right so we got the hex so
again once again we can do the decoding
now we end up with this and this is the
point where I giggle I sit in front of
the classroom and I sort of laugh
because I can see this moment coming and
you'll have this table of like there's 5
people on the team and 4 of them are
super smart and one of them's relatively
new and the four people are like all
gather around and they stand around in
computers and if you watch it there's a
lot of pointing like huh and then
rubbing the head and thinking and
wandered around and there's one person
by themselves and they're stuck now this
is a
third question in level 1 on a day six a
series of challenges level one third
questions supposed to be really easy and
we see these advanced people they look
off to the right they're like oh you
know what this is this is shellcode and
they start reverse engineering it so
they open up I does it doesn't work in
IE let's try hopper let's try red air oh
wait maybe it's armed
maybe it's MIPS maybe it's encrypted
shellcode and they do all this sort of
like craziness and you can see them like
working there at working like crazy
again
level one and then you see the purp the
person kind of off by themselves and all
of a sudden you they don't like they put
their hands in the air and they call
everybody else over and the new person
is looking as the answer and what
happened is all the advanced people see
this and they forget where they came
from they go to that next level to go to
the shellcode they go to like sort of
weird kind of encryption and do some
additional reverse engineering and
instead what the new person did is well
you know what
burp worked the first two times let's
try to get and they literally just keep
on clicking and when you get to the last
one it's like oh look hey more hex right
and we do the additional sort of
decoding here of ascii hex and then we
end up with a rickroll but this is a
sort of a fun challenge but it's it sort
of reinforces that point of try some of
the simple stuff now this is an example
for a CTF but I've seen this same sort
of encryption with a web app and a
mobile application where they encrypted
the data by encoding it multiple times
in different ways and literally just
walking through this very simple thing
ultimately led to the compromise of that
app
so sort of related to that you know go
out and teach others right like our
presentation well is we like to think
we're awesome it was pretty simple right
there the hacks that you saw we're
pretty straightforward come back next
year and you do your presentation do a
presentation at your local event because
I can guarantee you you you have some
sort of knowledge that we don't have and
the vast majority the people in the room
have and probably you even have some
knowledge that nobody in the room has
you could come back and explain your
perspective on something new
my favorite is is Mike last year at
Derby con did an exploitation 101 these
are techniques that have been around for
decades plural but he came back and did
this packed house here's how we do some
exploitation and people ended up coming
up to Mike afterwards say thank you for
doing that presentation that kind of
whispered because they were sort of
ashamed to not know and ashamed had not
asked so allow people to ask you and be
willing to share some of that knowledge
and it could literally be an existing
technique an existing way but put your
spin on it and tell your story now to be
honest your first presentation is
probably gonna suck right nobody there
first time when they were learning how
to walk like jumped up when their one
years old you're like I got this bro you
want a race there was a lot of falling
on your face my first talk was supposed
to be 60 minutes I finished it in
thirteen and a half minutes I had
diarrhea of the mouth and I couldn't
stop I kept going faster and faster my
brain is like you going way too fast you
know how we should fix it go even faster
and it was it was horrific and the first
time it's it's probably gonna be bad but
that second time you're like you know
what I kind of got this I feel a bit
more comfortable and that third time is
gonna be easier and that fourth time and
that fifth time it's going to get easier
and easier and if you really have a
terrifying fear of being up in front
I mean first off you can think of what
we did you're like you could told you
better than we did
but you could also write blog posts
share some of that knowledge again you
don't have to impress the wizards do
something in show put your spin on it
show some of your perspective come back
and share with the community we all come
here we like to share cool ideals and
some of those concepts we have a really
cool group in Dallas Austin has a
similar group where are you supposed to
come to the group and you're supposed to
talk if you come austin forces you you
have to give a 5 minute talk to even
show up and it can be whatever the heck
you want super simple and oftentimes it
is but I would encourage you share even
if it is relatively simply coming and if
you live in an area where you don't have
a group already established start one
that's what I did in my area is there
anyone here from Virginia oh wait yeah I
know him so I started a meet-up in the
Tidewater area because there wasn't one
and now it's so on it's all like third
year and I think we have like 300
members and basically we just go to a
bar and have a couple of beers and talk
about InfoSec it's completely open you
can not be an InfoSec you can just come
and hang out and it's really welcoming
environment it's a city SEC style meetup
you can go find them on reddit and so
just start one you'd be surprised how
many people in your you know in your
community would love to come and do that
alright so we get ready to wrap up here
really quick I just want to add one more
quick thing I got some shirts that I
want to give out if you guys want some
shirts they say make derp hacky HAC HAC
if you're not familiar with this story
there was a 16 year old kid in Australia
in Melbourne ended up hacking Apple and
they came and they searched his computer
and on his desktop was a directory
called hacky hack hack and it had all of
the Apple stuff so if you want a shirt
make to her hacky hack hack I'll have
some those up front my only request is
we've got some paper adjectives mailing
list not gonna spam you but will tell
you hey we got any sort of upcoming
webcasts not gonna try to sell you
anything it's hey you want to get some
free content we'd be more than happy to
give it to you okay and again no
marketing crap because I don't
I don't have the time for that so we
have a QR code on your iOS phone for
some reason - only shows my Twitter
address if you're on Android a shows
both read Steve calm slash dumb early is
the slides and here's our contact
information I thank you so much for
attending and hopefully we'll see you
around the conference we've got some
shirts of Brett
[Music]