[Music]
all right so here we go this is a
reprise from a talk from last year
whereby I'll tell you who I am
with who I am I command cuz that's a
nice way to start in it with in the ICU
domain I am JM the group's that I belong
to I belong to the everyone group
everyone does right within the JM Corp
domain I belong to the independent
consultant group that is optional but
for me enabled by default within the
SANS Institute domain I belong to the
principle instructor group that is
optional but it's an optional group
disabled by default that's a tough one
within the author domain I'm a member of
the Network forensics group that is also
an optional group
I think strand J strange J has may have
read in that group but then if I say Who
am I with Prive well let's see the SE
debug privilege which I have renamed the
description to in my own way I that for
me is disabled I don't have the ability
to understand what relic did just now
that's disabled for me stun hacking
privilege don't have that neither not
here to impress you with my hacks or
skills the rocket surgery privilege
that's a new one I just invented to
perform impossible feats I can't do that
but I do have some privet where the C
packets privileged I can read all your
packets and acts for me that is enabled
let's see the bad guys privilege for me
that is enabled I can hear glass windows
break I got a year's alright and finally
the blue team privilege for me that is
definitely enabled I know how to hunt
the bad guys and that's what this is
about
speaking of Who am I Equifax anybody
here from Equifax perk up your ears yes
still Equifax I'm not gonna stop talking
about this a little bit ago yesterday I
caught a
from Tim medine and Derrick banks all
about hacking dumb early and they
started out talking about the advanced
persistent threat with a P being
persistent right and the Equifax breach
what was persistence pop another web
shell they popped no fewer than 30 web
shells against Equifax that was how they
did persistence lose a web shell pop
another one and every single time they
popped a web show you know the very
first command was a ran Who am I who
runs Who am I who needs to know who they
are on a system Steve secretary logs in
Steve secretary need to know who he is
I don't think so
who runs Who am I who doesn't know their
login context sis admins and bad guys
that's it
so if all a guy does all the person does
is merely turn on event logging on a
vent windows event do the same thing in
Linux and UNIX auditing the use of
commands event 46 88 here is event 46 88
logging Who am I done this why then
Equifax might not not have to stand in
front of Congress that's the whole pipe
to call Congress PowerShell script right
if all they done that was that it's not
rocket surgery it's so not rocket
surgery turn that on somebody says Who
am I on an Internet facing web server
wouldn't you like to know it's not
rocket surgery all right so what's all
this then evil evil is running amok here
in the hotel in Deadwood okay no not
really
all of this is simulated evil running
amok on the Black Hills information sack
lab network although probably actually
really on the deadwood hotel network
right last year some Yahoo broke into a
room began pivoting through the doors to
the adjoining rooms crashing through the
doors noisy as hell and of course we see
this who uses the side door anyhow so
last year I ran that to ground and a few
minutes lateral movement totally easy to
see if you don't believe me
you go check out my talk from last year
it's on the YouTube channel at Wild West
hacking fast worth look all right so
this year they got smarter way smarter
well with a hat tip to Tim Madine and
Derek Derek banks they're still hacking
dumb early as we're gonna see they got
smarter they just slid notices under
every door in the hotel that simply said
when you're ready to check out don't
dial eight zero to check out or zero
whatever it might be
as that extension doesn't currently work
instead dial extension three one four
one and be sure to provide all your
payment details there sorry for any
inconvenience we hope you had a nice day
management is that gonna work get ready
to check out of your hotel you're gonna
look at that notice under the door you
gonna check out by down through 141 yeah
you give them all your credit card
details so you can check out that way
yeah that'd work
they thought it would work and it did as
usual but I watch them do it I'm gonna
show you how you can to imagine their
surprise when I crashed their room party
at room 3141 while they were still
harvesting payment credentials oops
alright so what I'm gonna be doing here
the same as last year all the analysis
is going to be done quick and dirty all
right
using nothing more than how you could
easily instrument your network flow data
transaction data some correlated
transactions as well a lot of traffic
analysis going on using nothing more
than snort bro which has now been
renamed to Zeke with default configs
default rules default scripts for the
most part we're a deviated from the
default that you could get on security
onion yeh Doug banks I'm sorry Doug
Burke mostly just default stuff I'm
gonna be using command line inspection
which is why I got to be down here
pointing out what's going on in the
command lines if they're commands you're
unfamiliar with on a linux box using
mostly bro but it's nothing that can't
be scripted for basically instant
real-time alerting because you got to be
able to see this stuff I limited myself
on purpose no full content inspection
I'm not a
that you get full pcap with all the
content in the world to be able to find
the evil nothing but traffic analysis
from flow data and metadata that bro can
get you know session reconstructions
know TCP streams nothing a little bit of
layer 7 content not much but I'll point
out where I've deviated from what you
can get without full content cool well
in this years for a exploiting l
eliminar and w pad my general
methodology for this I'm gonna start out
with some initial recon bad guys do it
you should - blue team blue team well
blue team I'm blue team looking at when
does stuff start and what kinds of
things are the different stations doing
who's who on the network
what kind of protocols are involved what
kind of ports are involved anything
unusual going on looking at that
anomalous behavior that unusual stuff
and trying to figure out who's evil who
are they being evil to because you know
if they're evil are gonna be evil to
somebody else did the evil propagate
hold on did you guys on the other side
of the wall I'll keep it down please
trying to talk over the conference here
so if they're being able to somebody
else who are they being able to is evil
propagating if so how so
right and some timeline analysis finally
putting all of the events of interest
into a line of events and some context
right correlating those events if you
don't understand the sequence of those
events you're never going to solve it so
that that will be how we end so the
first thing I'm gonna do is start my
timeline get my timeline boundaries I
got my Deadwood Hotel pcap now I know
that's not real
I got law enforcement in the room I did
not illegally wiretap this network this
is all simulated on the Black Hills
Network alright but I run cap infos on
it and get some information out of it
it's useful information first packet
last packet now I got the balance for my
time line of activities that I'm gonna
inspect all right then
I process my pcap again no full content
I'm only getting what I would get if I
was running snort and bro in real time
off the packets flowing through not
capturing full packet capture on every
cat
on every packet so I run snort alerting
in full reading in my pcap now using as
my snort config file snort reading Kampf
again I said I would tell you where I
modified from from stock configurations
basically all I did was tell snort don't
have any comment any concept of what's
inside and outside no home net external
net it's all the same it's Annie Annie
in any direction that way I'm going to
be able to see the lateral movement
because I'm not considering this is
inside that's outside right that's the
only mod imade so look at everything in
either direction no matter where you see
it and then bro Deadwood Hotel pcap now
I did invoke a local bro config here
where I just turned on a couple of stock
features that aren't turned on in order
to be able to see a little bit more
stuff so I run snort and run bro first
thing I do is say how BIG's my calling
log how many connections roughly thirty
seven thousand connections in this one
day in Deadwood cool alright so this
time last year last year I didn't bring
snort into it until after I'd done a
little bit of traffic analysis this time
I'm going to start out with snort see
what's the North thinks it sees so I
read in with snort I'm gonna grep for in
my alert file I'm dropping out of my
alert file snort a the snorts snout if
you ever wonder in your snort alerts
what bracket stars to our bracket is
that's ASCII art for snort II the pig's
snout that's his little nostrils in his
snout right there suitable for grepping
so I can look at just the alerts I'm
gonna sort them out unique if I'm with a
count that gives me the count of how
many of each unique alert and I'm gonna
sort them in numeric order in reverse
order right now last year I talked all
about looking at the long tail looking
at the least frequent events a lot of my
junior analysts be starting to look at
oh this is a big thing there's 44 of
these we need to go immediately now if
it's common I'm less interested it's
uncommon I'm more interested and now
this oh Java we got to dig down on that
you know what the ones I want to see I
want to see these uncommon uncommon
snort alerts but talking about some
stuff that is of interest to me LLM a
narc
my response to w pad NetBIOS name
service query response to w pad and /
port 80 probably auto proxy request of a
w pad app now what are these l eliminar
and duck and w pad things I'll get into
that in a second so as usual we're
turning our attention to the long tail
if you graph this out that's the few
things in the long tail right this time
I'm going to be looking specifically at
LM in R and W pad but let's take a
little bit of a closer look at snore T
the pigs long tail here I've given you
three of these alerts from these three
events right these three events here's
three of those alerts an example of each
of the three of those and what do we see
well we see in every instance we got
10.22 10 out to 33 - 33 202 henceforth
known as 202 talking to 10.2 33 - 33 201
hence force known as 201 they are almost
certainly on the same network since they
are adjacent IP addresses and we can see
they're talking on port 80 that's why
the win HTTP auto proxy request we also
see there's some NetBIOS name service
conversation between them that snort
didn't like and there's some port 53 55
LLM in our conversation between them
that snort thought was evil
what other ports are in play this is the
next thing I'm going to do is go
straight to some traffic analysis say
what ports are in playing who's
listening now I'm using proton bro data
exclusively but it cat out that
connection log and I'm going to use bro
cut to look for the responding port
meaning any port that responded to a
connection I'm going to sort those out
unique a fine with a count sort of again
in reverse order numerically and I get
these two columns the column on the on
the left is how many connections were
seeing successfully connecting to the
port which is the column on the right
now last year I drove down on port 5,000
because that stands out doesn't it long
tail analysis in Reverse fifteen
thousand connections successfully to
port 5000 you guys all know your port
numbers eighty HTTP 443 HTTP 445 SMB
what's port 5,000
it's evil if you don't know what it is
chances are it's evil right
so I drilled down on that last year I
also was looking at 40 to 49 666 which
is our PC and Windows we looked at those
and if I look I do another cat of the
con log this time I'm looking for the
originating host the responding host in
the end the responding port grepping out
just for port 5000 to see who all's
connecting to whom on port 5000 it's all
just these two it's just two oh two
connecting to 201 all of it for that
port 5000 traffic right so this year
we're gonna start looking at a different
port what sport 3141 well you saw my
preview right that's evil too right
that's evil too now we'll get back to
LLM in our on port 53 55 but if I do the
same thing looking for who's connecting
to whom encore 31 41 it's all of it all
of it again - OH - connected to 201
it's 201 evil what do you think
take your guess is 201 evil - and one's
evil should it be listening on port 5000
and port 31 41 no it's 202 evil should
it be connecting to its friend on those
ports clearly not so we got two bad
actors talking on port 5000 so let's
look at these this time looking at Mike
on log looking now at timestamps from
the originating host as responding
amounts to the responding port also now
looking at the number of bytes from the
originating host number of bytes from
their spawning host and again gripping
for port 5000 and what do I see any
periodicity there every five seconds -
OH - connects to 201 and every five
seconds - OH - sends a little bit of
data to a one since the exact sum name
same number of bytes in response is this
classic beacon Basie - activity it took
me longer to get to this slide then it
took me to see the c2
right so there we have it but they're
definitely both evil little deeper dive
this is a little bit from last year
turns out that bro decided whatever was
on 5,000 is HTTP I know this because if
I go look in the HTTP log looking at the
responding port and the URI that is
fetched again grepping for port 5,000
sorting unique fine counting I can see
this number of counts of connections to
this port for these following URIs so
it's pretty evenly distributed across a
couple of suspicious Uniform Resource
identifier x' then i'll go one step
further and say hey what was the status
code on those and i see every single
time it tried to get one of those it had
a 200 ok web server says this is fine
so let's get a little bit deeper i add
to that now I've got my responding port
the URI requested the method by which it
was requested in HTTP the the body
length from the request and the body
length from the response and what we
notice is almost all of these spread out
across these three gets no data sent
very little data comes back in fact it
ends up being just about an empty body
but a couple of times we see posts of
some data no response but one time we
see a get with a whole bunch of data
that those beacons hit a target did
mommy answer the phone
mommy answered the phone and said - OH -
here's your new evil so we know there's
some evil going on so clearly 2 + 2 @ 2
or 2 + 2 or 1 or evil the question is
how they get that way it's not a good
question you won't ask how they end up
like that well it turns out they're
talking on poor 3144 as well we saw this
so I'm going to do the same sort of
invocation where I'm going to look at
the timestamp and this is back out of
the con log we're looking at the
timestamp originating host responding
host responding port then the
originating bytes are responding bytes
dropping out just the port of interest
here and now I'm just going to give the
head and then later on a give the tail
and we can see this starts with a bird
Just In Time of connections from 202 to
201 with very static sizes of requests
and response stimulus and response on
that port but as you look on when we go
to the tail instead of just the head on
this we see that towards the end the
periodicity of these connections is
quite randomized as is the number of
bytes sent and the number of bytes
received so what happened what happened
over the span of time on port 31 41 well
last year I discovered that port 5,000
that was HTTP well rather bro determine
that for me it said HTTP is what's on
port 5,000 so I'm thinking myself let's
look in HTTP log and say hey HTTP log
how many different response ports are
there serving up HTTP that you know of
well there's our port 5,000 there's our
port 80 but huh
ding-ding-ding-ding-ding bro auto
detected that whatever's going on on
port 31 41 is also HTTP which I can read
with my eyeballs can you sure enough why
not right so I say hey HTTP log why
don't you show me all the responding
ports so I can grep on it and all the
URI is grepping for that 31 41 sort of
unique if I'm counterman show me and
what I see is a whole bunch of a whole
bunch of connection attempts - 31 41 for
these following you our eyes now why is
202 sending get requests presumably -
201 for things like wwl comm is 201
acting as a proxy on port 31 41 could it
be could it be well let's ask I just hit
use the exact same command this time I
include the bro field out of the HTTP
log of proxied and see what it says and
sure enough
sure enough it's pretty clear at this
point - a1 is now acting as a web proxy
for 202 for all of 202 s web surfing
needs could that be bad
yeah that could be bad so why are they
so evil how did they get that way so it
seems like 202 is a client of two of
one's evil what we saw so far to
summarize 202 is beaconing to 201 over
port 5,000 TCP to fetch the evil with c2
and evil fetchin also 202 is proxying
all of its web traffic through 201 on
poor 3141 now again it took me more time
to get to this slide than it would have
taken me to see that with the commands
that you saw on screen so far because
bro is watching so here's my theory of
the case I think 201 was evil first
anyone agree with me think 201 was evil
first just one person seriously are we
paying attention we in here who thinks
201 was evil first who thinks 202 is
evil first all right I agree with you
right so last year we actually explored
running patient zero to ground I died
under ground what the initial compromise
was and how it happened this year we're
gonna look at evil propagating 202
became evil after 201 did how'd it come
about I want to know so let's look at
link-local multicast name resolution
that's our LLM and our and the web proxy
auto detection protocol W pad let's look
at these so a bit of a primer if you're
unfamiliar with these two protocols host
based proxy configs for your endpoints
can be done a number of different ways
you can hard code the proxy config for
your web client right into the right
into the system or you can have them
Auto discover what their proxy
configuration ought to be and that's
what W pad is for does this through the
distribution what we call pack files
these proxy Auto configuration files
that a host will download and it will
tell them where the proxy isn't how to
use it now these are typically
downloaded via a pointer to their
location and that can be done in a
number of ways usually it's done via a
name resolution of the host W pad in the
local domain so typically is going to
start out with a DNS query for W pad
within the local domain something like W
pad whatever the local domain is now
that DNS query fails
and your configuration is weak the next
thing is gonna try is NetBIOS name
service to multicast locally a query for
that same name for W pad to figure out
where can it get its pack file if the
NBN s fails next saying if your
configuration is weak that it's likely
gonna try is looking looking using local
link or link local multicast name
resolution ll M&R multicast queries to
the local link asking for hey anybody
named w pad out there anybody named W
pad because I need to know who you are
so I can get my pack file from you can
also be done via DHCP the location of
the pack files can be served up that way
just like we serve up who's the DNS
resolver and so on and so forth with
DHCP and then once the pack file is
located it's gonna tell the endpoint
where is the proxy by hostname and port
what's the commonality of all these ways
of figuring out where the pack file is
it's all UDP all of that the responses
can be spoofed all of that right
so bottom line oh wait wait wait back
there we go there we go
bottom line this is a very bad idea
implemented poorly so what about this
201 and its use of ll M&R next thing I'm
gonna do is look in the con log looking
for the originating host and responding
poor a host and port alright
originating host responding host and
port sorting and unique ax fiying
and then just crapping for for 35:15
sorry 53 55 the LM in our port to see
what I find
now you notice the last bit I'm grepping
out ipv6 I will not be covering ipv6
today although there's a lot of ipv6
going on in here maybe next year that's
your T's or maybe next year will be all
about ipv6 but for the moment I'm
excluding that from view alright and
what do we see what do we see well we
see a whole lot
of LLM and are based stuff but notice
most of it almost all of it is to
multicast almost all of us to multicast
a little bit to what appeared to me to
be a server and so forth but that stands
out a whole bunch of LLM in are between
202 and 201 is that normal should that
be going on I'm guessing probably not
right that's probably bad
so noticing that Snorri complained
specifically about w pad this way now
I'm going to my DNS log now bro treats
all name resolution as it logs all name
resolution activity into the DNS log
whether it's DNS on port 53 whether it's
NBN ass on port 137 whether it's hell
M&R on port 550 355 all goes in the DNS
log which is handy because it's all in
one nice place so I act I asked the DNS
log from bro hey show me the originating
host and the originating port and
responding host the responding port all
of the queries and all the answers again
gripping for the lmn are specifically
not looking at DNS and NB + S and reppin
out all the ipv6 also grepping out
anywhere that the answer is a - which
means the field doesn't exist which
means there was no answer so I'm only
looking at where there was an answer and
I see three distinct instances of 202
being told by 201 on port 53 55 the the
name W pad resolves to me it me I'm that
okay so just to tie the queries and
replies together because I'm here I'm
just looking at the replies specifically
that was the point of gripping out the -
I'm just looking at the replies but I
want to see the queries at tied of the
replies well bro kept the transaction ID
for the queries and replies for me so
now a little bit of a loop over saying
hey for I'm gonna look at the
transaction IDs I get that by saying hey
DNS log showing me all the transaction
IDs again with the same grepping and so
on and so forth
reppin out and now alking just the
transaction ID out I do that and I loop
over each of the transaction IDs doing
another inspection of the DNS log
cutting out again originating host
originating port responding host
responding port transaction ID query and
answer and II grew up out anywhere we're
are you dropping in my transaction ID
and II grepping out my ipv6 and what do
I see there it is transaction ID 44 864
request reply 46 36 request reply 36 107
request reply we can see that sure
enough how's that going - OH -
multicasts the request 201 replies
multicast request 201 replies multicast
request 201 replies 201 is happy to be w
pad for anybody who asks on the local
link via ll M&R is that going to be okay
note under door do not dial 0 for
checkout dial extension 31 41 how are we
gonna get there well first off what
extension do we dial again here we have
it the transaction IDs and everything
lines up alright what's next how about
some timeline info remember I started a
timeline I had a start in an end
probably get some timestamps on this
data to see in my DNS log show me the
timestamp where my originating host and
my originating port and my responding
host responding port and my query and my
answers
grep tout give me LOL M&R searching for
an actual answer to this question to the
w pad question and excluding ipv6 and
there's my answers again with my
timestamps here's my timestamps for
these right so I'm looking in the DNS
log for this can I correlate that
activity into other streams of activity
that happened subsequently to it that's
what bro is for I'm sorry Zeke that's
what Zeke is for now now it's Zeke
that's what Zeke is for alright so my
next query is not to the DNS log my next
query is the HTTP log I say hey HTTP log
can you show me anyway
I saw I want to see the method I want to
see the URI I want to see the status
code I want to see what kind of thing
got responded with and the size of it
gripping for just that w pad dad and
what do I see how about those time
stamps - OH - barks out - multicast hey
who's w pad had 15 hours 29 minutes and
26 seconds and then 202 says - 201 hey
can I get W pad dad on port 80 and it
says 200 okay with a 312 byte file at 15
hours 29 minutes and 27 seconds
how about 32 and 10 seconds how about 31
and 43 seconds within the second the 202
discovers that 201 wants to be W pad it
asks W pad for W pad that successfully
gives a 312 byte that file wouldn't you
just love to see what's in that pack
file wouldn't ya that takes some content
that takes actual layer seven content
from that get it's only 312 bytes though
do you think we can have it what do you
think I know I want it I do so why bro I
mean Zeke here's why here's why I write
a bro script now if you are not coders
and you do not write script that's okay
I'm gonna walk you through this I'm
gonna cat out my new ll M&R w pad
download script all right now first
thing I'm going to do in this script and
this is this is why Zeke this is why
Zeke now I'm gonna mention a little bit
Rita which is Black Hills is free
open-source front-end - doing
correlation based on bro data this could
have got all this for me but why my
command line why am i doing this the
hard way
heck right on the other side of the
curtain hey I hunter is being sold with
a nice GUI to let you point and click
through all the correlation of all this
bro data why am I still some crusty old
geek at the command line with this
here's why I write a script where I
define where LM and r WP
resolution should not come from I set a
global a global array of subnets saying
there shouldn't be any of that going on
here
and then the very next thing I'm gonna
do is dynamically collect anywhere I see
it actually happening and log the event
so I define a new global array of where
it's coming from and on the event that I
see an address replying DNS all right
I'm gonna look and say is the responding
port ll M&R is the responding host up
here in this subnet is the query for the
host W pad if so I'm gonna say that guy
just answered that question and I add it
to that global array for future use I
saw you answering that query and then
guess what
I'm gonna go ahead and log that in the
notice login bro with a nifty little
line that says alert somebody used LOL
lmao' are to resolve that query to some
address for some address and i just
populate it with the bro data that i get
from that particular event from the dns
answering of an address query further on
in my bro script still catting out my
download bro script the remaining part
of it the last 13 lines you saw the
first lines alright this is the top of
it this is the bottom of it that's all I
wrote so when I said I didn't modify bro
much this is all I wrote so the next
stanza in my script if a subsequent
download of a W pad dad occurs
please parse it and log it how many
streams am I now observing I see the
exchange of LL M&R I record the fact
that I saw that exchange successfully
resolving W pad and then I noticed the
subsequent port 80 download of the W pad
dat I noticed that too because I say on
the event bro that you observe an HTTP
entity with data I want you to look at
it and if the responding host is his is
one of those W pad resolvers if that's
in my array that I just built
dynamically if it's one of those
responding port is 80 the host is asking
is W pad the method is get and the URI
it's asking for is W pad dat well then
what
I want you to throw another notice into
the notice log with another alert with
who served what to whom but also with
the DAT file data itself 312 bytes of
data file data preserved for our
inspection and let's see if we caught
that PAC file I now say bro again with
my same P cap using local dot bro but
now I include my nifty script that's
what less than 30 lines of code
including comments comment your code
comment your code you do that and what
do we see now I can look at my notice
log look for the originating host
originating port responding host
responding port looking for the message
in the sub message and what do I see in
here well let's see originating host
responding host originating port
responding port with an alert saying
this guy used lol Minard resolved that
query to that address for that requester
and the very next line I see is this guy
from this port to this guy to this port
apparently got served up 312 bytes of
WPW Pat file got it back via port 80 and
by the way here's all the DAT file data
here's all that dad file data so I
included my script and what did I get
out I can see right there in the dad
file data it's being told hey - OH -
your proxy isn't host by the name of ice
a proxy server and your proxy port is 31
41 well now now what does - OH - Doug
got to do it's got to go out and resolve
who is ice a proxy server it's gonna
have to ask the question who do you
think is gonna answer who do you think
is gonna be any guesses here comes the
punch line
sure enough sure enough we can see 202
says - multicast that parts omitted hey
anybody out there named ice a proxy
server and sure enough we see two a one
says it me it me too I'm also ice a
proxy server MW
I'm eisah proxy server and so you should
send all your web traffic to poor 3141
to me first and I'll send it out for you
right and that's how 201 fully pones 202
is a man-in-the-middle all its web
traffic is flowing through 201 now
hopefully everybody in this room
understands the magnitude and the
gravity of that every single page that
202 requests the request goes out to the
world and the reply comes back and when
the reply comes back it didn't use to
contain evil but by the time 201 got a
hold of it and proxies it back to 202
does it contain evil tailored very
special evil absolutely it does thanks
hello lemon our thank you so very much
handy handy all right so let's look at
our quick and dirty timeline evil in an
instant it's a lot more to run to ground
here obviously there's a whole lot much
a whole lot more going on inside this
traffic but let's look at a partial
timeline of our events of interest
packets start at this date starting and
we got that from cap info the rest of
these timestamps we got from bro and
also from snort I didn't include in here
where the snort alerts fit in but they
correlate nicely 2:02 begins multicast
and queries for the name W pad 2a1
answers a query with it may - o - does
it get successfully for W pad nat from
201 on port 80 which tells it to proxy
through is a proxy server on port 31 41
202 begins multicast and queries for the
name ice ax proxy server to which 201
also answers at me and then begins the
proxying of all of 202 s traffic through
its new evil friend let's look at the
dates on timestamps on that evil man in
the middle in an instant
now it literally oh I'm still on time it
literally took me could have if I wasn't
trying to get every last command-line
invocation right and fumbling around
about and trying to make sure I could
cut and paste all this into a
for Wildlife's hacking fest you could
literally do all this in the amount of
time it took for you to listen to me
talk about it how about that how long
did this go on longer than it would have
taken me to knock on the door room 31 41
and say hey what you guys partying about
what you got going on in there
now last year when I presented this
approach and I was talking about it
before the talk what I was working on
for this talk osmosis points out to me
you can't see me that's not gonna work
I'm too Trixie you can't see me all
right
I'll admit there are some weaknesses in
my approach so let's discuss those
number one you got to be appropriately
and and and prominently instrumented you
got to be instrumented in all the right
places unless you're seeing the traffic
inside the switch between 202 and 201
you're gonna see any of this would you
guys like to see that traffic turn on a
porch band fire up security onion have
it grab the packets fire up bro this is
not rocket surgery it's free for the
price of nothing not nothing nothing at
least for the software it's free but
with lack of visibility into those
lateral movement points lack of
detection of post exploitation in
general we don't see it but that's
what's fixable folks my blue team take
off your blinders open up your eyes and
look it's right there in front of you
even osmosis I see you also exploitation
is hard to see for most of us right that
initial exploitation that caused 201 to
be evil in the first place
probably a client-side attack with some
obfuscated PowerShell or obfuscated
JavaScript or obfuscated something it's
gonna fly right by all of our antivirus
all of our snort signatures we're not
going to see that initial exploitation
of the client something pop Steve
Secretary's browser we're not gonna see
that
live with it except that it's gonna
happen right stage two probably flies by
us too and that's less excusable because
stage 1 stage 1 that initial
exploitation that's not going to contain
all the code necessary for the lateral
movement for the situ for the
cryptography that c2 is going to employ
for all the Trixie stuff that osmosis is
gonna do to me all that functionality
didn't get shoved into a tiny little
buffer with a remote code execution that
didn't happen that RCE made a callback
for the big bollock tools for all the
crypto libraries and all the lateral
movement tools all that came down in a
second stage download now that should be
visible cuz if it contains the crypto
libraries is it itself cryptid should
all be in clear text should all be
visible we should be able to see it but
in 2018 mostly bespoke malware custom
malware not to say zero day that's a
different thing well known exploits but
custom code for the thing that's been
around for a long time the exploit that
popped target was a custom exploit built
just for that campaign using a well
known vulnerability but with a brand new
exploit that had never been seen before
that's why the target attackers were
able to fly below all the antivirus and
all the other detection like everything
else so we may not see that but this
post exploitation stuff it's easy to see
I don't care how you obfuscate your
PowerShell just the fact that two old
ones talking to 202 is enough isn't it
Jule won't ever be talking to 202 like
that that alone is enough to act on
right and I'm not going to be able to
pull apart all the c2 stuff especially
with with osmosis out there I keep
picking on you man but you're going to
be out there using social media for your
c2 how am I going to find the c2 at the
Twitter amongst all the normal Twitter
that's hard it's hard so just give up
now
same with exfil - pretty much the same
if your exfilling
via social media if you're doing all the
bad stuff in the trickiest ways it's
hard to see
but as I just pointed out - and I hope
you understand identifying at least who
the bad actors are on your network that
should be trivial can I read there see -
no do I know what data they exfilled not
necessarily but can I see when it went
from where to where how much and how
often can I see that damn straight
if I'm properly instrumented and that's
where we can win blue team hopefully
we're not all red in here you're not
picking up on my TTP's gonna try and
evade me further in summary lovely latin
statement that translates into in the
land of the blind the one-eyed man is
king you do not have to instrument
everything but at least take one of your
blinders off look some places instrument
where you know this is going to be
happening and also know that it's going
to be happening and that you got an
instrument for it but I got a variation
on that in the domain of the blind the
one-eyed man sees a new domain admin is
it really that is it really just that
easy
I would suggest to you that it is and I
hope you saw me show you how just now so
that's my summary plus summary plus plus
is my shameless plug now it's almost
almost seven years ago wrote as much as
I could fit in a book about how to see
all those fingerprints and footprints
but it was pointed out to me by my dear
friend John strand and my wife thank you
very much that I missed a bunch of stuff
missed a bunch of stuff I did not
include a chapter on DNS for Network
forensics and that I agree borderline
criminal that was a criminal omission I
just got tired of writing that's that's
literally what it was I was four I was a
hundred pages passed passed back and
said I I think I want to be done now can
I be done and didn't contain anything on
bro bro bro now Zeke Zeke Zeke so what
happened was sitting around with my
lovely wife Paola and John and Eric
Estrella
around a table after an even longer at
work and all of a sudden strand and
Paola start coming up with this laundry
list of oh you need to include this and
this and this and this and now
apparently it needs a second volume
including rpms al-alam and our games
Rita Rita we should talk about that
entropy detection we can automate that
that's nice finding entropy and all the
places it doesn't belong like domain
name certificate fields all that kind of
stuff lots of other topics and so I am
Rhian answer a year later with the
support of family and colleagues
renouncing again here still this coming
soon I promise some day to another
bookstore near you this time maybe with
John strand that was the other thing he
promised he would help that's the only
reason why I agreed to this project it
is in the works I'm working on it
currently this time it's not going to
come out through prentice hall we
couldn't come to an arrangement which is
one of the reasons why it took so long
to get to this point we self-published
this time so you'll have to keep your
ear to the ground because prentice hall
is gonna be barking about it alright
it's just gonna be me and my friends but
hopefully hopefully within the next six
or nine months we'll have something for
you so that's it any questions about
anything I've talked about today on time
might I add somebody could tell strand
II won't believe it yes
could W pad dotnet come across as a
Dufferin different name does it have to
be W pad dot dot dot certainly could
it certainly could absolutely it's just
a configurable thing but chances are if
you've got LM n R and W pad enabled in
your environment you got the the
straight-up defaults which is what
enables all that hacking dumb early
right what I mean seriously if you're
gonna be smart enough to say hey you
know what I shouldn't call it W pad dad
know what you shouldn't do is support it
at all you should burn your proxy config
into your gold master image prior to
deployment and not have any of this
asking your neighbor who should I proxy
my through which is why yeah am I
gonna catch it that's a prototype script
in in the real world would I make it
smarter to look at other things besides
W pad dad
yes I would good question any others yes
all right along the same lines is there
any reason to have a lemon are and
enable in your environment by God yes
absolutely it's damn well critical you
need your pan testers to be speedy and
you don't want to inconvenience the bad
guys that is its sole feature
no there is no anybody in here if you
can bring me a good business case a good
use case for valid business case use of
LLM anar and your deployment I'd love to
hear it because I would love to shoot
that down I don't think so
its primary use is by bad guys and pen
testers and the other good questions
like those because those are good
questions all right well if not that's
all I got and it's time for lunch Ilan
cheese go get your feed bags on
[Music]