[Music]
I'm happy to be here is my first time
out to South Dakota like many of you it
is awesome so I'm going to be talking
about one of my passions which is memory
forensics a little bit about me just a
little bit I teach for sans I've been
teaching for sans as a sort of an
instructor for five years and again in
the digital forensics Incident Response
tract so you might have had me in the
500 508 504 but the class that I own is
the memory forensics so that's the 526
and check it out it's cool I'm not gonna
talk too much about it but I'm going to
show you how I was able to make my team
more effective my most recent full-time
position was leaving an incident
response team at Cargill I think it's
still up there but it was a good time
and it was a good time and often times
Incident Response Teams
well you know there's no time for root
cause analysis so you have to be pretty
picky about how you proceed with
compromised systems on it anyone working
IR right now oh dude I'm so psyched to
be on ok ok I was pretty happy already
but the fact that about half of you
raised your hands I feel like I'm
amongst friends you know you should feel
that way too
so what we're going to be well first off
because we are talking about you all
good job and good job in furthering your
skill set it's no joke you know you have
to go to ground and continue your
learning constantly to stay up-to-date
in this field some of you may be
checking your Twitter feed right now am
i right no there's only a couple of you
looking down right now but yeah I mean
isn't that how we stay up to date just
constantly attending training watching
webinars which are so very very many of
them these days but I commend you I
commend you not everybody's here looks
your left or right there's empty seats
for shame for shame we're gonna shame
those other folks that didn't make it to
this this conference this attend
presentation
hey so as I was growing my Incident
Response Team there was a certain
skillset I was looking for it's true
it's true
definitely people who had been in the
trenches who had worked investigations
of an enterprise scale maybe who had
experienced a little bit of pain and
embarrassment you know that that tempers
an incident responder would you say
you're the more that you've seen the
more hard times that you live through I
I think that makes you a better incident
responder but don't tell your boss that
you know it's it's you have to act the
part like I can't believe the attacker
did this what but you know I grew the
size of my incident response team we
actually doubled the size while I was at
Cargill and I got to do a lot of
interviews and I was always looking for
purists you know what I mean by purists
people who want to do a deep dive who
actually wants to find out root cause
like okay this malware is fascinating
but how did it get there and they want
to apply whether there be a network
forensic specialists or host based
forensic specialists they want to apply
their unique skill set in order to find
the answer so I hope that you guys would
join me in doing just this very same
thing with the six systems
maybe Plus wine that we're going to be
looking at so first and foremost I have
to kick out and say memory forensics is
awesome yes oh yeah yeah he's a you're
an alumni right are you a GC FA already
yeah yeah yeah yeah awesome
congratulations 508 alumni here so I'm
not gonna go through each and every one
of these reasons why you need to be
looking in memory in system memory I'll
just ask are you do you have the ability
in your enterprise to reach across the
wire and pull back the contents of
physical memory some people are saying
no yes there are some hands going up
impressive impressive and the last time
we asked via sans survey it was right at
40% that was last year we asked how many
of the participants of the endpoint
security survey have the ability to pull
back memory data it was just a 40% so I
think I'm amongst the elite here very
well very well
so we're going to find hand how the
contents of memory is going to be
kind of like shed light on what happened
the first compromise system that I want
to introduce to you well it's an
anti-virus it you're like blah that's
crap I'm out of here I'll turn around
again so anyone who wants to leave okay
all right no no
so again if you're just walking in this
isn't the AWS presentation no it's even
better than that so host base host base
forensics this first system was
identified by my Sauk analysts yeah yeah
every morning we had a stand up meeting
incident response team and Sauk analyst
and I think that's very important you
know the communication we weren't there
for every turnover because we had 24/7
follow-the-sun Security Operations
Center but we were there every morning
when it counts right and we went over
the antivirus report and largely if the
antivirus product that we were using it
wasn't so folks come on the antivirus
product that we're using set in a
quarantine something my analysts weren't
concerned about it is that the right way
to proceed I mean well you might want to
find out more details so in this case we
have a screenshot of so posts
identifying an SVC host those are always
legitimate right I see some people
nodding how yeah I love this crowd yeah
so we got an SPC host but that's been
identified but it's be a scheduled scan
and I don't know how frequently
scheduled scans are in your environment
but we were like at a month mark and
we'd call it good you're like what's
scheduled scans are weekly not in some
environments I assure you it's like the
month mark so what happens if this SVC
host was detected be a scheduled scan on
the file system what could have happened
between the time that this binary landed
on the box and the time well in this
case so post detected it oh that's a
perfect answer you don't know or
computer science answer it depends right
it depends I get it I get it
I like I like this audience so we're
going to go about figuring out did this
execute isn't that one of the most
important things to find out at this
point yeah like I said my sock analysts
were like whoa
listen he's taken care of antivirus said
is quarantined but I'm like do
yeah it's quarantine today but what
happened over the last month since it
land in the box so I encourage my incent
responders to do some root cause
analysis to go back and figure out when
that SVC host ANDed hey can anyone tell
me this is obviously an exemple our
memory image and system them that I'm
cueing off of that I have so folks
running on where did I get the VM from
based on the user profile same will
recognize the user profile where the SVC
host was detected it says ie user is
anyone using the free VMs from Microsoft
thank you thank you if you're not
downloading the free VMs from
Microsoft's I know they put them up
there so you can do what a web app
testing but dude those are awesome all
of these different versions of Windows
and you can infect them so I don't know
it break open your left start
downloading now anyways so the next
thing that we did of course was dump
memory because I strongly influenced my
team and like you need to go get memory
of the system so I present to you the
output from running PS list and then of
course bringing it into calc which is
open offices excellent spreadsheets
application and kind of just filtering
on SVC host is Q which one of these
should I be concerned about you guys are
saying the last one can you give me
three reasons why the last one is all
kinds of crazy and worrisome you can you
can answer in your head you're just not
like yeah I totally I see three you can
give me two of them oh session two he's
only of his head so session enumeration
yeah he's saying that last one I'll just
go ahead and point it out that last SVC
host is the one that was hanging on the
user profile directory and this is a
process list so I'm I'm actually parsing
the memory of the system that we thought
was all clear because so folks
quarantine this I'm seeing that SVC host
is currently running despite it being
sucked off the file system and I know
that this is not a legit SVC host will
be
cuz it's in session two which is a user
session where why else the parent
process identifier we don't know what
the parent process identify errs are of
the legitimate SPC host we know it's
four seven six which is
services services yeah okay you just at
this point if you're not down with
Windows I guess that's respectable you
know saying it's good to deny the arrow
windows user slash investigator but four
seven six
it must be services because that's
legitimate and a Window System wouldn't
run without legitimate SBC hosts we hope
so having something other than that is
the peep it is concerning we could also
point to the start time this started way
after like days after the other SBC
hosts so I feel pretty good about this I
mean bad about it but remember my team
is a bunch of purist they're like hell
yeah this Michigan is compromised let's
keep on going let's keep on going
so what else should we ask at this point
in time
just follow your instincts it's hard
it's hard I know you want to fire
someone don't you you want to find out
how this got on the box that's what I
want to find out you were gonna say oh
he's actually saying that we do a little
bit more investigating and figure out
who that process identifier 400 is and
that actually turns out to be Explorer I
don't know whether I give that little
shoutout or not do I know Explorer
launched this thing you can see full
path of where this current process is
running from app data there it is man so
suppose said it taking care of this but
we have a copy of that binary up in
memory and it's currently running
whatever this mallow is designed to do
it's been on the box for well that's the
question right how long has it been on
the box can we find the initial vector
infection how did it get on the system
so let's do it let's do it so I'm
throwing out some volatility plugins if
you're are you down with the volatility
because incident responders are probably
using it on a daily so good good so I'm
just like kind of
I don't know given a little coating up
there this keyword coding for plugins so
the next plugin that Iran was MFT parser
because I'm a fight I love file system
forensics too so I'm all about the MFT
carbon for those 1,024 bytes
ching-ching-ching
and what were able to identify is not
the svchost.exe cuz that record I don't
know what happened to that record you
know some records are corrupted memory
you're not gonna get them all it's ok
but we do have the directory that was
created by the dropper and I thought
that was pretty cool the directory is
Google and so we have time and date
statuses show I'm smiling we have time
and dates it was the show when that was
created and I think that's pretty good
maybe actionable enough to fire someone
I'm also excited I didn't really share
with you that my background is an
employee investigator for a large
government contractor so I get really
excited like oh it's this fault it's her
fault ok I would always say it's the
user accounts I can attribute the
activity of the user account because
that's the way you write a forensics
report so it's good though join me
alright so we are going ahead and
looking at all of these MFT records
because there's a couple ways you can
run MFT parser you can actually send it
to a body file and then you can run mac
time against it this is just pure nerdy
digital forensic stuff folks that we're
working on the offensive side of the
house I used to work with them they
called me Indiana Jones and I thought
that was a little dated honestly I mean
it kind of showed how old they were and
it felt weird to me but I get it like
artifact hunter Indiana Jones no I said
yeah it's it's the 80s the 90s ok so
what do we see here we see the Google
directory because I know I have that MFT
record it's gonna be the one that's
lower and as you go up the slide you're
going back in time so it's older MFT
record so I actually have something
that's quite interesting to me it's the
loyalty card dot exe it looks like it
was from a directory called loyalty card
JPEG and that's weird
but I get it right because everyone
wants a discount whoa thank you very
much
jealousy hits it's a good feeling to
inspire audience here all right so I'm
thinking I'm
might have identified the dropper that
then copied the SPC host you know what
you don't need privilege escalation -
right then to the that profile directory
do you know so I'm thinking this is a
chain effect and don't don't believe my
MFG records because maybe you're a
doubter over the file system because of
like time stomping and all so maybe you
switch back and you want to do more
evidence of execution well shout out to
the fireEye team that developed the shim
cache Memphian and volatility it is
amazing you can actually go into your
memory image and pull things that have
yet to be written to the registry
you know shim cache it's all about
application compatibility and I know
that has very little to do with
forensics is up the fact that it leaves
behind artifacts okay it depends on
which realm you're working in but join
me and looking at shim cache mem
which are things that are hanging out in
a buffer somewhere in memory that we're
pulling out now this is evidence of
execution don't get too excited about
those time and date stamps that you see
there they're actually the last modified
time associated with the MFT record of
said evil but do you see what I'm seeing
I see the SVC host now the SPCA list is
up there and let me blow this up so you
can see it to fully appreciate what we
got going on here
I got SPCA host which is a higher rank
so the things that are the very top of
your shim cache mem are the things that
have run most recently it's beautiful
this this plugin
what did Fred do it's amazing so the
very top is going to be like rank one or
one most recently run you come down a
little bit further now we got a
historical walk back of evidence of
execution this is perfect for us
take a look prior to the svchost.exe
running from the Google directory we
have that strange loyalty card dot exe
lame all right so we probably have
enough to go off of from here to things
that we could go about extracting if lil
T card exe is still memory mapped you
know you want a copy of that you might
be able to find on the file system so
I'm not pooping file system forensics
but you know I have a memory image here
in front of me let me use it to the
fullest extent
so I'd pull these things out I think I
actually pulled out the SVC
and ran strings against it because well
you know that's a solid technique to
static analysis man so these are the
strings I was able to pull oh that I
found interesting kind of speaking to
you a bot some mutex ah and in summary I
think you guys help me I mean you listen
next time you'll participate more right
do you feel comfortable with how this is
gonna go
that was system number one okay thank
you thank you
the guy who participated actually gets
to celebrate with me it's fine it's fine
so let's talk about system number two
system number two it's a little bit more
sophisticated now I can't say that many
Incident Response Teams have that
opportunity to put on their proactive
hunting hats come on man we're working
hard these days and it's very hard to
convince the top-level execs that we
need to grow our team and expand because
they asked for metrics you know like ah
what's your time to remediation how many
events are you handling these days and
what are you gonna do when you're not
handling events and incidents and I get
it I get it so sometimes we do have the
opportunity to put on our proactive
hunting hats we have tons and tons of
content out there that tell us what to
look for but in this case what did I
look for oh I pulled back some prefetch
files so if you like me I mean pretty
much is my favorite favorite evidence of
execution I know it's not for me it's
not for the forensic examiner it's all
about efficiency right prefetch it's
supposed to like free load all of the
dependents dependencies for an
executable into memory and and track
that in a PF file that shows what is the
computer gonna needs it'll load the next
time that kicks off right and there's
optimizations but you know forensic
examiners we get really excited if
there's prefetch am i right am i oh yeah
I like to joke that you know if there's
no prefetch I'll subcontract out of work
outs you know it's like too hard so this
is what I'm doing I'm pulling back
across the enterprise all of the
prefetch files that I'm doing some
stacking some data stacking now you
probably have a method of doing this
right at the
enterprise-level you could be doing it
like just be a powershell Kansa a good
tool for data stacking right pull back
all of your prefetch with Kansa which is
a powershell framework and you're able
to sort by in this case maybe I've
chosen wrong because it's order of
frequency by most frequently occurring
is that notable like it's an TOS boot
interesting no not normally and TOS boot
you can certainly set your nevermind
okay let's switch this around and do
lease for frequency of occurrence and
you know there's a few up here there's a
few of these that like set up dot exe
maybe that's okay but I don't know the
things that make these unique are going
to be the path the path of the
executable so those pads are gonna be
different for various reasons but
because this is a hunting technique I
don't need to be right a hundred percent
of the time this is supposed to give me
something to look at that could
potentially aligned with attacker
behavior some crazy randomly named
executable that creates a prefetch file
I want to look into it and I certainly I
wish to you that you have a team that
has cycles to do this type of proactive
hunting so this machine was identified
using these techniques we found some
crazy prefetch file that was only
occurring on that one machine and we
kicked back and we looked at it alright
and this is what we were able to find
holy what's all right all right right so
maybe this is for DES quarry because we
don't see des quarry running so
frequently in our environment I mean
what is there des what does that stand
for
it's got if it's if it's associated with
a attacker it's got to be directory
services right directory services so
this is actually I I know this is the
real world investigation I worked at
manye
and I was like no way like 20 times
right
so I crafted this it's pretty cool and
he actually points to the attackers
school directory he dropped in program
data which i think is pretty awesome you
can see all of this because we had what
is that Frost detail process tracking
you guys know the the event ID for that
446 88 dude oh that wasn't a
presentation earlier today 46 88 I
remember I remember something all right
46 88 so detail process tracking was how
I was able to figure all this out but it
all started from her strange prefetch
file I know you're thinking I could
totally do this better I would have I
would have had an alert for Deus quarry
or D s ask or some strangeness run
anything running from the program
directory maybe I don't know yeah you
would have gone there I like to convince
my students that you would have gotten
there may be using a different technique
but you would have found said evil so
this guy was clearly interacting with
Active Directory creating accounts
initially trying to figure out group
membership and the story continues from
there this spun up into a full-fledged
investigation there was multiple
machines it's a good one proper scoping
proper scoping how did you do did you
feel good about that one were you
tracking like I want to do some free
fetch stacking all right all right
that's cool number three is another
proactive technique it's a hunting
method where you're looking for services
that are terminated tournament services
that are stopped that are really
designed to protect your environment
isn't it unusual to find systems with no
antivirus running so a little shout-out
to one of my favorite tools tain iam
it's a good tool is it good to anyone
anyone know I'm certain about it it's
you can't control it hello it's like a
race car you need somebody you need some
special training on a man you might wrap
it around telephone pole if you don't
you don't get behind it rain so I'm
saying the obtaining it was good today
was good but I'm I'm pulling back here
and I gotta give credit where credit's
due this is my forensics team now myosin
response team that crafted this quarry
the quarry was to pull back collection
of hosts every host that had the clients
running on it like ask the question okay
are you running the end start what does
then start why does that relate to
forensics teams and start 64 DXE
they don't come around to here do they
forensics people and in case in case
yeah yeah so they were wondering which
machines were not running in case but
they also asked a question which
machines are not running whatever our
antivirus was do I do a big reveal oh
the sub client ha so some kind of solid
man I saw it but there were some
machines that had that disabled so are
you concerned are you concerned that
there's some machines in your vibe you
can probably think of a few that are not
running your antivirus am i right
and maybe they they are the ones that
qualified for some exception because
they're in the you know the
manufacturing line and you're afraid of
I'm always operating a crane when I
stalk about industrial plant
environments but yeah maybe maybe you
have some that you would have a good
excuse you'd have an exception and some
some mitigating factors that have come
into play so you don't need antivirus
but you know this is how we identified
one of these machines is we had extra
cycles I asked my team go ahead and do
some data stacking pull back and figure
out which machines don't have antivirus
currently on and we go from there
do you agree with this you're gonna go
back and do this right now who's who's
like dialing in I'm VP adding into my
environment right now and I'm using
tinium it will not master me I will
master it I get it good good good
so I dump memory from this system and
you know I probably don't need to
convince you now why it's compromised
rate do you see the profile from this
volatility analysis wait what OS is this
system running oh you're like Windows
what version of Windows
yeah it's 2003 you can see up there in
the gray a 2003 it's service pack it
serves back to you though oh wait it
serves back whoa all right all right
enough calm down everyone what do you
see because I I initially start with
connections and you know you got to
adjust your volatility push your ninja
skills because it's a different set of
plugins whether you're looking at XP /
2003 or they look at a Vista and beyond
so we're gonna go with con scan to gen
up this are you concerned you're like
this is preposterous
who's feeling like this is a contrived
scenario but there's no way this could
possibly be in someone's environment why
we're do that oh not Metasploit users
either huh I see I see you got four four
four four this is a lazy pentester come
on
that's the callback that's the airport
that's why do you fold it Metasploit
it's true it's true so you're looking at
this list of connections which would be
equivalent of what you might call the
netstat ano and I see lots of pigs so I
don't really know the owning processes
but what's concerning to me is those
four four four fours I got a lot of SMB
maybe that's legit maybe that's normal
maybe it's normal to see from India to
Pennsylvania straight across four four
or five in your environment flat
environments I mean they're run
efficiently continue to research because
I am concerned about what those ports
those pads are okay awesome
do a little PS scan why did I choose BS
cam well because it gives me a
historical view of what ran in the past
a little bit more than PS list would
have you know now it's just carving for
those he process blocks and I have a lot
of run DLL 32cm nice I just have a
behavioral indicator of compromise that
scan for all the CMT's it was exhausting
to go through but I mean is putting on
your pro hunting we're proactive hunting
hat and maybe that would be a fruitful
what else is is curious about this net
cats all the way down there at the
bottom if you see and see exe and it had
a pit of 1308 so let's see if it owns
any of the ports no it doesn't own any
of the ports but certainly some of these
some of these connections are owned by
run G low 32 XE so I think what we just
did was increase the scope of our
investigation we just added some more
machines that are internal to this
environment that are involved in the
compromised we don't know what's going
on but we know it's not just this system
would you say I mean who's working for
billable hours you know did you see what
we just did there we took one system and
now we're like oh I need a let's go back
I need 10.10 not 75 one one one I need a
memory dump from I need a memory dump
from and on and on and on because you're
very concerned what's happening with
these systems
why are they making inbound connections
potentially I guess we could figure that
one out hmm all right maybe a little bit
more memory Alice's would ensue you'd
want to figure out what's going on in
the context of these run diello thirty
twos one of the questions you might ask
yourself is is there code injection and
of course we find that mouths mind
delivers yet again mal pond identifies
in the context of one run TL o 32 a ton
of memory ranges that are showing signs
of well they're marked is execute no
path the disk and they're not all no
bites so we have something that we need
to look into you I run strings against
one of these memory ranges and it comes
back with meterpreter boom all right
done done good job good job by the way
do you feel like is this satisfying
satisfied yes all right
so system number four this happens too
but it really depends on the
relationship that you have with your
users whether they're going to call and
complain like do my machine is running
slow just be aware that by the time they
call you they've attempted to clean up
right like oh it was probably that uh
that productivity lost website that I
was visiting him I don't know I probably
need to remove some of these programs
that I've installed that might have have
back doors so you know just realize that
if we're informed by the user that their
machine is running slow it's probably
made it through a couple of layers of
sanitizing I don't know let's see let's
see so that's how we're able to find out
about this one we reach across the wire
we pull back a memory dump and this
looks pretty legit anyone anyone want to
guess what type of system is is this is
system number four dude oh oh is it
because the profile is up there is that
is that why I was so excited because you
can kind of there's a telltale sign to
you in the process list then we talked
about in class and I like I swell with
pride
every time my students are like wow I
see that task task oh study X two years
there that's obviously a Windows 7
machine I was like hell yeah you could
get pretty good at this just by looking
at a process listen being like dude
that's the latest Windows 10 17 134
because it has a registry process boom
good stuff good stuff so I could
I don't see anything too suspicious what
tells me that someone's logged in do you
see a process that might be indicative
of someone logging in this is amazing
yeah you see it huh oh it's up there
it's up there explore that exe nice
explore yeah you don't have that
telltale sign of like session
enumeration that started like as a Vista
so we're kind of left hanging a little
bit on this one but you know I don't
really see anything the process list
let's go ahead and look at network
connections is there anything strange
here now I don't pull out your domain
tools and start looking to buy P
addresses and I know that's not
necessary
what do you recognize any of the pigs
there over in the right hand column I
know they all have to be divisible by
four that's just one of the things for
Windows but paid for what is this pit
for the system process should it be
communicating outbound on port 80 to
some remote host like oh my no no no no
unless you have a really good reason why
your system process is communicating to
a remote IP address on port 80 you need
to look into that you need to look into
that this turns out to be a storm worm
infection and if you were to pull any of
these IP addresses they would square you
away and be like there's a problem there
what I decided to do I know it's a
little bit advanced it's kind of a break
the glass technique my co-author that's
Jake Williams for the memory forensics
class this is one of his his terms break
the glass like you would never just jump
in and be like I feel like doing a call
back unless you were hunting in a modern
malware you knew that you can't hook
anymore to the system call table you
need to like be a little bit more
creative so join me in looking at this
callbacks plugin output from volatility
you can see here I have two callbacks
that were registered by unknown and
that's probably always bad it's always
bad yeah I need to figure out what
unknown is because clearly volatility
was on there was a map it to something
that was in the modules list so are we
good are we good like this isn't
supposed to be depressing we're knocking
the stuff out man
and do you feel like maybe I need to pay
you you know because you've been looking
at so much of my data and you're like
yeah go go Alyssa that one right there
thank you
is that enough thank you I'm going to be
turning in my deliverables after this
presentation and I'll have all of your
names on it be like uh my work is done
here so numbers number five system
number five is based on an IOC hit now
you might not be believer in iOS C's
much like you weren't believer in
antivirus why well indicators of
compromised are based on past evil and
my environment is totally unique and you
know act ackers are gonna have to try to
get into my environment so every iOS see
that you've ever seen before is going to
be null avoid as I'm looking maybe maybe
I know IO sees they can be brittle at
times but this one's pretty behavioral
based this pivots off of what we learned
from the number one and number two based
on prefetch conversations what you're
looking at here is a prefetch file that
points to an executable that ran from a
user's directory I think it's roaming
yeah just straight up roaming so that
should always be bad unless you have
some other explanation notice the
student has said to me Alyssa I can say
100 words what could easily be said in
ten and I said thank you they wrote that
on my eval we get evals all the time and
I was like thank you that means I'm an
excellent forensic examiner because she
should never say there is no malware
should you should you ever say there is
no malware on the system nah you should
say based on the time allowed using the
methods employed blah blah no evidence
of do you agree
no thank you I see you nodding yeah okay
so 100 words don't don't use the ten so
I will say that this indicator of
compromise allowed us to identify a
prefetch file that pointed to an
executable and it was running from the
roaming directory of a user's profile
and that I actually get a little bit
sick in my stomach when I think about
that because that's dirty that's dirty
you shouldn't be running there mm-hmm
okay and I think little IOC definition
for those either they're not down with
that but a MFT parser why did I decide
to go with that first
ah because I hit the prefetch file first
and then I parsed the prefetch file and
it pointed to this executable this is
the one that was running from the
roaming directory are you are you
feeling pretty down with this when I and
I is legit yeah I'm a winnin it when I
net when i and i know i am out to see
any not ignore do I see any violent
disagreement oh my god I don't don't do
it illicit don't do it double click on
that no so what we're seeing here is an
MFT record so a master file table record
straight up and it's pointing to or the
metadata of this task hosted exe and
this is pretty legit mad cuz task host
is supposed to be running on a Windows 7
machine so what's another task oh so
they kick it out there you know and it
would be really hard I'll admit really
hard for my ir team as well as my field
services and my sock analysts you pick
the side of the lineup unless they got a
process list and they're gonna go deep
and they're gonna get command-line so
important for command line stuff right
so let's see if this is running right
now we only have an MFT record that
we've drawn out of memory and yeah I'm
interesting so now we're the same
I mean timeline analysis yeah you'll
have to excuse me because it's kind of a
forensic examiner thing like oh I feel
like doing timeline I can't move on
until we put it on timeline so that's
what I'm doing here taking all those MOT
records and dropping them in anything
happening immediately prior well this is
a handle to the key and last modified
some of that key so I'm not really
getting any more than at what I'm an
initially had but what is this evidence
of it's the same executable but now what
are we seeing based on the presence of
the executable in the key I hear you
guys say it nicely done they're saying
persistence so yeah a lot of my buddies
they'll start their investigation I
think because they're so fed up with
malware today they're like I'm just
gonna look for persistence like autoruns
mark russinovich would want it this way
and they pull out their auto runs and
however a context or tool maybe it scans
I mean is taenia maybe it's just
straight-up autoruns be a power show you
can push that uh-huh
and they'll pull it back and they'll
just look through the common persistence
locations and the register
we're seeing here oh those are straight
up look for services man cuz that's
about 70% of malware that instantiates
persistence that is going to create or
hijack a service so that's pretty slick
ass pretty slick
it's a good job I mean I definitely
write this one up in my report so that
was current version run as you're
looking at it what's happening prior to
kerma ah who's flipping over the table
that this is a contrived scenario do you
see what's happening up here higher in
my timeline my MFT records this looks
like someone infected their own machine
because I see what is that a sha-1 sha-1
Exe spy net you can actually see how
this machine was infected because I'm
pulling user assists
actually this is timeline er output
isn't it timeline or not just MFT parser
but time liner is being pulled in and
shown to us so this is good stuff
because evidence of execution for Spina
XD and shortly after that we see that
relationship exists between the
persistence key and whatever else is
currently running this good stuff it's
good stuff you agree yeah I don't know
if you feel done with this one yet but
yeah we'll go ahead and we'll verify
that the user who's currently logged in
at the time we dumped memory has the
tosco study XE hanging right off of
their current version run in there and
to user dot dot so that's what we're
seeing here and a little shout out the
Thomas top idea who wrote this autoruns
plugin is good it's good so I think I
think we're rounding the bend on that
one whoa speed round speed round no it
gets a little bit harder from here
because I got a you have to hear from me
about this network forensics based tool
stealthWatch is anyone using this so me
using this still watch no whoops come on
man the ability to use net flow
information to figure out what is going
on in my network and I know it takes a
lot of time to baseline these network
intrusion detection products that are in
your environment but I would say once
you get it rolling you might benefit
from something like this which is a
stealthWatch high concern index hits so
there was one machine inside our
environment that was active okay there's
a lot of machines inside our environment
one of them was detected with this
technique and it was acting crazy
right network network so the fact that
we identified this one machine based on
network traffic means that when I get a
memory dump in front of me and I know
you guys are probably thinking like how
is she dumping this like how is she
dumping all of these memory images I
know what you want to ask me what my
favorite tool this am i right
like what's my favorite acquisition tool
it's like I can read your minds what it
what he is what do you use whatever I
tell you to do huh yeah when pee man
responds that's nice of response
what else is a possible solution here I
talk to attain iam Danny amuses the wind
pmm pushes that driver say in case we'll
do it right in case we'll pull it back
fdk know I step to K imager
I don't pit is never using dump it
little shout-out to Matt you sweet
really that's my stuff with you guys I
must have named your favorite it's very
early on it must name her favorites okay
we'll proceed now that I've made you
believe for the you Coon you too could
dump all these memory images we can't
proceed so is anyone nervous maybe
that's why I lost your attention are you
nervous about what you're seeing up here
because the first thing I'm gonna do
when I get that stealthWatch high
concern index is like okay it was acting
crazy on the network we're gonna go
ahead and we're gonna run net scan
what's concerning about this yeah yeah
four four five who should own four four
five comms mostly you know the majority
of the time who should who should own as
a process for four five like it depends
okay okay get past the it depends based
on what you've seen if it's just
straight up like net use a little nap
drive its system so pip or do you see
any pitfalls here that on the four four
five I see I see one and that looks
that's probably us that's probably us
connecting to the machine and doing some
investigations ah but who else I mean
what other process owns the four four or
five comms m/s sec SVC does anyone
recognize this process name is good you
guys you live a charmed life charmed
life alright then I'll save I'll stay at
the grand finale here
oh wait oh wait for it but you know four
or five can you tell me why did we think
this was patient zero in this compromise
as you're looking at this memory dump
and you see four four five connections
is there anything that would be
concerning to you it's a whole bunch of
outbound traffic so obviously this
machine is attempting to connect so
remote IP addresses on four four five
which is a little bit obnoxious a little
bit obnoxious but do you see the inbound
four four five the only way we're able
to see the inbound four four five
connection to this system let me get my
pointer out oh wait that's good is
because I'm scanning for the presence of
these TCP underscore endpoints I
wouldn't see this if I was interrogating
the machine across the network using say
wmic
I wouldn't see the close connection
because it's already been removed from
say your netstat output the only way I'm
seeing that closed connection which is
an inbounds to this systems four four
five for remote IP address is because I
have the memory image and this data
structure is there as consider it an
unallocated space in memory so it's cool
net scan allows me to carve this out and
I'm like damn you know this very well
could have been patient zero and what
type of infection it could have been
anything any any nasty eternal blue yeah
and he nasty eternal blue compromised
you'd be right in saying that so what
we're looking at here is what we deemed
to be patient zero and we're seeing
evidence of initial infection the bad
thing about time I say network
connections as we're pulling them out
they don't have time and date stamps
associated with them as you're
retrieving these artifacts from memory
yeah you got to get it from a different
data source yeah that's alright alright
we'll proceed yeah that one's pretty
pretty interesting too I would
immediately expand the scope of my
investigation it's the whole world I
don't know four four five this is
probably a highly infectious system now
where propagation was rampant
it was very aggressive so of course you
want to pivot to a winning process
getting more details about that
particular process that was running that
was responsible for all of those out
barons quarries you know attempts to
connect to remote IP addresses so this
what we were able to get note that time
and date stamp might be relevant here
but I know what you're thinking dwell
time ELISA right
what is that bridge to all the time
these days do it Everage dwell time it's
like a 6070 i mean it does depend on who
you are and what you're willing to admit
you we asked our sands participants for
the surveys and they say oh it's two
days two days less than two day less
than two hours we're able to detect a
system that's compromised ten minutes
after that it's remediated it's okay
it's okay
serious face serious face it's not easy
it's not easy stuff and it all depends
on definition so we kick back and we run
to shrimp cache mem which I know pleased
you before right evidence of execution
where you can kind of put it in order I
have MS SEC SVC and then I have that
task as CAG that exe this is obvious
okay it's obvious to me because I've
been born by it
but I can see all kinds of things
popping up in my timeline or output and
then finally an injected L sauce that
might be like the finishing blow this L
SAS has a memory range it has a DLL has
the MZ header that's tucked away in an
outlet memory a range allocation it's
clearly no path to disk that's why I'm
al fine is complaining about it so what
do you do when you find something like
this don't let me get in your way
don't let me get in your way you know
you can upload a virus oh no oh all
right so we upload that memory range
after already identifying and knowing
what we're dealing with and knowing that
it's my commodity but it's well known we
would upload this and we get back hey
this is wanna cry you can see that Ahn
lab it does not let us down improper
identification there you go Dooney did
you use virus Toto at all
all right yeah for some purpose to laugh
at others don't laugh at the victims of
the world I get it I get it all right so
I have five more minutes and I would
like to offer a bonus system are you
down with that or is it just is it just
too much this would be system number 700
I always always you miss your workplace
you want to go back to your shop and
look at you know images from compromises
- all right
jump in now this one doesn't look too
bad it honestly doesn't but I was able
to figure out that something was wrong
with the system because I enumerated
processes and looked at the session
Association now we've done this before
and it panned out for us if you remember
it was system number one when you're
like that SPC host is associate with
session two and session two was the user
session if they log on and session in
him rates and there you go so this is
what I saw when I was dumping memory on
my own system it looks pretty clean
doesn't it I mean I think I actually had
notepad running so it's a little bit
different from what I saw I teach the
526 class all the time and I was just
about to roll into day two and I still
had some content left from day one you
know so it's the memory forensics class
and I'm like I'm gonna be a good sands
instructor I'm gonna walk through my lab
before I get in and that lab was dumping
memory with wind peameal and then
bringing it over to my Ubuntu shift and
doing some analysis I think we were
doing analysis with volatility because
recall is in an unstable State at the
time so when I brought it over this is
what I saw you know going from that
desktop so now what I see in the process
lists I was a little concerned because
my students had the same VM as me and I
was about to roll in and see whether
they were seeing what I was seeing and
what's wrong with these Internet
Explorer's
volatility doesn't color code people it
doesn't color code for you but I'm color
coding those Internet Explorer's are
associated with session zero and I know
it's been a long time since you've used
ie I get it I get it I use it all the
time it's it's it's still good it's
still hanging in there but I you know
what session should Internet Explorer be
associated with in most cases don't say
it depends yeah one or above right
wonder about it should be associate with
a user session and you know what if
Internet Explorer was running it should
have been rendering Windows to the
desktop and I was a little sick I was
always a little concerned of course and
also because I'm a purist I was thrilled
I was like oh my gosh we have boom live
malware up in here
all right so you might want to figure
out that guy initially I was like those
aren't real Internet Explorer's you
might feel that way too like those must
be hanging off of the C Drive or running
from somebody's AppData local but it
turned out that these were legitimate
right or a seemingly legitimate they
were running from Program Files Internet
Explorer so we continue we continue now
you might want to do a process list
because we haven't done that yet because
before we were kind of looking at
sessions as we go back and we kick in
with a process list there's other things
to be suspicious of that are also
running quite close in proximity you
know starting right around the same time
as these crazy Internet Explorer's so
that's in spacio it's it's throwing out
I don't know what in spatio is let's
let's figure it out so as I kick back in
a run a PS list how many in speciose do
I see recalls a little bit different
notice that I chose to use a different
tool from my tool bag I'd you know I
swapped out my weapons arsenal is many
and I chose the difference for this time
so recall actually implements five
different methods of processing
numeration it doesn't just walk the
doubly-linked list to be process blocks
it brings in a little bit more a little
bit extra so we're able to see some
pasts he process blocks because of the
methods employed it's a little bit of
PSK and technique there and yeah two of
them are in a terminated state so I'm
like what is this this is also quite
exciting um you would probably want to
find out full path to disk what else do
I do
Oh Oh faster run
that's nerd stuff because it was a
Windows 8 service pack 1 x64 so I ran it
again and finally timeline analysis
because you couldn't stop me from doing
timeline like when did that uh since
passio land on the box we figure it out
we point the finger back to an
installation package I guess my advice
to you is when you're installing firefox
don't choose the first search results
when you type in Firefox download don't
do that don't do that it's not the
SourceForge one that you want to install
Firefox so yeah what we did was more
evidence of execution here you can see
an ins fassio did in fact Orion
I've played around with my am cash
because I couldn't get in spatio be
executable and get a solid md5 or sha-1
you can go to your am cash register you
hive and get it
so I dump this out with a recall my
total to us now and went ahead ran
strings against that am cash registry
I've and then what did I do
uploaded a virus total do it do it whoa
I mean again it's this tragic it's
tragic it was an absolute infection a
nightmare but a cool man cool live
infection I don't remember Yan
unbeknownst to me and shocking so you
know I I congratulate you you've made it
through all seven systems and it is now
like five zero minutes 50 minutes good
job good job I want to I just think the
Wild West hack best for having me it is
an honor to talk to you today
[Music]