so
welcome to my talk on anti-picking
features of high security locks
uh who am i well uh i'm the uh
secretary of the open organization of
block pickers in the uk and i'm a locked
scion fanatic who has been grappling
with the problem of how to design an
unpickable mechanical lock
for about the last half a decade
uh why am i giving this talk then uh
well i'm giving the talk
uh with the hope that maybe if i run
through a lot of ingenious attempts to
solve the problem
uh other people will be inspired to
grapple with the problem themselves
and uh maybe you know they'll see
something they think they can improve
upon
or if nothing else just to show you some
very cool lock designs
uh in order to do this uh effectively in
this talk
uh the problem is that uh
i'm gonna have to talk about lock
picking in a very abstract way and the
main reason for that is i'm covering
such a
bro uh such a broad uh
variety of uh locking mechanisms
that i it's simply not going to be
possible to talk about this
in the same way that you would talk
about picking conventional pin tumbler
locks
um so i'm going to abstract this out
uh it's kind of the very fundamental
concepts in lock picking and then we
will attempt
to apply those uh to
the locks
hopefully in in an effective way
so first of all we have manipulation uh
manipulation is basically just the idea
that
we need to be able to move the
components inside the lock if we can't
move the components inside the lock
well then we're not going to be able to
get it open without the key
secondly uh we have tension so this
hinges on the fact that we can't produce
um we can't produce elements in a lock
perfectly they won't all be identical so
if we can apply
some kind of driving force in the open
direction
then we will get contact against those
blocking elements
inside the lock whether they be levers
or wafers or
sliders or discs or pins or whatever it
may be
um then
when we've got that kind of that that
force which is what i'm referring to its
tension then we will be able to get some
kind of information out of the lock
uh i have to be able to do both those
things at the same time we will see some
locks that have uh
ingenious mechanisms to try to prevent
you from doing them both at the same
time although you could do either one
relatively trivially
on its own and of course we're doing all
of that
in order to get information out of the
lock so
when we're able to apply tension and
manipulate mechanism
typically we will be able to get
feedback from the mechanism
although some locks attempt to make that
impossible
even if you can do both simultaneous
manipulation and tension
we are not considering drilling snapping
cylinder or dial pulling angle grinders
excessive torque melting thermal last
explosive liquid nitrogen or chemical
attacks
or any other destructive attack
that is a different problem uh for for
some high security locks um they will
use a re-locker so this is a sacrificial
portion in front of the lock
and if you were to destroy the
sacrificial portion say using
any of the aforementioned methods on
this slide
uh you will trip the relocker mechanism
and
the whole thing will brick itself
whether that be a vault door
or a safe or whatever it may be
so these are a not a quick way
to get through all locks uh particularly
high security implementations but
secondly although these are things you
may wish to consider when designing a
high security lock
just keep in mind that is not always uh
something
that is a priority for the locks that
we'll be looking at today
simply because that whole this whole
problem can be shifted elsewhere and
doesn't have to lie on the lock
we're also not considering direct cam
actuation over lifting bumping snap guns
triac keys rapping jiggly keys
impressioning self-impressioning
decoding with a visual audio or any
other method
x-ray attacks or ultrasonic attacks
these are all attacks that you will want
to consider if you are designing a high
security
mechanical lock but realistically this
talk will be
too long if i try to cover all of these
things so instead i will focus on lock
picking because it is
in a very narrow sense because it is
probably the best known
uh and probably the best understood uh
of the attacks you can ask me about any
of these
other attacks in uh questions after the
talk
so first off the most common attempt to
make unpickable locks has hinged around
the idea of making the mechanism
impossible to manipulate
so the the kind of earliest examples
that we had were heavily warded locks
and this was an incredibly effective
technique uh back when there were only a
handful a tiny handful of people who had
the required skills
knowledge equipment
and so on and so forth to manufacture
these
locks and the corresponding keys so here
we can see quite an intricate example
of a boarded lock um and you can see
that essentially the way it works is
if you have a key cut with a matching
pattern then it can pass through
these wards hence the term word boarded
lock
and the rest of the mechanism is
essentially just a single lever that
once lifted allows the bolt to move
so essentially if you can get uh if you
can get something sufficiently long
through this uh through the obstacles
and the wards and this lock
then you will be able to retract the
bolt and open the lock
today that doesn't work so well just
because manufacturing has kind of moved
on a bit
here's a modern implementation of
basically the same principle it still
survives today
this is a heavily warded lock designed
by urban hawk but in a pin tumbler
design and it features a very
paracentric
keyway so this is a keyway where there
is basically no straight line that you
can cut down the middle
and there is no pick thin enough that
will have free travel up and down
inside that keyway um
but this is a a relatively
basic attempt to prevent lock-picking
attacks uh
as much as i respect all the work urban
hawk has done on his design
um so we shall move onwards
to um a more complex design
uh the previous design is very effective
at warding things uh
in terms of your pick movement left and
right and up and down uh
but of course the lock would be more
secure if we could also create some kind
of warding
uh as we travel into the lock in that
third dimension
and that's exactly what the layers chain
key lock attempts to do
the uh this works as a conventional pin
double lock except
the key is made of lots of little
segments that are hinged together
and the key is injected into the lock uh
which allows you to then travel around
these three dimensions of warding as you
go into the lock
a much earlier example is the
schneckenschloss which translates as
snail lock from germany i believe
um and uh
here we have a thin key that winds in
through
an obstruction at the front of the lock
which we can
kind of see that on the left hand side
here that obstruction and so again
there's no straight pick that you could
push into this lock in order to
set the elements correctly
is uh another example of kind of this
idea of
creating heavy warding although this
time not in three dimensions uh what we
what we have here is uh the tan reliance
which was an
1800s bank lock and
the key feature here is that uh so this
was the lever lock with
lots of levers kind of shaped like this
uh but the special feature here is this
is a lever lock
that has this half moon shaped piece of
boarding that's actually attached to one
of the levers
and we can see that that would fit then
this l-shaped cut in this key
and the problem that you've got here is
that traditionally if you were going to
attempt to
pick a lever lock well you have a wire
that simulates the
the typically the end of the key and
that gets inserted into the lock and is
used to try to retract the bolt
and when the bolt stump then presses
against the levers
um we would use a another pick wire in
order to
manipulate those levers into the correct
positions
but that is an l-shaped wire and that
would simply not be able to get around
this
l-shaped board so we'd have to come up
with some more complex design
possibly involving multiple pick wires
with
intricate bends in them in order to get
around that l-shaped
piece of wood inside the lock
here's a a modern implementation of the
tan reliance
albeit done much less well uh
using a pin tumbler mechanism
uh and then again in a slightly
different direction but still on the
same theme
we have the warm held meter lock so this
was used on gas meters in the uk
and essentially the the principle behind
this is
the same rough idea is what makes the uh
the sofa problem in mathematics
challenging
the sofa problem is essentially this uh
this problem of
designing a shape that's quite good at
getting around a right angled bend in a
corridor
and so we have this large cylindrical
obstruction right at the front of this
lock
and the wall mould meter lock key has a
moving
tooth in the end of it basically and so
that retracts as it travels down the
channel
and then it extends once it's inside the
lock and is able to set the single lever
inside this lock
and open it however from a picking
perspective
if you don't have a tool with a moving
end
then you run into quite a conundrum you
can either have a pick wire
that is long enough to lift that lever
into the correct height
but then it won't fit down that
cylindrical channel
or you can have a pick that does fit
down that cylindrical channel
but then it won't be long enough to set
the lever at the bottom
then we have the rosengrens 32a81 this
is a
swedish lock designed by the swedish
safe
company rosengrens and it uses a
curtain um to protect the discs
inside so the way this mechanism works
is it has a large number of discs inside
that need to be rotated to the correct
degree uh and if that is done correctly
then the
gates cut into them all aligned to make
one nice long slot and there is a bar
that can drop in
in what is called a side bar mechanism
in order to allow the lock to open
but most distant hand locks do not
feature a curtain
a curtain is this this piece of movable
warding
in the center of this lock this turns
one to one with the key
but it makes it impossible to insert any
kind of conventional
uh disc detainer picking tool
then we come to the abloy classic this
is also a dis detainer
um this one has a very iconic
half moon shape this is a finished
design
and um uh
this was considered uh very very
difficult to pick for a very long time
um but the the
the key here the reason why it's so
difficult to pick is we have a half moon
shaped
opening in the front of the lock but the
but in terms of the possible
configurations of discs a minimum
movement disc
does not move at all and the maximum
movement disc has to move
90 degrees and it turns out it's
incredibly difficult to design a pick
that is both capable of turning
one of these discs 90 degrees and yet is
small enough to fit through the
remaining gap
if you find yourself unfortunate enough
to be faced with a
maximum and a minimum cut disk right
next to each other inside the lock
mechanism
huxley pig has written a paper on this
where he goes into much more detail on
exactly how this
works i highly recommend reading it if
you can find a copy
and then finally we get onto the
conforty safety deposit box lock
so this is used for safety deposit boxes
that's why we have two
uh kind of two openings for keys here we
think we have a
one on the left and we have this much
more complicated
uh mechanism on the right and we will be
focusing on the mechanism on the right
uh what's curious about this is we we
have these two levers that are connected
together
uh like a jigsaw um and while it is
relatively trivial to set this uh the
upper lever
uh that's not too difficult at all the
problem is that um
the bolt stump that wants to enter the
gate in the uh
in the top lever is attached to the same
piece of metal
uh as the bolt stump uh for the bottom
lever
for each of these lever pairs and so
once we once we set that top lever and
the bolt stump for the top
enters that uh gate a little bit and
holds helps hold that up in place
uh we then attempt to set the lower
lever
but the uh this curve on the uh on the
edge of this lever is very cunningly
designed
so that as we get closer and closer to
the gate on the lower lever
what we find is we find that we are
pushing backwards against that bolt
stamp
and if we if we want to set it correctly
well
we're going to have to allow that bolt
stump to move backwards a little bit and
the problem there is if we allow that
backwards a little bit while we release
the lever above
and then they both drop and then we have
gotten nowhere and so with any
conventional picking tool
you will be caught in an infinite loop
of set top lever
attempt to set bottom lever and as you
attempt to set bottom libra release top
lever
resetting the whole thing and having to
start over
so now we come onto onto designs uh
that attempt to make it very difficult
to apply tension to the mechanism
even though it might be quite easy to
reach the various components and move
them around
so the first example we have is the van
lock this is a tubular lock
and we can see the seven pins there and
what's curious about this is the seven
pins come flush with the face of the
lock
and so this means there is basically no
surface to grasp or gain purchase on to
apply tension to the lock
the way the key does it is it has prongs
that stick into the
pin channels which sets them to the
correct depths
but then is also used to tension off
and since some of the possible pins
that can exist in a van lock include a
zero
movement pins so pins that must not be
moved at all it can be actually quite
challenging
to pick this lock using any conventional
method
we then have the gold atoms this is a
very cheap chinese
made padlock but it has a very curious
mechanism
uh it uses a reverse sidebar mechanism
and the way a reverse sidebar mechanism
works is it has its own springs that
bias it
constantly in the opening direction so
we don't have to apply attention to this
lock
um because it is constantly trying to
open itself
the problem arises that uh the pins that
have the
the gates in it for the uh for the for
this sidebar to drop into
uh they also have their own springs and
those springs are stronger
than the sidebar springs so
we are unable to tension the lock uh in
any conventional way and because of that
uh when we set any pin to a correct
height
it's not very difficult to reach the
pins uh the problem is they won't stay
there
because as soon as you set one you have
no control over the amount of tension
that the lock tensions itself entirely
on its own terms
and so as soon as you move on to
manipulate another pin well that first
pin drops back down again
and this applies to any one of the pins
and it doesn't matter whether or not it
would be
correct in the binding order or not
there is
simply no way to progress unless you can
find another way to apply tension
to the mechanism
um unfortunately that image hasn't
loaded which is a little bit awkward
but i've got this image so the uema 750
is uh
is an interesting mechanism so this is a
chinese-made um
euro eurocylinder as well uh this one is
a little bit more fancy
it is again a reverse sidebar mechanism
uh but this one actually uses a reverse
sidebar in
two parts uh and the benefit of that is
in this particular
configuration if you attempt to tension
the lock it will just spin
round and round and round and round and
round and round
and the way it achieves that is it has a
front portion to the plug
and has a back portion to the plug and
only when this reverse sidebar mechanism
when both parts of the reverse sidebar
mechanisms were allowed to drop inwards
by having these sliders correctly
aligned can the front part be locked to
the back part and therefore open the
lock
so here we can see the lock with an
incorrect key inserted
and we can see that we have we have
these
silver sliders which have this v shaped
cut in them here
not correctly aligned we have this lower
portion of the reverse sidebar
and we have this little upper portion of
the reverse sidebar that is sitting
above the shear line
outside the outer circumference of that
plug
and so when we turn the key
i'll turn the plug with the wrong key
inserted
well nothing happens essentially
uh however if we insert the correct key
as we can see here we see both parts of
the reverse sidebar mechanism
do drop in and then what happens is the
the cam moves and we might be able to
see that
up on the top left hand side of this
here
that uh that that actually turns
so that brings us on to the crankshaft
lock and this is a lock that i had
quite a bit of trouble categorizing um
but i i think i've settled on on leaving
it here and this is a concept i don't uh
to the best of my knowledge it's never
been produced or at least hasn't been
produced yet um
uh but it's a ten slider lock uh these
sliders are these
little reddish pink portions we can see
over here and they have gates in them
and when all those gates are correctly
aligned this sidebar can drop it the
thing that's uh
difficult about this lock though is um
it's not very hard to see how to tension
it
uh we just need the correct tip on the
end of our tool
in and and just turn that in order to
apply uh
tension to the mechanism but the problem
is if you
design a tool with a straight shaft um
well it's very likely that that's just
not going to fit into the lock as we can
see on the right hand side here
with this convenient diagram there is no
straight line down the center of this
lock
to get there and the problem with just
creating a curve
as we can see with this illustrated uh
potential tool
um well we don't know what the curve has
to be the curve is
entirely dictated by the slider
positions and we can't know what the
correct positions on the sliders are and
so we can apply attention to the lock
so that's another very clever design
that brings me on to the chroma
protector the penultimate lock
in this portion uh this is a lock i have
given a talk on
at the defcon lock picking village last
year there's also a talk that
uh iago fargoland has given a talk on uh
a much better talk entitled uh the
unpickable chroma protector
uh for all set con and i highly
recommend watching his talk if you're
interested in this lock mechanism
the interesting thing about this lock is
that it is a wafer lock
i have often seen it categorized as a
lever lock
uh that is certainly not correct
um but i guess the reason is because
most people don't believe that one of
the most secure locks
ever designed uh is actually a wafer
lock
uh the thing that is particularly uh
secure about this wafer lock compared to
conventional wafer locks
that you will see on low security
cabinets
and that sort of thing uh is that the uh
the wafers
look like this and uh
the the key only can apply tension to
the core
uh via the wafers
and so what's unique about wafers is
if you are if you have a wafer lock that
is designed in this
sorted configuration then you can make
it impossible to tension the lock
without first having aligned at least
one wafer so in this case what
what we would see is um that the uh
the key is going to be longer at any
given portion on one side
than the other and as we turn that
inside the lock
uh the longer side will make contact
with the inside of the wafer first
and that will result in a lateral motion
a side to side motion
um pardon me
in a lateral motion first until the
other side of the key makes contact with
the other side of the wafer
so that's what we see when the lock
starts to turn because at that point the
wafer can no longer move side to side it
is jammed in place by the key
and so that rotational force in the key
is then transferred to the wafer and
that is then transferred to the core
which is that
blue portion of your scene
of course if that weren't intimidating
enough this is the border panzer design
that is the exact same sort of mechanism
uh but this time it features
uh wafers that slide uh left and right
and up and down
and uh the key features four beards so
uh this is a
phenomenally complex to pick
and unfortunately very rare
a much simplified and much smaller
format design
on the same principle is the chub ava
uh this is a a very small uh wafer lock
that is occasionally found in the uk and
uh it works on the exact same design
principles just with
fewer options
and that leaves me finally
finally to uh to the drive cam mechanism
that you can find in many safe locks not
just
or many combination dial safe locks not
just uh this
model 6741 made by sargent in greenleaf
but this is the one i happen to have so
this is the one
i will be using as an example what we
have here is
we have a number of different wheels
which are these silver portions that
have a gate cut into them
and this strange lever shaped thing
actually hides a bar
that rests along those levers and when
the gates in
the wheels are sorry wheels when the
gates and those wheels are correctly
aligned
underneath this uh this nose portion
uh then it can drop in and open the lock
and uh you might have noticed that
there's a little corner of a spring here
on this on this lever and uh that
constantly
biases the the lever against the wheels
so the mechanism is constantly under
tension
but the problem that we do have is this
black portion
and forgives the fact that this the
camera angle changes slightly here
um the the this black portion moves one
to one with the dial
and it's necessary to move that before
you can move any of the wheels
and so the problem is in this position
uh
that the the nose drops in slightly
uh because it has space it matches the
gate in the drive cam
uh and so at this point we have tension
against the wheels
but anywhere else that we move this this
drive cam
uh the the drive cam causes the the nose
to lift up
or the lever to lift up um and at this
point there is no contact against the
wheels and so
there is no way of tensioning the
mechanism uh unless
we are inside that little gate in the
drive cam
but unfortunately that also means that
we only have
any tension against the mechanism for uh
a tiny portion of the dial
that brings me on to mechanisms uh that
attempt to prevent simultaneous tension
and manipulation so we are typically
looking at blocking mechanisms here
uh the first and for those that are
aware of blocking mechanisms perhaps one
of the most famous examples
is the western electric 30c this is an
american pay phone lock
or was an american pay phone lock and
what's curious about this is it's it's a
lever lock um
and the the way that it works is we
we have a bolt stump that needs to come
across and test the levers
uh and we can move the levers as freely
as we like
uh but when we apply tension before the
bolt stop can come across
this serrated lever grabber interacts
with the
points on the tips of the levers and
immobilizes them
so here we can see the gate on
on the levers and we can see the uh the
stump
uh trying to enter that uh but we can
also see the lever grabber has already
grabbed all of those levers so we can
move the levers or we can apply tension
but when we apply tension
the levers are immobilized and we can no
longer move them so uh that makes
picking this lock
phenomenally difficult
we also have the fisheye 787 this uses a
very complicated mechanism
um i've i've colored in the patent
diagram
uh that i've found on on lock wiki um
and essentially uh this red portion is
the key
the key directly interacts with some
levers the lever then turns to gear
the gear has a gate and here on the left
hand side we can see all those gates
aligned
and then before the gates and the wheels
are tested there is a blocking mechanism
which is this
kind of blob to the to underneath the
orange gear
that has to engage with the wheels
or the gears before they're tested again
preventing them from being rotated
uh which again makes it very difficult
to pick the lock
the abloy protec and protect2 are also
locks that include a blocking mechanism
although
this time in a distant format
the nato mersey lock on the other hand
uses a slightly different mechanism
to achieve its blocking which i will
attempt to explain
uh the the curious thing about this is
uh so this is a 14 lever lever lock that
normally features two sets of levers but
what we see here
is we see only a single lever
uh and this has been set up so that it's
much easier uh to kind of illustrate the
way the mechanism works
so thank you to automaton for that um
we have this kind of uh strange uh
element here with a nose and um
add a pivot which is this portion here
we can see the corresponding one up here
as well that's the pivot for it
and there's the nose on the end of it
and uh here we can see
there is a pivot for the levers and the
pivot for the levers
is inside this pivoting portion itself
so when we apply tension to the lock uh
conventionally
what happens is um the these two
uh stumps which are attached to the bolt
they just move
nicely into the gate when we use the
correct key and the lock opens totally
normally
however if we apply tension and
everything is not already in the correct
position
then what happens is the bolt stumps
press against the levers
and the levers press against their own
pivots
and the pivots then cause these elements
to move and when they rotate around
their pivots
they drop this kind of nose in into a
corresponding slot
inside the bolt work and immobilize the
bolt
and so when you when you attempt to
tension the lock in the open direction
then
what you find very quickly is none of
the levers are binding up and instead
you are basically
just uh blocking the bolt um
with these these two noses um
which makes this lock phenomenally
difficult to pick
more recently we've had uh shane's stuff
lock
which i believe is uh about
sometime late last year uh where shane
who has a youtube channel where he
he does all sorts of interesting
engineering projects he thought he'd
turn his hand
to the problem of creating an unpickable
mechanical lock and by his own admission
it was much harder than he thought it
would be which i find validating
but essentially the way his lock worked
is it would uh set the pins
to um a given set of heights
and then it would immobilize those pins
and then as you turn the key
you would lose access to those pins you
could not reach them and then the pins
would be tested
against a complex kind of series of
warding
um i highly recommend i highly recommend
watching his video
uh because he he does give you and i
have much better idea than i can
of how his lock works uh
and it's quite fun
uh that leaves us uh with locks
that attempt to deaden feedback
um despite perhaps being able to tension
them or manipulate them
so coming back to the uh sergeant green
leaf
6741 this is a combination dial safe
lock
and although it's it's quite tricky
because you can't really tension the
mechanism very easily
um turns out that is not a completely
impossible
lock to manipulate and so there are
various combination dial safe locks
which while having the benefit that um
that they largely dictate how you can
interact with it uh so you know you
don't have a key way you can't insert
your own tools
you basically only have the option to
turn left or right on the dial
um they have then on top of that attempt
to incorporate mechanisms to make it
very difficult
to get any feedback out of them so one
of these is another lock made by
sergeant
greenleaf this is the 8550
and the way this works is um where
you're going to have to look past this
large silver sprung element but we we
again have a drive cam this time
in a brass color we have our wheels
which we can see behind here
largely alive we have this curious
little
silver portion attached to the drive cam
and we have this rather odd
silver thing attached here as well you
can see behind that there is also
what looks to be and is a
and otherwise largely normal uh lever
nose
and the thing that's that's curious
about this is uh in this particular
position
uh the the lever is held up by this
spring and is not touching the wheels
but as we turn the drive cam uh this
silver portion will make contact against
the slope
and it will push the uh this
silver portion up over this little ledge
and it kind of clicks in
above this ledge and it's held there and
what that does is it basically
stores a lot of uh stores a lot of
kinetic energy
in this kind of spring and the drive cam
itself can actually move
front to back so kind of depth wise as
we look into the picture
and that means that the mechanism can be
uh released
and if it's in the wrong position well
then it will it will bring the lever
nose down the lever nose will test for a
moment of a second
uh but then it will effectively bounce
off the wheel pack
uh and so you only have that momentary
fraction of a second
to get any information out of the lock
before the uh before the lever is once
again
raised off the wheels
if you've aligned everything correctly
then as it fires it fires
fully all the way uh into the the slots
and
in the wheels and you can then retract
and open the lock
similar mechanism also by sergeant and
greenleaf
is the clock it has a few other names as
well
which i have and hopefully not included
but again this is a similar sort of
mechanism we have a uh we have a
silver uh lever of some kind now we
we have some brass wheels hidden behind
this plate
and we have a very curious looking drive
cam the drive cam
includes a spring and essentially
what happens is in its default position
uh
it kind of looks like this and so there
is no gate
to be found
as it turns what we find is it will wind
this
mechanism and we uh
we actually get the gate revealed uh for
a moment
and uh again if we're very lucky
and everything is perfectly aligned well
then the lever nose will be able to drop
into that gate and
it will prevent the uh the this
uh a clever cam mechanism from then
immediately
concealing the gate again and if we did
not get everything correct
well then what happens is that the lever
touches down against the wheels for a
moment of a second and then the sprung
element that is released
immediately pushes it back out of the
way and we get back into this position
here
where there is no gate and we have no
information
and then we have the manifoil mark iv so
this was a british
ministry of defense lock and it uses a
cunning
uh two-part drive cam so this drive cam
actually has two levels to it that needs
to be aligned in order to create the
gate
as we can see here but it also has
these uh two rather devious rollers
that uh make it very very difficult to
tell the difference uh
as to whether or not you're trying to
get information from uh the nose on this
lever which is actually useful
or if you're just working with one of
the two specially designed
rollers that can be very very tricky to
work out indeed
and then finally uh i'm going to bring
you on to some special considerations
it turns out my categorization method my
categorization method is not perfect and
i was unable to categorize every high
security lock that i wanted to
so i thought i would take a look at some
special considerations
that don't fit my schema but
nevertheless
have some interesting value that we
might want to take a look at
so first of all we have the chub
detector this was the unpickable lock of
the
1850s roundabouts until it was picked in
the 1850s
um and the way this works is uh
there are so there are lots of
implementations of the child detector it
has a very long history
um but essentially this is a lever lock
but what's curious about it is we have
this little pin that sticks out of
this lever and this pin rests across all
the other levers that would be laying in
front of it
and what happens is essentially if any
of the levers ahead of it is lifted too
far
during a manipulation process then it
will trip the detector mechanism
so here we can see the detector
mechanism is tripped so what's happened
is this lever has been lifted too high
and this small sprung portion has then
slipped over this little
lip and it then jams in place and
prevents
any movement of the bolt in the opening
direction if on the other hand we press
in the closing direction
then we are able to once again reset the
lock into this position so
the lock is not uh bricked as it were
uh if someone attempts to manipulate the
lock and anyone with the correct key can
uh
can once again reset the mechanism
and then turn the key in the opening
direction in order to open the lock
but this kind of trap mechanism does
make picking
very tricky um
for those who have not yet seen it seth
gould's coffer
as filmed in forged and filed which is a
video you can find on vimeo
this is an absolutely stunning video uh
seth gold spent
two years uh constructing this kind of
medieval style
coffer and although i can't show you it
very easily
essentially i believe there's something
like 11 steps
to opening this coffer even if you have
the correct key
so having the correct key on its own is
not sufficient there are a whole series
of hidden buttons and switches
and and steps where the key has to be
turned only 90 degrees and then it will
allow something else to open
and so on uh that are required in order
to open the coffer
and again you know you you could be able
to pick the mechanism
uh but that wouldn't necessarily result
in the lock opening
uh then we have the uh the rks the robo
key systems design
this is a tiny tiny combination lock
and uh in its kind of final form at
least
as far as it has today um the
uh it only has five wheels um but the
the whole idea behind the
railroad key systems design was to have
a large number of
combination wheels so you essentially
have a
a very um a very complex well
not a very complex it's quite a simple
uh combination lock
uh but it is one that will take an
incredibly long time to dial
and the robo key systems uh lock is then
paired with
an electromechanical uh key that
basically
has a motor in it and you engage that
motor and you you
press the buttons to put in your
combination and it will very very
rapidly
dial in your combination into this tiny
little
uh combination lock and it's not so much
the uh manipulation mechanism or
manipulation method for this is not
known it's just that it would take a
very very long time with a lot of wheels
uh to the point where it's kind of
infeasible
we've also got things such as these uh
registered
male counter padlocks from the us
uh they have these counters that
increment by one
every time the plug is turned um so they
might not be the hardest thing to pick
once or twice but you're going to have
to pick them
9999 more times if you want to conceal
the fact
that you picked the lock
so again
another interesting consideration that
uh
can make a lot quite high security and
tamper evidence um
obviously these were for avoiding
tampering with post
and then we have unfortunately a rather
blurry picture of uh
my favorite lock as it happens to be uh
the retina change key safe lock
so the so this is a lever lock where we
have a lever with these
teeth on the end of it and that engages
with this
this sort of gear that has the gate in
it and
uh so lifting the lever causes the gear
to turn and the correct key
causes the levers to lift the correct
heights turning the gears to the crate
the correct amount however what's
interesting is that
when the bolt moves inwards it also
disconnects the levers
uh from the wheels and so the the result
of that is
that every time you unlock the lock uh
it zeros itself
and it will then key itself to whichever
key you use to lock it back up again
so the idea here is clearly for uh you
know banks
if the bank manager realizes that one of
the keys is missing well it's
pretty much trivial for him to change
the key uh he can do it in
just a minute by simply unlocking the
bolt
and then locking it again uh with a new
key that he knows
um you know isn't uh missing and hasn't
been copied or tampered with or whatever
but from a picking consideration that
means that you could pick
a lock like this open
but you would have a very very hard time
to then correctly lift all of the levers
simultaneously
to the correct matching heights when you
lock
the lock again and while that might not
seem like such an issue most of the
benefit of using lock picking as an
entry method over
any other manipulation method or method
of getting in
um is that it's covert it's that people
won't uh won't notice that you have
picked the lock
it's for extraction normally of
information for example
otherwise you might as well use a
destructive attack
uh so i find it very cool that this is
basically a lock with a
very high amount of tamper evidence
finally i'd like to give my special
thanks to all the people on this list
for their either their direct help by
providing photos
uh or their encouragement or the
conversations i've had with them
uh to help me work out how to categorize
the locks in this talk
so thank you very much to all of those
people in particular
and that's the end of my presentation so
if you've got any questions
i believe we will now be moving to a
question and answer section