my name is Karl I work at lateral
security as a security consultant and I
have quite a few issues of privacy being
stolen or sold from me
well objection rather than issues so
lateral security does security
consulting work we have 15 technical
staff and some more support staff we
offer a variety of services right so
down to the business what is privacy
it's the right to be let alone this term
comes from ating the late 1800s
thus it sounds rather funny and modern
English harvard law book organization
thing the thing they release started RIF
that this comes from Daniel Saul's book
called understanding privacy is so I
heard from Wikipedia so right to be left
alone let alone you don't want people to
bother you you should be allowed privacy
thus the word in its own definition the
option to limit their access others have
to one's personal information just
because they're not talking to you
doesn't mean they can't know about you
you should have the entitlement to
privacy you should be able to choose
what people know about you and what you
tell others and what people know you're
telling others control over the
information people have um the Privacy
Act is very good of this you can
complain and they will do something
about it hopefully and you hit another
for additional concepts which I didn't
find interesting so why do I care this
is an interesting story I was away on
holiday taking a flight not quite in a
Zeppelin but still exciting I wanted
someone to t3
as people do and I got a prompt which
you can't really see down here and that
lovely 720p we have got what is your
address zip code and other stuff there
and I thought
well I'm moving here at the moment to
what address do I give them my current
address or my new address I'm picking
this duty-free up and shop why do they
need my address at all so I looked
through their privacy information
because hey they're asking for some
information and it's perfectly easy to
get out of this by sending an email to
inquiries at blah saying I don't want
you to use my personal information for
marketing purposes but by the time
you've done that you have already given
them your details in the first place so
yes I took quite a projection to that so
I thought about it a bit more your
personal information is your name your
email who's got a name here just yeah
some of you don't have names your secure
email phone number address employer
details appearance and tress hobbies so
all of these things for social
engineering that would help them out a
lot if they had any of that I'm just
you're right to be a little Lauren you
don't want them to have your address or
you don't want unsolicited mail with
email or a real mail so why do people
need with some formation the answer is
they don't but how do they get it anyway
so yes you're no trade off if you want
to get packages delivered to you then I
guess they need your physical address
you could have a proxy address you could
have a PA box if you want to be there
but what is the trade off to you
I'm giving out your personal address for
me if I'm picking it up in shop I am not
going to give you my personal address so
a Facebook Twitter something Google+
then your Pinterest LinkedIn and
Instagram I'm not too schooled on social
media because it has my personal
information if I use it so like LinkedIn
is a prime example of who does this
person work for what do they do there
what can I gain out of attacking this
person social engineering and stuff like
that Pinterest has all your interests so
if you want to know what someone's into
stalking them I'm another one that has
your other interests would be tinder and
they record all your messages and
someone did an interesting blog post
when they went hi gender I'd like to
know what personal information you have
on me under the Privacy Act of America
you need to tell me and I can amend it
if required so they came out with a big
list of these are all your previous
conversations you said this to this so
this company could do a UI learning and
stuff on that and find your interests
and record that against I believe
Facebook is here you see sorry mechanism
so yeah they could know quite a bit
about you and the way people get it is
the sign up page hey give us all your
information like a lot of the services
you don't even need a name or an email
address email is for password recovery
yes but your first name and last name
why do you need that for a Pinterest
account for instance why can't you just
have here is my anonymous account and I
look at stuff and you remember it for me
and the favorite one down the bottom
right there and hard to see as you have
won a free gift please enter your
personal details here to claim it which
probably gets quite a few people still
unfortunately and hey can you subscribe
to this competition to do that you just
need to text us your email address so
now that I've got hey you've seen the ad
hey we know your text number because you
sent it to us and we have an associated
email address for this text number if
any of our marketing partners already
have this email address they now have
your phone number as well so how do we
get the digital data some interesting
things here battery indicators there's
an html5 feature now to read the battery
state and it requires no prompting from
the user so just play visiting a website
they know if you're plugged in on charge
if you're the type of person who runs
around and 1% battery life nicer time
general things like that no prompting
from a browser you're for Tory's have
EXIF data so they know when and where
the photo was taken
assuming your device was up to date and
hit a real time clock
Wi-Fi probes you're shouting out
constantly
as my Wi-Fi available um it really
catches me out as other people I don't
have any social media but I had a social
media presence because I was in that
photo on that person's account and again
messages are fewer using an Apple
messenger not saying that they do or
don't but they have access to your
messages probably and they can make a
profile based on that tinder again was
an interesting one I read about of
that's quite a lot of very very very
very personal information that logging
and having access to and just general
device compromise and a fun one of let's
buy their data from someone who already
has it what you have noisy and because
you signed yes you can share my data if
everyone because I really want to use
Facebook so to get your location we have
got GPS which is an obvious one you're
wearing it in your pocket nearby Wi-Fi
you're wearing it in your pocket and
your laptops also use it so if you use a
browser we're we're ma functionality
it'll use SSID lookup MAC address lookup
from around here and then file it off to
Google if you're in chrome and Chrome
has Google has an archive of this Wi-Fi
access point is located here
you've given me these three that will
put you about here and you get about
half a block accuracy from a laptop of
no GPS nearby cell phone towers your
gain where anything your pocket and they
can find you that was a bit intimidating
context I having really good pizza right
now at the foundry oh so you are now at
the foundry I just told you where it is
or I am about to hit down to the
supermarket you know where I'm gonna be
so it's word related but it gives you
some context of what people are doing IP
addresses if you're not through a VPN
then your IP address locks you down to
an accuracy of 30 level usually maybe
the wrong 30 depending on your provider
but they at least know you're in New
Zealand and they can tell you hot
singles in your area New Zealand flag
which I'm signing will commencing and
historical information hi at the gym
again this to say my favorite thing to
do where do you think I'm gonna be next
Tuesday and the interesting one little
story here the hacker known as 4chan
does anyone know the hacking on its
fortune personally so this is it for
those who don't know it's a term coined
by a journalist who thought that an
internet forum was a entity or a single
entity so how a 4chan finds your
location this is a great little story of
Sheela booth any takers for Sheela both
being a good idea not right so he
decided instead of acting I'm going to
be an artist and instead of liking Trump
I'm going to oppose Trump
so he made a campaign called we will not
be divided and he went outside the New
York Museum and had a camera there for
people to go up and say we will not be
divided
Trump is empower but we won't let it
stop us so obviously we are in front of
New York art gallery as a kind of
giveaway that that's where he is so they
went there and they started trolling the
camera on live feed so then he took
objection to that and moved it to New
Mexico at which people don't want to
travel there probably so went fine until
someone was reciting poetry in the night
and gunshots were heard on the camera
anyway it's not safe to have this here
so he went what can I do so people won't
troll me but I can get my artistic
message out and he went to the middle of
nowhere planted a flag and a field or a
live stream on it nothing around it and
left that there and then people were
watching the live stream and went oh
there's a plane flying that direction to
that direction at this time and there's
another plane at this time and although
it's nighttime now I recognize that
constellation that's and that so it's
looking south okay I'm given those
planes and things we've narrowed it down
it up right send someone out there on
the ultimate location beacon is driving
a truck
around and afield honking the horn so
they sent someone out there honking the
horn when they heard the honk start to
come up on the feed they knew that
narrowing on and 36 hours later after
he'd potted this camera up and it filled
the hacker known as 4chan had located it
so yeah you're not safe from anything
really so these are a sample of personal
tracking devices that people would like
to carry around your car fob if the car
knows you're there to unlock then anyone
else that's the same hardware would know
that you're there don't lose me the
little Bluetooth dongles will tell you
exactly where your keys are they'll tell
me exactly where your keys are anti
fifth things are kind of cool to stop
people stealing but if you put silent
alarms around the room you can trying to
see how people are carrying the one I'm
carrying clothing around your shop or
hardware barcodes if you have a barcode
that your skin say you want to discount
on your groceries and the cost to you is
just your privacy you have a match to
your name address postal probably email
address and now they know that you liked
playing cucumbers and celery and this
day at this time and happens every week
so now you're felling your privacy for
what a $2 discount off broccoli and gym
memberships or whatever that car does
that I stole off the internet from
Wikipedia Commons so it's perfectly
legal to be up there you scan your card
to say hey I'm allowed in this existing
and the you know such you as you get
access to Cineworld
and the benefactor demo so you know
exactly who's got access to sunny worlds
when you're going there and probably
what you're buying or doing there and
your foreign which has GPS Bluetooth
Wi-Fi cellular to find that stuff and
yeah a web browser to tell everyone over
the web browser or any malicious apps
that you install or don't install so why
why do people want your privacy
they can sell products to you they can
sell advertising to you
at you yeah I corrected that and selling
your details through marketing partners
which is whoever they want to sell it to
for the right price and they improve
your experience if you have a better
experience you will buy more from them
you'll visit them more and you will make
them more money so in general your
privacy is a great commodity and
whatever the cost to you you can assess
whether it's worth getting 20 cents off
your broccoli but some are legal
requirements if you're a bank or
financial institute there's anti money
laundering laws they may need to track
your actual details drug laws if you're
buying restricted medicine then they
need to make sure you're not doing on
bulk and you know they don't want the
reason they adhere to these legal
requirements as they don't want to lose
money and why is all this because our
accompanying companies make money and if
they don't make money they're no longer
a company so running a bit fast but
there should be an awesome live demo
Rescue Me networks
boom boom oh look at that
so this is a 50 line Python application
that I wrote or if about 50 lines of
HTML on the front and it's nothing Wi-Fi
probes for every time your phone tries
to connect to something that's well oh
um
check out a prog sign high as this Wi-Fi
access point there and if it is at all
connect in a photo sent it will ask for
the next one and then if it doesn't who
asked for the next one and if it doesn't
who asked for the next one I'll just
scroll the server because getting bigger
hold yourself away but to get yeah there
you go
anyone recognize themselves up there
I'm congratulations I've sitting in the
front for a farm Wi-Fi turned on on your
foreign oh yeah
isn't it pretty this is um vis je s
which makes it very easy and it looks
really cool it's just the Krusty Krab
nori this is Patrick um can't lift all
come on guys
truest goose and perfect gift
yep not trying to name shame I'm just
reading things as they pop up because
it's interesting
anyone recognize he named Mia and
willing to get geo locations based
offers I also try and find something non
hi Carl yes that someone having fun
there I'm getting co-workers taking with
us right so I will pick one that
hopefully will show up you see wireless
which is local but let's see what
happens if I double click it does my API
work extremely rate limited
no errors are good or I don't have Wi-Fi
go to the center of each of those is a
location that has UC Wireless which is
not surprising although not that
interesting given we probably knew that
so that's got channel hopping on as well
so it probably landed it off right
someone's trying to seek rely me doing a
live Wi-Fi tomorrow is not the best idea
oh that happens to be around the epic
center who would have thought yes so now
from everyone out here and the Wi-Fi
making your probe request I can find out
where your Wi-Fi hotspots are um this is
using legal dotnet which is a
crowdsourced wardriving application so
yeah I can find out where you love that
is all thank you oh and one last slide
because I have to just noise by the name
all your questions of course any
questions final slide for questions
because I think I'm running under time
got five minutes as he five minutes
worth of questions on how you're being
tracked while you're being tracked and
anything like that yes
that's a good question um so I have got
my own domain and everything I sign up -
I give it that domain at my domain as an
email so as soon as I get an unsolicited
email I can go hey it's coming
- as aimed at this mailbox under my
catch-all and I can go this guy here
he's busted my privacy
which reminds me of a gain topic of the
day um Pizza websites there's a unnamed
pizza company which got popped recently
I'm not blaming anyone but that giggling
in the corner there and someone picked
up that it was this company which did it
because he ordered a pizza under the
name for a fifth of whiskers or
something as a jerk and then he got an
email from an unsolicited email address
saying hi professor whiskers would you
like blah and went well the only company
I have given these fake tito's through
was this company that companies preached
me not naming any Domino's yep yep this
is the main point of the privacy as it's
a trade off
you have functionality or you have
privacy you can run around in the
airplane mode but you won't have Wi-Fi
and you won't have cellular
functionality you know I have a brick in
your pocket
so yes why you know playing mode should
work and till you start going around and
reactivating Bluetooth which you can -
an airplane mode and then you're opened
up again
don't deal with them how can they yell
at me if I'm not on Facebook yes because
it's easy I haven't used it but there's
a lot of professional acts like you go
home it'll put your phone and a
particular ringing volume or something
and it work you have a different ring
profile the turning stuff off when you
don't want it's probably fine but again
airplane mode you can still - and
Bluetooth on if you've turned off Wi-Fi
and Bluetooth you're still doing
cellular beacons and then I completely
skipped over but any of fee if you're in
a physical proximity or your phone and
it's happy then it's gonna start running
out in your fee stuff as well
any more questions
yep
I'm not naming and blaming anyone but if
you think about the information you
provide to others and why they actually
need that information such as duty-free
does not need to know where I live
and if you look at their privacy
policies are all quite honest and hiding
that the selling your details it'll be
in the service agreement that you're
agreeing to but it's in the bottom or in
the middle and you're not gonna see it
but if you look through all your
providers you'll find out how much
you're getting taken from you and again
the bottom line is it's a trade off do
you want to be able use internet if so
you're gonna have to sacrifice some
privacy if you want to use Facebook
you're gonna have to sacrifice a lot of
privacy if you want to use anything else
in just the risk that this year and what
you're willing to share for the gain yep
so I've only had one real complaint that
I've made to someone cuz I was selling a
house and if you typed in my house I
came up with a flatmate website and I
couldn't do I could deactivate my
account but I couldn't delete my account
and no matter what I did that data was
still setting the owner deactivate an
account so I emailed them and said hey
privacy act what are you doing I want to
remove all personal data basically the
email goes Privacy Act says you can have
my data for as long as you need it I
don't no longer need your services
please remove my data and this was just
a one-man band or something and the next
day said hi Carla your data is being
removed and then so there's just a
Google entry pointing to a blank thing
and then I contacted Google by the
automated system and said hey this
website has no longer functioning that's
link can you please remove it and then
it took me off Google so if you don't
want your private data out there you can
remove yourself from the internet if
people will comply
hopefully guys my answer um oh my cough
um what you could do is set up I'm going
through all the config there are ways to
turn most of the stuff off if you have
professional Edition if you're in a home
edition good luck off there and if
you're really done you can go into your
file and like hostname block a lot of
the microsoft analytics I think it's
called Watson for this stuff and just
look at the traffic going out and go I
didn't ask for that traffic I'm gonna
block that domain so you can't do some
but it would be a pain maintaining that
white blacklist of bad marks off links
or any other company you're trying to
block oh and another fun thing all these
air tracking things and should use
vulnerabilities because I found a
product which had ad tracking in it or
it was an HTTP product and the ads were
loaded over HTTP and man-in-the-middle
resulted and remote code execution so
yeah
adding ads and tracking networks team to
introduce vulnerabilities as well if
you're gonna be that way inclined cool I
think that's about time I'd imagine and
took him
[Applause]