thank you for joining us today for a
second annual size Nova I wanna stop by
thanking a few people here organizing
these type of events is more than just
putting together one day conference it's
about giving a platform for a community
to network come together and share
information on that note so I want to
start by thanking a few people for their
support in making sure besides nobody
successful events and continues to be
one I also like to thank the review pick
I select the talks and put together a
schedule the speakers for sharing their
expertise with the community as a matter
of fact I'd like to thank not just a
speaker but every single person that
submitted a call for paper these
individuals that what make the content
for these conferences so I encourage
anyone that wants to have an influence
on what gets disgusting security
confidence to submit for a talk in the
future I also like to thank our sponsors
of course without the generosity we
wouldn't be able to have events like
these their funding goes beyond just
funding for this one-day event he also
goes into supporting his programs we
mentor Meetup middle school and high
schoolers and cybersecurity topics that
hands-on experience
and on that note I also like to thank
all the mentors that helping me with
that program here the list is so long to
thank them individually but their
support is amazing I would like to also
thank all the volunteers that been
working hard the past three days and
making sure everything flows smoothly so
can even have them and on that note I
would like to introduce Matt DeVoe our
morning keynote matt is a technologist
and entrepreneur and an international
security experts I know how hard it is
to pull off an event like this with
tremendous amount of work and I also
have a middle schooler who participates
in the Sunday hacking section so
grateful for that as well I am usually a
walker when I present but I'm told that
there are people try and stand still why
am I here I've been involved in this
community for quite some time there may
be companies up there that you recognize
that I've been part of I recognized 25
years ago really from a national
security perspective of the hacker who
was into political science a national
security issues that the two were
becoming injured intertwined and we're
gonna be dependent on each other that
there was an inherent risk based on our
vulnerability in our technology and the
role that technology was playing in our
society and I kind of built a career
around that first as a hacker working in
the Department of Defense and Intel
communities then out in the private
sector have been the founder of a couple
of different companies the Terrorism
Research Center fusion X I was one of
the founding employees that I defense
and most recently left in November as
the head of the global cyber defense
practices at Accenture so this is an
that I've been involved with for quite
some time and I've also known as the
toaster guy back 21 years ago I wrote a
paper called information terrorism can
you trust your toaster that typically
when I get introduced up the introduced
has to choose two person but back then
we greatly predicted a lot of ways in
which the world was going to go
including as you can see that the joke
around the internet of things with the
emergence of connected devices which
twenty-one years ago was not something
that a lot of people were talking about
but also in the talk later in the
presentation about what are some of the
things that we got wrong as well I love
events like these because it lets me
speak to I consider to be my peers and
I've tried to build a little bit of
something for everyone in here at the
core I am right I started as a technical
actor breaking into systems parlayed
that into kind of being an entrepreneur
these days I have got a much different
level I'm looking for systems in society
that are susceptible to change things
that can be transformed through
technology-based those remains the same
trying to figure out what to say to a
broad audience I'm hoping in the
audience we have some attackers with
defenders we maybe have some management
folks so I wanted to build a
presentation that stepped through a
bunch of different perspectives based on
the role that I've played in this in the
first I wanted to do was for the red
teamers in the audience I sat down after
being a red teamer for 20 years and said
one of the 20 there are 10 things that
I've determined over the course of my
career that are most important so in
step you through those 10 kind of
lessons learned the first is what I call
asymmetry everywhere
we're always taught that there's yin and
yang and you need balance and even in
Star Wars bring balance to the force
right and I've learned over time that
that is not true we are always seeking
revenge right and the challenge for us
in the cybersecurity domain is to make
sure that the good guys have live image
that our systems are more secure that
they're taking away that attack revenge
on a broader level we need to make sure
that as we are introducing technology
that they are providing a benefit to
society they're gonna go either way
they're going to be you know the
providing for greater evil in society or
greater benefits I think that is also a
challenge we need to face losses
recognition that don't look for balance
look to gain advantage look to seek that
advantage look to to get that asymmetry
in your favor
over time familiar military folks stands
for observe orient decide it's the
decision-making framework that was put
together by a Air Force fighter pilot
named John Boyd one of the things I've
recognized over time is a human wearing
Anubis shirt in cybersecurity their
essays and things that you can read
about that but that we were also facing
this scenario in which that Hooda loop
is going being compressed right and
we're going to need to be seeking
greater agility there are other elements
of the cycle that you need to take out
more trusted machines because on the
attack side the machines are becoming
automated or autonomous right so I throw
that out there about thinking about how
we can compress that into Luke how we
can factor in better agility around what
we're doing not only for a red team
perspective but from a defensive
perspective an analogy that's often used
and kind of demonstrating the benefit of
agility in the loop is if you're playing
a game of chess and you offer up to
somebody that you will take half your
pieces off the board but therefore every
time they move you get to move twice
even with half the pieces that chess
novice can beat a chess master right
because you've introduced that agility
so we need to figure out ways and bring
the futility into the equation to our
benefit no artificial constraints this
was something that I learned when I did
red teaming in the military in support
of a guy who's another person you can
Google is infamous for having brought
the red forces into play in a very big
and expensive war game and defeating the
US and coalition military partners in
less than two days one of the things
that I saw him speak to in a war gaming
environment
was he took his assets that he had of
which he had jeeps and tanks and used
mylar balloons and aluminum foil to make
the jeeps have a radar profile the
profile of a tank and then move them in
a particular direction the kindest the
enemy to respond with their tanks and
rap and what he was accused of saying
like oh you're cheating that's no fair
his response was what the bad guys don't
have access to aluminum foil and mylar
balloons too often when we are engaged
in red teaming environments the target
of the red team wants to impose
artificial constraints and I would argue
that you need to consistently push back
and say don't constrain me in any way in
which you can't get strange right if
you're if you're introducing constraints
now you're basically running a
simulation you're not running a red team
you're not truly testing to the extent
that a real adversary is give up your
car there is no spoon the great matrix
reference I'm sure most of you see that
I often get asked when I formed fusion X
we created a red teaming company that
operated with a ton of agility that
brought that atmospheric perspective to
the equation and I would often get asked
what's your assessment methodology and I
have worked with an assessment
methodologies for ever I was one of the
first people certified in the NSA
assessment methodology back to the 90s
have worked in all these different
environments that I said our methodology
is that there is no spoon I don't want
to again constrain how the red team is
fueling a particular network I don't
want to tell them the steps that they
have to follow in order to engage in the
red team we want to introduce some you
know basic parameters if you can kind of
an ethos or I do know arm things of that
sort in the engagement but I want them
to use their creativity in ingenuity and
the phrases that are often use I don't
want them to think outside the box I
want them to think without the Box right
if I am an attacker and I am motivated
to achieve a particular objective how do
I see the problem that's before they not
go to a checklist say what is the next
step that I need to follow
context is king I learned early on as
well that if you're going to be
successful in red teaming information
security that you have to be able to
articulate the problem in a way that is
meaningful to the person that you're
talking to there's a great story love to
tell back when I was very young red
teamer I stumbled into just based on my
capabilities to be the head of the red
teams of the department defense mid-90s
I got to travel around the world with
the team and break into any classified
or unclassified system that the US
military had it's a great gig for a guy
from Vermont who hadn't traveled a lot
that would just say
ye-yes Colorado yes spent a lot of time
in Florida but I remember in particular
the briefing one on one you gotta
imagine you know me 20 years ago
briefing a general who was the head of
our Special Operations myth and what I
was trying to brief him on one-on-one
was a particular issue I had encountered
in my red team and that he had a one
character password I think back 20 years
the introduction of computers
he's down in Florida at SOCOM with his
one curtain console and I said sir this
one character password is an issue and
he said son and I knew this was coming
because I talked to the staff son that's
my combat-ready password like okay but I
had a strategy and now I was gonna try
and bridge this gap between the Snake
Eater general it's so common the 25 year
old kid that was trying to get him to
change his behavior and I had been there
when his predecessor was in command as
well and there through the transition
and one thing that I noticed was that
when he arrived whether he drove himself
or was driven in that parking lot at the
SOCOM headquarters building he engaged
in what he called combat brain functions
very butchers are those that are
familiar means you back if you respond
right get the car you're ready to get
honest accompaniment going reverse and
drive put it in drive it though what was
interesting was I had observed that over
the course of two weeks
everyone in that SOCOM parking lot
started backing into their parking space
after he started looking so I use that
to my advantage and said sir
here's the thing did you notice what
happened in the parking lot after you
started pulling in doing your combat
ready parking of course pay attention
everybody else is doing you this problem
I said so how long do you think it's
going to be until the people in your
command whether you think your account
is working or not the people in your
command that are in the field not
sitting in Florida start instituting a
one crypto password I'll change my
effing password
I used the effing because my
nine-year-old son is sitting in the
center of the audience might have a
little bit more color to it so
understanding how to communicate and
effectively drive behavior that you're
trying to change is something that I've
heard over and over and over right and
the Attell community they refer to
bottom line up front learn that as well
right if you are gonna have limited
amount of time or you might be
interrupted what is the most important
messaging what you have to convey
getting that up providing tools are not
Talent
this was a finding when I was running
another red team and we were given what
I would call like the best of the best I
was running a red team that was a
coalition team rows of five eyes the
zealand australia canada UK in the u.s.
in each country and donated some
offensive smokes and they had also
donated and what i figured out early on
was that the people that were given to
me were more valuable than their
separate humans because they had the
ability to emulate and innovate use
their imagination bring you thought
processes that despite the fact that
this disability exit for schools the
talent was the most important thing and
I saw the reverse of that as well right
I couldn't give an untalented works that
are really good tools and expected
legitimate outcome just didn't work that
way so we constituted what we call kind
of like there was the equivalent of a
fireside chat a kind of interim a stir
and apprentices certain people that
weren't talented or peridot booth folks
over time in order to learn how they
think and
used so tools are not Talent you can't
script an adversary again going back to
the methodology right there is a benefit
to automating technology using automated
tools to check check the security
posture the environment what you don't
ever want to script them you can't
script human behavior you can't script
how a human is going to focus their
decision treatment given an objective
that they're troubled to achieve at work
the attacker is not at 1 or a zero
so they I came up with my friend Jay
healings now Columbia up in New York we
wanted to bring the human factor back
into the equation
too often we sit and think about the
technology or the attacker as what we're
seeing a view that we're seeing on the
systems but we need to recognize it at
the end of the other protection a
keyboard is a live human being even if
you're facing some sort of automated
tool it was coded based on one of the
things we tried to do at fusion X's
bring that human component into the
equation what is the threat model what
capabilities do they have what are they
trying to achieve right if you have a
Russian organized crime on your network
and your commercial entity they're
likely trying to make money right so the
decisions they are making and how they
view your network and how they move
laterally and what they decide to
compromise are going to have that focus
so you need to bring that human attacker
focus to the equation was pumped the
10th man rule made famous by the movie
World War Z right if you have the person
who is required to dissent against the
particular course of action is something
that I always have found very valuable
right teammate having the person that
it's challenging the status quo that is
countering the consensus that you might
have on the team to check new ideas or
to think you critically about the course
of action that you're about to take
speaking truth to power something that's
got me in trouble many times over the
years but I have a new filter I've
always told people exactly what I think
there have always provided that
assessment as well
can decode it spent once 45 minutes with
my team that was talking to the sea so
at a very large customer of ours
publicly traded customer
debating over the region of one bird
backed down because changing that word
would have changed the presentation of
the sign right so making sure that you
stick to your guns and that you are
articulating well the findings as you
see them they've been keeping track this
now many lessons we got I told you 10
but I built it a bonus right because I
added this after the fact after it came
up and that was getting out of
frustration don't call it but too often
I've worked with team they do certainly
oh man I got much sugar this happened
right luck is a result of the
circumstances you would write the
training the tools the perspective right
maybe and outcome in a particular that
if you're doing it at a B type thing
might be attributed to cotton but don't
ever give a briefing on you accomplish
something based on a particular
perspective the coupons the whole trail
of circumstances that brought you there
alright so we're going to shift gears
that was the attackers in the room soap
so you're happy that you can not off the
sleep coffee talk a little bit about
this to be what I encountered this quote
over year seven years ago with somebody
out in California is the perfect analogy
for the internet its problem right we
have something that provided this great
capability of communication changing
society but was not developed with
security in the original sins of the
internet was the fact that it was not
designed to be as important as it is
Steve Lukasik was the head of DARPA
at the time that ARPANET was started
totally once-over beer as well so maybe
there's a twelfth row which is drink
lots of beer
yeah he said hey we known that this was
going to be so important we would have
taken an entirely different perspective
right we just had no idea that this was
the catalyst was gonna happen
which to me raises all sorts of issues
we'll start talking about network
defense about the other aspect of this
is this is the new normal right we live
in an environment where the attackers
are the problem twenty years ago I just
making retention of prey they're trying
to get folks to embrace these ideas
cyber attacks were coming with cyber
conflict is coming the information
warfare was something that we're gonna
have to be dealing with now you cannot
you literally cannot go and read any of
the major news sites newspaper and not
encounter major storms right so we have
their attention for certainly but now we
have to live within that and deal with
the reality of it from a perspective
intellectual property theft I went on
the record I guess probably like four
years ago that I wasn't concerned about
intellectual property theft and I took a
lot of heat for that perspective from
academics and others on Twitter and
other social media and it wasn't that I
didn't think that we need to be
protecting our intellectual property it
was that I saw the development of a kind
of normalization or international norms
that would stop countries from engaging
in such a way that they don't fit we've
lost the other trend that I saw was what
I called innovation parity which if you
steal a bunch of intellectual property
you've reached this point where you say
if I apply the technical talent I have
to to stealing that incremental
improvement then you know actual
property over time or do I have applied
that technical talent that keep
innovating on that I eat itself and
we've seen that clearly right that it
places like China where they are
emerging as you know scientific whether
it's genetics core and artificial
intelligence investing a ton of money
and merging as a superpower on the
backbone of in our property that may
have been sourced from elsewhere so I
still think you need to think about
intellectual property but I don't put it
in the category of like national
security threats that I feel like
that that horse is already out of the
park at the time to protect Ivy was 10
to 15 years ago cybercrime obviously a
big one and not going away over time so
we have a huge requirement in a lot of
organizations for countering cybercrime
countering that ingenuity for those
folks that are motivated by making money
it make money they well folks at work in
the cyber defense practice know that the
criminals are successful they're still
money every day and innovative ways we
see it in the premise right who saw the
but to be just coupled as a great social
engineering attack against Google and
Facebook the resulted in a hundred
million dollars being stolen from each
of those organizations where was
somebody who actually interacted with
the accounts payable Department and
convinced them to say like hey I'm this
vendor and I want to change the bank
account in which how you deposit the
payments against our interest the
attackers didn't really even expect that
there was going to be successful they
didn't up the bank accounts created the
response to take back it's against of
course what bank account right that one
little switch and then every invoice
that that vendor was issuing is being
paid so sometimes even simple methods
are in it kept us off guard we don't
think of the Accounts Payable being a
huge grant somewhere obviously a big one
right the emergence digital currencies
and cryptocurrencies out there that
create a viable may for wealth to be
transferred associated with ransomware I
dealt with ransomware
he is far back because 16 or 17 years
ago it was cumbersome as to try and
figure out the path in which you would
pay the person they wanted to go through
some sort of Russian equivalent of
PayPal which was blocked by all the US
banks wire funder and take you a week
just to figure out how you of you pump
into the account that their asshole for
now it's easy right they give you the
sheet about at signup point and address
that even a grandmother can follow some
of our provide me with an 800 number
that you can call and get assistance
right so it
this is a an issue that is going to
become much more rather than over times
it's obviously all of our universities
espionage I think we all know the world
that cyber is playing it at the
traditional espionage domain why is that
I was moving to cyberspace the same way
that the bank robbers have moved to
cyberspace very City Rob's banks because
we're Canas why our SP is engaged in
cyberspace it's because it's very common
if Facebook is created what is the
greatest source of intelligence I think
ever perpetrated human history just
thinking about the volumes of
information connected immediately have
of course those platforms are going to
find of course people are the influence
operations through the rise just too
attractive because it is where today
what I call the kind of the leak
environment as well those that are
seeking to access information just to
post it online is going to be a
continuing trend we've seen this you
know most WikiLeaks but with others
whether its sense if information being
posted or state secrets this was my
experience in 2015 right anthem Experion
Experion OPM so health information
financial information and everything
else for those that are familiar they
are the holders of the sf-86 form that
you fill out when you're obtaining or
maintaining series as all of the
information about my family including
their social security numbers dates of
birth it has information about my close
contacts everywhere it would just rule
everywhere that I've ever lived my
foreign contacts as well right based on
my interactions with them it is a wealth
of information so if you just look at in
2015 if you're an attacker and you want
to target not devote you know more about
me than hide him about right which is a
little bit crazy
I am grateful this is a triangle and not
a square because it would have meant
that I was also involved with Ashley
Madison reach which I was not
thankfully my nine-year-old is not
laughing at that and everybody else's
and then we have the you know my
favorite movies of all time the the
cyber conflict cyber war the kind of
beyond espionage aspect frame which is
also a virtual it dive into that a
little bit deeper but recognizing that
our society is dependent on computers
and networks that is just the base
reality right there's no way to propose
that at this point and so it's obviously
going to be a domain of conflict partner
offense in 2010 officially acknowledged
that that cyber was a domain of conflict
so we have that reality that we have to
given its power its potential for that
to have a fairly drastic impact on
society freedom there are those systems
in which we are dependent on the
structure are connected to itself
against the structure that's had any
catastrophic impact I feel like you know
we have this misalignment where you have
the terrorist organization might have
the they don't have the capability and
then you have a nation state that has
the capability to do it but doesn't have
the intended right there's lots of
possible deterrents all these things
that come into play but in today's
environment where do we start to have
that misalignment that reaches that bar
where the bad guys with the intent that
are going to attack us no matter what
develop the capability or you have a
nation state in which for some sort of
Economic Security regional security
issue decides to delve into the domain
of critical infrastructure attack and
develops the intent
so you see it's part of this life for my
old employer let's think about their
this it's my my slide though they just
gave it to pretty graphic strategic
penetration for future exportations this
is an area that I like to talk about as
it relates to the cyberattacks against
critical infrastructure and it's a part
that I think that we often missed we
think that our intent needs to be in
mind with our current activities which
is not the case right if you think about
our perspective as a society tends to be
very short-term right we think in terms
of quarterly projections annual
projections I'd to do the right team for
the chairman of Joint Chiefs 2020 plan
and my first question spiral in 2020 why
can't we project further out right
whereas our adversaries are thinking in
terms of decades and generations and
would call the fact to say if you take
the perspective of an adversary and they
say well right now I don't have the
intent to attack on the structure but I
can vision in the future where I might
want that capability what do you need to
be doing now if you have that vision
thinking that you might want the
capability have to develop the
capability if you have to do that
preparation that positions you to engage
in the attack an analogy I often throw
out there with my audience is lesson
let's pretend that you're the President
of the United States prior to World War
two and someone comes to you and says
mr. president we think we're going to be
involved with this point we're gonna go
and deploy explosives and their ball
bearing manufacturing plants and we can
do it anonymously without attribution
you don't ever have to push the button
do to detonate the explosives but if we
are involved in military conflict
pushing the button will provide great
strategic advantage and save a lot of
American lives therefore if you do it
honey people would raise your hand you
can plant the explosives rewinding oral
area
the point I'm trying to make with that
analogy is that if you are an attacker
that repositioning of the explosives is
a new claim right so we need to be
thinking if you're chartered with
protecting critical infrastructure in
the space you need to be thinking about
those attacks that don't look like the
attacks over you hear about or think
about it web sites that are trying to
take down your power grid of your
particular structure
you need to be thinking about the
attacks that are positioning themselves
for that capability the future and the
signature what those look like is a lot
different than the attacks detail
databases knowledge meant of what I call
it time shifted intent right the
activity doesn't have to match our
intent the adversary might be thinking
with regards to the future it's
important that we introduce that into
our thinking as well and then targeting
trust this is I mentioned the
information terrorism can you trust your
toaster paper where we get a lot of
things right but we've got some things
wrong one of the things that we got
wrong was if we anticipated that in the
next 20 years I wrote the paper in 1996
we anticipated that there would have
been an attack on structures something
that's substantial consequential here in
the United States and the 20-year mark I
sat down with my co-authors Neil
hollering and we said well let's sit for
fun look at what we got right we got
wrong and we realize that we get this
you know targeting the critical
structure get that wrong what did we
miss like what was the replacement or
what we came up with was this targeting
trust right if we think about the role
that some of these institutions are the
the infrastructure and networks play in
our society with a lot of trust how many
people though or even get it's dependent
on information that is contained within
systems we see this playing out in
institutions like the election
right work even if there is an attack
which causes a change in some sort of
outcome you're diminishing trust in that
institution which creates conflict great
smiles like which we are seeing now and
my Facebook feed hit some spaces almost
becomes unmanageable based on amount of
distrust that's just been this dude
amongst each other in our society right
so the one thing I would say is to be
thinking about targeting trust in the
future if we're not going to see the big
critical infrastructure attacks what are
those other institutions of trust they
become attractive from an attacker
perspective right now we have the third
shift where I want to talk to the
defenders little feel like when I talk
to the network defense spoke to this he
says that this is the reality they're
trying to achieve which is this is the
aspiration it's time to make the
security it's like the time to make the
bill that's coming if you can't get from
the looping animation that's creating a
chain means our being there so that's
the aspiration that this becomes
something that we can manage and we have
technology that we're deploying and that
we're building and it's tense at
steady-state and then I come in as a red
teamer and demonstrate and then the
irony right of course is how many times
you think that padlock was brought to a
bond right even with that zip tie
attached to it right so our
implementation doesn't often match our
aspirations right and we need to keep
ourselves in check and recognize that
from defense perspective what's the need
to recognize this fact you know based on
the Neal Stephenson quote for attacker
advantage right it seems like the
attackers have their hand these days
that's something that would disrupt
one of my favorite presentations over
the past couple of years again jae-hee
layout of Colombia
New York cyber task force anybody
encountered that report yet what was
interesting was that at blackhat not
last year than you before that was rated
number one talk of the entire deep
pocket normally at blackhat right it's
the Atkins that pomper making attack pod
in Leeds yeah it's that sort but here
the number one talk was a guy that
wanted to talk about overcoming attacker
advantage looking at and they brought
together I would encourage you to go
watch the presentation on YouTube read
the report they looked at over time with
this panel of experts at you know 30
phenomenal experience what technologies
are things that we invested in that have
given us that disproportionate invested
the dollar on the side and its cost the
attacker more than a dollar to overcome
them so looking for things that can be
achieved at speed and at scale that is
our challenge really moving forward is
how do we swing we can implement more
dollar they're a dollar of defense that
cost the attacker is a very viable
strategy over time because you're never
going to ultimately defend the networks
are not going to ever be impenetrable we
do want to make it more disrupt didn't
make it higher cost for the attacker the
other thing that frustrates me in from a
cyber defense perspective is that we
seem to measure all their options right
if we look at Jack Walsh shoots regarded
as one of the best managers of all time
he has this quote and if you watch CNBC
or these channels that repeat it over
and over again did you get the beat did
you measure what do we measure in cyber
security number of vulnerabilities
number of attacks detected per day that
sort of right so I would question are
you really measuring the right things
are you measuring how critical the data
is just within your environment are you
measuring how completely you're able to
detect it
not just how many times of the targets
the efficiency of the response what you
think it costs the attack
this impact of exploitative exploitation
of controls so I would argue on the
defender side that you go back and start
thinking about what is important to us
that we can measure that we can actually
influence over time and my guess is the
list looks probably different from what
you're measuring today anyone familiar
with this study you can watch it on
YouTube you basically are given a video
and you are told count the number of
times that the players in the white path
white t-shirts passing the basketball
but most of themselves lots of confusion
the video pursuit walks in the frame
pounds their chest to box out of frame
at the end of the study you're asked how
many times do they pass the basketball
correct answer it's 40 then your ass did
you see the gorillas 50% of me that is
kind of a perfect analogy for the
current state of our security operation
centers in this problem I compromise on
flats right we are telling people based
on a signature here are the things you
need years an alert is a very old kind
of functional getting back to that in
the chain being generating when really
the rule that they should be playing
it's also thinking about if I were the
attacker where would I be hiding I have
a thesis like going out and actually
running hypotheses as to where an
attacker might appear how an attacker
might target them as opposed to just
dealing with the alerts are being
generated patients right analogy here is
that I feel like a lot of the times
those are too busy counting the
basketballs again this slide that's so
important that it makes it into the
presentation twice
your attacker is not a 1 or a 0 remember
that aspect of it this is what I think
you know at been in frustration of mine
but I see a lot of momentum where we
recognize that we have to give the
attacker nothing we want to stop
engaging in her defense but it is so
incredibly easy through spear fishing
through BYOD through lots of other
mechanisms for the attacker to establish
a football win in 2010 I signed up as a
special government employee to help the
first deal of cyber strategy this was a
key piece that I argued it argued and
argued with folks in the partner
defensive illusion of that strategy and
that was a presumption of reach if we
think about the fact that it's early
breach you're going to be breached in
the future how does that change your
perspective about defending can't spell
security without IT isn't it cute was an
episode of The Office but it's an
important point too often I see
functions separated the lack of
communication the focus on saying I'm
spending on security but that have been
or in my technology we talk about the
speaking truth of the power and
experience with a large traded company
who is me meeting with the CEO at been
doing a lot of work with that they had a
lot of problems one of their problems
which was not allocating spending
respective funds and the CEO you do not
look at me and said hey Matt aren't you
proud of me
I just approved the budget for this
great three million dollar network
intrusion defense Tacoma I thought it's
funny Matt aren't you proud of me the
CEO right successful guys back to my
general days briefing so calm and I said
sir that's great that you're spending
money I said but what you've done is the
equivalent of installing a smoke
detector and alarm system and in
elementary school where every kid has
connections because I've also seen over
the past three years where you have
denied the budget about the club owners
three point five minutes to upgrade your
local desktop environment away from
Windows XP flatten the attackers in the
router a lot of thing because they know
that it's really just a matter of when
you're gonna break into the system not
just a rating system but he had equated
improving in security in with just fine
security told us when there's actually
things from a security perspective
around upgrading their infrastructure it
would provide more benefit right so
again it's at finding useful analogies
but then getting to recognize that this
is a is a technology problem and of
itself security in the design process
I mentioned Steve Lukasik and saying if
I know the internet was going to be so
important we will decide security ins in
the get go how many people in this room
know that the Internet of Things how
many companies out there building
Internet of Things devices you think are
truly beyond the stuff dedication that
mutated password using SSL building
secure defenses right we are making the
same mistake and this time we know it's
gonna be important almost everybody in
the room raised their hand we know it's
going to be important but we're making
the same mistake right not building
security into the design process years
ago I did an assessment for a satellite
system that was providing IP networking
and when we went in it was a commercial
company talk to the team proposal was a
competitive one the proposal a huge
stack of design specs etc this brilliant
engineer that worked for me the moon way
and he found all these issues we want to
do to us so we went back to the company
we said hey we're ready you know let us
in the lab but a sec things we want to
bang let you in the lab like yeah we you
know you hired us to do the assessment
of this satellite we need to get access
to the components the satellite then
understand the satellites already in
space we've gone through this whole
process us thinking you're part of the
design process then they put it in space
again
tell us see I said you realize that our
value that we can provide is greatly
diminished by the fact that the
satellite in this imperfect space okay
[Music]
and you could be its truth to power
right in your environments where you're
launching these technologies are
building these things making sure that
we're thinking about it addressing
security as part of the design process
blowing it new plan survives contact
with the enemy this gets back to that
the chain-link fence with a zip tie
around it I think Mike Tyson put a
little bit better is it everyone has a
plan until they get punched this is my
plug for the value of red teaming right
for viewing yourself as the attackers
sees you independently then objectively
I think for me a yield perspective and
I'm a red teamer so empires I think of
all the security initiatives aren't one
of the most valuable by way of education
in the organization identify attack
surfaces that are etc etc etc great
teaming has a very signature compartment
prints you should be building foreign TV
in Islam learning from failures I put
this picture of the black box recorder
and then read last week that somebody
who is proposing that would create the
equivalent of a transportation see
entity for cyber security incidents I
think one thing that we need to do
better in this industry is learning from
our failure that's right and this is
inspired a lot by a book that I read
last year called black box thinking if
you haven't read it it's a great book to
read it looks at actually study of two
different industries in which lessons
learned were incorporated in the
industry and the world that that had an
improving public safety device when they
were not in the two industries they look
at the aviation industry they get black
box and having a very robust lessons
learning process and medical which tends
to do a tribute patient that the patient
health issues to bad luck right and
drawing that distinction I'm saying okay
if we had a mechanism for creating
lessons learned if we study where we
fail
died we just don't attributed to it bad
circumstances we could drastically
improve medical safety for patients the
same type of perspective in
cybersecurity right we need to be
learning those lessons from each other I
like the idea of a TSP for cyber that
can go out and independently looking for
view and published results around
someone it's not too embarrassed beyond
the point where breach is embarrassing I
worked through the Citibank reach over
20 years ago where they thought they
announced a four hundred thousand and
they thought that would be viewed as a
publish them I think we're beyond the
reach disclosure laws and with a lot of
these big companies championing that
perspective that we should be ashamed we
should be drawing from and it's easy in
this industry to become a pessimist
because it seems like we're always music
I'm actually an optimist I feel like
things are getting better I feel like
we're making the investments in
technologies that are gonna drive
security and lots of interesting
questions this is my new hope slide
things that I get excited about
behavioral analytics and machine
learning and artificial intelligence
right are we doing artificial it's a
complete head fake alright sorry to the
vendors that maybe have artificial
intelligence up in the lobby we're not
but we're gonna get there and what I
like is the fact that we're actually
making investments from a cyber security
perspective these types of technologies
I get very excited about the blockchain
the point that the blockchain it is
potential to be very disruptive in all
sorts of industries why should you pay
title insurance anyone will buy a house
why isn't that printed the blockchain
why should you pay a middle market you
know the pharmaceutical system will 45%
of the cost of drugs to serve as a check
that could be done through machine
learning artificial intelligence or
prescriptions into a property right
there are lots of ways in which these
technologies that we build on from a
security perspective are going to be
beneficial not just in security like in
other ways the last remark I wanna make
is what I call this generation right the
first conference I went to officially
for the first time was local here in DC
I was when summer come back but it was
invite-only was held in Georgetown and I
was at this weird point in my career in
that I was a hacker I had you know
messing things in my university I was
getting to be a hacker within the
Department of Defense but determined
this incredibly negative connotation it
was used as a criminal hacker and I
remember doing roofing massive 86 they
would ask you some of these questions
that has changed I feel like this is
generation packs right the benefits that
we are providing to society with this
hacker mindset with this methodology are
incredible and our challenge now as we
move out of it is verse 11 attacks with
slide our challenge now as we move out
of it is to make sure that we start
applying that hacker mindset to other
problems in design but I mention the
stuff why not use blockchain for title
insurance why not use blockchain for
right so I think the value and this
maybe is me reaching this age right
approaching mr. audience but I'm beyond
this point of thinking about it solely
from the perspective of we have systems
we need to be thinking about hacking
that's how do we apply those same
principles I want to study a problem
take it apart reassemble it maybe in a
different way maybe it's the elements
the equations do better other aspects of
society that I think is one of the true
advantages to a group like this is not
just what we're going to do in the cyber
domain but what we're going to be able
to do by applying that mindset and this
generation to other problems in society
that's right called arms I try to make
myself very accessible so feel free by
all means to connect I put the two links
at the bottom who the loop is where I do
a bunch of blogging and also
can find the written version of the
redeeming and lessons learned and in the
global frequency that's just my mailing
list it's just me personally I use it as
an exercise to say what did I encounter
in the past week that I think make you
like seven to ten stories that I put out
every Sunday morning instead of reading
the paper or actually just sit down and
say what did I encounter this week that
I think it's important so with that I am
done my formal remarks are saved about
five minutes for questions so Lou
absolutely you're in the audience can't
take question to the cafeteria yes yeah
I mean you have to you have to invest
intellectually to kind of that reversal
of roles this is an area I spend a lot
of time on and not 1 million in my
background I created a course called
mirror image which was a
counterterrorism course at nothing to do
with cybersecurity in which we took US
military personnel and Canadian for
example if you're Canadian military you
could not deploy to Afghanistan
they weren't indirect time you could
deploy Afghanistan without taking this
course and what we did is we took them
for six days and we did the drop them in
a terrorist training camp in Afghanistan
where they had to live like a terrorist
think like a terrorist be subjected to
the same propaganda the same training
tactics etc with the sole purpose of
that now when they were out responsible
for defending and engaging that they
could view themselves from the outside
so I think that that's important to me
from from my perspective over the years
people have always said I gave a
presentation in 2015 where I said our
focus is on China
right now it's not the China's not
important but I'm really scared about
Russia right and it was to some
intelligence in face data more signing
over the Russian flag and unless sign of
the China slag and a couple of weeks ago
somebody came up there's in that
presentation
did you know you predicted that the
Russians were going to interfere in the
elections this is going to happen I said
I didn't predict anything all I've done
is I have studied over the years the
doctrine that they put out strategy they
put out and I recognize we are at a
point in time in which they're going to
be taking advantage of that aspect of
reflexive control of engaging and
information operations psychological
manipulation etc recognizing the
staffing frame so I think one way that
you can really understand the adversary
perspective is degreed what they're
right and study what they're doing I got
in trouble and thought I was gonna lose
my experience in 1999 this is a funny
story because there is a site called
there was a John Young who's an
architect that moved up in New York City
decided to create this week site and I
came into my possession a unclassified
document still for official use so it
was a translation of unrestricted North
record for something that that provided
there if you haven't read it you should
read it even that's 20 years old their
perspective on how the world was
changing economic warfare information
warfare terrorism and I said this
document is so important that I can't
stand the fact that a lot of people
aren't me because I sent it to John it's
the open source Center which I was very
very upset but in the end I'm glad that
I did it because it created a whole
dialogue around let's think about the
Chinese perspective on information
warfare that I think better informed us
so we need to be doing that we need to
be thinking about some of these other
adversaries as well
what is iron thinking about cyber
warfare the North Koreans think about
some other art response and kind of you
have to put your head in it some shoes
one more question I wish I could say
that we had I know lots of great people
that have been over there and studied it
and lots of great folks from from with
us I think that the issue is that we are
we're creating this kind of house of
cards and especially as it relates to
government services when we're building
more and more services with the
technology dependent without addressing
some of the core issues like identity
and authentication and security and
privacy so I would say we understand
kind of the potential for attack but
haven't done enough to kind of establish
ourselves to be all right I want to keep
the agenda on track and it is exactly 10
o'clock so thank you so much as an
incredible honor