[Music]
sorry I have to entertain myself
that means flight nap I thought we were
all right so good afternoon guys Dave
Marcus this is my heterosexual life mate
koala father and we are going to be
discussing two different use cases of
how to use the intelligence cycle and
special operations or a methodology
doctrine to basically solve cyber kinds
of problems so we're gonna take you
through two very different use cases the
commonality between the two is is the
power that a person who comes from a
lifetime of a background in true
intelligence understands tradecraft and
what that kind of value actually brings
to the cyber II kind of world that we
all traditionally live it so I think
you'll kind of dig it what this big
disclaimer actually says is we use the
dnc breach data to do a lot of the stuff
that we're actually going to talk about
nobody's information is going to be
shown here who's also up so if you've
donated to the DNC your picture isn't
gonna pop up here or anything like that
so it's it's all scrubbed so we put as a
disclaimer we did use the DNC data we
could use the best data we could use the
email server data all that kind of stuff
but the point is is to show how powerful
data is in the hands of an intelligence
professional and to give you a little
bit of insight why it's bad when
breaches actually happen right so one
thing that we figured out a long time
ago is this is you know breaches
happening right hospitals are gonna get
popped but when you you read about it in
the news what do they give you so after
two years in the who here actually was
affected by the OPM data breach right
okay what did you get out of that we
credit monitoring right that's free
credit monitoring there you go
free three-block web searches they
monitored you on the dark web right so
who here was affected by the DNC breach
all right who was who was affected by
the RNC breach all right
lots of people was affected by the asset
a lot of people so what this use case is
actually all about is what a person who
has lollies kind of background and
that's actually a trained intelligence
professional does with that kind of data
so what we're going to do is show you a
different use case of how data is used
to create targeting packages how data is
used to develop assets make sense so
what it comes down to is is this why
should you really care about all of
these breaches that actually happen this
is all of your life that is in the data
when you add all of that data together
and you have an intelligence profession
of look at it what that creates is
leverage how do I get someone to do what
I want them to do how do I develop an
asset unit company or how do I develop
an asset of CIA age in another part of
the world it's not my leverage it's done
by knowing something about that person
to get them to do what you want them to
do and that's exactly what most of this
presentation is about just using two
very different use cases for starters
you know here's what we're going to talk
about we're going to talk about the data
involved talk about doctrine behind it
we're also going to talk about basically
what foreign intelligence services
looking for why we're also working on
civilities couple targets of interest so
in addition to see these really awesome
charts but if you don't know how to go
from macro to micro doesn't mean much
human toll further applications of the
methodology so our methodology starts
out with the intelligence cycle this
intelligence cycle is we took the basic
intelligence community cycle and we
modified it for us starts off with
planning direction we have collection
processing and exploitation
dissemination utilization and repeat but
why is this important so the foundation
once we have these really awesome
time-tested foundations all
you have to do is locate it to it and
you start doing the top we have what's
this is this iceberg okay so this is
where it starts getting great work the
Special Operations iceberg methodology
is from 1963 on the right you see the
Special Operations and this is how some
operations looks it insurgencies so on
the top of the iceberg you have things
that you typically see you have
small-scale attacks look about
negotiated settlements things of that
nature but when you really want to
attack insurgency networking you don't
attack things than the right chun-yan
you attack the factors that allow the
activity on the top and that's the same
thing so for us we don't really care
about the bright shining object when it
comes to hacking those being like
large-scale attacks DDoS is things like
that we don't really care that's in the
news everybody sees it well we try to
dig really deep for is all those
underlying factors under the surface the
things that allow the kind of shot and
actually sorry about
we're actually kind of shocked at how
quickly we were able to adapt arguably
5,000 years of tradecraft to a different
problem set all right and it speaks well
to what dr. it is and white doctors
powerful when you can actually take
established cycles of intelligence
creation intelligence is about making a
product and making a state medium
confidence low confidence high
confidence those things mean something
it allows a general or the person that
asks the question to make a decision
based upon confidence and that maps to
Cyprus so to speak if they're talking
about doctrine humans probably the
second oldest the second oldest career
discipline everybody uses it you use it
in your daily life you need information
from somebody you have to talk to you
have to get it so what do we look for
when you're trying to develop human
asset looking for the feed makers
looking for people who know things about
adversary intelligence
local political personalities religious
leaders heads of state excuse me miss
apologies if anybody means beeping war
even the person who can pick up trash
what we look for is policeman access and
accessibility
so that's your placement to the issue
your access to that and your
accessibility to the data that's so for
an example if you were looking at the
Iranian nuclear program who in here
would you go for a few minute
information anybody anybody guess who
would know the most about the Iranian
nuclear program
Maqbool Medina job so he has placement
access to accessibility to the patient
obviously but what he doesn't have what
you why you wouldn't use him as a target
we look at levels of cooperation his
vulnerabilities do we have something
that we can use against him didn't want
to commit espionage against Iran
absolutely now we'll if he does give us
information will be reliable and you
know can we is there anything that we
can use to pull more data aren't
reliable lists probably so let's get
into the DNC that Dave said all these
numbers are are we had real information
in there when you pull the charts
they're all seven five three of nine we
have a tactic called merging so
basically within the DNC data itself
there's hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of documents Excel sheets list
of members donors and all sorts of
information like that so first thing
let's say you want to do infiltrate the
DNC we put all that data into program
views called notebook and then it's out
of Turkey we have a methodology for
building the church as well but for the
example of who do you go after if you
wanted to look at piece issuing services
well they already broke out all that
all becomes a second example party
affairs if you want to know you know
what's next for the party or they're
gonna keep looking for you see the
little red circle and they and that's
from the bigger picture it's just
there's so much 3d capability so we have
new small examples actually how
structure you want to know about the
technology they're using you have all
about their financial information so
they had this really incredible list of
all the credit cards they also in some
cases to picture front and back if you
may have a needs credit card you know
it's one of those things well yeah sure
as a corporation
everybody keeps lists you need to grab
those lists don't I get it and we
combine this information with their
emails and email password all on the
same list or a different list you start
merging these things they can find
though here's here's another exercise so
let's say I'm a Russian case officer and
I'm talking to my people hey I can't
work in DC DC stunad give me some data
for New York or who should I start
talking yeah you can segregate data by
person place thing object meeting so for
this example New York and one here's
some here's some really cool stuff that
happens when you start together like
there would be one up one skyscraper in
New York and we see that like 175 people
donated DNC now we know that they like a
guy lives across the apartment from
another guy who donated they don't have
that right let's start talking about if
you wanted to start various different
fishing campaigns
really easy to do so let's say I wanted
to target donors with 10 to 15 million
dollars in donations or 10 to 25 million
where they broke this all down for us so
what this is is a compilation of all
these charts right here 6 basically 6 of
a large donor charts once we merge them
together look like this then you can if
you want to specifically target somebody
I mean you have all the information then
you can do further analysis on the
individuals you can start sending you
already have their people their person
email that person the cell would stop to
even call them up they can compile an
argument or send me an email saying your
personal information wasn't click on
this link for further information the
more focused financial target I know
here's here's where it gets really cool
so this is the coin emails so the
Clinton emails basically 41,100 money
emails we broke it down gave each of
those emails an individual named after
the individual name we had centered
receiver information what this tells us
right here this is a communication
network so which you can definitely do
is you can color code all the different
types of emails so if you want to see
how the State Department talks to people
with Gmail or hops you can color code
all that and what there's also another
thing this also indicates it's called
the preeto effect
pre notice the predate this distribution
is basically 10% of your organization
does 90% of the work so people with
social network analysis and eigenvector
centrality in here we can say okay well
obviously that big blob right there
that's somebody important you talk a lot
if you want to start targeting people
within the Hillary campaign
well they list actually titled trends of
HRC list so we know who our friends are
we know their evils we know their cell
phones
wait that's telling you to stand in
front of Mike so you're welcome you're
welcome Adrienne so we were talking we
got a start
so one of the things that kind of jumped
out to Wally not when we were doing this
exercise is what happened when we
started merging the hillary stuff with
donor information and then seating
charts believe it or not at political
events so you could see who in the list
donated a certain amount of money knew
who they were sitting at a table with a
particular so again you want to
manipulate the person chances are you're
not going to manipulate Hillary Clinton
directly talking to happen all right but
when you start looking at who's paying
to have access to her friends first it
becomes very very interesting you see
how much money they gave up that person
was sitting at a table with the people
who were going to be in her direct staff
if she became president I can focus in
on those people manipulate them build
out their networks identify their
innocence so it was a again a
fascinating exercise
who do you focus on to manipulate
developers let's talk a little bit more
about merging so basically we took all
the charts involved all the financial
all the Excel sheets we put them
together and you get this across and
this is probably still only 50% of the
data within that and as you can see the
green the flow of money started
connecting to all the other charts this
is everything you think of some events
donors contributors people are on the
call list email list anything that a
corporation would have plus a whole lot
more when you look into it
so you know we wouldn't give something
that looked like this to a costume
obviously we call it's like the Where's
Waldo effect you get so much data it's
just incredible just to give you example
this is just the first row the bottom
section here that's just the first row
of data in the master bridge and then
the second row this is just what a
cross-section of self that's the bottom
section stage is incredible it's
millions of pieces of data
jerk so let me go back in okay the
question was what's the deadlines in the
distance between things if you see here
look right under merge basically it's
one thing connected to another now that
might not be a solid connection that
could be something like the state of
Georgia so then you have multiple
Georgia and then it's just information
connecting information but the six
degrees of Kevin Bacon just keeps going
and just sometimes to get some of those
things are a lot of that stuff because
you'll have a connection by dollar
amount sometimes so that's not really an
individual connection between people
it's just a they just happened or
location phone numbers there's all sorts
of reasons okay so good question
people ask of them the question was how
long did it take to do this when I
started it I took three weeks straight
to start building and then a period of
eight months between our customer
request just whenever I have free time
so a foreign intelligence service or US
intelligence service could do all this
with a team of six and if you had if you
had people who worked in the same
methodology somebody to collect like an
inventory person - and then somebody -
you see this is a cross-section just
like you've seen the previous ones you
have person we have location you have
cell phones Ross lives in the house okay
so let's talk about some other things
that people don't think about you always
the elective said earlier you think
about credit and credit monitoring which
is if you're up against somebody like me
that's the least of your concerns but
what if I was on the extreme end of a
racist so you know the DNC had a lot of
lists for their LGBT community people
supporters etc all their emails all
their personal cell phones credit card
information etc
so we did to this it's like hey if you
wanted it really exploit somebody you
can really exploit somebody so we took
the six largest LGBT charts at the hands
put them all together and remember the
red start that's going to be important
we merge them together
so with merging something they had here
so there it's partially automated
partially not so if you have David and
Dave Marcus system so we have to go in
and it'll assume that they're the same
then it asked us Kannada do you but as
you can see just like the previous
murders it's an incredibly huge data set
and so the red star so we had to prove
that methodology so we found a guy this
guy's named Steve's everything written
here is from one of his websites and
this is what actually a government would
do so you look for somebody with the
placement access and accessibility so
he's got a huge lobbyists firm he does a
lot of work with both sides of the house
and so you start breaking down this
network so we didn't just use the data
within the DNC action although a lot of
his data was in the DNC hack everything
from emails personal information what
parties attended etc things that he's
supposed to this house and to
information from multiple sources
there's a little more than this but just
for size you know social network data
employment data Library of Congress data
because anytime you pay somebody with a
government entity it passed ago there's
a receipt for the library Congress
clients political contacts education
talks times he's been on the news so if
you look at the very top right above
this picture where you see this little
stem that's what it looks like when you
protect yourself on social media to the
left and right that's what it looks like
so this story is the more you protect
yourself you know guys like we won't be
able to get like this so if this was a
real exercise and this was a real
intelligence operation
this chart would look much different I
would exfoli explain you can consider
this it's like one level right there we
go
[Music]
and so the Twitter that's a Twitter on
the on the left side are that's Facebook
and that's Twitter I would exploit every
one of those that every friend there and
see where the commonalities are even
further there that I would also go and
get all the personal information all
their cell phones email successful and
so we talked a little bit earlier about
what does this guy do so here's this
company so if you have a company it's
great you know that branding is
important but when you put all your
employees pictures on there what they do
where they're from and then you got a
guy like me to go and it's really great
and then you see he's got two companies
so we had a heavily agreed that this
because people actually in this area to
know the guy so don't want to get in too
much trouble but you know he has two
companies and then they share members so
there's some you exploit intelligence
operation but someone like Wally would
do is build out every single one of
those other people because if we want to
manipulate Steve Steve may not be
necessarily vulnerable to direct
manipulation but you can be assured that
someone in this social network actually
is so what would someone like Wally
would do is they would target every
single person filled out that person's
networks can find the vulnerability to
action just like if you want to
manipulate Steve you look at somebody in
this network if you want to manipulate
somebody Steve knows you manipulate
someone and so on so you can it
manipulation so if you can't find a
vulnerability you can create one so
here's his clients for two different
companies right so let's think about
athletes right now with an athlete or an
actor gets accused of sexual harassment
his sponsorship goes away immediately
whether he's guilty or innocent or not
so let's say we go to Ford and we start
saying hey this Steve sky who you're
doing business with and lobbying with
like he is corrupt since this and that
and
and that goes way then you go to him be
like hey Steve
we told sort all these lies about you
and they believe it now they're not
miners so you work with us over and
making we're going to really affect your
pocketbook really fast and so another
breakout of the social networks with
protected not protected okay so the
first part was basically all the data
with the DNC so now we're going to show
you how we apply this to ad groups
viruses malware and similar et cetera
and this is where it gets pretty cool so
unbeknownst to me they touch and when I
started taking these merges which we
talked about earlier so this is the
indicators of compromise for abd ten
cryptolocker DN c-- AG Tesla cribs
walkie server and pull up so you see
here they all touch for those those who
don't recognize some of those terms it's
all ransomware for the most part with
the exception to apt ten the DN C stuff
it's pretty much all ransomware of
different varieties that were not
thought to be working together or have
infrastructure that touched so what does
this show us and why is this important
so these connections like this between
will encrypt a wall and Tessa prep these
clusters but have really nice centrality
same here here and this is the BNC the
actual data from the the actual happens
so what this tells us and what we're
starting to realize in a big way is
hackers hacker groups activists are
using shared common infrastructure
further attacks and here's these are all
the basically the types and how they
touch by the way to make a strong
statement to say they're all working
together
sake group the point actually is to say
there's more commonality and there's
more things that that touch that
previously thought what does that mean
that probably means that the
infrastructure that they utilize is weak
enough to where different groups are
using the same infrastructure or they
buy the same infrastructure access that
happens a lot with certain groups
certain groups are responsible for
maintaining access to assets and
sometimes more than one group has access
to said assets so we're starting to see
commonalities in areas that we wouldn't
have necessarily thought we would have
thought ABT 10 was going to intersect
with trip though in any way shape or
form
the DNC started seeing the commonalities
entire sees one of those commonalities
are IP addresses in this case URLs PHP
URLs yes and no for the sake of speed
not necessarily so generally what we
will do is we will use published IOC s
so just basic - IP domain that kind of
stuff however we could do the actual
Saint Luke it's themselves reverse them
pull out the artifacts and do the same
thing but the sake of brevity and speed
it was just published by OU system
analyst notebook it's up by I - they're
owned by IBM them so one of my favorite
so far is abd 10 it's really complex I
mean you can just you need to see this
thing from an intelligence analysis
perspective this is really awesome great
clusters things are broken out there's a
centrality there's AI in vector there's
all sorts of intersecting pieces in the
middle a lot of those are IP addresses
what I've done for this one now is I've
taken out location data because
essentially if this falls flat let's
like gather connectivity because they're
both in Russia both
China or opinion that's yeah okay it's
connection same country but that's not a
direct connection these are all direct
connections and here's another example
of how they touch and that's this is the
shared common infrastructure Wally and I
are probably gonna take on this is
pulling out to answer your question
looking at the source code stuff is when
we actually start adding Bitcoin
addresses into this as the next step to
see how that actually works together
this gut instinct tells us what's even
more centrality ground for the money
trail most most malware when it hits it
it can be it just depends upon this
animals make use generally we get a big
enough represent a preposition the
representational sample set to give us
enough of the addresses to at least do
some analysis on and then we can pull
the tumblers and figure out what other
tumblers they're actually talking to so
believe it or not the flow is pretty
straightforward to track through the
steer it's not really all that all that
just get to pick it up representative
samples but so this will this will go we
were to do this same presentation next
year there's gonna be even more stuff at
it it's using some words how much money
are they doing things like that on a
huge I over it will how much money into
a separate view of the top ten grand
summer 2016 how a touch now this is
totally unenriched to so typically what
we do Dave I are wet sitting here in the
front will take all the basically the
public indicators are compromised and
then we whole backbone of McAfee data
against it first scene last scene where
they touch all the pivot points and
everything like that those all come
together so this is unenriched and when
it becomes enriched
that's where you do for the crazy sounds
so to touch a little bit about the
methodology and bitcoin so going along
with
common infrastructure like we just
talked about same applies for bitcoins
in ransom art so one of my first
projects when I came on board with Maxie
was DD for beat DD for PC was a
technopath right we got all the
information about the PM GS with that
coin started to decline we did a full
exploitation of that months later the
Ashley Madison countless and whenever I
build a chart I have a Hall of Master
merch I take those charts and I plug
them into the big overall color code and
that's why 50 times blue so you can
notice on screen immediately these are
all parts of apt and go in touch here so
it was really surprising to me that the
Ashley Madison Bitcoin wallets were the
same are some of the same there's like
36 and leased wells
you know touched in the middle so that's
also a shared common mystery for
structure within financial resources as
well though what Wally actually did was
this was the DDoS that happened what
Wally did was actually took the email
addresses that were sent to the victim
exploited the email addresses to the
social media accounts to actually
finding a place where the person behind
the actual attacks mine car and then
mapped it back to the other end so he
was actually able to go from all just
the digital stuff through social network
analysis to the actual physical human
being responsible for the attack and
then map that back to other attacks a
two week period of time that that was to
go from DD 4 BC attack against the
specific bank to it's that guy buying a
car and it took about two weeks worth of
teach or the work and this kind of break
out kind of became the focus of a lot of
the work is finding those kinds of
commonalities because more and more we
find out that the people behind any one
particular attack by other protesters by
actually tracking things that the Queen
addresses it's it's immensely tractable
it's anonymous but it's not anonymous
way that's it's immune to exploitation
quality because we look for the
connection not necessary even for the
person we're looking for what IP
addresses are doing transactions what
other addresses talking to what are the
tumblers talking to build out the social
network of those communications you're
gonna find somebody buying something
particular big point that map's back
right into that cloud and it's immensely
fun bigboy words so that pretty much
wraps it up if you're interested in
let's do one thing we've do the smaller
cons we talked about is hey if you got a
set of data and you want us to apply
this to your data set as long as it's
not gonna be like weeks of work or more
than happy to take a look and then this
week is how you get the annals of it you
can't modify anything but you can see in
the chart so we have
real quick though you guys can take a
picture of this and you can apply this
to your work you can in any sense of the
word out building charts that are
complex like the ones we have in here
that's gonna take you some time
it's not something you learn overnight
you know for me I had a go twice with
special operations so through a bunch of
schools so that's a little bit trickier
but the intelligence I claim you can
Google US intelligence then find out
what works for you it doesn't matter if
you're in payroll intelligence or if
you're in sports
[Music]
any any any data you can hand him it so
it's not just automated oh the question
was what kind of data canals notebooks
yeah then JSON Excel or CSV anywhere doc
and so it really doesn't take in the
data like that it takes the table data
and and then you have basically a prompt
that prompt allows you to sign row a is
person wrote these a house and you can
do and then you can save those templates
so that's one reason I was able to do
the D so fast like I created a template
for like contact data because they had
the same rows stuff he didn't I just
move the rows from one contact list who
actually had a certain level of network
access on the DN C charts that were
specific to network operations because
we found the common fields in the common
tables and again when you start merging
all that data together that's the kind
of magic you get so it's not just such a
such admitted such as such admin with
access to all these different assets
Alps different networks and all these
different devices it's a powerful tool
into the Train though another cool thing
about the PNC they had all their budgets
in there so we had their cybersecurity
budgets like $35,000 said well how they
should invested a little bit more you
know and it's like that CD site
it seems incredibly low and then they
don't even hire these people they're
just part-time help between budget
cycles from the years and you know the
data was published right you know if
this was RNC that this happens that we
can do the same darn if we wanted to do
this to another reach like the OPM stuff
we would get even better you know so
it's I don't want you guys to think
about the data that were looking at the
data is just one example of the product
and methodology that is applied is we
can do the same thing quality could do
the same thing to data send the top not
any good not ones that are truly that
good which one do you use by other so
I'm sorry so the question was are there
any open source tools that are of the
same level that apples nobody's that
good said graph I own what else okay I
got that blue maybe to a little
different though multi go allows you to
enrich data don't necessarily do that
same way without other plugins those
know peachy it's not it's powerful
Palantir expense any of you use Palantir
up there it's not talent here expensive
but it's on it's not it's not as
inexpensive because multi voters but
there's lots of plugins available for it
you can just do something and they
amazing work actually in this time
finest awesome this for customer or no
this was totally our own that's just
initiative driven project just to prove
methodology so previous years we talk
our talk was a building a pint
intelligent self so like how we put
together our cell and all about
methodology
all about social network analysis this
is kind of like the follow-on to
original and so
it's yet no customer yeah this one oh
well I didn't have it's all on for this
it's all URLs IP addresses and I think
limits on domains so I I take out all
that and so I took out all the stuff
that could create a false flag things
like the country of America as an icon I
take all that out and that really
lessens your false positives connections
between group because just being in same
country that's not a connection but if
they share an IP address for something
or they have 43 domains that they both
share things like that that's my
certificate
oh please first let's do you so the
question was do we link IP addresses the
ranges yes absolutely so if something's
if we get just a range I will basically
apply the same methodology we do just to
a similar domain and the repetition is
how I figured out that these things are
actually happening
putting charts within the charts and
just at some point they're going to
touch that's some of them are not as
significant as others you know but seem
that they touch that right there is it
it doesn't answer a question it creates
a new question
yeah I mean there's separate networks
but then there's commonalities between
the two and you see the same thing with
humans I mean this these methodologies
to say ketchup and money you build these
charts based off of data that you have
you know you even download entire phone
books things like that just and
eventually you find point a point B we'd
see and then that can take years
no the charts come out like this oh sure
sure so that's a great question so we
have we call them tears expectation
tears this would be a singular singular
enrichment so that's basically you have
the type which we have an icon for for
the brandsmart and then what's connected
to that type and so this that and then
that's a tier 1 the tier 0 would be
enriched won't be enriched at tier 3 we
rich will be enriched rich and so after
three different steps like an IP address
and then you have the domains touch it
gets really clock fast and then once the
one downside to this methodology move to
get too big it's hard to see but when
you keep it small focus on the
connections or in the same with people
so it's like hey people have the
information that you need they all hang
out here they all drive these cars I
mean you those are the questions you
answer size isn't necessarily the goal
but the goal is to see the connections
and then you go from macro to micro and
so then you have I would enrich
affections like this where you have
these really big clusters that connects
one group to another instead of
enriching everything I would enrich just
that and see what that looks like
yes sir so the question is basically
does its indicate that maybe possibly
members of apt 10 are working part-time
with other groups and they will take
this if it was a North Korean apt roof I
think that's probably something I would
explore not necess I wouldn't
necessarily think that based upon this
chart but I would consider it something
more or are they renting out an
infrastructure or they just need some
point oh right
no because let's say the network that
that represents was targeted and if it
was wide open it simply may have been
opportunity so there could be a
gazillion different reasons I wouldn't
necessarily think that that is farming
out there services for that but again
who is the North Koreans that's probably
something maybe it's Swift now that is
in between to that that's definitely
possible well yeah if it's a banking
network which the North Koreans like the
target and write expect to find crypto
there you don't write out you know so so
again it just it just depends on the
adversary and everything else but it's
worth looking into to figure out why
they touch that's that's a good prop it
might have been a full runner you see
was a toyota for sure he's Malaysian
Donald he's Malaysian