all right so what question before I get
started showing hands
are there any Russian operatives in the
audience
nobody oh you got there good can they
hear me in Moscow can they hear me in
Moscow excellent
so before I dive in I want to tell you a
little bit about myself so you
understand where I'm coming at this
problem from my name is Megan I'm I'm an
intro psych analyst and Russian language
nerd I spent a year studying abroad in
Russia on a language immersion program
and while I was there I purposely
avoided English language news services
so that I could further my immersion
experience now the unfortunate side
effect of that decision was that I was
exposed to a huge dose of propaganda so
while I was in Russia Russia annexed the
Crimean the Ukrainian region of Crimea
and also began the military operations
in eastern Ukraine and at the same time
there was really sharp intensification
and information operations so I wanted
to talk to you about all the lessons
that came from all of that while it was
over there so first let me start with
some of the fundamental characteristics
of Russian information operations and
why they're so effective Russian
applause often takes a grain of truth
out of its original context and creates
a new false narrative around that
smaller ahem truth
for example the activities of current
and far-right fringe groups in Ukraine
have been used to paint all Ukrainians
as fascists this creates a siege
mentality for most Russians and greatly
lessens the likelihood that they will
question the Russian government's
actions more often than not Russian info
ops the intent of Russian across is to
create expedient narratives and even new
realities one of the most prominent of
these themes is we're no worse than the
West this is a line that I heard played
out over and over again to the point
where I became
to it one particularly pertinent example
of this tactic is that brusha points at
u.s. support for separatists Kosovo
which was part of the former Yugoslavia
until the late 1990s now Russia uses
this as evidence of hypocrisy saying
that since the u.s. supported separatist
Kosovo it should also support what
Russia calls Crimean self-determination
another common strategy is co-opting
fringe groups to further push misleading
information for example thousands of
far-right
Russian nationalists have volunteered to
fight in the ongoing conflict in eastern
Ukraine now these volunteer fighters
refer to the militants in eastern
Ukraine as separatists or brothers and
they refer to their enemies Ukrainian
army and governments as fascists so this
demonstrates wholesale adoption and
rebroadcast of the Russian states
carefully crafted terminology in reality
Russia's stoke the flames of this
supposed Property Group has propped it
up for years
these military and other forms of
support let's take a step back for a
minute so we can better understand what
is going on here Russian information
operations can be thought of as
large-scale social engineering
traditional social engineers have used
social and behavioral arms for personal
gain but in the case of Russian
information operations the attackers
have used societal norms for national so
how does this work in practice
it's very important to keep in mind that
Russian info ops do not refuse rather
they subvert in a road Western liberal
values for example transparency is a
volumen service vector for large-scale
social engineering specifically
transparency was subvert it in the use
of WikiLeaks as a proxy for dumping
stolen information and pushing
narratives expedient to the Russian
government you can see that mr. Assange
has been a guest on the network RT which
is one of the biggest mouthpieces of
Russian information operations so let's
take a closer look at our key
it's the international arm of Russia's
propaganda apparatus and as tactics are
a great illustration of large-scale
social engineering our key abuses
Western societies value of freedom of
speech and freedom of press when it
presents itself as a news source and
claims to provide an alternative to the
Western media establishment you can see
that's reflected in its lovely slogan
question horn and it may seem like that
slogan is encouraging more critical
thought but really all it's doing is
making people more likely to accept
conspiracy theories by pinching itself
as a supposed alternative to mainstream
media Russian in flops
also undermines the credibility of
reputable sources of information Russian
and broths both exploit and feed into
growing disagreement on what constitutes
a credible source of fat of truth and
whether or not objective fact is really
valuable at all I happen to think that
it is still valuable but apparently this
some people disagree with manner as is
the case for most of the most effective
social engineering campaigns Russian
information operations our target are
tailored to their targets based on
reconnaissance it's important to keep in
mind that Russian society generally
knows a lot more about American society
and vice-versa so this makes us
particularly vulnerable the annexation
of the Ukrainian Peninsula of Crimea
perfectly illustrates Russian
information operations at work the
annexation of Crimea is one of the first
and best examples of Russian military
and information operations being
completely integrated the invasion
started when Russian soldiers without
insignia on their uniforms infiltrated
the peninsula and took control of
government offices military bases and
communications infrastructure at the
same time
Russia's info ops pushed the claim that
these quote little green men or quote
polite people were militiamen and not
the members of the Russian military that
they were in fact
Russian forces were deliberately
referred to in this way to make the
situation seem less threatening and less
urgent it also made the operation seem
more like support to local residents
desire for self-determination now this
picture is a real photograph taken at
the time of the invasion of Crimea and
you can see that it perfectly
illustrates the narrative of little
green men you can see that a soldier
without insignia on his uniform is
helpfully hand in a cat back to a little
boy and he's aren't to the teeth but you
know never mind him he's a polite person
he's not going to harm you I personally
experienced the insidious effects of
Russian Inbox through a steady diet of
Russian control state TV now the
coverage on these outlets described the
annexation is a quote historic reunion
or a quote returned to Russia this
language is specifically crafted to
appeal to domestic audiences and
capitalize on common culture and shared
Soviet history Crimea was one of the
most popular vacation destinations in
the USSR and it was also home to key
Soviet Navy port I included this map to
show you how close the invaded regions
are to Russia both geographically and
linguistically now the darkest red
regions including Crimea and the south
and dumb nets in the east are our areas
where 75% or more of local residents are
native Russian speakers
after the infiltration was complete
state propaganda outlets both arty and
domestic ones trumpeted the overwhelming
and falsified results of the Russian
organized referendum in Crimea the
results showed that over 95% of voters
supported reunification with Russia this
was a direct subversion of Western
values as people who valued the freedom
to determine the nature of one's own
government we were trying to think that
because the results were supposedly
overwhelming we should respect these
people's desire for self-determination
I myself was inclined to believe that
Russia's claim on Crimea was legitimate
through this thought track in reality
the referendum was a rigged
justification for a foregone conclusion
the entire purpose of the vote was to
legitimize the seizure of territory
despite egregious falsifications like
turnout figures as high as 123 percent
in some areas now this picture is also a
real photograph taken at the time of
referendum in Crimea the translation of
the words at the top is on March 16th we
choose and you can see that the choice
being presented here is very very stark
basically voters were either supposed to
choose fascism or Russia so this was a
very biased promote environment so how
did I get myself out of this thought
trap it's all about different ways of
thinking when you're immersed in a
culture for long enough you start to
adopt a lot of habits including mental
ones for me we're trying to my home
perspective was key and this happened
when I learned about a about the
Budapest memorandum inner Spectre
Budapest memorandum is a 1994 treaty
signed by Ukraine Russia us and the UK
under this treaty Ukraine agreed to give
up its nuclear arsenal that it had
parroted from the USSR and in return
Russia agreed to respect Ukraine's
sovereignty independence and territorial
integrity when I learned this I realized
that the information operations
much like a successful one social
engineer would do on a smaller scale had
tricked me into not question the
narratives I was hearing by abusing the
value that I assigned to democratic
rights this led to my initial failure to
recognize the false narrative as an
effort to undermine the international
community's response and as a cover for
breaking international law the frame of
reference of international law triggered
a mental return to my own culture
causing more critical thinking to kick
in and allowing me to understand what it
actually happened I've hinted at them
already but I want to talk a little bit
about some of the targets of Russia's
social engineering the first set of
targets our foreign policy makers
specifically those leading Western
states in the case of Crimea Russia
obfuscated its real goal of keeping
Ukraine in its sphere of influence
through the seizure of territory Russia
accomplished this in part by pushing the
little green men narrative which made it
difficult for policymakers to respond to
the situation quickly and effectively
you can't counter what you can't
identify after all had Western leaders
immediately understood this to be an
invasion any that destabilizing Ukraine
a much stronger and swifter response
wouldn't been more likely social
engineering worked on policy makers in
the early days of the crisis enough
doubt was introduced to had an equal
action until after the fact this allowed
for the creation of a new reality on the
ground and it has proven impossible to
roll back the invasion has been accepted
as a reality with very few consequences
to Russia besides of course economic
sanctions but the will to maintain those
sanctions is flashed gently the Budapest
memorandum calls for seeking UN Security
Council assistance in the event of a
violation of the memorandum but Russia
violated it without meaningful
intervention interaction
despite the fact that Russian parliament
authorized Putin to use force at Ukraine
on March 1st 2014 the UN Security
Council only attempted to pass a
resolution on Crimea the day before the
referendum was held on March 16th it's
important to keep in mind that any
society be targeted in this manner
Russia's and Fox have been aimed at
citizens of Russia and other countries
to support foreign policy and military
goals in the case of the invasion of
Crimea Russian info ops shaped Russian
public opinion to be overwhelmingly in
support of the annexation my host mom
along with the vast majority of Russians
bought into narratives designed
specifically for domestic consumption
she said things like Crimea has always
been Russian or Russians and Ukrainians
are one people it may seem like the
mamelon calls for unity but in reality
the implication there is that Ukraine is
somehow not a legitimate topic state
state-run coverage of Crimea was also
highly emotionally charged or it used
the technique of strong effect and
social engineering see most prominent
among these strong effect techniques was
laying the line that Ukrainians are
fascists Russia's visceral memory of
World War two means the stoat strong
fears of siege mentality and invoked a
moral cause to save russian-speaking
brethren from non-existent us
victimization this and other narratives
also views Russians value of
collectivism we are together has been
the slogan of the day at many rallies
held in Russia and supported the
annexation these types of emotionally
charged appeals Clinic key role in
convincing Russian citizens to support
something that was actually not in their
best interest the annexation led to
astronomical federal spending at a time
when the economy and federal revenue
were both in sharp decline this tactic
of targeting mass groups of citizens can
also make it more difficult for
political leaders
West to generate or maintain popular
support for policies to counter Russia
now that we have a better understanding
of the problem I want to talk a little
bit about some of the mitigation
strategies that have been used to
counter Russian disinformation first
there's an over-reliance on a bucking or
fact-checking but that's not going to
solve the problem in fact it exposes
more people to the false narrative
people are also extremely reluctant to
question their own beliefs and a fact
check is unlikely to persuade this is
especially true in an environment where
there's a lack of general consensus on
shared sources of truth the Russian
government isn't even playing on this
level they're not playing a game of
right versus wrong correct versus
incorrect they want to convince people
that none of it matters and induce
apathy apathetic people don't really
question what they're hearing after all
another common strategy to fight
disinformation pushing out counter
narratives runs the risk of becoming no
better than your adversary to the point
where you end up creating propaganda
yourself and feeding into this dynamic
of apathy adding another narrative
doesn't necessarily cancel out the
original one in fact it can muddy the
waters that make people even less likely
to be critical about the information or
than through super hearing people have a
finite amount of mental resources which
can be quickly exhausted when they're
overloaded with a lot of information in
a short period of time there is no one
easy silver bullet solution to this
problem it is massive and very
complicated safeguarding the public
against the spread of Russian
disinformation needs to be a
multi-faceted community-driven effort
since the problem can be understood as
large-scale social engineering
this calls for drawing upon the InfoSec
community's practices in safeguarding
against social engineering public
awareness campaigns on Russian
information operations can go a long way
toward alleviating the problem it is
particularly important that effort
to raise public awareness which members
of the press media outlets should
consider creating new policies outlining
better ways to deal with leaked
information and sources with adversarial
motives outlets publishing information
to practice data problems consider who
leaked the information why they leaked
it and whether or not it's ethical to
publish a key question journalists
should ask themselves is am i furthering
and farías narrative such considerations
would make it less likely that attackers
could have used transparency as a value
for their own gain based on personal
experience exposure to other cultures
helps break you out of echo chambers and
makes you less vulnerable this
information worked on me because I had
isolated myself from my own perspective
for long enough and I did not yet know
enough about the Russian government's
motive and perspective those who
understand a range of motives and
worldviews are better protected
different people have different
perspectives and understanding those
perspectives increases the likelihood of
safeguarding against social engineering
spasibo za nemanja thanks for listening
so quick caveat before we get into
questions I'm not here to talk politics
so if you have a question of a political
nature I'd ask that you hold until after
the presentation answer your questions
yes they in this in this question the
big crime organizations well I think
that in this case the the crime the
crime organizations are working hand in
hand with government so I don't think
they necessarily have their own agenda
other than like being given the it's
basically what happens as far as I
understand and I haven't looked at this
in depth but as far as I understand
Russian criminal organizations those
that cyber criminals are given pretty
much free rein to attack other countries
as long as they leave Russia in law and
in return they are expected to help the
government when they're called upon to
do so so I think that in this case the
operation was supported by such groups
but I don't think they necessarily had
their own agenda and into its own right
I think that answer your back there in
the middle
because I guess the dividing line for me
is what you must do and what can I
extend to be worried about chronic
citizens because they're equal to some
things with that or ones are actually
okay so basically you're asking to what
extent is RT directed by the Russian
government in general in your expertise
in the model this is a pattern exeed
especially in your private organizations
so how efficiently they align with
United personal
I think like we have question you must
be a mystery like someone just happens
yeah I mean I I have not really
researched other outlets besides Artie
so I can't really speak to that you know
in an informed manner so I won't really
address that part of it but in terms of
Artie I mean they receive direct support
from the Russian government and funding
and and there they are directly dictated
their editorial line is directly
dictated by the Kremlin
I mean this is not an independent media
organization this is Russian state
propaganda and the more sensitive of the
Franks so I would encourage you if
you're interested in issues of media
independence and those sorts of things I
would really encourage you to read this
book by Peter paparazzo it's called
nothing is true and everything is
possible and it takes a really in-depth
look at Russian propaganda and all of
the machinations behind it in terms of
how the Kremlin dictates that editorial
line and you know basically some of the
tactics that are used but yeah like I
say in this line here a lot of a lot of
what I talk about in this presentation
was informed by that book so I really
highly recommend the point you made you
were saying that you've got too much
emphasis on fact checking and I think
that is it practically seems to be even
unchecking it I guess my question is
like what's the alternative
yes that's a really difficult I mean
like I said the problem is really
massive and really complicated so
there's no one easy solution to it and I
mean there is a place for fact-checking
it's just that I say I feel there's a
lot of outlets
in the West that focus almost
exclusively on fact-checking and that's
not a good way to deal with it because
again it just spreads the call
center-right nation around more like for
example the European Union has something
called disinformation review it's a
newsletter that they put out and it's
almost exclusively fact-checking various
claims in the Russian media and it's
like well ok I didn't even know that
that narrative existed until you pointed
it out to me and told me that their time
is blatant lie and if I were not you
know if I were not inclined to think
that the EU was a you know arbiter of
truth and I was I would dismiss it
outright and the fact check would be
completely not always so that's my point
basically and in terms of what's the
alternative
I really think public awareness
campaigns and trying to spread like
spread and education about you know what
what is going on here what the Russian
government's motives and present
perspective is because I just think that
as Americans we just don't you typically
just don't understand enough about those
types of issues to really insulate
ourselves from this type of influence I
think you sort of asked us to draw
allergy problems in the community from
hearing to and so I'm gonna try now
looking back from the building awareness
slide and that seems like the way that
we do fishing education which to me
seems I've had very good effectiveness
or so I wonder if the building awareness
will also have and to me the most
effective stuff for fishing has been the
technological like he can
email signing Marcel absolutely masters
and I just don't knows of what
technological aspects can apply to this
problem of the higher level yeah and I
guess it's more questions or community
is are there more now that you're doing
wrong coming to a second yeah I think
you make a great point I think there is
definitely more that can be done the
technological front I mean I'm
definitely not the person to suggest
those types of solution that's not my
background and not my area of expertise
but I think that there is a lot more
that could be done to fight BOTS on
social media for example to put measures
in place to better prevent the types of
abuse we saw from the Russian government
on Facebook for example you know there's
more that can be done and I think that
social media companies are reticent to
try new solutions and try to innovate in
this area and I mean Facebook in
particular as seem to say that our ads
weren't effective but at the same time
like they're you know that's their whole
business model is advertising so
obviously their ads are effective and
influencing behavior but at the same
time they're finding that it's not
effective and I think that they have a
lot more responsibility and that they've
taken in terms of trying to make sure
that their system isn't abused for ill
purposes so yes I short answer is yes I
do believe that there are more
technological solutions out there that
need more exploration
yeah so what are your suggestions
personal you got a crazy Bob is crazy
because source of news
so you suggest got a not a
counter-narrative but just yeah subtle
steps to help help off or pad you know
for their Facebook people that is a
great question
I think it's about having one-on-one
conversations really and trying to
approach that person from a standpoint
of empathy and because every I mean
every single person has their own biases
and their own preferences in terms of
where the answers their information and
if you know maybe you happen to like
MSNBC or something like that but and but
your uncle likes Fox News you just you
have to understand that there are
reasons why people turn to these
particular sources and have it you know
just not starting the conversation from
a point of view of oh you're absolutely
hundred-percent wrong like you should
never turn to Fox News that sort of
thing because that then the person will
just shut down and not not regarded have
any regard for anything that you say
further really they'll just you know dig
in their heels and that'll be the end of
the conversation basically I don't know
if that answers your question that's a
really really tough one it's hard right
yeah yeah way in the back
yeah absolutely so the propaganda inside
Russia is just as strong there're
several there are several state control
TV news channels that are trumpeting the
Kremlin line 24/7 so and that was one of
the reasons I mean a lot of what I told
you about the narratives of blow green
men and the plight people and the
historic reunion and you know the return
to Russia all of that all of those
narratives came from the state
controlled domestic TV programs so that
gives you a sense of just how insidious
the propaganda of those outlets really
is yeah just wondering from the
perspective of consolidation of like you
know is new pancit if they're sort of
like a like a parallel yeah I think that
I hit on something that really concerns
me in our US media environment like you
said there is a lot of consolidation
going on now especially with local TV
news being bought up by Sinclair like
you said which has a very specific
editorial line that they've been given
and you have specific programming that
they absolutely have to run and all of
those things are messages that people
don't necessarily understand where those
messages are coming from because they're
they're watching what they think is
local TV but what they're really
watching is is a dictated editorial line
so that's that phenomenon is very very
concerning to me because to me yes you
hit on it it actually parallels what
happened in the 1990s with Russia
TV and independent media in general
became completely swallowed by this
propaganda apparatus and that's
something that is just really has
insidious effects as I again person
personally experienced sure so I hate to
stick to our script - and it's not
propagated I swear but we got a flat
rate I do have a point two percent to
you to the speaker and hopefully
everybody had a good time but yeah
there's a little class outside so