any questions so
um
i'm pretty interested you know by by
this talk um i know you know 100 secrets
is very complicated
and doing it wrong you know i can have
you know tremendous you know
consequences you know for an
organization so i can't wait you know to
see what you brought us today at them so
the floor is yours
cool thanks very much alejandro
uh so this is attacking secrets and
cloud-based applications
hi everybody my name is arjun sudkov
i'm a security engineer at skyscanner
and this is my second time at b-sides
happy to be here again i've been
spending the last 20 years almost all my
life hacking to learn
it never gets old i do freelance
security audits i have certifications
and hobbies and then
software defined radio is a really cool
thing that i'm getting into it
today the agenda
looks like this
first i want to discuss secrets what
they look like and what they are
then we'll take the journey to the cloud
and finally see how we can attack and
defend secrets
so for the purposes of this a secret
will be defined as a piece of
confidential information
that is used for programmatic access so
for instance if you have login
credentials to an email account right
and you just use them through the
browser that's not programmatic
but if you were to write a script and
put those credentials in the script
then that that means you're using it in
a programmatic way and so would fall in
scope of this plain text secret that
term refers to the unencrypted initial
form of the secret itself so
if you had a base64 encoded password
string right
you would say that you obtain a
plaintext secret by base64 decoding that
stream
a hard-coded secret refers to the fact
that the plaintext secret is written
down directly in a file
cloud is
managed infrastructure with a shared
ownership model so it's like a huge data
center that you're responsible for some
stuff but the cloud provider is
responsible for some other stuff
the coupling is a very important concept
that comes into play when we talk about
the cloud
it's not specifically new but it's
definitely a central theme
and what it refers to is the separation
of a single system into operationally
independent components and we'll see how
that plays out throughout the
entire
presentation infrastructures code is a
sort of relatively new thing that came
in with the cloud and machine readable
files used for configuring the cloud and
so just think of it as like a config
file that you submit to your provider
and that config file tells the provider
how to deploy infrastructure what
resources it needs and so on
and then roles and policies again not
something new but made an appearance in
a big way
in the cloud because these are now the
abstractions that you as the client or
is the user defined
to specify authentication and
authorization controls
um
and finally the pipeline
once again not something new uh refers
to an automated sequence of steps for
building testing and deploying
applications and when we talk about the
cloud is pretty much a basic concept uh
because you want to be able to deploy
your code in a repeatable and automated
way
now so the journey looks approximately
like this
and we start off with one host per
application this was a little bit back
in the day where you have your php code
with apache server and mysql running all
of the same place
ftp your files over there right and your
servers will of course be on port 80
if everything hard coded in code and
config files that was all fine
so then
that sort of shifted into separating the
early signs of decoupling so to speak
having one host
with your a web server then having
another host of your database server
that quickly sort of shifted into using
containers because of course having
multiple hosts is very expensive so
you'd have just the one hose but with
isolated containers which could be
linked together
and networked together and interoperable
and this was good
and then
sort of scaling that we saw
data centers which were the big places
with people
who would be managing hardware and you
know the network behind this hardware
linking it all together and you could
rent some space in there and deploy your
application there
but the problem was that the scaling was
manual if you had a lot of traffic
and your resource you were just handling
it well you needed to go in and make
some decisions provision more
uh resources to handle that traffic on
the other hand
if you have a lot of resources and then
you have very little traffic
effectively you're paying a lot for an
infrastructure that you're not using and
so that's
not good
and the cloud emerged out of that
and apart from just managing the
hardware the cloud was now managing the
hardware and some of the software
and it provided some really cool
features like auto scaling
because docker wasn't built to scale
and cloud providers
they designed these solutions that
allowed you to scale it i think this was
a real game changer overall
there was you know a secret manager as a
product so there's all these different
products that you could use and there
was this infrastructure scope syntax
that you could use to define which
resources you needed
and of course roles and policies made an
appearance because
that's
you know they are the links between the
different components
define uh how they should interoperate
and then finally
that
you know today we see kubernetes as a
really big thing trending and
so
one way to look at it is kubernetes
first of all it's open source and has
all these built-in features it's no
longer a provider that and
like features you pay for or products
you pay for it's already built in
kubernetes already knows how to handle
auto scaling auto balancing it knows how
to roll out roll back things
it can do software updates at scale it
has a secret manager and this is all
built in like uh you know all you have
to do is just define that you want to
use it how you want to use it
and what that leads into the tendency is
application centric what that means is
that
uh we're trying to get developers uh to
write code and not worry about the
infrastructure setting it up or managing
all they have to do now is just provide
this additional configuration file
infrastructures code that tells
the cloud provider or kubernetes what
resources are needed to support the
application
the code itself
and when we zoom in on that the
applications themselves the application
code and how it works is also decoupled
into several components
and typically
there are three of them one of them
being the view which is generally like
the front end it could be you know
graphical it could be programmatic
uh this is what your users sort of see
and access
and then you have controllers which is
like the back end and this is your
business logic it knows how to handle
requests it knows how to handle data
what to do with it and so on
and then there's data which could be a
database could be a cache but it
provides some sort of model a structured
model for data
that the application expects to use
and manipulate
and then another dimension that that i
want to make a point about is
secrets and i think this is another
damage that can be completely decoupled
from applications and it's important
because really secrets are the ident
they are they're always associated with
identity and with some permissions
this is a security area
and for the purposes of this
presentation i'm going to be using this
icon to indicate a secret
now i could really find it like a good
icon to indicate a secret so i use this
one to indicate
the moment you know you
disclose some secret information your
heart skips a bit
so yeah
and
what you can see from here is that
really there will be secrets always
associated between
uh associated with connections between
the decoupled components
and so they're like sort of a glue or a
necessary part of a glue
that keeps everything ticking together
and we'll see how that
plays out
now to get all of that deployed into the
cloud as i mentioned we use a pipeline
pipeline is a series of automated steps
and this here indicates that the process
is continuous it means that developers
keep on writing code pipeline keeps on
doing stuff with the code and then
feeding back some information to the
developer whether it succeeded
whether it failed whether it was able to
deploy and so on and this process can
keep on going it's repeatable and
automated
and
the general
sort of steps that happen first is
downloading the code once the code
repository receives some code it will
use something like a web hook to notify
the pipeline that there's new code the
pipeline will use a token to access the
repository to pull the code download it
and it will install requirements and
this can involve uh using internal
package repositories and to use them you
will always need some kind of token or
secret to access that
then testing
generally uh the tests the testing phase
consists of linting which refers to code
style
so
it's like think about single quotes
versus double both how many spaces for a
tab so things like these
unit tests they refer to
testing the application code function by
function
and then finally you can also add a
security test and here you can throw in
your
automation tooling and as you will see
it's it's very useful and at sky scanner
we have worked on this problem and
towards the end we'll see
what things you could use for this
so then if the tests went well
the pipeline will start building uh the
application image and when it builds it
it will publish it into an image
repository which again people use some
kind of secret or a policy associated
with accessing that image repository
and finally deploy the infrastructure
and so it will use once again some kind
of secret to send to the cloud provider
the infrastructure is code configuration
that will reference this newly published
image
and so the cloud will deploy all of that
and then the pipeline will be sending
notifications back to the developer
again some kind of web hook probably
to
let the developer know let's see what's
going on
uh just to give you an example
a pipeline configuration is just like a
file it can be one or maybe multiple
files per project per code repository
but generally they're still in the code
repository
here this one here is from github
actions
in steps you can see the steps that i
was describing
installing linking and so on
they are sequential so they always wait
for the previous step to finish before
starting the next one
and here at the end
this step needs a couple of secrets and
what you can see here is that the
pipeline exposes the secrets as
environment variables
and through these secret placeholders so
it's not the real secret it's just like
a username for a secret and this moment
right here is key to decoupling secrets
from the application code
and we'll see
how that plays out
to put it all all together end-to-end
this is the diagram uh there's a lot of
information on it so just work through
it with me
right here in the middle we have the
pipeline as i was just describing it
then here on the left we have the
developers that are going going to be
writing some code and they're going to
be using some kind of token to send that
code to the repository
then we saw what the pipeline will do
and so once it deploys the app the
application itself in the backend may
have multiple secrets for accessing
databases external service providers
some kind of integrations what have you
in addition the graphical user interface
may have multiple secrets if you're
using
client-side widgets like
a map or a customer service or some kind
of contact
bought
they will all
probably use some kind of token and this
token even though it's obviously public
being in the gui it still needs to be
restricted
now your users they're going to be
accessing the application through the
graphical interface and again they can
authenticate themselves in the system
using some kind of secret username and
password typically
and then you might also have some kind
of
client services that are consuming data
from you or pushing data to you and they
will also use some kind of token to
authenticate them
and so in all of this you can see that
there's a lot of secrets
it's not something specifically new but
you can see how they have multiplied and
spread all over
and
they have different purposes different
scopes and and
different types
and
there's different ways to attack all of
this to gain
advantage and to hack the application
and so the general areas of attack
there's three of them the first one
being the repository
and
to attack it we can attack developers uh
through social engineering malware
infection or sometimes people
unintentionally disclose their secrets
and so using ocean
potentially an attacker can recover that
and then use a developer secret to read
or write
to a code to a private code repository
having that of course you can exfiltrate
information and potentially uh
execute in the supply and chain attacks
we'll see how that works in the later
slide
in addition you can also do code
injection through compromised automation
tooling
so
today
more often than not in a repository
there will be some kind of bot or
integration that's going to be
checking the request maybe notifying
people perhaps commenting with a cool
gif
uh all of these are third-party
things applications right and they're
writing inside
your code repository and so naturally
they may have access
to secrets
or
just code in general and here
a key point to make is that if a
developer
writes code that has hard-coded secrets
these hardcoded secrets are exposed
directly in the code repository
as well as everything that goes further
down the line the pipeline and the
runtime
in the cloud
if the credentials are hard-coded we may
have heard
[Music]
uh
stealing the
web hook for example if you have in your
pipeline configuration file as we saw if
you have it hard put it in there to
notify you
so the attacker could read that file get
the web hook and potentially
uh
continue on triggering build denying you
sort of
for building your own
services because your build holes will
always be building something
now
when we look at defending that
first line of defense is due diligence
which refers to evaluating what third
party integrations you're bringing in
uh
do security self
not some securities assessment
questionnaires which is asking
the providers how they handle security
how they manage data
do your own security audit
you know reality versus expectation kind
of thing
check it
um minimal privilege this is a big one
restricting scope of the sequence so if
your one developer token is able to
access all the repositories read them
and write to them
that's very different from you know
stealing a token that only has a
specific repository in its access
oops
use unique expirable tokens so that you
can identify in case of a leak you can
identify who was affected how and so on
uh using unique web hooks for triggering
builds so and sort of functional
segmentation right if you have one web
hook
that the attacker has and now the
attacker can build any repository with
that hook
it might give a much bigger advantage
and finally avoiding hardcoded secrets
as i mentioned is a huge one because
avoiding them will prevent them showing
up all throughout the pipeline and
avoiding them
is mainly using these placeholders as i
already showed in the pipeline example
in code you can also use things like
these
environment variables so your app
expects the api key to be there
and when it starts running it first
checks that key and then does stuff with
you
in this case you're avoiding a hardcore
hard-coded api key in here and if you
have a config file you can also use
placeholders here the format is you know
you can pick any format
i guess it will largely depend on
whether your pipeline
is capable to of automatic substitution
in these static files or not if not then
what you can do is just write a simple
shell script or python script what have
you that would substitute these
variables for you again using something
like this
alternatively if you don't want to use
environment you can use a request to a
secret service api like a secret manager
you would request it with
for example this key and then the
service would reply to you with a secret
value which again would avoid having the
actual hard-coded secret value in there
moving on to attacking a pipeline
uh
the pipeline can be attacked through a
supply chain attack
and so this attack might happen
because of compromise packages or
dependencies
and
in addition dependency confusion
it happens on this page when the
pipeline starts building the code and
it's pulling some
dependencies that it needs to install
them so that the app can run
and one really really cool case was by
this guy alex berson
uh
he
came up with this clever trick so
essentially
what happened was here you had some uh
in this case paypal
it's a paper project it had some
dependencies
and these right here highlighted in red
these were private things right they had
them in their own internal repository
and they weren't in the public npm
and so what alex did was he just
basically published a public npm package
cpp logger version one
and then all this pipeline tooling or
sorry the code repository tooling that
bumps up your versions to keep your
repository updated it basically saw that
there was a newer version of this
and it pulled it from the public
repository and so
here you can imagine that's like super
very critical because you're pulling
code
right directly into your python
and
you know to make
just to mention that we we're gonna have
around five more meetings you know for
the presentation
uh okay you know uh hurrying up
uh to make things worse uh this thing
the pipeline normally runs as root so
you're having a
arbitrary code as repenting in there
overriding pipeline configuration
if possible is another attack vector
which would allow you to
maybe leak
secrets from the pipeline
an injection additionally can be done
through pull requests and there was
another case with travis ci
and where they had masking of
pipeline secrets but then something
happened and this bug was disclosing uh
secrets through an injection of pull
requests
through injection injecting environment
variables in the polyrequest
and so finally common injection through
compromised automation doing the same if
your pipeline here uses
any kind of docker image or what have
you a package that is not managed by you
it's third party and if somebody
compromises that once again it's very
similar to a supply chain attack
uh defending that the first line is once
again due diligence uh making sure you
know what is running in there
uh
hardening the build host so if you
if you can run it not as root perfect
restricting connect to network access
so it doesn't have doesn't so it can't
access all the internet in the world
uh locking dependency scope in your
packages to make sure that when you
download the internal packages they're
actually downloaded from your internal
repository
in npm you can scope them
um
taking over registering in public
repositories registering the same names
to prevent people from uh hijacking them
in the way that alex did
and of course avoid using secrets and
pull requests in general
uh finally attacking the application uh
part here all the same wasp stuff still
applies in particular path traversal or
local file inclusion and remote code
execution
are nice because you can disclose
hard-coded secrets
and potentially with our ce call
other endpoints to retrieve them
if you have unrestricted api keys these
can be abused
[Music]
and ssrf server-side because for sure
this thing made an appearance in a very
big way
in cloud
because of all these decoupled
components you can abuse the trust
between the two components there's
capital one breach example
what happened was that there was a role
with all these permissions for accessing
all over the place
and there was a bucket an s3 bucket with
sensitive information so the bucket was
protected the role was protected and
then there was this person who had
access to the role
and the
trust between the role and the bucket
was absolutely because it was supposed
to be like an internal thing and so the
person was able to exploit that trust
and it says maybe a server side because
forgery i don't think
it exactly is a server-centered place
for you but the idea is there it's the
abuse of that internal trust
uh in the aws there's an endpoint with
metadata that you can call so if an
attacker can't compromise your ec2
instance for instance they inject
through the pipeline supply injection
and then they call this method at the
endpoint that you can retrieve active
instance credentials
for your ec2
uh the defense for this
you know the typical staff do early
design reviews and threat modeling of
your application to understand all these
different points where your secrets are
uh what permissions they need and what
are the vulnerable points to contest
security reviews
use automation tooling
as i mentioned in your pipeline in
security test
run static code analysis from static
file analysis and new secrets
placeholders in
your code to decouple uh the secrets
from the application
at sky scanner of course we have the
opportunity to look at all of these
problems and
whispers is one of these uh applications
that i've been working on it's a
tool that you can use to detect static
file
credentials
and so the difference here is that
static code analysis tools they
typically cover a dynamic called like
java python
what have you but they don't cover xml
or json files
uh to look for credentials specifically
and so whispers does that and what you
can do is you can put it in your
pipeline for security testing or you can
set it up as a pre-commit hook to even
prevent your developers from committing
potentially sensitive information
it's expandable with rules and
plugins and it's for non-executable
files including iac which is making a
big appearance and
it does like private keys
certificates and so on
we have
other security automation tooling
recommended check it out cfripr is
really cool if you're using aws
confirmation it will tell you uh if your
roles and policies are correct and this
is a huge advantage because it's very
difficult to understand it and if you
have this tool i think of it as security
thing for a yak it's super helpful
then we have uh lambda guard which is
for uh infrastruct serverless
infrastructure auditing
and certain secrets for hard-coded uh
for detecting hardware secrets and java
javascript but this one is sort of
getting phased out because there's now
other tools that are better and more
efficient
nevertheless check them out
and yeah to summarize
different types of secrets developers
accessing code build secrets assessing
repositories packages components runtime
secrets accessing services and data
different ways to provision secrets one
of them is hard coding them
which would be at
coding time another way would be using
environment variables which would be
better
and using a secret manager which would
also be better with placeholders and in
this way we want to couple secrets from
the application
there are many many many many problems
and questions that must not only be
asked but they also have to be answered
uh around secret management
where destroyed plane takes secrets uh
how to share it um how to go off
boarding you know when people are
leaving the company and what happens if
secrets are stolen or lost stolen or
lost how do you rotate them how do you
keep track of all these random expirable
secrets
minimal probations and in the end what
you have is you have many people using
many types of secrets for many different
purposes and you can appreciate that
this complexity goes away beyond
uh you know the password security
requirements that revolve around this
best practices
i think we're a little bit you know over
over time so okay well this is this is
pretty much it
uh thanks very much for your time and um
reach out to me if you have any
questions you want to follow up on
besides slack or on my linkedin and just
to mention we're hiring in security so
pick me up if you're interested thank
you
brilliant so i got a question but i
would drop that in the in this live
channel you know because of the time
constraints but thank you so much you
know for participating in visa personas
as usual you know we've seen your your
face a few times and you're always
welcome you know to come again so thanks
so much and for your presentation i
appreciate you thank you thank you