further ado
claudia the floor is yours
thanks for the introduction and let's
get started we have a lot of to cover
today so um as announced i will talk
about chances and the meaning of
opportunities and challenges of machine
learning in cyber security so what i'm
going to cover is that i want to give
you a basic understanding of machine
what machine learning is
we will learn about different types of
machine learning how they work and see
areas where machine learning is already
applied in cyber security but we also
want to discuss challenges and problems
that are related to machine learning in
cyber security so the goal is that by
the end of this talk you should have a
solid overview of how cyber security can
benefit from machine learning but also
which challenges and threats and
problems are related to it so it's more
meant like um
an introductory talk to the topic and
not a real technical deep drive but i
hope you can get
a few
things inspirations that then help you
to maybe dig deeper into this topic
so
just two sentences about me damien
already introduced me so i'm a
significant security consultant at in
visa where i'm mainly focusing on
penetration testing so whether mobile
application security
um but the interest in machine learning
i actually got this during my university
studies um
where i
dig
deeper into reinforcement especially we
will come to that in a second and i'm
now really curious to see and explore
how
i can combine kind of these two really
interesting topics machine learning and
cyber security
so first is machine learning precisely
to security at all a thing or is it just
kind of a yeah hot topic by uh
making it some propaganda or marketing
stuff so
um if you think back traditionally
security problems are aided by
mathematical models such as
think about cryptography
but those models have limits when it
comes to a very large number of
variables we have to consider and if we
have to process a huge amount of data
and these are areas that are actually
the strength of machine learning so this
is why it is indeed a thing we we can
use um or we should um
uh yeah cover when talking about cyber
security also because a lot of companies
are kind of adopting it
but the word of caution
not everywhere machine learning is
written on the outside it's actually on
the inside so because there are overlaps
between machine learning and just simple
statistics some vendors might claim they
are using machine learning when actually
they are just applying simple statistics
in the back so it is indeed sometimes
more kind like a
marketing thing or kind of thing to to
make look things
nice and shiny
so with this in mind first let's get our
terminology terminology straight so
there are terms like artificial
intelligence machine learning deep
learning flowing around
and
um often used interchangeably although
there aren't exactly the same thing so
artificial intelligence actually the
broad field and study
uh of simulating human intelligence
while machine learning is a subset of it
an approach to enable computers to make
decisions on their own and do
stuff and things they were not
explicitly programmed to do the phrase
was coined back in 1952 already by
arthur samuel a pioneer in the field of
computer gaming and artificial
intelligence so it has been longer round
than one might think but it has formerly
limitations due to the computational
power it requires and this is also the
reason why it's kind of gaining momentum
during the last decades
now deep learning again is just um a
subset of machine learning so it's
certain techniques applied within
machine learning
that is about simulating the behavior of
the human brain and we will come back to
this a bit more in detail later during
this talk
now
also machine learning is not just one
thing but there are actually different
types of machine learnings and all are
suited for different types of tasks that
we want to achieve
um we usually divide between three
different types of machine learning
supervised learning which might be the
most commonly known and can be compared
to learning with a teacher so you kind
of have someone or something that tells
you exactly what is what and
what to make of this things you see
and it's mainly used for prediction
so we want to map a certain input we
have to a certain output
and the most commonly known
sub-category here is classification
where the predicted output is
categorical so think of it in the
example of image recognition so we give
it a picture and we want to know if we
can see here for example a cat or a dog
if we want to predict some real valued
output then we are talking about
regression so this can be applied for
example for weather forecasts or market
forecasting
also in unsupervised learning we have
different subtypes unsupervised learning
can be comparable to doing self-studies
so
you don't have any
one telling you what to make of the
things you you read and study but you
have to kind of organize and structurize
it on your own and
so you usually use it for example for a
time like of pattern detection and
structuralizing data so clustering for
example um is about grouping input into
segments based on certain similarities
so the machine learning algorithm is to
kind of find those similarities and
group the data according to it
we have association rule learning um
which is about finding correlations you
might have always seen this for example
if you get proposed products in amazon
or if you have kind of like spotify and
your weekly discovery playlist or
something like that
and
it's based on the probability that we
see two events occurring together so
kind of if you like
song a there is a
eighty percent chance that you also like
uh song b because this has been observed
together um very often
and as a third
type of unsupervised learning we have
dimensionality reduction which is often
more like a
pre-processing or intermediate step it's
for filtering and reducing data so
reducing the dimension dimensionality
for example if we want to create
visualizations or if we want to process
the data further and
i want to kind of
reduce it for that purpose
and last but not least we have
reinforcement learning which can be
compared to learning with a critic so
someone who doesn't tell you upfront
what is what and what is right and what
is wrong but
will give you feedback based on what you
did before and the what it's used for is
like learning procedures of actions
based on the feedback you get and we
will have a closer look and all those
three types and how they are applied and
or can be applied for
in the field of cyber security during
this talk but first let's see the basic
machine learning process you usually
have and it all starts with gathering
data because data is kind of the fuel
for machine learning so we need it for
our training process and
um like with fuel for a car the the
quality and quantity we have has a
direct input on the results we get so if
you have bad fuel in your car um
it might destroy it or it might get you
very fun the same is for data and a
machine learning algorithm
next we want to prepare the data so kind
of for example randomize the data
samples but also very important check
for biases so for example is there a
certain type of data very dominant in
your data set and if yes your result
will also be biased toward this type of
data and will be struggling with other
types of data so the very yeah kind of
famous or infamous example for that is
the early phases of face recognition
which were mainly um
trained on
images of white people and then of
course the algorithm struggled with
the faces of people of color
now
something else we want to do is split
our
data set into a training and evaluation
data set so
usual uh ratio here is something like 80
30 or 70
80 20 or 70 30. so you have a larger
training than eventuation data set but
we need the evaluation data set a bit
later as we will see in a minute
next we choose a model so a model is um
kind of the the raw material uh
we have it's a it's a generic program
that is then made specific
by data so think of it like clay which
will then get molded through your hands
by repeating the um
yeah
molding it or turning the the wheel or
something like that
so we of course have to choose here
which learning algorithm we want to use
and
there are of course multiple algorithms
out there so there's not just one for
classification one for clustering but
there are a lot of different types and
um
what you have to choose is of course the
right right algorithm that's suited for
your purpose so is it at all a
classification task is more a clustering
task and which algorithm in for this
task is the best or could be the best
for your case
next we start training so this is the
learning process that forms the model um
until we finally have the result we want
and it's an iterative process so we do a
lot of training loops but
during which we make repeatedly small
changes to our model until we finally
get the result we want
and to check whether we've reached the
state we of course need to evaluate
our model so we run our model on the
evaluation data set you remember step
two where this where we took this out so
we give it data it hasn't seen before to
check its performance on unknown inputs
and see whether it can work with that so
you have problems we will come back to
this later where you might have not
trained enough and it doesn't perform
well
on the data set or you might have
trained too much and then it also
doesn't perform well on the evaluation
data set
so based on the outcome you will start
tuning
your uh
um
yeah your algorithm so
certain parameters you use and try to
optimize the performance for example get
to create a prediction accuracy
and last but not least you can finally
apply the model this step is also called
inference so putting the machine
learning model into production use the
trained model actually to solve the task
um
you would like to solve it
so
let's look at this process um a bit more
in detail in the different types of
machine learning we've seen so at first
uh let's look at the supervised learning
and here let's choose an actual example
from the
area of cyber security a very typical
one like spam detection
so this is a classification task we want
to predict an output that's categorical
so is it spam this is not spam
and what we need first in the training
process is label data so or we at least
we need two things we need the labels
this is what we want to predict like
spam not spam
and we need label data so in this
example a lot of emails for which we
already know this is a spam email and
this is not a spam email
now we will describe each data point
through a feature or attribute vector so
this is the criteria based on which we
will then train our model and later make
our predictions so this is actually data
or our features that are
probably relevant for for our
classification here
so
the example of emails this could be for
example the sender address or contained
links or attachments but something like
for example the date and uh time of
receipt might not be a
feature that's really important relevant
for predicting if something is spam or
not
next
we start the training process as i said
it's an iterative process where the
learner develops models or shapes the
model um based on the training data
and
we once we we are finished the training
process or also in between we then
run some evaluation to see if we whether
we first have to maybe change and tune
some things here so what we could change
for example is of course some parameters
in the algorithm itself so in the
training part but also maybe make
changes to the feature metrics if we see
um
maybe a feature might uh
be uh add a feature that might be
helpful a removal feature that we don't
think happened this all can change the
outcome
so after completing the training process
then we can use it for prediction which
will mean we get an email
also we have to extract the feature edge
or attribute vector as we did for the
training data
and now we'll put it or we'll give it to
the model that we've trained and as a
result we get back
a certain probability that the mail we
gave it is a spam or a non-schema spam
email
and the same principle can be applied
for example for or is already applied
for malware detection um where you then
of course have um
extract features from from the ba
from a binary to see whether you have or
whether it's uh
yeah
a good or or bad uh
um
executable for example you're dealing
with
now for those who thought oh this is
really interesting i
want to do this myself and get my hands
sturdy and give it a try what you need
of course is some data and there are
data sets out there you can use for
example for training your own spam
detection algorithms that the spam based
data set from the university of
california irving
and that has about 5 500 emails of which
about 13
are spammy mess so you have the label
data there you can use and also for
malware
um there are data sets like microsoft's
malware data set or endgamers ember
malware properties dataset that you
could use if you just want to try it out
and try training a model on your own in
these tasks
so what does the process now look like
or what are the actual differences in
the process now for unsupervised
learning as we remember this was more
for organizing and structurizing data
so the first difference is that we have
a completely different input here
which is we get unlabeled data so
as i said we don't have something that
already tells us what is what we just
get data as it is
and again we must describe it through a
feature vector
and um start the training process and um
shape the model and
as a as an outcome usually then there's
some human intervention needed and
required to interpret the output we get
at the end
from the model
so uh the
algorithm or we will get back some type
of clustering for example
and we will then actually have to detect
what
is the points or the reason that the
data was clustered that way so taking
the example here um what we could end up
with is for example like on the left we
got two clusters based on the shape as
we can see and on the right we've got
three clusters based on the color so
this is why we then here need some still
some brain to see what what we get as a
result
now where could this be used for example
um two areas of applications are user
behavior analytics and forensic analysis
so in user behavior analytics what we
want to do is of course find anomalies
and user behavior and detect uh to
detect insider and outsider attacks so
parameters you usually look for are for
example
my ip addresses and their geolocations
time stamps user agents or certain
actions
that are done
and
if you look at it as a very simplified
example here you can say that the
behavior of admins
has some typical traits putting them
into one group so kind of like the blue
cluster you can see here and the typical
behavior of your users is a different
group it's like the yellow cluster here
and if now an admin for example logs in
from an unusual ip address one that's
usually associated with a normal user
for example he
moves out of uh his admin cluster so
what we can do very well with
unsupervised learning here is detect
outliers and things that do not fit
into or
do not fit into their usual cluster into
a cluster at all
same goes for forensic analysis so for
example if you try finding anomalies and
log files which are usually huge
this is really
of help here to process this amount of
data
and to find things that really stick out
and can be indicators of attacks or
compromise
so outliers could be for example data
that
doesn't match any other data or
something that's unusual in terms of
frequency in terms of correlation on
sequence and there are tools out there
that already use unsupervised learning
um usually with a deep learning approach
which i will explain in a second
for example splunk or dark trace are
tools for user behavior analysis
using
unsupervised or using machine learning
and supervised learning to
do this task or a forensic analysis
you have the elastic stack um which is
free and open source and helps you
actually create your own machine
learning jobs to analyze and monitor
metrics from blocks so we also see
they're kind of a
machine learning becoming easier
available to end users so you don't have
to really understand the deep
technical stuff anymore and the
mathematics behind it but it's kind of
getting more user friendly and more easy
to use
now
last but not least from the types of
machine learning reinforcement learning
which differs a little from the two
things we've seen now because here the
agent or we call it the agent so then
let's call it the learner the one who
learns is creating their own learning
experience through interaction with an
environment so we don't have data
beforehand and it's like learning
through trial and error
so the best example to think about is
about this is for example cleaning robot
so if you think about a cleaning robot
running your how around in your house
what it has it has certain sensors
attached to it um which will um yeah
give it a certain state so for example
with it will see
all my front proximity sensors detect
something very close to me could be
translated to like i'm standing in front
of a wall or at least in front of
something
so and based on the observation it has
it now tries to choose an action and it
has an a certain policy which is kind of
its current knowledge
that helps the agent
or in this case the robot to select and
execute an action so possible options
would be here for example move front or
turn sideways
and as a result of taking action we have
another observation
so for example after moving front um the
agent will detect all my bumpers the
table is
detected that i hit something or when it
turns sideways it will say my front
proximity sensor see there's nothing uh
in front of me anymore
so
based on the observation we put first
head the action we took and the new
state and observation we are in
the agent will receive a certain reward
uh so kind of which indicates whether
the action was good or bad so kind of if
if we bump against the wall against the
wall that's bad we give it a negative
reward meaning basically a negative
number usually
and if we detect we have now a freeway
um we give it a positive
reward so kind of a positive number to
say this is this was a good result and
over time this then shapes the policy
so the re uh enforcement learning
algorithm then modifies the behavior
over time because the agent's goal is to
maximize its rewards and get as many
positive rewards as possible and this
will filter out the bad behavior
over time but of course it's time
consuming so your agent will probably
bump the ball around thousand times
before it starts learning that it's
actually bad what it's trying to do
there
now um for the application of it in in
the area of cyber security
there are some challenges as i said
already that
it is um
time consuming but also um
the the thing is that real world
problems are usually have a large
have a large state in action space so a
lot of possible states a lot of possible
actions that could be taken
and as a consequence reinforcement
learning is now usually combined with
deep learning approaches we come back to
this in a bit
and
this is still a quite let's say a quite
new thing um
and the first great success with this
was in about 2015 with um
maybe you've heard of it alphago uh by
google so a kind of a
machine that taught itself playing the
board game go and then
became so good uh that it defeated not
just the the best human players but also
the the best machine players around at
that time
so
so far the greatest success
of this has been in other domains like
video and board games or even robotics
and autonomous driving but there are
some
yeah
scenarios where it's considered and
experimented with uh in the field of
cyber security so one thing is for
example cyber physical systems so
meaning iot industrial internet smart
grids smart cities so basically
everything that's smart
and
you take the the
yeah the sensor input
of the or the sensor input of the device
defines its states
and
by training it um certain changes in its
state and in a sense it might help it to
detect if it's for example is if it's
under attack
and to select the appropriate action
so you kind of get a
device that can defend itself because it
knows how to react and which actions to
take if it detects some
malicious things going on with the
sensors
another area where it's
applied is for intrusion detection
systems but more as in addition to
other learning approaches so
combined with supervisor unsupervised
learning
and the aim is to
enable systems to choose more
appropriate log files for example when
looking for traces of an attack
by
giving kind of a reinforcement
additional reinforcement loop which will
give a reward or a penalty when a system
selects a log file that does or does not
contain um anomalies or signs of an
attack so that over time the system will
get back better selecting those log
files
and a really interesting area of
application is the one of uh yeah game
theory
so with game theory we can model the
conflict and cooperation between
intelligent decision makers so basically
describing for example an
attacker and a defender
fighting over
an asset
and this is exactly what um
experiment what was experimented with so
you have two agents the attacker the
defender
both act against each other and try to
learn the optimal attack and defense
strategy
but the problem with this that is that
it of course simplifies the real world
cyber security problems into a very
limited game of just two players and
with one two asset switch which is
usually not the case in in the real
world
now the most common
yeah algorithm use as i said is
when you uh combine reinforcement
learning with deep learning this is why
i want to look or give look the give the
deep learning also a closer look
so deep learning usually refers to the
use of neural networks
and
the neural networks is based on the
working principle of neurons in our
brain
if we look at a
model of an artificial neuron we receive
a certain input so in real life certain
um yeah a certain input from our senses
and uh those go through synapses
into our neuron and those synapses have
a certain strength that amplify or
weaken the input so these are called
white weights in the artificial neuron
and this determines of which input is
more or
less significant for our case
now the neuron will sum up all the input
we get
and then compare it to a threshold value
and if this threshold value is exceeded
the neuron will fire and meaning it will
produce a kind of a positive output
which is also called the activation
function
now in deep learning we
have multiple layers so a simple neural
network just has the one neural layer in
between in deep learning we have
multiple so the input of
the output of one layer is the input of
the next layer and each layer will bring
more complexity
uh to the
to the table so thinking about image
recognition it's um
so the first layer might be able to
identify edges the second layer
might identify a combination of x edges
the third might identify certain
features like eyes or mouth and the last
identifies combinations of features like
a certain face
um
now uh so
how does the learning then work in those
networks so the the training means that
we will again have an iterative process
where we tune those weights so the
strength of the synapses and the biases
or the threshold values within the
neurons
in each neuron in each layer until we
finally get the um
yeah get close to to what what we want
and so at the end there's always a
so-called cost function
which uh will determine the degree to
which the output we get now differs from
the expected output and um the result is
then pushed back across all the neurons
for for tuning those values
i see i'm getting a bit darker let me
enlighten myself a bit
okay
now
um
having learned about the basic
principles let's uh sum up um a bit on
the opportunities how we can actually
use this for our purposes so we've seen
already some examples but
the the main
areas where it's now applied and indeed
promising is
auto automation for example so that it
takes over repetitive tasks that such as
triaging and triaging
or log analysis or
so
that human analysts can then actually
concentrate on the really difficult
stuff
also most promising is again to actually
combine it with
with humans so enhance human analysis
for example to reduce human error but
also to increase efficiency
so there was a very promising experiment
at the mit's computer science and
artificial intelligence lab
called ai square
for log analysis and what they did is
that they had first supervised learning
algorithms that finds extreme and rare
events and logs
and those events get then reviewed by
human analysts which will label them as
this is normal or this is indeed an
attack indicator and now we have labeled
data and can feed this back in a
supervised learning loop
and based on this input then and also
the one what from the unsupervised
learning
part can do a prediction if an attack is
imminent imminent or not and
during this ex
experiment the attack detection rate
actually rose to 85 percent and heavily
decreased the false positives
also it can help us to improve threat
response time so by
pulling the data actually
required or really relevant data um
from from log files um
so we can
prepare them for analysis so that cyber
security teams get more simplified
reports making the
most important things or highlighting
the most important things and then can
make decisions um faster
and it's kind of like yeah of course the
dream that maybe also
at a certain point of time machine
learning might be able to detect zero
days so there have been of course some
studies and experiments on this but
i'd say um we are not entirely there so
usually
if you have something
completely new your model has never seen
it of course will have problem dealing
with it so um yeah yeah we're not quite
there yet
so
there are of course some problems and
challenges as i already mentioned i
already said you have general problems
during the training like um overfitting
it's like you you train on on your data
set like learning for a test and uh
getting sample questions and learning
exactly those sample questions and their
answers and then you get in the actual
test different questions and you
perform bad that's the problem of
overfitting
um underfitting means we have not
trained it enough so we have not studied
enough and then we also will not perform
well
also a problem is always dimensionality
so the more the mind dimensions and
factors and features we have to learn
and the more data we
is required
and again there's this inductive bias so
there are certain assumptions we made to
make for example when extracting the
feature vector
and
this has of course
an impact on the results we get
especially in machine in cyber security
a huge problem is also the shortage of
data or especially the shortage of label
data
and
then the imbalance of data set we have
so usually your ratio should be like
something like 1 to 10 so
in
yeah 10
normal emails have one spam email for
example
um but in cyber security
this is usually a lot higher so you have
a lot for example a lot of benign
traffic and just a very few malicious
samples
also think about the consequences so if
you if your model does produce false
positive
you lose work time and confidence in the
system but think of the false negatives
if your model isn't working good enough
so the worst cases of course you can
have a full system compromise
and another great problem is um that
often we want results to being
interpretable so
we want to know why a certain output is
made so why did the algorithm choose
maybe for example a certain
um
log file or a certain right did it
suggest as a certain category in
classification and it's kind of
difficult to see under the hood on which
basis um this is made so it's kind of
makes it difficult to explain
and of course the world changes usually
quicker than
models or there's always time as i said
required from
changes until a model can adapt to those
changes so you have new protocols coming
up new types of activities and malware
and this is of course also a
challenge so
my last
five minutes uh
let's look on the other side of the coin
so we've seen um a lot of cases where we
could use machine learning but also have
a look at how machine learning can be
abused
and the first cve
for machine learning component was
published in 1919
which was for an email protection system
so you see
the attackers never sleep
and by the end of 2020 my
cooperation with microsoft and other
companies published this adversarial
machine learning threat matrix as a
framework to for detecting responding
and remediating threats so in in
highlighted and white are threats that
are really on techniques
specific to machine learning systems and
as you can see there are quite a lot and
in grey there are techniques that are
applicable to both machine learning
non-machine learning systems
and due to the time i could just um
i just picked two very small examples to
demonstrate this
two types of
attacks here
poisoning and evasion
so
poisoning
is something that usually happens or
happens during training
meaning
uh the attacker is somehow able for
example to modify
labels if you want to do some
classification or to inject adversarial
samples into the training data set and
the best example for this is actually
from 2016 um microsoft's chatbot tai who
i think
who remembers this so this was a
chatbot
program to learn from interactions with
users so the user text it got was
actually the input and it had to be
taken down 24 hours later as it has
become sexist and racist so
means of course if you give it poisoned
input you will get poisoned output
and
another
very well famous let's say famous
example is evasion it's kind of like the
most common uh type of attack you have
so you try to design input that is then
wrongly classified by the machine
learning model and i've chosen here an
example from
from defcon 2019 the stealth shirt so
you have an object detection camera so
whenever you've seen the green square it
detected an object and as you can see
whenever he doesn't cover um the front
of his shirt
he is not detected so this is how the
stealth should
work so kind of confuse um
the um
yeah the algorithms so it doesn't detect
the model and this has also been shown
in research for example by
um
putting stickers on stop signs which
then get miss classified guy miss miss
classy
cry to not no longer stop signs but like
a speed limit 30 or 50 signs which is of
course if you think of um autonomous
vehicles uh really bad if this
was a successful attack
and
last but not least of course we cannot
just attack um machine learning but we
can also use machine learning for our
attacks so with with everything
everything can kind of be used
as a weapon
and there has have been some examples
showing this successfully like breaking
uh the google capture with machine
learning or generating passwords or
creating more concise lists based on on
data on the user which make password
cracking then more successful
that you create um
malware that can then evade um
anti-malware engines or also for
advanced phishing attacks so for example
the um
that tweets fishing posts targeting a
specific user and
seeding those posts dynamically based on
topics extracted from the timeline and
posts of the target and the user he
interacts with and retweets and follows
which makes it then really hard to
detect that this is indeed
fishing
okay
this concludes my presentation i hope
you gained a good overview of the topic
and
i'm happy to answer
questions now
thank you very much claudia
and let's wait a little bit to see if
people have any questions
again you can write the question here in
uh
in zoom or even in slack we will answer
those in the meanwhile
um i want to ask something claudia um
i mean first and foremost great
presentation thank you very much i feel
like was very informative and especially
talking about a quite complex topic we
could be i mean it's actually easy it
has a lot of stuff going on a lot of
winning parts but i felt like it was
really easy
broke down
and and you know and and sent to us you
know so that was was great uh i have a
question now then have you have you
surveyed or do you have an understanding
of how much learning has been applied in
nowadays security cyber security
solutions on what the one that they
claim that they have machine learning
on their solutions and if you do i mean
what would your you know what do you
think about that um
is there anything any
something that you want to comment on
those
um
just let me repeat your question to make
sure absolutely yes i
understood it right so um
so
where has it actually been applied
um and yeah
how well basically or um
in general i was asking if you had a
look at other uh softwares or services
in the internet they claim that they
promote machine learning as their
product if you have a look at you know
what do you think about implementation
of course uh this is usually the problem
that you can't really look under the
hood of the product so um because this
is kind of what their business is built
on
um
but uh
for sure you can see that like in
so it's mostly now and
let's say more more products for for the
blue team like i said like like splunk
or dark trace so
they actually they couldn't do what they
do if it wasn't real machine learning or
more concrete really deep learning that
they apply so you can be pretty sure
they're actually uh um losing it
the question is you get
very little on information on what
exactly they're using so they usually of
course say okay we have some deep
learning applied here but
they they won't give you details on the
models or
often also not so it's
often also the question what training
data do they use for example to actually
get their models trained
um this is also something you should
maybe ask the vendor when you consider
using their services but um
don't expect them to really give you an
a
very informative answer on that because
yeah that's a kind of part of their
secret
yeah i can imagine that i can imagine
that they can you know um
play in this regard you know what they
have um and also understand that some of
them you know they just
it's not easy to figure out if someone
is using that but it's good to have some
pointers and especially understand right
if the
you know the outcome is expected to be
from machine learning or just a bunch of
i don't know crown scripts you know and
then they just analyze the data and then
so so that's why that's why i was asking
if you had any of the experience yeah so
you can be actually pretty sure if you
have those large really really large
amounts of data um
the best way to handle this um for those
use cases i showed is this machine
learning you can't actually
yeah or
would take a lot of more processing
power to do it otherwise and so it's
kind of there also the economic option
to go for to use machine learning in
those cases
so we have a question uh from pablo uh
do you know an example of use of machine
learning to evaluate estimate risk
for risk estimation
i think he's actually more about yeah
business yeah it's called like yeah he's
kind of governed and policies
not out of top of my head but
let me do just uh
let me yeah and the answer to you maybe
a bit later and uh
have a closer look at this but yeah yeah
in the channel yeah we can you can reply
to the selection or tweet about it let's
see
okay
so i think there are no more questions
again thank you very much claudia