yeah if you ever
shut up
enough
for the
disclosing event
so we are just at the end of our um
first day
uh
we have this is the first time we run
this uh conference
uh the uh in in a private you know
visual setup i would say so we had some
technical issues
apologies
um
we have uh quite interesting talks
we
of course i think like we're doing
pretty good right i mean we're gonna
share uh at the end of the conference um
uh tomorrow a feedback form where you
can feel and tell us how you feel what
you like what did you like and hopefully
um next year we're gonna do a live one
but anyway it's the first day we have
seen few people joining we have seen
quite some attendance
on youtube
and
we want to basically remind these
participants to remind what we're gonna
do tomorrow tomorrow we're gonna start
the conference at 3 p.m central uh
european summer time
um we are gonna have the um
the google uh your smartphone
if i understand correctly
uh we're gonna have that
workshop tomorrow morning
at 10 a.m
which run on the monjuic track as we say
and then at 3pm we're gonna start uh
with the um opening
uh still in the segrada familia
and
let me see if i can share i think a
little bit let me share the screen so we
can go through
quickly what's going to happen tomorrow
so again as i said we're going to have
the welcome at 3 p.m we're going to have
tomorrow at 3 10 around table will be
joined by
maria dilon lola ogun
again apologies lola
i think it didn't spell that correctly
uh we're going to be joined also by
martin hoping martin ligo
this round table about diversity
inclusion um you know
acquisition acquisition and retention in
the cyber security industry but also at
large
and uh
rajvir will be our moderator for the
time
and after that we're gonna have uh some
more talks for focusing on again
pen testing iot security and and you
know uh
offensive security as well we're gonna
end tomorrow one hour before so that's 6
35 we have the closing still in this uh
track
i want to again thank you all the
organizers to make this possible i want
to thank kaitano he was the moderator of
this room uh track and i left us keeping
things on time and on schedule um and
also dealing with question and logistics
i was we also want to thank all the
volunteers at large the one that are
working on the social media
but also making sure that slack is is
tied and works correctly as well with
the moderators and volunteers for all
the rooms and tracks as well
i hope you had a great experience so far
and see you tomorrow