okay so i think it's about about time so
let's kick it off
cool so thanks everyone for
joining the closing ceremony
so i have to say i gotta mix feelings
right
like there's a um a lot of work
happening behind the scenes you know for
making this conference
possible to everyone and you know it
goes by so so quickly right so two days
has felt like it was flown you know the
uh the time he was so quick
i really enjoy and i'm gonna take you
know time to say thanks to everyone who
has attended
thanks for the speakers as well and for
the panelists you know we are today in
the wrong table so it's been incredible
you know the uh what we've seen in in
this conference right so
just to give you all you know some
numbers you know about the uh the
conference in the sake of transparency
um
so we have for this edition you know 50
call for paper submissions
uh we set it up a board of the um
uh independent members right you to
review you know those submissions and
rate them you know and
we also have shipped you know more than
one hundred squad swap boxes
into 20 different countries
uh so uh noting that uh you know not all
the bossie has arrived to its
destination as yet so you know there
might be some delays but eventually you
know they will get to their destination
we have also sold you know the um 300
tickets you know for this conference
we just generated a um around
1400 minutes of content on this
conference
and we had a total of 32 speakers and
finally so and again thanks everyone
that's been an incredible effort you
know to make this happen it's been
challenging for us as well you know this
was a virtual conference that we never
done before so we came you know from the
experience of doing an on-site
conference or i mean there is you know
different challenges that you have to
address right you know what they need to
say yeah it's a completely different
conference so we try to make it close
you know to you uh that's why you know
we came with the other swag
i think you know the um the the virtual
experience right it might not be exactly
the same as an on-site one so that's
something to keep in mind right um
well you know i'm gonna take the time to
say thank you to all the volunteers that
were having in the conference again they
were working behind the scenes they've
done an incredible job you know and
they're gonna be doing video editing
they've been dealing you know with the
um with the social media so a big big
round of applause you know to antonio
cooper evan you know guys
alberto pablo for your hope and
collaboration you know during this
conference we hope to see you again in
the in the next conference to come so
big round of applause to you to you
um
i also you know do you to say thanks you
know to the organization members are we
going
in here so we've got david christian and
i've seen i couldn't attend today so a
big shout out you know to all of you uh
i know it's a lot of work uh a lot of
meetings that we have to have outside of
your normal duties and i will know my
work
we do this
as a passion you know in our own spare
time so i know it's a lot of work and i
wanted to recognize you know all the
work the incredible work that we've done
you know in this conference to make it
happen right so kudos to all of you it's
always a pleasure to work with you
honestly i want to take the time you
know to to say thanks to
our sponsors and supporters you know the
conference so we've got keynes and times
you know it's the leading sport
we also have zero as well as the
contributing support there and then
we've got the um the community
supporters like the hackers the the flu
and drama as well
and also you know they did the squad
supporters right they are providing you
know the um
the uh the browsers right and i'm
visiting that's what's gonna do all the
attendees so kudos to all of you we hope
to see you again in future editions
right so you know
a big big thanks you know because this
conference you know
has happened you know because of all
your support as well
so
in in the sake of transparency as well
you know we are a um a non-profit
organization
right so i mean even we get you know
some cash you know from the um from the
sponsors we're using all that money to
prepare this conference and the money
that we have left you know we want to
also you know contribute back into the
community uh because in the spirit so
what this nonprofit organization was
founded
so in a similar way that we did in our
first edition we're gonna be a um doing
a donations you know of that money to
several the um organizations especially
in our privacy and digital rights
so
this year we're going to be donating
money to utah actually and next steps
in a similar way that we do on our first
edition so we want to
give it back right to the community as
well and in in the spirit of this this
conference and the uh the nonprofit
organization that is behind of the
business past alone
and now we got the giveaways right so i
want to congratulate mila yoroba
for winning the uh the apply network
defense the scholarship
uh you got a chance you have to go into
the page and uncrap you know one of the
courses so getting get in touch with the
any of the organizers and we will
provide you the delete off right and for
the fantastic lab we also have you know
a bunch of the um a witness as well
we've got terrance we got safety romero
we call paulo conception we call artem
applause to to all of you because you
also have you know the uh about that you
know to use on vendors
and there is also you know the um one
voucher left so whenever you get the one
of those swap boxes uh we encourage you
you know to take a picture of them put
them on social media and tap us and for
from all the ones the um all the
mentions that we have in social media we
will also be giving away another
dentist's life i am
about to one of you
so all the best and again enjoy you know
all those giveaways so really worth
yourself
also you know the um
i said like we we are small group you
know the uh of organizers you know
behind this how we also want to learn
you know from experience that you have
you know during this conference so we
really encourage you to provide a
feedback to us even if it's good or if
it's bad we want to know you know your
experience because that's the way that
we want to get better you know for the
future editions now besides barcelona
so i really really encourage you to take
a minute a small forum and you can give
us you know
the details and possibly your opinion
back to us and we will take everything
on board and learn you know from those
experiences and improved from there
and also you know we want to talk about
what's going to be next um
i mean
the
we know that the
copy situation is getting better uh
seems like you know next year he seems
uh continuing in this tendency we might
be able to go back to to an on-site
event right so we haven't actually
started talking about it right so
probably we're gonna take a break you
know from the
from the uh from the organization of
this conference i get our minds fresh
and i start thinking about what's gonna
be next right but you know maybe next
year you know in 2022 we are gonna have
again you know an on-site event where we
can all you know have a gathering
networking and go back to to the
experience right of being on an on site
here after for a conference right
and lastly i want to say thank you
to all of you again um has made possible
you know to um
to do this conference i want to also
give the chance to david and christian
if they wanna you know talk
again thanks to everyone
any last words
thanks to you alejandro
it was great also thanks to you
christian thanks to everyone who
attended panelists and such it was a
great experience looking forward the
next one
yeah great thank you everyone thank you
wg900 for organizing this
all together we pull it off at the end
of the hard work
thank you to all the people who attended
who asked questions thank you to all the
speakers for the sponsors to the
volunteers uh thank you everyone who
made this happen
uh this is for the community at the end
of the day um and we hope like the
community is going to enjoy it like one
of the good things about being virtual
is that all the recordings are going to
be there so people can still enjoy it
afterwards so yeah that's it
brilliant
see you all next year have a great one
bye-bye bye