so without uh further ado i would uh
introduce
uh
rajvir sandhu uh i hope i spelled your
name correctly
rashvi uh we're gonna hand over to him
he will be our host for next hour he
will introduce the topic the the panel
and
we're gonna have questions from the
attendees you can write your questions
here in zoom
um
or again if you are in in youtube you
can write your questions in in slack if
you are there
and what we're gonna do now i'm just
gonna promote all of you folks to the
panelists
role
and that should be it
okay can you hear me
raj
i can hear you now david can you hear me
absolutely great
um
unfortunately sorry unfortunately i'm
not allowed to start my video okay give
me one second yeah let's give a second
as i said we have some a little bit of
technical issues but
i should be able to
um
to allow you to
do that
um sure what it is now
okay let me double check if there is a
way to do so here if not
yeah i think we have okay you know what
i'm gonna make you calls
i think
this should work
does it allow you now to start your
video
and can you see me perfect i can
excellent
yeah policies for this like you know
glitch again as i said we had um this
technical issue we had to rechange our
links and and perhaps we need a couple
of things in the
configuration so i'm basically promoting
and all of people to panelist and then
co-host and then you can move from there
[Music]
i think
this is the last one
okay this is the last one let me then
promote all of you
two
calls because
yes
because
rash did i spell your
people incorrectly you did but you can
call me raj most people do most people
do call me raj nice and easy
okay okay okay hold on a second i've
only seen the promise the only one
i see i see martin
[Music]
everyone is here
hey everyone are you here i'll be
joining on video momentarily
hey maria
okay okay
okay great so again
uh a little bit you know the
introduction of the panelists to you raj
just for people who don't know him he's
a ethical
world health organization
so take it from there and thank you all
of you for joining
excellent thank you very much david
hello everyone i hope you are all well
welcome to b-sides barcelona 2021
firstly and foremost i would like to
thank the co-founders and organizers for
hosting such a great event as well as
our viewers and listeners because
without your attendance these events
would simply not be possible
so just to introduce myself my name is
rajveer sandhu otherwise people do call
me raj
i'm today's moderator or host of this
session
i have been working in cyber security
for the past 15 years providing security
expertise to organizations in ethical
hacking and risk management
and my current engagement is at the
world health organization in geneva
so today i will be speaking directly
with four panelists
who bring with them a significant amount
of professional working experience
within within their own specialist areas
of work so if you would please allow me
to welcome lola ogunteken maria dillon
martin hop and martin vigo so if we
could start please with lola lola how
are you today
i'm very good raj thank you how are you
very well thank you please take the
opportunity to uh introduce yourself and
then yeah and then we can go to maria
and then off to the gentlemen as well
okay brilliant um so my name is lola i
work as hr business manager for a
fintech company called silverfin
hq'd in belgium and we have
a team of remote engineers and as well
as a uk office as well
i actually joined initially
um to help with recruitment efforts and
have kind of progressed into a more
traditional kind of hr people ops
position
awesome great maria yes brilliant thank
you so much for having me and yeah my
name is maria gillam and i am the head
of people here at times
which is a security automation platform
and we're so excited to
be joining you all today i my main
expertise is
all things people so talent acquisition
and with a particular view on hr and hr
business partnering so i'm so excited to
to have a fellow hr person on the panel
as well with lola today
awesome great welcome welcome on board
and martin please
um
hi so so
my name is martin hopp i
come here from i live in poland and
uh right now i'm a staff engineer or
staff security engineer at uh old zero
uh mostly focusing on the security of
our platform uh but prior to that uh for
over three years i was
a security engineering manager at all
zero leading a couple of different uh
security teams
in application security vulnerability
management offensive security
awesome cool stuff fun stuff and uh
lastly martin please
yeah
it's it's funny we have two martin's in
the in the call so i can be martin
bigger
and the other martin so in my case i
think uh 12 years uh working in silicon
valley in different
companies actually some of the bigger
ones like apple and salesforce and
currently
at a company related to social networks
uh i'm on the hacking side of things so
first i started a software engineer and
then because my passion was uh all
things hacking i did a lot of product
security and currently because my
passion is really offensive the
offensive security side of things
i'm working in a in a red team
and it is a pleasure and an honor to be
to be invited to such a
such a panel of of experts and
especially for such an important
conversation as we're going to have
100 thank you all much appreciated so
as all our viewers and listeners know
our topic for this roundtable session is
on cyber security skills for high-tech
companies we will be talking about
talent acquisition diversity and
retention as martin vigo just mentioned
which are very interesting topics across
all industries which i personally
believe will always attract
attention due to its nature so let's
let's jump straight in let's start with
the topic on
talent acquisition
and if i could begin with asking
either lola or maria
could you please describe to our
audience what talent acquisition is
and what it means to an organization in
today's world
sure i can i can take that is that yeah
i'll take that and so towns acquisition
is how how you
um how you acquire your top talent so
how you source how you find your talent
and how you can be compete in the the
people market and within a such a
strong competitive zone such as cyber
security so and for us that is sourcing
finding
getting the hook getting them in hiring
them getting them through the process
and getting them in the door into into
our amazing organization
um and it's
the difference for me i i don't have
a strong cyber security background
i have a very strong tech background and
i've learned so much here at times in
terms of how we acquire the cyber
security people and it is far more
challenging than many other roles within
the tech organization
that's great and lola would you like to
add in addition anything to that
yeah um i think the only thing i would
definitely add i think it's on the
competition piece um uh you know
definitely if there it is a somewhat of
war um on talent
um and understanding what the best is so
you know every um company and department
and
um team manager will have a concept of
what they believe the best is the best
fit
so having a good understanding of what
that is for that particular unique
opportunity and trying to meet the needs
of that
trying to do that effectively
oh that's great that's a great
introduction
talking about competition um and
attracting talent
how do organizations or how can
organizations
ensure that they are attracting the best
talent
and in your opinion
what do you believe are realistic
expectations
that organizations actually want to see
in candidates
um i think when it comes to actually
attracting
the best candidates um
i always think organizations should ask
themselves well why should anyone join
us right so
um i think when you think of it from
that perspective that's the that's the
best place to start
um one thing people love um regardless
of the type of business it is is
a challenging opportunity
so um have being able to solve a problem
um and if you're honest about what that
looks like i think that's one of the
best ways of actually attracting the
right and the best people because quite
often when someone has been in a role
maybe for a certain amount of time it
starts to kind of feel like bau like
business as usual and actually people do
often want to get their teeth stuck into
something new right um or get the
opportunity to build or set something up
from scratch so i think um really that's
the first thing
one what type of position it is is it
and what type of opportunity is there
for that person to really flex their
muscles or build up skills
um or or do um a project or activity in
a more in-depth way
um
and then i'm sorry i forgot the second
part of the question i know it's just
really about what organizations you know
what their expectations are what they
want to see in candidates but i think
from my perspective
a candidate that wants to be challenged
consistently is a major plus point right
exactly yeah so i think what what
businesses are definitely looking for
what companies are definitely looking
for is
quite often when you are joining a
company or joining to solve a problem
so they are looking for people that have
that problem-solving mindset so
um you know we'll probably go on to this
a little later on but this is where um
you know into the purpose of the
interview is to really understand how
you approach problems um it doesn't
necessarily mean you always come out
with the best solution but how do you
work with people how do you tackle it uh
when it doesn't work the first time what
do you do then right um so they're using
that as an opportunity to really
understand whether you're going to be
able to do what they need you to do
it's not just about having that
technical skill set it's also how you
apply that and how you work you know in
general as well
absolutely and what about what are your
thoughts on
people skills
you know people that fit into the
organization especially culture i think
culture is absolutely incredibly
important and candidates need to be able
to fit in no matter what the culture is
like from my experience i've worked in
banking i worked in the public sector
and you know the two different
industries essentially even though my
role was very similar but culture is an
important important piece right
culture is um
yeah it is super important and actually
what is important to i don't know an
investment bank for instance
won't necessarily be important to a tech
startup or scale-up so i think one of
the things that's really important is
to understand the business that you are
approaching or talking to do your
research what does their website show
you what do their social feeds show you
um you know if you're not seeing much
about company culture then it could be
that there isn't much of a company
culture you know if it when it comes to
perhaps celebrating people etc so
definitely do your due diligence and
really think about is this the kind of
space i actually want to work in
i also recommend you know if you can go
on linkedin quite often when you click
on the company you can see the people
working within that company
you know just browse see where they've
been where have they worked before again
to get a sense of not just the culture
of the business but the culture of the
people who are you know the culture that
they worked in before and therefore what
they're bringing into the business so i
think really the most important thing is
having a realistic sense and
understanding
of the culture of the business because i
think a lot of people think okay i'm
working in tech so
working in this company is going to work
in this way and it really depends on the
industry
of the company when was the company
founded that's usually a big indicator
um as well so definitely i would say
just do your due diligence and and
research and see what you can find
great leather thank you sorry korea yeah
if i could just add to the culture piece
i i think they're they're phenomenal
tips and there's just one thing that has
recently come up internally that i'd
love to add we're we're a startup and
we're we're really trying to
define what our culture is which as we
all know is really difficult to do
especially at this stage so we've had a
couple of focus groups those were very
much about gathering information from
everybody in the business and one thing
that struck me about culture when i was
talking about like us getting our
statements out there our values out
there was i was so impressed with the
team saying
but let's back it up with actions so
that's the other thing that i'd advise
people to to look at there's there's
plenty we can all think of amazing
companies that have the best websites
and the best statements out there but
let's look behind that and let's look at
the actions that the actions that they
are doing to back that up so what we're
trying to do here at times is start with
the actions so that when we make those
statements we can bring in those
examples
live on our website on linkedin on
socials and get it out there
and then the other part of that is an
interview so that we can speak to actual
actions and impress candidates that way
that's something that we're definitely
looking for so to flip it on the
candidate side i would definitely
recommend they look for the actions as
well as the statements
that's great lola maria thank you so
much that's great and and now to of
course bring our security experts into
the same conversation so um and a
question to both both martin harper and
martin vigo
you know given the
exponential increase in global security
incidents
data breaches
news reports that are disclosing
new hacks against organizations pretty
much on a daily basis from what i see
in your opinion how do you believe
organizations or even cyber security
teams or it teams
can actually adapt successful
talent acquisition programs and ensure
that the talent that they are bringing
in
again as lola maria mentioned is to keep
them challenged how can those programs
be successful in based on what we see
today in the real world specifically to
cyber security
yeah that's that's a great question
because there is definitely
a
the word out that there is not enough
people uh trained in cyber security to
fulfill all the openings that we have
right and as as you very well mentioned
with the profession especially of
ransomware attacks that got so much
visibility to all the audience beyond
the hacking community or the cyber
security
uh
people
and
other companies started to catch up and
realizing okay i don't want to lose i
don't want to be open to lose this many
million dollars because of one incident
so i need a neck to bring in an expert
and take care of this so one challenge
that the
that the industry has is cyber security
is fairly new so
finding especially senior people
especially challenge if already and uh
the hr experts here will will will know
better than me but if already finding
juniors or or in entry-level um
candidates it's already challenging
imagine finding really senior people
i always joke with friends around that
here in silicon valley where you will
expect that all the experts are right
there is like 12 13 14 seasons like the
higher ups the most the the the position
with the most responsibility when it
comes to information security they just
go around the companies you know like
there are about 15 guys and women that
uh they just change companies among
themselves that are just not much more
just because the industry is what like
30 40 max 50 years if we really go to a
kind of the 70s when this all started so
it's difficult to be in hr and having to
bring people with seniority so now to
address your question more specifically
how can we do that my opinion obviously
from the perspective as one of those
candidates right what i've encountered
i can speak what is something that makes
me go choose a company over another
i was taking notes as as lola was
speaking here for me
one of the things that i've encountered
that has literally pushed me away from
that company even though i liked the
rest
was not having the possibility to
do research and present it at
conferences so for me that's a big
aspect of what i like to do it has i
could go on and on of the value that it
has for the company but i understand
this is not a critic but i understand
that there are companies that are
concerned of the legalities so or they
just don't really understand the culture
of of doing research in cyber security
going to big conferences to talk about
vulnerabilities they are just scared
that you may talk about one of their
clients or something like that or
someone will get upset and impact the
company or the business so for me when i
go interview with a company and they
tell me they don't have a
strong open policy on
do research or of course always
responsible right i'm not going to drop
zero days or critic vulnerabilities
without doing responsible disclosure but
that for me is a turn off and i will
probably pick another company
then training being able to get training
as you are at the company that there is
a specific budget to at least take a
training a year because you cyber
security in general computer science but
you get
you get rusty very quick like it evolves
so fast and when it comes to the threat
landscape we see it how it evolves every
day so if you don't get proper training
if that company doesn't provide you that
service then it's it's it's another
turnoff for me and then i will have
nowadays with
how the pandemic has changed
the landscape as well right flexibility
and here we have to differentiate i
guess in ages right probably the new
grads they don't care so much about that
they just want to cool work on cool
stuff enough opportunities to learn
especially what i would recommend is
look for a great mentor it's probably
most more important that you have a good
boss than a good job so to speak because
having a great mentor is really going to
make a difference at the beginning of
your career but when we look at older
people or older people i don't want to
call myself old but in my age are all
there that are starting to have families
then flexibility is really important
being able to work from home having a
hybrid a work environment in which they
can actually just go several days or
even beyond that if you want to hire
senior people you can't force them to
come to where your heart quarter is if
they live in new york and you have your
headquarters in san francisco and there
is a candidate that is really difficult
to find
over there
don't force him to come here and change
the kids from going to that school to a
new school they're wise or if it's the
opposite their husbands to have to
change the job and look for another one
whatever it is
that's another challenge that makes it
even more difficult to find senior
people
that's a great answer martin thank you
and it's interesting you mentioned the
pandemic and you mentioned hybrid
working as well as the remote workforce
so
martin i'd like to bring you in as well
on the panel please so could you please
you know from your perspective um
the kovid 19 pandemic
has introduced this new hybrid working
environment right and and this remote
workforce
how difficult in your opinion has that
transformation been
and what would you say are the lessons
learned
that we could now take with us
going forward
right so it's so it's going to be a
little bit hard for me to uh to say what
has changed because the company
that i worked at right now and the
previous ones as well
were sort of remote friendly from day
one so the teams we've been building
um
were
very distributed um like it's like from
from the get-go right so so this is um
this is something that
uh
it's like previously it was not really
possible for just one tiny part of a
larger company to say like we're going
to be remote friendly it had to be um
like supported from uh from the company
uh because ultimately security teams uh
work with the rest of the business with
uh engineering product management hr
finance like we
in our day-to-day job pretty much touch
everyone so if they're
the entire company is very focused on
you know bringing people together in
their offices and
like one all the team that's remote uh
would have had a hard time now you're
right like the companies that started
remote first um i think headed way
easier in the pandemic in that there was
literally no change uh in in how they
operate i can only imagine how um
how much of a transition that would have
to be uh for for other companies um but
you know talking to a lot of friends i
think the industry as a whole
was very successful in adapting like
some companies did better some did worse
um
but a lot of
companies
like they had to make that transition
and fairly
quick at that so uh so they did i think
one thing that kind of helped all of us
was that uh technology was there like
you know video conferencing um instant
messaging tools like uh teams and slack
and um
those things i think
uh in their maturity uh that they you
know we're in a zoom webinar i don't
know how difficult that would be to pull
out like maybe 10 years ago um
uh and today is just non-issue like
those things are just utilities they
work and i think that was uh that was a
tremendous help because then people
could focus on organizing themselves and
making sure that um you know their
communication protocols are
up to the task in this new um it's a
remote environment and not fight with
the technology so i think that was uh if
if this happened say 10 years ago i
think it would have been uh it would
have been much difficult um
like one thing i i want to mention and
to um
get a circle back to to what martin said
like i think the companies that
are um like very flexible and it doesn't
uh only mean allow people to working
from home but um you know also allowing
like flexibility and structuring and
structuring your day
uh and the flexibility in
like traveling so working from different
places different time zones as people
um
kind of find it either convenient or
necessary sometimes there are like life
necessities that
um we have to uh we have to take care
like those companies
do have and will have an advantage
because they're naturally a
their talent the talent pool they can
draw from is larger
but also since everyone is remote like
any person that's joining the company as
a remote employee has an easier as an
easier start and i think this is
um like attracting and acquiring talent
is
uh like this first necessary step but
everything that comes after that
onboarding people keeping them
you know engaged and included
i think that's that's super important as
well
that's that's great martin thank you and
and trying not to go off track but you
know being a security enthusiast myself
i would just like to say of course and
i'm sure you will agree
going remote especially for a full
workforce during you know the lockdown
phases in in whatever country
of course naturally introduced new
threats
new vulnerabilities
more phishing more scams more cyber
attacks
from your engineering background what
did you see
during this difficult time of lockdown
where everyone just had to work from
home
right this is so one
kind of tricky situation that i think a
lot of companies faced uh was that
you know
companies couldn't afford for the
business to stop like they needed to
ensure continuity
of operations and when people
went home
like there's always this question okay
so how are we going to enable everyone
to access that the tools the data
uh that they need to work on a
day-to-day basis and you can kind of do
that in a secure way or you can just
open it up uh to um like
very um
kind of public type of access just to
enable people to do their jobs but if
you're doing that in a way uh that
doesn't account for um
security and access control you're
opening up yourself to uh to a huge risk
so i think companies that
had a strong security story around
remote access in the past even if they
were not fully remote but had for
example
uh sales people that were like always on
the road and like did their uh homework
in allowing them to secure access i
think they had the foundation to uh
enable that enable that secure access uh
from the get-go uh and companies that
were sort of relying on
you know people being in an office and
treating
office and corporate network as the
security perimeter for the company like
they they were in for like a huge
readjustment
right so so i think uh it's um
like there were companies even though
that even those that were kind of more
traditionally um office bound so to
speak that were very well prepared from
a security and access management
perspective and i think this act this
sort of story around um we know who our
employees are we authenticate them
whenever they connect to whatever
corporate um tooling they need those
companies we're in a much better
position than you know companies that
were allowing anyone on their corporate
network to access uh things like
corporate intranet email and and and
things of that nature
that's great martin and lola or maria
how was your experience with with going
to fully remote because i'm sure you
were probably in the office prior
and yeah i i was on maternity leave when
it when it all happened so i came back
to a working environment and in a
previous company
that was extremely different
um and before joining time so i was
really really happy when i joined times
to know that our
view on where and how we work is up to
each individual employee
no one in times is going to sit and tell
you what your working week should look
like and we lead with trust and and that
was
a huge factor for me
and especially coming out of maternity
leave in particular so that's something
that we're finding is so vital we're
candidates they
not only is it like can i work from home
it is
how do you expect me to work how are you
monitoring me because so many
companies are either expecting people to
come back to an office
or they are like talking about hours or
how they monitor monitor them and people
have really gotten used to the
flexibility and and it's proven
that people can be successful companies
can be so successful we've been
incredibly successful all throughout the
pandemic which is amazing so there is no
concern around the productivity piece
and good candidates out there good cyber
security people know that and and the
companies that aren't looking at the
remote aspect and leading with trust i
feel are going to fall behind
yeah so i i would say that our
experience was a little different
but that's because um
we do work predominantly well we've
always been flexible so you could
usually always work
i mean if you work two or three days
from home before it wasn't too big a
deal
um people normally did at least two days
there were some teams that did more than
others
um we have our engineering team is
completely remote
so we've always worked in a flexible way
anyway
um
i think
remote based companies or remote first
companies have been growing um in
popularity anyway but when you join a
company knowing you're gonna be working
in an office then you make that
conscious choice for that and it's
because you do enjoy those face-to-face
interactions
um those physical and face-to-face
interactions um so i think for a lot of
our team
it was a shock a lot of people felt
isolated
um disconnected
um we had new starters and it's because
we didn't really i mean we tried but the
fact is we were never prepared to work
or on board people like this
and we just found that people weren't
actually
um engaged with our culture the way that
they used to be
um so there was a lot of learning
involved in terms of trying to turn
things around
but it was really hard work and
difficult to sustain
um now we're slowly kind of we're pretty
much back in the office now
and we encourage people to come in three
days a week if they're near an office
but they don't have to um so again it's
very much look we trust you you're
adults
you're gonna come in when whenever you
need to if you need to
and what we're finding is people are
choosing to come in on certain days when
they know they can collaborate with
other people
um
so that's what we're finding and
actually what we're seeing is people
just appreciating each other a little
bit more than they did before
and um yeah so for us we do like the
fact that there's flexibility and you
can choose when someone is remote
especially if they are in the same
country we try to get them to come to
the office
um on their first for the first couple
of days or so we cover the cost of that
but it's just to give them a sense of
you know silverfin identity so to speak
just that they attach
to more than the work they actually
attach to people
um and um
yeah the collaboration piece as well um
so it's been it's been an interesting
time for us and we're still working our
way through it
that's cool that's very cool if you've
got young children like myself then yeah
staying at home working from home and
managing those is a job in a job in
itself but yeah all good fun and games
now that's great thank you thank you all
so much for your answers um i hope it
was very valuable for our listeners and
our audience but let's um let's move on
to our next and in my opinion probably
the most important topic um based on our
discussion today which is diversity
and a question for all of you um and
please don't feel you need to answer
this in depth whatsoever i'm sure a lot
of our viewers and an audience have a
good understanding on this topic but in
your own words could you please describe
to me and the our audience what
diversity is
and if you believe
that there is a lack of diversity
within the tech industry
and we can start with maria
yeah absolutely um i mean sorry i was
nodding because when you said do we
believe this i was like yes yes it's
like shout out from the rooftops there
is and we should all be talking about it
every single
person in every tech org should have a
front of mind and i think that's where
we need to get to um i think there is a
general lack of diversity
in in tech in general but um as i said i
moved over from from tech
in general into into
a more cyber security focused um or and
from a ta perspective that is a struggle
and that is very very very clear that
there aren't um a huge range of diverse
candidates
ready to go like there are in other
companies they're there but companies
need to make a much more deliberate
effort
to go and source and find
um and to truly
truly put the effort behind it and i
think for me that's that's the biggest
piece and that's something that back to
my earlier statement about actions we we
have to lead with actions we have to be
really deliberate about how we do that
and i'll be really honest and i'm going
to make a bit of a statement here no one
has that right i i cannot think of a
company that is that i say they've got
it
they're sorted they understand it i mean
different companies do do well in
different areas but we in general have
such a ways to go and knowing that is is
a start
but man do we have to back it up with
actions
very nice and lola from your perspective
yeah i think um for me diversity um
comes in all shapes and forms so
we're talking about um you know your
background in terms of your ethnicity
we um sex um
it could be um
even just you know your style of
communication even uh it could be
um
yeah just so i i think one thing
that i do worry about when we do talk
about diversity like i think diversity
is very important
but
there are i think we first need to learn
what diversity tends to look like i mean
um i even saw a post on linkedin
yesterday
um about from someone at monzo and he
was saying that he um that we need to
also consider neurodiversity as well and
it's absolutely true and i think the
most important thing is one recognize
okay do we have
drones like or clones of people and if
we do why is there a reason why that's
important or we believe this to be
important
and how do we change this okay
and then on top of that we say things
like okay yeah we want to get people in
but then that it doesn't stop there when
you get people from diverse backgrounds
into your business is your business
ready for it is your is the culture of
your team ready for it because what i
often see is you hire people
but you don't know how to interact with
them you don't know how to perceive how
they're communicating with you or you
know perhaps you don't have the patience
to work with them in the right way to
perhaps train yourself etc and that that
is at company level department level
individual level
um you know is it actually safe
to be
different that's you know do we create
that kind of safety um
so that's what one point and then i'd
like to make a final point as well
just regarding
how we get more diversity so else
outside of the you know perhaps the the
traits that you can't see physically
um i think we also need to consider that
a lot of what people believe they can do
starts from a very young age
so how their parents raise them how
their parents teach them the difference
between boys and girls and how to react
to things what they should be interested
in etc like a lot of that is implanted
from a very young age
what do we or what do parents encourage
their children to do right do you
encourage your children to i don't know
do ballet if they're a boy or to do
sports if they're a girl like what what
do you accept you know do you let them
explore who they may be as well
um and then on top of that i think we
then also need to look at vulnerable
communities as well what do we do to
help them have access to these spaces as
well
um you know how do you let someone know
let someone from a deprived community
know that there is this cyber security
space and actually you know how do they
make that leap
so i think there's there are lots of
different buckets then there's a lot of
work that proactive work that needs to
be done
that's great lola thank you so much um
martin diego would you like to say a few
words on on diversity and
and yeah leave this
yeah please go ahead yeah
so i mean lola pretty much in a very
elegant way uh said everything that was
in my brain but i will try to add that
in uh yeah so the first thing will be
mentioning that depending who you ask
about what diversity is right you
probably get different answers because
um also because of the society or the
specific country what you see you may
get
if you ask someone what is what is
diversity they may focus on women or
they may mention the specific race or
they may or a specific minority so
that's one thing and meeting from spain
having worked there by being 12 years in
california in the us
and that's especially
especially true
so
so yeah one thing is is understanding
what diversity is right or that it just
doesn't stop at the specific thing that
maybe is more
relevant so to speak or more common in
in your specific country because it goes
beyond that
lg tv community for example that we
haven't mentioned that's that's another
one right uh lola mentioned very great
the company and it's also to be ready
for that there is
if you just uh start to make an effort
to maybe target
your your open roles or like try to give
opportunities for minorities or whatever
it is let's just say minorities as in a
in a global
sense uh and the company is not ready
you are not gonna succeed you're gonna
fail because that person
and that's not that's not on that person
specific
the rest of the company needs also to be
uh to be on point for that so to speak
um
then for example in my case when you
also mentioned
is there is a diversity in cyber
security i mean i just have
obviously we need to go to the official
data but when i go to security
conference and i look around
the pattern is clear it's it's white
males right so i i from my personal
perspective definitely there is a lack
of diversity i just need to look around
being in conference of thousands of
people and there is i think no question
in the value of adding diversity to any
industry but uh you know
from every perspective races
nationalities sex religion everything
else i i think there is no question
about that so we should definitely work
on that and then i will just just
mention specific between the spaying and
in the u.s specifically for me for
example in san francisco
the weird the the rare thing will be
that in a company i talk to the same
nationality so here in san francisco
when it comes to nationalities it's
pretty diverse but that doesn't mean
that it's the same case in cyber
security for example for races or for
lgbt community so for example here the
nationality diversity wouldn't be so
much of a problem again from my own
experience as a weight calculation you
know but it will be maybe
a problem for diversity when it comes to
two different races for example so so it
is definitely something that
we need to understand what diversity is
and that's why um
ravioli was such a such a good question
that you asked that what is actual
diversity
thank you thank you martin and and thank
you for that answer so
maria
marie you mentioned
actions actions actions which i thought
was great and
lola mentioned education from from
childhood
so what what if you could you describe
to me what you believe that
organizations
in today's day and age can what they can
do to improve diversity
where it will actually have a positive
impact
on talent acquisition
and you can see what i'm trying to do
i'm trying to link the two with
diversity and talent acquisition so what
do you believe organizations can do
better
to ensure that we
achieve diversity the way it should be
achieved
sorry
uh yeah i think one thing that i see um
with a lot of teams is quite often
um
we tend to promote
good
individual contributors to team leads
and managers right
and
that's fine but if that person doesn't
have the right kind of people skills to
understand how to kind of manage you
know different people that could be an
issue so i think
the when when you are promoting someone
when they are climbing up the ladder and
they have more responsibility um there
needs to be some training and coaching
that goes along with that and i think
before that promotion even happens they
need to already be demonstrating those
traits
and that's something that really
from what i've seen anyway
um doesn't really tend to happen um
maybe someone will do a managerial track
training course but that's it okay
you've ticked a box okay then you're a
great manager no it's not that simple so
i think there needs to be a much more
intensive way of actually looking and
measuring that
i think another thing that
companies can do as well is just
generally so for instance
do general training across the business
so what is diversity why is it important
how what what kind of things should you
avoid saying or how should you avoid
speaking about different people so i
think if we can have conversations um
training and conversations around that
because we don't want that to be a
one-way conversation but there should be
a two-way dialogue around that i think
that will help people um understand and
learn and when they're hearing the
experiences of perhaps a colleague or a
counterpart then it becomes more real
for them
um i mean what i have seen happen is you
know yes you find let's say for the sake
of this argument you find um a a female
who is willing to join the engineering
team
she's there for a few months and then
leaves why because people don't
communicate effectively with her perhaps
they're not listening to her when she's
giving feedback on hey i find this a
little bit offensive right so um i think
it's just we just need a little bit more
um
empathy
and to just take the time to understand
people as individuals as well um so not
just on work topics but actually spend
some time with this person so you get a
better understanding of who they are and
why they think the way that they do so
that when you are collaborating work
wise
there's a little bit more understanding
there understood and uh sorry maria
i was going to take the floor but
do you think that what lola described
there would encourage more women and you
know the lgbtq community to join
maybe the tech industry or any industry
for the long term
yeah i mean it
what lola was was talking about there is
is absolutely vital but also i was you
really triggered something with me in in
the general conversation
i feel like that is often missed that
like i know i talked about actions and i
believe in bringing in like bias
training and diversity training and then
following it up but it's also been in a
safe space to talk about it so we might
have managers um or people that think
oh i don't know how to bring this up but
i'm a little bit worried about the
balance on my team whether that be
gender whether that be people of color
whether that be race or sexual
orientation what whatever it is but but
it's also
sometimes it's a blue subject so it's
really really important that we we talk
about it more we talk about it and from
a leadership perspective in any kind of
all hands that we that we bring it into
every conversation that we bring it into
our performance reviews
and we bring it into our employee
surveys we ask people if they feel like
they're safe if they feel like they are
included and and to start touching on
the word inclusivity which is really
really important i feel like diversity
was the topic
10 years ago that we were talking about
just like women in business was 10 years
ago i feel like we need to start
thinking about that
inclusivity and how people feel on a
day-to-day basis we talked about how
people are working from home is there a
joke on a zoom call that makes them
uncomfortable because they're but
they're not in the office so they let it
go
like we need to bring in that culture of
open dialogue so that people feel safe
and can talk about it more and that in
itself will lead to more actions
that's great thank you maria martin hot
would you have anything to add just
before we maybe then move on to our next
topic
yes so like i wanted to reiterate that
uh leadership at every level plays like
a crucial role in that and
as as companies grow i think a lot of um
kind of is set by the early leadership
uh because as little i mentioned there
are
great employees who later on become team
leaders and managers but um i think
every time that that happens they kind
of grow into that role in a particular
context of the company so if there
there's lack of uh
diversity and inclusion company culture
at that point
it's very hard to like build that next
generation of leaders that will instill
that culture
um
and like
there's tons of work to be done both for
like enhancing
the existing structures like teams
departments and also encouraging and
um teaching that new generation of
leaders that um
that this is super important and
teaching them how to do that how to
listen to people how to coach their team
members to uh be
sort of more more open and
uh
behave in a way that does not pull uh
pull people off um and one other thing
is that um like i think to tie back to
the talent acquisition part
is that the interview process is like
super critical because this is when
when candidates talk to their future
boss their future peers and uh if you
want to bring in more diverse talent
this is this is sort of how you show off
this is this is where you show that
uh you know this this workplace is safe
for them to join so i think this is this
is super critical so when it comes to
training i think it's not only for
managers it's for
everyone who's kind of involved in that
interview process
that's great mason thank you so much and
and of course i guess it's one of those
topics where we could probably just
spend all day over a meal talking about
and with different opinions and
different experiences and backgrounds
but no thank you ever so much
um so that leads me on to um
kicking off our final topic which is
retention
so from my my perspective retention is
how do organizations essentially retain
or keep their employees
and based on your background and
experience once again
could you please
tell us
or you and the audience
what are the challenges
in recruiting and retaining people in
general
based on your experience at your current
organization
and we can start with martin bieger
all right i was taking notes here
because i have really bad memory so i
mean it relates a little bit to the
previous question that we had around how
we actually get people in in first place
right and i personally talked about the
the aspect of the flexibility and being
able to research and stuff going beyond
that once you are at the company how can
we make sure you don't leave i mean the
obvious one i will start with is a
career path right you probably people
doesn't want to get it depends because
sometimes there is people that they they
got to a good place they like the job
that they do and sometimes
there's this joke that a you know as
soon as someone does his job really
really well you promote him and change
him from that job or maybe it's actually
not a great idea because then you set
him up for failure if he's doing a great
job there and he's happy there just it's
fine keeping their
in i mean
from the monetary perspective obviously
you should still be motivating that
person right but maybe promotion is not
always the best path of course that the
employee needs to choose that but i
think a strong
solid clear career path is is a is the
way to retain someone because um
usually like here
in silicon valley right
because there is so much demand
especially in cyber security the joke is
hey
just if you don't like your boss look
for another boss rather than you know
look for another job and stuff you can
you can you have really a strong hand if
you are in cybersecurity in silicon
valley because there is so much demand
and
so many cool companies so many cool
products
to work on so retention is really
difficult so and it goes beyond giving
free lunches massages at the chairs
those are all good and you get that at
the big companies right but
i think a a strong career path is one
again flexibility especially an
understanding that the company shows
that understands that we've coveted
things have changed things have changed
and i i definitely understand
maria's point and lola's point that that
they have different experiences and it
is a challenge for everyone
i'm just saying that we cannot ignore it
so a company that
that gives you
um
facilitates a little bit of transition
if it needs to be back to the office
because not everyone has a job that can
do remote right if you work on on
servers you need to be on on the server
rack fix that so
so
that's another thing like the
flexibility and understanding and giving
tools for people to slowly transition
back to what it used to be if they have
to or even be open to to remote work i
think i will stop at those two because
i'm sure the the rest of the panelists
have others to add but for me those two
are very important
that's great martin thank you lola maria
would you like to add anything to that
yeah just as martin was was talking what
struck me is i i loved your point about
the massages and all that kind of stuff
because again
i if i look back five or six years in
horror and and talent acquisition we
were we were striving to bring in all
that stuff and now that stuff is
standard right so so you have to not
only compete with the standard stuff but
you have to really understand what
people want on a very personal level and
something that has
come up quite a lot recently is a voice
and a seat at the table
and i think that's
a new thing that people are looking for
and and listen it's great for us we're
we're a start-up on an incredible
product
people are interested and then we give
them the opportunity at the size that we
are and hopefully as we grow to continue
to have a voice so constantly getting
feedback not just on the day-to-day
stuff but on the product on on the
mission on the goals on where we're
going and and getting that feedback
constantly from the teams so that
everybody feels part of the journey and
that's something that we're really
really striving to do well here because
that is a differentiator it's no longer
the snacks because well we're not in an
office or well we are part-time but it
it's no longer that it's no longer the
dinners at google and it it's more than
that and it's really that self-worth
and what we're hearing a lot of is that
voice on the seat at the table and
getting getting hurt we're not always
going to agree but people want the
debate and cyber security people in
general love a good debate so it's
really really great to bring them in and
that's something there's loads of other
stuff but that's something i'm seeing as
a key differentiator at the moment
yeah i i completely agree with maria i
think
really understanding what is important
to the people within that business or
that organization or that team is the
first way to go again you can't make
everyone happy but at least being able
to understand what on the top line is
important to people
and i think
generally people want to know that you
are willing to invest in them
so whether that's
uh in in the view of a career path and i
think the wonderful wonderful thing
about tech and engineering in general is
that they're always these two parts
right so specialist and managerial so
there is the opportunity to do um either
one of the two and still earn very well
um but even where you don't have that
seeing that the company is growing
enough that there's always going to be
an opportunity to move into something
or perhaps work on another feature or
something like that
so
it's really more about being able to do
something new learning new skills
stretch yourself in a new way
i think another way is definitely more
around
policy
than the perks so
for instance if you want women to join
your organization what does your
maternity policy look like
like do you actually have one that
will support her
in her first year
and so that she feels like okay i can
actually
come back to work because i've been
given enough time or my partner and i've
been given enough time with our new baby
um and you know when they do come back
to work how are they supported when they
come back so i think it's really looking
at those
policies that help people balance what
they want to do personally
with what they want to do career-wise
and quite often
people have to choose particularly women
have to choose between the two just
because they're not getting the support
that they need
whether it's during that period or when
they get back and again this can look
very different for different people
but i think it's just ensuring that we
really invest in people whether it's
training policies etc and we support
them
um based on what their personalized
needs are
well that's that's great that's great
thank you thank you so much
something i've come across
pretty much every organization i've
worked at is employee survey questions
and in all honesty without
no disrespect to any organization i work
for
i personally have never really seen the
value of that maybe because i've never
stayed at a company long enough
however
in your opinion how valuable are these
employee survey questions to boost
retention and is there a real value in
actually doing so because i'm sure we've
all come across one before
yeah i think that's sorry
yeah i definitely think there's value
there i think um
depending on the type of organization
and business that you have but
especially with us
being more remote now in general it's a
great way to get an understanding of
what people are thinking
especially because a lot of the feedback
is anonymous and the surveys now also
look at things like well-being
as well as how they're feeling about the
company and their role
i think where it's a waste of time is
you have all that valuable information
um
and you do nothing with it i think
that's where actually it can be
dangerous and detrimental because
people just think okay what are we doing
this for if you're not actually going to
solve these key issues that keep on
coming up
so i think when you do these types of
surveys you need to truly be ready to
act
not just you know hey yeah we hear you
that's nice see you next month that kind
of thing
yeah you have to um it can backfire when
you don't i've seen it backfire when to
the point raj about
they roll them out you answer honestly
you're sitting you're waiting and then
they'll they'll come out with you know
here's the top three things we're
focusing on and they don't resonate
remotely with what you or any of your
colleagues wrote down and i think that's
the key point i think if you're doing
them you have to hold yourself
accountable and back to the transparency
piece of sharing every piece of data in
that obviously if there's something
really sensitive in in those open-ended
questions you can't but it's just so so
important
to be a transparent and the other thing
about them is
they're they are very useful but there's
also other ways to do them on a regular
basis like we we have bi-weekly town
halls we're going to have one after this
there's a question box or there's a
comment box we're gonna have a
suggestion
box virtually in slack at some point as
well
just to keep it regular because often
those
um
the surveys are once a year and
i mean by that point people could be
talking to other companies if there's
something that's bothering them so it's
more about that regular open
transparency and getting feedback from
the the teams on a regular basis
that's great thank you and um martian
hop i think we've just got time for one
more question before we open the floor
for q a but martin hop from from your
opinion in your opinion and from your
perspective what do you believe
organizations can do more
um in order to retain employees
especially in such a fast-paced evolving
industry that we work in which is the
tech industry or even cyber security
right so if i were to pick one thing um
because i would actually pick one thing
that the companies shouldn't do or
should do something to avoid that and
that is maybe something we don't talk
about enough in the cyber security
industry but that is burnout so i i have
witnessed that there are companies that
are trying to build their
cyber security
teams and departments but
given the for example amount of like
ransomware attacks that they're facing
and like constant fire drills and
security incidents like
those environments are burning people
out and this is um where we want it or
not like if people have
um
the choice between
a challenging environment where they can
focus on an interesting technical
problem versus fighting fires all day
long
like guess which company they're going
to choose um so
like trying to avoid environments where
um you know people are under-resourced
overworked
and burdened with tasks that uh they're
not realistically able to carry out i
think that's a
a very common uh problem the cyber
security industry so if you want to
retain our engineers let's try not to do
that or to do whatever is humanely
possible to avoid people burning out
now that's great thank you thank you
martin for that um so yeah thank you to
all our panelists for their
contributions so far just being courtesy
of time
we are now open to questions from our
audience and it looks like i have two
already um so for our panelists we'll go
with the first question which is
it looks like nowadays people move
companies every two or three years
um oh that question seemed to
seem to disappear
apologies uh it should have been
answered right
sorry you seen it
yeah sorry i think someone marked it as
a answer oh it looks already answered
okay that's fine that's time no problem
we'll move on to the next question no no
go ahead no go ahead use this one no it
was just a technical issue i think
someone just clicked it was answered but
it's not so
sorry go ahead no problem so i'll go
ahead so it looks like nowadays people
move companies every two or three years
what are your opinions about that is
that an issue
i yeah i'll take that and i worked with
a manager years and years ago who had a
real issue with that and would
immediately look at it at a cv and go no
i want loyalty and those days are gone
like those days are gone and in this
space they're non-existent so i don't
think we should be scared of it and to
the earlier question about attrition
there should be a healthy level of
attrition and people should be moving on
and companies should be happy for those
that are going on to a better position
and learning from it and pinching
themselves as their top talent but but i
don't think we should look at it as a
problem i think we should
look at it as
as the way the world and also then
not judge the person for it when they
come through on our applicant management
systems
what i will what i will add to that is
um i mentioned before having a clear
career path and ideally that will be
going up right but sometimes you need to
go in zigzag unfortunately which is the
job hopping which is like okay i need to
change careers if i want a bigger
opportunity for that so
it is a problem but the companies also
need to learn the why it could be
probably also as well
the case is i just want to go after
money so if i change three companies i
get a new refresher here in silicon
valley you get stocks for four years so
you get the cliff and all that stuff but
it is also a matter sometimes an issue
with the promotions with the career path
and sometimes you also get bored of the
product in technology there is just so
much stuff now you're working on
autonomous cars and then you switch to
go to rockets that and now there are so
many private companies and then you go
work for uh you know
the department of defense or cia because
you want to do more spy stuff there is
so much exciting stuff to work on that
uh it it shouldn't come to a surprise as
maria was mentioning that
we kind of look at it as oh this person
is not loyal
lola martin would you like to add
anything before we move to the next
question
oh yeah no sorry good go go ahead lola
i think it really depends because
how many jobs over what period of time i
mean
i think it depends i think if the person
is a consultant then it's expected
is it two years or is it a year and a
half like i will look at the months to
see like what's happening is there a
pattern does that mean you're gone in a
year and a half and it really depends on
what i need from that person and how i
how long i see that lasting for as well
so i think it really depends on the
environment but
i think two to three years is pretty
normal now to be honest
um
so yeah
sorry martin
yeah i just want to say it's uh like i
observe is the same reality to someone
changing their jobs two every two three
years that's perfectly normal these days
so i i personally and this is like kind
of my past experience as a hiring
manager i never saw that as a red flag
like if someone changed jobs every six
months then yes probably but also it's
also something um as though i mentioned
to to look into because maybe that uh
person was an independent consultant but
in which case is perfectly normal so
uh yes it's just i guess the reality
right now no
very few people work um
in a lifetime at a single company which
would happen before it's just not a
thing
okay that's great and we've got one more
question here
which is what would be some tips that
you have for one-on-one meetings both
for managers and
ics forgive me my acronyms are not the
best but
i think it's individual contributors is
it well that must be it must be
yes it's good
would you like to answer that one
um yeah absolutely so
i'll tell you what i do with my team
i mean it really depends on um i think
your space the place at which you work
the amount of work
everyone has and the seniority of the
people in your team
um i think firstly regular one-to-ones
are super helpful even if it's just as a
way to connect so i try to do
one-to-ones with my team
uh once a week i try to do it at the
beginning of the week to kind of kick us
off the right way i have done other days
as well
um i think it's really just finding out
what works for you and your team you
don't have to be rigid about how you do
what you do
we talk about generally how the previous
week went um i usually have an idea on
uh what their key projects are so it's
really to see okay what does progress
looks look like
what's holding you back in any area
and then we also talk about
achievements as well
any areas that are particular challenges
um and that's what we work on so those
are the regular one-to-ones
i then try to do monthly
one-to-ones again it depends uh but as a
minimum quarterly where we look over a
period of time okay how has this been
overall
um
and
is there progress from what we saw
before
um and i think it's those particularly
the quarterly ones where we then really
talk about the job itself how are you
finding things
is this still interesting to you is
there anything else you need to learn
what additional support do you need
so those are some of the things that i i
tend to personally touch on
anyone else from the panel
i would just add to um for individual
contributors to be brave and ask
questions of their manager i've seen it
so many times where
individual contributors think that their
one-to-ones are you know the space for
them to come and give updates but but
really that the value is that two-way
conversation
so and for individual contributors
listening and and for managers for their
managers actually in fact and we all
everyone has a manager at some point it
is really really important to kind of
respectfully challenge and ask questions
in those one-to-ones because that's
where the true value lies
any of our martians would like to maybe
add something finally yeah i will just
i will just mention that i had kind of
the two styles over over the different
jobs that i had i wasn't job hopping so
just in case i mentioned that but
i i had several jobs so i had the
managers that used it more as uh as uh
give me an update of what you've been
working on and i have managers that was
this is your time we can talk about
soccer or we can talk about a job but
this is a connection time and i like the
second one because uh we have stand-ups
to give updates right there with the
rest of the team and stuff but i really
like that half an hour a week or every
two weeks which i can literally sit down
with my manager and just talk about
whatever i want
because then that's kind of like a safe
space if i want to talk about
you know something that is not going as
i want it to go at work or stuff but i
can just also tell him about personal
concerns that may be affecting my job or
just in general about something that i
want to share with him because i have a
great relationship with my manager so
in that sense the one-on-ones are
valuable to me that time that i can just
really talk about anyone and as one of
my managers
used to say this is your time we can do
whatever you want so and we actually
used to go for walks
which is also cool like it's it's a
different experience when you are
walking than sitting in an office so i
will actually add that as well when it's
safe to do so you can always keep six
feet apart sure
oh that's great thank you ever so much
to all of our panelists for your
contribution i've definitely learnt a
lot i'm sure our audience have too
it's a pleasure to
host you all and
once again thank you again and thank you
to everyone at b-sides all the
organizers and the co-founders for
inviting us it's been an absolute
pleasure
and if there's nothing further ado then
we can put a close to the session
yes thank you thank you raj lola marcin
martine and maria
there is one question but we're going to
move that question to slack because now
we have to give space to the next
torque so
i don't know who send it but let's check
on the slack channel we'll have guytano
they will basically move there we can
have the conversation
again thank you much everyone it was
great contribution um
and um yeah let's talk
for sure at some point i love you