all right
hey everyone i'm rachel velasco
welcome to my intro to car hacking talk
i am excited to be back at carolinacon
and thanks y'all for coming out this is
catching the canvas
car hacking on a budget
so again i'm rachel based locally here
in charlotte
i've been in pen testing for a little
while now
and i'm psyched to be joining ibm xforce
red this summer
i'm also working on my masters in cyber
security
and i'm a graduate of the sans institute
women's academy which is a great
scholarship
program if you're looking to start out
in infosec
outside of work and school i'm all about
supporting
underserved communities in stem as
i am a part of many of those communities
i'm a next-gen leader with disability
inn
i am part of the north carolina
affiliate
of women in cyber security
and i most recently became the
us east coast coordinator for filipinos
in computing
which is an anita borg sisters
organization
i was a musician before i got into
infosec so you do not have to be
a car expert to start car hacking
so what is car hacking first let me tell
you the story
that drew me to all of this in the first
place
we have andy greenberg a writer for
wired magazine
going 70 down the highway in a 2014
jeep cherokee hackers charlie miller and
chris fallisek
are miles away telling him as they begin
their exploit
we're not going to do anything
life-threatening so don't panic
but they didn't tell him what kind of
attacks i had in store for him
the two start by putting the ac on full
blast
which is pretty tame they cycle through
radio stations
and turn the music up to a deafening
volume
greenberg tries to undo this but he
can't change
any of what they've done then they spray
wiper fluid
all over the windshield having your view
obstructed while going 70 miles an hour
isn't scary enough for you miller and
valasek just completely kill the engine
justifiably greenberg freaks out
guys i really need the accelerator to
work again
they tell him to basically turn off the
car and turn it back on again
just so he can regain control of his own
vehicle
this wasn't the first time that the
three of them collaborated on a car
hacking story
before this miller and valasek were in
the back seat
directly connected to what is called the
can bus
to terrorize poor greenberg who was
driving
this time they used the car's onboard
wi-fi to remotely attack the can bus
and as of the writing of this article
greenberg hasn't quite forgiven them yet
and because of this high profile hack
pricer recalled more than eight million
vehicles
i do have spoken about this at several
conferences like defcon
and black hat you can find a lot of
their talks on youtube and read up on
the research for free on illmatics
now let's talk about abusing keyless
entry
security researcher sami kamkar sami is
my hero
developed the roll jam in 2015 for under
the device would intercept and store the
signal from a car remote
that was currently unlocking its vehicle
and could transmit that same signal
later to unlock the
car again there's a little more to it
than that but that's the gist of it
two years later as shown in the video
these two men
are using a really attack unit to trick
the car into thinking that
it's keys in within range and so the car
unlocks
another two years later evanconnect on
youtube
has uploaded a video of a device with
the same functionality and he's selling
it for
nine thousand dollars
sami camcar said he can't verify the
authenticity of the evan connect video
but says it's still plausible
based on the state of hardware nowadays
and on his own research
so hacking cars to steal them isn't
sci-fi anymore
this is an actual threat
look at him driving away with the car
goodbye mercedes
however hacking cars does not
automatically make you a criminal
there are lots of fun things you can
achieve with automotive hacking
like improving the functionality of your
vehicle or using it for gaming
first we have makina on the left
they fashion a way to start their car
using if this and that and other iot
technologies
all i gotta say is okay google start my
car
next is open pilot top right
developed by comma ai which is an open
source
project meant to improve already
existing
driver assistance technologies like
adaptive cruise control and automated
lane centering unfortunately
[Music]
the hardware is expensive and the list
of supported cars
is still relatively small but that list
continues to grow
and finally in the bottom right we have
researcher pikachu
using his lame ass front-wheel drive car
to drift in a game of course
he's converted his mother's fiat 500c
into a gaming controller and ended up
developing the cam pad
so the can bus this is what we use to
actually
hack cars can is the
controller area network cars now come
with lots of little computers
called electronic control units or ecu's
and there are many kinds of ecu's
there is transmission control engine
control brake control
what i have on the slide is not an
exhaustive list
there could be one for controlling doors
telematics for
cruise control basically any
functionality the car could have its own
ec
and rather than connecting all the ecu's
through a mesh
they're all on a centralized bus became
a bus
the cam bus is more like a highway
rather than the bus
i alluded to in the title
implementations of can vary by
manufacturer
so you have lots of different flavors to
reverse engineer
and luckily can is low level and not
encrypted
so you can inject your own data onto the
bus
the easiest way to access the can bus is
through the obd2 port
commonly found in accessible areas such
as under the steering wheel like in this
gift
obd is onboard diagnostics which became
standard in the us
in 96.
so let's recap the different ways to
attack cars
first and easiest is physically using
the
obd2 port to directly access the can bus
next we can use other networks that
could be present like
wifi bluetooth or even through the
infotainment system
we have keyless entry and lastly
or more cars have mobile apps so these
could be used to gain control of your
vehicle as well
we're going to be looking at the
instrument cluster simulator by craig
smith
let me pull up my vm for y'all
alrighty so now let's dive
into the instrument cluster simulator
or icsim
it's running by installing the
dependencies for
it
so as you all can see i am using parrot
but really just use any linux distro
that you want
and what this does sdl
it renders the images and audio for the
simulator
awesome now we're going to be
installing can utilities so this is
installed by default on parrot but that
is the command if you're not using
parrot
cool now we're going to grab
the actual simulator
from craig smith's here we go
over to that directory see what we got
oh we have this setup script
and what it does is start up a virtual
can interface for
us to use so let's actually run that
let's confirm that
virtual can is up and it is cool
so now let's actually start up the
simulator
all right so here is what's called an
instrument cluster
um on this we just have the speedometer
left turn right turn indicators and an
overhead view of the car
on other instrument clusters you'll see
something for your fuel gauge other
indicators um
but this is all we're going to be using
in this emulator
so let's if he controls that
you can use a physical controller for
this but
i will just be using my keyboard
all right i'm going to hold the up arrow
see the needle going up on the
speedometer
holding down the right arrow left arrow
oh everything's working
let's take a peek into the canvas
you're ready so this is the campus
it is super noisy even though we're not
actively sending any comments
it would be nice to know
what are these message what these
messages do
so we're gonna hold down accelerate
but we still have no clue which of these
messages
since the accelerate command
so what we're gonna do is dump this
into a text file
and i want to figure out
what message
sends the command to turn the left turn
indicator on
on this so let's start the dump
i'm gonna hold the left arrow
so that the indicator blinks 10 times
3 4 5
6 7 8
9 10. we are going to look for
a message that was
in the canvas 10 times
now i will not be looking at it just
like that
we're going to sort through this
and we are going to look for the ones
that
came through 10 times
all right so we have these to try
so this is what your camera message
looks like this is the id number
how big the message is and the actual
data
so what we're going to do is send each
of these back
individually and see if anyone triggers
the left turn indicator all right
so we're going to be using can send for
this
we can we are starting off with the id
number
so it's this first three digit uh number
right there
the pound sign and then the actual
contents
packet one
fb
so you can see nothing happens so we're
just going to try all these until
bottom one it turns on
electron indicator
nice
[Music]
nothing
still nothing
yeah so we have one left
you try 88
and you see it blinked so we can send
back
this message as many times as we want
and that is the very basics
of car hacking and reverse engineering
you've only scratched the surface but
let's move on
all right now that we've taken a look at
icsu
we can go more into about starting your
own research workbench
you probably don't want to sift through
cam messages in plain text files
so here's some free applications that
you can use
some you're already familiar with most
likely
you could actually use wireshark for can
sniffing or
metasploit hardware bridge
you want something more cam focused
hearing caribou
and kayak are great places to start and
they
are installed on parrot by default
next we gotta find a way to connect our
computers to our cars
toyota researchers developed the pasta
the portable automotive security testbed
with adaptability
it's a very cool open source tool that
comes in a shiny heavy briefcase
and you can get your own for a whopping
28 thousand dollars
you might as well just buy a car at that
point
now the pasta is not actually meant to
perform live car hacks it's
more for brushing up on your skills
before moving on to actual car hacking
so this is a very expensive i see sim
now that you have some idea on why this
talk is called car hiking on a budget
here are some actual budget-friendly
pieces
that you can grab for live automotive
packs
non-display supports the elm 327
bluetooth dongle
like the one in the bottom left and
these go for less than twenty dollars
it's a little slow and upgrade is for
sniffing but you can still
transmit raw cam packets using this
dongle
minty net has been developing the nano
can bus for a while
which can get made for super cheap
he's also been working on a lot of
simulators and a value version
of the toyota pasta
lastly we have a couple of devices in
the 50 to 100
range so we have the car loop in the
middle
you can grab one of the makino devices
like the one on the bottom right i think
that one is the m2
and the contact i personally have a
contact
and i just got a hold of the
cantack pro so feel free to splurge on
more expensive devices when you have the
budget for it
now we just need a cam bus if you can go
out and buy a brand new car
awesome definitely do that if you can't
we have some more
options that are easier on the wallet
the ideal situation is grabbing
a vehicle from a junkyard with its
engine
and electronic cylinder maybe something
in the early 2010s
you could take it apart to give your
test bench more portability
and easier accessibility to the
different components
but that is not required at all
alternatively you can grab some ecu's
off of ebay
and stick them on a go-kart
now this last one i do not recommend
you can use your daily driver
now this is super dangerous especially
if that's the only car you have
so again i do not recommend doing this
you might accidentally get your horn
stuck and have it blur for all of
eternity
or when fuzzing blow your airbags out
or even void your warranty but hackers
don't care about that
and yes you could improve the
functionality of your own vehicle but
again not something i recommend
there's more resources i have two books
here on the connectivity of
cars there's this recent one
by alissa knight i can connect in cars
there is also this heavier one
by moeller and haas the guide to
automotive connectivity and cyber
security
i apologize if i did not pronounce their
names correctly
but my go-to is craig smith's
car hackers handbook so even though it's
a little dated
the foundations and concepts are still
pretty solid
he has a free version of this up on the
internet if you want to check it out
but i like having physical copies
i think i saw that he was working on a
second revision of this so
you might be getting an update soon
so some communities to reach out to
craig smith has open garages
if there isn't one near you he has some
detailed instructions on starting your
own open garage
asrg the automotive security research
group
has several chapters in the u.s and
worldwide
they host monthly events and training
and they've been
they've been really helpful from the
events that i attended
there's also the car hacking subreddit
and
it seems like a safe space to ask
questions and see what other projects
that everyone else is working on um i
haven't had any
issues in there so far and
of course we have the car hacking
village
i had a wonderful experience with them
at defcon
they're all really friendly and love
helping people start out in car hacking
they're starting to do more virtual
conferences like pancakes cons so
definitely check them out at their next
online event
so after all this if you've decided you
don't want to hack cars
no problem there are a couple things you
can do to
secure your vehicle as with all your
other electronics
keep the software updated if you have a
newer car
you can usually do this using a flash
drive or just bring your car to your
dealer
lock down bluetooth and wi-fi use
memorable passphrases so you don't have
to keep changing your pet's name
last you can prevent relay attacks by
storing keys
in a fairy day bag so these stop the
signals out
from getting out for about roughly 20
dollars depending on how big of a bag
you want
and where the chances some hacker is
going to drop a zero day to steal your
car
it's not very high but it's also not
zero
if you don't want to deal with any of
this just get an old car
or don't have a car at all
so thanks everyone i'm rach underscore
velasco
on a lot of social media you can shoot
me an
email thank you to everyone at
carolinacon
and enjoy the rest of the conference
you