hi and welcome to the session
in this session we are going to take a
dive into
discussing hacking movements we're going
to look at
some methods and some tips some
strategies that we have discovered doing
penetration testing and social
engineering engagements
to help you create social engineering
scenarios that actually work
so who am i i am william price
i help organizations identify
cybersecurity weaknesses resolve them
and reduce the risk of breaches
at cyberx and over the years
i've conducted a lot of penetration
tests
and what i want to focus on today
is social engineering engagements and
some of the methods we've developed for
going after individuals to get them to
take the action that we want social
engineering them
and so i think that's a good starting
point is so what exactly
is social engineering and
the commonly agreed definition is social
engineering
is any act that convinces someone to
take an
action that may or may not be in their
best interest
and this action that they take um is
going to depend on the type of social
engineering engineering engagement or
uh scenario that you are in if this is
physical social engineering trying to
physically access a facility
um this act that they take might be
allowing me to enter the building it
might be opening the door for someone
who should not be in the building
if this is email social engineering or
phishing
it might be getting them to click on a
link it might be getting them to provide
me their credentials
or it might be i call them up on the
phone
i want to find out a particular piece of
information i want to know what type of
antivirus they're using
and i'll create a scenario where in
they will tell me that the kind of
antivirus they're using without having
their suspicions around
they have taken an action that is not in
their best interest it is not in that
company
or that individual's best interest for
me as an attacker to know what kind of
antibiotics they have
why social engineering why
is that an attack myth that we should be
worried about
as defenders and why is it something we
should be utilizing
as the offensive security defensive side
of thing
and why does it even work and that's
what i want to talk about on this slide
why is social engineering so effective
these states
and if you look at the left we have a
traditional
network environment um we have computers
if we had some cloud instances
we had a vpn that connected us up to our
cloud instances
and we from the user's perspective it
still
appeared to be inside the network now on
the right we look at
what our i.t
environment has morphed into in the last
decade
or more and if you think about
your job or the company you work for and
the applications that are in use
it's not as common for every server to
be housed
at a data center inside the company in
some kind of network closet
server closet server room whatever it is
much more common now that we are using
applications um platform as a service
applications as a service cloud we're
using dropbox office 365
share file by citrix sharepoint
google drive and if you think about
how do you get to each of these
applications now you go to a portal and
you log in
you might be asked for some kind of
verification two-factor authentication
but we go and we log in and
this logging in in my opinion has
conditioned our users so that it's
normal to just go and log in
and that sort of lowers their
awareness of official consent that could
could happen
so according to this statistic um in
2017 this research that was done
70 of workers feel that they are
overworked at their jobs
um they feel like they don't have enough
time in the day
they can't keep up with everything they
need to do they're rushing
trying to get their job done trying to
get everything done they need to so they
can get out the door by five by four by
three whenever time they get off
they don't want to have to take work on
they're trying to hurry hurry hurry
and hurry and rush
quote dulls your senses um it dulls
and causes you to rush through things
and ignore
flags um that if you were
taking the time to be cognizant of what
you're doing
the they are rushing through these and
ignoring them and that as an attacker is
a great thing for me
and again this is 2017. think about
2020.
i've been sure to say 95 percent of
workers are feeling overworked or
stressed out
they're working at home they've got
children running around at the same time
children on laptops or
ipads or whatever learning everyone's at
home
and it adds the stress it adds to the
overwork and we saw
in 2020 the social social engineering
engagements that we conducted
um our success rate was much much higher
than it had been in past years and we
believe that that is a part of the
reason
another factor that contributes to the
effectiveness and the success rate
of social engineering is as humans
we have an innate tendency to want to
trust
the people around us we want to trust
our family we want to trust our
relatives our friends we want to trust
people we want to talk to people
we want to relate to people and we want
to be helpful we want to help people um
we've been taught to have good manners
as children all the way
growing up um talk to have good manners
how to be kind
and it's been ingrained into us to help
people to trust people
according to valley mail in
june of 2019 there were three
billion fake emails being sent a day now
if you think about the numbers of
workers that there are
the number of emails you receive in a
day
three billion fake emails that's a lot
of fake emails
that's three seven so the people in the
world are receiving one
fake email a day um
that's every other day you are receiving
a fake email
that fake email could be spam it could
be a scam some kind of fishing
um but that is something to be aware of
and again on the topic why social
engineering is important to focus on why
it's important to test social
engineering to conduct social
engineering engagements
to test your employees to train your
employees
or as an attacker to conduct social
engineering attacks to include them in
the services that are offered by your
company
three percent of malware and this is
according to know before
three percent of malware seeks to
exploit a strictly technical flaw
ninety-seven percent of malware targets
a user in some capacity in some way
um in that attack life cycle if this is
a ransomware
they will most of the time start with
the fish get credentials so now that
they have final vulnerability they can
send a payload they have credentials
that they can move
laterally inside the organization
so let's look at some cases in which
social engineering has caused data
breaches in organizations
you guys remember in the prior to the
2016 election there was the incident
with john podesta at the dnc
um he received a phishing email
and if you look at the email of course
the format is bad there should be
lots of red flags that should have gone
off there's a bitly address
um that you can see towards the bottom
with a change password
um lots of red flags um the emo the
domain that this is coming from is
google email
and the story is that he sent us to i t
they meant to say this is illegitimate
and they
actually said it's legitimate either way
this should have been a clear
red flag um diapers we see europe coming
from ukraine and we all know the story
what happened i got into his email
that was a pretty important breach all
caused by fishing
um if you remember around 2014 the sony
hack
sony was putting out a movie the north
koreans didn't like
on the north koreans retaliated they
fished
so many people at sony to get vpn
credentials
then they were connected to the network
they deployed a wiper malware that
completely wiped their systems
and did a lot a lot of damage to sony
and it all started with fishing
i'm close to home where i am um not far
away in greenville
south carolina there was a cyber attack
at the water facility
and this started by an employee who
clicked a phishing email
and we all know there's a lot of talk
about
critical infrastructure if you're
familiar with the 16 critical industries
healthcare financial banking
oil gas all of those this is a huge
level of risk
especially in these types of
environments where we have
networks that are connected an employee
on the corporate side can get fish and
that can connect over into robots and
manufacturing and it can be a really big
mess
and on that note the dhs
was i'm discussing a ransomware incident
that hit the us gas pipeline operator a
couple years ago
and operations were halted for two days
at that gas
compression company and think about the
down the chain effects this has
they're unable to compress gas it's
unable to go to the distributors which
is unable to go to the
end users so now individuals are running
out of gas
they might not be able to heat their
homes this can get to be a really big
mess
and it starts with a simple attack like
fishing
okay so moving on to the social
engineering life cycle
and this is the typical process we
follow
um when we are conducting a social
engineering engagement
it begins with information gathering i
want to know as
much about an individual as i can
i want to know their name where they
live what they like the tv shows they
like
the music they like to listen to their
hobbies the things they like to do
on weekends what they like to do after
work to restaurants they like to go to
their pet's name their children's name
everyone in their family's birthdays
their favorite color
if i can get a youtube video of the
person i know what they talk like the
words they use their intonations
i want to know as much about this
individual as i possibly can
and the company i'm going after
then and depending on the scenario
next step is building a relationship and
rapport with the individual
and again this depends on the attack
scenario
if you're fishing how much time you have
this is a
prolonged engagement um
get to know this individual get to like
them um
if this is a physical pendant with a
decent amount of time maybe i'll
bump into them at a restaurant while
they're out for lunch
and they'll like me and then start a
conversation and now i know
from my information gathering i know a
certain
non-profit that they support and i
support that non-profit
and we become friends and then i can
build my relationship and my rapport
with that individual from there
then we move on to exploitation and
exploitation is where i
craft a scenario to social engineering
here
social engineer them remember social
engineering is to get them to take an
action
that is not in their best interest maybe
this individual that i have met at the
burger shop two blocks away from the
office
location where they work maybe i get
into a conversation with them and i
i want to know how many cameras are in
the lobby maybe i
throw in something like yeah i heard you
guys places like fort knox there's 20
cameras just in the lobby
and they say no that's not true there's
only three cameras in the lobby
and boom i have exported them and in
this case execute it
to get that information and that's the
social engineering life cycle that we
follow
so when it comes to social engineering
let's talk about some tips for actually
accomplishing the goal
the mission to attain that piece of
information
you're looking for to get them to take
that action to clip
to log in bypass multi-factor
authentication we've done that in
engagements
how do you accomplish that goal
and so the thing to understand as you
craft social engineering attacks
is people respond basically one of two
ways they either respond logically
they think about it and they respond or
they respond out of emotion
i'm excited i'm angry i'm upset
i'm sad i'm intimidated and i
skip logic and i respond based on an
emotion
and as a social engineering that is
where you can get individuals to do what
you want
that is where you can get them to give
you information click on a link
take an action log into a fake portal
if you can get them to bypass logic
and respond based on emotion
so what are some of the emotions fear
i'm afraid
of something that might happen to me or
i'm afraid of
a circumstance i'm afraid
of authority i'm afraid to lose my job
if i don't do what i've been asked to do
i'm afraid money is being stolen from my
bank account whatever the scenario
happens to be
excitement i'm happy um
i'm gonna get something someone's giving
me something i'm getting a promotion i'm
getting money added to my 401k
i'm gonna get a free iphone excitement
authority someone hire up to the company
is telling me to do something i have to
obey
they are authority depending on the um
scope and what is allowed or not allowed
maybe
um you are some kind of governmental
organization
environmental organization that's going
to do an inspection authority
sympathy um i mentioned earlier about
the
uh um if you find someone that
supports say a non-profit or a certain
foundation
or you find they are sympathetic to a
certain cause
that is something that can be used
against
people maybe they feel a certain way
about
politics if that's in scope for the
engagement a lot of times politics is
out of scope
maybe they are sympathetic for something
that has happened to someone in the news
and they are talking about it on social
media that might be a perfect way to
come in with a social engineering
scenario
ego stroking making someone feel good
we've done use this on multiple
organizations making someone feel
important um there was
penetration tests we did for a pretty
large financial company
now they work with a lot of banks a lot
of back-end transactions
um fishing we were doing a social
engineering gamut to fish their
employees
and we came up with a scenario this
organization had recently been
recognized by a certain
board pre-reputable board in their field
the financial space they've been
recognized
as a leading leading in the industry
so we created a scenario where we faked
like
we were from a certain large media
corporation
newspaper and we had heard about
their recognition their award we went to
the marketing
the head of marketing the vice president
over the marketing department
and we wanted to ask them questions
um about or do an interview and we sent
over the questions and
it was shared quote via office 365
because we know that's what they were
using
and it took them to a fake portal where
they logged in and we got their
credentials
and we were able to even bypass
multi-factor authentication
this person felt important and they
wanted to take these actions because it
made them feel important
at their company
so we talked about building rapport with
an individual
and this is something i'll come back to
a little later
when i'm conducting a social engineering
engagement
there are times when i have to write off
the bats inefficient email
and ask for credentials but i typically
don't
i typically build a rapport with an
individual so
i'm going to build a conversation into
my ask
i try to never especially if i'm doing
if this is part of a penetration test
where i have one shot to get this um
or red team engagement something of that
nature and we're not trying to gauge the
different levels of complexity that
someone falls for
i'm going to be very very careful to
never come up with my ask as
in my first email my first communication
i'm going to build into that um
so i'm
i call up a company i fake like we are x
company
it's the end of the year we're trying to
get rid of five hundred thousand dollars
by the end of the year for tax purposes
we've been buying a certain product you
sell for a long time
let's see what we can work out i'm
talking to the sales department
sales and marketing people are always
easy targets keep that in mind
because their job is to interact with
people the same goes for hr
their job is to open resumes all day and
if you can
um do this right you can make take
advantage of that
so back to the sales i'm going to talk
to them build up a conversation on the
phone we're going to have some email
back and forth
and then at some point where it's
appropriate i'm going to slip in my ask
maybe that's to ask them to download a
certain pdf
that shows the schematics of some
product we're working on
or i'm going to share a certain file
with them and for some reason my email
is blocking it
i can't figure this out i'm not tech
savvy so i'm just going to put on one
drive and share with you and it takes
them to a fake login portal
i'm going to throw that in at some point
after i've already built rapport with
this individual
and they they're not suspicious of me in
the least bit
and i'm also always going to close the
loop and we'll get back to that
in a little bit
one thing that can be very very useful
for crafting social engineering attacks
is the principle of reciprocation and if
you think about it
you've been taught since the day you
were
little your parents taught you someone
does something for you
good manners what do you do you say
thank you someone holds the door you say
thank you someone does something for you
you thank them you help them and
that is a subconscious
um tendency that most of us have someone
does something good for me i want to do
something good for back
they smile at me i want to smile back
and as an attacker i can make a lot of
use of that
um i do something for you you want to
help me
i hold the door open for you
so you want to hold the next door open
for me and that lets me right through
security
and there's many ways that you can take
advantage of this
all right so let's talk about actually
conducting the social engineering attack
and some actual
hands-on practical things you can do
now i talked about building rapport with
the people
that you are targeting and another tip
that i found is only have
one to two things or pieces of
information that you want to gather
during any social engineering
interaction
okay if this is a fish i have one thing
i want them to do
i either want them to tell me something
i want them to
give me um
some information about something i want
them to download
file take an action i want them to log
in one thing i want them to do
maybe i want them to log in and fill out
a form too
keep it at that don't start asking for a
bunch of information or you arouse
suspicions um so for example social
engineering engagement we did recently
it was fishing and
we wanted to we're working with a red
team with our red team
under the engagement and we wanted to
understand what kind of
input protection that we're using on our
system so that we could create a payload
um to connect our command control
infrastructure our server
so what we did i emailed the individual
about a problem with my antivirus
but looked like i was another employee
and i asked them were they
using the same antivirus um
as i was you know i told them the one i
was using i said no
mine is not bad and they i ended up
getting them to right click do the
properties
see the version and actually send me a
screenshot shot of exactly what they had
i had one piece of information i wanted
from this individual
not i'm not gonna also go start asking
them about what other
applications you see in control panel
when you log in do you have to do x y
and z
if i need to know that i'm going to go
to another individual and target them
and this actually can be very useful i
can build my knowledge
and i can ask something that seems
completely benign to you
person a take that information
use it in my question to person b and
because i know that they think it's i'm
legitimate
they give me the next piece of
information i take those two pieces of
information i know now and go to person
c
because i know these two things that
look even more legitimate and they give
me what i need to know and now
i have a complete understanding of
everything i need to know from three
different
people
then for your interaction you have to
think about your targets questions or
objections
another quick story
another fishing scenario i was able to
fish
a vice president of a company um we were
doing a pen test at
got his credentials and i need to bypass
multi-factor authentication
so i called the individual up i planned
out a scenario
to use and so the thing
with thinking about your questions and
this is something i heard when it came
to
espionage and tradecraft i heard someone
talk about
always prepare to never
run off the cuff to never add limb
but always be ready to outlive those are
the two rules of espionage they said
always be so prepared that you you know
everything you're gonna answer
you don't have to ad lib but if you have
to be ready to
and i had planned the scenario so that i
did not really have to do any adding
lips so what i did is i called the
individual up
and i told them i spoofed my phone
number to look like i was coming from
another facility
on the facility where their security
team worked at
i called him i told him that
um we had an issue with an
authentication server single sign-on
server
upgrade had gone south i purposely used
big terminology like single sign-on that
i knew he probably would not know the
meaning of
if things had gone south and people were
being locked out of their accounts
permanently we're having all kinds of
problems trying to get them back
in we see five different accounts
that are getting ready we locked out
next we're trying to
preempt this and i was going to
reauthenticate him so he did not get
locked out
because he had important things to do
that day
i told him i just needed to authenticate
him i was going to send him a code
and i needed him just read me that code
so i could type it in and he should be
good to go it wouldn't take a couple
minutes i had just done it with
another person whose name he knew and
it worked flawlessly for them
the he proceeds to
notice that my spoof number had a little
funny something about it it wasn't
coming from a straight extension
you want to know why my number looked
that way um so i answered them um
i'm not actually on vacation i'm in the
mountains
you know i said i'm on vacation and
because it was so bad i'm having to help
and he said where are you on vacation at
i had planned for this in case i got
that question
i said i'm in the mountains in tennessee
in a cabin i'm remoted on
and i'm trying to help and that's why my
phone number looks funny
ah okay i'm sorry to hear that you're
being pulled out of your vacation to do
this and now he feels bad for me and he
wants to help me get this done so i get
back to my vacation
i completely turned it on and sure
enough we were able to
pull it off get us codes bypass
two-factor authentication we're in the
vice president of the company's account
added our own phone numbers it's all
alternative 2fa and from then on we have
persistent access for the rest of that
engagement
but again the point of that story is
think ahead about
their questions their objections and how
you can overcome those
questions or objections without looking
like you really want that information
casually but also being ready to back
off if you need to
if um i did this on another engagement
um i asked an individual about their
antivirus
they didn't didn't want to answer me i
said look i completely understand
i'm glad you are cautious i'm glad you
don't want to give this information on
the phone that's really good
i'm going to send so and so down they're
going to come to your desk
i'll try to get them there in the next
30 minutes and let them get the
information you can send it to me
that put them at ease and they actually
gave me the information i wanted i
didn't have to
do anything
so what when we start with ocean or open
source intelligence to
have the information that we can use in
our attacks
where do we begin and search engines
number one you can find so much on
google
google is a hacker's goldmine
you can find all kinds of information
from google
so what i want to do is i want to walk
through a few what they're called
google dorks and there are ways to
do special searches within google and i
advise you to actually go look this up
the google door library there are tons
and tons
and there are very complex ones that you
can use you can be
fine put in certain searches that will
give you
certain server operating systems based
on headers and
all kinds of things you can do and so
you should really spend some time
getting familiar with them
i mean looking them up so a simple
putting something in quotes you're going
to search for that exact text if i put
in quotes at whitehouse.gov
i am going to get actual email addresses
if i put in text colon same thing
now it is looking for those email
addresses inside the
text or the body of the page
um maybe i want to look at a specific
website only
i can do site colon and then whatever i
want to search for now i'm only looking
for that
item on that single website
um if i'm trying to find subdomains that
a company might have i might use
something like crt.sh and look at the
certificate history
for subdomains or i might use this first
google door
here where it is sitecoincisco.com
and then the negate sign means not www
so what that effectively does
is i'm looking for anything cisco.com
but not www.cisco.com and i'm going to
get up but all the subdomains of
cisco.com
i might want to look for pdfs that have
been left
documents documented even less
unrealized with
something like confidential in the title
or passwords on that site
um and as i am creating my
social engineering dossier what i
typically do is i find
all the individuals who work for company
that i can
and i research each individual if a
social
engagement is going to last a week i
spend two weeks
prior learning as much as i can about
the individuals i'm going to be
targeting
or the ones who are in scope i want to
know
i'm looking for their email addresses
sensitive or confidential files like
those google docs we're just talking
about
presentation files has someone from
their comp company spoken at a
conference
and given a presentation that maybe that
presentation has information about some
of the technology they're using
events they've been to or are going to
um there's plenty of scenarios i can
create around events
um maybe they're going to an event and
they're excited they've been tweeting
about it or posting on facebook
and maybe they're sponsoring the event
and i can create a scenario where oh we
forgot to have you sign this one
document
can you download this and sign it and
that's a malicious document
any awards or recognitions they received
i talked about the story about how we
use that
their children's names because that's
something they might be using in their
passwords
if i'm going to do a password spray and
i'm gonna create my own dictionary
pets names they're dogs or cats um i
want another background birth places
high school their engagement
um photos their maiden name anything
about their personal lives
that will give me information and i
could
create scenarios around this information
or i can put those
keywords into a script while creating a
password
dictionary to use in either brute force
or
password spring attacks
um the way back to archive time machine
is another good
uh resource you can look on websites who
has worked in the past because you can
go back and look at history things
they've done in the past events have
gone to announcements they made
all kinds of things
google news if i'm looking for in this
case
news about capital one i put in
the company that i'm doing
reconnaissance on or ocean
on open source intelligence gathering
hitting news in google and i can get
recent news about the
announcements they've made
again email addresses are very valuable
and some ways i can get email addresses
are the first the google doc i mentioned
earlier just
simply putting quotes at that domain dot
their domain ending
there's a tool in cali called the
harvester um and the command to run is
simply the harvester dash d
domain i'm in the white house you're
looking i mean the domain you're looking
for in this case it's whitehouse.gov
and it will search and you can also
specify what
search engines to search through i can
specify being google except firefox etc
and it will pull email addresses for
that domain
um if you know
um you found a domain or an email
address and you're
unsure you want to verify it you can use
this linkedin
um that particular address for the
individual
and you can see if that email address is
legitimate or not
if it's only used for their linkedin
account
i always want to know where email is
going
so i'll typically use something like the
mx toolbox or a similar tool
um put in the domain figure out where
their mx records are pointing to so this
company
um their mx records are pointing to
satos so i know they're using a
softbox email security filter if they're
pointing straight to microsoft then
my job is a lot easier because microsoft
doesn't do the best job filtering emails
and this also will give me can give me
some information on what tools i need to
use
if the company is using microsoft office
365 as an email
maybe i'm going to buy a legitimate
domain set up
use office 365 to send that because
office 365 is going to trust office 365
right
unless i do something super fishy or
spammy it's going to go straight to
their inbox and not get caught in spam
filters
if they're using um the g suite
platform google platform with g suite
maybe i will
set up my email using g suite so it will
again be trusted
and go through and straight to their
inbox without being filtered
of course social media you can find all
kinds of information about individuals
on social media
a few examples on this instagram post
all right let's see what i know about
this individual
i can look at the likes and the comments
who's liking this
i can start finding other employees who
work for this i can find their family
members
who their friends are maybe i can go
look at their friends and find some
hobbies they like
things they've done together who their
followers are who they follow
what are the subject matter that they're
following in this
scenario i have in this photo i have
pictures of their family
um who are these cars from what kind of
waters that they like
um now as i go and do some more
reconnaissance and figure out who their
family
are now i can identify these individuals
who's that guy in the background is that
employee do i see him anywhere else
can i figure out what department this is
based off of that um looking out the
window what buildings do i see
what operating system is this individual
using they're all kinds what
applications are open on the computer
all kinds of things i can get
gain about this the dress code this is
casual friday
is this a relaxed company
all kinds of information so look at this
one
i now see all of the programs they're
using all their shortcuts if i can
enhance this a little bit
i know what sports team they like um i
see some of the people following them
who like this
and i can gain a lot of information
about this
i know they like donuts maybe that
becomes a scenario if i'm going to do
physical
penetration testing maybe i wait for
this individual to come
and i have a box of donuts in my hand i
need an open door for me
i'm in this picture it seems like
there's not a lot but there's a lot to
be learned
i know the opera system they're using i
see the kind of phone they're using as a
voice phone so maybe i can create a
scenario where i'm sending
quote a voicemail that they need to open
i see that there's no printer on this
individual's desk so maybe they're using
a shared printer in this office
maybe i can create a phishing email that
is quote you got a scan
from x printer and that might seem
normal to them
now again badges this is great
information for me
i know exactly what the badges look like
um
i if these are rfid maybe i create a
backpack scanner i bump into them
outside i clone their rfid
now i can create a badge that looks
legitimate
again more badges i see the barcode i
see
how they're set up i see employees
there's lots of information to be gained
a couple other places when it comes to
instagram you can use
or social media in general is
igstory.com you can look up individuals
search my bio
pull from different social media
accounts
twitter of course is a great resource
for conducting
ocean learning about an individual
it's a company i can see who the
followers are maybe their employees are
among those followers
let me start figuring out who employees
are who works with who
i can see any recent events they've had
any changes
announcements they may upcoming events
they're going to and like that
scenario i mentioned a few minutes ago
um you're going to this event hey i
forgot to send you this one document i
need you to sign
and there's a payload done document or
something they need to run
um if i'm targeting a building
for physical penetration testing now
it's getting less common for people to
do geo-tagging alert images but it still
does happen
i mean you can use this search on
twitter
let me put in a geocode and
all right so if you go and you find the
coordinates of the building
i can put in the coordinates of that
building and the radius i want to search
and then anything on twitter
that has been um
geotagged within that radius i will get
those
search results those in my search
results those images what that might be
i can start piecing information together
about company
whether people are going around that
company maybe the restaurants are
visiting frequently because
it's within that radius um of course you
can the company you're looking at
uh you can look at the media that's my
company by the way cyborg security
that's our twitter handle
you can look at the media find images um
you can go to tweetbeaver.com
you can download friends followers
conversations they've been a part of
there's lots of information we gather
using social media
linkedin a great resource for osint
i can find employees names i know what
department they worked in
what certifications they have i've used
that in the past against people
certification tests renewals etc
i know their responsibilities what they
do for day to day
some people mention the specific tools
they're using
and now i can find out bosses names
who's whose boss
who's our own departments based on their
titles again some of the solutions and
software that are in use
if their bios are too specific
lots of information you can gain on
linkedin
um and finally another great resource is
communities and forums stack overflow
people are going to these forums they're
asking questions
things like stack overflow spice works
um
these are more on the tech side of
things but there's other forms
for other departments as well finance um
and
so if i'm targeting this company right
here and i've identified a user
maybe by a handle they use i see they
see
the same hand on twitter twitter as they
use on instagram as they use everywhere
else
or if i they use their name straight on
there
or their company name and in this case
as you see i know exactly the version of
software they're using i know they're
using esxi 6.5 they're using pfsense
2.4.4
i see a little bit about what they've
tried their setup
and this is great information for me as
an attacker we found
code basis which we'll get to in a
second github
repositories there might be hard-coded
credentials in
and there might be keywords comments
left in
describing things that are very can be
very useful for me as an attacker
um documents again i mentioned
um the file type and this is from a real
penetration test that we did
um this was a confidential document that
had been put on a website
not realized it was accessible to the
public trying to share it with some
people
and this was available to us and i can
look for powerpoints pdfs documents text
files
excel spreadsheets csvs
um and videos um like
like i mentioned if i'm targeting
someone i'm going to try
to find some videos of them i want to
know the words they use
how they talk and if i'm going to have a
phone conversation with them i'm going
to talk like them
i'm going to use the words they use and
they're going to like me because i am
like them
of course ip addresses you can use
things like showdan
to put in a company's domain find ip
addresses mail servers
related ip addresses
so we understand social engineering
attacks are dangerous
we have a high success rate typically on
our engagements we typically have
between a 40 and a 50
click rate and we typically get
credentials
um for at least 15
and we can typically bypass multi-factor
authentication with ease
and that's over that's our
average over many games sometimes we are
more successful sometimes less
but that's about our average i mean
that's bad
for the companies being targeted that's
bad we know it's
a problem and the reason we're doing
this
is to train them right we're doing this
to help the company improve
we're not bad guys we want to help the
company improve so what can we do
to train employees i want to spend a
couple minutes on this to do better
um sorry
i'm getting a little bit of myself um so
i want to show you a couple of fake
portals um this is one thing we've done
engagements
um it's been very successful
um and in this case
we'll buy a legitimate domain set up a
real website
maybe we're using something like
wordpress or some other template we can
put together real fast
um this is for email
phishing um for a fake 401 website
um and this is the real 401k
website um and this is our fake portal
that we can set up as you can see
they're pretty similar most people would
fall for it
this is a state office 365 portal we set
up
a fake linkedin portal fake owa portal
i mean again they look very legitimate
to a user we always have
https certificates
so they look even more legitimate
they're not getting much warnings
maybe i'm trying to get them installed
some kind of software an app a malicious
document is a good attack method
um and this is an example of an
engagement we did someone
tweeted about the test they had failed
the oscp defensive security certified
professional exam
and so we bought a domain very similar
to the real
domain we sent them an email saying hey
we realize that everyone who took the
test on certain days
um we gave them the wrong
testing environment we're really sorry i
want to give you the opportunity to
retake the test for free
please fill out these questions so we
can get the ball rolling um
and this was actually a security analyst
at this company they downloaded the form
which was payloaded gave us the command
shell
so now on to what i was getting ready to
get to how do we change this how do we
improve
and security awareness training is
important
but i also like to recommend what i call
an ocean self-assessment
take a few minutes and encourage the
employees that you're either testing or
at your company to do this as well
encourage them to take a few minutes
and go look at their web life
their web presence go look at social
media what kinds of things are known
about me
look at the pictures of you what can be
inferred about you from those pictures
what do people know about you before you
post something
do an assessment what is the information
this photo in this
tweet and this message i'm about to post
what is it because that is now public
about me
and now i'm going to be cognizant if
that information is
an attacker trying to target me i know
hey
that's public information you're using
that against me
next never trust always verify
you always teach employees to always
verify if there's a question
about something if they have a hesitance
ask
don't be afraid create an environment
where people are encouraged to verify
they're encouraged not to take action
swiftly
and do that verification out of ban so
if someone sends me an email i'm not
sure about i'm going to call them up on
the phone
i'm not going to use the phone number in
the signature i'm going to go to their
website
go to my contact list the phone number i
know for them
if they call me up and i start asking
questions and say hey
i know you have a job to do i want to
verify i'm going to send you an email
to your email address and just reply
back to that i know you're legitimate
um don't change to some email just they
tell you
do the one you know for them and verify
it
do some kind of alternate method than
what they are communicating with you on
um and as an attacker that's the worst
thing i can hear i'm going to send you
an email because i know i'm not going to
get it
um and the final tip i have is teach
individuals this if an email
a exchange interaction causes any
kind of emotion be that fear excitement
anxiety pressure again from authority
compassion pride happiness
any kind of emotion stop
stop reading that email don't take any
action
go do something else for five minutes
and come back and read it again
when you're thinking clearly and you're
out of that emotion
because it's likely not to be real and
you're going to be in a better state of
mind
if you have to ask a for one a co-worker
what do you think about this and if you
do this you're going to stop
your employees the people you're
training to stop
so many such a high percentage of
attacks
if you're looking for some resources to
learn even more about
some open source intelligence and this
is a great book
open source intelligent techniques by
michael bazelle
you can pick it up on amazon i think
it's between 30 and 40 dollars
not terrible but there's like tons and
tons of tools in there
that he goes through one by one on how
to use them how to
conduct those ten investigations
and finally um here is a qr code that
you can scan if you trust me
it'll give you the slides for this
presentation if you're interested in
them