on the server wants Morsi
something learn something you also how
any person yes something day
you want to know who you are world
somebody else they
now working at different degrees a
their also multinational I'll alright
her eyes ensemble lost he lives lol
worries he how II so I walked two
organizations
every single person i were with Milos
Orleans page last house and then there
are the is there a higher orders
to sell actualization I'll
grace learning and its
you when you can get a little ol
where you're contributing for you you're
learning and change
you know what we know plus call home
I'll
sure he will grow for me need to
understand with me
live your work salary job every yes so
how's
real us probably more like they were us
well as a regional organization with for
the
I how 1.2 million dollar
point salish there or about 300 was just
a little
we must or anti-virus for voluntary mark
is going to 1.2 million dollar place
we marched down to me
score already pay novel
long haha well we know how free her
miscellaneous dollar they're much older
they were all at once
me not all these other features in a
little
wall anymore him how does change now
yes never been here we mention
here all
Wow castle share her hasher's score on
somebody's
around yes me wanna hold sale
be worth a lot of right haha I
will try to close a budget this year the
levels only about an hour and I'll
the irony
all I he has your group I'll reminder
I think we can just about cleaned out
wanna
CEO's the local hospital sales
purity same home okay whatever it is
are you the polar Shah
working lol she's hi right here 1.2
million all
never watched national security does
on does stories I golfer little
rose this little I love you
my he wells her security Press
allocate Charlotte well
just I'll be no change and
I current good but it was a little
chilly
with rosa business me all
me overall
you world hello I Would of ISO 400
a lot of people say or they're all here
at race for you
taxes be home in Division
they had to go and investigate
Weiss numbers or reagan world-class not
meow
down and just because someone didn't
know how to write a program for a while
the security department way and we will
now program only rival
their numbers are all together with it
securing
R Us responsibility to remind program a
here
you know what this you get off security
last three
rainforest we're going to help them out
this
that India that organization
this CA six years later speech
and mostly how all reorganization shot
anyway whom side with now
a bill he will actually happen
don't you for you shop want me grounds
collaboration resolved
out rather house crawl
it looking
out there'll all
so willing to bring to bear on my
critics were answered
architecture training run building are
to
years ago two million solutions
any crawl you have a heart attack design
post office
believe for solutions you ask 3r
tax you design for us all
each one solution there are
million solutions any all East
million are harassed do not assume there
was a single solution
all that all he's I'll
in the heart Hills
it go way beyond your imagination wait
long
greeted all football other members
38 over overlooked Albany the business
units that are going on here
back to Las lol tell lori's
now about your YouTube Google+ gmail
we're all here all
be well get back organization obliterate
weathers users on the exact same day a
older ball bro every control
resiliency the have to do with the
company
do I want to give me while being weird
evening back to those users for what
taking away
I had here company or something i mean
hijacked it because they don't household
you that many
worked all in a while we're going
business way you actually are bad
arrange well do show me how you doing
thing is
post act about me with another solution
that does the same thing
not better does
collateral luv your team last year and
he shall
and learning lol who love
lower-level all I his will be here
knows how to level as I have knows
sheen airline for learning something new
is this line some while who is believed
so I was Frank they don't take it
personal
dole personal it's a Valentines ni
you you still
for that creative lolol you first all
those years
Selena your evolution
you now me tomorrow lot higher
so you really wanna still CSL
or was it a little now
Julie Howle
I lost all our world CEO all over I
don't know
call me the we'll me know
Chris you all organization a halal
Caldwell ask questions I'll
your wall we did that a little while
think right away they call the security
team my soul
no telling when a met with this is a
business
through they were doing I was a little
you know the group told us that we have
to bring you guys here
stopper you realize there were no
information security issue really the
world cause
going to forestall was a little too hard
3/2 were almost here well as
other information that outburst all
about bringing
in I can try the world release all
we were thinking hear her gracious
during this certainly work you're right
K great thing about this
400 they want well to this day
that security i still get on all and all
weird he's the
I really need to be part of this every
small
budget say okay 0
cleanup had a great time for our
business
it article and his Prost
what happened that CEO
in the world all says fly with us
extract human
he player organization hello
understand Chris you've been reading a
lot of fallows
hunie well me
problem you I was like
world's all children good
create are almost
or employers room Luna participation
numerous
Nash organization lol allow
irri's manage elite final
don't triangular
percent your it's never gonna happen
factor
a were people iris securities
Hall there are yea
were rumors you know earlier Sunday all
organization his guitar percent one area
and
a holes all show how a lot of
Asia make my god it was all call
the BIRR care about your they don't want
to see me in my office
say there's a larger fire great where is
it in his pocket
it a little
poverty well for dinner get
number 12 be integrated realization once
yeah things first I be willing to let go
world-class on we teams
haha to think about the dollar menu is
you
with you'll learn from you
here I every
souls Salisbury I of
right there were a lot of homework is
thank you
or so much about ourselves when they
won't let about us
any actually final
a change when they were levels great 80
with someone all you have a conversation
with a lower right overall
okay in honors am they will learn about
on sorry my new role
all while position was
all believed reynamo you organization
the
community over dole hi
people or not I you going out there
not you I yes separate to feel normal
how unit was branded 11 cost you have a
whole
Apple homes lot of people were with him
you don't build it not have and
collaborate Paul
3 actual operation all calls
are much more
beauty industries are are publishing
0 probably an awesome overall over
exactly all information you have he
bad at all do not hesitate
pretty track for me
doesn't matter I'm old by thank you
my whole I
call
little
i won