welcome back everyone our next speaker
is andrew lemon
and the title of his presentation is bne
from a to z i'm looking forward to his
presentation
so without any further ado i'll pass it
to andrew
hi welcome to my presentation i'm andrew
lemon
and this is b and e from a to z a guide
to physical pen testing
where we're going to go over the last
year of physical pen testing my company
did
and talk about how we got into your data
centers even during a pandemic
so i originally started this talk
thinking of just be 25 minutes
turns out i didn't realize how much
information wasn't in the wild
so instead i'll cover the techniques the
tools i've used some of the breakdown
anatomy of doors
and what's made me successful in
engagements
so who am i i'm the principal security
engineer for a company called alias
i've got 10 years of professional pent
testing experience
20 years of unprofessional unpaid
fantastic experience
i'm the lead engineer for pen testing
and incident response
as well as the other engineers
so what is physical pen testing
companies spend millions of dollars on
cyber security but forget about physical
security
what i spend time finding a zero day
when i can just walk in
and get the proprietary data or
intellectual property office system
i feel like this comment kind of sums it
up so
this multi-million dollar computer to
crack a password i'm like no just
hit this guy with this five dollar
wrench until he tells us the password
so most people say it can't be that easy
is literally that easy
planning portion so you've got your
recon creating an alias
and then pre-texting for that alias and
if you guys ever watch the a-team
believe that's hannibal loves it when a
plan comes together
so the recon phase ocean's a super
important tool
so use the company's social media to
determine the culture are they jeans
culture are they suit and tie
use a site like dns dumpster so you can
learn what isps the company use
in the event that you're going to come
in as an isp tech you want to
collect as many pictures as much info as
possible
so use google maps and street view to
get an outside view without getting
burned
walk sister buildings determine the
layout you should know the names in the
face of the players who the secretary is
the cio
the important people know your ingress
and egress points
most importantly know where your
bathrooms are the first thing you want
to do when you get into a building
just head to the bathroom take a chance
to calm down
recollect yourself get comfortable and
then go back
you can always use the bathroom as your
safety net because no one's going to
stop and ask you
why are you in the bathroom
so you should have a plan a plan b and
plan c so i'm going to go on this
door and if that doesn't work i'm going
to this door
it doesn't remove this door same thing
with buildings this is my primary target
my secondary target
but don't be married to a plan don't get
so caught up in the planning phase and
knowing all the names and everything
that
you psych yourself out and you can't do
your job and you just panic and
run away so you should be efficient with
all of your tools if you plan on using
your gate tool and you find door to
launches suck
pivot over your under dwarf tool or
figure out what's going to work when
you're on site
it may be all social engineering
so creating an alias who are you so on
the left hand side here
i'm going to go ahead and critique
myself a little bit this is for a
chemical plant
so what's wrong with the image if we
start top to bottom
look at my shiny new yellow helmet so
you can see that any professional that
works in the industry
uses a white helmet glasses are brand
new
i'm wearing the proper fire resistant
clothing but why am i wearing a collared
shirt underneath
while this engagement was still
successful it's important to go back and
critique yourself and
understand the industry that
so here's a better example of where i
identified the av
vendor i created a badge i've got a cell
phone number that actually redirects to
one of my teammates
i have a fake email address not a
lanyard everything's above board
and really sold it if you think of
a university i consider well i don't
have all my pen testing tools on me when
i'm breaking into a university
but a backpack's not really out of place
and that's something that i had to think
about
so put it uh hit your local thrift shop
one closest to the place you're working
they're gonna have your company shirts
you can also get them off ebay and
amazon
but thrift store is great like if you
want to have legitimacy to a disguise
like
who's going to have a shirt that says my
company name barbecue
2019 probably only an employee and if
you know their t-shirts and jean culture
you're going on a friday by all means
use that to sell it
pre-texting so who are you why are you
there who you seeing
who authorized you and what's your story
so you want to create a story
if you're going the whole social
engineering route who are you there to
see
make sure you know the names and the
faces so you don't want to tell them
that you're there to see the cio
and it turns out you're face-to-face the
cio and he didn't authorize you
you don't want your lies to fall apart
in flight
so if you're an rfid tech isp tech hvac
building maintenance just make sure you
know what you're doing so if you say
you're a senior software developer you
should be able to sell that
and so here's an example of where i am
an av
technician so blanked out the customer
information
but what am i here to do i'm checking
all the access control systems including
the rfid
and inspecting premises for proper door
fitment
so initially they tried to reach out to
the contact and approve my work order
and we got her information her signature
from a phishing email
they were validating they're trying to
call her so i said hey while you guys
are reaching out to her i'm just going
to go ahead and do the outside
so if you see a weird guy walking around
trying to open doors and unlock them and
whatnot
that's just me just a heads up so i was
completely able to walk around the
building have no interactions with
anyone
outside because i had pre-texted and
told them this is what i'm going to be
doing
you can take really obscure and strange
behaviors and normalize them
just by pre-texting
so the tool is the trade it's not all
locked
there's lots of phone apps lots of
physical tools
i always tell the other engineers think
more dumber
as engineers we tend to over complicate
problems we want to show off an awesome
tool that
maybe only a locksmith has access to but
i think it's way better to show like i
opened this door with a fly swatter i
found the receptionist desk
it's good to show high impact attacks
but for the most part you want your
attacks to fall in that 90
and not that top 10 percent of not
feasible
looking at the tools here you've got a
push tool the gate tool which is one of
my favorites
and if you don't have the gate tool on a
pinch you can use a contractor square
the under door tool this is a thumb turn
tool or the california tool we'll talk
about that later
the double door tool exploits gap and
double doors
we'll talk about the airbags later and
how they can be used to manipulate door
fitment
and then a boroscope
talk about my edc from the top we've got
the
covert companion from covert instruments
this has your traveler hooks your
jigglers
come picks some some rakes and then some
word
uh word picks that's always in my bag
also from code instruments is this bag
of openings so these are your five most
common keys you're going to see
and i've added a couple you've got your
door king your linear keys
ch751 126a
your ford fleet key i never got to use
it but i'm keeping on my key ring and
holding on hope
for rfid cloning don't over complicate
it get the keys
you don't need to build a hot pad you
can but
you can get your hands on a badge try
this first always work easy and then
work your way up to more complicated
attacks
this is the tuxedo from sparrows that
have included some chrome picks here
you have your nfc tags so at the height
of the pandemic
we found that people started using qr
codes and with apps on our phone we
could program these nfc tags
stick them behind the qr code and then
color out the qr code so it doesn't work
and create an easy fishing site
you have the shark jack so when we
actually need to show
impact actually physically gotten in
this is a shark jack from hack five
so once again i throw an army mode plug
in leave it run for 10 minutes
grab a hash walk out and leave the
sparrows quick gym
this is just for loiting doors and
honestly i went with this because i was
tired of cutting up my hands
so i just needed a convenient little
package i could throw it in
you can cut out a milk carton cd any
hard plastic blister pack
can do everything you need
[Music]
so phone apps you've got the hd wi-fi
that's for the borescope
keep that the burner and spoof card app
so the burner app will let you create
phone numbers
and you can create burner phone lines
and then the spoof card app will
actually
spoof phone numbers text messages and
caller id
so on an engagement with a data center
where you had to have pre-authorization
the night before i called ahead using
the name and the phone number of the
client
i was able to put myself on the list as
an auditor and as an auditor that means
we're gonna roll out the red carpet
we're gonna
unlock everything for you uh the company
was completely unaware that
we were actually doing a physical
security audit and that i wasn't who i
said i was they took me at face value
and didn't do any validation
[Music]
the nfc tools that's what we use to
program those nfc
tags wi-fi sweet spots
most of us will fall back on our career
at iit so if you need a reason to wander
around
like an idiot have that up the app it'll
show you wi-fi signal and you can walk
around and stare at the ceiling looking
at wireless access points
usually no one's going to stop the it
guy
instacode this is a an app for locksmith
i
just recently in the last year started
using this i didn't realize the value of
it until i actually
dug in and started playing with it
so cloning keys and here's the spoof
card for playing numbers
so here's the instacart app uh you can
actually use this to clone a key
this will give you the you know the
manufacturer and series
you get all the cutting depths
so here's a really fun practice of
cloning key
so you use what you have available
instead of
studying a key or trying to cast one in
lead
instead just color with a sharpie throw
some tape on it
and put it on a business card if it's a
dumb wafer lock it's
pretty apparent it's going to work
clearly that never work right
unfortunately it did
so another chemical plant this poor lock
box that we have here contains
all the keys of the facility so it's
nasa apple and cement co-locks
uh this is by the receptionist desk
though so after we hit the request
exit sensor with compressed air where
we'll get access to the lobby
we didn't have a physical key but if you
zoom in on the actual lock body
it says jc 31 so
uh google search lets me know well jc31
is a default key
i plug that into instacode and google i
can get the key profile
use calipers and who has the lunch i was
able to
throw double sided tape on a business
card cut out the card
come back and unlock it well i showed
the customer that the key was readily
available online
i just got to take it a step further and
take that from
a kind of lame attack to elite attack
airbags so this one was a happy little
accident
i was attempting to use airbags to
create space to actually hit this
requested exit sensor with my under door
tool
that says request exit button my under
door tool uh so imagine my surprise and
the door just
popped open and the magnet holding open
wasn't
strong enough for the
for the door so surely that worked once
but
there's no way that would happen twice
right
so once we got inside i found the data
center we couldn't go over or under
and it was rfid locked so i figured i
would cram the airbags in
so i'm going to get them as close to the
lock as possible you can see there's no
latch on this door so it's got to be
hard if i need control
so if i pause here for a minute this is
actually your most important tool
your get out of jail free card is what's
going to keep you from knowing the
handcuffs
so make sure that that's always on you i
keep my back right pocket with the
signature
ready to be pulled out and ready to be
easily shown
but back to the video we air up the bags
and originally you can hear us laughing
and you can hear the door creaking a
little bit
there's no real damage that i found from
this so no more further issues
last bit is push your foot along the
bottom and you're inside
so rfid cloning got access to a badge
use the key so here's an example of a
badge that well it doesn't work
but just like that using the keys
all right 35 millimeter film so there's
a term in lock picking called
loiting as from the days of using
celluloid to open doors to celluloid
film
so here's 35 millimeter film this one's
purposely bent
but you can also use it to go over the
door
i'll show you guys an example of that
so come through too much gap in this
door
down grab the latch
pull it and it's open
found keys so why try to exploit a door
when you can literally just take the
keys
keys are in common places they're
normally labeled if not
you can kind of take a guess of what
they might be to but always look out for
keys
lock picking so this never works on
engagements
never ever pick a lock on engagement
unless it's your absolute last
choice
blocks are going to be difficult to
begin with you're looking at acid
abloy's
best medcos even a master key system
while the wafers will make it easier
you're still not going to have great
luck and the added adrenaline and
pressure it's going to make it difficult
so unless you're regularly practicing
your craft
i don't recommend trying all the human
engagements
so that being said sometimes lockpicking
is your only choice
so this is the deadbolted door the
magnetic strike isn't in place
but we can pick the lock
so after a little bit of work and a
little bit of finessing we're able to
break in that way
but again always the last choice
so field tools if you're playing the
part
of an rfid tech well have a clipboard
but you can see the tools that i have uh
doing pre-recon ahead of time
i knew that there were some doors that i
could use my j tool on
have a screwdriver to look for the part
as well as this film this is good for
loading as well as pretending to check
the gap in rfid sensors
uh gate bypass tool just looks cheap but
it could also be a ruler
but use the information you learned in
the recon phase to create a proper
persona
as well as having those tools on you
the gate tool for latch slipping gate
tool is going to be by far my favorite
tool
and then the wallet size pocket version
is the sparrows hall pass
when you have our uh when you have
electronic strikes
on doors these will almost always get
you in
and there are very few instances that
i've had where the gate tool
didn't do everything i needed
so you come to the door
slip this behind the latch
and grab the latch there so the door's
not open there
okay so let's talk about exploiting
doors
these are the doors that you're going to
see in corporate environments
either a double door or a single door
and the door is either
mounted on this side of the frame or the
other side of the frame
but let's break down the anatomy of the
door if you think about the door
like you would as a pen tester they're
really like four sides
you've got top bottom hinge and latch
so the hinges they can be if they're
exposed like they are on this
image the pens can be knocked out the
door can be walked away from the frame
if there are security pins i'm never
going to walk the door away from the
frame or knockout
hinge pins on an engagement i just
haven't run into an issue where
that was going to be the resolution so
from the bottom and under your door tool
i vastly underestimated this tool
early on in my career i made heavily on
the gate tool
and so i found in a lot of corporate
environments there is a gigantic gap
under the door
and fire code requires these leather
locks
so i could reach underneath the under
door tool and pop every door in a
facility
with ease extremely fast
so from the top there's an over door
attack where you use
film to push through the gap these
frames make it a little harder
but you can also think of going over the
top of the wall
and pushing up the ceiling tiles and
then attacking the film
carry 12 to 15 feet of film it's super
cheap
the last side is going to be your most
common attack surface
you're going to be exploiting the lock
up between the latch and the frame
so if the latch is visible use a push
tool
if the latch is shielded use a gate if
the door is properly hung
and the dead latch is engaged preventing
the latch from actually moving
then use airbags we're gonna use airbags
to exploit the gap
indoors and then consider alternate
routes so
drop ceilings raised floors so can you
go over the door
or under the door what's easier
attacking impossible doors so let's say
that you have a
well-hung door and a facility and
there's no real way around it
right we can't see the latch so we can't
attack it
i'm not seeing rfid on this side can't
go under the door or over the door
this is where your specialty tools are
going to come in so latch needles
these will actually be used to slip into
this gap and then push the striker on
the door
and the last spatula is actually slid in
from the bottom
to latch slip
and this is an instance of using a
specialized tool to exploit a known
weakness
so how will we attack this door right
off the bat
look up here at the top there's a
carriage bolt that's holding a magnetic
plate in that's holding the door closed
but on this side there's nothing so this
is where we use the j tool
to actually come in the thumb turn and
unlock this door
okay so how do we attack this on the
left
you can see the latch is exposed it
doesn't look well
hung you could do an under door tool but
let's ignore that
but that's also an option the hinges are
also exposed
which could be knocked out and walked
away and it's a glass door
if anything it could just be broken
so this second door is a little more
well secured still a glass door still
easy to go through
can't go out with hinges under door tool
of course
you definitely don't want to pick two
locks so this is where your
latch needles or your spatula will come
into play
so how do we attack this door you can
try to brute force
the combination you look for known
weaknesses in that combination style
walk
the hinges are exposed the latch is
exposed but
let's say that you're just trying to
show impact the customer and you've
already latch flipped and
worked on hinges and exploited these
locks well what's this
the customer used to have a deadbolt on
this lock and they just replaced it with
this jeep screw in
so a little bit of pressure while
pulling that out you can actually
unscrew that
and create a gap big enough to slip film
through and then
grab the latch in the backing side
but when in doubt just go around
this is where that pre-planning comes in
handy where recon comes in handy
and we're just looking for alternate
routes to help look for fire maps
look for building maps a lot of security
areas have attached bathrooms because
they don't want to create another set
so you can walk straight into the
bathroom and then out into a secure area
and so one of the great examples of this
from our team was a bank assessment we
were working on
they had biometric thumbprint locks
there was no way we're getting a secure
area
but we walked into their overflow
activity space that they bought
and there's a kitchen and in the kitchen
there's a pantry so i open the door to
the pantry and i find
this door which is the door to their
store room and right over here directly
connected to that store room with an
unlocked door is their secure
area so instead of trying to bypass
super complicated locks or knobs or
thumb print
i was able just to walk around and no
suspicion because i was in a low traffic
area versus trying to use an underdoor
tool
in an area that was well trafficked
so access control
what you're most commonly going to see
going to be your magnetic locks
and your electronic strikes
so you can see your protection here see
a hidden reader
and you see an unshielded contact
so a firefighter if you're allowed to do
destructive entry
just punches these out with halogens
hole and the door comes right off
but we've got to be a little better than
that so we couldn't really use a lash
spool here
because this is likely a dead bolt so
that's going to be a picking attack
this could be last flipped but health is
a dead bull box
and then here's an rfid reader that's
just left out on the outside of the
[Music]
building
so access control attacks we're looking
at the
locking mechanism of the mechanism
keeping the door closed attacking the
reader
the request to exit sensors and buttons
and the controllers
so the first part is going to be the
lock whether it be a magnetic an
electronic block
then we'll have our readers and then our
request to exit so this is going to be a
button
or a sensor that detects heat or motion
these are the clicks you hear when you
walk past an electric door
and you have your controller at the top
so your magnetic locks and your electric
door strikes so you can identify these
by carriage bolts on the latch side
if they're screwed into the door that's
a different story but most commonly
you're going to see this especially on
exterior doors or solid corridors
if you have access to a space prior so
if you're doing some
social engineering ahead of time if
you're able to access the lobby
then a paper clip and a piece of gaff
tape right here
as you're walking out slap that to the
lock that will significantly reduce the
hold force
a lot of these are weak as just as they
are
so an average person can just row that
door open but
throwing a paper clip in there and
increasing the distance between the iron
plate and the magnet
significantly weakens the system
so an electronic latch is the other kind
of holding mechanism you're going to see
these have all the same common
vulnerabilities you would see
in say a regular latch and a regular
door however they also have some
additional
vulnerabilities so because people are
lazy in their installs
they'll use the biggest latch that they
can
and the door will be improperly hung
making slipping electronic latches
super easy
your rfid readers so you've got
the only real way to attack an rfid
reader
is with an esp key so from red team
tools
this is a postage stamp size tool spins
up a wireless interface
and can store up to 80 000 credentials
in memory
so the tamper switch behind a hit
carburetor
is rarely hooked up so you can walk in
punch one of these down
and then the credentials can be replayed
later from the web interface
so don't really bother cloning a card i
mean you can use a
you can use the prox mark or
try to replay the credentials and get in
that door but really just
on the daily engagement take that off so
we prior you installed it on the daily
engagement
take it off the primary door go to the
door that you're trying to get into like
say a server room or a secure area
punch it down and just replay
credentials
save yourself the time of the complexity
of trying to clone a card
so request to exit so request
exit sensors or button are used to allow
you to exit the control area without
badging out
uh these sensors like this hall effect
sensor here can be triggered with a
balloon
air duster smoke vape pen
any number of things a flash water
request
exit buttons have type requirements
related to fire code
so your request exit button has to be
within a certain height
and this distance to the door and be
open for this time
so a little wire taped here on your door
tool and your borescope
can be used to actually hit that and
open the door
request exit sensors depending on their
severity are also constantly being
triggered
so you'll hear them click as people go
by you can also watch a lot of the hit
readers you'll see them go from red to
green
for no reason so if you watch that
you're staying in a hallway
you have that go red to green and then
grab the door open it and then badge
just for effect
because your badge is going to make a
sound regardless
that's also another good tip for when
you're tailgating so even if you're
tailgating behind someone
say you were in the smoker's pit you
followed them along
you can badge in with any badge it's
still going to be
and most people aren't going to check to
make sure the reader actually read
anything
the door controllers uh rtfm right
so door control systems are often
unprotected with default credits
uh you can pivot the controller from the
network
and then just read the manual so how do
we connect the controller well here's
the default id address
that could change but admin admin is the
login
once we get to the login click the
dashboard button this tells you
exactly how to exploit the system so
pick your door say
i t closet hit m unlock it'll unlock
temporarily
or hit em up and it's going to stay
unlocked
and then our last option is if you have
access to the door control system let's
say you have an engineer in another area
say you've popped the security room
but you need access to a server room if
you can locate the door
you can jump for the contacts so if it
is a
normally closed jumper across if it is
normally open just pull a wire but
understand
how your systems work make sure that
you're not breaking your own systems
last little bit of advice is going to be
around cameras
you're going to see cameras everywhere
but it's important to think about
if you count 30 cameras you probably
still only have two sets of eyes on them
don't let a camera discourage you from
doing the work you plan on doing
uh there have been a number of times
where i've used another door tool
right underneath the camera i've walked
around for hours on end with
nothing at all uh no response no
interactions or anything
just confidently walking through
anywhere is going to be your best bet
a lot of times i won't pretext i'll just
walk in as i am as a person
just to show the different levels we'll
have a high quality social engineering
attack with paperwork
we'll have a low effort with just a
costume and then we'll have a no effort
which is
a stranger walks in off the street
well that's everything i could think of
so if you have any questions please send
them in the chat