hey everybody and uh welcome back wow
what an amazing event a great turnout
some really great speakers and trainers
appreciate all of you
uh attending and appreciate all the
speakers and
uh for their presentations so i'm gonna
let uh danielle and savannah take over
go ahead
uh thank you for everyone for coming
really enjoyed everyone attending mayhem
over the weekend and make sure if you
missed anything it's going to be on our
youtube channel
so make sure to check that out if you
did have anything you want to go back to
and i'm going to go ahead and pass it
over danny
and in addition to all the videos being
available we also
encourage you to hop on our discord
we're available 365 days a year to keep
that conversation going hit us with
with questions or topics you want to see
in the future
you can interact with us and we've got a
whole community there that that's
waiting for you to participate yeah
absolutely
like danielle mentioned we are on on
discord all the time
people ask me why i'm responding at
three o'clock in the morning it's
sometimes i'm there at three o'clock in
the morning so
please join us and uh thanks everybody
and we'll see you at the next event