welcome back everyone our next speakers
are jorge cheeses and tim schultz
they're going to be talking about purple
team maturity models
so it looks like a really interesting
presentation so without any further ado
i'll pass it to jorge and tim welcome
hello
red team village and mayhem
2021 my name is george ortiz
and i am tim schultz and we are so happy
to be
here for the second mayhem uh
we presented on the first one about
adversary emulation and purple teaming
and now we're coming to you with the
purple team maturity model
see over the last year we've really been
telling people about purple teaming and
collaboration and the reasons you should
do adversary emulation
how to do it and we've gotten such great
feedback a lot of organizations
are seeing the value of doing purple
teaming and have started doing it
in purple team exercises but what we get
a lot of
is okay what do we do now
and the benefit of working at a
company that sells to customers
and clients enterprise level but also
does some professional services is we
get to see the entire spectrum
and speak with all of these amazing
people
of course give back to the community so
that's what we're here we're gonna share
what we've seen in the last year and
hopefully give you some
actionable uh things that you can do
today when you get back to work or not
today because today's saturday
on monday when you get back to work so a
little bit about myself
i'm george ortiz i'm the chief
technology officer
here at site um if you haven't heard of
us we love
coming to conferences speaking giving
back to the community
doing workshops and things like that we
also have these
lovable unicorns that you're going to
see throughout the presentation
as we have different uh actors uh that
we're going to portray
i've also written the purple team
exercise framework which we're going to
talk about here in a bit
the c2 matrix co-created that with
bryson bohr
the ceo of scythe and uh
founder of grim and ics village and adam
machinshe
who's running the open source projects
over at red canary so things like
atomic red team right um before that was
10 years at citigroup running the
offensive security team
i also teach for sans and have a sans
uh red team course uh back in the day i
wrote a book on an operating system you
should not be using because it's end of
life
uh but still i like to put it because at
the end i wrote a book you know
was a lot of work would never do it
again do not recommend uh
anyway over to tim tell us a little bit
about yourself
so uh i'm tim schultz i am the adversary
emulation lead
here at scythe uh and prior to
scythe i've worked at uh mostly uh what
we call ffrdc's are federally funded
research and development centers
and so while not as many people have
heard of like sandia national labs of
course people have heard
of mitre miter attack team the miter
attack evaluations
effort so i was lucky enough to be able
to work
with the teams uh while i was at miter
uh doing that
so i've got about probably a decade of
experience in this space about
six years in adversary emulation and
sort of red teaming
so uh yeah super excited to share with
you
as george mentioned what what we've been
working on
i was super excited to hire tim so we
gave him the coolest title
ever adversary emulation lead i love it
um actually met tim uh at the first
purple team summit so shows you the
importance of networking and
talking to folks i know we're still
virtual but definitely
talk to us uh we're we're very open uh
always happy to help and and give
feedback so uh
do ask questions as we go uh the benefit
of having two speakers
is that we can see the questions and
answer them sometimes even live
so what are we talking about today well
this is totally tim's slide because
he's very methodical he likes answering
the why
the what and the how so the why is why
does purple team need a maturity model
that's going to be our first item i'm
going to talk a little bit about that
now i'm going to turn it over to tim to
talk about the what
what is the maturity model and then of
course we want an
actual practical way of using it with
examples because
this is red team village and we know you
love examples and actual use cases
so we will cover the how so to get
started
the why why does purple team
need a maturity model well i said
earlier right
we've kind of figured out that it makes
sense to
collaborate with other teams
right and we learned this the hard way
back when i was at city group
we had our blue team right our security
operations center
there you see the blue unicorns again i
told you you're gonna see these
throughout the
uh presentation um and they're in charge
of defending right
then we had our red team our offensive
team our offensive team
was in charge of at first finding
vulnerabilities and technology
then doing things like social
engineering then we got to a point where
we were testing response processes
but we did all this from a stealth
perspective the blue team didn't know we
were doing this
because we wanted to realistically test
them right
and all of that brings value so don't
think that what we're presenting here
today means
don't do vulnerability assessment and
don't do reddit tv no that's not what
we're saying
then many organizations also have
brought in
cyber threat intelligence and cyber
through intelligence
has evolved as well from providing just
indicators of compromise to the blue
team
to also providing things for the red
such as tactics techniques and
procedures
we want to know what threat actors are
out there which ones are likely to
attack
us and then get those behaviors so that
we can emulate them in our red team
exercises
so this is the infosec team of today and
you might have all of these internal you
might have some of these that
you pay outside right uh vendors either
a red team that comes in you might have
managed security services
or managed detection response or even a
vendor cyber threat intel team and
that's okay right this talk
will apply for uh for all three of these
so
how did we get started well we got
started by saying
look don't just do
blue team cti and red in silos
let's collaborate right for the longest
time and probably in the last year and a
half or even
since that first purple team summit
where i gave the first talk on running a
purple team exercise
we said that purple team is a virtual
team right
where you the following teams are going
to work together and they're going to
collaborate right
those three unicorns i showed earlier
right the cyber threat intelligence team
does the research learns about a
adversary that's likely to attack you
they
look up those ttps those behaviors
tactics techniques and procedures
and they provide them to the red and the
blue t
the red team then looks through that
creates a
plan and emulates
those adversary behaviors while the blue
team
who are the defenders right the security
operations center hunting
defer or managed services all work
together
and we published this research
into what is called the purple team
exercise framework it's free you can
download it right now
and it should get you started in your
first purple team experience because a
lot of people hadn't really heard of
purple teaming
this was a great place to start right
starts with cyber threat intel
then preparation which is very important
when you bring everyone together
in that one exercise they're taking time
off of their day so
you want to ensure that you are
using their time to the best right be
the most efficient
so you execute the exercise and then you
have
lessons learned so how did this first
purple team
exercise go well it has a
flow as we can see here in the next
slide
that first the cyber threat intel team
provides a threat actor with the
capability intent and opportunity to
attack
you're all already sitting together so
you have a tabletop discussion this gets
you know breaks the ice say okay
look at this ttp if someone were to do
run dll32
right for a dll it's a sign binary it's
one of those
what we call low bass living off the
land binaries and scripts
and would we be able to detect this so
the cti team provides that the red team
says all right this is
you know this is a low bass this is a
file that's on all our windows systems
then the blue team says well i think we
might be able to detect it with our edr
because our edr logs that run dll32
and then sends the log to our central
log aggregator say splunk in this case
and then we have an alert on splunk
that's gonna show us
that's fantastic right sometimes that's
not going to be the case sometimes
you're going to say hey
what happens if we run this and be like
i don't think we have any detections for
that
but that's great you want to document
those expected defenses
then the red team is going to share
their screen and because they did that
preparation
they're going to be able to emulate that
for you very quickly and very easily
they're going to explain how it works
right run dll32 again it's part of the
windows operating system
and it's used to load dlls so we've
before the exercise we created this dll
that when it executes it's going to
establish command and control
with rc2 server over https
this is the ip address this is the host
name this is the domain
this is the port right we provide all
those iocs and we show it
so cti is learning how the red team
operates and how the attacker operates
the blue team is learning and seeing and
has all these iocs and
these indicators and then once the
execution is complete
the blue team looks for those indicators
of behavior
and sees if it matches the expectation
right
did run dll32 get logged by the edr
yes or no yes great did it get sent to
splunk
yeah i did i i could see it here when i
run a query
but there was no alert there should have
been lr why was there an
alert well let's look into it oh my gosh
look this is the reason why there was no
alert
maybe there was drift who knows right or
in the event that uh you had no local
logging for instance then you do
detection engineering
where you create these security controls
for those gaps
and then you test it again one of the
things about purple team exercises is
you want to use a platform
that is consistent and reliable so you
can re-execute that
same exact ttp over and over as you do
detection engineering
once you do have a security control then
you can train the people
your sock folks right what to do when
that happens
go through the process etc right the
next slide
was actually an image created by tim
that i totally stole and love because it
says
everything i just went through in a much
prettier way right
you have an exercise coordinator
exercise
coordinator is very important for purple
team exercises because they bring
everyone together from the cti team to a
blue team
to red team they put the proposal
together they ensure the exercise is
running smoothly
highly recommend that's a dedicated
position then
you do the tabletop like i said red team
emulates
blue team shows the detection of those
behaviors
if there weren't any you do detection
engineering and then
you repeat them right which is fantastic
the next slide you're gonna see
if you document all these ttps each
each week of your purple team engagement
or however often you do a purple team
right
we know some organizations that do it
once a year some organizations that do
it quarterly some that do it monthly
but the point is that you're documenting
where you stand
at the beginning of that exercise and
then
where you are at the end of the exercise
and you show that improvement
now this chart i know goes up and down
and the reason it goes down is because
we were
baselining we were going back to
original system that we had
and in that system there was very little
detections so
you can see uh the improvement and that
was very very important so
we finished doing this purple team
exercise everyone's satisfied it's like
wow i learned a lot from the blue team i
learned a lot from cti
i learned a lot from the red team high
fives
all right let's get back to work because
you know exercise is over
and then what happens right
maybe another ad hoc exercises in six
months or in a year
or you could turn it over to tim
to tell us what we are seeing most
enterprises
and uh small and medium businesses
actually heading
towards well
and to to sort of lead off with what
george mentioned
some of the challenges in this space are
that we
we do come together for that event we
see all of the
the greatness that purple teaming has to
offer as an exercise
and then everyone goes back to their
silos and so
often times purple teaming will expose
some some pretty big gaps whether it's
in detections
or whether it's in if you have a really
mature
set of defensive technologies and stuff
like that maybe
the tests that you're running up against
it are are not mature enough to sort of
actually stress it enough to to see if
there's any gaps
and that's partially because all these
teams are independent and so they're
developing capability independently they
have different levels of maturity
and so the challenge is how do we
measure that and
put it together in the current landscape
and i think
the answer is we can't really do that
with
all these teams oftentimes if you have
a large enough organization or even a
small organization
everyone is so consumed trying to do the
things that are within their
their current job that it's tough to
collaborate
and communicate because it's optional
it's something that
teams can decide whether or not they
have the time to do
and i think that is sort of the the core
issue
that purple teaming addresses is
bringing all those people together
and so the information security teams of
tomorrow
are going to be this blended purple team
uh all of these backgrounds red teaming
blue teaming
cyber threat intelligence as a dedicated
team
and so that's where for instance as
george mentioned with
uh not just large enterprises that have
you know dedicated teams for all of
these to
you know uh carve off a couple people
and say all right you're going to be
now in our new purple team i think for
small businesses this is the way
to move forward because you need to
understand
not only uh what are we defending
against but how are we doing it and so
we're going to show you
a couple of different ways first what
the purple maturity model
is so you can measure and see how we're
going to
continue to build these teams and then
we're going to go through an example
that's going to highlight how a current
team would use this model and hopefully
you can see yourself in there or your
team
and how how you can progress using this
new model
so that's where overall our our
sort of argument here on why there
should be
a purple maturity model is that there's
fundamentally
different mentality because of that
communication because of that
collaboration
than there is with the current red and
blue teams and so that's not to say that
red and blue teams aren't can't be
effective you're still going to need
people that have
the background you're going to need uh
red and blue teams ideally to
sort of do additional things outside of
what
the the purple team mean that we're
going to highlight is and for blue team
that could be things like
for instance setting firewall exceptions
and anything that's going to involve
uh information technology administration
and things like that
uh for red teaming you know if they're
depending on how it
sophisticated advance your your
organization is you're going to need
dedicated people that are just trying to
break in the entire time
and are doing additional research on top
of the threat research we're going to
talk about
but overall this is sort of the starting
this is that core
core set of skills and expertise that we
think that
are going to be required for most
information security teams moving
forward
and so with that we're going to dive
into the
what so what is this maturity model that
we keep
teasing and talking about and so with
that let's walk through the purple team
story a little bit as george has already
talked to so i'm not going to spend a
lot of time on it but it's basically
been
the set of three teams sort of coming to
the infosec
scene so with blue teaming sort of being
the first
set of larger teams and then having red
teams to
address that in some space we knew that
you know we needed to test our defenses
so
of course we're gonna set up a dedicated
team and then
uh cyber threat intelligence has sort of
come along and and really evolved and
grown over the past decade
into into his own series of capabilities
and teams beyond indicators of
compromise as george mentioned
and so that's where they really have
brought context to both the
information that they were providing the
blue team and
the red team with the tactics techniques
and procedures
that the red team should be emulating
and so again
this is sort of all come together under
the umbrella term that we like to call
purple teaming now in this
world where you have a purple team what
are they doing how do we measure that
the way we've broken this down is into
two major categories
and that is threat understanding and
detection understanding
and so for folks that have a red team
background you might easily see yourself
within the thread understanding space
if you've got a blue team background you
might see yourself in the detection
engineering space
i'll get to sort of the area where i
think cyber threat intelligence provides
the most value in this model as well
but overall the idea here is that this
is going to be a team that needs to
leverage both
consistently and as equally as possible
and so we're going to dive into how do
we measure the maturity
of our capability in each of these
spaces
and so we did do that by we have a three
level
model and so overall though with
detection engineering just uh our
understanding
to dive into what that is before we go
into how do you measure it
is overall you'll see a lot of questions
here
around that that are very similar to
what threat hunters what blue teams are
doing right now
although you'll see a couple of things
like have detections been validated
and so detection understanding is all
about trying to understand
what is a situational awareness on your
network what are the assets that you
have control over and what are they
doing
and so from the same standpoint of the
threat understanding
overall the question here is what
adversaries are targeting
our industry what are the tests that we
should be building based
on the capabilities the technology and
tooling that they're using
in order to test their defenses and
again what detections have been
validated
there's intentionally some crossover
there because that's really what's going
to be needed between
the two teams having a lopsided team as
far as skill sets and expertise
is not going to be something that's
going to be necessarily a benefit to
your overall purple team
and so we'll get into that and so this
is where we're building our model this
is that first level of maturity
maturity level one is deployment and so
this is where most teams start so your
team may not be here right now but this
is probably where your team started
deployment is uh about using someone
else's tools
and so can you take uh and someone
else's tools technologies process
and deploy it within your environment
for some effect
and so this is where this could be
vendor tools uh
that are that are a new tool you're
trying trying out to see whether
it does provide value it can be
something like an open source tool
where you again are attempting to bring
out some additional value
or cover some gap and then uh and then
it could also be something like
indicators of compromise right can you
deploy
indicators of compromise in your
environment to have some effects can
they look for
uh those and so that's sort of how we
span deployment here and i'm gonna go
over an example
uh using two open source projects that
is going to to sort of showcase this
maturity model this one two and three in
both
the threat understanding and the
detection understanding
so level two is integration so this is
building on top of deployment this is
after something has been deployed you've
used a little bit and you've decided
this is something that we want and in
fact we want to achieve greater effect
by putting
by integrating this with something else
that we already have
maybe this is two tools that you've had
that two teams have used that have sort
of been on a collision course and
integrating them is going to provide
additional uh you know people hours or
it's going to require less expertise in
order to get spun up on
one interface instead of two and so
that's where this integration really
comes into effect but of course it is
building on this initial deployment
and so that's again this is can you
integrate a new process you know can you
integrate something like miter attack
i mentioned before that i was going to
highlight where i thought
uh cyber threat intelligence was could
really play a role and this is
this role at level two integration for
both the threat understanding detection
understanding
understanding where you need the points
of integration
and where for instance you have
threat modeling is going to help help
you identify
where the areas that we have gaps that
we need to address
where we need to combine two resources
in order to
achieve those greater results and this
is where again
cyber threat intelligence can really
play a key role in providing context
around both threat and detection
understanding
to help with identifying key integration
points
or showcasing how those integration
points can provide even more value than
they are right now
and then our final level is level three
is creation
so creation this is the sort of you know
ultimate it's the the top level for each
because
if you can create novel tests and
techniques based on
your integration based on your
deployment again or building up here
that's that it allows you to adapt to
new techniques to new threat groups that
are going to appear in this space and
that
overall means that you're going to be a
highly adaptive team
which is going to be really important in
this industry and in this space
for continuing to adapt to new
adversaries you know and that's
that's something that's that is sort of
why it's the pinnacle here
is that in addition to deploying and
integrating what you're doing
you have a team that can extend uh
extend these tools
extend these technologies or processes
to be tailored to your environment
to whoever you are going up against and
that is
really really important especially again
as we continue to adapt
because adversaries are unfortunately
have been well funded
so they are adapting as well
so with that i'm going to dive into two
open source
projects that a lot of you are probably
familiar with especially from the red
team side
uh you've probably a few times been
caught by some sigma rules
and you may have started your journey or
may use something like atomic red team
to help transition some of the testing
you're doing so
that the blue teams and the folks that
you're running tests on
can run similar things in the future
so the first one we're going to dive
into is the detection understanding and
sigma
and so the deployment phase here is not
just
deploying uh sigma rules but it's
setting up that
scene setting up that edr deploying it
with what it's gotten seen
can you get those results and so then
you can work on
building out and integrating something
like sigma either
into just the standard edr uh
and and your general logging and and
scanning
or it could do something like if you
have a sandbox environment
making sure that you're running these
rules against it to to see what you're
introducing into your environment
and so again it's it's sort of making
sure that you're providing
additional value at each stage that this
tool this technology this process is
providing additional value
and that's where we get to the pinnacle
here is developing your
own tools giving back to the community
by
releasing potentially new ways of
building detections around specific
techniques or procedures
and then of course developing your own
internal
sigma rules if that's something that you
have a very specific use case that you
want to be able to
detect on this is where your team is
going to continue
to work and build and play and so that's
why again
creation is sort of sort of the what
we're driving towards here
and and that is because you are able to
adapt
anything that you're bringing in to your
team
so and of course then we'll move over to
atomic red team
so uh most organizations start out here
and this is we've had a lot of
conversations with people that are
just building out their initial tests
and so atomic red team is
is builds off of if you're not familiar
with the project uh atomic testing
in software engineering where you are
building a very
small uh focused test case that's that's
only gonna test one thing
and so that's where you can either use
uh you can use atomic red team to test
like a singular
technique and it'll run through a bunch
of procedures or you can test a single
procedure
and so that's that's sort of the
starting point can you deploy
atomic red team to test your detections
integrating that might be ensuring that
anytime you are building new detections
that you are running an atomic red team
to test whether it works
or you're using atomic red team in your
detection development pipeline to make
sure
all of your detections work as they
probably should
this is where i'll give a shout out to
our friends at splunk
who have released attack range to help
with this exact
uh challenge because as george mentioned
earlier
maybe you have detections that you have
built over time and you think should be
firing an
alert for instance in his example and
then when you are building new
detections maybe
you change some of the logic to fit fit
some new one that you're you're
developing
and it changes previous tests wouldn't
it be great if
you had an automated way to see just how
big of an impact those types of changes
have
and that's where integrating these tools
together can really have
a greater effect because you'll be able
to identify and see that immediately
and not when a red team comes in and
exposes that
you know six months later and hopefully
you haven't had any adversaries that
have been able to
uh skirt by without without being seen
and so this is that really important
part again building value
continuing to build on top of your
previous work
and of course our top one here is
creating
and developing brand new atomic red team
techniques
so a lot of adversaries depending on who
they're
targeting how they what their normal
mode of operations are
they're going to use slightly different
variations of things
whether it's different flags whether
they like to obfuscate
things a certain way especially when we
look at like invoke obfuscation and some
of that
those were based off of initial uh i
think the initial talk talked about
uh when it was released that this was a
lot of financial sector
uh threat actors that were using these
techniques
and so that's going to potentially be
you're going to develop these new atomic
red team techniques that are very
specific to your industry they're
specific to your use case
and the groups that are targeting you
and so again
that's why this is so critical is these
continue to build off each other and
you will mature your level of threat
understanding
and uh and detection understanding
as you go through each of these and so
these it's meant to measure a team
not just a tool but overall i do want to
highlight
communication as sort of i mentioned
before
and george mentioned before that
communication is sort of optional
between teams it can happen the red team
the blue team
cti can get together everyone can talk
for a purple team exercise
but overall when it comes to a purple
maturity model
this is a team communication is key they
are one team
they are all going to do this together
so communication isn't optional anymore
this is something that is ingrained this
is built
and it's uh you know felt that it needed
to be explicitly said and covered in a
slide because
it is so critical to the success of this
team
so with that we have this three levels
uh of maturity for both thread under
understanding
and detection understanding and from
here
we can sort of uh chart them against
each other
and build them into this nice square
to represent the three levels of
maturity for both threat understanding
and detection understanding
because as we mentioned before part of
this is not just
introducing here are these maturity
levels where are you
but how do you chart the maturity of a
dedicated purple team
as you're building it and measure where
they are in your organization
and so this is sort of the the key the
key slide of our our maturity model here
because your team every team is going to
start a little different
and so if you have a super high level of
detection understanding
you may start in the top left and so
this is where
you're going to be needing to build out
additional threat understanding because
there's a chance
a lot of your detection engineers are
building their detections in a vacuum
they're not being validated by a red
team you know there was a great talk
at the sands purple team conference that
a quote i'm gonna i'm gonna pull from
uh one of them i don't remember exactly
who it is but
the question was you know that they
asked was how
many red teams are looking at you know
detections and in an organization how
many
of those meetings are happening and so
that we're trying to drive that here
with this purple team
model and that's where making sure
you're going to build your thread
understanding
so you know you might be looking at this
you can
sort of picture yourself picture your
team
and maybe others are are are not able to
as much
so that's why we are going to walk
through uh our last set
of slides here and as uh building
out how we are going to walk through a
fictitious
team going through the purple maturity
model
and so again this is our sort of final
question that we're answering in our
roadmap is how can we use it
and we are going to start with it by
introducing
unicorn inc so as george mentioned
before unicorns
are the scythe uh scythe logo and symbol
as he has great shirt there also you'll
notice we've got red and blue we've
we definitely didn't coordinate this
morning when we were
working on building this presentation
but we're going to walk through each of
the roles of our current
team members and the sort of scenario
here is that they've
been thrown together they've been
designated uh as the new purple team
and so we're gonna walk through uh what
they what they do
before they join this purple team uh how
they're going to integrate the purple
maturity model
and then what their roles look like and
how things have shifted
afterward so first we're gonna meet alex
alex is our blue team background alex
typically builds new detections uh based
on the latest indicators of compromise
from casey who's our cyber threat
intelligence
uh focused person and
so there's already some collaboration
happening which is great and that was
part of the reason they were chosen for
the purple team is that everyone knew
communication was key and so alex and
casey
were uh you know a great set of people
to have
already on the purple team we have
brooke brooke is our red team background
and so brooke keeps up with the latest
and greatest
red team tooling amsi bypasses that
microsoft has recently patched
and all of the things uh that the red
team community shares on twitter and has
tried to
sort of uh integrate a couple of tools
together for
greater effect and it's had some some
really good success on some of their
internal red teams
and then our final uh final unicorn here
is casey
now casey has a background in cyber
threat intelligence reads
every cti vendor's threat report uh
sends over the indicators of compromise
to alex as we mentioned
earlier and so has a good working
relationship
with the blue team and and feels feels
like they're doing a pretty good job
and so something you'll notice with all
of our unicorns here is that they are
all
they're all doing their job and so
that's that's not a bad thing but again
this mentions and sort of ties back to
what what we talked about before how
this is something that i think a lot of
companies can probably
and people can see themselves in each of
these unicorns
and they are doing their job but the
problem is they're siloed
and so they're sort of you know we have
a little bit of break uh breaking down
of those silos between casey
and alex but we can sort of highlight
what what some strengths of
collaborating can be here in the future
and so as i mentioned uh brooke casey
and alex have all been designated for
the company's new purple team
so they're looking at this model and
then
they're like cool we're purple now where
are we
and so i mentioned before uh you know
just building off the bios that we've
built up here
that while alex and casey have done some
collaboration they've mostly
stuck to indicators of compromise and
deploying those within the environment
and so that means that their their
detection understanding is probably a
one
and then in this case brooke has done
some integrations with their testing
and uh you know combined a couple
of tools together for for greater effect
and so
brooke has probably moved the threat
understanding to the integration phase
and beyond just deploying
those tools and so they'd probably start
in the
middle bottom and so overall
what we want to chart out here is how do
we get them to
the top right how do we get them to a
strong purple team
and so since they do have a little bit
of this you know
lopsided um skill set the question would
be
where do they need to go next and so my
argument here with the purple
maturity model is that you are better
off
moving uh if you are have some sort of
expertise and you can choose where you
go next
would be to try and even it out and
balance it out
and so move towards detection
understanding
and so that would mean that this purple
team would need to
build their understanding in detections
and the process
and all the things and would need to
chart a path on how to increase that so
how do they get to integration
and so with that we're going to dive
into
how this new team has sort of built out
their roles to address some of those
gaps
that they've had and so alex
alex is running new detections by brook
to ensure that they work and are not
easily bypassed so this is again this is
something that
alex was already doing before was
building those indicators of compromise
was building detections based on the new
part is
is frankly some integration between uh
this new member of their team
so passing over detection to see do
these work
uh are they easily bypassed
incorporating new detection from malware
that's specifically identified by casey
our cyber threatening intelligence
analyst
and sort of bringing those in to make
sure that
we can we can detect against malware
that's targeting our industry
and then as i mentioned before moving
from
deployment to integration requires doing
some research
where can we where do we have these
integration points
and where can we do additional analysis
to incorporate uh
you know our to increase our level of
detection logic
and so this is where you know each
component is not just a
necessarily a doer but also trying to
understand
how do we mature this and build this up
next and alex is going to be one of the
key people in this because alex came
from the blue team
so now brooke this is brook is our red
team background uh brooke
is now going to start building tests to
validate those detections
so again this is part of that that shift
towards purple because
instead of just building new tests it's
making sure that
all of the detections are working as
intended
and so again incorporating these
techniques and procedures that
uh from threats that have been
identified by our by casey who again
is our cyber threat intel background and
so
this is going to make sure that all of
the
uh new malware and and tools that the
threats that are targeting
the unicorn industry are going to
potentially
be already tested against and we'll see
if there's detections
but that doesn't mean that brooke is
going to stay off twitter and that's
okay
because new techniques from uh twitter
can be passed on to alex to either build
detections for
or they can be passed on to casey and
this is where context is important
because casey can say
this technique is being used thank you
for identifying this now we
let's let's work on you know building
out a test case and a detection for it
or casey can also say this you know
this is way beyond anything that we need
right now or
that is being leveraged by uh by
threat groups targeting our area let's
you know put this on the
backlog and so having that sort of that
dialogue and that conversation between
teams is going to be super important
and although we've already touched on
casey's new role
uh the focus i want to point to here is
that the
research is going to be focused within
the unicorn industry
and so while casey was reading every
vendor's cti
report before and that's really great
for knowing the entirety of landscape of
threat actors
as far as making sure that casey is
providing the value necessary to both
alex and brooke uh it's going to require
a bit more focused uh research and so
that's really what this role is
is changing too and you'll see that the
two other bullet points also sort of
highlight that
so the shifting rules that we've seen
here between alex brooke
and casey are on how do we make sure
that we know how to address these things
as a team
and as you're doing this you're going to
be able to
again chart your understanding and so
you have a joint goal between all of the
blended expertise of red teaming blue
teaming and cyber threat intelligence
as you're able to weave through the
model and so the story here goes is that
you know while while the team started
with a little bit of a lop side
of of threat understanding they
charted out a path they had a lot of
momentum and so
uh it took them to the middle they were
able to level out their detection
understanding with their threat
understanding at integration
and then from there uh they created a
couple of novel detections
realized that they didn't quite have the
research needed
and threat understanding to test those
and so that's how they
kept working their way to creating their
own
novel uh threats and detections for
those
and they ended up with a very strong
purple team
and so that's sort of the story of the
purple maturity model
is that it's taking the expertise we
already have
because expertise is something if you
look at the the top people that
are in each of these fields red team
blue team cyber threat intel
we have a huge amount of expertise i
mean these people
are are wizards right and geniuses when
it comes to
building these things out building up
detections building out
bypasses to it and and some of the tools
that have come out have just been
amazing
but how do we take all of that and bring
it together and purple teaming
i think is that vehicle it's sort of and
that's where
we are trying to showcase how that can
be used
to move everyone forward in the industry
and so with that we have answered our
three main questions
why does purple need a maturity model uh
you know what is that maturity model and
then how can we use it
and so with that any questions
and thank you all for attending hand it
back to you george
yeah thank you red team village thank
you red team village organizers and of
course
all the attendees and sponsors and all
that really appreciate the invite
and we will take questions on discord
and
hopefully you have some good feedback
for us again this is all what we're
seeing out there
and hopefully we come back next year and
let you know what what else is happening
and of course uh call to action for you
to contribute as well how are you
implementing purple teaming in your
organization are you doing
purple team exercises you have dedicated
purple teamers right
keep sharing information because the
malicious actors are doing it
and we should too so uh thank you again
to the red team village for all the
contributions to community
and uh thanks tim for uh collaborating
with me and allowing me to come
uh speak a little bit uh on this on one
of our favorite topics
so thank you again