hello good morning guys my name is
Archana cassavan I am representing
Thousand Eyes here some of you are
probably familiar with the name
maybe the t-shirt rings about but if not
we're here for a couple of days and you
can get to know us but more importantly
the reason I'm here is to talk about a
research and study that we conducted
earlier last year that compares the
network performance of the big three
cloud providers AWS Google cloud and
Microsoft Azure start with this so for
the next 25 minutes or so what we're
going to do is I'm going to give you an
overview of why we did this study what
was the reason behind the study the
genesis of it and then get into the data
methodology that we used to gather
results and then actually talk about the
insights or how did these three
providers perform what was the network
performance like were there any
similarities were there any differences
gotchas that you know came out and then
we'll start with some summary
recommendations and we'll have time for
Q&A as well
so when we started you know before we
went on this study we're looking at how
our cloud decisions made today at
enterprises how are you picking AWS
versus Google cloud versus Microsoft
Azure and it turns out that obviously
there are a few guiding principles that
come into play right you're interested
in understanding the global presence of
these providers which is where are their
regions located how many data centers do
they have how many availability zones
exist within these regions and so on
pricing is definitely a big
consideration and sometimes it has the
power to sway decisions one way or the
other depending on how many free credits
you end up getting from each of these
providers and then most importantly is
the technical fit is ec2 or compute
available in all form factors that match
your requirements what's the load
balancing architecture like what is a
firewall look like and so on and that's
a really important criteria
when it comes to you know making your
selection of these three providers but
then performance is important as well
who performs better do they perform
better in certain situations what should
you be aware of and it turns out that if
you do a google search on AWS vs. google
cloud versus as you're the first three
quadrants that we just discussed you'll
get a lot of information out there but
performance was something that we saw
was deficit with very little information
in there and whatever information was
available was not really comprehensive
from the perspective of the depth of
data that it had all also they were in
snapshots in time there was not a lot of
trend analysis out there there was very
less information on network connectivity
architectures how does the network look
like within these three cloud providers
for instance so when we notice this
deficit of data we decided to go ahead
and bridge that gap by doing this study
and we leveraged our fleet of you know
agents or monitoring probes to gather
data so a little bit about how we can do
this data how we went about doing the
study is think of we have what we call
as software probes or monitoring agents
right and they are located in tier 2 and
tier 3 ISPs around the globe and also
within each of these cloud service
providers so now these agents are
emulating user traffic and let's call it
by using what is called a test where
they trigger a test that emulates user
traffic now these tests inject network
packets into the system and they can
understand not just end-to-end network
performance metrics like lost latency
but what we do is also use a highly
customized form of traceroute in there
that can give you information on network
paths as well something that we wanted
to address in here while we were looking
at would be the right you know mechanism
to get gather this data was we wanted to
stay
away from ICMP because ICMP has
shortfalls are that we're aware of for
instance that can be rate limited you
know within these hops in the network so
we chose TCP traces to get this data the
other thing that we wanted to be aware
of and bear in mind was how to get past
around the asymmetry in network routing
and when that means is forward routes
are different and reverse routes so we
wanted to make sure while we're
understanding performance and gathering
these you know network performance data
we look at both forward path and reverse
path as well so every time a test is
triggered data is collected and this
happens periodically it happens every 10
minutes and we collected this data for a
four-week period we ran the data for in
July of last year for a four-week period
with these tests triggering every 10
minutes right so every time a test is
triggered there's some amount of data
that's collected so what is this data
look like what would we get out of here
is n 2 n metrics so we can understand
what the end-to-end source to
destination and destination to source
because we are using bi-directional
traces here network loss latency and
jitter look like we're also
understanding when the network path
looks like I mentioned we use a highly
customized you know version of trace
route that can give us information on
the layer three hop-by-hop view of the
network with details on you know where
these hops are located which a SN or a s
network they're apart of N and so on so
what does allowed us to do was really
understand performance from two aspects
one is connectivity architectures to
these cloud providers and also end-user
performance metric to these cloud
providers so the probes are these agents
that I was referring to which was
basically the source or the foundation
of our data collection mechanism are
they managed by us what that means is we
have continuous access to these agents
so that allows for any easy detection or
if there were issues with
say connectivity or local false we could
eliminate it and replace it a new agent
but fortunately in this four-week period
we did not see anything like that which
was a win it was a very clean test run
for these four weeks four weeks that we
run these tests also I'm just a point to
note that there were no outages as in
these timeframe as well and what I mean
by outages is there's no net heavy
network packet loss that was seen or an
ISP outage in the network or within
these cloud providers as well so really
for for most parts it was a very clean
run so the data that you're here is
unbiased in terms of you know any
external factors that was influencing it
once the data is collected it's you know
periodically exported to a cloud-based
engine that can do trend analysis and
reporting which is how we were able to
crunch the data here to come up with
like inside system what this meant now
just something that I want to note here
is it throughout the rest of the
presentation I'm going to be heavily
focusing on network latency because that
was one metric which were we did see you
know anomalous behaviors and trends loss
and jitter were metrics that were
collected as a part of the test but I'm
not going to talk about it specifically
here just because there was nothing
interesting to report lots of latency
was class was really minimal and jitter
was as expected so there was nothing you
know pending that really stood out to
talk about it all right a little bit
into test scope so that was the
infrastructure that was used for testing
but how what were the different vantage
points we looked at this comparison from
is we try to understand end-user
measurements so we're trying to
understand how the users connecting to
these cloud providers what do they
experience from the perspective of
network performance and connectivity
what does inter AC and intelligent
machines within a single truck cloud
provider look like as well because we
know that redundancy load balancing
microservices architecture is increasing
the communication within availability
zones across these
and within regions within you know in
each of these providers so we wanted to
understand that metric as well and then
finally we did multi-cloud measurements
which is understanding connectivity and
network metrics from AWS to assure
assured and Google and all the
permutation combinations that exists
there so when it comes to end-user
measurements we place these monitoring
software probes in 27 global locations
so 27 global locations connecting 255
regions of each of these providers so 15
AWS regions were used as in this study
25 Azure and 15 Google Cloud regions
were used here so they were
bi-directional tests running across from
27 global locations to 55 regions agents
located within these cloud service
providers as well which is how we were
able to generate this data so that
amounted to approximately thousand four
hundred and eighty five tests these
tests were again triggered every 10
minutes for a period of four weeks we
looked at inter AC measurements same way
through these agents that are pre
deployed within availability zones
within a single provider now the
interesting thing about availability
zones and how they are a map is that
they're really independent per account
so we wanted to take that into
consideration what that means is if I
log into AWS with my account login what
gets assigned to me as availability zone
could be different for somebody else
so we wanted to you know take care of
that exception any anomalies that might
create so we had multiple samples
running across multiple availability
zones within a region and as a for this
study we tested this across for AWS
regions for Google Cloud regions but we
tested only two one major region and and
that's because of azure is still warming
up to the idea of availability zones so
we just started with one region future
we'll be expanding that and then inter
region was across regions within a
single provider so
fifteen regions in AWS 25 in Azure and
then 15 in Google Cloud and these were
all bi-directional tests again running
periodically and the final piece of
measurement that we looked at was
looking at multi cloud which is
connecting each of these regions from a
single provider to another provider so
you can imagine the amount of crisscross
communication and tests that were
executed as a part of this so what did
this really result in right 30 days 10
minute interval a test triggered every
10 minutes across those four different
you know verticals that we just
discussed end user interests inter
region and multi cloud that gave us
about 20 million unique measurements
after a month but we were looking at it
by directionally which means we had 40
million unique measurements and each
measurement that we get takes into
consideration network loss latency
jitter and network path data so that's
four attributes for data point that will
make measurement that was collected so
about 160 million unique data points
that we had gathered over a period of a
month to come up with these insights and
and to look at how these three providers
were performing so now to the fun part
of this who was a good ballad a gay of
network performance where their
similarities who performed well who won
the cloud war will start with the good
really here is interesting performance
so there has been a lot of claims we've
heard made by each of these three
providers that inter AC performance is
always going to be below two
milliseconds we've heard that in a lot
of talks that have occurred in the past
those were claims that were made and
what our study showed that with all
these three providers performed
exceptionally well when it came to
network latency within between
availability zones so AWS and this
instance averaged at point eight two
millisecond and you can see the you know
split across each of those regions that
we picked as your
the same 1 millisecond range and then
Google Cloud with 0.79 as well so
overall interesting measurements or you
know performance network latency was
really good its signal that these
providers have robust well connected
internal architectures it also gives you
an idea of how far apart a data center
might be located within a region given
the latency numbers next year will be
increasing the number of regions that we
are going to be testing along with
increasing the number of regions in
Azure as well
the next is inter region performance
inter region performance is measuring
Network latency large and jitter within
a single provider but across multiple
regions for instance testing between AWS
East and AWS London for example Wahby
node is the first thing that stood out
and this is you know based on the
network path information that these
agents are continuously collecting we
notice the traffic stays within the same
provider when you're talking about inter
agent communication so think of these
agents are they deployed within these
providers is compute so if that means
AWS its ec2 instances that we are
triggering tests across it's a
communication between two easy two
instances go between go within an AWS
network right that's the first thing
that stood out and we were able to get a
lot of absolute measurements in terms of
what the latency looked like but we were
not able to you know understand if this
was good or if this is you know
suboptimal performance so what we did to
get a better idea of that is to we
baselined it with internet averages so
we understood performance from a
relative you know score so what that
really means is I'll give you an example
to explain this is if you're looking at
interesting measurements for AWS for
instance between Ashburn and London we
get an absolute measurement value for
latency which is great but we also
wanted to see is that how does that
compare with respect to internet-based
lines going from
two points in Ashburn and in London
outside a WSS Network right that's how
we baseline it and we got this relative
measurement so we did those bad
performance across those 15 25 and 15
regions across all of these providers
now the assumption is that these
providers have really robust backbones
you know it's not the best effort
Network so it's a private connective
network so that should perform better
than internet averages and that's how we
did this grouping here so the first two
as you can see the first two vertical
very leaning heavily there in that angle
and what that distribution really means
is the number of intelligent pairs that
performed better than the Internet or
same as baseline to the Internet is
greater which is good and what we should
be expecting compared to certain regions
performed really poorly there were some
regions that was 30% slower than the
Internet all the way to the extreme
right for instance right so again from
overall most parts into region
measurements were good but they were
exceptions that existed and one of the
example is here in terms of exceptions
that exist so the data that you're
looking at here what the chart is
representing is bi-directional Layton
sees going in from Sydney Australia all
the three providers regions to Tokyo
Singapore and Mumbai regions for all
these these three providers and that's
the comparative metric and the green the
color coding that you see is average and
relative to internet baseline so when
you see green it means that connection
between Sydney Australia and let's take
AWS and 109 millisecond latency so AWS
latency between Sydney Australia and
Tokyo is Green and 109 which means it's
10% better than internet averages but if
you look at GC p and Mumbai which is 228
92 milliseconds that's 30% slower than
what you would expect on going across
those two location
on the internet right so there are
exceptions that did exist and it comes
into play when you're making these
choices on your architecture in terms of
how to choose these region pairs so this
can be a guiding factor in terms of what
constitutes good performance versus poor
performance in an inter region setup
well then jump over to what an end-user
performance look like and just to recap
the end-user performance measurements
were done from 27 locations globally to
55 regions of across these three
providers again now the way to the key
to reading this graph here you're going
to see few more occurrences of this
graph so let me spend a few minutes here
explaining it what you see on the x-axis
is the user location so these are
continents from where the user is
connecting to do this cloud service
provider which is denoted by the hosting
region so the graph on the Left that
you're seeing here is users connecting
from Asia Europe North America Australia
and then South America to u.s. East
Virginia or to Microsoft's East data
center located in Redmond and and the
cloud same thing as GCP counterpart as
well and then the one other graph is
very similarly it's connecting to United
Kingdom which is London and Cardiff or
as where these providers have their data
centers located and then the three
colors represent AWS Asia and Google
Club so what you notice here very
quickly is that if you're hosting
centers are in North America and in
Europe then your latency for users
connecting to these hosting centers are
really comparable across these three
providers there's not really a question
of who does better here they are their
comparatively all doing really good
no outages like I mentioned in this four
week period so this was really positive
information in terms of performance but
this only holds true if you are
connecting to North America and Western
Europe for instance as your data centers
when you move to Asia we start see
a different story right again the way
you read this chart here is the graph
here is user locations connecting to
hosting region in Bombay India all these
three cloud providers have hosting
regions in Bombay so it was easy to
compare them right and the first thing
that stands out here is that Google has
three terms a network latency when users
are coming in from Europe to India so if
you see the other user locations it's
it's it's pretty comparable but the only
thing that stands out here is that red
line which is Google's Network latency
bi-directional latency which is three
times that of AWS and sure the reason
for that it turns out is that Google
uses a very suboptimal route to move
traffic from Europe all the way to India
Google GCP they heav'nly rely on their
backbone to move traffic around and it
sounds like and it naturally sounds like
what if data showed is that traffic
moves all the way from Europe to the
United States to get to India so let me
explain this visualization that you see
here is the green dots that you're
seeing there are representative of our
agents located in Europe in those
particular locations and all the way on
the extreme right which is Mumbai India
that's the region you're connecting to
so these agents are emulating user
traffic going all the way up to Mumbai
India and back now the the the marked
region there towards the very end is a
representation of Google's backbone
those nodes there that you see show the
data is traversing the Google Blog phone
but it also shows the location of where
those nodes are located so all the way
from Europe they go to the United States
come they hit California and then they
go over to Bombay now that explains why
the latency was three times compared to
AWS and Microsoft Azure so what we
wanted to do is we wanted to verify and
validate that this is
indeed you know right this is how
Google's backbone works so what we did
was we look a look at the fiber
connectivity of Google cloud right and
it turns out the reason Google takes a
circuit shows part is because there is
no direct route in the Google backbone
from Europe to India so the only way
they can go around is to actually go
around right so this was this was really
interesting this stood out for us from
means if you know the data that we got
but something else that caught our eye
as well from an exception is how AWS was
performing now let's shift focus and
this is the exact same graph that we saw
earlier which showed performance network
latency bi-directional network latency
from these global locations to a hosting
Center in Mumbai but let's focus on
those black lines that you see they're
not the actual vertical bars itself and
what that represents is basically
standard deviation right it shows how
much latency can vary in a given period
of time and as you notice AWS seems to
have the largest variation in network
latency for users coming in from Asia
but connecting to Bombay now this seemed
anomalous as well so digging into the
data a little bit more we noticed that
this is a trend that we've seen across
all AWS deployments especially in Asia
so what you see here is bi-directional
latency variations for AWS for users
connecting from Asia to hosting centers
in Tokyo Singapore and and Bombay and as
you notice the yellow line here is AWS
is variation in network latency and it's
so bad in one way that it your network
latency can vary anywhere between 0 to
150 milliseconds that's pretty high the
reason AWS behaves this way again this
was if we were able to dig into the
network path data that was collected is
because AWS relies heavily on the
Internet to move traffic so AWS
basically hot potatoes traffic from the
user location to their region where does
that mean a user coming in from Mumbai
for an
Stan's going up to AWS east in Ashburn
is going to go over multiple IP hops
right and enter AWS is network pretty
far away from blue close to the region
where its host it's pretty far away from
the user location so in this particular
example users in frack Frankfort traffic
from Frankfort only enters AWS is back
one in Hong Kong for instance but that's
not the case when it comes to Google
cloud and Microsoft Azure if you notice
your traffic from the same user location
in Frankfort they enter the back one of
these two other providers in Frankfort
itself which means they ride the
backbone of these providers longer than
how a user who relies on AWS might and
we know that the Internet is less
predictable has has is you know is more
vulnerable to like it's a best-effort
network so you can see variations and
performance that exists when you're
starting to rely heavily on the internet
for example which is which explains AWS
is you know variation and performance
especially in Asia now again this is a
snapshot which shows how traffic moves
from global users to AWS this network in
AWS region in u.s. East which is Ashford
so notice how like users from Singapore
they have to go through multiple high
speeds going all the way from Singapore
to LA to Texas and they enter Amazon in
either Texas or they're entering
Amazon's network and Ashburn or New York
so it's really close to where the
hosting or the data center is this is
completely different than what is your
and GCP do same user coming in from
Singapore is going to enter Microsoft's
backbone in Singapore to go to Richmond
Virginia which is Microsoft's hosting
data center right so there's definitely
a difference in terms of how you connect
to the cloud so there's a variation in
cloud connectivity architectures as such
so this research that we did it was
conducted like I mentioned last year in
July and the research is now available
online for everybody we list it in
early November right and as we know
reinvent is end of November it happened
end of 2018 and AW was very
interestingly introduced a new service
in there called the global accelerator
the global accelerator they say is for
improved performance and in what it
translates to in simple terms is you pay
w as more money to write their network
to get better performance right that's
what it means and that's a that's a
ploughed trend that we are starting to
see it's it's what I call the
monetization of the cloud backbone and
this is not just specific to AWS Google
made such an announcement as well last
year so Google now gives you two tiers
of service a standard trio and a premium
tier if you pick the standard tier
you're going to hot potater around use
the Internet you're not gonna write
Google's network but if you pick the
premium tier you're going to go on
Google's network faster which means
couldn't code better performance right
so in lwith made this recent
announcement last year we don't know how
much of an improvement in performance
this is going to give and that's going
to be on a use case by use case basis
but this would be really interesting to
compare Internet performance versus
performance through AWS is global
accelerator all right finally we coming
to multi-cloud performance so
multi-cloud performance involved you
know testing from multiple regions
within a single provider to multiple
regions to another provider because
there's a lot of communication today in
enterprise architectures that involve in
multi club so we wanted to see what this
looks like and as you can see here a
jitter and packet loss and I mentioned
this earlier as well that was not
anything significant or interesting that
we noticed in terms of trends the
interesting takeaway from a multi cloud
performance angle with how these three
providers connect and pure with each
other so they obviously pair directly
with each other and what that means is
traffic in a multi cloud scenario never
really leaves the backbone of these
cloud providers so if you are connecting
AWS to Google cloud you're pretty much
going to take either go with AWS and
then move on to Google Club now the
interesting note however is because AWS
does not use their backbone to move
traffic they will push the traffic over
to Google as soon as possible and Google
will carry the rest of the traffic so
that's just you know an interesting
detail that we noticed while we were
looking at I'll take you out performance
so really that that kind of brings me to
the end of you know the the presentation
here and put me learn from this which we
went in this into this without any
assumptions or not expecting one is
going one provider is going to perform
better than the other right the idea was
to learn and find out what the
differences are what the similarities
might exist and what we noticed is that
cloud connectivity architectures are not
the same they have an impact on
performance and it's something we should
be aware of geographical performance
varies especially when it comes to Asia
not so much in North America and Europe
intra-cloud performance which is inter
region and Inter is a performance for
most parts did really well so that's
definitely a positive and then multi
cloud is a safe alternative right these
three providers have a symbiotic
relationship so multi cloud is
definitely a good way to go if you're
considering that so in terms of
recommendations what does this mean for
you know enterprises moving to the cloud
or starting to rely on these cloud
providers is use data as a guiding
factor to make your cloud investment
decisions there are a lot of criteria
that you need to consider while you're
picking your right cloud provider right
pricing geographical location services
availability but use data as well do not
discount data right because in the cloud
you can trust but you always always
always need to verify and you cannot
afford to make assumptions in the cloud
because there is no steady state in the
cloud what looks like good performance
today might not be good performance
tomorrow all these three providers are
continuously investing in their
architectures to make it better so good
today might not be good tomorrow
which really brings us to our research
vision right since we
nice that this is not a snapshot this
cannot be a snapshot in time we want to
keep doing this research every year and
we want to broaden the scope of this
research as well this year again it was
the first time we were doing it we
started with the big three
you know we had 27 global locations 55
regions but in the future we're
expanding we're thinking of expanding it
to maybe other providers maybe more
regions also understanding and comparing
differences and performance for their
private connectivity service right which
is Express route versus direct connect
and and so on so that's something we are
thinking of going forward and you know
executing later on this year as well so
it really brings me to the end of the
presentation if you are interested in
you know looking at the report reading
more about it you can download it from
the link there it's it's free if you
have questions hit me up now or I'm
gonna be around for the next couple of
days and happy to sync up with you thank
you
[Applause]
you're there first hi Dan Goulding with
Google first but first I just wanna say
great present don't be nervous cuz this
is a great presentation yeah really
impressive in terms of what you're
working on next would love to see the
private interconnect stuff I I think you
may want to consider some different
forms of measurement when you when you
do that and even private interconnect
from one provider to another provider it
could also be extremely interesting we
would love to see that data as far as
the Mumbai issue great catch I by the by
the time you run another set of tests
that will be resolved okay great
[Applause]
[Music]
definitely great talk met PTAC here on
the inter region one of the earlier
slides there you tossed out a comparison
to internet baseline without really
defining that too clearly if you come
back and do a future report I would love
to hear a little bit more about how you
decided on what that internet baseline
was because that is a whole kettle of
worms on how you measure that piece of
it absolutely so the way we did that is
these agents we're talking about for
inter region we're located within the
service providers but we also have
reagents that are located outside these
service providers in tier 2 and tier 3
networks so when we picked say Ashburn
in London for instance the measurement
that we got the absolute value was
within AWS and then we used the internet
baseline was we picked our agents
outside which was a which is either and
I can't remember which exact ISP it's
located out of for that region but we
looked at Ashburn and then another agent
in London and that's really what we
meant by internet baseline which with it
was in going with in AWS Azure Amazon
right but where the selection of your
agents is you're measuring specific
backbone tier 2 connectivity and that's
not really internet average so
reflecting that out saying okay this was
a CenturyLink to a cogent measurement
point you're looking at two specific
providers there unless you have enough
data points to really get a good
aggregate you're actually looking at a
separate set of measurements which is
yes full of provider to provider
connectivity but generalizing that as an
internet baseline might be good talking
great thank you
hi my name is Evan Moore from first
light fibre corporation I'm very curious
on this ten minute sampling interval
that you used in your study and what
discussion or consideration brought you
to the ten minute interval my first
response is ten minutes is an eon so I'd
like to hear that well there's nothing
really restricting us from you know
reducing this intro
all the way up to one minute as well it
means to be honest we thought well do we
want to test it once every hour or once
every minute is there going to be much
changes once every minute because we
were measuring over a period of time so
we just picked 10 minutes as you know a
point that that worked out well it is
possible that we can reduce that in the
future as well David Silberman LinkedIn
hi so glad to see that I sure wasn't
worst of most of the categories I was
positive plus one on the private
connectivity part Express route and if
you're not aware of it the Express route
direct might have different performance
envelope so you might want to look at
those somewhat separately or whatever
they're renaming them to but most
importantly did you do these tests over
ipv4 ipv6 or both it would be before you
have any plans to include ipv6 for 2019
it's possible I haven't really thought
about it right now but our agents R and
B for mv6 environments as well so that
is something we could consider I'd like
to touch base with you later on to see
if there's specifics with v6 you're
looking for oh sorry any other questions
all right I won't stand in a way between
lunch and you guys so thank you so much
[Applause]
you