good morning
arrey morning
few words above myself i'm reporter
etske and worked for Juniper Networks
since 2006 five last six years here see
in a Bay Area this presentation is about
the techniques we know big worth
invented who used last year to to do we
do one of our key customer challenge
which tends to be a how we can control
the state explosion of best guest
protocol sorry bottle gateway protocol
in a specific environment
which I would say it's a scarab drink
so o if you have any question during the
presentation or just break me
I prefer interaction so the agenda is
like first what is the environment what
is this scale-out peering why what is
differe
what it is what is what is not why it's
so specific and what are the principles
of operation this leads us who leads us
to the controlling challenges right so
the BGP scale and limitation of the
well-known common practices and finally
to I want to share with you the solution
or a solution for that
with a create the construct of the
abstract next up what it is and how the
internal BGP architecture will look like
when we use the abstract next abstract
nexif is by the way my term so we can
always change it as community over time
and finally some configuration examples
this is not
fitting presentations so I would say not
I would try to keep it very short but we
spent more and more time on the on the
on the devices with the screen our
application are even if screen is dead
like my iPhone the application are
running in background the message is
coming the notifications are coming so
the bomb wave is growing especially the
need for boundaries and also in round
trip delay right that that is equalized
to experience how my experience with the
application with a with a webpage with
the app is and this in addition to the
fact that the consumer consumer of the
data and producer of the data is usually
different Network Facebook and t-mobile
or sorry that whatever operator this
leads to the situation where the peering
is more dance and dance it's more points
more connection more bandwidth needed
and they that's that's why not only we
are generally seeing the at least from
place where I am up juniper networks we
are seeing this this interest in the
scale out architecture where we have
good residency without extra cost
because it's n +1 residency we can
provide the capacity and scale the
capacity as needed and by reducing the
requirements for the bandwidth density
on every elements in the network it's
just good for for competition right it's
easier to easier to use different
products so what is this scale out
peering I would I try to put this kind
of formal definition so if we have a
given period connected to multiple a
autonomic system ASV ours at a given
site
and that's the situation when we have a
schedule peering right we period a with
the given P is in the scale-out manner
and then of course the whole routing
system is set up to enjoy the ECM PL
downstream at the upstream of course
there is a limits right the PAS can do
whatever he wants with the policy but
conceptually I'm advertising on all four
devices down to the pier AES my network
equally with the equal attributes and
expect the same opposite and the scalp
image is specific sub case or subset of
distributed peering right we may have
these different environments where the
given a s is connected to to ASB ours at
different sides or to ASB are at given
sites connects to different here is s
that's the distributed peering right we
distribute the peering cloud but it is
not scale out at least not in context of
this presentation so if we if we have a
peering side with this scale out peering
model we have the bunch of IES be ours
we just discussed that we will have also
the set of core routers or core switches
whatever we call it spine even that's in
this year or last year fancy name of the
of the core device I'll probably route
reflectors and we will talk a little bit
about them later and in between there is
the need to be something which connects
this it connects these elements in a way
which allows me scale out peering so
added appearing devices without
impacting the rest of the network and in
general it is something in between could
be a passive network just the cables or
some active elements so Altos which is
the we'll see
this example or sets of switches that's
a little bit vintage it could be L free
underlying network five stages clause
it could be just pure L free device flat
or probably there will be more
possibilities however if we look how it
looks from the how this behaves from the
routing perspective how this be this
option perhaps from the peering so
internet routing perspective free out of
these four ends I put the same situation
when my core routers and they and the
IASB ours are directly peering at layer
3 right if we have override there are
tunnels if we have L to switch we have
segments if you have passive Network we
have closed topology if we put the like
on the bottom right side some active
elements with the full capabilities of
the internet routing in the middle it's
nothing else than just bigger closed
network so like a hierarchical core if
you like or spines and Quarterly's
that's a little bit back to the future
when I draw it first time as a half hmm
I saw this somewhere and look my CCIE
book from 90s I say yeah yeah core
distribution access that same but just a
side note for the rest of the talk I
would rather for we will talk about the
the topology on the left upper side just
because it's a simplest but everything
is valid in all other cases so what are
the common principles when we go to the
scale-out peering right we want the
boundary if we want right out on the
ecmp
so what will be impact on my network on
my control plane you see a equal cost
load balancing cannot ASB ours that
implicitly means that we have to use
best bgp multipath in some point in the
network
the BGP routing will be across multiple
gateways load balancing and that scale
up drip routing information base yeah if
we say okay I have a half-million
prefixes for gateways it's ultimately
two million paths just like that the
second we want to write on n plus one
redundancy model right so if one fails
we are losing only proportion of the of
the capacity and we can over-provisioned
like a twenty percent of twenty five
percent instead of one plus one that's a
big financial gain and this has to be
the the redundancy has to cover us
against the interiors interface failure
also multiple session failure because we
don't know what is on the opposite side
on in the pas de so single failure on
the periods can appear on my is as a
multiple session down my ASB our failure
and the entire site could go out
hopefully never but then I want to scale
out I already said it so be able to add
additional ASB are on one side without
impacting the other so it has obvious
consequence across on the physical
network if I add do i I don't want to
add the links across the entire global
network but also on the control plane
I'm using the two or very few carota
Reuters outside I can keep scaling out
the ASB ours but scaling How Tos beers
mean also scaling out the number of read
of paths in the BGP and now I can say in
this remote region somewhere in Alaska I
have my old router right and I don't
need to upgrade them there is enough
capacity and enough enough interfaces
but
because my routing information based
Kayla I need to upgrade hardware upgrade
the tutor as well that's that's not what
I want so myself network wired solution
should isolate this scale out at the
side from the rest of the network and
ideally I would like to restore the
traffic in seconds rather than in tens
of minutes that's a general call to
avoid or try to mitigate situation when
my convergence of network is really
dependent on the traffic spur path we
draw our entry advertisement it would be
much better if we can do this in the
bulk so that's what we want and how this
how the traditional typical BGP design
will deal with that first look at the
scale and if I have the network of 40
sides for ASB ours to route reflectors
each asbr gets from Piraeus to help me
on traffic's it's not that much only
half of it is active because the other
half is better from the other exits one
million active prefixes is also not out
of the rich looking globally on the
network it means that the network lanced
eight million paths and we have globally
we have 80 path / traffic's if I want to
use the ecmp I need the add path if I do
the crazy up of 80 I don't know if
everything hard work and do that but
that leads to the situation when I have
like 80 path out of it for maybe eight
is active another for maybe eight is my
backup or second path the best path if
you use something like BGP peak but 80%
of this information is just not needed
it's not primary it's not backup why to
keep it across the network and this the
BGP without without half buff is doing
this nicely
just select the best active path and
that's it but if you do the add path for
the multipath ecmp well boss
we have this challenge the other thing
we cannot forget is that we have limited
control of what our purine KS is doing
all right it we assume they advertise
all prefixes on all links because they
also did these my periods also like to
use the ecmp characteristics but people
make mistakes and policies always could
be put there for whatever reason so it
could happen that some of prefixes
doesn't exist on every laser on every on
every session on every asbr
and this leads to some trade-off right
either we need to be have to something
smart and deep in the network like a
core router which is able to do the full
IP lookup and knows where to send its
the ICMP over free for the prefix number
two or we have to agree on some some
suboptimal routing inside in on the
egress side when one asbr will drop the
traffic to another area I believe that
the optimal routing is d our goal this
is the way how we control the cost so
and latency so that that's the
underlying decision was what we go with
and by the way the customer we work on
with that who triggers did that work
anyway is doing IP routing on every
device so and finally if my peer a s is
doing the same as I'm doing so going
scale out the number of session will
draw come on
so we will have to reduce the number of
BGP paths across the network we will
need to have ecmp and these two are kind
of contradiction Airi requirements and
enable some fast convergence ii or
subsequent restoration sub-second maybe
it's this is what we almost achieved in
the in the particular scenario but a
restoration of traffic in seconds not in
tens of minutes that that's what what we
try what we can achieve here and to go
deeper into this solution this will be
my reference network with is some naming
convention where the there is a role
there is a site and there is a number of
device outside on the entire network is
doing i-95 P forwarding we have the
route reflector which are connected in
two full meshes so the first route
reflector at given site in full mesh
with first reflector on all other sides
road reflectors are running multipath
and ad path would be with their clients
so the core routers and ASB ours toward
other route reflectors out of sight will
advertise only single a single path just
to prevent the situation when our 80
million path goes across this entire net
system asbr
except the multi path except up at part
from reflector but when it speaks to
route refer to route reflector it
advertised only best the best route so
the first typical the deployment we have
today is using next up self how many
network is using Maxwell of your network
is using max of self just to free okay
for five good
[Laughter]
[Music]
with that before either failure happen
everything is perfect I just want to
highlight that the core router has the
four paths - for local exits and all the
next hubs are duplex of the SBR 1.1 up
to the asbr 1.4 and all these lubis are
in IGP so what happen if this link fails
all four route backs are still in IDP
and asbr 1.1 the one it which is
impacted obviously will withdraw the
routes will send a withdraw out to the
route reflector for half million it
takes some time tens of second minutes
depending on the hardware right and what
else is going on in the network route
reflector reflects this information back
to the core routers and the Carothers
remove the path and updates their feet
which takes another X minutes and then
Reuters add other sides may need to do
exactly the same thing right if this
path particular path was the one chosen
as a best from route reflector probably
based on the route ID then these change
this chain need to be propagated okay so
maybe using the except unchanged is the
better behavior but in this case again
we have for next hops because of the
passive interface passive IGP on the
external interfaces all negative for
next cops are reachable through the IGP
on the core routers and the failure is a
session down not interface now
unfortunately next hop stays in the IGP
and the story repeats we have to
withdraw all half-million perfect
or whatever the number is it takes time
you may say it's overkill how it happens
that the session goes down and
interfaces up it could if you have a
switch in between if you have some old
DWDM system in between but even we have
a situation when actually interface will
go down the the mechanics is that
traffic at site free will be move it to
the sub optimal path all right because
the next hop is removed and the route
reflectors and core routers and the ASB
are outside or whatever edge routers on
the site number free buy some time
running which has invalid BGP path with
the unresolvable neck scope so they will
select the another one and I said that
before that the route reflectors
propagate only one best path out of
their sight so from site to free the
alternative path is free here site two
and then of course there is a BGP
conversion as we draw all updates
etcetera so traffic loop comes back to
site one because it's closer on in the
IGP but we have these traffic shifts not
nice this could be avoided if we run the
ad path between sites but then is a cost
which we try to reduce right the scale
of the BGP routing routing information
base and it's not only the memory but
it's also the time of the cold start up
right when we start from scratch it's
four times more information to be
carried between sites it's also
challenged with the chair next order
because we have four paths and if forth
best path or third best path is flapping
it doesn't really change anything in the
network but we have to propagate this
information and consume resources CPU
resources okay
I think the most interesting part come
on okay the solution is based on the
construct called I called abstract next
hub so first of all this is not a change
to BGP there is no protocol change we
use exactly the same old BGP protocol in
terms of the how we encapsulate the
frames in terms of what is the semantics
of every attribute and in terms of the
BGP selection algorithm no changes to be
deep in the abstract next hope is a
slash 30 33 32 33 would be or / 128
obviously address which is set as a BGP
next hope in the advertisement if the
advertisement is if the path was learned
from one out of the set of BGP session
right so this is like option two group
couple of BGP sessions and say okay fine
if if at least one of them is
advertising these prefix I will keep
using these as a BGP Naxal so it's a
little bit similar to the loop the next
up self right we change the next one but
at the same time these these abstract
address this this address is in my AGP
advertise to I GP conditionally only if
at least one session is up and running
if the session goes that what all
session in group goes down I remove the
next up from the AGP and what is this
add a subset of session which is
associated with the abstract next shop
it's up to you it's a part of this
network design it could be all session
from even asbr with the same period but
it could be also set of the session on
given a guess BR with the all transit
providers then the abstract next so we
oh there is a where
through the transit provider or it could
be a set of session from given side with
given period all right so we up we say
doesn't matter which of asbr sat outside
has the active session with the given
period at least one is there we keep
advertising these DS as a as a BGP next
attribute concept is very generic and
there could be also other use of them I
just working on some other use of the
abstract next job but let's see how this
would work in our example network right
first look in the inter side how big how
this will behave between ASPRS
Carruthers and route reflectors and for
this example the abstract next-hop
represent the all sessions with the a s2
s2 is on the bottom right from given
asbr
so each ASB are therefore the IP address
the i would be specific and unique for D
my I guess B R and P Reyes I call it a
PA up abstract Mexico a ESB are PAP
raised specifically abstract Mexico so
with that each is BR advertised the one
path to the prefix to with the next hope
BGP neck subset to abstract value
associated with the advertising pays BR
as you see on the picture so abstract
next hop 1.1 underscore two if the pas
is to underscore free if the pas is free
under and then the route reflectors are
doing now doing the rather attachment to
the core routers and they are doing that
with the ad path so all four paths are
reachable are visible to the to the core
router actually the good idea is to have
one more path and we'll see later when
it comes to comes to play
having that information corroder can
load balanced traffic address traffic
address egress downstream traffic across
all for ASB ours in the example so how
this will behalf in the in the failure
scenario the first simple failure
come on it's a one session between a s2
and asbr 1.1 and in this case between X
hub would not change right because we
have another session there is no need to
send update to root reflector this is
more like an ex-cop self to do global
the same the rest of the network will
not see much here the next could be ok
what if I don't have a second session so
the example now is I guess a is free the
end asbr
1.2 we lose the session this is only
session to a debt is BR to das free
therefore bgp NEX hub has to be removed
from I GP when it's removed from I GP
the core rotor immediately sees it
immediately is everything has time but
it's much faster it so one operation in
the IES is all in OSPF all right and
based on that d one of for path used
beef previously by by corroder
is not valid anymore and so one
operation with triggers local local
local convergence or local path
selection on the core router without
need of propagating BGP updates and
withdrawals and if these device has
something prep program it in the field
and it's possible to do this even in sub
seconds for the
hundreds of thousands of millions
prefixes another example what if we lose
all session between asbr 1.1 and as2
david out the abstract next hope now is
has to be removed from IGP because there
is no more session on a SBR one with pas
- and the story repeats right we just
remove the next up from IGP these
triggers the local fixing on the on the
core routers and rest of the network and
a final doom day we lose all we lose all
sessions on all days be ours with the
as2 of course all bgp NEX have become
unreachable in the out sorry in the is
is or IGP and corroder just removes the
four of them now the fifth path become
interesting because corroder can send
traffic to other exit at other site with
all these failures after the fixing
happens and traffic is restored there is
a normal BGP conversion there is a
withdrawal there is a tough updates but
they are but our traffic restoration do
not depends on that time so what if we
just stop here we'll see that the all
for may s be ours are visible across the
entire network and we have the same
challenge as before with the fact that
we have only one update going out of my
site to another size we have to renew it
send the update within new BGP next hub
so let's make the another step of
abstraction and whenever the update is
leaving my side let's change the BGP
next hub to another abstract address
which now will represent
not all session per asbr but all session
of all ASB ours as a set and you can
easily find two things right that first
of all we advertise only one path
regardless of number of the ASB are sat
side which is good because this reduce
the scale on the on the network wide
scale and second it doesn't change if
one of the ASB ARS lose his connectivity
with the neighboring areas and again the
how this operates under the failure the
single single session fail there is no
withdrawal at all right no update at all
next Club doesn't change if we lose two
sessions to from the if we lose two
sessions from asbr 1.1 there is a there
is a removal of the abstract next up
which is specific to SBR 1.1 inside the
inter inter side but from the inter-site
update the next sub doesn't change so
there is no need to do anything out of
the out of the given side one note there
could be and there is a possibility that
the object need to be signed because our
janitor ID change for example but
because the BGP next hop is not
unchanged there is no need to do any fit
programming or fifth chain jizz um and
if we lose this all session with a s2
like that then of obviously we have to
read we draw the this site-specific or
site pas specific BGP next-hop abstract
next up from ID from good network quite
IGP and that force us to use the backup
exit so what would be the results from
the scale perspective and in same
network with the same environment the CR
needs to handle between two and five to
ten million path that depends a little
bit how many what is the ECM p on the
one side of your network so in most
cases it would be 2.5 million not 80 on
a ASPRS we need like a three million
path maybe ten million in very worst
case scenario where five other remote
sites are equal or in equal cost right
so rather I don't know network which
gives me that characteristics that five
remote sites are in equal cost from me
so I do the ecmp that way but we may
save like eighty percent of the of the
path this part which I previously said
it's like it's never used it's unneeded
in not propagated we have quite good
ecmp right if we if we are going to
reach something out of my out of my side
and we can may have may we may have up
to 24 ways right we did at par 5 all
right so provided that these site to two
side six are in ecmp there they are in
the same cost
iid P cost from site one we spray the
traffic coming at site one we spray
among three core planes in this example
and then each Corp lines when delivered
to egress site is spread over for ASB
ours
and then this is pray these girls to the
PAS opposite is a four-way because
that's what we if the egg race is local
to site one we have four aggressors and
finally the configuration so this is an
example of Juno's we have these quite
specific construct here just to for
convenience under egress de we can give
the IP address that's exactly address
used by um this is the address of
abstract next hub and this is a part of
BGP configuration so this address is
inserted in the routing table as as a
family ARP only if we have at least made
at least one neighbor up and running
most precisely is in established state
and we already receive end of end of RIP
marker so we even know that it's
converged and then of course this this
address need this address needs to be
liquid into the into IGP this is a
simple policy and that's it so as a
result we see the abstract next op 1 1 1
2 in the is is in this case ID repealing
state database and in bgp update when
the ASB are advertised the prefix 100
50000 search 24 the next hop is set to
abstract value I try to make it also for
iOS XR and it's almost possible without
this special knob it's almost possible
because but it's possible with iOS XE so
the idea is that the abstract next hop
address would be a static route title to
the interface and the next hub which is
the IP address this 11 1 1 1 11 1 105
its IP address of my remote peer
external appear so if the interface goes
down or the arp resolution for the peer
go away also this static route go away
then we need to read vert ice these into
the IGP
and here is a trick right I can do that
but the fact that pure the address of
peer is reachable doesn't mean that the
bgp session is up and running and the
only way I found to mimic that is okay I
know that this session should make it
should give me some leading prefix in my
case is fifty fifty seven fifty seven
one one so if I get that from the from
the session I know this session is up so
this is a condition the condition here
you can simplify that remove this
condition and say okay if the interface
is apt and the abstract neck scope is up
the rest is the same
right bgp update is setting these are
these abstract abstract next hop address
as a BGP next hop and the logic is
exactly the same and finally third
example is again from Geno's I'm a
little bit more familiar but you
remember I said it would be good to
represent to change make another level
of abstraction when we when we advertise
out of the site right so now we we
create the static route which is this
side space side peer specific abstract
next hop and we will advertise it back
to is is on the SB ours only if I have
this specific a ESB ours is BR ax NH in
the in the routing table so if we come
back to you see that is BR specific
abstract next hop is one dot one dot one
dot two
and here at the bottom on the bottom
bottom left I have a condition there is
a condition which says if one dot one
dot one dot two exist in the eye not
zero then all this will redistribute the
static with tattoo to IGP and of course
I may have more conditions like that so
I can check the asbr of the abstract
next op of ASV are one two three and
four and if one of them exist in inot
zero then I will register Butte the site
specific address abstract abstract next
hope to the to the is is alright OS p f
so then you can see in the in the link
state database that this site pas
specific abstract next hope is in the in
the routing table in the IGP routing one
dot zero dot one dot two and this is
also what a wrote reflector advertised
as a BGP next hope to another sites not
locally to clients but to other route
reflectors added other sites
okay so short summary the scale out
architecture cell solve some challenges
with boundary friend and an zero
round-trip time also might help with the
commercial site the cost of scale out is
always the control plate state the
control plane states they are going up
so we need some new practices in
construct how to deal with that and
abstract next up is useful construct
it's a tool I can i it's not a Holy
Grail it's not something which solves
all the problems on the word one of my
colleagues commented that though it
doesn't solve the optimality of the BGP
routing of course not it's not for that
it's a tool which allows you to control
the scale of BGP path across your
internal
you peel out it's just and the use of it
is documented in the draft it I
submitted it for the ITF Gras working
group so you can comment
bhishan me fix it and make it usable for
others thank you and it's your time for
questions eat any Peter you promised
grill me what about the best gets
protocol come on speak to Mike mics are
on the back or I can give you your
example is essentially a search rider
scaled out appearing with other example
but given that it's a spine leaf
topology and the fact that a lot of our
modern data center designs are bgp
spying leaf is this something that would
be as well yes there is a possibility to
make it applicable for tea for the
underlay routing in the spine on leaf
the thing is it's not for free there is
some cost operational cost associated
with that right when you need to
configure these IP addresses etc so
depending on the scale right if your
network if you're if you're close high
peak loss has say ten thousand prefixes
not $100 $500 and prefixes or million to
exist is it worth to do that right but
yes it's it's possible it reduced the
reduced the how far in the how high in
the cost network this the object has to
travel to close the traffic I seems like
a net architecture you typically run
into models of
networking devices that have a limit on
the control plane even more so than you
do in the search router edge networks
right
actually I don't know the again one of
one person which commented my my draft
said you know what who cares about
control plane performance there is no
problem at all the people who trying to
do sub second subject sub second is
always about the provisioning state
before and yes then it's useful if you
if you are looking for the sub second it
could be useful because we remove the
one object which fix the tens of
thousands if not hundreds of thousands
of the of the of the routing routing
entries but your hardware has to have
proper indirection so not every hardware
can do this that's I know that if we
have only two levels on the example most
of the merchant ships including trident
tomahawks and all these can do that but
if the if the indirection depth going
father and fathers of VPN over BGP are
you over a tunnel over another two now
then things become a little bit more
more complex yeah the example is service
provider you can think about this also
from the content provider which peers we
do with the service provider and want
the boundary fried that work is network
widget is bidipi doesn't matter is
service provider or content provider