good morning everyone we kind of all
filter in so we can kind of
anybody in the room hungover from last
night
show of hands
I don't drink so if anyone needs it a
designated driver sometime just let me
know all right we're gonna do something
a little different today it's my goal
that we create more transparency and
openness within the organizers my
clicker within our organization so today
we're gonna have a community meeting
gonna be about 30 minutes I'm gonna go
over a few topics that I think are
relevant to our community and give you a
chance to get some feedback
so why community meetings now MOG is the
is really devoted to its community and
the people that make up our community we
want to develop an environment of
openness and transparency we have a
desire for open dialogue and meaningful
conversations we want to keep our
community informed and we're hoping for
constructive feedback within the namma
community with to create a more open and
diverse environment so what I'd like to
talk to you about today is first of all
the code of conduct tina referenced it
in the opening but i want to go in and
just line by line let you understand
what it is and again solicit some
feedback about that so you can
understand what kind of community we're
trying to build and reinforce with the
Nanog a second i want to talk about nana
outreach we're making a transition
you've known it before is Nanog on the
road and we're trying to expand it so
that we can do more outreach within our
community that'll hopefully feedback
into the membership and do more good
within our community I'm gonna go over
the website I talked about it briefly
I'm not gonna do an actual demo but I'm
gonna take you through so a few screens
so you can see how we've changed our
navigation some of the improvements were
made and let you know how you can go
find take a look at it
can I go back weird sorry I wouldn't get
a chance to meet the staff and then open
up for Q&A so I have a truncated first
line but that's okay so our code of
conduct we've since a lot of time on
this and trying to create a document
that will again reinforce community
openness diversity so in our code of
conduct we are trying to avoid any
unwelcome behavior including our not
limited to aggressive pushing of your
own services of products or causes
distribution or consumption of alcohol
in nanog Contracting spaces and this is
basically any alcohol that's not served
by the hotel so we don't want you having
a little homemade hooch being passed
around through the community audio video
recordings of the few sessions we're
recording is not permitted engaging in
any activity that is illegal or violates
nanog or there are sponsors contracts
and the with the venues or our
contractors offensive comments physical
contact because of sex sexual
orientation gender identity gender
expression age disability physical
appearance personal appearance race
color national origin or religion or
lack thereof sexual images of any kind
displayed in public spaces deliberate
intimidation stalking threatening or
following of individuals demeaning or
disruptive behavior or speech harassing
photography or recording of any kind
sustained distribution of presentations
or sorry sustained disruption of
presentations or other events
inappropriate physical contact and
unwelcome sexual attention I think this
is something we probably all can agree
to but again there give me a chance for
Q&A for you to give your feedback
outreach outreach is something that's
kind of really near and dear to me
and I think the purpose of outreach is
to increase diversity within our
community and to do so we must look
outward there's there's no way you're
gonna create diversity within a closed
environment the only way you're gonna
create diversity is by looking outwards
and trying to bring more people who have
different points of views or are come
from different situations to help build
and reinforce our community educational
outreach beyond our community is crucial
to the development and diverse ecosystem
it is our plan to empower students women
people of color and groups living in
areas unless with less access and
resources we plan to work with community
liaisons to plan and deliver targeted
programming that resonates within each
unique audience the website so we've
spent a lot of time trying to focus and
rebuild the website I'm very fortunate
to have a great team of people who have
been sitting here and spending a lot of
hours so that we can kind of restructure
our website so that we can have better
communications within with for our
community and with a prospective
audience it's about Nana as I mentioned
before our website is kind of divided
into sits in sections where there is the
public facing piece for people are come
in and figure out what is nanog and
there's also the meeting area and then
the other section of it is the area
where people who are doing business
within Nanog you're submitting a
presentation etc so first I want to talk
about just kind of go over the
navigation and for those of you want to
take a look at the new site that's up
the beta it's at noon an org so you can
always go to new Domino go to org and
you can see the new website so I want to
talk about our navigation structure so
as you can see the first navigation
structure is participate so I was trying
to create a structure that was focused
on making it easier to find out where
things are so how do I participate in
nanog membership there's a tender
meeting presented nanog and sponsored an
on ways that you can contribute ways
that you can get involved
then they get into the section about
Nana what we do who we are our story
timeline and code of conduct and then
there's the outreach area Nana got reach
education get involved resources mailing
list organizations within our community
tutorials fellowships news and stories
news and stories where you will find now
Naga in the news articles that have
found out in external publications that
referenced Nana or irrelevant to the
mountain our community and Nanog stories
will be our blog if you are have an
account a member and you're trying to
log in or you're participating at Nana
in terms of presentations here you'd
find the tools related to accessing your
your profile managing your membership
recover your account information and
related presentation tools and I'd like
to introduce our staff so I'd love to
have the Navajo come up onto stage I
want you guys chance to meet them all
they've all begged me not to do this
with and I promise them this will be a
one-time thing
I just think it's really important for
the community to get a chance to the
know the people who help make all these
meetings of reality
I'm missing someone but I will forgive
them
Valerie Witt cough she is our program
director Valerie works in conjunction
with the program community to make the
content in these meetings of reality she
works very hard she wears a lot of hats
and really really fortunate to have her
with us day Harvey is our meeting
director day Harvey is magical she puts
a ton of work into making these meetings
amazing and she's made me promise that I
won't make her talk so I will do that
for the time being and then we have in
our new additions to our staff because
now we've doubled we had three staff
members and now we have a whopping six
people when I first got here and I
realized that there were only three
people to make these meetings happen I
was just absolutely blown away I mean
these are huge undertakings and just you
know Betty Day and Val I just hats off
it was just so much to pull these things
off so we have some new people and first
of all we have brandy Herrera and brandy
is our senior content strategist I had
the fortune of knowing brandy for a
while before I had tried to get her to
join Nanog and at first she said no no
I'm not interested I don't think that's
gonna be fun no no no no no but now
she's here and you like your job
okay yeah yeah she's been charged yeah
it's fine
she's been in charge of our social media
helping to come up with rewriting all
the content on our website a lot of the
materials I think she's been doing an
amazing job and we're really fortunate
to have her aboard Sean Winstead Sean
Winstead is our business development
specialists Sean is not shy Sean will
talk to you she will reach out she's
very friendly and we're fortunate to
have her aboard Alissa had done a
wonderful job for Nanna
it was just a thought that we were we've
grown to such a size it'll be important
to have someone who worked for nanog who
was focusing on our our customers and
who was just that was her singular focus
and I will tell you this that woman
lives breathes and sleeps Nanog she's up
in the morning early and then I'm on the
West Coast she's on the East Coast I'm
talking her at 7 p.m. on the West Coast
Shaun is the Energizer Bunny always
going and we're fortunate to have her
and then we have Lee Brooks Lee Brooks
is our senior designer and I'm just
really thrilled to have the combination
of people that I have here I'm also a
designer so it was kind of I was always
kind of worried what would it be like me
picking someone who's gonna be a
designer and I am thrilled to have Lee
aboard we think really well we get along
really well so it just all kind of works
magical so here's a team here's the
people that make this happen I want to
give a chance for a little bit of QA
anything you guys want to talk about the
mics were open come up and we're gonna
try to answer anything you can Edward -
thank you - and thank you to the staff
up there I think one of the questions
that came up this morning over breakfast
which i think is really good for us to
talk about is right now we have a
two-tier structure with men are we have
members then we have non-members and at
the start of the meeting we had a slide
that said hey we've got 300 and some
members we've got 300 and some
first-time attendees and then there's
the rest of you unwashed masses that
just show up my question to you and the
rest of the community is is there still
a purpose to maintaining a two-tier
structure of saying hey there's members
who are special and they get special
member bacon in the breakfast but then
there's everybody else who shows up to
these meetings why not open up the
participation - everybody who attends
the meeting why not make it so that if
you're here you can vote for board
members you can participate you have an
equal say rather than continuing this
kind of casts partner well first of all
that would be I appreciate your comments
that would be a bylaw change okay and
the reason why we're having the
community meetings is because I think
it's important that the entire community
is a is informed and I'm looking for
feedback from the entire community as we
kind of go forward I have known kind of
personal views about membership but I'll
just kind of keep that to myself but I
think it's really critical that we we
include everyone and that's why we're
having these community meetings yes hi
Patrick Gilmore board member and one of
the people who started the two-tier
system just so that we're here to be a
501 C 3 and the way we did it there's
lots of ways to do it by the way we did
it requires a Membership class now that
class doesn't have to be restrictive or
whatever we made it a hundred dollars
and then we gave you 25 dollars off of
thing trying to make it pretty much as
easy as possible etcetera etcetera we
could look at redoing how membership is
defined and their different ways of
doing it but we need a membership
legally or at least that was the legal
advice when we broke from merit a long
time ago so yeah we need members but
maybe we just bump the registration fee
and make everybody who attends a member
but then that would leave people out
from the mailing list etcetera etcetera
so there's this is a very long
conversation and I don't think we should
have it right here but just realize that
we actually did think about it and the
membership is strictly things like you
know you to get some perks but it's
mostly to create the 501c3 have voting
rights and things like that if you come
here if you're an attendee there's no
limits on you know attending any of
those sessions or anything like that
based on whether you remember or not
Thank You Patrick
yes my name is mercy oh no I'm a student
at Ball State University yeah my
question is is nano membership strictly
for professionals is the open to student
and it's open to anyone yes
so your grandmother could be a member of
not any other questions all right Sean
Kennedy and I'm an anti volunteer
that's my only affiliation right now so
great job on the hotel I particularly
like the atrium there's a lot of spaces
to meet and talk the open seating area
has been very valuable can you talk a
little bit maybe two to five minutes
about how you select hotels some of the
cities we're going to I realize you
don't have the slides in front and how
far in advance does nanog plan location
sizing so on okay well we plan in that
and advances you can hold your fingers
up it's on you know at the top yeah two
years advance we're right now we're
three years out and we based upon a
criteria of first of all I'm very clear
to the membership we don't want to be in
convention spaces so that means we have
to find hotels which are large enough to
accommodate a group this size so a lot
of the restrictions come in in the size
of the events the rooms that are
available and that restricts us we also
try to it's a rotation every yeah Ward
another conference meetings which are in
our space such as IETF or MOG even
though we did collide with MOG this year
so that people who travel to a series of
events they can go to the events without
thinking oh I've got to choose between
nanog and going to IETF meeting the
Canadian rotation is yeah Canada every
three years again as part of North
America and the meetings up in the queue
we're gonna be in DC is our next meeting
Austin is after that back here in San
Francisco so I'm sorry Boston because
she's got to list my cheat sheet she
knows it in her head but I'm gonna be
kind to her so it's in Washington DC
Austin San Francisco Boston Seattle
Atlanta Minneapolis
than Toronto but again the biggest
restriction is the size of the actual
event I know you're not so another thing
I'm I think it's really well okay
so the other thing is this the
availability of meeting rooms because
many of the organizations that come here
want to have private meetings so we look
at the availability of private meeting
rooms and also the big ballrooms we need
a room like this and the you went to
beer and gear last night so we need a
room that can accommodate beer and gear
which is one of our most popular events
and then sometimes we've had to been in
spaces where we have a flipped the
ballroom for a beer and gear and I think
we have one event coming up who I have
to do that but we try to avoid that if
possible it's a lot of work for our
contractors to come in working all day
long I didn't happen to come in and turn
a room over and then come back have beer
and gear and then turn the room over in
the morning so we try to be kind any
other questions sorry a part of this is
to correct my oversight before my name
is Matt P Jack I forgot to introduce
myself thank you the first question
again Matt PTAC so in the past well the
questions that's come up is why three
times a year we do a joint meeting with
Erin in October which works out really
well
and and you're gonna tell me it's a
bylaw change right have we thought about
doing a pairing up and doing two
meetings a year or we just join up with
air and we do April and October instead
of three times a year good question this
is Patrick again I'm gonna take this
because Edward doesn't wasn't around
when we did this several times so
personally I think it should be twice
here and what we do is we survey the
membership every two three four years
and we say would you like to go to two
times a year
and the overwhelming majority say no
they want to keep it at 3 some of the
reasons given is that I can't go to
every meeting but if I if there's three
missing one isn't too bad if I miss one
of two that's worse some of the other
ones are you know from silly to I really
like to meet people for three times a
year because it fits my business needs
etc etc we do what the membership and
community in general wants this actually
was a survey of the entire nanog
community not just the membership maybe
things have changed maybe we should run
the survey again and ask but we've tried
to change the to before and just the
membership in the sorry the community
didn't want it yeah and again this is
the purpose of these community meetings
so you may chance to understand what
we're doing and then get feedback from
all of you straw poll who here wants two
types of beer raise your hand who wants
three times a year raise your hand no
two hands in the air
no I'm not asking for four again this is
the purpose of these to get raise your
hands you know let us know someone says
we want to do something we need feedback
all right I guess if there are no other
questions thank you for your time
appreciate it
oh no if there's more questions please
we got time
hi it's mike from yes net um just a
question to you guys cuz i know that
there's a we're kind of on a borderline
in terms of our attendance and there's a
very limited set of hotels we can use if
we went to two meetings a year would
that have implications for that as well
in terms of make it harder for us to go
to second-tier cities and make it harder
for us to find hotel most definitely
most definitely and there's also the
option of a hybrid where you have two
large anchor meetings a year then a
smaller one that's in a you know second
or third-tier soon thanks hmm all right
if nothing else thank you all for your
time
[Applause]
you