Thanks ok this morn I'm going to talk
about a tool that we're building at MIT
that's hopefully going to be making some
of your lives easier soon so I don't I
don't need to go into a detailed
explanation here but the bottom line
which I'm sure you're all aware is you
know because of the highly flexible
configurable nature of BGP we think that
bgp in addition to being viewed as a
network protocol should also be viewed
someone is a distributed program and
this type of you suggest that we need
practical verification techniques to
verify that once you've got your router
is configured or your program written
when you turn all those routers on
everything's going to go as planned so
again you probably know this slide
better than I do but let me just
describe to you my perception of the
state of the art as far as configuration
debugging right so operator decides that
he wants to make some sort of change
tweakin IGP policy route map etc at a
customer makes that configuration change
that configuration changes their logs
sort of a CBS stiffing style tool
similar to those that were described
yesterday everything seems fine you know
sometime later you know some strange
behavior might might appear and that
that behavior might be hard to link to
the to any particular change that was
made so the reasoning process that that
transpires is something like well when
did this problem start showing up let's
try to roll back the configuration to
the time you know before we started
seeing that problem sort of revert the
configuration hope the problem goes away
and and and you know continue tweaking
right so imagine if you had to write C
or pearl or anything like this right be
hard to actually get anything done and I
and I would argue that this is this is
not an appropriate programming
environment for operators it's it's ad
hoc it's painful waste a lot of time and
people get angry while you're while
you're doing these types of tweaks the
other point that I want to highlight is
that type of error checking where you
make a change and then see if
everything's all right at the particular
time is is is not really optimal right a
problem could show up a problem could
could appear much later than at the time
at which the configuration changes made
right a failure could happen at some
point later and cause some that's not
something to go wrong that was not
apparent at the time of the original
configuration change right so you want
it you you want to have some sort of
tool that tells you at the time you make
the change you know this type of problem
is likely to happen at some point in the
future or you know warning you know the
change that you made is not really a
recommended change to make your life
happy in the future so we're looking at
building a tool that does a little
better better job of verifying what we
call configuration correctness and I'm
going to talk a little bit more about
what i mean by correctness and by all
means I'm open to feedback here I'm just
going to throw out some ideas and you
know you may have some ideas things that
you know that you consider to be correct
behavior and and I'm definitely open to
feedback there but but I've got some
ideas that I'll describe and I and I
define correctness in terms of these
correctness properties so when you talk
about verifying configuration
correctness you want to verify it in
terms you know systematically in terms
of you know some set of properties you
know I've got a configuration is
property a satisfy this property be
satisfied etc then how do you go about
verifying whether your configuration
satisfies this property's well you
figure out the aspects of configuration
that could affect those properties and
then say you know do those configuration
commands on these routers satisfy that
the particular set of constraints that
I've set up for that property now you
can talk about configuration in a number
of ways you could talk about you know
how I got this particular router
configured properly have I got this set
of routers in my autonomous system
configured properly are Maya
are the routers of my autonomous system
going to play nice with routers and
other autonomous systems etc and we
haven't fully considered all those
questions in particular things that
involve configuration across multiple a
esas those are questions that we haven't
figured out what to do about but in
particular the tool that we've built
thus far and then problems that we're
focusing on our configuration problems
that go go wrong inside one autonomous
system and and I'll give some examples
in a minute but so what this talk is
really about is it's thinking thinking
about ways to a reason at a higher level
about what goes wrong in configuration
and then building a tool that's based
around that that reasoning framework so
that's really the first point let's take
a set of existing configuration router
configurations and verify that certain
properties hold so i should mention that
the tool that we've implemented so far
is meant to sort of chomp on cisco iOS
configuration it can be extended to two
you know other existing vendors but also
let's say that we have a completely new
configuration language this type of this
type of tool is always going to be
necessary right you're you're always
going to want to be able to chomp on
configuration files and say you know
I've got you know this property
satisfied or I've got that property
satisfied so no matter what
configuration language comes along we're
always going to want some sort of you
know higher-level validation that what
we're doing makes sense in second
something that we're thinking about that
I'm not going to really talk about a lot
in this talk but that I'm going to sort
of wax philosophical about at the end is
that you know a lot of verifying
correctness of router configuration
depends on verifying that what I've got
configured in reality jives with the
intended behavior of what I want to
actually have happen and in order to
verify that that's going on I have to
have some way of specifying that this is
my intended behavior um so the insight
there is once that I've specified this
intended behavior why don't I use that
specification of the intended behavior
to actually be the router configuration
so talk a little bit more about that at
the end but mostly I want to talk about
how our verification tool works um so
let's just sort of first get a little
more concrete right so um talking about
configuration talking about correctness
properties let me just talk about one
that I call information flow control um
and let's you know let's sort of examine
a very simple rule let's say autonomous
system be you know is hearing rounds
from see one of its peers and wants to
make sure that those routes aren't we
advertised to a well how does this
happen today I would argue that the way
we do this today is is really not the
way we want to be doing things and it's
very error-prone right what's going on
is you've got a high-level policy don't
advertise the routes I hear from one
period to another peer and i'm
specifying that policy in terms of a
mechanism a route comes in tag it with
this community you know really advertise
it to these routers etc it goes over to
this router you know if the route has a
particular community don't riad ver ties
it right so there are a number of things
that could go wrong there right I could
specify the wrong route map I could
forget to define the community list I
could tag the route with the wrong
community etc and they're all sorts of
things that could go wrong I mean these
are the types of things that we want to
check at a higher level right at the end
of the day is the route from C going to
be riad ver ties to a and there are all
sorts of they're all sorts of tricks
that people try to play that fit into
this sort of property that I call
information flow control things like
partial peering or prefix propagation
conditional announcements etc you want
to make sure that when your routes are
coming in being manipulated a certain
way passed on to other routers and
eventually sent on to other autonomous
systems that things are being passed on
in the way that you expect them to be
passed on okay so in addition to
information flow control we've got a
whole bunch of properties that that that
we suggest our things that fall into the
realm of correctness properties so I'm
not going to be labor these points on
but I just want to illustrate that these
are sort of the five areas that we've
sort of highlighted as
kind of important things we're routing
configuration can go wrong and I've
listed underneath each point examples of
you know configuration mistakes or
conceptual misunderstandings that can
cause each one of these types of
properties to be violated so the idea is
when when we when we're writing our
configuration checker and as we as we've
developed it so far we keep these
properties in mind and try to figure out
okay let's say I want to write a check
to you know to make sure that validity
your visibility is violated you know
what types of things affect these
properties and how can we write rules
that make sure that that these prep that
allow us to say whether or not property
a is satisfied or is not satisfied okay
so the rest of the talk i'm going to
talk about the tool that's sort of
motivated around this reasoning
framework which we call rolex and if the
lawyers come after us it'll probably be
renamed to MIT project rolex but let me
just sort of describe to you what we
have so far and then later on in the
talk i'm going to describe to you things
we're thinking about developing for the
tool and as you see at the bottom of the
slide there there's a URL you can visit
you can send us feedback that's one of
the reasons I'm here actually is to try
to get feedback on what types of you
know checks you think are important
features bugs try it out etc but for the
rest of the talk I'm just going to talk
about what we have today and what you
know what you can download today and and
that's that's actually what I've shown
here basically the tools thus far is a
tool and two parts and the first part is
something we call pattern based
constraint checker and if you if you're
familiar with things like yak or or
anything like that that sort of matches
on patterns and then sort of execute a
finite state machine to figure out you
know what state the configurations in at
any particular point that's kind of what
the pattern based constraint checker is
and I'll describe that a little more
detail
in a bit and then the other piece is
basically working towards that sort of
talking about information flow and
things like that the example that I
described before basically you want to
get some high-level representation of
what's going on in the network and the
control flow analyzers basically just a
way of sort of browsing what you know
what's going on in the network who's
connected to who what route map do I
have configured on this router etc okay
so let's talk about this pattern based
rule checker first as far as using it
it's it's very easy it's just as simple
as running the script I've included I've
included a couple examples for the
script in the distribution I mean
basically what happens is you run on
this you run on you run the script oh I
should say also that the tool is
designed to chomp on the configurations
offline maybe you could combine it with
some of the functionality that's you
know some of the tools that were
described yesterday to run it online but
basically thus far I've designed it to
chomp on offline configs okay so you run
this script you know it's it grinds away
and then gives you gives you some errors
I should mention that the way the way
that we've designed the rules is you can
kind of write them in a way that kind of
makes sense that says if I've got a
router if I've got a router here and our
router there I want to make sure that
the constraints between these two
routers are you know are satisfied and
it's very easy to write rules that are
distributed across across multiple
routers and I'll show you an example of
that so here's three examples i'm going
to describe each one of them to you in
turn the first i sort of throw in the
category of validity and what this rule
what this the output of this this rule
this test is showing is based on a rule
that that has to do with the next-hop
self setting so what this rule says in
English is if I've got an ebgp session
that session should either have next-hop
self set or the IP address of the loop
back on the other side should be
injected into my igp right so the reason
I throw that in validity is obvious
right if you have neither of those cases
then you've got to route somewhere
inside your is where
Robert doesn't know how to get to the
next top so that's bad I should also say
that these examples are there based on
reality but I fictionalized you know
router names and a s numbers and IP
addresses to protect the innocent okay
so as you can see sort of the output you
know you run the this particular test
and you see that you know this
particular gateway in Atlanta has an EVP
session you know next-hop self wasn't
set oh and here we've got an error
because the the loopback address that's
on the other side of that session was
not injected into the igp so then the
next step that output of the next test
that I've shown I throw into this
visibility category right so do I have a
is there a path but for some reason the
BGP route is not being advertised right
so what this what this test says is if
I've got a router that's trying to it's
got a BGP neighbor statement to some
other router let's make sure that and
that's an and that's an ibgp session
let's make sure that somewhere in my
configs I've got a router configured
with the loop back of that router the IP
address that the neighbors that
corresponds to that neighbor statement
so first three lines show cases where
you know for example you know there's a
router in Boston that's that's trying to
that's got a neighbor statement with
this particular IP address but I can't
find any router inside my autonomous
system that has the loopback address set
to this IP address etc and then the test
cranks away and it also finds finds
other things you know the last line
there shows for example that I found a
router where there was no bgp statement
said at all maybe that's good maybe
that's bad but it's at least something
you should know about right perhaps it
violates some assumptions and then there
are things that I would throw into this
determinism category you know is
deterministic med set is a best path
prepare router ID set etc and the output
at the on the third test their shows
sort of you know what would come out for
running that test okay so let me let me
just describe some details for your inch
you know for those of you who are
interested in how this pattern based
checker actually works as I mentioned
it's kind of based around this sort of
yak model where you match on a
particular pattern and then go into a
particular state depending on you know
depending on what patterns I've seen and
as I mentioned it's easy to spread this
across routers in an autonomous system
so it may be difficult to read there but
basically the at you know the fsm starts
at the top and it looks for any you know
r1 will basically match on any router
looking for a router bgp statement with
a particular autonomous system number
that will match John EAS number and then
a neighbor statement with an IP address
and remote is once I've matched on that
statement I you know I find that I bind
the loose variables and say I've got a
you know on router in LA I've got a
router bgp you know 701 I've neighbor
whatever remote is whatever and then I
and then I go through the graph and sort
of figure out what state you're in and
then you know at particular points you
can sort of hop off and you know either
say okay this configurations you know
for this particular router it's instead
of routers is okay or it's not okay so
how do you actually specify one of these
these fsms well I've in the tool itself
I've I've I've given a bunch of examples
but presumably you know they're going to
be a lot of examples that I didn't think
of or I'm just not aware of because I
don't you know I don't configure routers
on a daily basis so I try to make
specifying these types of rules
particularly easy so this rule that I
described with the next top self and
making sure the igp the the IP address
is injected into the igp etc was the fsm
that I showed you on the previous slide
and that's that can be written in sort
of the it's basically written as a perl
module and what what the tool does is
provide the finite state machinery and
all you have to do is sort of write the
transitions or or all i have to do
rather so basically what what this 41
lines of code does is basically just
spec out what that fsm looks like what
are the notes what are the transitions
etc so this is this is the one that I
sort of shown
from the previous slide and I'm in a
particular state if I match on a
particular pattern go to this state I
mean it's it's it's that easy um and as
I mentioned you know there are things
that I you know that I haven't thought
of that you you know probably encounter
on a daily basis and that's the type of
feedback I'm looking for here these are
the rules that you should have or you
know if you feel so inclined to write
you know write some of these rules
yourself I'd be really happy and I've
tried to make that easy so let me just
briefly talk about the second part which
I call the control flow analyzer and
we're not to the point of actually
checking high level properties here but
i think that the tool as it stands is
actually something that's pretty useful
basically what it does is chop on router
configs and give a high level summary of
what of what the network state is at a
particular time so it's got a number of
features one is it is it allows you to
to sort of graph the network at a router
level and then it the nodes are
basically routers and the edges or
import and export route maps labeled
with some canonical number so that you
know seven here is the same as you know
seven on that edge and when I say route
maps 7 i'm speaking of some
normalization of what that route map
actually does not what it's called so if
you've got a route map called customer
on a New York router and a route map
called customer on an LA router but they
actually do two separate things i'll
call that two separate route maps so
this is sort of a sort of a again I've
sort of anonymized a way things to
protect the innocent but this is sort of
a snapshot of just a little piece of
what that network graph looks like and
it's probably more useful for for
smaller types of networks for larger
types of networks you want to use let me
just go back you want to probably use
the second the second part which is this
database backed web interface so what
this does is sort of chops on the router
configs throws everything into a
database and then allows you to sort of
browse that's going on it from the web
and i'm going to show you just a brief
example of the things that you can do
with it with the tool as it stands so
for example you can look at all that all
the routers that
I'm sorry all the bgp sessions at a
particular router so you can say give me
give me the bgp sessions at this gateway
router in LA and I'll say oh you've got
you know two sessions to a particular is
and here are the import and export route
maps that you're using on those sessions
and again the palace the route map
numbers are normalized based on on what
they do not what they're called okay so
other things that you can do is sort of
look at you know the number of sessions
that you've got your particular
autonomous systems you know we've got
force for bgp sessions off to 1239 let's
see let's see what those are right so
you know click down drill down and see
what those four sessions are you can see
I've got bgp sessions to 1239 it at
these four routers and these are the
import and export route maps that I'm
looking at so one thing that I want to
highlight here is that it's pretty easy
to see you know differences of you know
I treat the incoming routes particular
wave at three places but I treat them a
slightly different way at a third plate
at are at a fourth place so with the
tool that allows you to do is say hmm
well that looks different let's let's
sort of see what's going on so with it
you sort of click down on that and you
and you see you know what these two
route maps actually are and then what it
does what the tool does is provide you a
diff that says you know here's the
here's the sort of difference between
these two routes um so this slide maybe
may be hard to read even if you can't
see you may not understand what's going
on but as I mentioned I've normalized
the route maps away from what they're
called us to actually what they do so
basically what I've done is you know
dereference community lists dereference
basically dereferenced everything and
sort of said you know this is this is
actually the mechanism of what the route
map does and then actually run the diff
on on those two on those two
specifications um so you saw some tools
that did config diff yesterday and I
just want to highlight what the
difference is here right so yesterday
they were talking about configuration
dips in terms of time right I make a
change at a particular time and I want
to see the difference between you know
what my what my route matter what my
configurations look like to
day versus what they look like five days
ago this is not that this is I've got a
configuration on a router in LA and I've
got a configuration on a router in New
York and I want to see what the
difference is okay so that sort of
summarizes what you can do today with
the tool and I just want to briefly just
wax philosophical about sort of things
that we're thinking about what you might
eventually want to do so let's imagine
what you do if you take that sort of
high-level Network summary like this is
your 10,000 foot view of the network
let's actually figure out if we can run
some constraints or verify properties
based on that so if you had some way of
specifying you know this is what should
be going on don't riad ver ties the
routes that I hear from pearcy over to
puree let's sort of match that up with
the high-level description of what's
going on and see if that actually
matches up with reality so going back to
our example right as i mentioned
specifying the policy with mechanism is
complicated and it's hard to get right
but how do we actually tell whether this
is doing the right thing or not well we
need some sort of specification of what
should be happening and I think that's a
key challenge and that's something we
haven't really figured out one thing
that's tricky right is you know it's
easy to say you've got peer a and you've
got pure see and you don't want the
routes from puree going over to pearcy
and you can sort of specify that with
with you know information flow lattices
etc but it's probably more complicated
than than that or at least I think it's
more complicated than that you should
maybe tell me if I'm wrong but you know
you may want to treat things differently
based on you know what the a s path is
what the prefix is it you know what
router it's coming in on etc etc and if
you get to the point where specifying a
high-level property is as complicated as
specifying the configuration itself then
you're in trouble so the real question
is how do we make the configuration
specification as simple as possible so
that we can check whether these
low-level things are actually happening
I mean that we can actually make it
easier for network operators to you know
say what they mean rather than say what
they want to happen when a route comes
in at a particular router and goes out
router so just to summarize with the
what the control flow analyzer does it
basically just provides a bird's eye
view of the network and allows operators
to view what's going on in terms of
where my EBT piece or where my bgp
sessions are what route maps i'm using
where etc and it's fairly navigable um
there's some other things you can do as
far as restricting what shows up etc and
there's some things that we want to add
sort of immediately one is you know it
would be it would be natural to use this
type of thing to ask a question what
happens if I get a route advertised on a
particular session at a particular
router where does that route propagate
to what attributes get manipulated and
where does it pop out what what ebgp
sessions does it come out on for example
okay so as I mentioned you know once you
have this specification it's natural to
say let's not only going to use a
specification to check existing
configurations but why don't we just use
this high level specification as the
router configuration language itself so
as I mentioned that the first set of
questions sort of gets at this problem
right we want to make something that's
you know simple for people to express
what they mean yet allows for enough
enough detail so that you can actually
do what you want without without getting
burdened with the same type of
complexity okay so finally I just want
to thank a couple of people who have
provided me with with many helpful
insights on this work Jennifer rexburg
from AT&T and also a Randy Bush gave me
some advice that hopefully made this
talk a little more interesting for you
guys if it wasn't interesting maybe
maybe you can throw some of the blame on
him too right and finally I just want to
say that I think we've got a symbiotic
relationship here right it seems to me
that you've got a problem as far as you
know router configuration causing you a
lot of headaches and I've got a problem
and that's you know I've still at MIT
and I'd like to leave eventually so
let's work together you give me some you
know feedback as far as you know what
would be useful in a tool like this what
types of problems are real what types of
things do you want what
you know how can I make your life easier
download that's download the tool you
know test it out or if you want me to
test it out on your stuff I'd be more
than happy to do that I'm more than
happy to you know write tests that you
think would be helpful for your network
I'm an expendable resource at this point
I'm a grad student so I've got time on
my hands just let me know what I can do
to help you and thanks for listening I
actually have a question I didn't think
I'd have questions today but I do in my
experience which you know God knows I
don't run a network anymore but in my
experience I I named route maps things
on purpose and so to have a tool that
took those names away and called him
something else even if they didn't do
the same thing would would make them
somewhat meaningless to me so is there a
way or have you thought about
incorporating both so so maybe I have 52
route maps thats a customer and to me
customers an important thing and they
might do different things and it might
be useful to know they do different
things but it might also be useful for
me to understand that those are all the
customer route maps yeah i think that's
that's something that would be easy to
add yeah that's the type of thing that
you know is helpful for us to know the
thing the the reason that that I was
motivated to do it this way is that my
hypothesis is that you know occasionally
you know you've got sort of a
cut-and-paste type of thing where you
know I've got a customer route map I'll
just copy this one and then at some
point you know maybe I do some load
balancing I make a little tweak and you
know five months later i come back and
they they appear to be called the same
thing you know especially if i'm looking
at a name you know five neighbor
statements or something where they also
a customer customer you know i look at a
different router and I've got customer
there and you know I might assume that
that's the same thing but you know I
think that it's important to see that
it's not
but I do i do agree that you know
something that also allows us yeah
bollywood alone it would be great yeah
but that was that was my motivation yeah
oh I makes total sense but it would be
nice to have both because then you could
reconcile what you intended with what
you have yeah yeah definitely in the
front okay I Owen DeLong tellme networks
your rule-based parser or I forget what
you called it at the beginning but is
playing where you feed the set of rules
in and you feed the config in and it
sort of tries to do pattern matching
between them right the the rules that
you have to feed into that or the
patterns that you have to feed into that
is there any possibility of perhaps
generating those from our psl or
something similar that's the best good
idea actually and I hadn't thought about
that actually in fact one thing that I
didn't mention that that is kind of a
problem with that is the sort of manual
nature of having to write those
specifications and that's a big pain in
the neck right so I've thought about
ways where maybe you can kind of infer
some of these rules like let's say
you've got you know let's say you've got
it some sort of configuration option
that's turned on on 98 routers and it's
off on to maybe you could say that the
you know let's call that a rule that
says you know this this thing should be
turned on in this particular way that's
another way I've thought about doing
this but but using our psl to generate
rules is also a great idea yeah because
we're already having to go through that
pain at least some of us the other
question I had is currently it looks
like you're primarily parsing iOS
configs that's correct is there any and
it looks like as you parse those you're
sort of abstracting them as the first
step before you do anything else with
them that's correct yet trying to get
Lou it would be nice if we could sort of
separate that adaptation layer so that
and you know open that process up so
that would be easy for you and also for
other people to build sort of module
that would allow you to parse other
vendors configs yeah that would be
excellent um yeah as i mentioned i think
i think what we're trying to do is
independent of any router configuration
language so that yeah that's definitely
a point that i'd like to get to and
hopefully someone else will write you
know config parsers for other languages
because there's only one of me but yeah
getting to that point would definitely
make make that a lot easier so yeah
that's a great suggestion thanks Dave I
just had to kind of take questions on
another questions or comments I just
wrote down some and some of them kind of
been covered but one of the things that
I've noticed is that we have some tools
that are kind of syntactically based
like rancid right and then we have
weight something like what you're trying
to do which is trying to bring some kind
of understanding of the semantics of
what these things are trying to do right
to management of configs right so are we
on a track where we're going to have a
proliferation of tools or are these
things is there a place where these
things can come together so that you
know I have a kind of a unified
management of my config space that was
one thing kind of a thought I had while
you were talking and the other one was
on and I think I only mentioned this is
that your trip you know you're
developing metal language for router
configuration and we've talked about
this over the years millions and
millions of times and we tried to do it
with our psl and you can argue up and
down whether or not our psl failed or
succeeded or whatever maybe it was too
ambitious to try to put the database
thing there or whatever I don't know but
is that where this is all going that um
we think that our vendors are going to
supply us um a language like you know
maybe ansi standardized router language
or something like that I you know I
don't care who does it I mean but I you
know what I'm saying you know some kind
of standardized router i mostly currency
so you know some kind of standardized
router language that they all speak the
same thing and if they and if we do that
then how do i mean i'm just trying to
see how that fits into the space of what
vendors do which is try to kind of
distinguish themselves by value-added
while at the same time being
interoperable so I was just interested
in what you thought the direct
there was so first question first about
rancid and things so actually I think
these tools are fairly complimentary and
actually might rather than proliferating
I mean eventually it might make sense to
think about one tool that does all these
things I mean you think about what what
rancid does and it's got a lot of I mean
it tries to tackle a lot of problems
that are definitely very necessary but
it's things that we aren't looking at at
all like you know doing mass
configuration you know looking at route
map tips over time like the whole CBS
thing and looking at differences that's
all very useful and that's that stuff
that we're not looking at it at all but
you can imagine combining you know
things like what rancid does with things
things like what our tool does which is
you know you know now I've made a change
you know I you know chomp on it with
with a tool like mine you figure out you
know oh you're likely to have a certain
problem and then well let's see what
we've done you know let's see what this
looked like in the past exactly just
what many of us do is we have you know
crying scripts that run against our
routers so that or a rancid thing and so
at some point it says hey this realm
have changed but that's all you know
right right go anger out what that dude
right right right so I mean so I
recognize that that's you know something
that you want and I think something that
you also want is is something that
actually explains you know this change
and it's likely to cause x y&z to go
wrong so that's where I think you know
the two tools together could actually be
quite useful oh so as far as the second
question with with configuration
languages yeah so I'm I guess yeah I'm
not sure exactly what all what all i
should say there except that i think you
know i want to take the position that
yeah specifying specifying your policy
in terms of you know what the router
should do in terms of when a router
arrives and
you know import-export policies etc and
actually the mechanism of how a route is
manipulated I think that you know we
should be moving towards actually
specifying the policy in terms of the
policy and not in terms of the mechanism
and yeah so I'm I'm trying to you know
get people's attention on that and and
we'll see how far that goes that that's
all I wanna say Ruettiger okay will you
go thought you did ago well okay I have
two points one is I'm not quite sure how
close you are actually to getting to
some common router language even the
terms you are describing your tools in
terms of not grammars but patterns kind
of kind of hints me that well okay
getting having having actually an
abstract model of what you're dealing
with which could be mapped into a
language for describing ruler
configurations on well okay I i I'm
asking aha I are you doing something
there or are you just abstracting from
what you're seeing on a particular
window and when the next one comes up
you have to reach roof it and while okay
okay so i think there's so in my view
there's there's two things that are
going on one is you've got you've got
kind of what's happening in reality
right these you know these are the
routers that are in your is this is
what's going to happen when a particular
you know route consonants can be read
advertised here here and here it's going
you know local press can be manipulated
med etc right so that's you know you
want to sort of view that a high level
away from you know what the cisco iOS
looks like what the juniper looks like
etc so that's one thing i think you're
always going to want to do that
independent of you know whatever the
language is right you know no no matter
what's a storage unit or whatever
decides to do in the future you're
always going to want to be able to sort
of view at a high level what's going on
in terms of where my routes going
how am i treating this particular AAS in
terms of you know how am i treating its
routes at these different locations etc
so that I think that's always going to
be useful now there's a separate
question you can ask there right so
that's sort of like a representation of
what's going on and now I want to ask
you know does that representation agree
with what I think I want to have happen
so then you can ask you know how so how
do I actually specify what I want to
have happen and that's sort of a
language question and something that I
don't have good answers to right now but
I think it's something that that we
should be thinking about I mean I and to
sort of get back to the previous
question about our psl when you look at
our psl and it's still sort of very
mechanism-based right and I'm guess I'm
sort of advocating you know independent
of the mechanism if we could have a way
where you know you could actually say
what you meant to have happen in a way
that's actually simpler than you know I
want to prepend this thing out 10 times
or you know I want to assign this
community that's not actually what you
want to do that's just sort of
describing how you want to get it done
yes well okay I'm good at some work off
that dummy but look wait that's it let's
let's do the second one offline sorry
but we are running late yeah thanks
thank you