okay good morning my name is Thomas fees
fees i'm going to give you an update on
fast IGP conversions so let's first
define conversions we have a traffic
stream going from source to destination
via the green path so there at a certain
time t1 there going to be a link failure
along the green path so at time t1 the
loss of connectivity starts at time t2
an alternate end-to-end path exists from
source to destination at time T to the
loss of connectivity stops we define
convergence as t2 minus t1 this as the
loss of connectivity duration we're
going to analyze convergence for IGP
learn it prefixes and we are going also
to analyze the impact of igp convergence
on bgp learn it prefixes common sense
typically says that I GP conversions
takes from 10 to 30 seconds the
objective we set for ourselves with this
project was to achieve sub-second
convergence for the first 500 IGP
prefixes and for the BGP prefixes that
recurs on them assuming obviously no bgp
flaps this presentation is given with is
is we have work on Isis and ospf and the
principle applies for both I GPS here is
our black box lab set up the unit on the
test is the Dorado with the yellow dots
it's a 12,400 router which will be
equipped with two types of processors
either a grp or PRP one and the line
cards I Engine 2 engine 3 or engine folk
blues the router is running running a
pre-release version of 12 dot or 27 s
we're going to test convergence in the
bottom in in the top to bottom direction
it mean so what I'm going to do is to
send traffic from A to B and I'm going
to cause a link failure so triggering
convergence I send 10,000 packets per
second on each stream so if i count a
number
bucket drops I can derive the loss of
connectivity duration / stream the
granularity is zero that one
milliseconds so I'm sending my traffic
from A to B the cloud that is faking a
realistic ASA's topology is situated at
the bottom of the picture it's a cloud
worth 1000 is is node and 2500 is is
prefixes as you can see it's a
worst-case scenario because when I'm
going to fail the link from the unit
under test a few points all the cloud is
impacted so it means a full SPT will be
required also I inject 160,000 bgp
prefixes in the in the lab setup i'm
actually sending 15 streams from A to B
12 streams going to IGP destination and
then three streams for bgp analyzes the
12th creams ygp destination are going to
prefix number one prefix number 250
prefix number 500 and so on up to 2500
this allows to monitor the convergence
as a function of where you are in the
modification list the prefix treat the
stream number 13 is going to build a BGP
next up the streams number 14 and 15 are
going to two bgp destination so prefixes
learn as bgp destination that recurs on
the bgp next up in stream number 13 for
each of the streams we sending 10,000
packets per second the lab setup is
convenient because I can test for four
scenarios if I fail this link or if I
fail this link I have respectively a
local or remote failure and then
depending if I set this to 200 or 300
before the the conversions
experimentation I have load balancing or
notes so i will always analyze those
four scenarios for each scenarios we
will repeat the test 100 times so let us
look at the results for the
on the desk being equipped with a grp
processor and an engine to line card
yeah all the interface applause applause
so let us look at the results for a
remote failure no load balancing the
processor is a grp and the language is
an engine 2 plus the x axis gives you
the prefix position in the update list
you see the 12 is is streams and then
the three bgp streams just forget about
the three last points that for for the
beginning so the x axis is the prefix
position the y axis is the loss of
connectivity that was measured for each
test we repeat it 100 times so I'm
plotting three curve in dark blue it's
the minimum across 100 iteration for
each stream in ping it's the median and
in yellow it's the percentile 100 or the
other maximum so what you are seeing
here is that first the system is linear
the convergence process is linear the
initial delay is short on the order of
150 to 200 80 milliseconds the slope
which is coming from the prefix
dependent update it's much more
important than the initial delay the
initial delay is made of the link
failure detection the LSP origination
the LSP flooding and the shortest path
tree computation this represents 150 to
200 80 milliseconds here then the prefix
dependent process is going on that
updates the ribbon fifth tables and you
see that it's more expensive much more
expensive than actually all the other
components of convergence even that's
why we have introduced a prioritization
capability that allows the designer to
flag prefixes in the igp as being either
important on
important for the convergence and so the
important prefixes always converge first
that's why you see the red fig bar on
the bottom between zero and five hundred
because it it just to highlight that the
500 important prefixes always always
converged first it's important because
if you design and normally you design on
the basis of worst-case analyzes if
you're looking at the worst gas
conversions for your most important
prefixes you need to look at the yellow
dots for the for the point number 500
and this is much different to what you
should do if you would net would have
nope prioritization in which case you
would need to look here and you see that
the difference between the two is quite
important the next thing we learn from
this experiment is that the spread is
small so the spread is the difference
between the minimum and the maximum and
we try to work a lot on this to increase
the determinism of the convergence
behavior so finally we can look at the
BGP results the free last points the
first one to the left is the BGP next of
the two other points bgp are the loss of
connectivity measured to bgp destination
and what you see from here is that the
loss of connectivity for a bgp learn
prefix is actually the same as the loss
of connectivity to its bgp next up which
is learning the igp which means that the
bgp learned prefixes also leverage all
the optimization for the igp it's an
important result so here we summarize
all the test scenarios for the remote
versus local load balancing versus no
load balancing scenario so we have four
scenarios what we plot is the worst-case
across the 100 iteration the worst-case
loss of connectivity for prefix number
500 so it's the last important prefix
it's the worst case convert
measured for our important prefixes the
first three groups in in blue red and I
think yellow from here yeah basically
engine to engine 3 engine for place with
the grp processor you see that first
it's it's consistent whether you have a
remote or local failure whether you are
load balancing or not the convergence in
the worst case is measured at a run 400
milliseconds and then the second thing
we learned from from this short is that
the results if you take the PRP one with
engine three it's actually much smaller
on the order of 250 milliseconds so what
we derive from this is that cpu power is
very important the PRP one is twice
faster than the grp and you see the
consequence it's also an indication for
this for the future and what could
happen if the CPU power keeps on
increasing so as I said earlier it's
when you design you typically test and
look only on the worst case and it's
important to do it like this but it's
also important to look at the difference
between the average behavior in the
worst case so here it's for the engine
three combination with the PRP 1 100
iteration and you compare the blue curve
the blue results come with the yellow
results the blue one of the worst worst
case loss of connectivity measured for
the 500 important prefixes while the
yellow whistles give you the average
Convergence measured for the 500
prefixes and so it's it simply gives you
a an annex margin of safety margin when
compared to the sub second target so if
we come to that point the result seems
pretty pretty good and confirming the
sub seconds convergence behavior there
could be two questions that would arise
first it's basically to say
in your lab set up you you look at
different scenarios you you have bgp and
so on but you do not consider the
flooding impact because you don't have
many hubs also you do not consider the
fact that the routers could be spread
over a continent or multiple continents
actually those two points are negligible
and that's the purpose of the remaining
of the next slides first let us look at
the flooding impact we we take our unit
on the test define it as previously and
we add a load to it we add SNMP probe
and we add eight bgp flaps per second
the cpu on average is at 35 persons
utilization we connect the unit on the
test to to aging and device the first
one is standing on LSP and we measure
how long it takes for this LSP to be
flooded to the second agilent device we
repeat the test one one thousand times
and we plot the flooding time to hop on
the y-axis so we see that for ninety
percent of the measurements the flooding
time / hut is smaller or equal to 2
milliseconds the reason for this is that
it's important in the implementation of
the igp to make sure that you're going
to flood the important LSP before going
into SBT computation the other question
was related to the propagation distance
so intuitively it's quite a
straightforward to compute that this is
negligible but we still wanted to
analyze it in a more formal way to
confirm it so let's first define the
propagation distance so again there was
some animation but let's see what we
wanted to do we have initially a green a
strain going from left to right that
initially goes by at the green path at a
certain point of time the link between f
and z is going to fail so we will have a
convergence events and the traffic
stream will eventually be routed
according to the red path we define f as
the failing the failure node where it's
the note that is locally connected
the link that that is going down we
define the rerouting node as intuitively
it's easy to think that the rewriting
node is the point where the two paths
diverge it's the point where the
rewriting of yours and so let's see if
we define it like this we can define the
distance between the failure and the
rewriting point as here being one up and
being in terms of propagation between
the propagation through that link the
propagation is more or less 5
millisecond per thousand kilometer of
fiber actually if we would have time we
could show show that this intuitive
definition of our is actually a worse
case they exist better case for
rerouting no than this one so the
results that you will see our worst case
and we are recomputing them to have a
better analysis still the results
confirm the intuition so one of the lead
customers that work with us gave us the
topology it's a worldwide Tier one isp
they gave us the full well why topology
the full traffic metrics and we knew the
propagation distance between any two
rather so we fail we have failed the 340
most loaded links on the network and for
each failure scenario we have computed
the distance as previously define it we
have waited each of the distance as such
computed by the amount of traffic on
each flow as we knew the traffic metrics
and what you see be included here is
basically the results of all these
computation what did what it says is
that if I remember we're fifty persons
for fifty percent of the cases we have a
distance of zero up counts so it means
that when we have a failure we it's the
local note that will locally rear out
and we have four ninety-five percent of
the cases the hub count is smaller or
equal to 3 so it means that you really
don't need to flood very far and so the
hub count that influenced the flooding
time is very
more bounded by three four ninety-five
thousand of the cases we take the same
analyzes and we look at the propagation
distribution what we find out is that
seventy eight percent of the cases the
propagation distance is zero
milliseconds why because it's either
rewriting in the same note itself or its
a rewriting that occurs in the pub and
we find that many two persons of the
cases are going to have a distance to
the rewriting node which is smaller or
equal to 35 milliseconds so this
confirms that the flooding time if you
indeed flood well before you run SPF and
the propagation distance are negligible
and and so that the results that we
present it actually relevant so the
conclusion is that sub second
conversions for is is is realistic and
it's actually conservative and that the
technology has significantly improved so
the question that would arise now I
guess is why is it possible so the way
we work in our project is basically we
have optimized other all the components
that in that I involved in the
convergence behavior we don't have the
time here to explain all of this it
takes so typically one day but I'm going
to highlight a few key points that put
come to mine most frequently the first
one is dee dee is the link failure
detection time we leverage bus passes
but based on SONET and SDH which will
discover the failure in less than 10
milliseconds so it's a very fast failure
detection system and we leverage it the
only questions that that still is prison
is how long does it take for the
discovery of the failure to be
communicated from the adware that is
going to detect it very fast to actually
to the CPU where
is is is going to be triggered for its
conversions so we actually did this test
and this is her unit under test equipped
with an engine to pass line card again
it's the same configuration with SNMP
load and a bgp flaps per seconds the
average CPU time was 35 persons we
repeat the test 1,000 times and we have
we measured the time the time between
when the other way on the LAN card finds
the failure and when on the processor
the ISS conversions is triggered we find
that in ninety percent of the case the
time between the two events is smaller
than eight milliseconds model or equal
to 8 milliseconds so overall you would
have up to 10 milliseconds to discover
the failure in the Senate as the edge
layer plus on the order of eight
milliseconds to communicate it to the
processor now a question that could
arise here but also for the flooding
time / hobbies what is the reason for
the rare points or the rare measurements
we're actually the detection time or the
flooding time is actually larger so why
what is the reason for this and is it
important so the first the first
question the reason for this is that the
worst case is going to be on the order
of 50 milliseconds why the worst case
would happen if you would have a process
of the same priority as is is that is
scheduled on the cpu just before the
convergence even occur and then on top
of that condition you would need that
the process that be scheduled is
actually a very busy process that would
have to keep the cpu for 50 milliseconds
for its allocated time start so it's
rare by itself and this is you can see
it in the distribution here the worst
cases is very rare but the next question
that could the next question it thanks
the next question is is it it is it
important and the answer is no for from
for multiple reasons the first reason is
that first it does not occur free
only seconds 50 milliseconds is 20 times
smaller than the objective that is one
second third in reality in an IP network
it will happen even less likely than in
these measurements reason is that for a
failure detection to actually show this
a detection time larger than eight
milliseconds it would need to occur at
the same time on the two routers
connected to the link failure and for
the flooding it's seven worse because of
the meshing of an IP network you have
many flooding path between the failure
node and the rerouting node so for the
worst case to occur you would need to be
extremely unlikely because it would need
to appear for the same LSB on all the
notes across all the possible flooding
path so for for these three reasons I
think that these rare points are not so
important and anyway it's 20 times
smaller than the target which is the
second the next topic that would be
discus most likely if we talked about
convergence is shortest path tree
computation how long does it take to to
compute the extra the deck for
implementation normally is in n log n we
we connect our unit and the test to a
cloud where we control the size and we
measure the time it takes to to compute
the shortest path tree for the full
cloud we find out that actually the
relationship between the the SPT
duration and the number of nodes is
pretty linear for the PRP one it's on
the order of 59 microsecond per node it
means that if you have a topology of 600
notes you will compute your full SBT in
35 milliseconds so this is with a PRP
one if you remember one of the first
slide where we had an initial delay on
the order of 150 to 200 18-minute second
it was with the grp and with a cloud of
1000 notes so the grp is twice lower and
1,000 not it means that the SPT
computation in
case was 100 milliseconds and and so it
confirms the reason why you have such a
small initial delay now again if you
have a topology of 600 nodes running on
PRP one and you do a full SPT it's 35
milliseconds but actually in reality it
will be lower than this why because we
don't do a full SPT we will do an
incremental SPT so we will compute the
graph only for the notes that have been
impacted by the failure so the 35
milliseconds by itself is also a
worst-case and the relative will be
better than this conclusion we have
presented test results that show that
subseconds is is convergence is
realistic as an is conservative and the
technology has significantly improved
thanks for your attention any questions
welcome I have you done any lab testing
looking at health us would work or
benefit in cases of route redistribution
so does incremental SPF provide a
benefit if you dump 10,000 20,000
100,000 routes into the router to
letting it deal with that gracefully you
know do some computation pass on the
updates not get bogged down just doing
you know an entire network recomputation
for every update or so no other reason
is that we have I would say 556 lead
customers and so we focusing on the
testing for for these customers also
with the experience of the type of
designs the design that you mentioned is
very rare to almost unknown for me so I
mean I would be interested to test it if
it becomes real but at this time i have
not yet tested it okay it doesn't happen
very often but when it happens it's very
bad so yeah I'll pop you some email
excellence yeah but it's also very good
to have suggestion like this because we
learn a lot from any feedback so it's
welcome I
just had a kind of a related question I
was wondering if you had in your in your
in your study of the problem kind of
built up any design guidelines for I I
GPS kept if you want to build fast
converging networks um I know that the
reason I'm asking is because when I was
when we were at sprint and we were
driving a lot of this work because you
know well now we found that some of the
Seraph fast convergence features weren't
really operative in our network like
incremental SPF really didn't help
sprint like that much because of the
topology the network and so forth so
have you have you been able to distill
guidelines from that work yes actually
so it's in two points there is a design
guide that comes with this presentation
it's based on all the work we have done
and the interaction on the different
design so that there is some mileage or
experience behind the design guide and
then the second point is that an
incremental SPF the benefit itself
indeed it's unknown it depends on the
topology but in all the tests that I
showed I never capitalized any benefit
from incremental SPF I was always
running a full SPF so if they would be
benefited with becoming on top of
everything but it's not included
thank you thank you