in a fine tradition of me traveling the
world giving other people's
presentations Here I am again I'm
presenting Garrett during work his
global ipv6 routing table analysis so
none of this is my work and I happily
take your comments back to him and I
answer them when I can so and also the
slides have been modified from his
original version as you'll see in some
of the later slides and when the headers
get a little more interesting and I'm
sure that just wanted to make you to let
you know that that's my doing and not
his because you know it's kind of not
keeping to the you know the theme of the
original slide so we're going to talk
about what the global IV please be six
routing table is some numbers and
pictures some recommendations and his
original slides so that you can compare
them with these are available at that
URL and these another version of these
will be available on the nanog site but
I doubt if the quotes quotes Laden
version will be available so what's the
global v6 routing table it's what you
get when you connect to the internet
with vgp 4 plus plus and people are
actually doing that actually how many
people in this room are doing v6 more
than last time cool it's a mixture of
different kinds of address space 6 phone
address space and the regional internet
registry address based like Aaron ripe
ap Nick lack Nick there's actually a new
original registry there's some a SS that
still announced only six phone space but
as you'll see later the six bonus is
starting to decommission itself so some
of that will transition the network
infrastructure differs from region to
region and and the peering agreements
are somewhat loose not like they are
with v4 so transits usually free which
creates some really interesting and
stabilities and lots of a SNS don't
filter anything and that's unfortunate
and there's still a lot of tunnels
there's a lot of problems with
actually one of those one of k's
diagrams of the tunnels would probably
be pretty cool so this is a pretty big
over all of the different prefix lengths
and then if you look at the first three
columns global rir space and six bones
space those in the parentheses on the
end or what those numbers were on 513
2003 so this is 99 September of 2003 is
what's in the main part and then the
stuff in parenthesis is what it was in
may so there were you know 266 last 32 s
and of those you know 238 or rir space
and 28 or six phone space that sort of
thing so you can browse through this
there are a lot of / 48 s being
advertised and some of the reason for
that I think is because you know yet
again the multi homes solution isn't
here so people are doing the best they
can and advertising more specifics and
then there are a lot of pathologies that
we'll talk about later there are
actually some / 64 s in the global
routing table which you know kind of
like / 32 s yay okay and the 624 address
space there's several several companies
that era Mina organizations ISP is
announcing it and they're looking for
more because it's sort of like in any
cast for six to four which is a
translation address space and there's
some a guy you can contact if you want
to become a relay and there are actually
more specifics being seen which is a big
no no i'm not a big 64 person but so i
can't really give you much more than
that so the total number of prefixes
over the last 24 months is this so each
line on the x-axis is a month and the
number is on the y-axis so there are
these big spikes will talk about some of
those later but it's increasing and
there's about I don't know 480 total
I'll talk about that some more and this
is a breakdown of of the RIR space
versus this six bone space so the six
bone space is green and the RIR space is
red
it's no surprise that the RIR space is
getting bigger because you know they're
starting to assign blocks and in the
beginning they warrant it was just six
phone so the six bones kind of going
down a little bit and I was kind of
going up no big surprise this is the the
prefixes in the last six months I'm
sorry three months one compared to the
other so the the red is the RIR space
and the green is the six-month base and
you can see that there's some really
interesting little bleeps on here and
I'll talk about those some more in a few
minutes and this is again you know not a
huge surprise so back in what does it
look like almost a year ago maybe a
little more than a year ago the
registries changed their policy so your
default your minimum allocation used to
be a / 35 ounces / 32 so and there was a
trade-in program a trade up program for
the / 35 holders to get sloshed 32s so
the / 32 s or the green and the / 35 of
the red so it's no big surprise that the
32s are going up and the 35s are going
down but there are a lot of people that
still haven't gone back to get their new
and improved huge space because they
probably don't need it so and you know
the summary of all of this there are
four hundred twenty nine blocks is
signed by the the regional registries
out of 2001 / 16 and this is the
breakdown so that the the main number
like 76 is how it was in in September of
this year and the 63 is what it was in
may so Aaron's assign 76 ap 912 ripe as
leading the leading the race with 238
and lack Nick the new registry is
starting to assign some ripe actually
went back to icon and got a new block of
address space so they've used up their
first one and they went back to get
another one and somebody actually got a
/ 31 on in September which is a huge
amount of address space so
so let's see some more information
there's out to micro allocations that
have been happening for root servers
let's see what else there's a 371 total
unique prefix our a s numbers so it's
crawling from last time I don't remember
exactly what it was last time it was
quite a bit less let's see and this is a
breakdown of prefixes by region but
these are regions from right because
garrett gives this talk at the right
meetings and he's in germany so like
there's the countries are up in the
corner that's a breakdown by country
basically in Europe French France and
the Netherlands and such if you're
interested okay this graph is I learned
a lot when I had to figure out what this
graph met at the bottom those are all
the shortened version of each allocation
that's given from I can to an RI are ok
so those are the / 24 s and then the
y-axis is the number of / 29 s out of
that / 24 that are allocated so when you
get it when the RIR gives you a block of
/ 32 they actually reserved it out of a
/ 29 and the reservations are apparently
quite long lived so what Garrett is done
it has broken it down by that since in
essence when you get a / 32 the / 29 is
is you know used for all intents and
purposes so this is a breakdown of and
basically that you know that what you
can take away from this is that there's
a lot more that have been allocated than
or in the routing table and and the
newer ones it's even more so so people
are getting address space a long time in
advance of when they're advertising it
unlike in v4 when you get a block and
you needed it a week ago and you're
frantically trying to get it in the
routing table it doesn't seem to be
occurring with these six not really sure
why so so this is the beginning of the
changes to the titles of the talk so
there's a lot of interesting things that
are happening out on the network they
are almost like things we've seen before
actually exactly like things we've seen
before so again we have the it's all
mine incident where an AS decided that
they were going to advertise everything
as / 32s and various things and and
there and they're not Garrett's not
really sure how they did this because if
they were like redistributing a couple
of times from one protocol into another
they would still only be re advertising
routes that actually existed in the
routing table but there are routes that
were never seen before or since this
incident and he's not really sure how
they did that but that was one of the
big spiky things in the graph let's see
oh and the other the other really
interesting thing about this is there
were two uniquely independent autonomous
systems using a s 1654 which of course
we know is not a useful thing to do and
we're not really sure why they were
doing that either this one is a is a bug
and it's a withdrawal bug and what
happens is there these paths that stay
around in the routing table for weeks
until somebody resets the session so
they'll just kind of hang out there even
though the routes gone away it's not the
count to infinity bug he's done quite a
bit of work on this it's actually a
different bug this is my very favorite
one these are actually like really long
paths that they kind of the route goes
away and the pads grow and grow and grow
and then they all of a sudden go away
all by themselves and what people do is
there's not a lot of peering policies
like we have now so as a ISP I'll pier
with a whole bunch of people and then
I'll just redistribute everything that I
here to everyone else so you know
usually if you're a transit provider you
don't you are not a transit provider you
don't rien Anse all your peers routes to
all your other peers but in v6 land
right now that's what everybody's doing
and so you get into these situations
where it takes a while for all the
redistribute turns from all the other
networks to go away pretty cool
this one is is a filtering thing I guess
nobody's reading the headers on these
because they're actually kind of funny
you know just didn't know how to do
those ackles so we're going to you know
advertise a whole bunch of more
specifics because you know the route map
just didn't work as we intended maybe we
need one of those tools from earlier so
and let's see this one is something
we've all seen a million times before
private AS is getting advertised just
because they should and I guess people
are getting better at I cleaning it up
but it's still not going away so let's
see so what so what's new what is it
what's the news like I said the six
phone is going away which is you know
kind of it was a great experiment and a
lot of works been done some of the bad
things that were happening are starting
to decrease like the number of bogan
networks and stuff is going away
unallocated a/s numbers being announced
is getting less there's commercial ipv6
backbones in Europe and I probably think
that Garrett wants to know anybody else
who might be doing that so we'll talk
about that there's still a lot of
tunnels going on and there's there's
problems with the tunnels like countries
and you know organizations in Europe
will get one tunnel for all their all of
their transit you know they're outside
traffic but it goes to the US so to get
to another part of Europe they're going
through the US and then back you know
all that kind of stuff is still lovely
and happening so you should always get
more than one tunnel folks are actually
using traceroute because you know it
hasn't been around very long and we need
to start using it let's see I like this
one ipv6 is no worse than ipv4 I'm not
sure if that's a bonus and US is
starting to get more allocations before
it was moving along slower so what needs
to be done
work needs to be done on filtering
recommendations and it seems like this
group probably has a lot of that
information from before there's also a
group doing a ipv6 minimum hearing
policy and I have a reference to that
and I'd encourage people to get involved
because which there are some differences
and and people are trying to put that
down so that you know people so that
there's recommendations bad tunnels need
to go away people need to stop you know
giving transit to the world although you
know if you don't pay for transit that's
kind of nice bug your ISP to offer ipv6
so I'll you ISPs use traceroute get rid
of non useful tunnels that kind of stuff
so the myth I was talking about the
minimum peering policy project
recommendations like I said jump here
over bad tunnels use prefix filters
filter private private asm's you know
all that stuff we do in v4 needs to
happen in v6 you should only give
transit if the person you're giving
transit to wants it and junk like I said
don't take transit from too many peers
and again avoid your single upstream
over in our continental tunnel it's all
stuff that we've heard before and before
and these are the references and again
I'd like to stress the myth one because
they're looking for folks to participate
and it seems to me that at some point
we're going to be really fired up about
v6 here and and having it being involved
in the policy making is is a really good
thing and oh wait and so that's the end
of this talk but in the fine tradition
of quotes that I collect like all these
headers I had a couple that I thought
were a particular interest so if you
were reading your email you might want
to just stop and look up for a minute
because this one is my favorite this was
actually in a trouble ticket where I
used to work
and I would say that if you could unroot
the switch that would be cool and I had
I had a couple more so anyway and the
first one I'm here was also in a trouble
ticket because we need to left justify
all the cards in the router anyway um
thanks and the last one was actually a
Randy Bush quote I like that I left off
part of it because I didn't want to
offend anyone so are there any questions
you