alright so it's been quite some time
since I guess it would have been Dave
Meyer who last spoke about Rob Hughes 22
nanog so we figured that an update was
in better we figured at an update was in
order so here we go give you an overview
of of the refuse project its purpose the
status of things that we've added
recently and that we're working on and
some of the issues that have a have come
up and perhaps solicit for some help
from from the community the slides are
on our website here if anybody cares to
follow along I apologize because MGP cut
off a few of the bottom parts of the
slides but they're mostly rudely so
review started around 1995 started by
Dave Meyer its original purpose was to
give operators an opportunity to see
their routes as seen by say uunet
genuity or BBN at a time and so you can
answer your own questions about how the
world saw your routes as opposed to
having to call the NOC of your provider
or or your friend down the street or
whatever so you can you can do the
debugging on your own without any help
and many see this is sort of redundant
with the with the looking glasses that
are well numerous at this point i guess
but at the time they did not exist and
we started off with a view from that was
provided by Randy bush well first from
from a west and and then from a yeast
and so on and others started to
contribute which well makes it a whole
lot more usable if you can see your view
from multiple different providers today
we have on the order of 70 peers on on
our cisco which is which you can tell
that to its Rob views route dash views
refuse org and you can look at your
routes or anybody else is there are
complete tables again from around 70
peers and for those that are actually
sending us multicast or M bgp routes
they're available there as well so given
all this data the uses of that expanded
greatly from just the operators
community to folks doing research folks
doing reports such as the site or report
and later on to folks actually doing
research on the behavior bgp and issues
that need to be corrected and how we
might do so things like a lot of the
projects that the k'da has produced
skitter is an example actually uses of
the portion of the data from from ralphs
use and we see it m laner is another one
I actually don't recall what the end
later stance where do you
notes thank you on a repeated that
nobody heard that national again
national laboratory for advanced network
research all right applied research all
right good enough so what we have is is
the CLI access again by a telnet on the
cisco and that's taking approximately
5,000 connections a day it it does vary
and when there are significant events
such as the release of these worms that
have occurred in the past couple of
months that jump significantly so
obviously operators are making use of it
as a debugging tool and since then in
order to make it more useful for the
folks doing research I think this began
around 97 or so and it was first the end
lanar folks that started collecting it
and and that is in that data was also at
least transferred to the PCH or
transferred by the PCH folks to their
own archive box but they were collecting
just the show IP bgp output all right i
supposedly need to go for a little bit
faster here in addition to in addition
to the cisco in the show I PVG format
which everybody knows is as a pain to do
screen scraping so we have zebra
collectors and they dumped this the MRT
binary files we collect ribs on a
regular basis every two hours and then
updates consistently so as they occur
the files are rotated on a 15 minute
basis we also have a couple of other
services including a beacon and all this
does is advertised wait an hour and
withdraw the route and then repeat that
cycle which
the research folk are using to to follow
timing for example or how such events
ripple through through the internet so
at a remote collection point you might
be able to determine that well you know
it took 10 minutes for example as
opposed to 30 seconds to actually
propagate that event we have a
collection of papers or a bibliography
things that have been based upon our
data as well as some other things that
pass presentations about rock use and if
you look at our website www sorg that's
misspelled there's a list of the things
that we have as you can see here we have
a number of route servers all of which
are accessible by a telnet and they
currently consists of three zebra
servers juniper and cisco and see a
couple of mailing lists that are
available for questions and information
about route views and the new stuff
we've placed a probe views collector at
the wide or nsp exchange in in Japan and
one that is on its way to pax very
shortly these are hosted by kddi and ISC
to which we oh great thanks so if
anybody this is my plug if anybody would
like to appear with us locally at pax or
at at the wide exchange please please
contact us the the main interest here is
to eliminate the multihop sessions that
we have on the servers located at the
University of Oregon we also have some
DNS zones that convert ribs collected by
the refuse collector and
present those as as to DNS zones that
you can search and things that we were
working on is some data mining utilities
ways to collect data or to extract data
out of what we have in a more timely
fashion and perhaps even automated let's
see this is an example of the as path or
asos we have as you can see Dave
throughout these for me it returns a txt
record for the reverse of a prefix this
happens to be the University of Oregon
prefix 1 22 23 / 16 and it returns in
the answer section here the record and
it returns the a s the origin is the
prefix in the length of that prefix and
there are similar there is a similar
Zone ass path instead of ASM that
returns to full day s path so be
whatever 630 582 let's see so issues
that we've we've come up with or have
been faced with our basically
scalability issues with zebra and
questions about the the effectiveness of
the the timers that are used to
timestamp records in the mrt files this
is the binary files and a number of
people have also come up with these same
issues there are a couple of other
projects doing the same thing or similar
things and some of these folks have
actually made progress already on
correcting some of these problems
and these are a few of the other
projects that have been collecting BGP
routing data ripe risks which has been
very effective and has a very large
accumulation of data though i think we
probably have a at least a data set that
is goes back further some thanks to to
PCH who provided us with with the older
information we see there are looking
glasses available which everybody knows
about I don't think that's it just about
right so kind of sit there with that but
is one of the things that I think
perhaps we missed yesterday and the
rancid discussion and and also applies
to to Ralph uses a lot of the folks in
the community some of you seated here
have have helped us greatly providing
views providing information about
hardware these sorts of things and we
owe you a thanks for that so thank you
any questions of course these going to
hassle me
Kathy said I had to UM I'm dead my um
actually the last slide there where I
was wanting to get on some sense of the
folks in this room about it two things
one is that the data collection aspect
of the Ralph use project has become kind
of much more important even for
operational purposes because a lot a lot
of the operators are actually analyzing
that data themselves now so there's a
research component to having that data
around but there's also an operational
component which is simple yet another
thing I didn't expect to have happened
but on my question really for the group
of people would like to comment on that
is whether or not it would be useful to
try to do some kind of coordination
effort over all these sources of data
that are starting to be on house in
various different places seems to me
that we could do a better job of not
only collecting it for archival storage
because it seems to become we be
becoming more valuable with age at least
some of it depending on the events of
the day and then it's just becoming
quite a bit of data so if anybody has
any thoughts about that one please
contact us the other thing I wanted to
ask folks is there are a lot of bgp
listeners out there but they're mostly
based on either Cisco's or whatever
Juniper's or whatever they are but the
collection aspect of this really doesn't
need that overhead or that heavy weight
and what we were thinking about doing is
building sort of a standardized listener
that output this data in a standardized
format so we could compare it around and
that's another thing i'd like to get
people to comment on if they have any
thoughts about that thanks
Randy bouchage it's really nice to hear
that something's getting better with age
day um I use it both both as a
researcher and operationally I'm not
really that interested in compatibility
between the different ones um we take
the data we process the data into our
own formats we archive it in our own
formats we analyze it with our own tools
etc but we may be more sophisticated you
just go slip the data and look at it
everyone I'm my concerns are far more
with the accuracy of the data collection
then the presentation and I'm
specifically concerned with I really
don't like egb multi-hop because that
relies on the TCP stack of the
collecting device and the delicacy of
TCP connections over long distances so
you get reports like the notorious one
Code Red by supposing researchers were
fifteen percent of the data that they
demonstrated was actually useful so on
and so forth so getting the collectors
at the peering points getting hard
connections getting uniform data IE not
customer routes from provider a deer
routes from provider be and God knows
what from providers see getting the data
marked would be just wonderful in other
words you're peering connection with
provider ex it would be really nice if
it had a community telling you either
they got this is their out they got it
appear they got it from a customer etc
would be just delicious really would so
it's the accuracy and detail of the data
having formats phooey with it we know
how to program computers right let me
say that getting rid of the ebgp or the
multi-hop sessions is one of the
objectives of placing these machines at
pax and wide for example getting people
to peer with us or even to change
Spierings once they're in place is shall
we say more than difficult a lot of
people tend to be unresponsive or give
me a list of who to beat up here elson
that's you improvement but if people can
can help us do these things get peering
especially at these new sites help us
with getting colocation at safer is for
example a site on on the East Coast one
in Europe someplace links for example
this would help us along this road
greatly to get the data that the folks
like Randy actually need to do to do
their research and that includes if they
ask you for the information please help
them it's in your best interest okay
we're running really late so woody and
then we're going to help to move on I
well obviously being a proponent of all
this I do it I just encourage people to
think about how necessary it is to have
a third or fourth one of these packs and
a third or fourth one of these at links
as opposed to putting them into
exchanges that aren't yet covered so I
get people think about that when
deploying these sorts of things rather
than just saying oh where do I most want
to have a box because it's the same
place that everyone else most wants to
have a box it's not just that though but
I'm you might want to cover some of
these smaller naps but there are a
particular naps that are of greater
interest shall we say because of the
people that are there right but the
thing is those who already had two or
three boxes doing exactly this for years
at this point right so having a third or
fourth one in the same location that now
has to be supported by the exchange
operator as to you know get everybody
appearing with it all over again he
isn't adding any value whereas like Hong
Kong right there isn't one in Hong Kong
right now there never has been that
needs to be covered right the exchange
operator is happy to have one has space
dedicated waiting for somebody to deploy
there nobody's had money to deploy there
yet right I don't know I mean I could
probably name a dozen other reasonable
sized ones that aren't covered what
Milan right none in long there are a lot
of other big ones that I'm sure there
are other possibilities our budget seems
to be actually they confined as well so
while we try to try to accommodate the
the places that the research folk have
actually asks us to to appear so being I
guess our primary customers we need to
need to accommodate that first I believe
but I understand yes how is it that you
feel that those are not already
accommodated by the you know the three
or four boxes that are already doing
exactly what you're doing at that
location that have been for years
they've made my question they have made
that choice for me might need is you
guys are going to have to take this
offline because you know Dave's up next
and he needs some time oh I just Hank
have a quick comment while Dave setting
up yeah I just had gotten on ripe ncc
the ripened CC in response to build will
install a router collector in Milan
shortly in fact the machine is already
there bc just have to switch it on
you