that's this is some work that we have
coming out of a research project of ours
at arbor networks we have a / 8 network
we used to monitor parts of the internet
for things like DDoS backscatter and
things like that so Casey you're pretty
familiar with how that stuff goes but
this is some of the data that we have in
the plaster world and it's a great segue
thank you very much and of course thank
you to the organizers as well for the
conference and the opportunity this is
work that I do with some folks at Arbor
they're almost at the end but it's a
great team of people who put this thing
together and and I participate in the
analysis the blaster worm you know as as
was stated just a minute ago had kind of
a short timeline and this is thing that
we're kind of seeing more and more with
words we had this advisory put out in
the middle of July which was released
without any exploit code but to some
nice details that people almost
immediately began developing exploits
using and about three or four days later
we saw several exploits and one of those
actually called decon see came from HD
Moore and that's thought to be kind of
the core exploit and back door that was
using the worm and that the world appear
on the August eleventh of course here
and within a couple of days to sort of
seen variants and one of the most
sinister ones that we saw was the SD
bought variant so blaster has this DDoS
attack that it had it had a trigger and
a predefined trigger and a predefined
target whereas things like SD Bob's and
stuff like that can you know arbitrary
details toolkits anytime almost any
place and build up these enormous botnet
armies and heck just just use a worm to
do it right so somebody kind of
piggybacked on that last year chooses a
semi-random target it does some sort of
island hopping kind of like like NIM de
and other worms do on occasion it scans
a / 24 from 0 to 250 for so it's not
random hosts forty percent of the time
it chooses a local network and lops off
the last octet and scans that network
sixty percent of the time it generates a
random IP address and lops off the last
octet and scans that network it's scans
for tcp port 135 which is where it's
going to commit its exploit it the
parent now it actually listens as a tftp
server so can
download the child node connected
download from the parent that natural
executable if it can connect to TCP port
135 it attempts the exploit it didn't
use the universal offset that people
found a little bit later eighty percent
of the time it uses the XP offset twenty
percent of the time uses the windows
2000 offset and that's interesting
because the wrong one will actually
crashed the Box causing it to reboot if
it can do that if it can wants the
exploit it goes ahead and tries it and
what it simply does its kind of grief
forces its way a few seconds later to
see if the remote backshell remote back
to our shell is demolished on port 44 44
TCP since a series of three commands
which caused the child to download the
executable the single executable file
from the parent started and begin
operations so we are simply monitoring
this large network reflecting packets
and doing some distillation in real time
and one of the things that we do is we
actually classify port scans and sweeps
and so we simply detect port 135 scans
against a / 24 of 255 hosts we're not
setting any response like we do with
port 80 worms so we're not in a
fingerprint the worm traffic here we're
not going to have any active sampling so
one consequence of this is that we
cannot differentiate the variance of the
world and also we don't see any port 44
44 traffic so we have this very
primitive way of classifying the worm
but it actually seems to work quite well
and then of course you take the data we
measure the traffic and then the unique
IP address is seen over this time this
is kind of a quick schematic of what our
block of architecture looks like quite
simply you know we have this box over
here on the lower right hand corner that
listens to a / 8 and the three biggest
things we catch their addy das
backscatter from spoof space in our / 8
we have Code Red and other types of
words which scan random targets hitting
us on occasion and we have attackers and
even some other worms like blasters
scanning or random addresses and random
networks and of course we're going to
capture some of that and with then we
analyze it this is the raw traffic graph
that we captured out of this the large
dips that you see sometimes in this clip
recent data collection failures it's not
a perfect system but this is enough that
we can go on and we can actually do some
analysis
then that didn't show up well at all
very simply let's see here very very
simply it's you know it's a rapid
increase it's a slow decrease and then
kind of a sinusoidal pattern at the very
end looking at the demographics of the
worm this one-week period we actually
see about 280,000 unique IP addresses
based upon the host names during the
lookups there we find about ten percent
of those are dynamic they have worked
you know names like dynamic or dhcp
hearing things like that so we can kind
of assume that we're going to double
count those at least so we
conservatively see we have about 250,000
unique IP addresses that were observed
doing glass early traffic glass or like
things the big yellow thing here in the
dns on the pie chart here is net or less
what you'd expect based on the
populations calm as a second what's
interesting to notice that UD u & K are
for Korea or not anywhere near the top
10 dot edu is much much higher than
Korea but Korea with just a sliver of
traffic so the big green part here of
the pie chart is was no no response from
the DNS server so it's possible the
Korea had all this DNS servers turned
off but ultimately we didn't get a large
chunk of Korean addresses like we
normally do for other large events that
we track in this space and edu is
probably there's a much much much lower
than it should have been given the
population and some of the situations
and some campuses mainly because it was
August so school wasn't quite in session
yet so there are very few systems
relatively speaking online in the ED you
space I talked about how we classify
these scans and blaster and I mentioned
it's kind of primitive shown here in
this graph we is kind of the first 10 or
11 days of August where we can kind of
see where we have a four to 12 port 135
scan sources per hour and before the
release of the adviser you saw maybe
four to 12 a week in this space so very
very few very very low severe very low
noise and our signal these there are
some spikes in the graph here that you
can see in these correspond we believe
based upon looking at list
thick and other things too toolkits that
are designed to actively scan large
networks and and route boxes essentially
with one of the most popular ones being
from a group called chaotic for example
and at the very very end here you can
see the actual blaster and traffic
taking off kind of like a rocket so the
actual growth rate of the of the worm is
shown here in this graph again doesn't
show up too well my bad we put it to a
simple constraint growth model where we
have a logistical growth equation I fit
it to a very simple Boltzmann equation
because it's what I know heavily and
only has a few few variables in it we
find is that at the peak we have a close
to 16,000 unique sources per hour in our
in our data set we have a minimum
doubling time of about to our maximum
rather doubling time about 2.3 hours and
we never hit this large plateau value at
the top so we don't get an accurate
measurement of how how steep it was
going about the steepest it never really
gets a chance to to slow down gracefully
it's not a true sigmoid curve so on the
basis of this we don't wait kind of an
incomplete data set for analyzing the
doubling time so that a maximum it's
about to 2.3 hours or 2.2 hours the
effect of routing on this to kind of go
along with the previous talk is in the
sense in some things that was very
similar to so far in the sense of this
someone never routes dropped out of our
monitors a bunch of us about three or
four thousand dropped out the inside
here shows sapphire traffic and the
effect on the routing and the larger
graph is from blaster but it was much
less pronounced than we saw a blaster in
fact don't let me saw a sapphire one on
the routing tables which is probably my
initial guess is probably why you guys
didn't catch it as an instability marker
there's a little more graceful and so it
didn't kind of trigger your thresholds
essentially almost immediately within
about six hours of the worms
introduction we begin testing a dramatic
decrease in the amount of worm traffic
and we believe this is due to people
starting to install these very simple
filters on their networks and pushing
them down kind of
to the leaf nodes essentially there are
other networks fitting into a very
simple single exponential equation we
came up with about ten point four hours
of a half-life of blaster activity again
there's kind of a dip in here due to
data loss this is a times fan here shown
here about five days and we pretty much
stopped seeing people cleaning up the
networks at the end developer at the end
of amount that five days started about
four to six hours after the worm was
kind of announced and pretty much
identified part of this is because it's
quite trivial to filter this worm as
opposed to code rather aninda you simply
install a filter a simple simple tion
for example at a pix would do it as
opposed to having selectively filter out
traffic that's used quite legitimately
across the backbone of the internet so
we saw quite a number of operators
installing filters very very quickly and
working very quickly to contain the word
spread which is a pretty good thing I
think we're learning a lot in that
respect at the at the end of that time
period we saw the end of the decrease we
actually see this kind of circadian
pattern of blaster activity suggesting
that these are machines that get turned
on as the day starts and turned off and
people people go home or something like
that the peak start out near midnight
eastern daylight time but kind of start
drifting throughout the day one of the
things I thought would kind of indicate
where this was centered was looking at
the dns lookups however it's a global
top-level domain distribution within
this time span and there's also a slight
increase kind of in the mean value when
you go from the 20 from about the 20th
to through the 26th or so and then it
drops down again I think it's really
important to note by the way in this in
this figure here we see the exponential
decrease the worm with is that this is
not an effective well chea well she
appeared about a week after of last year
appeared and this is about six hours
after blaster appeared so it's people
just simply installing filters so that's
kind of it so we're still seeing a lot
of blaster activity that more or less
mirrors what we see here still circadian
we're still seeing about at a minimum of
300 machined and a maximum at a thousand
machines per hour every day circadian
patterns still continue we saw a kind of
a global
the domain distribution of the sources
they're looking at the second-level
domain distributions we see a lot of
cable modem networks a lot of broadband
a lot of consumer dial-up things like
that we don't see any large any large
providers kind of standing out too badly
it's kind of flattens out very quickly
when you look at the second-level domain
analysis so really quickly you know some
some very simple conclusions right so we
had this advanced warning we knew this
thing was going to happen we had
exploits we know people were going to
talk about others it was way too juicy
people were just going to have to do it
and the exploit that was used had a very
nice signature great showed up quite
easily we could have very simply install
firewall rules this wasn't a core back
one service for example could even solve
idea signatures it's very very simple
and yet it still hit pretty hard and you
know there was even a patch attila for a
month it increases it escalates the
threat level a little bit here we have a
worm which is being actively used to
continue to consume hundred about as the
machines to build limited eNOS type
zombies which caused some very
interesting things it spread quite
quickly much what we're cookin I think
we give it credit for spread it in a
matter of a few hours as opposed to the
course of a few days it's been about six
hours spreading and it about five days
cleaning it up and the DDoS against
Windows Update com was it was eventually
thwarted the potential there was about
1.3 million syn packets per second each
worm no would send 50 packets per second
of sin to Windows okay calm and multiply
that by the number of hosts that's where
you get that value so it could have been
worse in the sensitive the author i
dissuaded say a few hours instead of a
few days to do this trigger people would
have been scrambling i think to deal
with the fallout instead we're able to
analyze it look at what was going to
happen next and install filters speaking
of that creep parent is here from
microsoft networks he was actually a
ground zero he he describes it as the
one foot view of what happened at
windows update calm with respect to the
d das that was set to launch against set
the launch against them he's open to
talking to people offline he's a great
guy the Scimitar singh stuff happened
that week for them so talk to him and
there's a team of people here who also
worked with him on that so it wasn't all
just him but a great team of people who
eventually thwarted this really serious
problem for
the cells and like I mentioned it's a
team of people who do this and very very
proud to work with them so thank you
very much it's no time for a question or
two and then Susan will make her magical
ending comments yes Lawrence Baldwin of
my with my night watchman I spent a good
amount of time looking at blaster and I
just wanted to maybe throw one thing out
if no no if you thought about it or not
but just sort of by coincidence I happen
to notice that when the Microsoft tftp
client tries to download a file and it
failed it leaves a temporary file behind
which then prevents any future client
downloads so one of my theories as to
why this spread didn't go quite as fast
as people would have expected was that
if there was any kind of instability or
congestion or I don't even know if the
tftp server that was in the worm has had
any kind of reliability mechanisms in it
but it seemed like there was a high
probability that on the the actual
potential victims will be blocked from
infection because of this t ftp client
behavior that makes a lot of sense
however I think we would have seen in
kind of a leveling off the number of
addresses per hour so the graphs are not
new house but just a muni coach within
any hour so we see this decrease as
opposed to kind of a leveling off that
would if it were simply that I think
that that probably contributed a lot to
it you know as worms grow and increase
of traffic the increase congestion and
that would definitely cause symptoms
like that incomplete downloads and the
worm at a stupid little check to see if
it was already infected which would and
the scenario you describe what it would
have prevented the worm from getting
much further however I think if that
were only that what the thing that were
going on we would have seen a leveling
off of the number of infections per hour
as opposed to a member of observations I
should say so the growth rate waters
would have slowed or even stopped but we
would have seen a lot of activity remain
so that's probably part of it but I
don't think that's the whole story
yes yeah I am Kirk parent from Microsoft
actually I only marginally work with the
networking key my work with the
microsoft com web operations group now
the one quick point that's only
marginally related with this but I
wanted to put it out here a lot of
groups hijacked the windows update calm
domain and they ended up carrying it
themselves their own resolvers we're
still seeing a relatively non-trivial
amount of sites that are doing that so
I'm trying to spread the word broadly
should people find out the organization
is doing that please unhide Jack the
domain there are some components of the
domain that are still in use the
specific Windows Update com host is not
in DNS anymore and it shouldn't be a
problem but broadly there are some hosts
within that domain that are still in use
so please don't don't hijack the whole
domain within your within your resolvers
thanks thank you very much