so this this presentation is about
troubleshooting BGP I've angled it at as
a inter sorry as a beginner presentation
rather than anything admit intermediate
or advanced what I'm trying to impart
here is more about how you go about
setting out good principles and practice
practices with trying to do
troubleshooting within BGP so if you
came looking for Marik's presentation
it's not here it's at the other side and
Salaam F my name is Philip Smith I work
for Cisco I live in Australia well I
have a house in Australia but I spend
most of my time it seems pretty much
anywhere else in the world so coming to
visit you all here at Nano is just one
of the many things I I do mostly work in
the asia-pacific region mostly with ISPs
mostly doing training tuition bgp stuff
like this so if you want to follow the
presentation the slides are actually up
in two places given I gave Susan my
presentation about two hours ago I'm not
sure if you've got the absolute latest
slides or not what may have been on the
merit website were just the draft up
until about two hours ago so but what's
on the Cisco FTP site is what I'm
actually using here I've made some
subtle changes so if you want to follow
the presentation the slides are there
for you assumptions well I'm going to
assume that you actually know BGP you've
got a fairly basic working knowledge of
the protocol if you've never heard of
BGP or have never even really used it
and you're just coming here to try and
learn a little bit presentation will be
useful for you as well but say some of
the principles may not make much sense
and you've actually gained some
experience of the protocol Messer says
there as I said
or please feel free to ask questions the
microphone is is in the middle there if
you'd like to use the mic please okay
but really three parts of the
presentation the first bit quite short
we're going to look at the fundamentals
of troubleshooting we're going to have a
look at some of issues you can get with
local configuration problems ie within
your own network and then depending on
what time we have at the end have a look
at some of the internet reachability
problems so in other words how you go
about trying to do troubleshooting when
it's not inside your network right first
thing is really all about trying to
recognize what the problem is right you
first step you've got to do is try and
recognize what caused the problem now
this is true for any troubleshooting
anywhere whatsoever and BGP is not
special in this case but I find in my
what 10 to 15 years experience in
industry when you mention the magic
words BGP people panic especially if
you're newcomers to it and I suppose the
new entrant a minor panic with good
reason because the use of BGP in your
network determines your network
connectivity you break BGP you break
connectivity somehow for your network
your customers and so forth and of
course customers start complaining and
then everything gets to know about it
it's best especially your boss and the
people who make money from your business
so I find quite often the result of this
is that people will work around problems
in the most bizarre ways
sticking-plaster
funny kind of configurations just to try
and work around the particular issue
they have rather than sitting down and
trying to work methodically to fix the
actual problem
also I mean this is true for for
anything this is not true not
necessarily just for BGP but best
Troubleshooters one who learned from
experience when you fixed your first
problem you feel great which gives you
incentive to go and fix other problems
after that and you have more confidence
in doing this so you just have more
practice you get better at doing it and
the second one mistakes if you learn
from your mistakes well when you do
troubleshooting you actually make a lot
of mistakes I mean there's nobody I know
who is actually sat down able to do
troubleshooting and has never ever made
a single mistake when you you tend to
learn a lot about what you're doing from
mistakes that you make and yes you'll
get better at it you get better at
learning and you get better at the
troubleshooting and also you learn from
others as well so learn what other
operators say there are plenty of BGP
problems discussed on various mailing
lists sometimes it appears on Nanog
usually lists like ISP BGP and so forth
all these were discussing BGP issues
problems that people face look at some
of the issues that people discuss some
of the problems and how the soft you can
maybe use some of those for your own
troubleshooting later on and also the
best troubleshooter will go about
creating some basic principles and those
principles are based on what you've
actually learned in the past so you're
kind of building up a historical record
of what you of what you've done when
every problem is different every network
is different so you can't really ask in
public you know how to go about fixing
such-and-such a problem because nobody
will really have the identical situation
so the best they can do is give advice
if you can use this advice to figure out
what's wrong in your network and then
add it to your source so-called database
then it makes solving problems much
easier later on now before a transistor
I used to work at you
net and our network operations center
sunny for the for the UK operation we
use this type of thing I didn't
particularly want them coming running to
me every time there was a BGP problem in
the network so we gave them a basic
thing encouraged them to go and try and
figure out what the problem was and
learn from Lauren thing so every network
operations center operator would
actually access I suppose a little diary
of the problems that they had and they
would use this diary to try and figure
out what was wrong with with the thing
so is it SOCOM building a kind of
knowledge base and they all became
pretty good trouble shooters they didn't
have to bother me or ended my network
engineering team that much now where can
you actually have problems with in BGP
well as with anywhere else
miss configuration now this miss
configuration could be caused by bad
documentation misunderstanding concepts
through communication between colleagues
or departments I mean that's all typical
stuff human error
typos man you could be sleepy you've
just finished working 36 hours of some
kind of big problem in the network
you're more likely to make type of
typing mistakes then you use the wrong
commands or the command can be
completion didn't quite work as you
expect just plain and simple accidents
poorly planned or executed maintenance
activities that's that's a favorite one
and plus all of the above miss
configuration problems all can be human
error technical problems such as
problems with the hardware you may have
some weird hardware fault that's causing
something really strange to go wrong
with bgp but it looks like a routing
protocol problem but it's actually could
be something physical within the network
or other equipment software problems we
all know interrupts are linked loads
affecting protocol stability in other
words link is congested BGP falls over
no I mean you can see well BGP falls
over but why is a link congested
that's the type of thought process more
problem areas feature behavior as I'd
like to call it or used to do this and
in one release but you upgrade to what
should be just a minor change to fix
some bugs and some behavior completely
and absolutely changes and messes things
up that's another potential problem area
interoperability issues certainly if
you're using different equipment in the
in the network could be using say Cisco
or juniper zebra mixed up within your
network that could be interoperability
issues you can't just assume that what
one is right and others are wrong you've
got to figure out the different
interpretations of the BGP standard and
then of course the problems caused by
things beyond your control your upstream
ISP has some major policy change within
his network that has a fairly serious
impact on your own network okay how did
you go about solving these that means
that the next step is to try and go and
fix the problem and that's simply not
about dividing the network's are jumping
into your network and trying some random
commands where I've seen a lot of people
especially when you're operating more in
the panic mode you just simply dive in
the network and do this and do that or
think it was this and I remember
changing this yesterday so gone undo
that not a very good way of
troubleshooting especially when you
don't really understand what the problem
is
yes I know we're all trying to work
really hard to minimize downtime we're
actually sitting down and spending a bit
of time figuring out what could be wrong
yesthey even though mase seem to give
you a longer time time in the first
instance that you tried actually you
come to a faster resolution but I've
been there done that so many times
panicking doesn't really solve the
problem and before you actually begin by
begin jumping into the network well as
I've been saying don't panic create a
checklist create a list of things you
want to actually try and check and then
then work through that
list try and start at the bottom and
work upwards I say if bgp has fallen
over well there could be a whole range
of things that are wrong try and figure
out what could have caused it to fall
over and look at all possibilities I
mean it could be something as stupid as
the circuit that the routers connecting
to has gone down okay so you sort of
reminds you of the old joke you know my
computer doesn't work so well is the
power switched on it's that kind of that
thing you've got to think of checking
that the power switched on isn't as
stupid as it sounds you know it can be
the solution and quite a few problems so
I'm not really going to mention
checklist at the start of the
presentation but as we thought I'd get
about halfway through and so on and I'm
going to start making reference to the
checklist how you can actually work
through any of the problems never seen
before it's what a lot of not staff
actually follow when they're trying to
diagnose and solve that with problems
okay you've also got to be aware of the
tools and if you've got one vendor in
your network you can probably figure out
what all the tools are pretty easily
when you have X different equipment
multi vendor network you have more tools
that are available to use some equipment
may have tools that others don't have so
you got to try and understand these and
be aware of what you can use with them
to actually help you in what you're
doing
familias familiarize yourself with these
tools for example it's logging of the
bgp process enabled a lot of defaults
don't have this I mean it isn't default
down in Cisco IOS
you get log messages pretty much
anything that's happening in the bgp
process are you storing these logs
somewhere useful if you're just storing
the logs in actual on board on the
router you may have only got a small
buffer and you don't know what happened
a day up to you ago so stick some of
these logs somewhere useful so you can
and have a look at the history of what
might have gone wrong and you know what
the logs mean
when some of the logs can have a lot of
gibberish in them to try and understand
what this gibberish could actually mean
are you familiar with the BGP debug
process some of this implementations
allow you to debug the BTB process do
you know all the commands available or
what is available what you can do with
them yes the customer support will say
don't ever dare use them but that's just
so you don't go and switch on crazy
things and then complain that it doesn't
what the router doesn't work right but
you can actually use some of these tools
to very very good effect so check the
vendor documentation check operational
recommendations okay in other words what
your peers in the industry might say any
documents have been written by other
service providers or the operators and
and so forth to get tips of what you can
do and then you can go switching on some
of the debug tools you want to work in
the principle of having fewer surprises
so don't so you should be surprised if
you switch on full debugging on 130,000
prefix writing-table that your router is
going to probably fall over okay
lots of fundamentals say that the
nothing really too specific to be GP
it's all fairly simple straightforward
troubleshooting that you would apply in
any part of a network operation so now
we're going to really look at the main
part what sort of issues that you can
have within your own network I'm not
going to include any configuration
examples unless I'm just going to have a
look at some of the principles and some
of the common problems and the solutions
that you can get
so rather than load this down with iOS
configuration examples we'll just have a
look at some of the natural concepts
themselves and I split it into four
pieces
the first one about peer establishment
many many issues of peer establishment
and people look for the complicated
reason why they're problems and then
that generally tend not to be like that
then we've got missing routes
inconsistent right selection
and of course loops and convergence
which is entertaining as well peer
establishment a like this this slide
because in this these days people are
very security minded and they put the
filters only on the edge of the network
like the good people they are and they
forget to allow BGP so I mean I usually
have an email or two per month that says
well I'm trying to bring BGP up but and
because people will forget port 179 BGP
uses TCP 179 so you need to allow that
through your packet filters between you
and your neighboring router this is for
establishing bgp peering between you and
your neighboring yes and let's
definitely have definitely a frequent
frequently occurring problem people are
over aggressive with the filter the
second problem I'd be connectivity can
you actually get to your neighboring
router if you're trying to bring up say
internal BGP with a router somewhere
else in your network well you can
specify the IP address of that
neighboring router but can you actually
get to it
can you trace to it can you ping it
because we can't trace a ping to it with
not much chance so if you're actually
going to bring up a BGP session either
what's - a very very simple but oh my
gosh I come across those so often people
don't do that fundamental check so you
have a BGP session not coming up first
thing you check filters and can you
actually reach the neighboring writer at
the address you specified once you've
got that far of course the open messages
are exchanged pinning addresses must
match and the local a s configuration
must match
that's another classic try to bring up
an eye BGP session and your typo'd the
actual a s number you may be thrown in
an extra 0 or a 1 or you got nervous on
the keyboard and may be typed in an
extra digit for the a s or something or
you've confused an 8 with a 0 because
it's hard to read what your colleagues
scroll down in a bit of paper seen all
it all happens you you need to make sure
that these type of things match
okay so some of the common problems you
know I do
IP reach ability you could incorrect
configuration flapping peers
another issue that could be layer two
problems they're the most common link
saturation problems or CPU utilization
problems
I'll give you flapping peers let's have
a look at the peer establishment give a
simple situation like this well trying
to bring up a session between router 1
and router two are the two routers
actually sitting in the same a s number
when you can check that by looking at
the configuration quite easily it's the
remote is assigned correctly so for
example peering between writer two and
writer 3 have you actually type a s to
inter altitude have you typed a s1 into
router 3 for the neighboring a s and you
just verify with a diagram or the
documentation that you have these are
these are very simple things to actually
overlook certainly with some of the a s
numbers I suppose I tend to find in the
days when a s numbers like two or three
digits it was hard to go wrong but now
when the 30,000 or so it's very easy for
people to transpose numbers when when
you're typing or when you're tired it's
so incredibly easy to transpose numbers
and the so many issue is simply caused
by that so if you find in trouble when
you're deploying BGP in your network
trying to bring up the BGP session check
things like that is is have you actually
enter the configuration properly so we
assume that I become activities been
checked that you can reach the neighbor
check TCP to find out what connections
but you're accepting or most routers I
know of you can actually sure what TCP
connections have been terminated on the
Box do they make sense do they match
what what you expect do the source and
destination addresses match
one common problem that you find
deployed ibgp when you deploy a BGP you
run ibgp between loopback interfaces on
the router
you don't run ibgp between the physical
interfaces
you should know that if you don't run it
between a physical interface that
physical interface goes down your ibgp
goes down the whole point of deploying
ibgp in the network is to have a stable
system of delivering prefixes around
within the backbone so having an
internal BGP depended on a physical
interface means that your internal BGP
is only as stable as the interface or
the network that that interface is
connected to most routers have at least
one interface connected somewhere in
fact any router in the core of the
network will have multiple so a physical
circuit failure or interface failure can
be worked around by running the ibgp
between the loop backs
so a common problem is you're running
ibgp between a loopback but if if
somehow missed out some of the loopback
configuration now you may be lucky
the ibgp may come up you may be very
unlucky as it's more often the case an
IB GB just sticks that you look at it it
looks fine you forget to tell the router
the basic thing of saying we're actually
peering between the loopback interfaces
and not between and it were else
remember the source address for any
outgoing packet is the outbound
interface so it's the IP address and
iPhone interface open interface is not
the loopback it could be your serial
could be the phone app so it's important
to tell bgp my ID band source is
actually the loopback now
EB GP is by and large problem-free when
you try and bring out the peering you
only need bit a one line configuration
say the neighbor is this address that is
number
but yes the source addresses that
divided by an interface
sorry destination address is that of the
remote router that's easy too it's
directly connected time to live is set
to 1 there's no real problem with
bringing you up BGP you've got your
filters right so you allowing tcp 179 in
both directions but the problems start
arising and ebgp when you try and do
load balancing or you try and use ebgp
multi-hop in other words you're setting
the time to live to be more than one
you're trying to talk external bgp user
devices not directly connected to the
local writer okay for example you may be
trying to peer ibgp with a rioter
central router in your neighboring osp's
network rather than on the aggregation
writer
some are espy's do that a lot of ice
piece want some of some Lawton have
policies where they will not let you do
a BGP multi-hop because the problems you
end up with are so obscure that they
could look as though there's something
else ok 'lord balancing can be another
issue as well if you aware how you do
load balancing you point a static right
to the remote loop max of the remote
router and then you compete at ebgp with
that loop back and that's great for load
balancing over parallel circuits but you
have to be kind of careful with that as
well because the ebgp session might stay
up or the link might be very very bad
and you may not be aware that it's
actually a physical connection between
your router that's causing you some of
the problems so you've got to be kind of
careful and in fact a lot of my
trainings when I'm introducing people to
a BGP I just say don't even think of
using the ebgp multi-hop unless you
really understand what's going on and
your neighbor knows what's going on and
you're aware of the potential problems
okay so the beaching multi-hop problems
that can be I P connectivity to the
remote address so as the riot in the
local routing table is the router the
remote writing table to get back to you
because you may have everything set up
right but does your neighboring is Pete
have everything set right as well to
point back to you
in fact that's quite a common problem
they forget to put their static right
pointing back to your loopback you can
check this using ping okay and check
using ping to the remote address you're
trying to get at you can specify your
source address whether it's right by an
interface or you loopback or whatever
and that will tell you pretty clearly
what what the problem might be there
other filters in the path we need bgp
multi-hop between you and your mediate
neighboring ir SP should be too much of
an issue but if you're crossing multiple
network boundaries somebody could be
filtering bgp somewhere in the path and
then you've got to cooperate and work
with the ISPs in the path to try and
make this thing work from with passwords
I mean I know a lot of eyespace don't
use passwords on the ibgp and ebgp
session it's certainly a a good current
practice for a lot of people that I know
they were using passwords on bgp
sessions introduces own set of problems
you bit if you type the password in on
the local router to the remote right you
find the BGP session won't come up
you've been through all the previous
troubleshooting and it just won't work
some of the common problems I've seen
are missing passwords I mean you have to
just forget to type it in cut and paste
arrows okay so it could be white space
or a character might have snuck in or a
character might have may be miss tired
cutting pieces just such a nasty thing
something when it comes to running a
network trying to troubleshoot what's
going on in a network
because it introduces so many possible
possible problems typos as well
certainly if you're using quite an
obscure password trying to distinguish
vertical bars and back slashes and
comers and full stops and the number
zero with the letter or all those things
and I've seen cause problems and
capitalization sometimes capitals those
case sensitivities or non case
sensitivities extra characters white
space using white space in the password
well how many white spaces are there and
so forth so when you're dealing with
passwords and bgp sessions you need to
be actually quite careful common
solutions actually well quite simple you
start from start again it's just too
hard to try and troubleshoot what the
password problems could be some
implementations will encrypt the
password as it's stored on the writer so
you've got no way of knowing what you've
typed in in any case so as much as to
use easier just to say okay start again
type the password in and does that bring
the session up don't cut and paste
flapping peer in the symptom you have is
that the ebgp session flaps it comes up
stays up for a bit that falls over and
that restarts comes up falls over and so
forth round and round and round well you
need to ensure that logging is enabled
if you don't have any logs of what's
going on in the router I either end you
have no clues what's going on and you
should always be trying to configure
your router so you get maximum clues to
try and help you the troubleshooting
what do the logs say well problem like
this is usually caused by the BGP
keepalive getting lost a keepalive is
sent every 60 seconds or whatever the
two routers negotiate between each other
and if a keepalive gets lost then the
bgp session is is pulled over okay
no keep alive it means the local route
assumes the remote has vanished so it
tears the bgp session down because you
know bgp is trying to do its good thing
of peering gone down i want to fail over
to my
of path and so it will try and tear the
session down as expeditiously as it can
because it then tries to reestablish
your session as it as it as it tries to
do iron you get my stick you'll bring up
the session everything happy then it
starts exchanging updates and everything
freezes up again
well the keep our lives get can get lost
because they get stuck in the writers
queue behind the beach the update
packets now the beach you update packets
tend to be packed into the full size of
the empty units available to 1500 bytes
for example it's all the updates are
packed in there so you're efficient with
a number of packets you're sending where
is thy keeper lives are probably
occupying nice little packets like that
so you can send the keeper lives because
little packets but updates are big 1500
byte packets and they get stuck
somewhere there's something the network
that's not and not allowing these
through so if you if you see something
like this it's worth using ping with
different sizes to try and find out
where the jam is now it could well be
that ICMP gets through is it hasn't have
a problem in TCP does so you got to try
and use different tcp-based ping but
generally an ICMP ping will let you see
if there are any any MTU problems within
the network and of course then if you
find that that's a problem you need to
pass this to the people who look after
the the layer 2 part of your network but
try and be helpful we not just say thank
you bgp going after you problem dump I
mean try and figure out where you where
the problem might be in the network if
it's if it's not a meet between
immediate neighbors or you've got some
other physical bits in the network you
can try and use paint to find out where
the problem might be you can't have to
work together i'm each troubleshooting
team is not a particular island it can't
all sit in the same place in any case so
working together makes a lot more sense
other common problems well if you see a
bgp peering cycling within about three
to five minutes it could be the remote
router rebooting
and it's come up it's working and then
it suddenly crashes it comes up again
and so forth that kick tends to be a
three to five minute cycle it might even
be longer depending on on the on the
well I suppose the loading of the
neighboring router but that's a sort of
slower bgp cycle time or could be the
remote router bgp process is unstable
and that's just restarting like that
it's possible to another favorite
traffic shaping and rate-limiting ahem
people will rate limit different sizes
of packets that may let little packets
through and me dookey horrendous rate
limiting on big packets and that's going
to affect beach be updates you might be
able to bring the session up but it
could be taking hours and hours and
hours to establish your hundred thirty
thousand prefix feed from your neighbor
what rate limiting on the dream what
traffic shaping are they do I'm empty
use incorrectly settle links so make
sure that path MTU discovery is actually
switched on I'm not sure what all the
routers do but means in Cisco IOS is
disabled by default so you need to
enable that let's see what else for what
if you're not using HDMI frame relay
links I don't know if a great deal of
ATM a frame really links still in use
certainly here in North America but
parts of the world I visit there used
quite a lot and the still can be issues
there as we know with em to you but if
you're not using those links well there
could be issues such as faulty muxes bad
connectors interoperability problems PPP
problems satellite radio weather and so
on and sunday on them poor links you can
get small packets through very easily
but the large ones that are needed by be
to be updated probably won't survive so
there could be issues like that to
trying to send packets through fog or
snow storms or heavy rain and that type
of thing but ping is the type of tool
that's best suited to troubleshooting
this
okay so that's pure establishment that
what what I've described covers most of
the peer establishment problems that
I've come across most of them all are
some are some of those
what about missing routes well once this
session has been established updates or
exchange updates contain all the writing
information that's passed from BGP
speaker to speaker the router will pass
all the locally known routes and
basically along the advertise its best
path to advertise the best path once we
once we've sent everything we know about
we don't only pass on the updates okay
so after the initial flood or 130,000
prefixes or whatever you then only send
updates onwards to your neighbors best
Panthers receive from ebgp peer and you
advertise that to all peers whether
external or Intel the best path through
is received from an internal BGP speaker
that's only either ties to externals
because remember you need a fool ibgp
mesh you don't get an AI BGP speaker
passing a prefix to another ibgp speaker
okay unless of course you get using
route reflectors but I'm going to assume
for this that we're not using a route
reflector and we're not talking about
BGP Confederations either okay so let's
look at these four first one originating
a route common problem occurs from
putting prefixes into the BGP table now
routers will run different routing
processes on them BGP is just one of
them right you've got OSPF for eius eius
static writes and all the rest all these
are used to feed the routing table or
river and then the routing tables used
to build the forwarding table or the fit
okay so BGP table is just one of the
tables and it's the best of all those is
with what you used to go into the
routing table to put a prefix into BGP
you generally have to make sure the
prefix exists in another writing process
as well well
static riot or OSPF or so forth
typically most people do it by having a
static right pointing to customer that
way you put customer rights into your
ibgp for prefixes you want to announce
to the Internet at large it's a static
route pointing to a null interface or
any other type interfacing that will act
as a pull up to let you generate your
aggregate and announce it to the
internet generally the bgp process will
require that the prefix sits in another
in the writing-table before to be
announced or put into the BGP table
that's quite a common one to forget and
again a most my experience is with Cisco
boxes and people will put the network
statement in for BGP completely
forgetting that they need the equivalent
entry in the writing table whether it's
a static right pumped into the customer
or static right pointing to the null to
generate the aggregate both what 1 / 2
is essential what about the update
exchange missing routes well I never
really saw too many problems on to write
for factors came on the scene it's such
a nice solution to help scale BGP but
people seem to enjoy breaking all the
rules all the time I mean whether it's
through bad documentation or just I
don't know trying to take shortcuts or
believing that route reflectors meant
that there are no more rules at all with
an eye bgp but there seem to be so many
issues with route reflectors that people
run into common issues are koala two of
them as the clashing writer ID and the
clashing cluster ID here's one example
we've got to route reflector clusters
router one and three and the first one
router two and four in the second one
router one is the right reflector and
right to choose the right reflector
respective way for the two clusters not
to force advertising a prefix I've said
Network 7/8 here router 2 has the right
but one and three do not you know that
causes lots of head-scratching because
people don't understand why I mean we've
set it all up according to the man
it's all just wonderful our one is not
accepting the right to burn our two
senses onwards and the reason is usually
something like the clashing router idea
our one sees its own right or idea in
the originator attribute and any receive
prefix it will reject that prefix if my
router idea is there that means I've
sent the prefix I'd someone is coming
back to me so I don't want to hear it
again
because I know it's mine okay that's one
of the way it's a riot reflector
attempts to avoid a writing loop and of
course all you've done is you've set up
a router already in the router factor
and then another write reflector cluster
you set the same writer ID by type or
deliberate or otherwise more it's most
usually by type or some people come up
with wonderful strategies to set up
you'll have unique router or ID type
things across the whole network and I
never honestly see the point in doing
that all routers will generate the
router ID automatically it'll get it
from somewhere it's a unique IP address
IP addresses are unique so it could be
from a loopback if you're using a
loopback address parameter or it could
be from one of the physical interfaces
that's all that's an IP address the IP
address will be unique so trying to set
a router ID by hand I don't really see a
great deal of sense in that and most of
the problems I've seen in this case come
from where people will set the router ID
by hand and people who don't set it by
hand they just leave the box to do its
own thing generally don't have this
problem
what about this one router effector
cluster you've got to write reflectors
r1 and r2 of the router effector for the
cluster three and four are the clients
our force doing advertising our one and
three do not see the prefix for the same
thing our one is not accepting the right
when our two sends it on but this time
our one will see its own writer ID in
the cluster ID so
got clashing cluster ID if you set the
cluster ID the same on to route
reflectors in the same cluster then each
route reflectors zooms that you're
running a full mesh from the clients so
each client will appear with the
attractor factor but of course I just
move back what people tend to do is just
say set up client earrings with the red
reflector that's closest and they end up
with black holes in the network the
situation where you the prefix coming
from are - okay that's a very common
problem people trying to set up write
reflectors this way because some of the
original documentation the way way back
said that the way you get rod reflected
under redundancy is to put to write
reflectors in the same cluster and I
mean a lot of people have done that
quite successfully but then they've been
meticulous about making sure that each
client appears with each reflector in
the cluster and well I've never done
that even from the day that write
reflectors first appeared the way I did
it was overlaid my ride reflectors to
clusters overlaid one red reflector per
cluster to foster's pair part of network
and we never we never ever had any
problem like this at all and this
problem only really happens when people
forget to do the full mesh and have dual
redundant bright reflectors in the
cluster so just don't don't do the
jeweled redundancy like this do it by
the overlay and you just won't have this
problem okay filtering you get all sorts
of types of filters on Rogers especially
for BGP you can filter by prefix you can
filter by s path you can filter based on
community also you can also manipulate
attributes and apply policies and so
forth you can apply this in inbound
outbound and these give all your own
class of problems also
if you suspect a filtering problem is
good to become familiar with the router
tools to find out what filters been
applied and how hot tip don't use cut
and paste
I know cut and paste is nice and easy in
all the rest but really it causes so
many problems in fact I've seen more
problems caused cutting and pasting
trying to diagnose filters than anywhere
else okay you can have weird effects
from cut and paste buffers what is in
the cut and paste buffer may not be what
you put in there you could have problems
on the client on the router in when the
connection packers get lost to be trying
to cut a whole big configuration and
paste it over a a lossy link where you
might lose bits of it
who knows meaning that has happened and
that could do weird things to the router
it's generally much better to prepare
your configuration and load it into the
router by some other method T fdp fdp
whatever typos and regular expressions
as one of the common problems extra
characters missing characters whitespace
extra characters is quite common or
getting a minus in place of a plus or
square bracket in places or of our
curved bracket or whatever regular
expressions need to be fairly precise
for doing poetry so if you get them
wrong it can do really worried the weird
stuff and if you see we strange things
happening with your bgp filtering with
your neighbor you're not getting any
prefixes you're getting too many
prefixes it's worth checking your
inbound filters your i-pad filters
really really carefully
you also get typos and prefix filters
watch the Kamat command-line interface
on the router watch the filter logic if
you need to watch the filter logic main
obvious obvious as you think and may not
be as simple as the manual says and this
is my favorite watch the net mass
confusion and the 255 right okay these
days most people are using mask notation
for doing prefixes you're doing Blandy
biodiverse slash 24 but if you're still
using some
rotation it could be 250 400 200 0 and
when you're typing that it can be easy
to mix up to 55 and 0 yes I know they
sound very different but you'll be
amazed how many problems are caused by
people mixing up 0 and 255
alright 2/24 netmask I've seen it quite
often as 255.255.0.0 or even better
still 2 ver 5.2 2 5 2 0 at 0 I don't
know why but those just simply so common
people mix those up all the time and it
caused so many problems avoid them by
using the slash notation the mask
notation you generally can make less
errors doing that make is to make
mistakes but a lot less communities a
lot of is PC using communities but seems
to be each implementation is different
defaults for when communities are sent
some dots to get sent communities
between peers at all Cisco others do for
ibgp and not for ebgp sensible others do
for all BGP peers by default
hmm you need to understand and watch how
your implementation actually handles
communities especially if you're mixing
different brands of router in your
network you need to make sure they all
do the same thing decide what your
default should be and then go from there
don't just say switch ON switch on you
basic configuration off we go right
it just makes troubleshooting harder so
you need to try and understand what the
implicit filtering rules are before you
try and work out with them how to solve
the problems more on communities each is
been as different policies never assume
that the community exists that your
peers will actually use them ok often
peers were advertised that we support
the RFC 1998 style communities if you've
seen any of my other bgp tutorials I
talked a great length but how I as peers
around the world who use communities
just because they say they do it's worth
checking if you sit down try and figure
out why you're standing them 5 or 6
different
is to get them to send you a certain
group of prefixes and you're not getting
them well there could be a reason for
that it's worth asking them first
differentially obeying them and checking
that they actually are obeying them
don't just assume it'll save you a lot
of time in your troubleshooting also
never assume that your peers will pay
attention to the communities you send
I've called it the no export problem
does not mean that your neighbor will
obey it when he may have set something
that says ignore em all communities and
so if you send something with a new
export to your neighbor and he's saying
ignore it
he's gonna send that prefix everywhere
okay so it's cooperation not assumption
how do these all fit into a
troubleshooting well this is about
trying to send prefixes to your
neighbors now it could be neighbor
within your own network if you use
communities for filtering within your
own backbone some ISPs do this they may
carry full prefixes in the core and
maybe just their own prefixes on the
edge and the use communities to do that
filtrate I mean we certainly did
when would you your net okay so when
you're trying to troubleshoot my
prefixes aren't going places or arguing
places when they shouldn't be
check your communities make sure that
the defaults that you've set on your
router are actually there or are still
there when I've seen what something from
Cisco point of view the sand community
directive disappear from configurations
magically and muninn oh I didn't touch
the writer but you know somebody's
logged in and done something by mistake
and have forgotten all the commands as
they backed out of it the magic send
community that forgotten geo communities
not sent to your neighbor so your
neighbor
I cannot apply any policy at all what
you were hoping to do okay
so what you want to do is try and make
and then stay with some simple policy
rules most implementation of particular
rules for filtering prefixes airs paths
and manipulating bgp attributes and yes
they can get really complex situations
in an iOS right maps can be very very
complex certainly with some of the newer
features have been added in there you
can tie yourself in knots very very
easily
I've seen people do that another
implementation stall it's very very
powerful policy language and if you're
using a policy language to apply policy
as well as doing filtering you can get
some really amazing things happen so
when you're designing your policy at
your setup try and set up simple rules
and stick to those ok ibgp mesh problems
well here's here's one example customer
complaints but patch internet access you
can reach some parts of the internet but
not others ok you can get to some of
your backbone but all of your backbone
you can get to some of them to met but
not all of them to net when you see
things like that
movies completely but poor performance
that's nothing to do with EGP usually
but just complaining about or we can get
to half of Europe and you can only see
your West Coast operation or nothing in
the east
you should try and start suspecting ibgp
problems I mean if you see nothing wrong
with your network otherwise try and
suspect an ibgp problem it's more than
likely to be that in this case here the
customers connected to r1 cs3 but you
can't see s2 it also complains about not
being able to see sites connected to our
five so you can see bits in your back
book most of your backbone but not all
of it
and of course typically you get no
complaints from other customers because
this is your really fussy customer who
measures connectivity to your entire
backbone every 30 seconds and sends you
emails when it breaks
and if everybody else's like now your
Internet's broken again in the good way
and make a coffee but so ok no
complaints from other customers just
this one this is like 90% the time this
is an ibgp problem sat certainly in my
own experience the full mesh isn't
complete that's the problem if you look
at it customers connected to r1 if you
can't see a s2 or s2 is connected to
router 3 well that means router 3
somehow not passing writing information
about a s2 to router 1 let's think about
the customer connected to Roger 1 you
can't see tuesday's got no right
information that gets them through to a
s2 you just no idea how to get to
network 10.10 / 24 ok so there's a
problem running between router 3 and
writer 1
you also can't see r5 our customers
connected to R 5 so R 5 is somewhere not
passing writing information about sites
connected to our to our file but you can
see the rest of the internet so the ibgp
is working everywhere else so it's not
that this prefix isn't being injected
into the ibgp properly that's not the
problem is not but where he is connected
to is how his router is connecting to or
there is that router he connects to it
is connecting with in your own backbone
so when you're using a full mesh ibgp
check on every ibgp speaker that it has
a neighbor relationship if you've got 10
writers in your network you'll have 9
ibgp neighbors hundred routers will have
99 ok when you get start get to the
extent of 100 ryos 99 ibgp neighbors
that's a lot of counting that you have
to get to try and do but the point is
when you have a large number
it's easy to miss one especially if you
just have got a random numbering scheme
for all your neighbors if you're using
loopback I Beach ppm clean nuke bags you
number them all sequentially you can
usually spot when ones missing
it's very easy just count from 1 through
200 and if anything apart from you your
local router is missing then you know
you've got a problem okay so in an
example here what was wrong was the
peering with our three speeding with our
one was actually down it was listed as
as down through sewers through some kind
of miss configuration and you can go
back to the early troubleshooting the
dish I did at the start to show you what
that miss configuration could be and of
course router vendors have quite kindly
given you configuration shorthand to
make it easy for example in iOS
you've got peer groups or peer templates
and that makes it it gives you shorthand
and there's like yeah that makes things
work a lot faster but you can also get
mistakes with those as well and when
you're talking about setting up ibgp
some people do a core ibgp and then an
aggregation edge ibgp so you've got
maybe two different peer groups and of
course you could apply the wrong peer
group to the wrong neighbor and you may
even use peer groups through your
external bgp and you may call 1tb GPP
another one i bgp peer and you made
typos the names you actually end up
using the wrong peer group and get
completely different result from what
you're expecting so see the more
shorthand that is there again you've got
the potential for different mistakes
happening so when you're setting up your
ibgp mesh it's worth checking very very
carefully that all the pairings are up
that you're using the correct names the
peer groups and so forth
so say use configuration shorthand for
efficiency and it helps you avoid making
policy errors with an eye bgp mesh
suddenly for a large number of peers is
a tidier configuration if you can use
any shorthand but of course be careful
that you don't introduce typos and these
subroutines themselves this is why
people tend to use route reflectors
these days rather than driving a huge
ibgp mesh we start splitting our network
up into lots of red reflector clusters
and that helps with trying to keep the
number of ibgp peers on each router down
to minimum then of course stick to the
right reflector rules keep them all nice
and simple don't go for complex setups
and situations they'll say here changing
defaults and ignorant ignoring the best
pattern practice techniques just
introduces complexity the thing has been
said here for years and years keep it
simple right if you try and keep
everything as simple as possible
it makes your troubleshooting much much
easier so these are some of the common
situations that you can get with missing
routes ok inconsistent route selection
or the routers got it wrong honest well
for two common problems right selections
inconsistency in other words the router
makes it to suit different gives a
different best path every time or it
just makes a mistake then you're you're
determined the routers got it wrong
well RFC 1771 is still the standard the
BGP standard when the the new RFC is
like also close to actually appearing
was in draft 21 or somewhere now but the
thing is decision algorithm kind of
appeared before BGP was really used
Tillich's BOM to the extent that's being
used today
that's a stupid comment but obviously
the standard has to start somewhere but
we've gained a lot of operational
experience and since it first appeared
and of course every vendor has taken all
this experience that got from the
customers and tweaked the algorithm
and all these tweaks can lead to
interesting interoperability ISM and so
forth because each tweak is slightly
different for example the RFC says that
the meed is not always compared and as a
result the ordering of the paths can
affect the decision process for example
the default in iOS is to compare the
prefixes in order of arrival well the
RFC didn't see anything else
so what do we do so we just compare them
in the order of arrival the most recent
to the oldest and of course this will
result an inconsistent path selection if
you reset Abby to be peering then the
prefixes arrived from the reset period
become the newest and then your best
path may change pretty much will change
and so something is bees have got large
numbers of connections between them
they'll see the best exit possible
whoops
the best exit go from here to there to
there back to here depending on where
they did the maintenance which is highly
annoying because the symptom is that the
best path changes every time and no it's
not a bug it's just well that's what the
implementation does and yes it can cause
problems routing loops convergence loops
changes and traffic patterns the latter
is probably the most annoying one for
people and if you've never seen this
before
I mean you just have sleepless nights
and days and nights and even more days
trying to figure out what it is but in
this case the vendors provided a simple
workaround because enough people
complained about it that the
deterministic meed configuration was
added in there and so what happens now
is the router will give you the same
answer every time it doesn't do the edge
comparison it does the comparison based
on es number so smallest s number all
the way up to the largest is how the
comparison is no done so for example in
this picture router I've got three paths
to get to a s10 ok the meds from es 3
are not compared with the meds from a s1
you only compare a media fits from the
same
of course there's a hack to work around
that we don't like that either Roger a
will sometimes select the path from
router one is the best but may also
select the path in router 3 is the best
depending when you reset the session so
you have got the best path oscillating
back and forth between router 3 and
Roger 1 which is not good in if you've
got expensive links connecting your s 2
to s 3 and 1 you've got this traffic
slowing back and forward depending when
you do your maintenance very unpleasant
so if you enable the the knob that was
provided with deterministic med 1 then
the paths are ordered by neighboring a s
and then the best path is the same every
time it's worked on per net neighbor a s
group and no matter when you do your
reset or - do your resets or your
maintenance on your edge routers you'll
always get the same best path selection
result I mentioned this one quite a bit
because it has been quite a common
problem that well something that I've
come across and it's all one of the
reasons why you know the fix is provided
to the best path selection or maybe
knobs provide to the best path selection
that may make a lot of sense for your
network Geron part of the
troubleshooting here is well if you do
this then you don't have to troubleshoot
this problem but if you see this problem
this is the particular solution to it ok
and then yes just the diagram what the
solution is this time with with that
knob applied a s1 path is always the one
that is chosen because of the ordered
according to s numbers s1 will beat the
2's es3 best paths ok second example
best path changes every time the peering
is reset well again there's something
else not specified in RFC by default
that all this external is the best path
okay that's just once there in iOS I
mean if the all this all this path is
the best one well as stability I mean
though this one has been there for ages
and ages and ages but as a new ones
flapping up and down while you don't
particularly
type your traffic slewing to the new one
and then back to the old and and so
forth but again this can be annoying too
so you can disable this by enforcing it
to conform to what the RFC actually
stipulates and others comparing the
writer ID but it's just difficult when
people have asked for particular
enhancements that dual counter to what's
being written down but then other people
want to do work according to the RFC
depending on particular situation it
just depends on how networks configured
how the external relationships are so
this could be another potential problem
we see the best path changing every time
that peering is reset that's an issue
for you then it might be this particular
thing that that's causing the problem
and the third one is only peculiar to my
dear employer path one is hire local
preference but path two is better
always because IRS has synchronization
on by default in synchronization is an
ancient historical thing that's still
there by default unfortunately basically
if a prefix is not synchronized in other
words it doesn't appear in I GP as well
as in BGP
it's not going to be considered for the
best path process this is like the 101
that catches out everybody who tries to
deploy BGP on I on a Cisco router but
doesn't read the documentation okay they
forget the no synchronization command is
necessary for Cisco tech have you done
the new synchronization
oh I didn't know how to do that I mean
it doesn't say anywhere that you've got
to do that okay historical default is
still on that's there to catch everybody
out and what's happened is
synchronization is part of the best path
process if you don't disable it then it
will be included the preface is doctor
peer in your eye GP as well as a BGP and
the Roger appears those making the wrong
decision because sync because the
synchronization test is done before the
local preference check
okay so summary of that RFC isn't
perfect when it comes to path selection
you probably know that just from
operational experience but that's fine
we shouldn't be surprised Ben does a
nice piece of work to put instability
enhancements you know vendors are
generally asked to or pushed into doing
these enhancements or knobs whatever you
want to call them but these can lead to
interesting problems too
and of course some defaults linger on
much much longer than than they have any
right to do so so again watch the
default that your box actually comes
configured with because they can cause
issues also finally loops and
convergence issues one of the most
common problems every minute routes flap
in the routing table from one hop to
next one with full routes most obvious
symptom is just a high CPU on the the
bgp process and typically it's something
like this router fee will prefer yes for
one minute and then a minute later
router 3 prefers by it's pretty s12 and
then back to a s4 and it oscillates
between the two different and exit parts
on a pretty much one minute basis what's
going on
well this symptom is almost always
caused by the BGP next stop being known
only by BGP one of the rules is that the
BGP next hop must be known by another
way it cannot be known by BGP okay it's
a common problem we when this first hit
me about I think was seven years ago I
first came across this one me it took me
two days to figure out what was actually
going on and it wasn't actually aware
that that that was what it was it was
just a bizarre problem of traffic
oscillating between our two exit points
in London it didn't bother me too much
but it's the 80% CPU and the right of it
causing bit of problems and customers
are complaining about big round trip
times so we had to try and figure out
what it was and it was simply because
the next hop was only known by BGP
because somebody removed a static route
and it was some dish some meat removed a
static route and it was it was as simple
as that okay so the BGP next hop was
known via BGP which is an illegal
recursive lookup and what's happening
was the scanner will notice that the BGP
next hop is known only by BGP so it'll
drop that path so your toilet of path is
known via the IGP so it will install
that but then of course your next hop
which was known as BGP is then valid so
then it will be reinstalled as the best
next bar exit point
so you just oscillate back and forth
with between these two okay and it just
goes on and on forever and the reason
it's one minute because in Cisco IOS
this kind of runs every one minute so
that's why you have this one minute
cycle time so if you see this one minute
cycle time you're using Cisco boxes in
your network it's going to be this more
than likely so make sure all the BGP
next tops are known by the IGP whether
it's OSPF or eius eius or static or
connected drives the next stop is also
an IP GP ensure the ibgp distance is
longer than IGP distance that catches a
lot of people hunt I mean with when I
bgp distance is set much much smaller
than cos pi/4 is ours you can end up
with this problem
because i bgp becomes more important
than the IGP which quite frankly should
it should never be or don't and carry
don't carry external next hops in your
network use next hop self-concept in
other words you change the next hop for
externally learned prefixes to the
router itself right so you don't have to
carry your neighbors IP address in your
backbone because he may be sending you
the point-to-point link by bgp as well
or an aggregate of the punch
that can cause weird stuff to happen
Nuth what actually bit us because our
peer was sending us the network that was
the ebgp next hop by BGP of course when
the person the person who was doing the
tidy up of the network configuration saw
that we already heard this prefix by BGP
Wow why did Phillip put the static right
in there so you took it out and well of
course the configuration was like yeah
huge and did I spot that all that that
static one static out of like 60 or 70
other statics and the box were missing
no so I didn't even didn't do that of
course what I should have done which I
finally did about 36 hours later was
looked back through the RCS log that we
kept to the configuration
static great was missing yeah that's
what it was put it back in and this
oscillation disappeared but this is done
external next ops within your own
network ok so that's the general summary
of high CPU utilization bgp process use
the convergence problem find a prefix
that is changing a lot if you can do a
show on that particular prefix and if
it's changing a lot like last update was
within a minute or two trying to
troubleshoot or do debugging on that
particular preface find out what is
doing what's happening - okay we've got
a BGP routing loop first check for IGP
routing loops to the beach would be next
hops
BGP loops tend to be caused by while not
visit falling the physical topology and
write reflectors environments some
people love to have route reflectors
just like one router effect and their
whole network of 500 routers that's well
yeah okay that maybe works some of the
time but then you end up with a red
reflector definitely not connected to
any of its clients by a physical point
of park link and that can end up with
lots of trouble and it can be caused by
using bgp multipath within
confederations I mean
not so much lack of a fool ibgp mesh is
a classic for causing writing rhythms
and then to try and figure try and
troubleshoot some of this have a look at
the writing table entry remember the
routing table is not the same as the BGP
table look at the BGP table entry check
the right to the next hop is it know
about BGP is you know IGP doesn't exist
then finally in this section convergence
problems here's the first example you've
got a right to factor with 215 clients
it's not unreasonable hundred thousand
prefixes and just BGP will not converge
at all log showed the neighbor hold
times have expired
okay the bgp router suddenly will show
that peers will establish drop
re-establish a timeout and so forth and
it's not the MTU problem we saw earlier
okay this is another manifestation of
this problem and here were either
missing hellos or the peers are not
sending them we're missing the keep
alive or missing some information like
that and here you don't blame BGP you
look further down check the in check for
interface input drops for example the
number is a large number got huge number
of drops in interface and interface
counters are showing recent history then
this could be the cause of the PIO swim
tank a large number of drops large
number of packets are being dropped on
the router and this could be due to the
input queue being too small and each
interface will have some buffer
associated with it if the buffers not
big enough example you've got 250 peers
there 250 peers Center who lose all at
the same time you've got 250
conversations with the local ratchet
you've got to try and handle if your
buffer can only take say 75
conversations then what happens to the
other a hundred and well whatever 140 or
so
okay they get lost oops so yeah sorry I
missed the solution the solution is
basically to increase the size of the
input queue so you can handle all the
communications that you have with your
actual peers okay just make it a big
number much much bigger than a number of
peers that you have especially you're
trying to deploy right reflector typed
networks like this the defaults are too
small second example BGP converges in 25
minutes for 250 peers and 100,000 brats
we know it's not using a motorola
processor anymore it's something that
should be nice and fast on them from the
modern day so rather than just say a
wall it's slow Hardware try and actually
figure out what was going on within the
TCP process and check the MSS size and
able path MTU discovery on the router if
it's not on by default okay that's quite
important before empty you something
Cisco's is Wow MSS is 536 which means
that the router needs to send almost
three times the amount of packets
compared with an MSS of 14 60 which is
what could be possible over an Ethernet
connection and if you do that you're
missing we find that you see BGP
converging about half the time 10
minutes or so is pretty good for 250
peers and a full routing table for each
peer so that's some of the possible
problems you could find as some of the
workarounds
I suppose it's less troubleshooting than
saying well here's a possible problem
that you can get and here's the actual
solution to do to deal with it right in
the final 15 minutes I'm just going to
have a quick look at some of the
internet reachability problems this is
less of the local network and more how
you go about troubleshooting problems
with between your network and other
networks on the internet and that's
quite an important part of
troubleshooting also
um well the first one is a BGP attribute
confusion um in people come to these BGP
tutorials at nano oak and we tell them
all about local preference and any DS
and es path prepend and then they go
away
I drew a lots of workshops I do lots of
other trainings and the amazing thing is
people completely confuse what the
different attributes are actually useful
if you were to control have traffic
flows in to your network you need to
send any DS and s path pre parents or
whatever to your neighbor quite often I
see people try and use em EDS in the S
Pen path prepend just how to control
traffic going onto the network and I'm
not completely clear how that's meant to
work routing information flows not as a
direction of traffic very very important
fundamental concept now I tell people no
of all walks of life about this and some
yeah sometimes feels them insulting
people by telling them this is the sort
of thing but I've seen seasoned
engineer's completely forget that basic
rule routing information goes that away
traffic will flow in the opposite
direction very very important to
remember that remember that for trying
to do troubleshooting then actually
makes troubleshooting and multihoming
and transit and so forth so much easier
right as as I've said in many words here
multihoming and transit travel shootings
often happen because the relationship
between writing information flow and
traffic flow is forgotten
all right I'm laboring the point because
people forget this far too often path
selection process and kind of talked
about before each band has tweaked the
path selection process you really got to
learn what it is for your equipment if
you're using multi vendor try and make
it usually consistent amongst all the
routers you use any de confusión
default a medium Cisco IOS
is zero in other words if you don't
specify any any immediate all it is zero
it may not be this on your own writer
okay or your peer you
pmas you and meed of 2032 - one as the
default another was huge very
unimportant where's mi d of zero is very
important so you can end up with pretty
interesting writing loops if you just
leave the for immediate or one default
to zero in other ones - 332 minus one
communicant community confusion if you
set community it does just that it will
set the community to something it
overwrites anything else that's set on
the prefix so something iOS you can use
an additive keyword to add communities
to those that you've learned figure out
what you want to do for you on equipment
also use the internet format for
community in other words a s number call
on community number rather than than the
32-bit ITR format the internet format is
kind of easier to read understand humans
are not too hot when it comes to looking
at 32-bit numbers whereas two 16-bit
numbers are kind of easier to handle
Cisco IOS never sent community by
default all those do ok figure out what
it is never assume that your neighbor is
going to bear your no export you may
overwrite any community u s-- and so if
you're going to use new export make sure
your neighbor knows that you're gonna
use no export yes path prepends twenty
pre parents won't less than approach of
your path any more than ten pre parents
well but lots of people out there you
seem to think doing a twenty thirty
forty fifty time prepend means that it
definitely won't be used well I have
news if it's the only path from the
writing table it's going to be used no
matter how long the pick the s path is
okay let's say the Internet's on average
is only five es is deep maximum a s path
prepend most ISPs need to do is about
five or six also and in fact semis use
these days lashley truncate the a s well
they want truncate they'll throw away
prefixes that are more than fifteen or
twenty guesses long okay so i've thrown
in the cisco version of the commander to
chop out those prefixes just be aware
that some ISP
actually do this so doing a 50 times
pre-paint is a waste of time
private ESS should not ever appear in
internet like private address space
this should get oust so again the
vendors have come to the aid of people
using private ESS for local reasons in
the network example is to remove private
es command but it only did that would
want to move every instance of a private
es so if you get a private ear
sandwiched between two public es numbers
that's not going to be strip type
because that's a configuration error
okay so you've got to watch that also
right let's look at some connectivity
problems symptoms this s ones announcing
a network 181 succeed 1/24 to s 2 but a
s 3 can't see it okay good you got your
friend or somebody like that or some of
your customers trying to reach in a s 3
and well your nights in the network but
a s 3 can't see it this will introduce
the checklists
go to try and set up a checklist to see
how we're going to work through this
so yes 1:9 says but does he has to see
it well here we're checking the ebgp
filters on roger 1 and writer to writer
ones and es one writer 2 is an es to
remember that you need writer to access
to do this that doesn't mean you send an
email to your neighboring highest PNC or
you give me access to your router you'll
ask him I'm trying to troubleshoot
blah-dee-blah
do you see this network on your
neighboring router and if they do well
then ask them to give you a show output
for that prefix does es to see it over
the entire network while he would check
in ibgp across s two's network mainly in
this particular example is not needed
because we've only got one writer but
most are ESPYs have a large ibgp
mesh quite often IBG peaceful
misconfigured it could be a bright
reflective problem it could be a lot i
BG be mashed problem things that I've
covered earlier in the presentation
ok you want to check through some of the
things that I
I've mentioned before but about the ibgp
mesh does as2 send it to as3 he were
checking ebgp configuration Roger to
towards writer three as it filters or s
path filters of prefix list of
communities or something like that
causing a problem does as3 see all of a
s - s originated prefixes he were
checking ebgp configuration in router 3
maybe s 3 doesn't know to expect
prefixes from a s 1 but you can't go
send you an email to a s 3 saying am I'm
trying to remove them because they're
gonna say who you you're just somebody
else in the Internet
another of the 16,000 es is out there G
you can need to rely on your near boat
yes - - they work with a s 3 to figure
out what's going on cooperation okay so
troubleshooting connectivity beyond
immediate peers is much harder relies on
you appear to assist you
they have relationship with the peers
not you ok so sending the email saying I
is not gonna work might mean people are
generally friendly and cooperative and
helpful in Internet so they may be
sympathetic whether they may choose to
ignore you as well okay what about this
s1 announces picked a real network this
was my DSL network at home that law is
no more but anyway was my DSL network at
home so it's a bit more of a real
example the ass is still on feel better
so I'm announcing this to the upstreams
in Internet but the air street can't see
the network at all s1 announces do the
upstream see it
checking ebgp blah blah blah blah ok we
need supporter here up streams to
actually try and do this is the prefix
visible anywhere on the Internet well
that's a harder ask now this doesn't
mean you go sending lots of emails to
everybody on the internet saying do you
see my prefix
next slide is actually going to show how
you do that the looking blast the
looking-glass is probably the most
valuable important tool for
troubleshooting BGP outside of your
network there are many networks around
the globe which will run a looking-glass
they basically at UC BGP table and often
like to run simple ping or trace writes
from them as well www.redcross.org boss
what's all the sites that well the
collector actually knows of for Frankie
before and there's an equivalent site
for all the ipv6 looking-glasses as well
they mostly trace right but some of them
will also actually let you see the BGP
output from them many people still use
the original nitrous to dodge X net
which is the first lookingglass that I
was certainly aware of ok so I've got
some examples if you've never seen a
lookingglass before while I just picked
the right Ben CeCe's wrist service just
because it was there so you got
something like that you've got various
sites you can go to as you see in this
screenshot that's just a lot of things
well about a year or so old now but
those were the sites that they they had
a present size you could go to any of
those routers and have a look at the
writing-table and then I went to the RC
0-1 box at the links which is in London
and did a show IP BGP for my two or
three 51 206 Network and there we have I
put 4 - 3 42 0 / 14 and it's heard from
three different neighbors so the three
possible paths to it that means that
this Looking Glass I can see that my
network with being a nice as part of a /
14 aggregate so this is that was
complaining that it couldn't see my
network the problem is more likely to be
closer to them it's something nowhere
near here because here they can look for
three possible paths or we're back to -
Australia
okay so the looking glass' can see the
14 so the problem must be closer to a s3
and a trace right confirms the
connectivity so here I've done a traced
right from the from lookingglass and
starts at London and then goes to the
task for network all the way up to
Brisbane ok so that's the sort of thing
that you can do and you can see from a
list fingers show BGP BGP summary
neighbors you can put regular
expressions in you can tell the paths
I'm not sure how the version useful but
you can do trace route and pink that's
that's typical of most of the looking
glasses you get around the internet
another place you can go to is right
views I've I use right views and the
nitrous Looking Glass site from my early
days because they've been around for a
long long long time and right for use -
the real router that you can log into
and well when I put the slide together
it had around 60 peers it could well be
more than that we'll find out in the
next couple of days but another report
on the right views system okay again
WWWF used to org explains what the
projects about you get access to real
writers are saying so you can do a show
IP BGP or it can do a trace or whatever
else you want to do okay so that's the
two places you can go but looking glass
and alright views
extremely viable and letting you find
out problems and on the global scale for
the network reach ability right getting
back to the here right does s3s upstream
sender to es3 well what you do is you
try and find out from the a s path hue
s3 is upstream is because e s3 is
announcing networks so you can find out
from them what the s path is and then
you can try and figure out from there
upstream if they can see the prefix if
if s3 is upstream is running a looking
last big book looking-glass there
and you can see if you can see it if
they're not that tryingo as close as you
can
does the s3 see any of ayres ones
originated prefixes I mean if they can't
see you a particular slash 24 can they
see anything from you at all okay and
that way you meet there may be some type
of filtering that's going on in s3
somewhere they may be specifically
brought blocking your network who knows
okay troubleshooting across the Internet
is generally harder but the tools that
you've got of all the looking-glasses
traceroute ping BGP status and so forth
available all over the globe I have no
idea how many looking glasses there are
I mean to be honest I haven't looked at
the trace driver org website in quite a
while because I mean I've got my
favourites that Hughie's that they're in
my browser and that's it that's all I
really need to deal with but those I'm
sure there's at least one in every
country of the world if not close closer
to that so it should allow the vast
majority of situations to be dealt with
okay what about this third example the
s-1 is trying to load share between his
up streams but it's trouble getting
traffic through the s2 link while you're
trying to find what trouble means
getting a report from a customer saying
trouble there's like oh yeah information
please it sideband traffic load sharing
okay so you can usually fix this by
selectively rejecting prefixes
that's all multihoming okay that's it's
not really a troubleshooting thing
that's trying to configure a multihoming
that's easy to fix
inbound traffic load sharing is harder
to do okay
and yes I mean you can do s path pre
pans and you can fiddle around with
communities and ME DS and leaking sub
prefixes and all the rest standard
multihoming practice and click
configuration practice did they do
nothing then you've got to look deeper
yes one analysis but does s2 see it
checking the filters were working
through the checklist again okay same
checklists does he has to send it
upstream checking configuration
checklist when I'm going through the
process of checking these
checklist in any how does the internet
see all of us to s originated prefixes
for checking EB cheaper configuration by
looking on other Internet routers which
usually means looking at the looking
glasses they're the best ways of trying
to find out what's going on okay
checklist repeat all of those above for
a s3 okay of course what happens then
people will do that and then they say
hmm no dear okay let's do a huge prepare
and that will solve the problem it's not
going to as I said before huge prepend
if you the only path it's not gonna make
any difference whatsoever so here you
try and break it down to smaller pieces
the s2 is not seeing s once prefix or
it's blocking it and inbound filters
okay so that's fairly obvious what
you've got to try and do there so you
just go to your neighbor and see yeah
boy fix this if there's a trickle of
inbound traffic well if you're around to
support something like net flow where
you can see the actual traffic flow the
source destination address of all the
packets coming into your into your
network switch it on have a look where
where the packets coming from is it just
from your upstream ISP and nowhere else
then he's probably not announcing your
prefix out to his peers okay look for
the clues and some of the other tools
that are available if they claim that
they are announcing it ask their
upstream if they'll answer you or just
use a lookingglass because it's bound to
be one close bar if there's a light flow
of traffic commuters to but say 50% less
than from es3 use the looking-glasses to
try and figure out what's going on there
meaning maybe communities that are
setting weights onto the different
prefixes that could be filters going on
anything like that I'll try and use net
flow to figure out the source address of
the packets that are coming in to the
network and you can see what what's
going on
okay example four don't quite have time
to go through this but again
looking-glasses try and figure out layer
two problems right flap damping can
cause an issue as well okay but flap
damping can cause interesting and
unknown things to happen on the network
it can cause situations that may be a
transient it could be causing problems
for an hour or so and then they
disappear altogether and you're not
quite sure what's going on okay as I say
many ISPs will actually implement right
flap damping many ISPs use the vendor
defaults I'm of the opinion that vendor
defaults are far too severe we've got
the right 59 virus which a working group
of us put together well it's been going
for a few years now but right digitizing
it it's document and there's opinion
that those even are too severe as enough
in that paper there again try and look
at looking glasses looking glasses you
can display the flap damping this is
from the nitrous dye Jake's net looking
glass these prefixes happy on the router
have no gone but we're hanging on for
historical reasons okay damping can
cause issues
but then we can cause connectivity to
persist the alternative paths even
though the primary paths have been
restored you got to kind of watch it the
common symptom is bizarre routing that
will just clear up automatically in an
hour or so and you think well well what
nuts going on here okay so try and be
aware of that and there's not a lot you
can do about it you might be able to try
and persuade your upstream to clear the
damping settings that he has but it
could be more often a problem somewhere
else in the wider net I'm just nothing
you can do about it apart from just let
it slip by so just a quick summary of
all this most troubleshooting is about
well experience unfortunately this is
why I've never really but have been
asked to give a an advanced
troubleshooting tutorial but as I said
previously advanced troubleshooting it's
like that become so specific to each
individual network it's probably not
interesting to other people or if it is
interesting it's hard to apply to other
networks and then some of the advanced
problems may be the operators who have
them are not too willing to share on the
particular issues that they had but
anyway so what I'm really trying to do
is give you the basics so try and build
up experience use some of those simple
tricks and concepts that I've mentioned
here not panicking is really important
and panicking you tend to end up making
more mistakes so just try and stay cool
you'll get an ice cream or something
like that and then come back and think
through it logically check the
configuration first the big
configuration problem check locally at
first before blaming your peer I mean
yes your customers will blame you of the
internet breaks but they don't know how
it works I mean you should just go and
blame somebody else try and make sure
that what you've brought is fine
first and then troubleshoot to start at
the bottom layer one two three you may
have to do layer 89 troubleshooting
before you look at your own stuff but
try and work through it and logical
steps
use the tools available so the debugging
tools in the router hardware internet
looking lastest
ask colleagues ask friends on the net
ask public mailing list for appropriate
ok so that's what we covered closing
comments well blah blah blah miss that
for sake of town that's where the
presentations are again if you missed it
at the start and there on the Nano
website there also on that FTP site as
well and that is it thank you for we're
staying 5 minutes I hope that was useful
go to any questions feel free to send me
email or catch me I'll be here for the
rest of the week including their own
meeting so if you want to ask questions
let me know
previous slide back up