for told me that probably the confused
before where I was confused with people
not raising their hands was might be
because people don't usually use IPSec
within their ISP infrastructure you know
per se except for remote VPN access but
again you know you are configuring IPSec
and what I have found in the last few
years is that there's so much confusion
because there's so many different ways
that people will configure IPSec or the
terminology that they use that III try
to you know unconfuse people at least
say you know here's what the spec
actually is here's what terminology
people use that essentially mean the
same thing okay and that will be
clarified in just a couple of minutes
one thing that I do want to point out
and if you guys have your laptops and
you know want to type this or go check
out the the site right now there is the
VPN consortium okay it's run by Paul
Hoffman and you can get to it by VPN see
org if you look on that particular site
there somewhere on the right-hand corner
there's a whole bunch of you know other
places you can get to and one of them
I'm trying to think it's something like
implementation examples or conformance
examples something like that
click around but what he basically did
about a year and a half ago was he
decided that you know it's so hard like
everybody has these different
configuration requirements and he wanted
to do some kind of intesting but you
know why should he spend days trying to
figure out how to configure all these
different devices so he set up a sample
scenario which is basically two gateways
talking to each other doing tunnel mode
IPSec and what he had was most of the
vendors that are part of the consortium
should then send in configuration
templates in terms of how to configure
to this specific scenario and why that's
really useful is that if you have these
different devices then at least you can
figure out you know how do you configure
your your king your ike phase one your
Ike phase two and what are the
terminology that they use
so again VPN c.org you know and there's
a whole there's probably about 15
vendors on there and actually a year and
a half ago I did the net bsd
configuration for him you know
installing raccoon and all that kind of
fun stuff because i was just starting to
play with with a bunch of stuff so it's
very very useful if you're starting to
configure IPSec or you know you've kind
of been holding off because you haven't
had the time yet to figure out you know
how to configure it and on different
machines so anyway okay IPSec whole
bunch of RSC's that define it what does
it provide so at the network layer right
it provides confidentiality and there's
a whole bunch of algorithms to choose
from des is still mandatory within the
standard but basically a lot of people
use Triple DES okay most implementations
have that so even if you look at what
the standard does it's kind of
interesting because a lot of the the
must and the algorithms that they have
to use and maybe some people use that as
the default it may not be the best
algorithm and my point in my perspective
on security in this day and age is that
use the strongest algorithm the largest
key and if you run into a performance
issue then you know start to go lower
but if you do not have a performance
issue I don't see any reason why you do
not use the most secure strongest
algorithm and the longest key and you
know if you're running OC you know I
don't know 12 links and you have a lot
of data and you might have performance
issues if you're actually encrypting
everything yes that will be an issue but
if you have T ones T threes and you know
you're using hardware encryption you may
not have any kind of performance issue
just pick the strongest algorithms and I
will later have some examples of the
the parameters to pick and again with an
IPSec or it is really a pain in the butt
is that most vendors have different
defaults so you're going to have to
change them anyway if you're in a
multi-vendor environment so alright so
IPSec provides confidentiality and then
data integrity and source authentication
there is anti replay protection but it's
optional so the sender can can say that
yeah I want to provide anti replay
protection but the recipient can
actually ignore it key management ike is
used for key management and it
negotiates sessions and establishes them
the sessions are Rekia or deleted
automatically secret keys are securely
established and authenticated ok using
diffie-hellman we discussed that earlier
and the remote peer can be authenticated
using varying options I was just talking
to somebody a couple of minutes ago we
were talking about manual keying versus
automatic keen automatic keying is is
Ike ok manual king means that you are
actually configuring your sha in your
md5 and those parameters you know the
whatever 40 bit values and if I talk
about manual King that does not equate
to pre-shared keys okay that's something
completely different
so for IPSec you can use manual King
where you enter these large god-awful
strings and then you know determine what
your keys are for encryption and for
data origin authentication unless you
are very well-versed with the algorithm
algorithms and have you know maybe less
than five devices that will talk to each
other with IPSec you should not use that
and you should really use Ike
so a security Association NSA is very
integral to IPSec and basically groups
elements of a conversation together and
what it does is basically defines a
group of parameters for the
authentication algorithm the encryption
algorithm the lifetime how long the
session is valid form that you use
certain encryption keys and also whether
or not you're using transport or tunnel
mode and typically it maps from a host
to a gateway and from a host or a
gateway it maps to a particular IP
destination address and you know you can
define whether or not you use
authentication only or if you have
confidentiality and I have some slides
that describe more about a H and ESP so
these unfortunately have not been
defined adhere a spy number it's just
used locally okay this is not really
something that you need to know so I'm
just nice to get that IP traffic
selectors this is important you may not
want to encrypt everything if you have
very large links and you do run into
some kind of a performance issue right I
mean you might just say you know
something the only traffic that I really
care about providing confidentiality for
is maybe my telnet traffic in between
routers okay because some people are
doing that they are instead of using SSH
okay they are using telnet protected
with IPSec because what you don't want
any of your password information to go
across any wires and the clear so even
though I said do not ever use telnet
well there's a caveat if it's protected
okay in some kind of a secure tunnel ie
IPSec then it's okay now the problem is
most people don't do that because IPSec
is a nightmare to configure and you know
even within certain big vendors if you
have different IPSec devices they may
not interoperate with each other right
even out of the box they might have
different defaults or things like
that so IPSec is a real pain in the butt
because there isn't really an
interoperable easy way for people to get
IPSec to work and you know vendors are
working to make it easier but you know
it's it's it's it's still hard but so
anyway selectors for traffic matches you
can define what traffic you want
encrypted so maybe you just want telnet
or SN impede traffic encrypted right so
you can actually define that so your the
three main components of IPSec there is
something called the aah and that's the
authentication header and essentially
what that does it provides for data
origin authentication and integrity of
the packet so that if you're sending
something from a sender to a receiver
the receiver can be more or less ensured
that the data hasn't been altered in
transit now ESP was originally defined
to add confidentiality so the thought
was that you would use a H for your
integrity and then ESP for
confidentiality but as people started
using the standard and implementations
you know came to market it became very
clear that things are just really
difficult and convoluted and so what
people did was they modified the ESP
standard so that you can actually do a
thent ocation you can do null encryption
which means you don't provide for data
confidentiality but you essentially also
but you essentially provide for data
origin integrity so some people want to
do away with a H because they think that
it causes too much of an issue you know
it makes the protocol too complex and
what most people do is they actually use
ESP so you also and then the third
portion that's important is Ike which is
a internet key exchange so it's how you
actually derive your
session keys so with the aah portion ok
the authentication is implied to the
entire packet with the exception of some
fields that get modified in transit
right so if you think about the IP
header there's fields like the flags and
an offset and type of service and as you
traverse many hops at the network layer
they can get modified so these can't be
used as as part of the authentication
check so again this will just be an FYI
if you really care what the header looks
like so so eh again you know it provides
for just basically integrity check that
data hasn't been modified and that the
sender is who you think it is
so with ESP you either encrypt and/or
authenticate each packet the encryption
occurs before authentication so that you
can actually encrypt and then you can
authenticate and as a passes different
hops you can then verify the
authentication so again here's an ESP
header format it's more of an FYI I
don't think it's necessary for me to go
through that so here's a example of how
packets are altered if you're just using
plain you know IP packets and then if
they're altered for a H and in transport
mode so before applying a H you have the
original IP header you have your
transport header either TCP or UDP and
then you have your data portion so after
applying a H you still have your
original IP header you then have
following that the a H header and that
follows in the rest of the packet your a
transport layer on the new data and the
fields that aren't a part of the
authentication are the five listed there
which is a type of service TTL header
checksum offset and flags okay but
everything besides those fields
Afeni cated so for ESP okay
essentially this usually adds
confidentiality so where I say encrypted
okay it's encrypted for confidentiality
and then the fields below that I say
authenticated that's what's
authenticated so when you're using ESP
the encrypted portion is your transport
layer and your data and also the piece
of the ESP trailer and what's
authenticated is also the addition of
the ESP header all right now IPSec can
be used either in transport or tunnel
mode okay transport mode essentially was
meant for a client to a from an
originator to the recipient and tunnel
mode was essentially created in
scenarios where it would be gateway to
gateway communication so the first
scenario that I just showed for
transport mode would be for example if
you wanted to use from router to router
right telnet protected with IPSec but if
you have a network behind the router and
you're going to another piece of your
network let's say a customer network and
they have a VPN and if they have a
gateway then what you probably want to
do is you want to do tunnel mode IPSec
and so this is what the packets would
look like if you're using tunnel mode
IPSec where again with authentic with
using the authentication header you
would authenticate everything even the
new header that's added on because
remember if you're tunneling right then
your new header would have to
incorporate which of the Gateway IP
address is a source and the destination
it's not the actual
source and destination right of the
packet itself
and then this is the same thing for
tunnel mode if you're doing ESP but
that's you know that's just sort of FYI
the internet key exchange
Eike Eike I think is the most confusing
thing in the world right and they've now
finished I could be too it's very
unclear whether or not people will
actually ever use Ike v2 and the reason
why is because as people started doing
the you know analysis of what does I
could be to buy u over V one it doesn't
really buy you very much so you know if
you're talking to your vendors and
you're trying to figure out oh you know
I just figured out IPSec I don't know do
I upgrade my image just because you know
it now includes Ike B to be very clear
in terms of what it buys you and what
vendors are doing because from my
personal talks with people it looks to
me like IP two is more or less going to
be a checklist okay and most people will
just end up using IP one so just an FYI
be very clear on that
you know don't listen to marketing food
but really try to understand what I
could be to would buy you so the thing
with Ike alright and why it's so
confusing is because there's two phases
to it
there's Ike phase one and there's Ike
phase two phase one Ike all right some
vendors call it Ike some vendors call it
is a K&P all right they're the same
thing it's Ike phase one and I think the
reason why the controversy or the the
where the problem came in is because is
a KMP is a framework for how to do the
internet key exchange Ike is a specific
implementation of is a KMP so as an
engineer was coding up you know the
internet key exchange stuff you know
depending on what their thought process
was somebody said okay it's is a KMP
other people said it's AI
soin is a KMP tunnel equals an IKE
tunnel equals an IKE phase one tunnel
right phase two
also there's people that either call it
Ike phase two or they call it the IPSec
tunnel and so what I craze one does Ike
phase one sets up a secure tunnel so the
two piers can then have a secured way of
negotiating the keys and the algorithms
that they will actually use to provide
authentication and confidentially
confidentiality for their data okay
which is then Phase two and let me go
through that a little bit more but I
tell you if once you just understand
what the terminology is I think things
become a lot clearer
so overview of Iook here's a picture so
you've got two IPSec peers and traffic's
coming in from the pier on the left and
you want to create a secure tunnel IP
using IPSec to then communicate to the
IPSec peer to the right so what happens
is you go through a phase one so there's
a number of parameters that you can
define you can say okay I want to
provide data confidentiality using
either des triple des some kind of a
secret key technology okay you also can
do data origin authentication you can
define either sha md5 you can define a
parameter which is the diffie-hellman
group okay which is the mod P group
which basically means that okay how how
big as how big of my prime numbers are
going to be if you will recall way back
about an hour and a half ago when I
showed the diffie-hellman slide right a
device has to come up with two numbers
there are two prime numbers that it then
sends to the other side
the fee helman the two common sizes for
these prime numbers are 768 bits and
1024 768 bits is the diffie-hellman
group 1 equals mod p group 1 and some
devices ok the 124 bits is you know
diffie-hellman group 2 mod p 2 okay I
don't know you know I don't understand
the people that came up with this
terminology but you know essentially in
one run router you configure mod p group
the other wonderful Hellman group and I
don't know you know the defaults vary
among different devices and so the first
thing that you need to do is really
figure out for yourself what is it that
you want to use and I will have a slide
later that says you know this is
typically what i I just configure for
everything so you have your
diffie-hellman group you have your
authentication your integrity algorithm
you have your confidential a
confidentiality algorithm and you have
your lifetime and usually that's what
you configure for Ike phase one and then
you have a secure tunnel now you go
ahead and try to figure out all right
well what do I want to do to now
establish how do I want to encrypt my
traffic right and again you define which
authentication algorithm do you want to
use md5 or sha-1 which encryption for
confidentiality algorithm do you want to
use Triple DES AES DES Blowfish do you
want you know a different lifetime in
which diffie-hellman group so you have
to define these things twice and then
for the second one psych phase 2 is
completed now you've got your IPSec
tunnel where your data is going to be
encrypted
all right typically you don't have to
configure this Ike phase one okay equals
is a KN p equals Ike there's two ways
there's you know two two choices here
main motor aggressive mode main mode has
more messages and it's typically what's
used so it doesn't diffie-hellman
exchange and it doesn't authenticate it
diffie-hellman exchange and so here's a
slide that kind of shows what happens in
main mode so you have six messages that
gets sent across you know pairs of three
messages request response so you have an
initiator and a responder so what the
initiator sends the first Ike message
which basically is a proposal saying
that here's the algorithms I want to use
here the key sizes here's my lifetime
blah blah blah the responder then said
sends a message back saying yep I accept
your si and then both of them after this
first initial request and response had
been sent they both have enough material
to compute the diffie-hellman shared
secret and derive some key material
oh no sorry so now what happens is that
after the first set of exchanges you
send the si proposal and the responder
then says back yep I want to use you
know the md5 algorithm I want to use
triple des I want my lifetime to be
eight hours the next set of exchange is
you're doing authenticated to fiy home
in exchange so you're trying to derive a
shared secret so you send the
diffie-hellman public value and a nonce
which is simply a random number and then
the responder replies with a different
Hellman public value and a random number
and now you have the information that
you need to compare this year to derive
the shared secret
and so once you have the shared secret
you then have you protect the IP
identity by sending by sending the
authentication material and the ID and
then you get it sent back and this this
exchange is encrypted so with Ike phase
one main mode you have an authenticated
diffie-hellman exchange okay so you're
fairly ensured that the public values
that you're sending actually came from
the person that you think it should come
from and the identity is encrypted we
talked about the free Hellman so I'm not
going to use that so for aggressive mode
right which is the alternative for doing
Ike phase one you only have three
messages versus six and you do not have
any identity protection and it's
optional and usually people don't really
implement it so really I wouldn't even
worry too much about it so for eyepiece
like if you're configuring it just think
okay you have Ike phase one which is
also is a KMP and you need to define
some parameters for you know how you
wanted to your encryption and you
usually use main mode and so once you
have this secure communication tunnel
setup now you can negotiate the
parameters for how you want to actually
authenticate and encrypt your actual
data you know via the IPSec tunnel and
that's essentially done with something
called quick mode and once quick mode is
is finished what you end up is with two
security associations so a security
Association is unidirectional so for any
IPSec communication you have two
unidirectional security associations and
it's funny because you know you can have
different algorithms so if I'm
communicating with you over there I can
just say well I want to use you know
sha-1 for authentication and DES for
encryption and you could potentially
want to use MDF
and maybe a yes for encryption but you
know that's typically not done and you
know you basically use the same
algorithm but the flexibility is there
so here's just a picture drawing for
what happens when you do I face two
quick mode so you send the first message
to the responder and you send some key
material and your proposal for what what
kind of algorithms you want to use the
responder validates message one right
make sure that okay it is indeed from
you and then the responder sends back an
authentication McKean material and the
accepted proposal so yep you know I do
want to do sha-1 and yep you know I do
want to use AES encryption the initiator
validates message message to make sure
that you know it is indeed from the
person I expect it to be from then it
sends a hash for proof of integrity and
authentication and finally after the
validation of the third message the
keying material is computed so so as a
summary for Ike right
you basically negotiate the parameters
to establish and secure a channel
between two peers you provide mutual
authentication so both the initiator and
the responder are authenticated and then
there is Ike v2 again I'm not very clear
how much it will buy you a PQ was very
largely created because once people
started using IPSec
it became clear that for many remote
access scenarios there were things that
weren't considered in the in the first
part of the spec for one thing how do
you do user authentication right so most
authentication is done thinking of
devices and so if I am a remote user and
I am coming into a corporate network or
you know my Knock or something then okay
you know that this is my laptop but you
don't know that
I am the one that has my laptop right so
within remote authentication there had
to be a way to define or provide for
mechanisms to actually authenticate the
user and typically what's done right now
is you actually authenticate both the
device and the user so there were
extensions out of - I could be one to do
that
I think mod P is what one of the
extensions is called or in Ex auth
actually X authors the extension that
provides for user authentication and
even though that's not a ratified
standard it's been widely adopted and
then another issue with with Ike was all
right you know there's a lot of DHCP out
there and a lot of ISPs are giving out
addresses you know to folks and so these
addresses change and so how do you
actually you know do any kind of a
tunnel mode using IPSec when you're
authenticating the IP address but it's
changing right that's an issue so that's
where you know they had all these
extensions that they were then defining
for IP one and then instead of having
all these convoluted extensions they
decide you know we should really create
an IV - and then incorporate all this so
all right so you had the dynamic address
issue you had a device versus user
dedication issue and of course our dear
friend not right not impact so there's a
lot of environments that use network
address translation I used to find it
really funny when when some vendors used
to market not as a security mechanism
right oh well you don't know my IP
address so I'm secure I'm like all right
you know that's a little bit security
you know through obscurity but um
I think most of us are using that in
some way or another and not breaks a lot
of things and an IPSec it's it's a very
large issue and so there's been a
proposal that's been ratified and it's
called nat traversal which helps solve
some of the issues
all right so if we look at some of the
problems that exist right so you've got
two different areas of a network and
they're trying to quit with NAT and Pat
what happens is if you look at the first
arrow there you have a private source
address and it's converted through
globally unique address alright so then
the corporate network the remote router
replies to the IP address but the
destination IP address translates to
private IP address using port numbers to
help with the multiplexing and there's a
lot of issues with what if the tables
run up you know and just keeping track
of who are you translating to so here's
a slide that shows what in the IPSec
working group they've come up with for
transport mode ESP packets so not
traversal doesn't work for it for every
single IPSec scenario okay it's mostly
meant for transport mode and because of
the fact that most people thought well
eh is probably going to go away and not
people use it it's also only been
defined for ESP so the encapsulating
security payload portion so this just
kind of shows you what the packet would
look like and where its applied now I
have such an issue with IPSec because no
matter what you do you're going to have
to spend some time trying to figure out
in your own environment whether or not
any any two devices that aren't the
exact same devices will actually speak
IPSec appropriately okay because if you
buy two devices that maybe one is a
client and one is either a switch or a
router or firewall and you're speaking
IPSec to it
even if it's from the same vendor
unfortunate may not interoperate right
and so we run into the okay so what do
we do I mean I think this is one of the
reasons that people have been shying
away from my piece SEC and the only
thing I can say is that you know I think
people do need to start using it and I
think that some like websites like BNP
and VPN Sea Org who's providing some
useful input for how to actually do
sample configurations and it was very
useful so anyway so that's my spiel and
IPSec and again if some of you have any
any practical experience or have
actually looked into whether or not you
want to use IPSec for your routing
authentication versus md5 authentication
I'd be very interested in that because
I've been talking to somebody that I
know from Cisco Dave Ward who actually
had a draft out on BGP right and to
actually do IPSec authentication and he
asked me whether or not he should
continue and my response was well you
know I really need to think about what
the trade-offs are between doing md5
authentication versus using IPSec for
authentication and the one trade-off the
only one that I can really think of that
that would be a big proponent is the
rekeying issue that it's a lot easier to
actually rekey using IPSec with ike than
if you're using md5 so I'm just asking
people like if you you know how
practical experience I have thought
about it I would love to discuss it with
you alright link layer security I'm
going to kind of run through this
because I want to get more into the
architecture piece but with link layer
security a lot of people are using LTP
and if you're using l2tp and if you're
using any kind of VPN people are also
implementing MPLS VPNs I hate hate hate
hate when people say that MPLS VPNs are
secure okay
because MPLS VPNs are only secure if you
actually put some kind of security
functionality even with them ie meaning
that you apply some kind of firewall
strategy as well as probably
implementing IPSec because any layer 2
VPN via ATM frame relay l2tp MPLS pick
your flavor is not secure ok you have to
actually add security functionality on
top of that to have a secure VPN you
know I I mean I'm a very strong believer
and that people need to do security
right to do security right you want you
need to understand what is secure and
what's not and what your vulnerabilities
are so just something that I wanted to
point out and here's that statement ok
very important so now we get to the more
interesting part I think which is
alright so now we've got our networks
right and we've had to implement some
kind of security stuff on them just
because well you know we're all Afeni
cating something we all need access to
devices and you know we're all trying to
figure out what what to filter so what
this section is going to go through is
sort of my version of best practices
which quite frankly hasn't changed in
the last 6 years not very much and I
forgot to mention I will just because I
can but I wrote a book on security and
this is the second version it just went
to print 2 weeks ago right my first
version came out in 1999 alright and in
1999 I had in there filtering I had in
there you know using your your
encryption schemes I had in there I mean
for if you're showing configurations
I had in there you know filtering I had
in there all kinds of stuff that I was
very surprised and somewhat shocked a
year ago when I started looking at stuff
again that people hadn't implemented and
I'm like this is not new stuff I mean
this is all the very basics of actually
securing your devices and nobody's
implemented the functionality that has
existed in there for years right so one
of the things that I kept thinking about
like why and I thought well it's
probably because it's very low on the
priority list and as in the last couple
of years it's become more clear that
infrastructures will get attacked and
you know there's more money being lost
because of actual attacks but I think
people are paying more attention and I
find it very interesting I think a lot
of the things that you will hear today
you will also hear tomorrow and Tuesday
as people talk about this is what you
need to do to secure your infrastructure
devices and you know these things have
really existed in most of the vendor of
implementations for years so I am you
know I'm hoping that people will become
more aware that this is a real problem
and even if you haven't been attacked
today something Rob Rob Thomas keeps
saying and which is an important point
is that you know you may think that you
have not been attacked because it hasn't
happened today but your infrastructure
device might be compromised somebody
knows what the password is they just
haven't used it yet you know so you know
don't don't don't sit in this like you
know unreal reality world of nope didn't
happen to me no bombs secure because
more likely than not you know unless you
really put some thought in it you know
unless you're constantly auditing your
devices something something not so
pleasant is gonna happen in the near
future so and you know as you get more
involved in security I think people
become more paranoid at least I do so
you know I might be more paranoid than
most but just you know be careful out
there
so with security the thing is - it's not
just a technology problem I mean the
analogies have existed for a very long
time and when people tell me oh you know
it's so hard to keep up with security
because things are changing all the time
I'm like well no not really what's
happening is okay somebody is you know
being better at math right so in terms
of us or you guys who are implementing
security all right if you're providing
confidential confidentiality algorithms
all right so instead of typing des you
then try to type triple des all right
well then you use AES you know and
fundamentally you don't need to
understand the math but you do need to
understand that yep you know this will
be harder for somebody to break so there
are things that are better right IPSec
is getting better slowly slowly slowly
slowly okay but it is getting better and
vendors hopefully are also making things
a little bit easier to configure but a
lot of stuff exists out there that is
really very easy to configure can
provide you a lot of security and will
keep the stupid attacks from happening
all right so of course when you're
looking at your own networks right I
mean you have to figure out okay what
vulnerability and what threats am i
susceptible to right and in this day and
age when people especially with the
filtering stuff filtering is
controversial because every environment
is different and every time people come
up with the best current practice you
know you're hoping you're hoping hoping
hoping that 80% of the people will you
know take advantage or will benefit from
this best current practice and then
there's a whole slew of end scenarios
right in cases because your mileage is
going to be different so I'm sure you
know there's gonna be a lot of talk
tomorrow about things but the types of
threats that you need to think about is
you know unauthorized access how easy is
it to eavesdrop all right how easy is it
to impersonate somebody spoofing packets
denial-of-service getting worse and
worse
viruses they're getting worse and worse
email spam worse and worse and worse and
worse right so which one are you
susceptible to and what can you do to
mitigate the attacks you're never going
to be able to stop them a hundred
percent okay but what can you do as a
best effort to mitigate them and you
know when people talk about
reconnaissance attempts I mean it's easy
and people do it all the time right I
mean how many times have we heard that
okay you know stick some kind of device
out in front of your firewall and just
you know let the log run like I mean set
up some kind of filter to say okay deny
this traffic coming in and guess what
you know people doing port scans right
and left I mean some people just have it
running automatically from all over the
world right 24 hours a day seven days a
week I mean it's crazy it's it's nuts
but there's a lot of bored people out
there or you know there's a lot of
people that are motivated by money
there's a lot of 14 year-olds who's not
playing soccer but instead you know with
their game boys or their laptops and you
know saying oh cool let me see what I
can do right I mean it really stinks but
the thing is is that people do it and
you can't just say no it's not going to
happen to me and for people that again
you know watch nanog mailing with some
other ones Rob Thomas again pointed out
just recently that a lot of people are
looking for Cisco routers okay that have
HTTP enabled right and there's still a
lot of routers that have really easy
guessable passwords Cisco okay I mean
you know I sit there and go I can't
believe somebody's doing that but that's
because I wouldn't do it right and I am
hoping that none of you would do it but
for somebody that's a network
administrator and there's small ISPs out
there and let me tell you I'm switching
my ISP right now because I've had two
years of okay this is enough where you
know there are small outfits and they're
like oh you know I'm sorry no we don't
have a single UNIX machine and they're
proud of that okay
I mean they exist they're out there
they're you know maybe in your hometown
okay and you know you try to educate
them and then you figure oh well if
they're not knowledgeable enough well
that's okay you know not everybody's
billing doesn't mean you know the
problem is if they don't care I have a
big problem with that and unfortunately
there are people that simply don't care
right all they want is to provide some
service get money coming in and do
whatever they do and you know that's
simply how it is but so these are the
people hopefully you know that have
these Cisco passwords and then I don't
really care what happens to them if they
go out of business but okay people do it
it's never gonna go away it's just gonna
get worse
so we're dialing right you think it's
gone away nope
you know as long as modems are around
and that's the way that people can
access networks you know that's what's
gonna happen people are gonna figure out
do it they're gonna try all kinds of
ways to first of all try and figure out
all right what kind of equipment do you
have and then they're usually going to
be somewhat knowledgeable from their
network of friends and you know slew of
chat rooms that they're probably part of
to know what kind of vulnerabilities
exist and then try to exploit them
so we're dialing denial of service
attacks right so look at your favorite
protocol header and you know there's
some problem and not everybody is going
to be running the current version of
everything so there's all kinds of
issues right here's the Packard format
just because you know pick any one of
these segments and you know somebody can
manipulate something and can create a
denial of service attack and the problem
with the denial of service attacks - are
that people getting so much smarter used
to be that you know maybe first of all
people would mostly use spoofed
addresses and you know people really
don't have a lot of filtering in place
even now you know even like the RFC 1918
addresses the ones that people should
use from that well that all right I mean
people don't put filters in place
because well why should you you know
it's I have to configure this stuff I
don't feel like it okay well the problem
is that with the knowledge service
attacks people can spoof packet headers
you know and you can cause huge huge
outages of networks and especially as
they get more automated there's a lot of
automated than our service attacks out
there and what's really scary is that I
have so many people I give a lot of
these talks to corporate environments -
and it's really funny they're like oh
god no way you know nothing's happened
to us ever you know I'm sitting there
going you know something how do you know
that nobody's installed some kind of
Trojan on your you know ten thousand
computers in your environment and it's
not going to use that tomorrow to launch
an attack and they're like oh you know
because who has the mechanisms in place
right now to actually figure out what
kind of files are on their computer and
whether or not somebody's installed it
or not okay now there are companies
they're startups that are hopefully one
day gonna make a lot of money because
they're going they're working on this
issue right to make it easy for people
in a multi computer environment to say
oh you know every day they do some kind
of scan and say oh that file that's
weird you know that shouldn't be there
but went up there we're probably a long
way from being there really so just keep
in mind I mean you you need to
understand and especially you guys who
are running choirs peas all right I
don't care how big or small you are you
need to understand your infrastructure
equipment you need to know who has
accessed that you need to know who has
modified any of the files
okay configuration files you really do
need to need to have absolute control
we're becoming control freaks so I mean
what if a router becomes a target
they're becoming targets more often than
not and so you know you can disable the
entire network right
so a lot of CPU vulnerabilities too you
can get to the router and guess what you
know people can launch attacks to just
take it down and so this guy George
Jones is working on a document it's a
device security requirements document
okay and if you haven't heard of that I
think you know hopefully you will he
will talk tomorrow on a panel and that
is something where there is a lot of
input that would be very useful from all
of you in this room who are running
networks and using devices and are
really exasperated by some vendors
because you have to do all this
configuration where things might you
know should maybe be default so I
encourage you to actually look at this
document and provide some input and one
of the things that's in there is like
stealth mode right because I don't want
people to know that if they've
inadvertently gotten access to a device
somehow that it's a switch or it's a
firewall or what it is because then they
might be able to exploit some
vulnerability that I might not have had
time to fix it because I'm fixing all
these other things in my network so here
are just some points to consider for a
routing environment and what you do you
definitely want to limit access to
routers in critical backbone areas I
mean I think this is no operon you want
to control router access one of the
things that a lot of people do is they
create some kind of a group password for
staff it is much better to have
passwords or you know access rights for
individual users and the reason why is
because if somebody leaves right then
you have a lot less configuration stuff
to do so that's something that I try and
point out to people is that veer away
from any kind of shared group passwords
because it's really not a good idea
oh yeah and of course I'm making the
point again for the HTTP access right
because it's happening quite a bit right
now for scanning so I have a question
all right
this actually happens somewhere and so
you've got this this you know
engineering land there's all these
people that you know are responsible for
the backbone and it's a knock and you
know you've got all these secure servers
and you know got a workstation and some
people actually telecommute and but you
know they they need to know what's
happening with the infrastructure so
what is a potential issue here
anybody ah very good
yeah okay yep because nothing's really
secure well I didn't say 100% secure so
you know mileage may vary all right what
no I don't care about the firewall
although that does come into play
all right the issue that I'm trying to
point out here is that well that's it
yeah the workstation was modem right
because I'm like god you know I'm really
important I really need to look at the
infrastructure I need to make sure that
nothing's been modified you know so
every hour I got log into my router to
make sure configuration hasn't changed
or something so even when I'm home it's
a Saturday night I need to log in so
what's the best way of doing it now I'll
just hook a modem up you know to my
workstation well the problem is is that
you know that's very susceptible to some
kind of a scanning reconnaissance attack
right unless you have you know
configured like your reverse telnet
maybe or you know your authentication
mechanisms I mean some some pretty smart
little twelve year old kid can probably
get into access to your network and this
all comes back to a security policy and
I know anybody who touches equipment
there like policy smallest II I hate
that stuff right but the thing is is
that you're leaving yourself wide open
for people to do stupid things you know
and I am very much a proponent of if
nothing else you know create a one page
that says we authenticate this we
provide this for confidentiality do not
ever do this you know and this do you
know five or 10 most favorite things
that people do just because they don't
think that it's a security issue because
people never know as much as you do and
mostly you learn stuff regarding a
security through experience you know and
the one one story I always kind of tell
and you know it's kind of embarrassing
but when I started working with Cisco
equipment I mean this is you know 1989
and I was really curious about what it
did so one night you know I'm sitting
there and I'm did a debug all and left
it on all right went home next morning I
come in and my buddies are like running
around they're like holy you know
packets are dropping mind you we only
had five buildings connected there
wasn't a lot of traffic okay but pockets
are getting dropped and you know I'm
just getting my coffee and I was mostly
a fiber person anyway so you know I was
just like yeah you riding people figure
it out you know and it turns out that
some yeah my friends Joe comes and he
goes the hell turned on debug all and
what I did why right this is 1989 you do
it today you're fired you know it was a
funny story then but people do that so
you know you have these denial of
service attacks that are not necessarily
malicious right I mean you know I was
curious I actually wanted to be smarter
but you know I did something stupid so
you always have to kind of you know just
look at what what people can do and make
sure that especially people who are
responsible for your network
infrastructure understand some of the
security ramifications because some
things that you think are no-brainer
just really aren't alright so what do
you do to secure your infrastructure
devices you have to just go through ok
who has physical access who has logical
access and what's confidential again I
told the story before about just a month
ago right in Australia there were guys
that you know impersonated these these
these workers and they ended up
carrying out some kind of what mainframe
all right with all kinds of confidential
information in there so these are not
just funny stories I mean they actually
happened so you have to really figure
out well what do you do and when I was
at NIH I mean we actually built
equipment closets I mean my boss fought
tooth and nail to have specific
equipment closets built in 50 different
buildings were there were only five keys
and three of them were for our group and
then one of them was for like the fire
marshal and that was it and it's a very
light thing space is really hard to
combine but you know you if it's really
critical to your business and as a - P
infrastructure equipment is critical to
your business you really want to be a
little bit annual about this stuff you
know you don't want to say oh shoot I
should have okay and you know I'll be
the first to admit the more you deal
with security the more paranoid you
become but I don't know I that's hard
anyway so okay physical location also
you want to figure out where are you
located
if you can't necessarily get physical
access like your own you know space for
it for your equipment so you have
complete control be at least aware of
who goes in the closets another thing
that happened years ago was you know we
shared a closet with some
telecommunication folks because it
wasn't yet combined and you know come in
one Monday and the network's down and
you know the building's like a mile away
so who's gonna go to the building so you
try to do everything else and try to
figure it out and last of all you know
you're like us you I got to actually
traipse over there turns out but
somebody had just connected a fiber you
know just dangling there you're like
what in the world turns out some
telecommunications God come in wanted to
fix some the wire was in the way he
disconnected and forgot to connect it up
you know it happens right people I mean
it sounds ludicrous okay but there's so
many stories so understand where your
equipment is understand who is access I
think it's really really important to
figure out who ever either goes to the
physical device you know whether
have physical console access who goes
into these closets or you know whoever
has the logical access because if
something should happen what you want to
do is you want to have some kind of
mechanism to trace back and figure out
who it was or what it was so it won't
happen again all right for secure
configurations all right clear text
passwords shouldn't exist any more
packets plus in radius most devices some
maybe it's just really recent but they
will have mechanisms so that you can
keep track of authentication credentials
with either tax plus or radius and I
would strongly urge people to use this
because it makes it much easier to
manage and the thing is you have the
accountability so whenever somebody logs
into a device and does something you
actually have the accounting information
and that to me is the most important
point so I would very strongly urge
people I mean with your switches your
firewalls whatever devices that you have
that you incorporate this Triple A
functionality for when people access
your device and mostly for logging
purposes you may not look at it for two
or three years but you know if something
ever were to happen the log logs I think
will become very important to you also
because of input from years years and
years of you know people banging on
vendors many of them have multiple
privilege levels some only two some
fifteen you know whatever but of course
it's always very good to for the very
privileged commands to only have as few
people as possible have access to that
and then kind of figure out like okay
who needs to know what and so I think
that's also more or less what people do
I think most people at least have a
two-tiered approach where you know
there's a few
people that have access to every command
and can do anything and then there's the
rest of the world that can basically
just show and monitor and you know do
the limited stuff encrypted passwords
when viewing configurations most people
I think do that the thing to be aware of
though is that depending on which
versions of software you use on which
devices that some passwords which you
think might be encrypted or not ok so if
you're troubleshooting something and
you're sending configuration information
off to your vendors you may not have all
of the passwords become financial and
you know I'm talking about you have to
make sure your SNMP community strings
your NTP authentication stuff your in
md5 authentication stuff for your
routing I mean I think most vendors now
in the latest release releases do
encrypt everything but just be aware
that you know they actually are
encrypted all right I talked about
telnet and why I think it's a bad idea
again the reason it's about idea is
because you do not want to send any kind
of credential information ie passwords
in the clear it's too easy for people to
be able to to use network sniffers to
get that information and in case you
know you some people think all my
networks so secure that'll never happen
here's another story it was kind of sort
of funny but not really in June I was in
New York and I was writing this book the
editors were really getting mad at me
because I'm always late and you know I
was like past my deadlines so I'm
visiting a friend and I you know decided
oh I'm gonna use this cool gizmo that I
got a year ago but I've been afraid to
use on the airplane because God knows
maybe it'll damage my computer and I'm
like oh I'm being so stupid you know
nope I'm gonna use it five my power
supply and so Here I am you know in New
York far away from anywhere that I can
get access to anything I'll be gone for
a week you know editors yelling at me
okay
what do I do friend of a friend works
for Sony downtown Manhattan it's a
Saturday I'm Estonian he's Estonian
we're buddies
even though we don't know each other so
I go up to the Sony corporate network
right and it's really funny because he
left the office right and I'm sitting
there going wow you know I can actually
like to plug my face that way but then
you know he left but then he came back
and he goes medica you know wait a
minute can you plug into that you have a
network sniffer on yer top and I'm like
uh-huh and he goes do you mind if you
just walk with me you know so that was
good but you know he could have just
left the not come back and I bet sure a
lot of people do that
right because you just trust people you
know and like I mean I said before my
laptop wasn't working well we tried to
figure it out and he gave me another
battery and that works and my battery
has just been fried but so you know if I
had been any kind of malicious person I
could have sat there and said oh no I
don't he might have gone away I couldn't
maybe tapped in maybe looked at some
stuff and away you go
so never assume that just because your
network is secure that nobody's going to
ever tap in the assumption has to always
be paranoid somebody's going to be able
to view what's on the wire all right now
of course that doesn't cover all of your
scenarios I mean if you connect it to a
switch and this is it or you just have
two devices okay you know probably not
but just don't don't you know don't
assume because unless you have full
control of absolutely everything 24
hours a day seven days a week you're
physically there you don't know what
somebody else is going to do so I'm
always very careful with passwords you
know at some I don't want to send
anything over the wire and clear text
okay just done I mean it's obviously
from from Miss Cisco and this is
actually from a router that I had at
home and I'm going huh okay now this is
actually not so secure so what's what's
wrong with that forget about the telnet
part
yeah
yeah that's one okay but ya know this
yeah yeah nine BTY okay it's the line
vty stuff
what what's so wrong with those three
lines for people that kind of have used
Cisco's no I said not don't worry about
the telnet right there's no there's no
timeout and you know it was funny
because I looked at this and I was like
oh shoot yeah last week I was
troubleshooting something right so I
hate it when my console kept typing out
I mean timing out and I had to keep
typing in my password right so as I'm
telling into my router if I troubleshoot
and I will make a bet that all of you do
this okay you change because of course
you wouldn't do this normally you change
your timeout so at zero zero
so so that if you walk away to talk to
somebody your session hasn't timed out
and you have to you know we started
again but the problem is that a lot of
times people forget right and they fixed
it they're so happy it might be 3:00 in
the morning right you're really happy
you're really tired and go here when you
go home and then the next morning all
you remember is that you solve the
problem but you forget that you left
yourself wide open well you know where
you cause a potential issue with you
know if somebody logs into the session
walks away that somebody else might get
access to the computer so there are
little things you know and they might
seem really really silly but the problem
is is that if you leave any kind of a
window open right for somebody to
exploit any of your devices at some
point somebody's going to take advantage
of that so as much as you can you know I
just really I make people sick with you
know just telling them please be
vigilant and yeah somebody had mentioned
also yeah naval secret password that's
all cisco specific if if there are
mechanisms where you can encrypt the
password like on a configuration so if
people view configurations and you know
they tried to break the encryption
scheme I always try to use the one that
is the strongest one available
alright here's another thing
banners how many of you have banners on
your devices okay so out of curiosity
what does somebody near the microphone
can you say what your banner says would
you that's u.s. DoD networks and that's
it that's quote that's fine but there's
two issues with that one is if I really
want to attach tax DSO DoD then I will
try to make a harder job of it and
number two and this is very important in
the US and I think it's becoming more
and more of an issue worldwide and it
depends on you know you your country's
regulations and legislation and law and
all that fun stuff but I was told about
a year ago that in the US for your
devices if you want any kind of a legal
ramification or something were to be
used as evidence you need to have the
sentence that you will be prosecuted to
the full extent of the law
if you at some point in time want to
prosecute because somebody has attacked
you and anyway so this particular one
yeah I decided that I named all my
routers after drinks so I then decided
that okay what I'm gonna do is just kind
of say well here's how you make it right
so I looked at it and I'm going hey I'm
pretty smart but then I'm like no I'm
actually really stupid because at the
end I say get off my router so I've told
somebody that they're on my router why
did I need to do that right so you do
not really want to tell people if they
have somehow managed to get access to a
device what kind of device it is because
it gives them information in terms of
what kind of vulnerabilities to look for
impossibly exploit and then number two
is you do want to use some kind of
language and you might want to speak
with your legal departments so that if a
security breach happens
that you have not somehow invited the
person in like if you say something like
hello welcome leave now this is you know
unauthorized the term welcomed because
you know the legal system is just so
wonderful in the u.s. it can mean that
no you know you were actually inviting
that person to your network again it
seems maybe really stupid a really silly
point but I think even things like this
are going to become very important
especially if you do have some kind of a
security incident and you might want to
prosecute alright so as a checklist I
was at a session it was a at the last
Nanog and it was the security security
birds of a feather session that we had
and some guy just asked the question he
goes all right you know what should I do
right so if you can name some things
that I should do to provide security
what do I do and the answer was along
the lines of well security
infrastructure devices and I'm like what
kind of an answer is that you know it's
very clear that you know the person is
asking for help in terms of what are
maybe the two or three things that I
should do to it secure my infrastructure
devices so I like it when people
actually give a little bit more
information right so if somebody is
really looking for okay you know I've
just really started looking at building
my ISP I'm still kind of new but you
know and I want to now provide security
and I want to secure my devices what I
like the two or three things that I
really should do a number one is make
sure that you control access to your
devices from a console point okay so
even when you have console access like
physical device access put in some
measures in place that say you know you
have to authenticate with this username
password alright
logical acts is the same thing and
logical access can be either your
terminal line axis so SSH it can be your
HTTP axis it can be SNMP axis
allow only what you use and again I
think I saw something on a mailing list
recently where it was assumed that a
certain vendor turned off the HTTP
server as a default and I believe that
it depends on which version of software
you are using so you know and I could be
wrong but the thing is never assume that
you know a vendor will do something
consistently throughout its software
versions okay and as unfortunate as it
may be you know sometimes you have to
figure out especially if you're running
multiple versions of things what are the
defaults and what aren't and just the
point of caution you know I think
vendors should get a lot better in this
to say you know here's our defaults so
that people can be aware of what might
be a security risk for them and what is
it you want to shut down on all unused
interfaces and this is basically a
precaution because it used to be that if
you had them turned on but some of my
people could could could you know gain
access so or maybe even just cause a
denial of service attack so anything
that you're not using really should be
shut down
I would also test device integrity on a
regular basis and this is something that
I don't know who has time for usually
people outsource it but I would try and
attack my network you know trying to
attack your infrastructure and there's a
lot of people that have created test
equipment either for free or you know
you have to pay for it that you can just
run and it can emulate an attacker and I
would do that because macare how smart
you are how much you know there's
sometimes you configure stuff and you're
tired or you know your brain just kind
of goes wacky for a minute or two and
the best way to actually see whether or
not you have a secure infrastructure is
to try and attack it and it's better to
attack it when you know you're attacking
your
often trying to fix the vulnerabilities
then if you're waiting for somebody to
do some of them I caused you a lot of
harm all right
so securing infrastructure devices the
main point is is that any way that
people can get access to it make sure
you understand it make sure you turn off
anything that you do not use and use use
use access controls one thing that some
people are doing I really like this is
that they put in certain filters so that
only certain certain equipment certain
let's say NOC machines can get access to
routers or switches now this means that
if you're traveling you usually have to
then access these NOx machines and then
you know gain access to your
infrastructure devices but you know it
adds a little bit of security and some
people do find that very useful so
routing protocol security the biggest
problem with routing protocol security
is that the best you can do is you can
just verify where the routing update
came from right so you have origin
authentication and you can also validate
that you know when router X sent an
update to router Z that during transit
nobody has injected any any you know
bogus routing update information but the
problem comes in is that you don't know
whether or not that router that person
was authorized to send you that routing
information and I liken this problem
to the same problem as the public key
infrastructure problem because you have
to have some kind of a trusted database
that keeps track of you know who's
allowed to send what to WHO and then
somehow you have to be able to get the
information and validate that yep I got
a routing update yep that came from that
person yep they're allowed to send me
these updates you know now that's
getting really paranoid of course but I
do believe that people are working on
you know whether or not this is going
to be a real huge issue in the future
and how do you resolve that but the best
that we can do right now is to put in
route authentication and again I've
mentioned this quite a few times ready
which is the typical md5 authentication
built into most routing protocols most
routing protocols also allow for you to
have a shared secret that's configured
that send in the cleared path back and
forth you know it's in the specs it's in
almost all the specs actually but I
believe that if anybody goes through the
process of configuring their routers for
authentication then they at least use
md5 and you can also put route filters
in where you can say you know you should
only be getting routing updates from
these specific IP addresses now you know
somebody can tell me oh well but people
can spoof IP addresses yeah they can but
you know it takes a little bit more work
and what that also does is that may that
may help you in case somebody does some
kind of a weird configuration you know
so how does about authentication work
essentially you append a signature to
routing update and all right so yeah
that's what I was saying most of them
also have plaintext neighbor
authentication I don't know why people
would ever use that all about any
protocols have md5 authentication at
this point in time and just about every
single vendor I know that's a routing
vendor does md5 authentication for any
of the routing protocols they support so
how does it work if you have a routing
update and you have a key remember I
know for those of you that were here
earlier you know I went through this
whole slide of a keyed you know hash
function key th Mac this is where it
comes into play
so you have a shared secret that's
configured on on both routers you
combine that with the you combine the
shared secret with a routing update run
it through a hash function it's
typically md5 you end up with a hash you
append that hash to the routing update
and you
and you do not encrypt the hash okay
it's just the hash that's sent and so on
the other of the receiving end you then
get the routing update in the hash you
kind of hold onto the hash and keep it
somewhere in memory
you take the routing update you have the
shared secret you concatenate those put
that into the md5 algorithm come up with
the hash to compare the hashes if
they're equal then you know you can be
fairly ensured that the update came from
who you thought it came from at the end
the data hasn't been modified in transit
so that's essentially how md5 neighbor
authentication works so as a summary I I
do believe that everybody should turn on
md5 neighbor authentication and again
with the caveat that you know I still
need to look at what what what the deal
is with rekeying because most people
don't rekey because it will then cause
an issue with with you know the whole
routing network so one of the things to
think about and to look for in the
future is whether or not it makes sense
to actually use IPSec
for the integrity part rather than doing
md5 because with IPSec using ike you
have a an easier and more automated way
of rekeying
all right now perimeter network
perimeter right people always talk about
firewalls and I networking is so funny I
mean people try to create new
terminology to sell products you know
and just recently I mean it was sort of
tongue-in-cheek I guess but I was
looking at some inner Exchange where
people were saying well what's a layer 3
switch and what's a router you know well
if you put it sideways it's a switch if
you you know put a horizontal it's
around or all that I mean I I think of
it this way ok if you have anything to
do with layer 2 it's a switch if
anything you start going to the layer 3
your router and I don't know whether or
not it was my boss who actually came up
with the term of layer 3 switch but I
think he might have and I just remember
this meeting and we were laughing so
hard because we're going God you know
they're selling so many of these
switches because people think they're
faster so we think a router if we call
the layer 3 switch people will think
they're faster and they will start
buying more routers again ok and I mean
prove to me why a layer 3 switch is not
a router I mean I don't get it because
the minute you look at you know the
layer 3 your routing you know you may
not look at the routing table you may
look at a cache or a portion of it but
you're still looking at layer 3 yeah so
I don't know mileage may vary but so
when I look at firewalls right nice that
that mic ok so what's a firewall and I'm
like well it's something that can filter
now and mostly something that can
probably filter it layer 3 all right at
least at layer 3 because usually you
don't look at something that can just
filter Mac layers or MAC addresses as a
firewall but anything that can say okay
permit you know this packet that has
this IP address and maybe you will look
deeper into the packet and say and this
port number and something else you know
and either permit or deny its
happen that's a firewall and I believe
that you know firewalls came out of well
if you had a router and you had filters
there was a point where it couldn't
scale anymore right because you were
taxing the CPU so people created these
separate devices so that you could do
real in-depth packet you know look in
depth into the packet and make some kind
of decision because the deeper you look
into the packet right the more CPU
cycles you take so rather than take away
from a router that was forwarding right
at layer 3 you then had a separate
device then did it so anyway firewall
you know it's it's filtering and state
will firewall is well you know there's
some protocols or the deeper you look
you need to know well if I sent you this
and I sent you this you know I have to
keep track of that information right and
that's the stateful firewall because you
can't just throw one packet away you
have to look at a communication as a
whole so terminology to me gets really
funky I mean sometimes people like oh
you don't really get it I'm like no I do
I don't like your terminology because
you're confusing me you know let's get
to the basics of what it really does so
all right filtering I was driving people
nuts at a conference that I or a talk
that I gave and type in February because
every hour I would say what's the word
of the day and they're like filter you
know because people still do not filter
people do it more now and I think it's
because people just keep mentioning it
over and over and over again but there
have been a couple of RFC's written
within the ITF that just recommends
certain best practices and you should
always always always put some kind of a
filter in I think at least at the edges
of your network and of course then it's
like okay what is my edge well you know
that mileage can vary as well but the
closer you are to the customer right
that's where you should filter
and there are some things that really
are no-brainers I would very strongly
urge for those of you that either are
not filtering I don't want to know who
you are
look at this RFC okay and at least
implement this filtering there's another
RFC a draft that's written by Bill
Manning and he lists a bunch of more
addresses that really should be filtered
and I have that in one of my slides but
you know I'm sort of hoping that vendors
will do it I know that some vendors do
do it okay that by default they they
filter the really silly stuff all right
so that if you are in an odd environment
and you have a ten dot blah blah blah
address that you don't propagate traffic
to the real entrant internet using that
address because even though it might not
go more than one hop you know you're
still causing issues with that one link
and if that link is shared by a whole
bunch of people that could be a denial
of service attack you know and so anyway
I think filtering is really important
and again you know here's a header
format right people I mean this is
typically what you have what you filter
on you filter on source and IP addresses
for layer three and the protocol type
and then if it's TCP right you look at
the port number destination and source
or UDP same thing destination source
port number
logging filter port messages properly
logging is always interesting because
how much do you log and what do you log
right and that again depends on how
you've created your filters you need to
be very careful about but when I look at
filtering what I think about is okay if
somebody has attacked my network and I
need to figure out who it was or what it
was and and make sure it never happens
again
what is the logging information that I
need and also how much logging
information do I need so that I
you look at it alright because if you
have reams and reams of data you just
kind of go oh yeah whatever right and I
mean there are hopefully you know there
are products there's things people have
cobbled together so that they can have a
better way of viewing the logs and have
an understanding of when something
happens mostly I believe that these
things are starting to get called
intrusion detection systems in some way
shape or form but you really you know
logging is interesting because there's
all these questions of well what do you
log you know do you need to know what
interface that came into depending on
what device do you use how much is it
going to affect your your CPU right and
anyway so my tendency would be if you
create any kind of a filter you always
want to allow things that you know and
deny everything else and then I
typically log everything that I deny
because I want to know why somebody's
trying to get access to something that
they really shouldn't you know so that's
just one thing to think about
all right so this is just some
recommendations and these are sort of
that just template filters that are the
no-brainers where you should never have
a loopback interface or any of the RFC
1918 networks going out from your
corporate network out to you know your
your your whatever your upstream right
now for you I mean since you're the
service providers I mean this is more at
your customer end and then you know the
thing with ISPs that's so interesting as
some people have control over their
customer networks or the edge that's on
their side and some people don't so you
know what do you do and what do you put
your filters and what I always say is
well with security it gets interesting
because if you have again the horrible
word policy what you do is you try to
adhere that policy with whatever you
have control over and of course whatever
isn't a performance impact so you may
actually want to put in some kind of a
filter going or in the interface that's
coming in from your customer because you
can't trust them to actually put in the
filters in place and now again that also
depends on whether or not it's really
going to be an issue for you or not and
that's where the controversial part
comes in because of I create a filter if
it's never going to be an issue boom
it'll be interesting to see what comes
out of dust current practices I don't
know how many of you have seen that but
there is some some interesting fight
going on right now because apparently
the IAB has you know made a statement
that that it's a bad thing for ISPs to
filter you know things like you know the
Microsoft port numbers and all that
because it breaks applications so that's
true but what do you do right because
your your if your customers aren't
filtering then you're leaving your core
open to you know these horrible denial
of service attacks or these viruses that
keep propagating so if you're doing
filtering and I believe all you should
do it at some level the ordering is
and what sequence is the packet
inspected in and most implementations
have a sequential way of doing it so you
actually want to be aware of what your
traffic is so that most of your your
traffic hits the first number you know
first first 10 first 20 entries people
used to always say God I have such a big
performance impact on my on my filters
and then in some devices that you know
if you had like 500 entries sure if all
of your traffic kept traversing all of
them and basically they match that you
know entry for 98 and for 99 of course
you're going to have a performance
impact so reverse it right some
equipment vendors don't have that issue
so that's great ok what else is there
remote access I'm not going to talk too
much about this because we gotta go
but remote access I mean again it's
mostly to your customers you have VPNs
do you do SSL or IPSec the one thing
that you need to figure out and you
really need to understand what it is
that you want to do is that if you have
let's say a customer or somebody coming
in remotely and you have a VPN and
you're trying to figure out whether or
not you want to use SSL or TLS or IPSec
remember that any time that you poke a
hole in the firewall ok and let's say
that you know you you you really want to
understand your traffic and you have a
stateful firewall so you want to know
what the negotiation is back and forth
for whatever you can keep state for
anytime you poke a hole in the firewall
for SSL or TLS you know you're bypassing
that policy right and so it's becoming
more of a more of an issue where well
what do you do and so I sometimes like
IPSec more simply because the way that I
would design a network would then be
that I would actually have a some kind
of a VPN concentrator you know some
device that has a lot of CPU that can do
the in decryption part or encryption
part for my IPSec and then send the
traffic to a firewall so that my
firewall can still pick up what kind of
traffic is going to the rest of
Network now you know there's no best
practice for that because really it
depends on your particular environment
but you have to do the trade off and you
have to think well what is important in
your environment and what do I care more
about and what do I have more control
over and you know I do this when I look
at any network device - or when I build
networks forgettin about security
my biggest question always is alright
the device works great well it's
supposed to work if there's a problem
how quickly can I solve the problem you
know what tools are available for me
within that device or so it's the same
thing with security right it translates
completely over so yeah you know I'm
configuring these things I think I'm so
secure I'm supposed to be secure now I
have an attack you know now there's an
intrusion what is the way what is the
quickest way for me to first of all try
and figure out where it's occurring and
to stop it you know it's it's the pain I
mean that's what makes security hard
right because you really have to think I
mean about a lot of things and it's all
about risk mitigation so you're never
100% secure all right
mitigating DDoS attacks again filtering
will mitigate some of the really stupid
attacks right where addresses are
spoofed and somebody's really lazy and
just using spoofed addresses director
directed broadcast traffic I mean
hopefully most vendors actually do have
that on office default but if you're
using certain versions of software
especially for Cisco right some older
ones don't have a director default
I mean director broadcast turned off so
you have to specifically define that
committing only traffic that's necessary
and denying the rest is the best way to
go the securest way but it's also a big
pain in the butt so even though you know
that's what I say hey you know do this
you know it's really not practical for
all environments and especially in ISPs
because you know you're just basically
you're supposed to let all these people
just communicate with each other right
you're not the traffic police
but you have to be very vigilant in
terms of you know what's happening what
kind of vulnerabilities are out there
what your customers are doing and
whether or not you can trust them to do
the right things so this is from bill
Manning's RFC this is basically the the
filtering that he recommends and again
most of it is that they've just
addresses that should never be seen on
the public internet reverse path
forwarding those of you that have kind
of berry greens presentation talks a lot
about black hole filtering and reverse
path forwarding which is a really good
way to actually maybe try and ensure
whether or not a packet that's coming in
from it to an interface okay whether or
not the source address is reachable from
that interface so it's it's a sanity
check so if you can and if your devices
support that whatever flavor you have
you know it's probably useful to turn it
on but also remember that it could be
problematic and asymmetric routing
environments so just some tools for for
detecting DDoS stuff and we're out of
time so what I'm going to do in the next
you know after dinner and all that I'm
going to talk a little bit about things
to think about in terms of auditing and
you know what kind of tools are
available what kind of things you should
keep track of and I'm also going to have
some sample configurations for kind of
templates like here if you have a switch
if you have a firewall if you have a
router you know what are the no-brainer
kind of security things that you do need
to actually configure because
unfortunately they're not default okay
and again just as a closing for this
particular portion of the session I
encourage you all who have not yet read
George Jones's draft if you don't know
him you'll see him tomorrow ask them
where you can get a copy because the
draft that he's trying to put out
through the IETF is a security
requirements one
which hopefully will also help vendors
the non clued ones that you know these
are the best practices for what you
should incorporate in your devices so
that way you guys don't have to do all
this god-awful configuring to you know
make your device is secure alright thank
you