one of the things that I'm trying to do
today is basically condense a talk that
I've been giving for the last year to a
whole bunch of people that tries to kind
of do a comprehensive view of security
especially if you're either running an
isp or an enterprise network and
typically what i do is you know i it
becomes some security sort of a
chicken-and-egg problem because you have
to understand some technologies before
you even know what you might want to
implement and sometimes you're trying to
figure out what to implement but you
don't really understand that
technologies and you know I've spent a
lot of years trying to figure out how to
best teach this and so the way that I'm
going to do today is there's going to be
three separate sessions all three are
going to be an hour and a half long and
the first the third is going to be more
or less describing what security
technologies are like how do they work
which is like Eskie SSH
IPSec l2tp I mean you know list your
favorite acronym and just trying to give
kind of a global overview of what they
are and how they fit together the second
third is going to be an hour and a half
spent on all right so now we sort of
understand what all these technologies
are and if we look at our networks how
to how do we use them you know and what
do we do within our own architectures to
have a more or less secure architecture
and in the very last third we'll be
taking a look at actual configuration
examples because one of the things that
I found and then will tell you just a
little bit about myself
I started in the networking world in
1988 and I worked for the National
Institutes of Health which is a major
medical research facility in Bethesda
Maryland and I had the luck of actually
being there fiber person so I designed
their FTDI backbone and we started using
Cisco routers back in 88 okay so very
early on and for five years
I'm designed and ran that network the
backbone and then I ended up working for
Cisco in 1993
until April of 2000 in 1996 I started
looking very seriously at security
especially because the IPSec stuff was
starting to get finished and he's the
first round of it and I ended up doing a
security initiative within Cisco right
so that all the security pieces would
get or try to actually be somehow
brought together and as I started
teaching security for the various
customers it became very clear to me
that security means different things to
a lot of people you know you asked one
person they said oh it's encryption you
ask another person these they're all
it's filtering and on you ask another
person now it's there a dialog from
stuff you know Triple A and the thing is
that it's all of these and the reason
why security is hard in my perspective
is because it touches all areas of the
network and there's so much to know so
it takes a long time to really have that
comprehensive view of security and what
it is in your networks so anyway today I
will just try to hopefully you know
educate you in terms of what the right
things are that you should think about
to then come up with how to try and
appropriately secure your networks and
remember I mean security is never
absolute right you will never have
anything such as absolute security the
best you can do is mitigate your risks
so before I actually begin I just want
to get a sense of how many of you are
responsible for providing security in
your networks okay how many of you
actually think you understand and know
most of the security technologies out
there okay so that I'm not surprised how
many of you have a security policy that
you have read within your companies
raise and hire okay it's better than
most that's about you know maybe a
fourth of the room so let me just begin
so here's the sessions all right the
first third is security technology
details
um but before we get to that and this is
why I asked a question about a security
policy all right policies are boring
right I mean who cares about a policy
but the problem is that you might not
even need some of these technologies
right I mean you might think that
they're really cool and they're really
fun and hey I can play with this stuff
but you know something from a corporate
point of view your tie might be spent
doing something a lot more important so
the first thing that people have to do
and anybody who is even an operator you
know you know you can sit there and
throw your hands out and say you know
policy stuff that's for the higher-ups
but the problem is is that in this day
and age when companies start losing
money because of security issues
sometimes they'll just take a scapegoat
and some of you may end up being
scapegoats because you implemented
something that may have not been part of
a policy because maybe your corporation
doesn't have a policy but you may end up
getting fired so I am very adamant that
everybody who is at all responsible and
security go talk to your peers to your
higher-ups and they say we have to have
a security policy and get whoever the
top-level guy is to sign it create
something on one piece of paper that
maybe just shows that here's what I'm
configuring because this is the policy
which basically says we're not going to
encrypt anything and we're not going to
authenticate anything have the CEO sign
it because that way you know if there's
a security breach you're not going to be
held responsible you have this piece of
paper that said hey I just did what the
policy dictated so you know I really get
discouraged when when people just kind
of blow off policies because unless you
know what kind of technology and what
kind of security you actually need to
put in place in your networks what's the
point so you have to look through you
know what are you trying to protect so
what's confidential what what resources
are actually important to your
corporation and what are you trying to
protect against and you know what's
becoming more and more prevalent is also
regulatory stuff right so what kind of
legal ramifications are there and I just
read something
I guess it was on the Nanog mailing list
I think that there is one corporation
that they trashed the radius accounting
stuff every 30 days and that's because
the federal government there was some
issue where they wanted to see their
logs and so because of privacy reasons I
mean that particular corporation I guess
decided that you know they're only going
to keep the logs around for 30 days
right
but as a corporation as an ISP you have
to make that decision and it should be
written down somewhere so these are
characteristics of a good security
policy i mean you will see these slides
later on they will be on the website
currently they're not and i'm not going
to walk through them but you know this
is something i just i want to point out
and I want people to seriously um you
know take these things into
consideration and again why should you
care right I mean your job of reputation
may be at stake and since January I mean
I've literally been around the globe you
know I was in Sri Lanka in July Taiwan
and February and I keep asking like how
many you have a corporate security
policy and there's very few I what
really impressed me the Indian
government they had a you know 160 page
document then they also had like a five
page document because let's face it you
know you want everybody to read it I'm
not going to be 160 page document but a
five page document
probably right so you should have both
like one that's really comprehensive and
if there's any kind of legal issues at
some point in time because of a breach
that you can show them this you know big
fat document but you also want something
that's an I prefer usually to a three
page or that every single person will
read and understand okay so it is
important to have one very few people
have them so if we look at a typical
Network component I don't care what kind
of network you're on whether or not
you're an enterprise person or whether
or not you're a service provider
typically your networks can be broken up
into these components so you've got your
main corporate component your corporate
network so you know if you're an ISP and
you're
a medium a larger size ISP you have some
building right that's usually your core
network and then you might have other
branch offices and then you might have
your remote access points where people
may be telecommuting and you also have
your customer networks and so the things
that you need to look at what to secure
you need to look at all points right I
mean it's the weakest link right who is
your biggest problem and so security has
to be a comprehensive strategy so you
have to look at ok what routers do I
control what switches do our control
where my web servers where my email
servers where do I provide for
authentication and for all of these
devices you have to systematically look
at who has control and access to these
devices communication to and from these
devices right is it authenticated is it
to be kept confidential right so there's
a lot of legwork to be done before you
actually start implementing any kind of
technology and so these are the elements
that you need to consider and I'm sure
most of you are aware of these arming
authentication authorization data
integrity data origin authentication a
lot of people when they talk about
integrity another issue was with when
people talk about security is people
have misused terminology a lot and so a
lot of times people talk about integrity
and it's not integrity of the data or
the packet what they really are talking
about is data origin authentication you
know and for any of you that are
familiar with IPSec you know that's
another one they talk about oh you get
integrity but what you get is data
origin authentication that's what they
mean by integrity so be very clear you
know in terms of when you're defining
something or trying to figure out what
you're trying to protect against you
know what your terminology actually
means
so again these questions are just more
for reference because I don't want to
spend too much time on policy I will say
though that I personally you know went
through the process two years ago when I
created my own little home network and I
started to play with a whole bunch of
different devices and just them making
sure that I understand what kind of
security needs are out there even from a
host basis because I've usually been
more of a network person and it became
very clear to me that you always have to
do a risk assessment and to me it falls
into two categories one is you know am I
going to go bankrupt or am I going to
just be embarrassed and that's where the
trade-offs between technologies become
very important because there are some
technologies where you can spend a lot
of money trying to implement it and the
cost of actually implementing these
technologies will far outweigh the cost
of if you actually have a security
breach in place and so it is very
important for people to do a risk
analyses and to see where your money is
better spent and again these are just
going to be more or less for reference
for risk analyses but when you look at
what's important from an infrastructure
point of view okay you have to have
security controls in place and when you
look at devices right you have to figure
out okay well what kind of media am I
using am i using wireless networks am i
using fiber optics am i using a shared
media you know Ethernet that or maybe
still bridged or am I using switches the
equipment location is important as well
as environmental safeguards and with
equipment location I mean you always
used to laugh that oh yeah who's going
to carry you know a big machine out yeah
ha ha but I believe a couple months ago
in Australia you know there were people
that were impersonating some what repair
people and what they actually ended up
doing is taking a mainframe out of the
building with confidential information
so you know it's funny because it didn't
happen to us but it happens so you do
want to be somewhat careful
you know and make sure that your
physical controls and accesses are in
place the logical security controls are
the ones that people are you know more
or less familiar with and pay more
attention to and what these are it's
your console axis your remote your
logical terminal axis and I have to
always correct myself because I'm so
used so we saying oh I'm going to tell
knit into the router which in this day
and age is you know I really should get
away from that because you should be SSH
into your routers or switches but your
logical security controls include not
only your ssh axis or your console
access it's also any other way that
somebody can access your critical
infrastructure devices and cue
mechanisms that are very widely
exploited or either through the web
right HTTP or SNMP so you have to really
carefully think about you know do you
need that access and why and there was
something going on recently where people
are starting to do some reconnaissance
attacks on on specific routers and
looking to see whether or not they have
HTTP servers enabled because some
equipment has vulnerabilities right so
it's very important to disable these
services or these mechanisms of access
if you're not using them you also have
to look at system and data integrity
right so we all understand firewalls I'm
sure and then also the network services
and this is a very controversial issue
and especially fly aspies because you
know are you going to be the network
police for all of your customers an
answer is a resounding no okay that is
not your role however if there are some
denial of service attacks happening and
you know it's causing a huge headache
you have to put these filters in place
so that the network's can still be
available okay it's a problem that you
know cannot be resolved by just saying
nope we'll never put in filters yep
we'll put in filters and we'll keep them
in for you know two days it's a moving
target
so the
thing to do is just kind of you know
work with your customers and kind of see
what the better solution is but ISPs are
not the network police because it breaks
other applications as is becoming
clearer and clearer as you know more
ISPs are putting these filters in place
for specific ports and ends up breaking
things
alright one point I want to make is that
no matter what you will always have some
kind of security incident okay I don't
care how big or small it will be there's
always something you need to deal with
and it is very important that you have
procedures in place so you know how to
deal with it because no matter what
whatever equipment you have right it's
software software is written by somebody
nobody's perfect you may think you're
perfect yeah maybe you are I doubt it
so the thing is that there's always
going to be a software bug some bug is
always going to be construed as a
security vulnerability because guess
what this vulnerability somebody can get
access to this equipment or they can do
some kind of damage that can bring down
your network you know what that is
that's a denial of service because your
network is unavailable so you have to
have certain procedures in place so that
when vendors tell you that there is an
issue that you know you know how to test
maybe this new software because if you
just listen to the vendor and you know
put in this new software version I
wouldn't want to work for you you know
you have I mean yeah I don't trust
anybody okay and even as a bug fix okay
or vulnerability fix can have issues and
so corporations should have some kind of
procedures in place to test new versions
of software before they deploy them all
right and you might just have this thing
in place that says you know anything
that's supposedly really critical and
can bring our whole network down well
then your NOC will you know stay you
know 24 hours to test the software run
through all the tests and then implement
it I mean whatever it is or you have
some way of putting in that software and
then as soon as you see an issue you
know you backtrack it but you you have
to be aware that incident handling has
to be part of your your known procedures
for what to do and a lot of people just
kind of wait to see when something
happens right because they've never been
hit by
security issue or they're like oh we're
all proactive we really keep track of
everything and you know nothing will
happen to us but the day that it happens
you know it could be a disastrous so
just have something in place and one of
the biggest reasons to do this also is
that you as network operators right I
mean you're going to be sitting there
trying to put in filters in place you
might you know need to shut down certain
customers customers will sue the
corporation and again it comes down to
you don't want to get fired okay so you
want to have your management say in case
of a critical event you know for 24
hours the guys of the operators and you
know the NOC team members or you know
the five big grand poobahs who you know
configure the routers that they have the
absolute right to do whatever they feel
is necessary for the company and that
will save your butts so you know anyway
I keep stressing it I think I've
stressed it enough so now put the 101
front stuff how many of you understand
what secret P and public key technology
is okay I'll go through them fairly
quickly then all right so cryptography
it's not just used for confidentiality
right I mean cryptography is used for
authentication it's used for data or
chthonic authentication data integrity
and data confidentiality so when people
say oh I you are you using encryption
right typically with that what
somebody's trying to say your ask is
that well are you using you know
cryptography for confidentiality but
keep in mind that cryptography is
actually used to also authenticate
provide data origin authentication and
integrity of packets going from one
place to another to make sure that
nothing's been altered in transit so
what is public key encryption public key
encryption you basically use two keys
there is one key that's called a public
key and the other one that's called the
private key
I think it makes sense that the private
Keys should be kept private okay nobody
and I mean nobody should know the
private key except for the entity that
created it but computing this key pair
is pretty computationally expensive
right so because there is mathematical
you know gobbly gook where certain
things have to be you know just
precisely so and I'll go through that in
a minute actually for some but it's it's
usually more processor intensive than
another mechanism however public key
technology is very often used for data
origin authentication so this slide just
shows how that would work where
basically let's say that we have two
routers router a and B so router a would
create its public private key pair and
then it would in some way okay and this
is always this oh it's trivial to do
this but you send the public key over to
the other entity so in this case router
B and so to provide the data origin
authentication what router a would do is
it would encrypt whatever data it's
sending with its private key and then
router B would decrypt it with its
public key and because the assumption is
that only router a knows the private key
right you have therefore then provided
data origin authentication now the
problem comes in is that how do you
actually know that router a send its
public key right how do you validate it
how do you verify it and that is one of
the biggest issues in security and
there's been a lot of hand waving at
least in the last 10 years that oh yeah
it's got to be done in a secure method
but then when you sit there and you run
your networks and in practical ways you
sit there and go well what is a secure
method you know what do you do you know
do you call somebody up well some
devices did do that you know where
you're required to actually sit there on
the telephone with somebody on one
router and some in
person on the other end with the other
router and then say yep you know here's
the fingerprint yep I'm the one that
sent it right now you know that's not
scalable so anyway so there's another
common way to do cryptography and that a
secret key encryption and so secret key
encryption you essentially use the same
key on both sides
so both router a and router B would know
a secret key and then run one router
would encrypt the data and the other
side would decrypt the data using the
same key and some of the algorithms that
are used in that use secret key
encryption or like des Triple DES AES
and idea so for those of you that might
just see these these you know acronyms I
mean I'm just trying to put some
perspective in what the acronyms whether
or not they're public key or private key
technology so but the scalability
problem with secret key encryption is
that usually people configure the shared
secrets on to entities right that's not
scalable either I mean you have a
thousand routers what are you going to
do you know configure these these keys
on them that's not really very practical
so there's an algorithm called the
diffie-hellman algorithm and what it
does is it uses a combination of public
key technology to derive a shared secret
and this is a very simplified slide that
essentially shows how this works and so
you have say two routers right what ends
up happening is that router a creates
two very large numbers a and P both of
these numbers are prime numbers and and
they have specific characteristics you
know I don't remember exactly off the
top of my hand what they are
but you know these really smart
mathematical geniuses here you know have
come up with all right so if you have a
and P they're both prime numbers and
they have certain characteristics then
it's very hard to guess what they are
and what ends up happening both router a
and router B then on their own also come
up with another large prime number so
for router a will be XA and for route a
B of B xB and they go through this
particular algorithm to create y a and
YB all right then they exchange Y a and
YB to each other and they again go
through that this mathematical function
and end up with the shared secret Z so
in essence what diffie-hellman does is
you can send some large numbers right in
the clear to each other and end up with
a shared secret
that's only known to those two parties
now the issue with this though is that
diffie-hellman is subject to a
man-in-the-middle attack so what needs
to happen is that diffie-hellman needs
to be authenticated so you need to use
some cryptographic means to authenticate
the numbers that you send across so
remember I showed just a couple minutes
ago the slide where you can prove data
origin authentication right with public
key technology this is basically what
you use to send the values in the clear
to the other side okay but just remember
that I mean the really important thing
about security and to me it's always the
most essential element is authentication
you know what degree of Trustee you have
that somebody is who they say they are
right I mean if I send you some kind of
information and I'm encrypting it what
does it matter if nobody can sniff it on
the wire when you are not really sure
whether or not I'm the one that sent it
or somebody else
so I'm one of these people that I don't
really care that much about encryption
for confidentially on the wire the most
important thing for me is authentication
you know being able to more or less
trust that you are the one that you know
I expect to send me the data and that's
always something that I look at when I
look at okay you know what do I need in
terms of security so another very
fundamental concept that really needs to
be understood for security is what is a
hash function and a hash function
creates a hash it's also called a
message digest they essentially mean the
same thing and what it is is it takes
some kind of arbitrary length input
message and it produces a fixed length
output okay so I think most of you have
at least heard you know the md5
algorithm or strong algorithm these are
all hash functions they're one way
they're irreversible an md5 produces a
128-bit output and sha produces a 160
bit output so you know a lot of times
people try to figure out which one
should I use I don't know shows a little
bit more computationally expensive but
some people think that md5 may be more
susceptible to some attacks a lot of
people really if they don't really know
which one to use recommend sha-1 so if
anybody has more data in terms of you
know md5 really you know has issues you
know speak up because I would love to
know but anything that I've read people
have talked to it's just kind of like a
hand waving like well we think that
sha-1 is more secure so ok I threw this
slide in there because there is times
that I talk about certain technologies
and how they work specifically in IPSec
you know and you hear about all this
technology and you know you will hear
quite a bit about H Mac you know H max
sha
H Mac md5 and another thing that I find
so funny about security is that you have
to understand like the security in depth
little nitty-gritty details to actually
configure security I hate that I think
it's stupid it's like understanding the
Dijkstra algorithm I you know really
understanding it to configure your
routing protocols and now I'm hoping
that vendors will get away from that
because I don't really care what cha or
md5 or all these things are but I have
to make a decision whether or not to
pick one or the other right I mean
that's a pet peeve of mine with security
but anyway so exclusive-or how many of
you know remember this from math way
back when okay cool
I'm not going to go over it so look at
this slide I mean it's pretty simple you
know it just means that you have you
know one string of bits the same size of
the other string of bits and you know
you come up with some answer in that
that answer is reversible so you can
come up with the input again so the
reason that I brought that up was
because when you do a keed message
authentication code it's also basically
a keyed message digest a lot of hash
functions are used with a specific key
okay you combine a shared secret with
the hash function and essentially that's
what H Mak is it's a keyed Mac so the
message whatever data you're trying to
send okay let's say it's a routing
update the message is broken down into n
blocks of 512 bits then the shared
secret key which you've configured on
both sides is ex-ored a function that I
just showed you in the slide is the XOR
is applied with a specific array and
these arrays are well known they're
defined okay and then you end up with a
k1 and so that's jarett see if the
shared secret is exhorted second time
with another specific array to produce
all right so this is just some
pre-processing that's done all right and
so when you're doing IPSec I mean this
is basically what's what's used so you
have the standard itself there's people
that have come up with these arrays that
you use okay and so you have a message
that you're going to be sending and so
you then XOR the message with one array
come up with the result and then you
take the shared secret key and you XOR
it with another second array and you
come up with k2 now you start the
hashing process so you then take the
first block of the message and the
result k1 and you apply the md5
algorithm to it and you end up with hash
one then what you do is you take that
hash one and you concatenate that with
k2 and you end up you apply the md5
algorithm and you end up with hash two
and now depending on how many blocks of
messages you have you end up
continuously iterating the hash function
by taking a block of message and the
previous hash and applying the md5
algorithm all right and then essentially
once you get to the last block of
message you get your last hash you end
up with a string of bits remember that
it's 128 bits for md5 and 160 bits for
sha and then depending on a specific
algorithm like H Mac md5 96 that means
that you truncate to 96 bits all right I
don't know how many of you care about
this but it might be interesting so
anyway I figured I'd explain it so so
keyed md5 and keyed sha is very often
used in most algorithms again to provide
more security right so then all right
what a digital signature is all about
because we hear about digital signatures
in my best experience you know there's a
lot of talk around it there's not a lot
of people that actually practically use
them
and most of the reason why is because it
relies on the public key infrastructure
right a PKI and i believe since 96 or 97
you know people there were really hot
and heavy about being able to implement
a PKI but the problem is that nobody
knows who to trust right I mean do you
trust the US Post Office I remember that
was a you know something that people
wanted to do at one point in time and
you know you you might be you might
trust your own corporation but then
again how scalable is it right so I
believe that hopefully now like most of
the other security issues have come to
some kind of resolution that nobody can
hand wave anymore about the PKI issue so
I am still optimistic that maybe in the
next couple of years you know people
will will come up with a credible and
practical solution for how to actually
enroll certificates in a secure manner
because that is the whole entire problem
that still needs to be solved is how do
you bootstrap the entire system right
and and I like here - I remember if it's
tomorrow night or I think it's tomorrow
night the PGP key signing right I mean
people get in the room to say yep that's
who he is right how do you do that with
thousands of devices right so anyway
that's a big problem to be solved but so
what is a digital signature it's
basically a message that's appended to a
packet and it's used to provide the
identity of the sender and integrity of
the packet and to common digital
signature techniques are RSA and DSS and
how it works is that a sender uses its
private key to sign a packet and the
receiver uses the public key to verify
the signature so I'll talk about digital
signatures a little bit more later
because especially in route
authentication the problem is and what I
found and I for years was also under the
misconception was that md5
authentication
is actually digital signature but it's
not so it's basically you just append a
a hash message digest to a routing
update so you know the power that is is
you know a little controversial I think
and one of the things I'm going to bring
out in the second session just as
something to think about is that whether
or not it makes more sense in the future
to look at either using the md5
authentication mechanisms that are
either an extension or built-in to the
routing protocols or whether or not it
makes more sense to beat up on the
vendors and provide some mechanism to
provide for IPSec authentication okay I
know that some vendors actually have
made it fairly simple with doing bgp
authentication using IPSec and the thing
is that key getting new keys is a lot
easier that way I think a lot of
implementations of md5 authentication
the major issue is that all right so
you've configured your key what happens
when you want to have a new key maybe
two months six months down the line
because you really should not have the
same key for years and years on end and
then it becomes this problem of well you
know through the inflammation
implementations actually support that or
is your routing going to be down for you
know a couple of minutes or even longer
while the new keys then get
reestablished so that's just something
to think about if you haven't even
implemented it I'm a very strong
proponent of doing some kind of out of
ten occasion whether or not you are
going to start using IPSec or use the
md5 is still something that I think on
people should really really look at from
a practical point of view all right so
as a summary public key encryption okay
is typically used for data origin
authentication and it's often combined
with a hash function so to do a
to do digital signatures secret key
encryption is typically used for data
confidentiality and to do secret key
encryption it's usually computationally
a lot less intensive all right public
key technology you take up a lot of CPU
cycles when you're trying to determine
what your private private and public key
pairs are the diffie-hellman algorithm
is very widely used to create a shared
secret in a in an open environment and
let's see hash functions rather easy to
compute used for data origin
authentication and data integrity and
digital signatures use hash functions of
public key cryptography all right so
that's just that's sort of the basics of
how any kind of security technologies
they use one of these fundamentals right
either a public key technology a
symmetric key technology or a hash
function or combination of so now all
right in the real world right what do
you use and again I'm going to talk
about first authentication technologies
because there's a slew of them and
there's a number of trade-offs and then
what do you do if you're looking at
providing confidentiality from either
your application layer or your network
layer a transport layer and there's so
many security technologies out there
what do they fit into your environment
and what should you consider wear so if
we look at methods of authentication
right how many of you do not use
one-time passwords when you're accessing
your infrastructure devices higher all
right so that's probably about half of
you I would very strongly urge you to
try and get one-time passwords in place
it's not very difficult to have these
systems one of the things that people
always tell me is that they hate
carrying around a DES card or some token
car
and what I always say is I point to
somebody and say well take out your
wallet
okay and how many credit cards do you
have in there and I usually say you know
throw three of them away put a desk card
in there okay and only keep one or two
credit cards in or whatever because it's
just a matter of carrying a card and it
will make your infrastructure a lot more
secure now the assumption of courses
that you are logging into your
infrastructure when you're traveling
around to conferences such as this okay
and I believe that most people do that
most people who run network
infrastructures do not just sit in there
knock and login okay you will be
somewhere else probably 50 percent of
the time and you do not have control of
the network that you know your data
travels across so I just very strongly
believe and if you can put in one time
password schemes ok so s key and token
cards are the typical ones that are used
s key these slides will show basically
how the algorithm works and most of
these technologies I'm going to talk to
you about now they're all RFC's right
they all come from the IETF so if you're
really interested in more detail
you know either read that this is just
kind of a synopsis of how they work so
what happens with with s key is you
typically have a client you have a
network access server and you have the S
key server both the S key server and the
client are initialized with a shared
secret so what happens is that the
client sends an S key initialization
packet which gets to the server and the
server then says all right you know I
I'm going to send you a random seed and
a sequence number so what the client
then does is it takes the password and
the random number and it applies a hash
function typically md5 and doesn't 98
times ok because again 98 was the
sequence number that the S key server
sent and so at the end of that 98 times
it then gets a sick
swerd output which it then goes and
sends over to the s key server now the s
key server knows that it sent the
sequence number of 98 and what it does
is it then takes the input that it gets
from the client and runs it through the
md5 hash function and the output of that
should match what it has in its database
for sequence number 99 okay so that's
essentially a quickie version of how s
key works now s key resources there's a
lot of free implementations available I
put a question under Microsoft because I
don't know but it you know there's I
believe that s key is very very widely
available and it's something that really
a lot of people should look into so ok
authentication authentication is
interesting because there's so many
different ways and so many different
things that you could use PPP all right
I believe that all of you that run any
kind of an ISP use PPP authentication
right you have two so you could either
use PAP you could use chap you could use
mschap or EEP so why would you use one
over the other well let's just go
through this a little bit
so with PAP within ocation tap when PPP
was first created right it was assumed
that people would just dial in via the
leased lines and that nobody would be
able to sniff the wire okay if you are
in an environment where you run a DSL
and you might be using PPP over ethernet
okay which changes that model some of
your PPP traffic may run over a shared
media and people will be able to sniff
the wire right it's very easy I mean
just you know go to ether real you know
downloaded right now if you're connected
to the network and you know probably
takes about two minutes to download
click on the icon you're sniffing the
network
okay well this for a wireless but on the
ethernet too it's very easy on to get
access to Ethernet networks so with top
authentication what happens is that the
password is sent in the clear so you're
doing authentication both the client and
the server have a shared secret
configured and what you're doing is that
when there's an authentication request I
you basically send your ID and you send
the password the pre-configured password
the server looks it up in its database
it sees the match and says ok yep you
know you're authenticated but the
problem is that nothing is encrypted
nothing's confidential so you're sending
the password in the clear so I typically
recommend that people stay completely
away from PAP just last night though I
was talking to somebody and they said
well you know people like Pat because
you can store the secret in a secure
manner so when I talk about chap soon
the the way the RFC is written it
basically says that you can't store a
secret in an encrypted fashion but that
is very much under controversy I believe
that if you do some pre-processing then
you can so I would stay away from PAP I
don't like anything any of my passwords
send over clear text anywhere because I
just think that in this day and age it's
too easy for people to sniff the
passwords or some shared secrets and as
the years go by I tend to trust people
less and less and there's more people
even within a corporate environment you
know even in your ISPs that I don't know
I mean they could just cause too much
damage and so to me any kind of password
sent across a wire really should be
encrypted so with PPP chap with n
occation the client and server are both
are configured with a shared secret just
as with
have and the shared secret is used as
input to a hash function with which
computes a challenge and the and it uses
repeated challenges so during a session
it's a user configurable parameter but
you can send a challenge maybe I don't
know every five minutes you know just to
make sure that nobody's hijacked the
connection and either of the chap here
connect as the initiator of the
authentication so here's sort of a slide
that that describes that so if you have
some kind of a router and that's
connecting to a network access server
the first thing that happens is the
network access server would send a
challenge message and the challenge
master message would have an ID it would
have the challenge number just a random
number and then the name of the remote
host the remote host then would sit
there and compute a hash value using a
combination of the ID the challenge
number and the shared secret it would
chant send a challenge response back
okay and the challenge response would
include the ID the calculated hash and
then also the the name of the the
network access server the network access
server would then calculate the hash it
would compute I mean it would compare
what it computed to what it got and if
it matches then it says yep okay you're
authenticated and sends an
authentication success but the point
here is that for Chapa then' occation
either end can start the initiation both
sides can be authenticated and you're
not sending anything in clear-text so
you're not sending any kind of password
in clear-text across the wire so there's
also Microsoft came up with its own
version of chap and it has two versions
of it one of the major things that it
did was that it allows you to store the
shared secret in an encrypted manner
because the
ERF see that specifies chap which is
1994 claims that you cannot store the
shared secret in the database in an
unencrypted fashion it has to be stored
in the clear I have heard from some
people that have implemented chap as it
is that if you do certain pre-processing
that that's actually wrong okay so
whatever I don't know but if you're
implementing either chap or you're
implementing path understand what you
are vulnerable to okay you have to
understand or you have to see how secure
your servers are your database servers
you know where are they who can have
access to them and you know how many
networks do you traverse going from the
network access server you know to to to
where you're actually going to the pier
so if it's just one hop away maybe you
trust the network but if it's five hops
away you know there's more likelihood
that somebody can maybe sniff the
network alright more recently recently
for years PPP there is a working group
that has come up with an extensible way
of doing authentication because as our
networks have evolved right it becomes
clear that PAP and chap really aren't
going to cut it in terms of providing
any kind of real good authentication
mechanism and the thought is more
towards the future and hopefully maybe
being able to use some kind of a public
key technology to provide for
authentication so the extensible
authentication protocol on e was created
to provide more flexibility for
authentication in PPP environments and
so essentially you you can negotiate
what kind of authentication you use
during the authentication process
because for both PAP and for chap what
happens is you create a PPP
which is a link connection protocol and
during the link connection protocol you
have to define whether or not you use
pop or chap and then you do your network
control protocol and in the beginning of
that you actually do your authentication
and the authentication is optional for
PPP and so what ends up happening is
that with eep you don't have to define
what the authentication mechanism is
when you're doing your link control
protocol all right so you establish your
link and then you do EEP and during the
EEP phase you then say oh you know
something I want there's a number of
packets that go back and forth so you
requests and responses and basically
without those packets there changes you
then decide on which authentication you
want to use do you want to use a
one-time password do you want to use
chap do you want to use Kerberos
authentication I mean there's a whole
slew that are being defined and so as
new authentication mechanisms evolve
then it can handle that ok so more and
more people more and more devices when
they're implementing PPP and doing some
kind of authentication they are using it
because it gives you a lot more
flexibility so essentially here's a
picture that shows how this would work
and once the PPP link is established
between the telecommuter and the network
access server the network access server
would then say ok you know I need some
credentials from you telecommuter you
know and it sends an e prett
the telecommuter would then send an e
p-- response which gets forwarded to the
e p-- server typically this will be a
radius server maybe a tack ax+ server as
well but a lot of times radius is used
the EEP server then would send an e per
quest which basically gives the the
mechanism that it wants to use and
forwards it to the telecommuter the
telecommuter would then respond with the
information the credential that the
server needs the server would verify and
then you know the telecommuter would get
authenticated so essentially the network
access server then just becomes a
pass-through
and what's nice about EEP too is that if
for instance you are using a one-time
password today for your authentication
but you want to use digital certificates
maybe five years down the line three
years down the line you do not have to
change any software on the network
access server per se right you can just
do it with the each server or the radio
server so that's that's a pretty cool
thing so just as a summary for PPP
authentication in PAP the password is
sent in the clear and in my personal
opinion should be avoided in a PPP chat
the passwords are at least encrypted and
then PPP EEP is the most flexible and I
think in today's networks if you're
figuring out or trying to decide on what
authentication to use PPP EEP is really
the way to go so all these
authentication mechanisms all right so
what do you do I mean you're going to
have large networks and you need some
kind of scalability right I mean you're
not going to sit there and configure on
every single device these shared secrets
so most of these technologies that I was
discussing with PPP like your path your
chap your EEP they end up being used in
conjunction with some scalable protocols
like tack x+ or radius which provide in
addition to the authentication piece
also access control and accounting and
then there's also Kerberos so just to
get a feel for it because I know I mean
as I give these talks you know it's like
people who understand it you know they
might look at one piece or another other
pieces or never other people have never
seen it you know their eyes get glazed
over because there's just way too much
information to process so I am NOT going
to go over this in detail because the
primary thing that I've
we want to focus on anyway is just
alright you guys are going to be
architecting your networks some of you
have already put security stuff in place
and what is the most relevant in your
environments what are the five most
important things that you should be
thinking about and then giving you some
you know configuration examples so these
particular slides I mean remember I give
this talk and it's usually a couple of
days or a week long but you will have
this alright you will be able to see
this in your slides if you are
interested in how this works this is
very much a synopsis okay
and if you're even more interested than
you know you might want to read through
the RFC's but who has time for that so
I'm just giving you some quickie like
crib notes in terms of what's important
when you look at authentication for tax
plus the thing to keep in mind is that
the transactions between a tax plus
client and a tax plus server are
encrypted okay it's confidential so if
I'm sniffing the wire between attack ex
plus client and attack ex plus server I
will not be able to understand what it
is just by sniffing the wire and if
anybody's interested in sort of how what
algorithm is used that's right there so
it's a combination of a hash function
and the XOR function Cal Cox plus header
I don't know to put that in there
because sometimes people interested if
they're you know trying to debug
something that's what the header looks
like so the exchange the main reason
that I have this picture in the exchange
or regarding the exchange is because
there's a misnomer sometimes that what
the user sends to the network access
server is encrypted it is not okay so
what is encrypted and how tacacs+ works
is that the network access server is the
tax plus client and then it talks to the
tax plus server that communication is
encrypted but what the user sends to the
network access sir
River is most likely not encrypted okay
so if you're using chap or using PAP or
or you know you're trying to ascertain
what kind of a password to get it could
be sent in the clear and so if you're
connecting a user to the network access
server be very clear and whether or not
you understand whether or not somebody
could have access to the information
that's traversing the wire okay so when
we're talking tac-x plus and we're
talking about you know encrypted
confidential transactions it's between
the tax plus plus client which is the
network access server and the tax plus
server okay so the transactions or the
information being sent from the user to
the network access server is going to be
in the clear so radius radius is very
much like tax plus right they're more or
less anonymous I mean there are some
differences again tax plus was basically
Cisco trying to you know get market
share I mean they did add some value to
it but I think in this day and age most
people will use radius it's more widely
available there's a lot of free versions
available and you know even Cisco at
this day and age is not pushing tax plus
they're just saying you know whichever
one you want to use so the major
difference with radius and tax plus is
that within radius you have the same
kind of client and server model where
the network access server is the radius
client but the transactions are are not
completely encrypted only the password
is encrypted so whatever the user
credential is okay that is encrypted
between the radius client and the radius
server
so the the transaction looks basically
the same or how the authentication is
carried out and again the same kind of
consideration here where the password
that's encrypted okay it's from the
radius client through the radius server
so the radius client being the network
access server so whatever you're sending
from the telecommuter or the user going
to the network access server may or may
not be encrypted most likely it's not so
as a comparison tax plus I mean uses TCP
so it uses a more reliable transport
radius uses UDP and it's supposed to use
UDP port 1812 some older versions use
the other port 1645 just an FYI only the
password is confidential and radius and
when people ask well which one should I
use right um I think the answer comes
down to more of a well what features are
supported and you know what is the
vendor support like so I think those are
the most important things in terms of
you know what are the attributes that
are that are supported and if you have a
variety of different equipment or you
know you're using an NT environment and
you know money comes into play so the
trade-offs are I don't know you know
it's it's really one or the other and I
think most people do end up using radius
simply because it's a little cheaper and
the it's a viable option all right
another question here because there's so
much material I need to find out so I
can figure out what to like kind of skip
how many of you are in a Kerberos
environment considering how many of you
are considering Kerberos ok I'm going to
skip over these slides how many of you
want to know about Kerberos all right I
won't completely skip over them so but
I'll go over them fast I mean you know
you won't understand if you don't know
about these technologies I can't teach
them to you in five minutes
or you know even ten minutes again if
you are more interested in some of this
and it's new to you or you have some
questions I mean I'll be here till
Wednesday morning right so we can sit
down and I don't know you know if I can
provide you with some information great
you know I actually really like security
so so anyway so just as a caveat so if
you're wondering why I'll shoot you know
she was going too quick I want to know
more it's really hard when you have so
many different levels to really get
everybody you know to like please
everybody completely so grab me later
so okay Kerberos it was designed by MIT
major point is it uses a trusted third
party to issue tickets to users all
right I think most of us actually sort
of know that so Kerberos Kerberos relies
also it relies on a shared key so you
have a KDC which is a key distribution
center and that's the trusted third
entity in Kerberos and you configure
keys so shared keys so you configure a
shared key between the KDC and the
client and you then configure another
shared key between the application
server and the KDC so those would be kay
client and Kay server respectively so
the KDC has this whole database of
principles which is basically entities
that it has shared keys with and their
associated keys and also access rights
so what are they allowed to do so in
what ends up happening for a Kerberos
authentication is that the client sends
an authentication request the key
distribution center the trusted third
party server verifies the client access
rights like is it even allowed to do you
know what it wants to do and it sends
some kind of an authentication response
which starts the whole process where it
sends a session key a random number and
server name and these are all encrypted
with the client key
it also sends a Kerberos ticket a ticket
that's encrypted with the server key and
then what the client does it prompts the
user for the password right so whoever
sitting at the client and it uses that
key to then decrypt the session key so
now we have a session key okay that both
the client and the server have and now
you're trying to you know dedicate the
application so the client then sends out
an application request which is the
Kerberos ticket encrypted with the
server key and they also sends an
Authenticator which is sort of a token
encrypted with the session key the
server decrypts the Kerberos ticket to
get the session key which is then used
to decrypt the Authenticator and I see a
lot of eyeballs just calling hook yeah
yes this is very confusing so you know
you're going to have to like spend a
little bit of time probably to just kind
of mull over this and I'm just reading
off the slides because I don't know how
else to do it right now but how
essentially what happens is there's a
number of transactions that happen you
have shared keys between the client and
the trusted third party you have a
shared key between the trusted third
party and the application server and
there's a number of transactions that
happen back and forth and you know how
it's encrypted and how somebody gets the
key and the end result is that you end
up having this ticket okay which is
basically you know string of bits that
as you're sending it back and forth
between your application server and and
yourself you can verify that you are who
you say you are and that you are allowed
to do what what you think you're allowed
to do and for example if you want to do
Kerberos authentication for accessing a
network device right so the network
device then will have to have some
Kerberos
software on it you have to run Kerberos
on your client and then there's another
Kerberos server of course the trusted
entity and then the transactions happen
in place so that you you as a client end
up with a string of bits that when
you're sending your telnet packet to
let's say the router but then the router
can verify that yes it is actually you
and you are allowed to tell it to the
router alright and it is complex right I
mean that's why the RFC so big but but
mathematically it's fairly sound the one
thing that you need to know in a
Kerberos environment is that it's very
dependent upon time stamps and the thing
with time stamps and it's it's something
that you know it's it's a simple concept
but it's amazing how many people just
you know it kind of falls through the
cracks it's you want to make sure that
you have consistent time stamps
throughout your network and I ran into
this I mean I have a very small network
at home I mean I do have about five or
six routers and I have probably two
servers and maybe five hosts because I
play with stuff I want to understand all
the security stuff with all these things
and I started you know just configuring
syslog and I have a UNIX machine and I
have my router and then yeah I'm just
like oh cool I've configured logging
right and about a week later I started
looking at these logs and I'm like huh I
got confused and I realized the reason
why was because I hadn't set up NTP on
my UNIX server you know I just used
whatever those system time was on there
or I had used something else and it was
off by about a minute you know and I
mean trying to actually figure out it
took me about a day to realize what I
had done I can't remember not what it
was like two years ago but it was off by
one minute now if you're doing some kind
of forensics later and you're trying to
figure out what happened a minute is a
very very long time okay so it's
extremely critical that you configure
your timestamps on all of your devices
that you are going to require to have
logging capabilities and make sure that
they they're all synced up and extremely
important and you know again it might
seem like a simple
point but I've run across a lot of
people who are like oh yeah shoot you
know and they go and verify and you know
they put in the commands for the NTP
servers but you know check your logs
make sure that they sync up and with
Kerberos it's very important to have
synchronized and dependable mechanisms
because Kerberos very much depends on on
timestamps so all right now when we talk
about real networks again okay cool so
you're authenticated well so what right
so I'm sitting at home and I want to
access my network infrastructure because
for some reason I need to change an
access list or a filter somewhere so the
thing is you know if I authenticate can
I then have access to absolutely
everything well that used to be the case
I believe now people are getting much
much more stricter in terms of what kind
of access rights people can have to
various parts of their network and
unfortunately I think it's going to grow
worse because it used to be that you
know networks were all open and you know
everybody thought it was really cool now
that it's become a business and there's
a lot of money involved we basically
have to restrict access and so ok so if
you authenticate how can you then
control access to what people have
access to well here comes I Triple E 802
dot 1x and you know people have been
doing proprietary things for a number of
years now there's actually a standard
way to first of all authenticate
somebody and then to give them
privileges to access certain parts of
the network so 802 dot 1x has three
entities defined one is a supplicant one
is an Authenticator and one is an
authentication server just you know
three terms and basically what the
supplicant can do is it can
gain access to the Authenticator the
Authenticator will only allow traffic to
go to the authentication server the
traffic can't go anywhere else and only
once the supplicant is authenticated can
the authentication server then define
the access controls as to okay what
areas of the network can you actually
have have access to so I hate the term
supplicant I don't know to me it's
always so confusing a supplicant is
simply you know you you know my host
okay
my host that's trying to gain access to
the network so and 802 dot 1x as again
you know it's new forward thinking so
you use the extensible authentication
protocol for your authentication because
you want the flexibility right you might
want to use one-time passwords today you
might want to use public key
cryptography you know six months from
now so here's sort of an example of how
this works and since I don't wear
watches anymore what what time is it
twenty two three okay cool thank you so
802 dot 1x so here's what happens
supplicant ie workstation and then you
have the Authenticator which is
typically a workgroup switch and then
you have some kind of a server which
more or less is a radius server so all
right what happens so when the
workstation connects to the switch port
ok it's only enabled for a certain
defined traffic which the acronym is
Ipoh and I forget what it stands for so
I'm like Ethernet access something
something something ok basic it's a
protocol that says you know something
the only traffic that's allowed is this
e Paul traffic and so the workstation
then sends an initial authentication
packet exchange using this protocol
alright so certain bit in a packet that
says hey on
hope so the last which then gets that
packet and thus which translates between
the eep-eep all messages and the eat
radius servant messages and it's just
the pass through all right so the
workstation now talks to the radius
server and they carry out the
authentication exchange and you know
again EEP is basically just a bunch of
requests and response packets the first
one says hey you know I want to use one
time password and then the response is
like okay well you know here's a
challenge and blah blah blah and they
send whatever credentials they need back
and forth
so whatever authentication mechanism you
use you just kind of request hey I want
to use this authentication mechanisms or
mechanism and then you transfer the
credential information back and forth
and you hopefully have a successful
authentication and then once you have a
successful authentication because you're
typically using a radio server you can
then define your access control as -
alright you know this guy is now
sonicated and here's the the access
control rights that that particular
workstation has okay so I believe that
people are not really going to allow
access control all over the place to
their network and this gives you a lot
of flexibility so that if you have
different kind of customers with
different requirements right you don't
have to worry so much about doing other
convoluted things but you can use this
mechanism to then give the access
control rights to only certain places so
I think it's a very powerful thing and
you really should think about it and one
of the things that I've also thought
about I mean with all this stuff with
the viruses and worms I have become a
very strong component of if you at all
can do this right - and especially if
you're an ISP that has a lot of
customers that really will not be very
knowledgeable about any kind of virus
checking or upgrading their soft
okay I mean the environments vary so
much in terms of what you guys as ISPs
do but if you have any kind of control
at all what I like about 802 1x that
used in a conjunction with maybe being
able to have some kind of control of
your customers machines and having them
go through some kind of a virus check
and then maybe pointing them to a
particular area of the network if they
fail so that they can then download
whatever appropriate version of software
you think you know and you've tested in
your environment for your customers that
this could be a very interesting thing
to do in the future
you know because the biggest problem we
right now have in terms of security is
really the proliferation of viruses and
network downtime and it's getting a lot
worse and I used to be somebody that
said nobody's ever going to touch my
machine have control over it but as I
look around you know it's causing a lot
of detriment in terms of ISP networks
and you know the issue is just getting
worse and worse that people have to be
be educated and I do think there needs
to be more control especially from ISPs
and again you know that's very
controversial but I'm just going to put
that out there all right so
authentication technologies right I mean
there's tons of them everybody uses
probably bits and pieces of everything
that I've discussed and they always will
okay because no technology ever goes
away then again chaos and that went away
didn't it so you never know but as an
authentication as a summary I am a very
strong proponent that used one-time
passwords whenever possible you know
come up to me with whatever excuse you
have and I will probably have an answer
to mitigate that hopefully but you know
seriously you know try to do one-time
passwords it's it's really the securest
way to go PPP eep with radius okay if
you're using PPP environments that is
really something you should very
strongly
consider and Triple A solutions again
radius or tactics plus can be used with
most authentication functions a nato 2.1
x will replace proprietary port of the
location features and so 802 got 1x is
is something to really look at and and
of course if you have a multi vendor
environment you know understand what
what some of the interesting features
and functionalities are where they may
or may not be interoperable but that's
other discussion all right application
layer security s HTTP mime or to ones
that usually come to mind a lot of
people don't use as HTTP because a lot
of people use SSL which i will describe
in a little bit s/mime the reason i want
to bring this up is because for people
that are considering voice over IP
networks for authentication s mime is
part of the standard
it used to be PGP they got rid of that
so s mine will become important and you
should understand that s mine provides
these security services so
authentication message integrity
basically verify or validating that
nobody has messed with your message
while it's going from let's say caller 2
to a receiver and and origin
authentication and also privacy and data
security so it provides the services but
you don't have to use all of them it is
up to the implementation is to decide
whether or not to digitally sign a
message first or encrypt it ok and
there's of course various trade-offs so
if you first sign a message and you
provide the integrity for it and then
you encrypt it you will always have to
decrypt it before you can verify maybe
who the caller was or the initiating
party right
so there's trade-offs its implementation
specific which you know I always hate
because that means that there's all
these issues with trying to figure out
what's interoperable and who's doing
what and if you're in a multi vendor
environment gets interesting so s/mime
the reason why it's really really
important to understand it is
more or less if you have or thinking of
voice over IP networks transport layer
security all right
SSL TLS long history basically the top
sentence I mean it provides data
encryption server authentication message
integrity in an optional client
authentication for tcp/ip connections
basically it uses the tcp transport so
you know you're not going to be
authenticating UDP and what ssh does
I mean SSL sorry essentially you have an
SSL client and an SSL server and the
client will initiate the SSL connection
and send a supported set of Cypress
cipher suites now cipher suites are
essentially okay what algorithm do I use
for confidentiality what algorithm do I
use for data origin authentication and
some of the first slides that I had
remember that your encryption right you
basically use something like DES or AES
or Triple DES so you pick one of them
right or for a message or origin
authentication you might use some kind
of a hash function so do you use md5 to
use sha-1 so in the first initial
message you send basically what you
propose as alright this is the algorithm
that I want to use for you know
confidentiality encryption this is the
algorithm that I want for data origin
authentication blah blah blah the server
then selects a cipher suite and returns
its digital certificate to the client
and the client sends and encrypted
shared secret back so what now happens
is that the message encryption and data
integrity algorithms are negotiated so
you now have a secure tunnel to
negotiate your message in
encryption and integrity algorithms you
create session keys and then the data is
sent over
you know the secure tunnel with the
parameters you've negotiated now the
important thing about SSL is that client
authentication is is optional and what a
lot of implementations do is because
public key infrastructures really do not
exist very much somebody always tells me
well we use one and then last night
somebody goes well we have one but well
it's not really that public okay well
you know so what people do is for client
authentication they usually have some
proprietary client authentication
mechanisms and what happens is they do
it after the secure tunnel is
established for SSL so actually the
client authentication the credential
material traverses over the secure
tunnel so if you look at transport layer
security
there's a lot of people that talk about
you know how to create VPN so I use
IPSec do I use you know SSL TLS in the
second part of the session I talked
about sort of architectures and things
that you have to think about for
anything that deals with with with the
transport essentially you're going to be
poking a hole through the firewall right
because firewalls typically look at
layer three traffic and you look at you
know your port numbers your your
addresses and you don't look any deeper
you don't look at the transport layer
per se and what end well now you do
anyway but if you do SSL or TLS you end
up more or less poking a hole in the
firewall and then ensuring that the
traffic will go to its end destination
right whatever its application is and I
think that SSL or TLS and IPSec work in
conjunction with with each other but
later on I will point out that if you do
encryption or
at the network layer you have a little
bit more flexibility yes I don't know
offhand it could be pop I think I
actually looked at the the RFC numbers
so we're at the Ayane numbers so the SMT
it should be 25 okay okay
you could be right yeah you know
something I I don't know them offhand on
top of my head so but you could be right
so basically what the slide points out
is that there's a defined port number
for these protocols either your your
mail server FTP or whatever and then if
you're using TLS or SSL to secure them
then there's a different port number
that's defined by Ayane I'll check on
that all right
SSH I'm not going to go through this um
what SSH is essentially it's a mechanism
to people use it to access your your
devices it's a low-level Transfer
Protocol and it encrypts traffic so if
you're on a device let's say your laptop
here and you're trying to connect back
to some device somewhere else rather
than having all the information sent in
clear text where somebody can actually
view it you know if some I mean
everybody's using Wireless here rather
than sending the information in the
clear you can be fairly assured that you
know II well nobody is going to be able
to nobody if they're actually sniffing
the wireless network will without doing
more work be able to compromise your
devices and you know if we careful what
I say because of course you know you can
get the encrypted data and depending on
what other computers and what other else
you have you might be able to crack
whatever scheme there is but for the
very silly little little little attacks
where you know it's very easy for
somebody to sniff the wire and see the
word if you use SSH it keeps your
information much more confidential and
you know people have to do a lot more
work to actually try and compromise your
systems so SSH you should if at all
possible
always use SSH to access your devices
telnet is very very bad people should
not be using it anymore the only caveat
being that you know sometimes there's
bugs and devices and what some people do
is they actually do SSH to certain hosts
within their networks and then from that
trusted host they then telnet to
whatever device right but if at all
possible use SSH so okay
IPSec how many of you are using IPSec
currently how many of you are using
IPSec to authenticate your routing
updates okay how many of you are using
IPSec for confidentiality so that means
that most of you using IPSec for
authentication so data origin
authentication how many of you are using
IPSec only for data origin
authentication all right I'm confused
okay
unless I'm asking the wrong questions
but so most of you raise your hands to
say that you're using IPSec
so IPSec can be used for either origin
authentication data integrity right same
thing or for data confidentiality or for
both so most of you using IPSec but none
of you raise your hands for integrity or
confidentiality so what are you doing so
I'm curious somebody you know it's
alright let me ask the question again
how many of you have configured and are
using a no sending traffic between your
devices use
IPSec nobody okay alright okay alright
so we're going to talk about IPSec
because maybe maybe somebody will at
some point use it you know a lot of
people spend a lot of time in these
meetings to define this god-awful
standard and it well I will tell you my
perspective okay because I'm up here and
I can is that the thing that I think is
the problem with IPSec is is quite
frankly vendors and I think that what
vendors need to do is that they need to
simply have these configuration things
that tell users that do you want to use
IPSec do you want to have data integrity
do you want to have confidentiality and
then you one more thing that they need
to ask is how do you want to
authenticate because you have to figure
out whether or not you're going to do
pre-shared keys which is a shared secret
whether or not you using digital
signatures like RSA signatures or
whether or not you have a public key
infrastructure and that's it you know I
don't understand this garbage about mod
P groups you know who knows what a mod P
group is now you do well
what my P group is it's a different
group so you have to know the IPSec
standard to configure IPSec in your
devices I don't get it and then you know
I've talked to a bunch of the engineers
and the reply that I used to get was
well I don't want to define somebody's
security policy I'm like D fault you
know it's changeable so I've been
wanting for these smart security
engineers to get together define the
defaults have all the vendors implement
the same algorithm and stuff for the
default so that for the users they just
have to enter three commands and you're
done okay so I think there's a big
conspiracy theory going on but but
people are working on it it is getting
easier and I will actually try and
explain IPSec in a way that hopefully it
becomes a little more clear because
again I think a big issue would like
Pisa call so
is there is very confusing terminology
and you know I've spent a long time
really trying to think about why is it
so confusing
and you know people interchange
terminology in to two terms mean the
same thing right and I think that all
adds to the confusion yes five two
minutes okay thank you okay let me ask a
question another question sorry but um
security really there is so much to know
and I really try to at least get a lot
of the basics down because something
that I learned earlier land were very
early on in my security career or
networking careers how do you ask the
right questions you know so rather than
just sit there and give you a bunch of
templates which you're going to have
anyway in these slides once they're up
on the web you know and that's easy you
can just look at them say oh okay well
this looks cool I'll configure this I
very much want people to kind of go away
with a thinking process of okay this is
what I need to think about and because
people don't talk about them and I think
that's the hard part with security
because there's always trade-offs
there's so many trade-offs and just as
you have trade-offs when you're actually
just architecting your network like do I
use Ethernet or token ring or FTDI ATM
or whatever security um because there's
so much to consider there's many more
trade-offs to consider and I think
that's what makes security so hard is
because you have to spend a lot of time
talking about the trade-offs all right
so what I would like to do is I would
like to break what I would like to do is
spend maybe the first 15 minutes when we
come back if you guys come back or
whoever is here talking and trying to
simplify what IPSec actually is and what
the relevant parts are because then as I
go over how you actually configured in
different devices it might become easier
to understand how you configure it so
rather than go through that and then I
will very quickly go over what l2tp is
and then I will start in on ok so here's
all the slew of technologies and when
you're architecting your network
what are the things that you need to do
to actually you know do secure routing
you know have device security what are
the things you need to think about when
filtering and to do some kind of
auditing so I think I'll break now you
know that your brains were grouped for
about half an hour and then come back
thank you