this talk is about root server abuse
sort of a follow-on to a talk I gave
last year just doing this work with in
conjunction with kada and we're still
interested in understanding why the root
servers are getting slammed so much and
unlike the previous study which where we
analyzed traffic this one is a
simulation a lab simulation of various
name servers caching name servers so
we're interested in seeing are any
particular name server implementations
worse than others are they more abusive
are they distributing the load as we
would expect them to and here's a
cartoon of the test Network that I used
there's basically five boxes one box
handles root server queries one handles
top-level domains and one handles
second-level domains and actually
anything beyond that third level fourth
level etc there's a simulated wide area
network with packet loss and delays this
guy is the the caching name server where
this is the the part that we're
interested in testing and there's a box
that just submits whole bunch of queries
as a user might the workload is taken
from web proxy logs about 12 hours worth
there were five and half million total
dns queries with 107,000 unique host
names 70,000 unique second-level domains
431 top-level domains many of which are
invalid and only one root
I made up a bunch of zone files and the
the contents of those own files are sort
of based on reality for the for the root
and top-level domains it uses the actual
zone data for the number of nameservers
the and the TTL zon the name server and
glue records for the second-level domain
since there were so many of them it's
you know possible to have the actual
values there so I took a sample of real
data and then use that sample to
generate random values again here the
trying to mimic the number of address
records / name and the TTL zon address
name server and cname records one thing
that's a little different than reality
is each second-level domain has just two
name servers and this this last
measurement is thirty five percent
probability that any name is a cname
record was actually based on actual
measurements as well here's a sample
zone file I don't expect you to be able
to read this at least not on the screens
if you're really interested you can look
at the slides but this shows some
samples from from my simulated org zone
this is before the move to any cast
servers so there was something like
eight or nine different name servers and
on the right side you see some sample
zones some second-level zones under
there
this is a list of the caching software
that I tested two versions of bind bind
Aten by nine djb dns and two versions of
Windows this these different software
packages run only on the the caching
name server box the top level domain
second level and the roots all run bind
eight I did six different test
configurations the simplest one has no
delays and no packet loss then I did one
with constant hundred millisecond delays
and no packet loss I have three with
linear delays which I'll explain in the
next slide what that's about one with no
packet loss 5% Becca Lawson 25% packet
loss and finally one with one hundred
percent packet loss here's how the
linear delays were configured on the
first name server it was 40 milliseconds
delay and increased by 10 milliseconds
for every name server after that so the
13th name server in in cases where there
were 13 nameservers had 160 millisecond
delays
so there's a few results this graph
shows total number of queries sent by
each tested configuration each each
version of the software for the case of
no delays and no packet loss the blue
represents queries sent to the roots the
green is query since the top-level
domains and the red is queries to the
second-level domain name servers and you
can see that bind 8 has the most queries
with just over 1 million total for this
12-hour period and then then they sort
of go down from there one of the things
that's sort of striking about this is
bind9 sends quite a bit more queries to
the roots than any of any of the others
although DJ B DNS is similar there's a
few numbers down there just to show you
just even idea here's another result of
a sort of a more realistic case with
linear base delays and five percent
packet loss and the numbers are about
the same in most cases there they just
went up a little bit due to the delays
on the loss so x + 8 sends a lot of
queries and here are some of the reasons
why at least on in in my tests where I
had ipv6 on the box it sends both quad a
& a 6 queries to all of the nameservers
the roots the second level of top-level
domains for any name server address that
has expired and bind eight and actually
all of the other software except for by
nine do what I call they forward cache
misses for pending hits so they they
forward misses for repeated queries and
here's her sort of an example of that a
TCP dump output where there's two
queries right in a row for the same name
and if you spent the time to follow this
through you would see that the bind9
caching name server sends for queries
all the way through through the roots
the second-level domains until it gets
the first answer back so in the case
where you have a high rate of queries
for a single a name you can get a lot of
queries perhaps and onion esses ery
amount of queries by nine is the only
software that is sort of smart enough to
realize that it's expecting a reply for
this name any second now and it
postpones later queries until that reply
comes back but on the other hand by nine
still sends a lot of queries to the
roots and one of the reasons is that it
sends a & a 6 queries for both expired
name server records starting at the root
so when the cached glue record expires
it doesn't start at the top level domain
it starts back at the root perhaps
because it doesn't trust the the cached
data for the top-level domain and below
there's there's sort of a real real
world example where this might be
excessive Microsoft is a relatively
popular site they have for NS records
for glue records with relatively low
ttls so every time one of those blue
records expires a bind9 caching name
server is going to send eight queries to
the roots
and DJ BDS is similar it requires the
roots for the expired glue records but
only for one of the nameservers it
doesn't query both unless I suppose the
first one doesn't come back and it only
sends ipv4 address queries one of the
things that's unique about this software
is that it if it gets a an additional
record in a reply that is a glue record
with an IP address that has a TTL 0 it
is thinks there's something fishy about
that and starts back at the roots to get
that name servers IP address and here's
an example of that the first line shows
the user's query the second line shows
shows the caching name server asking for
this address at the top level domain the
answer comes back and there's a blue
record with a 0 TTL which you can't
really see but in the fourth line there
you can see that it goes to the roots
for NS a-- 0qu jebo calm and so on
here's all of the results for x + 8
except for the hundred percent loss test
which I'll show separately one of the
things that's interesting about this is
as the sort of network conditions get a
harsher bind9 their bind eight sends
slightly fewer queries it I don't know
if you can tell with the the graphs go
down a little bit especially for the
hundred percent millisecond or 100
millisecond delays there's quite a drop
to the top level domain queries there
here's the same thing for by nine and
one of the things interesting to note
here is that the number of queries is
unaffected by network delays but only by
loss so for the first three cases the
the total number of queries is just
about the same just about equal the
results for djb dns nothing nothing
really obvious to comment on here here's
windows 2000 and windows 2003
this graph I find particularly
interesting however this is the the
tests with one hundred percent packet
loss so this is what happens when a
caching name server can send queries out
to the roots but for some reason those
responses aren't aren't getting back and
there's quite a quite a lot of
difference here between the different
software on how they behave by nine is
obviously lower than any others and
remember from the workload slide that
this workload has five million total dns
queries so in the case of bind eight it
ends up sending about 38 million
quarters out to the roots for those five
million original queries and obviously
windows 2000 is even worse with
something like 65 million here's a
here's another way of looking at the
same data these are traces of the query
rates for all of the different
configurations the black line shows
queries generated by the user and as you
can see all of the software except for
by nine actually amplifies the query
rates I don't have the data shown here
but due to some other tests that I was
running at a higher query rate some of
these some of the software would
actually throttle itself you can't see
that here but I think windows 2000 did
not and bind eight and nine or DJB DNS
and find eight actually did throttle
themselves at some higher-level say you
know 2,000 queries per second was their
limit
I have a little bit of data now on the
way that these different caching
nameservers distributed the load to the
roots and in one of the top level
domains so that the common perception is
that the name servers pick the best one
based on measurements they perform they
know the network conditions they know
the round trip times and so on here's
here's an example of how this data looks
there's a there's two datasets shown
here the red shows queries sent to the
roots and the green shows queries sent
to the calm tlds the x axis has the 13
name servers for each one and the the to
y axis is show that counts although
that's sort of not not critical here
this is for bind 8 and in the case where
there's no packet loss of no delays by
and eight just latches on to one
particular name server and keeps using
it there's no reason for it to switch
the rest of this there's look pretty
reasonable there's something funny going
on however with the hundred percent
packet loss case where it hits some root
servers a little bit harder than others
twice as much it looks like but for the
the case is worth the linear delays it
looks reasonable sort of what we do
expect remember that the and all these
the the first name server the a has the
lowest latency in the M name server has
the highest here's buying date for the
no packet loss no delay case it's much
more even it's round robin essentially
currying all nameservers equally and the
same for the other two cases there at
the top and a nice exponential
distribution for all the linear delay
cases
djb DNS always does essentially
round-robin distribution to the name
servers regardless of packet loss or
delays and that's not no surprise they
they mention that in the software
description this is Windows 2000 and the
surprising thing here is for the cases
with linear delays that it seems to
ignore any actual measurements at all I
guess it always picks one names
essentially always fixing one name
server and just sticks with it and
additionally for the for the dot-com
name servers it always ends up picking a
and sends all of its queries to that for
the roots it's it's a little more random
this this may be an artifact of the the
way my test was set up I'm not sure or
it may just be that the way windows 2000
works for the hundred percent packet
loss case it's interesting that there's
some green lines there which probably
shouldn't be there at the x-axis shows
just one so it's sent one query to the
top level domains for for a few cases
but that's sort of an anomaly and here's
the current version of windows 2003 and
it's a little bit better still some
funny things going on with the one
hundred percent packet loss case where
some root nameservers get hit a lot more
than others and in the linear delay
cases it's not quite as smooth or not
not quite the distribution I would
expect to see but at least it is
distributed a little bit
so now I have to say a few things about
this this quote is from slashdot based
on the talk that I gave last year or the
paper that was presented last year where
I mentioned that two percent of only two
percent of the queries hitting the roots
are valid basically and here's the punch
line from last year's talk these are the
nine or so categories that I came up
with and I told you that you know
there's a lot of repeats there was a lot
of unknown top-level domains etc but the
legitimate category only got about two
percent so I i took the the results from
from this study my simulations and ran
it through the software from last year's
study and here are some of those numbers
unfortunately you know I didn't see that
all of my track all of my queries were
legitimate not surprisingly other I I
would expect to see this unknown TLD
category but I was a little bit
disappointed to see so many repeated
queries show up here and the referral
not cached category has a little bit too
high of percentages so the explanation
is that in last year's talk I was not
really aware of that software like bind9
and DJ be dns start over at the roots
for certain cases for expired name
server records and you know 0 TTL glue
records so if I exclude those queries
from the result and running again this
sort of shows some of the some of the
numbers it's it's better but it's still
not perfect another explanation may be
that the last year study I assume that
all the top level domains and the roots
had TTL is longer than the time of the
test so longer than 24 hours and in
running these tests that's certainly not
the case there certainly are top
domains with ttls shorter than 24 hours
but I'm still not sure that it's just as
simple as that so this perhaps means
that that number of two percent is
higher and that the case where this
referral not cached category which is
about four percent those may actually
have been legitimate queries and some of
the repeated queries may have been
legitimate also so I've just a couple of
conclusion slides left here bind eight
as we've seen can sort of latch on to a
single name server in in a low latency
low loss condition and unfortunately I
didn't run more tests and find what
those thresholds were there there must
be some threshold where you know it's
decided something's not quite right and
it starts to distribute the load a
little bit but I don't have those
numbers djb uses uniform distribution in
all cases ignoring ptl's are knowing the
round trip times and packet loss windows
2000 dns server is has a really really
bad service selection algorithm as far
as i can tell and the 2003 algorithm is
maybe a little bit better but i think
it's still be improved
it seems to me that the fact that bind
eight at least in by nine also since
queries to the roots for ipv6 addresses
may be causing a little bit of abuse I
really love the fact that by nine does
not forward cache misses for pending
hits I think that's a very nice thing be
and another thing I like about by nine
is that it attenuates the the load in
the case where it's not communicating
well with the root name server it
doesn't send more queries than the user
sends it sends fewer and finally as as I
admitted we need to I need to improve
the models for analyzing traces real
traces from real root servers and so on
to see if we can figure out how many
queries are legitimate and how many are
bogus that's it
you didn't go as long as I thought you
did any questions from the assembled
multitude for Dwayne okay I got 14 I've
got one for you are you as you try and
create refine your technique are you
going to try and refine your test bed to
more accurate or accurately reflect DNA
deployed DNS infrastructure or are you
going to just work on the modeling and
the software give me for example not
assuming that delays are linear across
name servers and so on like that yeah
yeah yeah I would I would I think that's
an important next step it but it's
obviously difficult because you know the
route the round-trip time distribution
depends on where you are who you are and
that sort of thing I guess that's
difficult with all the anycast name
servers out there and so on that that's
actually sort of intriguing because if
you actually put in any cast instance
into play in your test bed it would be
part of the problems with with managing
anycast instances is how how do you
actually mana monitor them and do load
sharing among them or do you just sort
of roughly guess and saying well that's
sort of an underserved area or an
underserved thing we'll put something
there because latency is so high and you
hope that things will work right on
routing protocols and the like so it it
would be interesting to see how you do
your test bed yeah I don't I don't think
it's I don't think I'm nearly to the
point where I could actually use actual
any cat servers in the test fit but
certainly it's it's easy to you know say
change the distribution of ttls or round
trip times nobody interests