all right we're going to go ahead and
start people filter in they'll miss the
exciting beginning of the talk
hopefully it'll still make sense anyway
this talk is called the edge of normal
my name is Mark I am a computer hacker
you might know me by the hacker handle
of simple Nomad that's usually how I
gone before in my past actually I kind
of still do and in some circles but with
this advent of you know Facebook
demanding you put your real name in or
they cut you off you can't have that
right so anyway I am a security
researcher at duo security they're the
two fa people the the good ones not the
bad ones that you hate and I do research
there for them a lot of protocol
analysis and general I look for
exploitable patterns which will be kind
of a running theme throughout this talk
that does conclude the sales portion of
my presentation this basically doesn't
have anything to do with with two-factor
authentication I may touch on it later
but just as a theme in passing I wear a
lot of different I've worn a lot of
different hats and as a result I've kind
of walked a lot of different paths and I
push the envelope in weird ways and so
this presentation is kind of a
continuation of that I'm going to touch
on some weird things and I decided as an
experiment to actually play around with
the typical format of a presentation
itself so I wanted to touch on some
things that you're not going to see in
this presentation you are not going to
see a detailed bio where I tell you
about
everything I've done in all my past
employers and everything if it seems
relevant I'll bring it up to whatever
I'm talking about so we won't have that
I'm not gonna put an agenda slide up
because there are wastes of real estate
really I mean you know just because
you're gonna say this stuff later anyway
as a speaker so I'm gonna eliminate that
I absolutely hate bullet points in
presentations it's a lot of words up on
the screen and I don't like them and the
most controversial one of all is that
there's not going to be any memes or
gifts in this presentation I find also
they take up a lot of real estate on the
slides and so they might not be
culturally relevant to everyone so
sometimes you put up a great example
that only you find funny and no one else
does so I'm just mixing those as well
yeah so just that's just the one so
that's that's where we're starting from
all right so we'll start with a nice
these are gonna see a lot of a nice
black hacker canvas to paint upon and
we'll kind of get going here I wanted to
talk first off a little bit I want to
kind of explore kind of my take on
society how it seems to be structured
and at least in a way where I can kind
of you know bring forth some other
concepts later on that hopefully you
guys will find interesting or at least
somewhat entertaining to a certain
degree
and like I mentioned I you know we're a
lot of different hat colors and and
whatnot I've done I've done my share of
bad things if I broke into your company
in my youth I'm sorry probably not that
sorry but you know I am sorry
nonetheless it was there was a different
time back then I guess but in general
society I think of it as kind of a
circle okay think of it as kind of
Circle and there are things that happen
at various points around the circle
sometimes at the edges things happened
most people that are that you encounter
including a lot of you probably spend
most of your time living in the normal
part of society where you're not faced
with the scariness of what's going on
around the edges because sometimes it is
kind of scary around the the edges of
society and there's nothing wrong with
being normal
there's times and multiple times in my
past of where I really wish I was living
a more of a normal life out there on the
edges you do find what we call the
crazies and these are I'm talking about
the people that are there all the time
all right they're right out there on the
edge and is kind of they're kind of now
it doesn't mean they're good or bad I'm
not meaning that kind of judgment you
have people that are like you know maybe
someone likes a Steve Wozniak might be
considered a person that's right out
there on the edge and he's you know did
weird things came up with weird concepts
and whatnot but then you also get like
you know you know Ted Kaczynski and
people like that are also out there on
the edge living all the time and end up
you know killing people and stuff so it
is kind of weird and crazies tend to
look into the middle and see those
normals as complete strangers and they
think of them as the crazies now I mean
obviously with what I'm referring to
with these two different groups is it is
kind of interesting to wander back and
forth between these worlds and to spend
a little bit of time out there on the
edge among the crazies is a lot of live
insight can be gained from that now when
things happen and it is part of that
whole pattern recognition thing when
things happen out there on the edges
they tend to make ripples across all the
society for good or for bad
and seeing some of those things is I've
had a kind of a hobby of mine is making
predictions about how things are gonna
go technologically and I've been ride a
lot of times but it's not that it's not
like I'm you know magic or anything like
that a lot of people have predicted the
same types of things but what it is is
you're just basically looking at some of
these ripples as they come in and kind
of identifying patterns with them and
seeing where things are heading you do
realize when you're wandering around on
those edges though things aren't just I
mean this I've got a nice neat circle
here but that's not how things actually
are out there there's times when things
look really creepy and bad okay and for
someone that's in the middle that
ventures out they're gonna see something
very horrid and for the crazies that
live out there all the time they're
gonna look in the middle and say oh my
gosh it looks so so bland and dull and
boring in the middle and why why aren't
you out here you know living life to the
fullest
etc in a weird way though being a nympho
sac you were having a lot of times to
make forays out into those areas because
you're dealing with technology right and
technology is one of these drivers of
these waves that come in repeatedly and
so that kind of puts a lot of us
probably most everyone in this room I
mean you're out attending
security conferences trying to learn
more and everything like that a lot of
your colleagues don't step out of the
office except to go home you know what
I'm saying I think I think you do anyway
IDEs that's kind of why I put a lot of
us living kind of on the the very edge
of normal kind of halfway in between we
can kind of see a little bit of both
sides it's nice to kind of pull back on
the weekend or something and into the
more of the normal range but you know or
whatever your equivalent of weekend is
I think for me it's usually sleep that's
usually what I do to relax
anyway to kind of give some
illustrations of how some of these
things have kind of played out oh we're
going to cover some items from the past
and some of these are going to be
relevant as far as the those ripples on
that big big pond big ocean or whatever
and basically they give you some
examples of this the first one and this
occurred this back late 90s when it
started the rise of distributed
denial-of-service you anyone remember
when amazon only sold books it was a
bookstore remember that and that a weird
thing and then the denial of service
attacks started happening and you
couldn't buy a book for an hour and that
New York Times went crazy because it's
just like oh my gosh you know the
world's coming to an end you can't buy a
book for an hour but I mean that was the
kind of things that were kind of going
on then there is also this other
denial-of-service thing that would occur
on occasion I know that reddit is the
new big thing now but anyone remember
slash dot more and it's when it was more
in its heyday back then if you had a
let's say you had some blog you wrote
and it's like some techno blog and of
course you had it on a web server that
was like either sitting in your house or
sitting at an ISP where where you
physically drove it and plugged it in
right and this poor little server once
you your meat tech blog went up someone
put it on slash dot and everyone got
excited and started going for it all
sudden your server was what they call
slash dotted where it would crash
because it couldn't handle the load
again a form of denial of service now
there were some CD ends at the time
probably the content distribution
networks Akamai was a
the main one that I remember from back
then and what they did was they said hey
we can turn this into kind of a business
we're going to say hey you tired of
being you know knocked off the net from
being slashed on it or evil hackers with
their botnets and whatnot we're going to
offer this up as here's a place where
you can stick your your web presence and
this is basically continue they offered
no security whatsoever and trust me
there was no security whatsoever it was
so amazing to go in and change a couple
of headlines on on CNN via Akamai
because they left it pretty wide open
but I mean that was the beginning of the
cloud essentially that's what the cloud
is that's the whole model is there
someplace where you put your content and
people come and and grab it another big
one was the the weaponization of cyber
now this is we've all heard about Xero
days and all this stuff and way back in
the day you would find out about these
things through you be popped someone
else would be popped and they'd put
something out on say bug track and you'd
find out about it that way I think it
was the early 2000s when someone decided
they were going to start offering a
brokering service and this was a they
kind of did IDs type stuff this
particular company I don't even know if
they're around anymore
I can't think of the name the names
slips my mind so they're probably not
around anymore but what they did was
they offered money to hackers they said
you give us your zero day we'll buy it
from you pay cash and when you do that
you know we're going to work with the
vendor and get the thing patched and in
the meantime they're going to write a
IDs signature so their product would be
secure from the bug they've just
reported to the vendor
and they thought that was a great model
I thought it was terrible
I wasn't the only one that thought this
I thought this is this is horrid I
remember doing a panel back then and
there was actually some people on the
panel from a us-cert who agreed with me
and had come to the same conclusion she
said this is bad money being thrown into
this realm is going to be a bad thing
and it has turned into a bad thing I
mean we have you know there's whole
wholesale zero-day things going on in
the darknet all the time people are
buying and selling this stuff at one
point the US government they did pay
more than anyone else in an attempt to
kind of corner the market and buy
everything up but still did they say I
have a friend of mine back in Texas
where I'm for where I'm at that I've
known for a number of years he started
up a brokerage firm they were in the
black in six months and he was a
millionaire in a year and he's taken a
cut all right and that's all he's doing
is she's just buying and selling bugs so
uh that's that's really kind of affected
things up until this moment and then of
course the big one was the the death of
the perimeter and maybe 15 or 20 years
ago that wilt
Frank Zappa had this quote he was
interviewed and he has asked about what
he thought about modern jazz and he
didn't have a high opinion of it but
what he said was a modern jazz isn't
dead it just smells funny all right and
so I was saying that about perimeter
security probably you know at least 15
years ago and I've since changed fairly
quickly changed my mind into just saying
it is dead whether we want it to be or
not sure there's a delineation but it is
essentially dead and that's kind of
worth exploring on its own as to what
killed the perimeter because this gets
more into that kind of you know waves
that are coming in first thing that
killed it was laptops I'm gonna guess
everyone in here has a laptop
okay and most of your employees probably
have laptops even if they aren't
corporate provided they probably have a
laptop so they're used to being mobile
so if you have people that are chained
to a desk with a desktop system they're
gonna eventually probably be on a laptop
anyway it's just easier there's smaller
pieces of hardware you know that kind of
thing and and they're gonna they're
gonna beg for it that's that's gonna be
one thing that's really helped kill the
parameter the next one was of course
wireless protocols because I don't we
can pretty much probably all agree that
Wi-Fi was a huge mistake that should
have never happened
okay it is a terrible terrible
technology it is built upon well the
main reason is it's terrible technology
is because the whole premise behind a
lot of the protocols that already exist
on the Internet
require a physical element of security
to them and you can read through some of
the RFC's for some of these things where
it actually says by the way there's a
security issue if if someone is
physically attached to your network well
that happens essentially with Wi-Fi and
so we've got there's entire things where
you've gone through like you know you
shouldn't use free Wi-Fi
you should always if you do you got to
use encrypted this and that and how can
you trust the certificates and entire
presentations have been given time and
time again there's probably at least one
or they're talking about Wi-Fi at some
point at this conference and certainly
at at Derby count as well and I'm not
talking about necessarily just Wi-Fi
Bluetooth also was another another
horrid mistake that is an extremely
complex Bluetooth is basically a
conglomerate of sub protocols to make
this big thing that is overly complex I
don't know if anyone's seen this
standard for it it's like if you printed
it off it'd be like a phone book it's
literally it's the PDFs plural add up to
about 2,000 pages of technical stuff to
cover everything in it okay and so that
was a mistake we should have done that
and then of course the the next one was
a smart phone so there's a terrible
mistake now some companies they did you
know start giving them out to employees
but then they bitched and complain
because they had to carry two of these
things around their home one and the
work one and eventually we pretty
particularly when you had up our
management saying no I'm not gonna carry
two phones so I'm gonna carry one it's
gonna be my my iPhone and nikka's you oh
I'm not going to take that blackberry
it's dumb I don't get it you know and so
that's how that all
came about so essentially really what it
boils down to is what killed the
perimeter was mobility that's really
what did us in because we wanted a
mobile user Bay
well the users wanted it more than we
did
we're obviously reaping the benefits of
it everyone here is probably you know at
some point gotten on their phone to
check email with work or some other
thing or they communicate I've been
communicating via slack you know to
slack using my slack app with work and
stuff like that granted I'm doing it
over the over against my data plan I'm
not using the network here because I
don't I don't really trust it but I'm
sure it's fine for everyone else sorry I
is gonna try to keep a straight face is
that one I just couldn't do it all right
well that's the kind of the past so
we're gonna get into more of the present
things that are going on right now that
are kind of kind of interesting
infrastructure adaptation we're moving
to a cloud okay that's a given I know
I've spoken to a few people here that
just said no we're not going to do that
you know we're gonna we're gonna keep
control you will move to the cloud
eventually there will be services that
you want to use there will be
applications that your user population
will demand that will work that our
cloud-based and
that's where you will end up heading so
that's kind of this you know ties back
to that whole rise of DDoS this is where
we're at now
the cloud is is pretty much everywhere
this next one I really wasn't sure how
to say this so I just went ahead and
went for it okay smart shit I just all
the smartness that were included because
you know you need to be able to ping
your toaster okay that whole idea of
putting an IP address Bluetooth
everything on these various devices that
is a reality as someone I'm going to be
doing a presentation at Derby con on on
Internet of Things stuff and it's and
it's this is a the word shit is
extraordinarily accurate for a lot of
this stuff okay just trust me on that so
that's that's another thing is happening
and the last thing that's really kind of
interesting here is the death of privacy
this is not a popular subject but
essentially we've the privacy is dead
now I know that a number of years ago
Scott Neely I guess the Sun guy said you
know privacy is dead get over it and I
mean I mean that was harsh the way he
said it and particularly within the
context because he was I think he was
actually spitting as he said it he was
pretty hostile about it but that is
essentially kind of true in many ways
and I wanted to talk about because that
was kind of an important one that why
why it's why it's dead the first one is
probably because we've entered into this
social media type thing and we are
probably all doing it to some some
degree okay everyone is probably doing
some degree sure you can say Facebook
Twitter that would count because you're
kind of putting yourself out there in a
certain way
Facebook's a big one though there are
the ones that seem obvious when you talk
about selfie like you know Instagram or
snapchat and these kinds of things and
on LinkedIn LinkedIn is a big one okay
that is actually a big one you're
putting lots of nice juicy information
in there about yourself saying you know
here's where I work here's here's my
skill set when I was at this job I did
this I did that and you can pretty much
build up a pretty good profile there are
attackers this is previous job when I
worked for we only had one customer
which was the US government we were
starting to see then that attackers were
the the ones that were being thwarted by
even there's zero days getting in they
would start becoming friends with every
person they could with the on LinkedIn
with the target individual or someone
that worked at the target organization
only to say oh here's my resume can you
after they became friends and chatted
with them and stuff like that
so oh here's my resume and then you
write back say hey your resume was
corrupted just came up blank something's
wrong oh I'm sorry okay here's the right
one and then they send in a correct
resume you know the whole premise being
hey can you give me your opinion on this
as an attractive person that would know
how this is wonderful you know in saying
all those flattering things in the
meantime the person has been popped and
you know lateral movement etc etc this
is but this really has kind of destroyed
a lot of a lot of privacy as a result
because we're all participating in it
commoditization just everything about
these products it could be is there's
been an ease of use that's been slowly
coming in to all these products it used
to be really hard just to get onto the
internet and it seemed like a major
miracle that you would send packets
across this creepy Network and it would
actually they make their way there you
know it's just like wow I made it all
the way there and on my answer came all
the way back you know and so when
someone would complain and say it's slow
just like you have no idea how hard it
was for it to work in the first place
you should look at the protocols how
they're written it's amazing but
everything has been commoditized now and
there's this ease-of-use element now it
has a bad effect for a lot of us is that
we tend to blame the user a lot of times
for things when they go wrong which is
in my opinion that's not what we should
be doing if really I mean if there's if
the users are having a hard time with
something I blame us okay not
necessarily InfoSec but a you know like
in particular but as technology people
we have failed the user community I mean
if you work at a shoe store you know one
of these major brands that puts out
shoes all the time you hired a an expert
at selling shoes we're then saying oh
you also have to be an expert at
determining what a phishing email looks
like and they could care less about that
kind of thing they're trying to make
sales or trying to make what if they
were an expert in selling shoes they're
an expert in sales they don't care about
it because they will do the minimum I'll
get on passwords in a minute it just
I'll go on a rant about how terrible
we've we've given the things we've given
to users and tell them that it's okay
trust us why the last thing that's
really been killing us is just this
whole everything out there is a service
at some time as we continue cloud
adoption for any number of things
everyone wants to put their data in the
cloud a lot of people don't know how to
secure that data they sit there and
really it's not even the clouds fault I
mean if you put data up on AWS and it
AWS will securely serve it up regardless
of how pathetic your permissions are on
that data so if you didn't secure the
data right AWS will go ahead and hand it
to anyone who asks for securely you know
they'll you make sure that all the all
the encryption is in place and
everything to make sure that
transmission goes right into your
browser but that's that's a part of it
and it just that is eroded privacy
because there are people that are
gathering this data from multiple
sources and and and pulling this
together and that's kind of the real
paranoid me talking but there you have
it so let's talk about the future a
little bit and this will be near-term
we'll get into longer term and it'll get
really weird but right now we'll get
into a near term stuff and I'll kind of
whip through these mainstream journalism
this is the main reason why end users
and the general population really
doesn't get what we do okay they don't
read the trades outside of the trades I
you get into mainstream media and
I swear to god you get a better
explanation of technical issues like
okay I saw this great thing on on the
last week tonight with John Oliver the
explained encryption and explained the
whole thing with you know when the
government wanted into the the attackers
the some terrorist guys iPhone and so
they did a bit on encryption and it was
you know look it up it's like about I
don't know 20 25 minutes long but it is
a beautifully put together thing
intended for a non-technical audience
that completely explains encryption and
it does so very good and it kind of
presents both sides of the the
encryption argument law enforcement sand
and other people's the other one that's
kind of funny is Teen Vogue has changed
their editorial staff slightly and so
when Teen Vogue writes a med tech
article they're getting it right and
that is amazing I follow them on Twitter
now there's a contest in my group at duo
to see which one of us can be quoted or
interviewed by Teen Vogue first okay I'm
not kidding
hey there's you know alcohol in the line
for this contest but but yeah I mean
that's that's the thing this is to give
you a kind of a state of the way things
are that you can trust a you know a
comedy satire show and Teen Vogue to get
it right
and you can't necessarily trust
mainstream media who are saying things
like oh there's you know the the
remember the Samsung this came out about
maybe in the past year it was this the
Samsung TVs you know hackers can spy on
you with their oh yeah because they can
backdoor Samsung TVs alright well
yeah they made a big deal about it and
they said that's what the CIA was doing
here someone I don't know this had to do
with releases from WikiLeaks and and
whatnot but anyway the the point was is
is that yeah a hacker could do that if a
hacker went in and had rewritten
firmware custom firmware for one
particular model of a samsung TV and
they physically break into your house go
to the thing both bolted to the wall and
find the USB thing and go in there and
do a bunch of stuff to it you know
because just setting up a you know a
microphone would be you know so much
more complex than that oh and also this
was it was first discovered in 2013 and
one of my co-workers presented on it at
either black hat or Def Con that year so
this is something it was like it's you
know it was like you know four years old
by the time it made mainstream press and
it's just like ridiculous but that gives
you an idea of just how things are going
another one is politics and I'm going to
lump in cyber insurance into this we all
know how much the auto industry and auto
automobiles in general were influenced
by the advent of the insurance industry
it created whole new facets and wonders
and there's even laws where you have to
have a apparently you have to be insured
to drive and all this other kind of
stuff all these crazy rules that they
have now well I would expect that
between the politics of having
politicians who don't understand our
world to making knee-jerk reactions to
these headlines like we mentioned them
previously that we're going to end up
with particularly with the people that
are doing this cyber insurance stuff
they're gonna start really making a huge
impact on our law our lives this I think
is going to happen sooner than later
it's interesting if you know anyone
that's in the cyber insurance industry
talk with them and you probably will be
like oh that's that's scary this is
already kind of happening I was
imagining kind of a IOT ransomware
phishing is all just going to kind of
merge and I'm not really going to delve
too much into fishing and and ransomware
really because I mean that's kind of
their the hot topics right now they're
kind of you know attack of the month so
to speak there'll be something else that
comes along that'll get another cool
name probably within another year or two
and then that will be the thing I mean
what this will go still be there it'll
still be there for you know just like
you know people misconfigure systems and
whatnot but you know between like you
know mira the mira botnet and and all
that where you can kind of get into grey
area where you say okay a whole bunch of
home routers if you want to call those
IOT then they all got popped and turned
into a botnet that court that code by
the way became open-source there's a
framework so if you find a new iot bug
you can potentially you know weaponize
and botnet command stuff to go do things
and i mean the part where i see where it
actually ends up killing people will be
when someone uses ransomware and takes
over every smart coffee maker in the
country and the entire united states has
ground to a halt because no one can have
coffee you know that'll that's that's
what and people will they will kill each
other when that kind of thing happens
it'll mass chaos cats and dogs living
together IOT
we'll just become I okay there will no
longer be an internet of things because
everything will be on the internet well
you know we call it I mean how many
people got a phone right now
okay you got a phone on you right now
I didn't say smartphone but I said phone
you all knew what I was talking about
few years ago they were smart phones now
they're just phones it just except of
course they're really not phones or
computers that you know show cat videos
and and and and and send stupid text
messages also you can make phone calls
on them which most people don't do
anymore
they use it for all the other stuff so
you've got that going on that's gonna be
kind of interesting how that all plays
out it's just I have a feeling that
based upon you know what's happening
like it is just imagine a day when your
children or your grandchildren depending
on how old you are they will know a
future where the toaster always printed
the weather forecasts on the toast okay
they will always know that they there
will not be a time when that did not
occur that every toaster will be a smart
toaster though they'll just be called
toasters and the old ones that aren't
you know web-enabled or whatever those
will be known as antiques so then our
vintage vintage yeah they're beep yeah
yeah all of a sudden you know like yard
sales and estate sales when when you
know granddad dies and he's got all
these vintage electronic products in his
house is just like that's what people
fight over
Bluetooth I think is going to eventually
kind of I would hope go away and it'll
kind of start to migrate to LTE you see
this already I really didn't think it
was going to be Apple that did this but
it turns out it was or it turns out it
was I thought it's gonna be Fitbit we're
gonna do that I'm going to speed up here
even though we started later so kind of
running a little bit behind I think that
multi-factor authentication is gonna
kill the password password is
practically dead a lot of us use we use
some type of thing like LastPass or or
you know or something like that where
the password is stored for us is
automatically generated as massively
long and complex so in a way we already
don't know our passwords anyway we're
just heading that way as soon as we get
we get improved the whole biometric
thing I'm still curious as to where
they're like face ID how good that's
gonna end up being and I'm real curious
it's like I'm just kind of the morbid
part of me speaking but like if you
could defeat that by you know like say
someone died you can like you know hold
the phone to their dead face if they
died with their eyes open I guess I
don't know just curious but but
nonetheless I mean his biometrics
improve I think this is this is gonna
become a reality because the pass and
that's the thing think about this we
have to factor now because the first
factor our first security element is
insecure why do we have it that doesn't
make any sense
all right now sometimes I do this for
the show of hands I'm not going to do
that because it's always the same but
just I'm going to go over this I'm
hoping that this becomes a thing how
many people can tell me if just think to
yourselves if you have strong
authentication on most of your apps
okay most of the things that you asked
if you've got strong authentication I
saw a few people nodding their head are
all systems you manage patched and up to
date okay the other people are nodding
their heads and then is it just these
patched and managed devices that access
corporate data that's the killer right
they're not I mean you can go and talk
to all the vendors out there and
everything like that about I need to
secure my stuff and everything but these
basics need to be done - these really
need to be done if you can take care of
that that whole thing like was said this
morning in the keynote about covering
ninety percent this covers a huge chunk
right there all right so to kind of get
into the long term future stuff and of
course you're probably saying to
yourself is it going to be smart cars
he's going to talk about smart homes no
it's not gonna be any of that my
template for the future is power tools
okay
this right here is a Milwaukee this is a
m18 drill driver this thing is Bluetooth
enabled okay so you got a Bluetooth
power tool okay why is this a thing I
mean okay you can do some cool things
with it
I don't know if you can see very well
this slide there they got the 1 through
4 on the that's on the base of it you
can store up to 4 profiles on it it
comes with an app also a web interface
to the website all the data stored on
the on their website which is basically
in the cloud there are some really neat
features about this like let's say that
you're a guy that you know you're your
construction company owner and you got
four of these drills and your guys are
out there drilling unstuff two of the
guys are over drilling causing the wood
to crack and so they're having to go
back as contractors and replace that
would miss extra work and going as in
his app set up a custom profile for the
tools push it down to all the tools and
now the tools the torque has been
adjusted okay so now you've got
something kind of cool there is this the
only tool they have that is Wi-Fi
enabled know it's not they've got a few
others they're wanting more they are
extreme I looked at this for work by the
way it's a research project I'll if
you're going to derbycon I'll cover a
lot of this in detail but you can do a
lot of cool things with the tool and it
has features like a like you can say you
can mark it as you take a photo of it
and store it with the tool in the cloud
so you know what the tool looks like you
can take a picture of where it's
supposed to go take a picture of the
receipt tag that to the tool upload it
it has and you can do this with all your
tools if you're a contractor you could
have your whole inventory of tools they
even sell this little thing they call it
a tick and you can put this thing on
other tools so you can track other tools
that have magically allowed to alter
features but it allows you to track from
an inventory part of it you can mark
things in inventory like who's checked
out the tool if it's been lost if it
needs to be repaired if it's been stolen
and you can actually it does GPS
detection so someone else is running the
same app and you know the thief drives
by with the tool it'll pick it up
so that way so that you know you'll know
that's the thing is like in a contractor
could go to another job site find
someone that has one of his tools that
you know left his job site and went
there that kind of thing the tool
community is going nuts over this
because it's completely changing I dare
use the word disruptive but I mean
that's you know buzzword you probably
haven't heard today but that's but
that's it here's one other disruptive
thing that's kind of interesting you'll
look at that and you'll see that I don't
if you can really see it on the
especially toward the back this is from
my phone using a app called light blue
does Bluetooth scanning and I'm up there
in the very top left-hand corner it's in
airplane mode because I was on a flight
when I did this and I'm scanning and you
look at there the very top thing as
Kali's hearing aids Bluetooth enabled
hearing aids all right think about that
for a second
by the way I was able to connect up to
Callie's hearing aids and get a bunch of
information off of them it might have
been fun to you know Callie this is God
gives the rotund man with the gravy rat
all your money yeah you could have had
some fun with that one but I mean this
is kind of interesting because later
Callie got out her iPad
I'm assuming it was hers it said
Callie's iPad and she starts watching a
movie okay because they functioned his
headphones as well and you started
thinking of as I said hey wait a minute
I mean I could be anywhere and like take
a phone call and I can hear it you know
just you know you also do you're saying
hey this isn't just for hearing-impaired
people I want to have better than normal
hearing I could do that something with
this this might be kind of interesting
or make them noise
insulation Oh they'd be really good all
right couple of real quick concepts and
then we'll wrap this up for you Preppers
and paranoids out there the the gray man
the gray man concept you may be familiar
with basically hide in plain sight you
look like George Costanza from Seinfeld
you look like everybody therefore you
are not noticed at all okay I it's kind
of an interesting concept and I put gray
man I mean it could be a gray woman okay
but it just if you're gonna google it
you need to go cray man otherwise you're
not gonna find anything on it that's not
my fault I'm sorry but nonetheless I
mean there's a few of people I work with
that we kind of play with this concept
because for one thing using some of
these grey man concepts really get you
through TSA security very quickly you
know because they're looking for odd
Ceph and I'll tell you this right now if
as a computer security guy who
occasionally carries a weird electronic
shit in his bag that I'm worried that
the TSA is gonna question if I'm dressed
very plainly very normally and I act
like a normal human being and I go
through with that type of gear versus
the guy that's got the the laptop
covered in stickers you know you know II
FF you know screw the man and it's
wearing an antisocial t-shirt and a
utility
okay and he's carrying the same stuff
they're gonna stop him and make him go
check his bag and not me okay so I mean
that's kind of you know kind of the way
to I kind of use this whole concept that
it's also a fun thing I was able to get
through a lot of a black hat and DEF CON
avoiding people I didn't want to have to
talk to for various reasons because I
made sure I blended right the hell in
so that brings up the concept which I
think will become a thing the digital
gray man okay and you're in all these
databases privacy is dead and all that
and everything what would it take to
make sure that the data is that's
included in all these databases makes
you look like a completely and totally
average person okay that's the idea
behind a you know a digital gray man
hiding that way hiding within all the
data you you want to use this stuff you
have to for work in many cases what can
you do to kind of deal with that this is
kind of my idea I'm just I'm hoping to
get more into this I need to talk with
people that are involved with big data
and discuss how one would go about that
it bothers me that someone says oh
because you're right-handed and you're
the age you are and you have a car
that's blue you have a 65% chance of
owning a cat you know that that kind of
data gathering is just kind of creepy
for me that that's Isis few couple
people shaking their heads I I kind of
exaggerated slightly but not that much
there are people that gather marketing
data like that that are able to pull
this in for weird information out so
that when you go on Facebook and you
post something about you know whatever
they're able to read your likes and
dislikes and bam you get served up ads
that are specifically targeted for the
way you are and the way you think what
can I do to change that that's the
digital gray man concept
all right this is last one human-machine
hybrids
we already saw a little bit of this with
Kali our frequent flier cyborgs where is
this stuff going to come from I think
it's probably gonna be come from the the
military that'd be my guess
so we're gonna start to see and Japan I
mean let's face it Japan's gonna be the
first ones to clone people right am i
right okay they're gonna do it all right
and I mean and I'm all in favor I know
it may be controversial or whatever I'm
all in favor of growing a headless clone
of me that has a little for starters
it's gonna have at least two livers in
it so as I say drink one out and just
slap in another one you know but I could
have it genetically engineered so that
you know my pancreas because I'm
diabetic
shocker that I'm diabetic but you know I
could have a new pancreas put in place
you know I could have any number of
parts or plays I improve my eyes for one
thing that'd be another thing to do but
we're already we're already kind of
started down this path ourselves
everyone how many people put their cell
phone
oops I use the word cell phone I meant
phone I'm sorry how many people put your
phone in your pocket and it's the same
pocket all the time and there we go okay
and so what happens is when that phone
buzzes you know you know you know
exactly what it is and you can possibly
tell the difference between the alerts
from the but from the buzzing what it is
is that a text messages is an email that
kind of thing I got a UH the I got the
Apple watch on I can identify four
different types of alerts based on the
haptic feedback sensor this in this you
know because like I can't be troubled by
reaching all the way into my pocket you
know I I can get it all right here I'm
looking for there's haptic feedback
shirts and I'm looking for some that are
hackable because I think it would be
interesting to have like you know
someone came along and compromised the
system the
it was a slide up the back you know my
shirt or you know tap here on the
shoulder for a tax here for an email but
slide up the back in case your system
you're monitoring is compromised but I
mean this is I think the direction we're
heading I mean you have I think it's the
military I it's not gonna be like in
Call of Duty if an enemy drops a gun you
can go and pick it up it'll be a smart
gun it'll be biometrically linked to you
you'll be the only one to be able to
take it out of his charging station in
the carrier because it's you know
biologically linked to you by then we'll
have the implants in the eyes for the
heads-up display you've already got
Callie's hearing aids let's put in a job
on microphone which are things that do
exist make it look like something that's
like jewelry that way you could be on a
noisy battlefield and still get a
cellphone I did it again still get a
phone call or zoo get communication more
importantly from headquarters giving you
Direction out there on the battlefield
that kind of thing
my hope is that eventually because we
have an office down in Austin and I live
up in the Dallas area my hope is that I
can get in a car that drives itself I
can say wake me up at the Starbucks you
know in three hours about you know three
minutes from the office so I can get
some coffee and then just hop in the
backseat of my self-driving car and have
it drive me all the way there and you
know and then maybe my you know because
I've got stuff inside me monitoring me I
get an alert for my doctor oh by the way
you've got some type of thing going on
I'm going to give you a medication
there's a CVS at the next exit we're
gonna have you exit here and you can go
in and pick up your prescription it's
covered by your insurance and it's
already been paid for and every cetera
that's kind of the future that's kind of
the way we're having we're heading I can
tell from the people sticking their
heads in that we are over I know we
started late I actually believe it or
not roughly ended in 50 minutes but we
may have time for just a one or two
quick questions please put them in the
form of an answer
to save time if you got any questions if
you want to come up and ask me afterward
I'll be around and out in the hall and
all that anyway thank you very much
appreciate
you