um as we're already running a bit late
i'm going to try to keep it short but
now we want to go on
talking about some fuzzing as
dan already
touched on and he i think already uh
brought up some of the very interesting
issues that also came up for our work
and also the
problems that we are tackling because of
those um observations for example what
he was talking about is that we kind of
need systems to be uh easily fast
testable for in order for us to be able
to test them and the other thing that he
said is that there are different kinds
of input types that we have we're gonna
talk about i'm pretty different ones
that you might be interested or then you
might be expecting or
then you might know yourself uh in here
and which are very interesting from from
my point of view which i have
put some research into so this talk is
called password automating and scaling
fuzzing for firmware
and
this talk in a nutshell is going to be
something like this and so we want to
take in some firmware from
binaries that
come for
iot
platforms or little small embedded
systems which are just a bit smaller
than what you would expect and have a
bit of a different format than what you
would normally be used to and then we
put this kind of trimmer into
the clouds and there is a lot of things
going on um but we will get into this
later and then we want to get bugs out
of it and this talk is about um how how
can we achieve this and shed some light
on this so first of all who are we uh we
in quotation marks here for the moment
as i get into my name is toby i'm a phd
student at roy university beaufort i'm
also a ctf player ponton participant
before and i'm interested in binary
exploitation and reverse engineering in
my
research i'm focusing on firmware here
normally margot also wanted to
join us here but he sadly cannot due to
covet reasons but he's recovering
quickly and he's also sending his
students
all right first of all let's understand
a bit about systems that we are going to
talk about today um embedded systems so
what do we understand by embedded
systems a lot of you might think about
something like a router
that they have at home anything that's
kind of close to what they're using and
those systems what they do is
they run linux a lot and sometimes so
most of the time it's a bit of a boil
down linux in the form of a busy box or
so but then we figure out um this type
of embedded system is not the only one
and
there are a lot of other systems out
there with very different properties
as we can see here we have different
types of embedded systems
some plcs here which you would find in a
factory deployment or an ecu which you
would find in a car then finally on the
further right you find some home
automation appliances which get smaller
and smaller uh what all these devices
have in common that they usually do not
run any limits so they are very hard to
kind of
grab your hand on but we still want to
have some
security analysis of these as well
and we'll get into why this is a bit
tricky to do and how different ways that
we could go about doing that and
analyzing them so first of all in order
to do this we want to understand how do
these systems actually talk
to the hardware around it because if we
do not have a linux system
kind of the hardware still has to be
talking to be spoken to by the firmware
and we cannot just have a linux syscall
and then have a read or something that
we can get our inputs we do not have a
file system things like that what do we
do in this scenario and as it turns out
we have three main ways of communication
between the firmware image and then
the hardware that's surrounding it and
one of these is called memory mapped
input and outputs or mmio for short and
what this is basically doing it's the
magic memory region which doesn't really
represent any ram as you would
see it in a normal
computer if you have just ram memory you
write something in you read it out and
you get back whatever you got but
instead what is behind this is an actual
device and it's talking to you and
depending on whether you do a read on
this magic memory region or you do a
write you can either find something out
about the state or read some data out of
this peripheral or
you can put some configuration and this
very much depends on how this mio is
laid out but we'll talk about this in a
bit the second
mechanism which we have at our disposal
for talking between firmware and
hardware is interrupts and this is
basically a doorbell sign where the
hardware can tell the firmware okay
buddy i have something going on please
check on me and what's happening in the
firmware then is often that you have
something that's called a an interrupt
handler and the input handler will check
on the device using mmi oh and see okay
what's going on do i have a new network
packet coming and nothing segment
and then we have the third kind of
mechanism which is called direct memory
access or dma for short and here we have
some communication mechanism for high
throughput scenarios where we have
something like an ethernet card which
has to run very rapidly or um usb or
things like that and in these cases what
the firmware and the hardware do is
basically
they unify on a
memory region which they want to talk
through and then they can both
simultaneously read and write to this
memory region and then of course for
example if the
if a device wanted to send something
like an ethernet frame and make it
available to the firmware it could just
write something into an ethernet frame
buffer and then give a an interrupt and
then the camera knows okay now i can
access this directly without having to
use mio to like
phenically read out every bias one after
the other
and this is what
a reading input would look like for us
from a normal like buzzing perspective
for example we have a get char so we
want to read a single byte
of user input and this is pretty
straightforward in linux what we can do
is just have a resource call
pass in standards
in as the file descriptor 0 and then
just get our value back and return it
from the function however if we look at
the same thing now for
the serial interface of an embedded
controller for example this would look
much more complex in this case and we
can see that we have already
talked about some mio and here we can
see that three different mmi oh
registers are actually involved in
reading this and so it's much more
involved to do and we have some talking
to the hardware to do in here as well
and we'll go into what exactly this is
doing
in a bit
but let's skip this for now
so with these kind of um
basic things out of the way then we want
to go to rehosting and first of all um
we want to define what rios thing is so
i just read it out here it's the
automatic creation of virtual execution
environments for embedded firmware so
what we
basically want to do we want to take
some piece of firmware out of the device
and run it somewhere on the general
purpose system for example an emulator
something like that and
and there are many reasons for this uh
for why we would want to do this and we
could go into all of these details and
we actually wrote the paper about it
remember i'm dabbling in some academia
but we do not want to do it here instead
we want to
take it down to something a bit more
streamlined and maybe easy to understand
and also the main reason quite frankly
why we want to do this so on the one
hand we have those smart things
so-called smart things such as a
lightning bulb or
a temperature sensor and these things we
do not really get an ssh shell onto
there we cannot deploy afl and then just
run some some binary on there we have to
have a
bare metal
system which just doesn't allow us
anything uh in the traditional means and
um they are very slow as well so i just
got told uh outside here that somebody
actually tried to pass test the router
for example and that the chip was
actually like brown afterwards so that's
very cool to hear so maybe we also
don't want to like blow these things up
in the first place and if we turn to
something more powerful like like cloud
computation then we can just deploy it
on a massive scale and whenever we get
it into an emulator and actually are
able to do this then um
we can get buzzing to
um
to a very potent level here
all right so with these things you might
say okay toby you already set it we have
an emulator we have the cloud uh we can
just combine this right so we just take
the emulator that we already have it's
very good
it's scalable and it's a community
project which is developed and very
mature why can't we just plug the
firmware into qa move and then just do
some fuzzing on this put some cloud
service behind it and the box will
follow eventually right
but there sadly is a bit of a challenge
with this and this challenge is
mainly uh
consisting of the complexity of hardware
devices that we have faced and so if we
think about the different vendors that
would
prevent or
offer some device like this uh every one
of those vendors will
have different devices that they offer
and then for every device we have
different peripherals it wants to have
timers it wants to have a serial
interface it wants to talk via wi-fi and
things like that so we have all these
different peripherals and then
afterwards each peripheral also has
different memory registers and this kind
of multiplies up and if we kind of see
what this entails in the documentation
which we sometimes have available not
always then we can see it the details
are not really important here but we can
see that there are device regions and
each device region has a peripheral
region and each and then which we do not
even see here it's different on my o
register so kind of explodes and
some of these devices are fully
implemented if we look at some system
for example a very well established one
like in raspberry pi we have a full
implementation of all these registers
but it's a huge amount of work and so if
we think about that we have all these
small little devices which do not uh
really are not really covered by this
then we might not even find an
implementation in something like um and
um then what makes it kind of worse is
that a lot of cases we do not even have
documentation so even if we wanted to
comb through like a thousand page
document which describes all these
things then we couldn't do it even if we
wanted if we don't have documentation in
the first place so this kind of begs the
question we have so many devices and we
want to secure the firmware that is
running on them and it's very hard to
analyze them so how can we automate
emulating these systems uh in the end
and as it turns out different people
have looked at this problem before and
how can we kind of model this hardware
for systems that are not quite linux
like systems and we cannot use any
abstractions um that we are used to and
cannot really apply the tools that we
are used to as well and which have also
proven very reliable sources of
of finding
and so one of the first things that i
would like to mention here is uh what's
is called pretender so what they
basically try is to take a piece of
hardware run it and take some traces
from it and then try to understand based
on the trace that we have seen and that
we know are valid can we figure out how
the hardware behavior works and then
people took it a bit further with ps4m
and part emu where you take it in a
fully like virtual domain you do not use
any hardware anymore but you uh see what
the excess patterns are in something
like ua moon but cream without actual
devices and then you kind of monitor
what communication is going on and then
you may be able to derive from these
excess patterns what the behavior should
be and then people
even further
where we use some
program analysis techniques um like
symbolic execution and to do this kind
of modeling for us so whenever we have
an excess can we figure it out by
analyzing this success and then seeing
okay does the code tell us something
about what we suppose to do
and then of course we're in 2022 and we
have password and this is kind of the
prototype that we want to talk about and
the work that i've been performing
um all right
so further rehosting via the fuzz
envelope so let's recap for a bit uh
what have these previous works done uh
on a kind of
um
broader level so these uh
these prototypes have looked at this
problem in a two-step way so first of
all what we want to do is we take a
piece of firmware and then we re-host it
so that we can run it in an emulator
then afterwards we can put a fuzzer to
it and have the father do the security
auditing for us and um our
the question kind of that's begging here
is can we also integrate the father from
the star can we not treat it as a
two-way process but i have the father in
the
in the loop um directly
so the idea behind this would be that
modern fuzzers are already very good at
kind of identifying what is useful for
programs so we can take something like
coverage feedback and whenever we find
coverage feedback within a
program then something is likely or an
input is likely to be useful for it and
the idea here is can we have used this
for modeling as well can we just have
the fuzzer do the heavy work for us and
and do this but this again if we think
about this a bit more it has some issues
concerned with it and the first thing is
that
while not fully random puzzles
still rely on a lot of uh like rolling a
dice basically if you look at the source
code of afl or
plus it's not quite 100 random but um
the mutations
try to modify it in a lot of ways and
what comes out is
more or less a random behavior and then
um
this makes it very hard if you have a
lot of choices to kind of find the right
thing in the first place and firmware
makes it a bit harder still because as
we will see there is a lot of low level
like firmware and hardware chatter going
on which kind of explodes the state
space a lot which is kind of needlessly
so and i will see what this means here
so let's look at code example and what
you can see on the left side it's a
function called perform and then on the
right side we have the control flow
graph or cfg
that represents the different path
through it so what we can see is that we
have an mio operation
register which is curate so the firmware
will look okay what kind of operation
does the hardware want to do or what
state is it in how should i behave based
on that and
depending on what operation comes in we
can step through this and see okay if we
do the d4 case it would do some
housekeeping within uh with some
coverage here assigned to it then we
come to the b case and there is some
special handling to it depending on the
status of its special then there's some
special handling and otherwise we have
the default one so we can step through
this as well
so
as we said the idea is to kind of
involve the puzzler in here so what do
we do if or how does this look like in
case the fuzzer is choosing some values
for us and as i said there is some
randomness in here so we can kind of say
okay we just pick some values it's not
quite random in the normal case but we
just pick some random values here and
then we can see okay what kind of fixed
degree it gets and we can highlight them
here and then plot them in this coverage
here and
the greener or the more dark green
coverage i know it is the more it was
visited and as we can see we have some
parts of this coverage not even
occurring at all and this might be
problematic in case we have a bug hiding
in some special case for example we do
not get any coverage out of here
so this kind of asks the question or
brings up this
idea of the paradox of choice so on the
one hand we want to give the fuzzer all
the flexibility in the world we do not
take away any parts because especially
the
specific or special paths could contain
bugs as well but at the same time if we
give it too big of a search space then
we cannot really do anything and the
question or the puzzle will not be able
to find them and the question here is
can we reduce these available choices a
bit and this is where a little toby on
the start of the academic work started
going on the internet looking for some
some quotes for inspiration and the
first one that he found was look for
chances to take the less covered pass
and we had a second from the same author
uh
we do not still or yet know who it was
it was you will regret the paths you
didn't cover
and then at the end also a keep it
simple stupid and as it turns out was
already called our lord and savior by
then before in the keynotes because of
course afl the little fuzzing uh
american fuzzy love and this kind of got
me thinking so you have keep it simple
stupid so
can't we kind of make this live of the
further easier just make it simpler and
this is where kind of the idea stems
from and we can look at what this
entails and looking at this code again
um so if we look at this code as we went
through it was
a case a case b and d4 k's kind of
scenario so what the fuzzer should kind
of be
aware of is that there are three choices
we do not really have a big search space
we have just three choices based on our
mmio and what if we change this
representation for uh the little bunny a
bit here and then we just spray out the
ones which do not matter so we just have
a b and c and b is the representative
for the default case here and if we i
just let the puzzle choose between one
of these three
options now what we can do is go through
the same scenarios again and then we get
a and b here and then we get two or a
and default and then we get to the b
case and what is interesting is that we
have the same kind of situation here as
well we can kind of nest this idea so
here we have an
another if else statement depending on
whether we want to status the special
case or not the special case and this is
again just a
choice between special and not special
so what do we give the father if we
could find a some modeling approach
which just gave us one of these two
choices we could just have the father
choose the one or the other and the
interesting thing is that now it's much
easier for the fuzzer to find all these
different um coverage parts and this
allows us
to find bugs mainly
all right this brings us to the modeling
component of
fuzzwear and the different models and
this it turns out we have already seen
one so this is what we call the set
model it's um
it just gives the fuzzer
precomputes the set of choices and then
the father can just choose between them
uh based on some fighter filing input
for example and uh let's complete this
picture of it so we have some more
models in here um
so let's look at this serial getc
function again and so i go through these
different lines a bit more detail so
here what we can see is that first of
all the firmware has to make sure that
the hardware actually has some data
available so it stays in a busy loop
until this data is available and it will
actually get stuck in this busy loop
until the data is available and
in case we want to do fuzzing it's clear
we do not want to get stuck in any loops
we just want to go on so what we do here
is apply what we call a constant model
and just have the excess return it has
data if we can show by some analysis
that this is just
being stuck in the loop without anything
happening then we can safely just assign
the constant value and not have to
involve the puzzle so this in this case
we make it really simple for the puzzle
because it doesn't have to do anything
in this case and the interesting thing
here is that
we have an a four byte access before so
the father would have given us 4 bytes
but now we have just 0 because we can
handle it by ourselves
and this kind of applies to
the seconds
here as well what we have here is that
we have a gpio value which represents
something like an led lighting up and
indicating uh some activity on this huge
interface for example and
this is what we
what we can see here is that
this hardware value is first read then
modified and written back and everything
kind of stays in the hardware domain so
we do not really care about this because
the firmware doesn't take anything into
account in its logic if we can show this
again we can just uh
keep this as a normal memory access here
we call this ambassador model so
whenever the humor writes something and
reads it back it gets the same value and
the puzzle still doesn't have to be
involved in here
and then finally we have this data
access we see we have a four by eight
excess first but then we are masking off
only one byte so we only have to um have
the father give us one instead of four
kind of if we summarize this we can
reduce the input
space by uh quite a bit because the
buzzer before it had to deal with all
these different things and without
changing the program logic we can just
reduce it by over 90
and um kind of what we had have now is
we have a function which takes one byte
of input and just takes one byte of
fuzzing input as well so it's very
familiar to the fuzzer now as it would
look like in a linux system for example
all right if we put this together in a
little diagram here we have the
um the full system overview so in the
middle if you're not familiar
with it it's
the emulator called unicorn engine and
what it gives you is um basically
instruction execution without any
hardware components around it so it's a
stripped version of qa and at its core
and what it's doing is just
executing the swimmer image and then
whenever there is any hardware excesses
it just forwards it to the puzzle again
and then if we see any hardware access
which we have not seen before what we
can do is have
symbolic execution in this case our
modeling components perform some
analysis and see whether we can fit one
of these models which we have seen
before
and
this kind of gets
fed back into the emulator while it's
running and then it can afterwards
handle
some of the excesses transparently or
boil them down and it's kind of a loop
going on as soon as long as we have more
mio registers or kind of hardware
interfacing that has not been previously
discovered
and what we
did is that we wrote in kind of complex
prototype for this
it's about 10 000 lines of source code
and it's also available
so with this of course let's get further
and
what is important for fuzzing is
obviously and as an academic especially
to have very novel ideas about how to go
about fuzzing so having to set up
something and then fuzzing something and
how towards preaching precious is
something that nobody would ever have
come up before with before so
we in the academia are all about giving
some novel ideas to everybody right so
uh that's uh what we did here no of
course uh what we at least do is that we
supply some um
utilities for what we already know is
required to do this housing workflow and
without like going into these
right now in just theory let's look at
some examples here
and i have a little demo
prepared so what does it look like to
use fastback so first of all we want to
do a work on password so we are actually
in the virtual environment to use it and
then we want to configure
um setup configuration for the binary
file using power gen config and then we
can see we have some configuration files
created and i can now use the pipeline
component to do some fuzzing
so after some setup what we can see that
as we would expect we have some um some
coverage coming in some translation
blocks or basic blocks being discovered
and what we can see afterwards is that
we also have some models being created
and so this is the the modeling
component feeding back some
configuration snippets to
the emulator which is then consumed by
the emulator to set it up for for a more
efficient um workflow
and then if we wait for a little bit
more
we find some more coverage afterwards
this would be expected and this is where
we can also stop the puzzle for the
um purpose of this demonstration then we
can see we have a password project
directory which contains all these
results from
and here we can query the red curve
so that we can see
what kind of functions have we already
covered and we can also replay an input
based on coverage here
and get the behavior of it
second thing that we can kind of look at
is a is the the models that were created
themselves and you can see in the mio
config.yml we have different ones of
these uh models are constant
pass-through there's a set model in
there as well
and so on so and then of course if we
have run this for a bit longer time and
not only 30 seconds we can go into a
project which has run for a little bit
longer time and went through some
configuration updates and then we found
some crashes for example then we can
also replay and analyze these pressures
afterwards and look at what the behavior
is and then we can see here
that we have the refresh state and then
can see what the reason for it was in
this case we can see it's a bit of a
messed up pc so and this is a stack
based buffer flow in this example but
we're not going to go into this exactly
okay this is that for the demo
and um
let's go and look for some bugs that we
found with it
so first of all it's important what kind
of system did we choose in the first
place and
as it turns out what we found
interesting is kind of the
systems which other firmware uses
afterwards to build upon and then have
some embedded operating systems which
come with a network stack um which then
allow small power devices to be
connected and these are
implementations
of such operating systems which are
connectivity driven so sapphire rts and
then contiki ng on the other end and it
comes with a lot of
connectivity features something like
bluetooth energy wi-fi 6 lowpan
different companies are behind this
because they are interested in having a
joint core of a high quality software of
course and they also have a security
development life cycle and the team was
is also very cool to work with so great
projects uh both of them and we found
some bugs in here and we want to
actually look at those and
as we kind of go into all these bugs in
detail we want to frame them in the
terms of famous last words or what the
firmware assumption could have been just
before this kind of issue record so the
very first one let's start with this it
says these two objects will never be the
same which kind of resulted in one of
the bugs which we have then we have a
second one we know something about
something like a data structure or so in
the program and we can just do that
right we can optimize our algorithm to
do just that work on these assumptions
and make everything run
very fast for example this also
resulted in some bugs and then we have
somebody else we surely have initialized
this so we'll surely initialize this
and if especially across api boundaries
if you find something like this it it's
very very much lends itself to box and
then does anybody have an idea of what
kind of category could be there as well
it has to do with something that i think
a lot of people have seen before
this length can never be smaller than
it was there was actually something that
accorded a lot and then there is the
king's category of course this length
can never be larger than so anything
with missing bounce checks and one of
these um
bugs that i uh that we encountered i
would like to spotlight a little bit
here and this uh accordion the six
lowpan fragment reassembly and uh for
some context six lowpan is kind of the
the way that um smart
and constrained devices can
use to talk ipv6 to each other so what
they can do send they can send small
frames over the over the air but they
are pretty small so what you have to do
is to plug different fragments together
so you can have a full ipv6 packet and
so what the standard says is that you
have kind of a track one uh fragment and
then fragment n fragments so one is the
first and then the follow-up frames and
as everything goes over the air you
cannot really rely on something to come
in in a specific order so what you have
to do is just um you take everything in
and then have to reorder it afterwards
and so then
it's kind of a good thought to have we
already have a pre-sorted list right we
have a freight one so it's always at the
beginning so what we're doing is not
really sorting a list but we are
starting a list with the first element
already in fixed place and we can just
assume that the first element just
doesn't change and it turns out if you
generate an algorithm for this and do
the sorting what comes out at the end
is an infinite data structure it's a
ring instead of something that's finite
and now you have an assumption about
something being finite data structure
and you start working on this this is
where things get a bit weird here um
because you what you have to do in six
lowpan
in order to put together the fragment
data is that you have to strip the
fragment headers from all of these
different fragments and you opt to do it
once but you can do it once by just
going through this finite list of course
and if it's a ring afterwards it's no
longer finite so you turn it into an
infinite header removal packets get
smaller and smaller over time the
integer of the size just gets negative
you have a really big mem copy and then
the firmware is not really happy about
what comes afterwards
and
the actual crash
triaging here was a very interesting
process i find this quite interesting
because i am sure i have looked at this
kind of functionality before and just to
understand kind of what is going on in
the
network layer and
i'm sure i've missed this kind of bug
here and
the the triaging process was pretty uh
involved and i tried to
try running this with marius and telling
him about it but it
was kind of resulting in
this scenario and he
said okay maybe we should not go into
all these details so i'm scaring you
these details here
but instead we want to get to some
closing thoughts and first of all of
course what are the boundaries of what
we can do or what we want to do here as
well and so first of all it's a research
prototype we have implemented for arm
products and we are working on extending
it but for the moment it's uh working on
a very popular platform but obviously it
doesn't cover all of them
and then there are also special cases in
perma which we are just not this
this way of
looking at this mio modeling does not
really cover because vma is just a
different beast it's an interesting
problem but something that we do not
really cover here and also if we have
some very specific assumptions about
timings um
then things can get messed up as well
for example the um
the emulator tries to make things go as
quickly as possible of course but then
at some points for example if you wait
for some initialization or you are sure
some device takes for a bit longer time
we may not always scale the timing in a
correct manner so that things can come
too early logically or maybe even too
late
so if we have situations like this
some modifications are required and then
of course there's a bit of common sense
in here so in case you have a linux
system
and you can use what tools you have
already available just use the tools you
have already available so and that
should work
and and then finally one thing i would
like a vision of mine that i would like
you to take home it has to do a little
bit uh has to do something with the bug
with the duck and uh here it goes if we
want to convince firmer to walk like
possible software and then also quite
like possible software then we might
someday be able to actually give the
tools to the
embedded firmware development guys to
to do the fuzzing themselves and find
all these bugs so we don't have to do it
for them because currently we do not
really supply them with the tools to be
able to do it but if we can do this we
can find a lot of bugs in the process
and with this thought i would like to
thank you for the attention and
questions
yep
test
so if i understand correctly you drop in
the firmware that you have no
pre-assumptions about
and then it will automatically find out
what hardware mmi oh it does but how do
you deal with stuff that actually
changes like for example if we take a
game boy for example and we have like
bank switching so you're right to an
address and that changes ram completely
or as a more recent example we set up
page tables which does virtual memory
how do you detect these kind of things
um so currently um this prototype
doesn't do
these things on the architecture level
which are kind of
baked into the core of the architecture
so what we for example implement is the
the interrupt controller so
for
enabling and setting
priorities for interrupts we still give
this
architecture level completes
architectural components and this
functionality and have this
done by the emulator itself so what we
can do then is that we can if we know
the
architecture on a very broad scale then
we can create an emulator which
has these core components in it
something which
the architecture cannot do without and
would have these represented by that and
then the modeling of the mmio afterwards
would be something done by other models
so you could adjust some of these things
by hand for the emulator
you would create
this these core components once for
example for the
interrupt controlling and so on and then
do this to fast test any
component which is
working on on this kind of base
architecture yes okay thank you
and
regarding
the
differences uh
between piece of hardware and interfaces
uh i saw uh that you have kind of
profiles uh
based
yeah that will uh use profiles where you
can take from the orientation
their addresses uh and
in this way right
yeah what you do to set the the base
emulation up is that you supply some
base memory ranges in that case that you
um kind of tell it okay where can you
expect hardware accessories to be and
then where can you expect some ram to be
and where's the code loaded this is kind
of the base assumption that you need to
know where are things based quite
roughly not
um you do not need to know where some my
origins are or any ranges like this um
but you have to know the broad memory
range where things could occur and then
i listen for these successes
okay you know um i i was asking uh uh
more specifically if
you're uh providing uh
addresses for specific
uh interfaces
uh yeah okay okay thank you
we can also talk about this afterwards
if i have not understood your question
correctly that's very fine i'm sure it's
a good one so
hey thanks for your talk group never uh
disappoints um
maybe i didn't get that right but
how do you
create the constraints for your model is
this manual work or is this being
computed with like i didn't i didn't um
explain the one symbol on the right
which is was the symbol for anger and it
was maybe it was implicit from my side
but it's it's do not make symbolic
execution okay i think kind of in the in
the context of we taking a snapshot of
what's going on in the emulator and then
just look at this very specific
excess and just have to step a couple of
times to not kind of run through
completely automated yeah this is yeah
which we also saw with the in the demo
where the these models caught up it was
also an automated process
would uh modeling not be uh useful by uh
non-firmware software
yeah i think this is also a very good
question i haven't always said that but
these questions were really good um and
valid
this one is actually something which we
could also
apply in non-firmware
environments the the bit different or
the kind of difference here is that for
mio access what we have is an excess
which is very local and very short-lived
so we have one mmo access to a register
we use it this operation for example and
then discard the value afterwards so
what we can do is we can do the analysis
in a very confined space so we don't
just have to look at this one function
or some basic blocks of this this
function to see what it does
what we could also do for um software in
the non-perma space is that we
have this type of model as well and then
fix some values in place for example or
have some
some kind of grammar description maybe
coming out of this modeling that we say
okay this this field can either be that
or the other one and then we have the
fuzzer just give us some input and then
we look at these fields and then based
on what the puzzle gives us we insert
the right choice and kind of do the same
modeling maybe in place of where the
input starts being fed in or maybe in
the place of
the fuzzing process itself where we
inject some code or like uh
some listeners or things like that i
could see that yeah it just has a bit
more um
it's not that natural to to do it in
that case because it just has a more it
has a broader frame you have to trace
the data for a longer time but in
general this is yeah so it's a good idea
right i think there are no further
questions if you have any questions we
can talk outside as well so thank you
again and have a good break