all right thank you so much for that
very kind introduction
um again we will be
doing the final keynote for b-sides
vancouver
12 monkeys curtains for security theater
a little bit about me i spend a lot of
my day dealing with clients in a variety
of different industries and essentially
what i end up doing is being responsible
for translating the needs
of the security team
to their executive and decision-making
team who have the buying power and the
decision-making capabilities for the
organization
i focus on not only blue team compliance
assessments risk assessments and risk
analysis
identification of vulnerabilities in
people processes and systems but i also
get to simulate attacks against those
systems and do some red team type
theatrics
phishing and voice fishing over the
phone smishing or text message fishing
all the silly fishing names
i do those as well
and i participate in collaborative
engagements that include things like
tabletop
assessments for clients who want to test
their response capabilities
um with a simulated attack um
so
moving on
enough about me i would like to thank
this besides vancouver team for inviting
me to speak to you today for giving me
the honor of rounding out the keynotes
with a closing keynote for the event and
just recognize all the hard work that
these individuals put in to
organizing putting together managing
hosting and enabling this event to
happen
facilitating an event like this is not
an easy feat so thank you again for the
invitation to speak for all the hard
work that you put into this and all the
other individuals who contributed behind
the scenes to make this event possible
our agenda today in curtains for
security theater
is pretty simple but we'll get into more
of the detail here as we go we're going
to talk about an introduction the
process culture people and then close
with some final thoughts i'd like to
remind everyone that this is by no means
enough time for us to go into enough
detail i really wanted this talk to
focus on
sparking a new interest in the audience
and people who review this talk to
look further into how they can resolve
some of the struggles that we have
related to what i like to call security
theater and we'll get into what that is
here in just a second so introduction
the purpose of security why does
security exist ultimately security
exists to protect people to protect
information to protect people and
information and a great illustration of
that is the campaign that was brought
about in world war ii
that used propaganda
to spread awareness that gossiping and
talking about where their loved ones
were positioned where
resources for the military and people
related to the military were positioned
could lead to enemies learning of where
those
resources were and then attacking them
so the idea of security goes
back to more of this basic need to
protect lives to protect people to
protect information
and to keep those things
confidential and private
for the sake of protecting
rather than simply
keeping data secret or client personal
identifiable information or health
information private we really want to
think of security as
a means of protecting our population our
people our information about those
people and how security has a real
impact in all of our lives on many
levels everything from locking your car
doors to
keeping your home alarmed and secure
while you're away
all of those things relate back to
security and what drives that security
is a passion to keep those things safe
and that i think is something that's
very important to keep in mind as we
progress through this because
essentially
our perception becomes reality and what
is popular
in media and what we see
when we learn about security that
becomes
the truth or our perception of security
and sometimes that can be slanted
away from its original purpose
when we learn about information security
we learn that it is specific to
confidential confidentiality of data and
information
it is
related to the integrity of that data
keeping the data intact and complete and
accurate and our it systems information
all of those things operational and
accessible and available so the
availability of that data to the members
of our organization
and our clients to keep our businesses
operating to keep us making money all of
these things relate back to that
security keeping those systems secure
keeping that data private
and a lot of this has been driven by
a need to define a process for
business security when we think about
information security we think mostly
about business security and not so much
the original purpose of security which
was to keep
our information private for the sake of
protecting people we think of protecting
systems now more in corporate
information security
so related to
a need to define this process
we identify
process drivers things that are driving
the process behind information security
in our corporate security programs for
our businesses
some of those key process drivers are
related to third-party risk management
these third-party vendor risk management
programs have come about
out of a lot of recent incidents where
third-party vendors were used as a means
of accessing a corporation or a business
through a utility an application
a piece of hardware or a connection that
was made to that
victim of that attack
using a third party that has
a trusted connection to that business
meaning the attacker used a neutral
third party and their trust
and access with their target to
basically
step stone through them to the target
and this has really
pushed the development of third party
risk programs
in
corporations and a lot of my clients
from basically non-existent to extremely
important in the last couple years
especially since we've moved to a more
distributed workforce and become more
reliant on that remote access to
complete processes updates
and to connect with each other
another
metric that has
essentially contributed to
this process requirement and information
security is the cyber security insurance
requirements we've had a multitude of
incidents over the last couple years
especially that have had
claims made with cyber insurance
companies that spiked the amount of
dollars going out of those insurance
companies significantly enough for them
to start putting in
requirements and restrictions on how
claims will be made accepted and
processed
and so these insurance companies are
insisting that the companies that they
insure check a certain number of boxes
or complete a certain certification or
show evidence that they have a competent
security program
we also have the corporate audit and
compliance frameworks that are being
pushed down from corporate levels into
more franchise locations and larger
organizations that dictate how those
locations are allowed to store transmit
and process data for example you may
have one large company with a
headquarters in canada but they have
many branches all over the world that
are subject not only to
the you know compliance and audit
requirements of that state nation
province or location but they're also
subject to the requirements of their
corporate headquarters as to how they
can manage and process their client and
vendor data
so the solution has become to create
more certifications to create more
compliance frameworks that are specific
to different industries specific to
different areas or business sectors
it's become this need to certify an
organization as compliant or security
conscious
rather than examining the culture of the
company and finding out if they are
truly secure in the way that they
process data transmit and store that
data
these audits only look at a snapshot in
time and not the ongoing state of the
security of the organization
a company could pass an audit could
receive um you know compliance against a
certain framework one day and be
vulnerable the very next day
so we see this cycle of
insufficient security
the overlay of the compliance process
and this solution to make this company
more secure then we see analysis and
assessment and then we revert right back
to insufficient security whether it's
through unpatched applications
poor security posture in the defense of
things like social engineering phishing
emails and a variety of different types
of attacks
despite technical technical controls and
compliance that we have in place that
checks the boxes on those frameworks
so to draw from 12 monkeys
there's this theme that you'll see in my
talk here that we all feel a little
a little crazy and i think that's
because a lot of us wake up in the
morning and we go to work and we defend
our organizations we defend our clients
we help
stand things up we create new security
processes we
execute security awareness training we
measure we simulate attacks we analyze
data and it seems that the very next day
we have some kind of a breach or an
incident or a situation that hits the
news and we all feel like we're fighting
this uphill battle
where we work and work and work and work
and we're not seeing a net result that
shows that our work is
valid that it's producing a measurable
um an impactful result and i think that
that is mainly attributed to the fact
that
real security
is not compliance and compliance cannot
be made to be security
a framework can't account for the subtle
nuances of your company its operations
the environment your people how those
people interact with each other
these audits only look at a snapshot in
time they're not going
to be able to see the ongoing state of
your security and
you know i can demonstrate that i have a
policy document that says that we do not
have hold or process any cui or
certified unclassified information
within a company and meanwhile i can go
look say and do a review of email and
find oh shoot there's a whole bunch of
it all over this company and i had no
idea i mean we had the policy the policy
said we didn't do it so i believe that
we didn't do it but the practice or the
process may be different
um and so sometimes you have these
audits that are maybe not as
thorough you have folks that are
self-assessing you have
um even the most cyber
resilient organizations that treat
compliance as a baseline and it's not
true security
um so essentially what i'm saying is
compliance in most instances and that is
a blanket statement and a generality
in some cases it can be a wonderful tool
to measure an excellent program so i'm
not saying that the two are
never
uh present in an organization and
simultaneously only that you can't rely
on compliance to create security
what usually ends up happening is i have
a client that will say okay well
you're telling me that there's a
recommendation that i should do x y z
but i'm going to ask you since i only
want to be certified as compliant with
this framework
does this framework mandate that i have
to do x y z and if it doesn't i don't
care
that's a problem that's really a
breakdown in
the security fundamental purpose of
protecting data if
the recommendation from the security
team or the general best practice from
the security team is to do xyz for the
sake of protecting people processes
systems and the client and company data
then that is what we should be doing but
what ends up happening is
that
we are simply checking boxes against a
compliance framework and creating this
appearance of security and saying that
everything is fine
because we're doing this list of
controls and we've
you know developed a way that we can
show that we're doing each of these
controls whether it's 100 accurate or
really rooted in a culture of keeping
the data protected through that control
is different
and that disconnect in the security
culture of an organization versus
compliance and a security program that
is mapped back purely to compliance
is fundamentally the problem that i'm
discussing today and that's what i want
to improve so we've talked about
what security is what really a passion
for security looks like it's protecting
people it's protecting information and
it's protecting companies data their
clients vendor and company
intellectual property data
and having a passion for doing that and
i think that is
why so many of us originally came to
this field why we got involved in
security it was that passion
to protect data and people
who are at the root of all of these
organizations and who stand to suffer
the most if that security is not in
place and what's happened over time is
that that passion has been eroded by the
process and the creation of these
frameworks for security compliance
so what do we need to do
essentially
we need to fix the culture
behind security
and get the buy-in and investment from
the top down in all of our organizations
it feels to me
and this is my personal opinion
only
that most of the clients i speak to
their security teams have been siloed
away from the rest of the population and
they don't feel like they are being
heard like they are being understood or
listened to by the folks who are making
the decisions about where the investment
financial or otherwise is going to
happen within the organization
and
what i love about my job is i get to
bridge that gap i get to take the people
who feel like they've been locked away
in a corner to protect the organization
in the dark with their keyboards
and
i get to bring their
wants and desires and their passion to
secure their systems and protect their
businesses to light and i get to give
that
validity through issuing a report that
says that this is important and
typically what i'm doing is just
restating what the security team has
already known to be
the main or primary issues for this
organization that will help and enable
them to better protect
what they have
been tasked with protecting for the
organization
you can have
this incredible security program
you can have the policies
long detailed beautiful
styled letterheaded
gorgeous branded policies along with
aspirational procedures that say exactly
how all of your information data and
assets and ip are going to be
stored delivered handled
transacted you can have all of these
things in place along with the practice
and have all of your people
trained aware of the practice aware of
the policy aware of the procedure
and you can still be missing that
security culture
that uh drive that passion
and the buy-in of everyone at the
company to behave as a team and
essentially create this
masterful puzzle with each person
playing their part and acting as a piece
in that puzzle of the organization to
form a wall and protect this data and
information
to make these systems
available to protect the integrity of
the information
and to secure
all of the hardware software business
systems and other processes linked to
making the
company function and be able to do
business so how do we
fix that how do we
remedy that and
essentially marry these two sides of the
equation find the security culture and
then marry that with this amazing
compliance framework
um supported security program
what it really boils down to
in essence
is people
and people are going to be at the core
of pretty much everything that we do
um
and so why not get their buy-in
i've heard some incredible talks today
i've heard people talk about
um
systems that hold up our infrastructure
and how these systems can be breached
and how they can be protected i've heard
people talk about creating security
awareness training programs and how to
get the user
and executive
and
middle and management buy-ins from an
organization to make that security
awareness training
adopted
and engaged with by the employees i've
heard
just some
absolutely incredible talks about
adversaries and threats
and ways that we can protect and defend
our organizations and i think all of
these different facets
of security work together and it is so
important for us
as security professionals to understand
that we each have
our part to play
in this we each have our own specialty
and through working together
we can show the rest of our
organizations people who don't really
think about security and who haven't
been tasked or or made responsible for
security
what's going to happen if we don't
change this culture
breakdown within our organizations
um from 12 monkeys there's a line about
cassandra in greek legend
you'll recall she was condemned to know
the future
but to not be believed when she foretold
it
hence the agony of foreknowledge
combined with the impotence to do
anything about it
and what that means is she knew what was
going to happen in the future she would
tell anyone and everyone who would
listen nobody would believe her and she
was left with this agony of knowing
where things were headed
but not having a way to do something
about that
a way to shift
this perception that she was wrong
and to make people understand that what
she was saying was in fact true and i
think we're all kind of in that boat um
i mean correct me if i'm wrong i can't
see the chat right now but i'm sure
you'll let me know at the end
but
we all feel like we're constantly
screaming at a wall telling everyone who
will listen what's going to happen if we
don't protect this system or handle this
process differently or adopt this new
method this new best best practice um
you know patch this system upgrade this
hardware
get new software uh dispense with old
vulnerable software we all know
and i'm sure you can think of it right
now the top three things that you would
change in your organization or for your
clients right now you know what those
things are and you feel like you're
saying it over and over and over and
everybody just goes aha and they don't
actually believe you
about how severe the problem could be
if we don't
rectify that and mitigate that
vulnerability
so the definition of insanity
doing the same thing over and over and
expecting different results now this
quote is often attributed to a couple
different people and frankly a large
number of people who probably never said
it so i don't know who to attribute it
to but it's kind of true
we keep falling back to this position
of
wanting
to use a process to create the security
that we need for our organizations we
want to find a framework that's the
magic answer like if i can take all 20
of these boxes
you know with three to five sub controls
on each one of them like this will be
the answer and now i'm secure
and it's really just not the case
i think it's fantastic that we have all
of these um you know tremendous leaps
and bounds that we've taken with
technical security controls and means of
mitigating a lot of these types of
attacks and avoiding
um having our staff and our co-workers
dealing with having to defend against um
a lot of the volume of phishing emails
and other
types of attacks that typically target
folks within an organization
i think those are fantastic and i'm not
at all saying that we shouldn't use
those technical controls and those
capabilities and monitoring
and alerting and all those things to the
fullest
but what i am saying is
we can't just say that we ticked 10
boxes on a framework and that we're
secure
without really looking
at ourselves and at the culture security
wise within our organizations and doing
something to get the buy-in and i know
you're like okay well what's the thing
i've got to do
it's really different it's different for
a lot of organizations
i don't know the culture of your
you know nation
your region your province your state
your city your town it may all be
different what will encourage people's
buy-in in some areas won't help make a
difference in others
but it really comes down to
continuing to try
that
persistence that
drive in that effort
you can't have one security awareness
training and do one fishing test
and know where you are
you can't
execute
a one-time plan to you know check all
the things in a compliance framework and
say yeah we're good you know we're
eternally fine because back in you know
2010 we checked all the boxes on this
and everything was fine and we're doing
everything the same way so it's okay
it really takes this
constant work and effort and continued
uh
trial and error to determine what is
going to be the thing
that
helps people to understand
how this can impact them
not just in their daily lives at work
but in their daily lives in total
and
choosing the right
humans for the job is very important in
inspiring that security culture
so to encourage
that
creation of the security culture within
your organization
i want you to think about both your
existing and your emerging workforce not
only related to security but in general
i want you to think about encouraging
innovation
hiring or encouraging the individuals
that you have on staff already
to use critical thinking skills and go
beyond simple process docs
to study adversarial tactics and learn
about how to defend against those and
new threats
to go to continued education to attend
conferences to
seek certifications that they find
interesting and relevant to their jobs
or completely irrelevant if it's just
something that is security adjacent
maybe to their position but that they
find very
enjoyable to learn more about and
understand
to foster environments where you have
collaboration and sharing of ideas and
support for that
that will ultimately contribute to
innovation within your security program
to review the requirements in your job
descriptions
make sure that you are evaluating the
whole candidate that you are reducing
the education and experience
requirements to the bare minimum
and then maybe list some nice to haves
if you have some other certification or
educational requirements that you would
love to see in your unicorn ideal
candidate
make sure that you're not leaving
potential candidates
feeling like they shouldn't even apply
if maybe they have some other real life
experiences and other skills that could
compensate for that lack in education or
experience
offer
non-wage compensation especially related
to work flexibility there are a lot of
jobs that can be performed
at a not a set shift that will allow
people to have more flexibility in how
they balance their work and their lives
to have that
perfect balance struck between work and
life
so that they can you know take care of
family or friends as well as attend to
their own personal
um priorities and make sure that their
work gets done you can measure
most humans effort through their work
product and not simply their
green dot availability
status on a messenger application or
something like that
invest in your candidate pipeline
what i mean by this is
find programs that create
amazing security people find programs
that invest in
things like
capture the flag competitions not just
for hacking but other security related
areas that focus on innovation and
um
people who are inquisitive and
who
lift those people up and give them an
opportunity to learn more about
information security and participate in
programs like pisces which is something
that critical insight
puts a lot of effort into and i'm happy
to share the details of that following
this talk if anyone's curious but
essentially we help college students to
get into the industry um using our
pisces program
look for programs in your area that do
similar things so that you can find
those folks who are most passionate
about security because the folks that
you find who are
the most passionate will have a much
better chance of creating that culture
of security and buy-in from people at
all levels within your organization
encourage diversity through embracing
unique perspectives
uh trusting your employees to complete
their work i mentioned that a little bit
earlier measure folks
based on their work output and their
work product and the quality of that
product rather than simply
you know hours in a day or being
available
increase your opportunities for a
variety of work types and what i mean by
that is part-time full-time remote fully
remote
wherever that's possible make that an
option
um you don't want to limit your
candidate pool just to your specific
geographical area if you can avoid it
because you can source talent from all
over the globe if you're motivated to do
so
then foster that security mindset within
your entire team
you play as a team you operate as a team
you win as a team you lose as a team
don't single people out mentor teammates
maybe have more experienced teammates
mentor those who are newer or emerging
workforce candidates
also make sure that you have cross
training and the ability for people
within different teams to learn new
skills from their co-workers and share
that knowledge so that you don't get
stuck in that rut
of tribal knowledge where you know just
one small pocket of the company is aware
of a process or how systems work or just
one individual knows how to operate
maintain or
handle things within a specific
application or system or process
encourage transparency throughout your
teams empower your people to speak share
their minds without judgment
suspend your own judgment of others
reward new ideas
you want to give people a space where
they feel like they are valued where
they can share their ideas where their
perspectives are taken seriously
and where their recommendations are
thoroughly evaluated
in conclusion
there's this uh
the sentiment from 12 monkeys where
james cole is saying that you know the
human race is just asking to be wiped
out
and jeffrey gohan says wiping out the
human race that's a great idea that's
great
but more of a long-term thing i mean
first we have to focus on some more
immediate goals
and i think we all get overwhelmed by
the big picture
we all get slightly discouraged and
overwhelmed when we think of how far we
have to go
and i really want to encourage you to
look at this short term to look at your
daily goals your weekly goals your
monthly goals and then maybe start
projecting outwards towards the years
and the three years and the five year
plans it gets really overwhelming when
you look at a three or five year road
map and just go i cannot do all this
this is insane it is insane
so bite off one little chunk at a time
start standing up your frameworks your
processes
and start measuring
what you've completed each week i start
every week writing out a task list i
would show it to you but i can't
and essentially it's on a post-it note
to the right of my mouse and it just
says you know this is the client this is
the thing i have to do this week client
thing client thing client thing and for
you maybe it's application thing
application thing and you set this list
of things out for the week and you knock
out one of those things per day and
you'll start to feel that sense of
accomplishment and an achievement and at
the end you take a post-it that has all
the things and you physically cross it
out
and just that that manual tactical
physical being able to cross it off
really does a lot
just psychologically to help you feel
like you've made some progress
because a lot of us stare at the same
screen using the same mouse and keyboard
all day long and it just feels like it
looks exactly the same every day
so try to make your goals more
bite-sized
try to set out a framework that reduces
things down to the daily weekly monthly
level and tackle one week's worth of
things at a time
try to delegate as much as you can and
if you're being delegated to
don't hesitate to push back if something
is not going to meet a deadline if you
need to
for your mental health your work life
balance your flexibility ability
to
function and be productive
don't be afraid to ask for help to push
deadlines out to create more realistic
expectations of yourself and your team
and communicate those effectively to
leadership management c-suite
all of that will help to not only keep
you on track
but also to make sure that the
expectations are managed appropriately
so
the future of workplace security i
believe that the future of workplace
security is human
it's going to start with the people that
we put in
the position
of creating these training programs of
getting the buy-in
of you know top all the way down from
everyone on the team to participate and
to engage in our security practices that
are mapped out and framed out by these
frameworks and policies and the
procedures that support them
it's going to take real human investment
to
stress the culture over the compliance
for the individuals who really only care
ultimately about themselves
most people are going to do
what is in their best interest and
empowering someone to believe
that what's good for the company is in
their best interest
is what comes down what it comes down to
when we're talking about creating this
culture
you want to have
people who want to support your clients
your vendors your company and be a part
of that team that is actively engaged in
fighting
the adversarial threats in defending the
systems and the data
and uh you know buying in to this
culture of security
and
creating that culture
fundamentally comes down to
understanding people
and processes
and behavior and how we can shape mold
and influence that through leadership
from our positions within the security
team
so oh wouldn't it be great if i was
crazy then the world would be okay
we all kind of have our little spot in
the security universe and some days we
can feel like we're absolutely losing it
and if we were crazy and the rest of the
world was fine then everything would be
okay but i think the truth of the matter
is we're all a little crazy for a reason
and our passion really boils down to
keeping our companies our organizations
and our people safe
and to do that we need to find what
makes us passionate about security and
remind ourselves why we got into this
mess to begin with
and that comes down to what we talked
about at the very start of this talk
and that is protecting people protecting
lives
in a lot of organizations that i work
with they are literally protecting lives
of people in hospitals and clinics
um and so
i want you to take a moment today
just to review everything that you saw
here today
and yesterday at besides vancouver
what are you passionate about what
brought you to security you don't need
to tell me
but jot yourself down a little list of
things that you think
brought you here and what you're
passionate about
and try to figure out how you can walk
into work
even if it's walking three steps from
your bed to your desk tomorrow and
find that passion in what you do every
day
again
and that's a wrap for me so i will move
it over to questions these are the ways
that you can reach me
um and thank you again to besides
vancouver to everyone who contributed to
making this conference possible to
everyone who attended um and listened to
talks and contributed talks all of the
speakers
um it's absolutely been a joy to watch
everyone share what they're working on
and what they're passionate about over
the last two days
um so please reach out to me share your
feedback
um i want to hear it all the good bad
and the ugly
um and i hope to connect with you all
irl
soon
thank you elise that was great amazing
you know really good talk i see all
kinds of kudos in the chat here and
looking to see if there's any questions
um
i see lots and lots of love for your
talk that's for sure
um and the besides crew thank you alisa
i appreciate that
um let's just see if anybody has any
questions here it was amazing
lots of love exactly
it was a great yeah i know you guys are
all fantastic
so appreciate everyone
we appreciate that it was really a
really amazing talk that's for sure you
got it
well i'm going to give it a couple more
minutes for q a and see if you guys got
any good questions i know i i know at
least hasn't answered everything in life
so uh
you might have some questions for her
yeah you i left a couple easter eggs
behind me too if anyone can find the
thing that's connected to vancouver in
my background i'd love to see if you
spotted it
let's make it bigger here hang on a sec
what do you got in that photo
so you'll make it bigger she said oh
woman exactly
what do you got back there
what's your biggest what's your okay
here here's one question for you what's
been your oh hang on a sec i got two
people throwing things up there
uh what's been your biggest challenge
my biggest challenge um well let's see
it related to security my biggest
challenge for my clients really has been
expressing
um
that we can't rely 100 percent on
technical controls to keep us safe
and i don't know if you picked it up
from the theme of my talk but
if something is a best practice and
security and not specifically required
by the framework they're trying to get
audited or certified against doing it is
the smart thing that's my biggest
challenge is communicating why and
getting that investment
definitely yeah i hear that yeah
okay let's see if we got any more here
q a
[Music]
stage
q a
awesome
okay lots and lots of comments all kinds
of good stuff
lots of love okay okay uh i see i think
i see ryan reynolds in the background
oh you moved your camera
hang on so you're gonna make her bigger
there see oh see but you know that you
can't see as much in your background
there i changed no you can't
so
so ryan reynolds is right there where's
ryan reynolds see it dude
and gibb says exactly right you got that
exactly
got it
awesome okay well thank you elite we
really appreciate it that was an amazing
uh and keynote we super appreciate that
definitely um i'll be seeing you at the
next tracelab ctf at uh def con
absolutely you got it uh you have a good
uh day take care and we're going to
start
here in a couple minutes um thanks take
care ladies have a good day