hi everyone
time for cracking passwords for fun and
profit uh my name is chris timmons i'm a
penetration tester and security
specialist team lead at ion united
um
second time presenting for b-sides
vancouver so let's hope it's a good one
this time
so passwords everyone has one
um and they you know people make
passwords differently um you know you
look at the complexity requirements and
things some people think they know how
to create a good password some people
don't we're actually going to take a
look at the back end on it and see how
some of that stuff
works when we're actually trying to
crack passwords so if we're doing a pen
test and we're getting passwords how
quickly and easy can we crack them
and some of the human nature around it i
mean obviously a lot of people
understand why but we're going to dive
into that a little bit for those who
don't
so who am i as i mentioned security
specialist team leader ion i've been
doing this for about 27 years i've
been in the department of national
defense i've held senior roles at
various companies i've been working at
ion united as a pen tester for just over
three years now
so we have
done lots of
things and according to my what loving
wife and i have to say loving wife my
workshop can act as a nasa disaster
recovery location it is got stuff all
over the place and it's used to help
extract passwords i do forensic hacking
i do
password cracking hardware hacking a bit
of wireless
did smartphones for a while
uh
obviously doing a lot of forensics for
things like incident response and i used
to play around with robots and stuff as
part of an innovation team so hacking a
robot is fun
so why well i like shiny things and i am
a chronic procrastinator if there is a
reason not to do work my boss is going
to think that i do it um i'm also a huge
fan of build once and use many if you're
gonna do it once great if you know that
you're gonna have to do it twice just
automate it because then you'll thank
yourself the third fourth fifth sixth
seventh time you've done it
and as i mentioned i like cracking
passwords so this is my home rig right
here i've got four nvidia gtx 1080s in
it
with
terabytes and terabytes of space
because i like to collect things i'm a
data hoarder so i've got password list
anytime i find a dictionary on the
internet i grab it i check the quality
of it breach compilation data um
i've got it all and just sit there and
keep
building up more and more and more
so i'm going to dive into a little bit
on hash cat and i'm going to focus on
hash cat today just because uh nothing
against john
it's just i wanted to use haskat for the
presentation today
so
one of the things with hash cat is it's
very versatile um it supports what are
called a number of different attack
modes straight combination brute force
which technically is a mask attack
and then two different kinds of hybrid
word list plus masks so word list and
mask or mask and wordless and then
another one that a lot of people don't
know about uh called an association
attack so we're actually going to go and
walk through some of these
so
some of the basics on this one so
dictionaries dictionaries are big giant
word lists and they're either two things
one
they're a compilation of exposed
breached passwords so things like rock
you
weak pass is a good one because they go
and they get all the breach data and
stuff that comes out scrapes it and
basically puts all the passwords and
stuff into a file and it's a big file uh
the latest weak pass three
is just over 100 gigabytes in size so
that is a lot of passwords
um and they do a pretty decent job of
cleaning it up crack station was one
from a couple years ago it's a decent
size
um but it's beyond just looking at
passwords that are exposed you know like
summer 2022.
great it's in a password file but what
about other things that don't have
letters and numbers and special
characters on it and that's where
dictionaries really come in so use all
the languages why because well you don't
know what languages might be in use of
the password that you're cracking
um they could be using um
german or russian
characters or something with um lots in
them and that's why i mentioned about
utf-encoded dictionaries are the best to
use because they support
it um other wordless sports sport teams
music
names of songs
breeds of dogs that's actually a pretty
common one
another one is pass phrases um i've got
some stuff in here i'll show you guys on
how to get some good passphrases and
we're talking things like every verse of
the bible or every lyric to every song
ever made or you know those are phrases
that people can use when they're
creating a password
and of course i mentioned data breaches
there's just a lot um so i don't rely
necessarily on week pass and stuff like
that to go get them for me i've got a
couple of terabytes of breach data that
i go munging through whenever i need
something
one of the things about is
if you
are ever
pen testing or
cracking passwords against a customer
one of the important things to do is
make sure that you're using words in
terminology and things that are relative
to that company
um the number of times we've gone in and
and we're doing password cracking for a
customer
and they're using words that are posted
on their website they're using the name
of the company um so cool is a custom
word list generator it's just a little
rui app you tell it to go spyder a
website it goes and searches through all
the metadata pulls out names of things
and software and that was used to create
the file
and then it compresses it all into a
nice sorted list and you can tell it to
make it all lower case and you can
mangle the data however you want
afterwards
but it's extremely effective um
first thing i run anytime i'm doing
ocent on a customer uh just getting
ready for password cracking because the
number of times that it's
company name
12345 is the password or
the name of a software project or
something that they're working on and
we'll actually get more into the name of
the software project in just a little
bit
second part of hashcat is rules and the
rules as part of the mask attack
are just these are just some examples of
some of the good ones that uh hashcat
has in it and a couple that aren't
um and rules this basically take
letters and characters within a password
and flip it so it can make
lowercase to uppercase so the toggles
rules for example will capitalize one to
five characters in the password
concurrently so a toggles two rule we'll
just take two characters so first
character and last character and then
first character and third character and
just keeps going through the iterations
um trying variations on it
99.999999 percent of the time human
nature people will put a capital letter
somewhere usually not more than a couple
though and it's usually in the first
spot
a second one is a combinator rule where
you can actually combine two words so
you take two dictionaries
or even the same dictionary and you
throw it together
why well because way back in the day
people were telling people make good
passwords and then so you would make a
password your password be the name of
your dog
and then they realized oh well you need
to make a better password it's got to
meet windows complexity requirements so
it has to be a longer word oh okay well
let's get the name of both of my dogs
together
combinator rule
uh and of course
you can't crack passwords without leap
speak because everybody makes a password
uh the dead rule um just one of the ones
that i find between that and best 64. uh
they you know they're a little older but
they get the job done uh there's even a
reduced version of the dead rule which
takes the 75 000 rules or something and
dumps it down to like 1500 so it's like
really small very efficient
because what happens with a lot of rules
and i'll show you some statistics after
you hit kind of a point of okay we've
gotten just about everything so but
you're still processing things in the
background and it's not
doing anything useful
the one rule to rule them all as i
mentioned it's not a lord of the rings
reference but it does work uh it's
probably it's a large rule but it tends
to be highly effective and really it
depends on what you're cracking at the
time um i usually just put them all i'll
you can you
you can load up all the rules at the
same time but it'll just take forever
think of your talk
nice one data
the second thing is so when you take a
look at when you're creating rules and
masks and stuff
you use character sets and these
character sets all break down into
different ones so
the l is lowercase and upper is
uppercase d is digit s stands for
special characters
a lot of people use the a which is all
four of them uh you can also define
custom character sets so i could use
like dash one
and say i just want lower upper and
digits and no special characters and
then i can use that in my mask so i'm
not having to type it all out and i'll
try those three different variations
within the character set
some of the lesser known ones of course
hexadecimal and uppercase or lowercase
it's got a flag for both
so why do we use masks well the masks
are based on the whole strong password
rules we've forced on users for years
and unfortunately users are really bad
at picking passwords usually it's a word
and a number and a special character and
as i mentioned it always starts with an
uppercase letter knowing this you can
actually
say well let's not test every password
we'll just test the
key space that we want to that we assume
that the users are going to go and take
a look so if you use a mask of upper
lower lower lower digit digital that
equals spring 2020t
perfect
so and because we don't have to go
through all these special characters and
uppercase characters and everything else
you're only checking 26
potential
tries for each position instead of the
you know 300 and some so it makes it
happen very very fast
how do you generate masks well you can
do it manually
and there's a couple of different ways
there's two that i've got here in the
presentation the first is mass processor
which is built into hashcat
and you can actually just basically
generate a word list that has a whatever
you want so in this case i used mass
processor and i said i want to make b
sides and i want to a file
that has
every
possible combination or potential
combination of this one so i made it and
now i have a file that has b sides zero
zero zero and it'll go all the way to
nine nine nine nine nine
obviously you're not you're you're now
throwing a file at it but you know if
you're using a cpu based attacker you it
sometimes comes in a little handier but
you can also then take this dictionary
file and use it with other rules like
one ruler or leap speaker something like
that and generate better candidates
another thing that's really handy is
called packs the password analysis and
cracking toolkit
it basically you feed it a
password file
and it just goes through and generates
everything and i wish i had made this
screenshot a little bigger i'm sorry um
but it tells you the character sets that
you're using if you look on here it says
we're using lower alpha num so there's
no special characters in 90 of the
passwords in this and then at the end it
generates masks
what you can do with pack afterwards
then
is generate what's called a hashcat mask
and it basically says here's a list of
all the different rules i want or not
rules masks i want you to try so i want
to look at all the upper lower lower
digited kind of ones and then i want a
whole bunch and with a special character
on the end and things like that and
it'll just run through so that makes
your password cracking much more
efficient
and what are we cracking well
common hash types for using md5 because
anybody finding a backup file on the
internet that's where we find it uh shaw
one microsoft office files ntlm
obviously the gold uh when you're doing
pen testing that's the one you want net
nclem v2 very common as well and then
there's three types of kerberos and a
little pro tip on this one if you use
invoke kerberos dot powershell
uh
you won't you'll you'll get these but
you won't be able to crack them because
the formats are all wrong and the
salting is all weird but if you pull
a kerberos with rubus instead
every time
so
hashes said here's all the different
kinds what were you going to get them as
i mentioned config backup files this is
actually one i pulled off during a pen
test got access to a digi connect router
and pulled out the the config file
and there's the password
in
md5 which took me and because it ended
up it was actually the default password
still for the router they hadn't changed
it so digiconnect by default has root
and the password is dbps so that took me
about a half a sec i think it took me
longer to type in the command than it
did actually crack the password
um
curb roasting of course i mentioned
before this type 23 tends to be a little
faster than the 17 and 18 so if you can
go for that henceforth rubio so you have
you have an option to downgrade
dc sync of course is always a fun one um
one thing i've always had a problem with
is when you get the log file from it
it's painful so there's a little
powershell script uh that you can use to
just efficiently get all those files out
and of course nttds.dit extraction so
this is when you're actually either
you've taken off um the volume shadow
copy service from a domain controller or
as i get into it you're actually going
to do it just for fun
um
so but how do you know what when your
hashes when you're taking a look at them
so for example
i know this is an md5 just because of
the config file and i knew that that's
would do but how do you identify that
well the good thing is hashcat actually
has an auto detect mode
um
i rarely do it
just because
um i'm i have the example hashes
bookmarked and i literally just look for
the right string
hash id is an older application it's
about seven years old but it still gets
the job done as well so you can just
either have a file full of hashes or
just put it in on the command line and
hit go and it'll tell you statistically
which
hash type it probably is scifi and cyber
chef
limited support they're not going to
tell you have an ntlm hash or things
like that um
but they are very good for a couple
things scifi is really good
if you don't actually want to get
hashcat up and doing like if you're on a
ctf or something and you've just got
encrypted text
cyphy will actually use an ai engine in
the background
and crack it for you so most of the time
if you have like a sha-1 encrypted
or
if it's using weird ciphers like veneer
or caesar or things like that it'll just
crack it and spit out the plain text for
you so very handy to have nice little
command line tool and of course cyber
chef is
in use all over the place as well i do
find cyphy works a lot faster
on
some of the auto
cracking stuff just because the way the
back end is but cyber chef's just gold
okay so if we're going to show you guys
any cracking stuff first we need hashes
so
what i've done is i've actually used the
ntdds.dit
customer files um
by lauren gallant um
with the she actually does a domain
password analysis toolkit and so she had
some sample data and there was actually
a
active directory populated from rock u
so this actually works out really well
for some of the demos
um
so straight out dictionary attack so
this is where we're gonna take
i actually had demos and i was actually
going to do video demos for this entire
thing and up until the two days ago i
realized i can't do videos
i apologize for the the screenshots
there's a lot of them um
we take a look at this so what we've
done we've extracted all of our ntlm
files into it we've got the our actual
customer.hashes file
and what we've done is we've just run a
straight out
thing against rockyou
now
the flag dash 0 actually limits the
password
size that you can crack so normally you
can crack up like 200
256 characters
when you use an optimized kernel it
squishes it down to 32
so you won't crack any passwords that
are bigger than 32 when you're using
that flag
um
in this case we're using roku and 99 of
the files in there are all like
8 to 12 16 character kind of passwords
so it did make a difference on this one
but you can see here so on this
we ram rock you just straight out
it took 12 seconds to run and we got
99.98
of the digests
so we're missing like 20 passwords or 21
passwords out of the entire
87 000 that we were able to get pull
so that that's pretty fast
let me take a look at start adding some
rules so hash cat supports rules and
when you actually create a rules file
there's all these things so like a t
means for transpose letters and stuff
like that we're not going to get too
much into that one because i don't think
anybody on here is going to start
creating their own rules from scratch
um
but so we'll take a look at this we did
this again we ran rocky and we threw on
the one rule to rule them all it took 48
seconds so you know four times increase
in in time
we actually got 99.99
so now we're down to just
13 passwords that we didn't get
and just by doing that whenever i ran
these um attacks i was using a flag on
hash cat called disable pot file
um and that just makes sure that it's
always in memory i'm not pulling it out
of my pod file
this is raw
results and and thanks dana for uh
posting all the links it's great thank
you
um
one small pro tip is if you have a small
dictionary and a lot of rules so if i
had
a cool word list for example that only
has like 50 60 17 you know anything up
to a couple of hundred words in it uh
throw dash s on it and you'll see a
speed increase from like an hour to like
seconds
um but if you try and do it with a
larger word list it'll tell you because
you'll realize really fast because your
cracking goes from an hour to like three
so
so now what up i mentioned passphrases
so passphrases are definitely something
that's becoming a lot more common um you
know people are saying oh passwords are
bad stop using spring 2022. make a
passphrase remember that you can use
spaces and things like that
and and so people do and you know i've
already started cracking passwords where
because somebody's typing in uh quick
brown fox jumped over a lazy dog uh if
it's a known phrase that is very popular
well we've pulled it why so on init
string created a pass free word list uh
last updated i think in october uh so it
keeps up being recent but it he cites
all the sources he's pulling stuff so
he's pulling from like wikipedia like
actually every word off wikipedia or
quotes
famous quotes bible verses everything
it's all in there and there's two rules
that are in there the first rule deals
with capitalizations and stuff like that
the second one deals with permutations
so things like adding spaces between
words or putting underscores or dots or
things that people might do
when creating their secure passphrase
so it'll create a thousand permutations
of each phrase so a quick round dog
jumped over would become like uppercase
a lowercase a or a dot or an underscore
and on and on and on
when we take a look at that
um
oops hang on
there it is um
same thing i mentioned this before watch
out when using dash show with pass
phrases because you're still limited to
32 characters and past phrases can
typically get longer than that so
um
sometimes maybe run it with a dash oh
see what you can get and then run it
again without the dash oh
just to get some of the the low hanging
fruit
one of the things that we also have is
what's called a combinator attack so
very similar but this takes multiple
dictionaries into an attack where you
can use the same file it's whatever you
want um
you just put it in the mode you take
your hash files and then you list out
the files so for example if you think
people are making passwords with um
breed of dogs and breed of cats you
could put in here's your dog dictionary
here's your tactics nerd and i'll just
try every word so it'll be like you know
or apples oranges and then i'll try
oranges apples
so tends to work pretty good with that
you can throw rules and stuff on those
sometimes as well
if you can't use a rule this is where
you can generate back
what i mentioned for the the mass
generator because you can go create one
of the files with all the digits on the
end and then just use it on this one
and so we take a look at how far we did
on this one this one said it was going
to take two hours which yeah it's about
the right thing
but it also creates a lot of potentials
that's why it takes two hours um however
you'll see that within 22 seconds i
still had that as 99.98 just because
we're using rocky
but it if i had to do the full run it
would take two hours
which isn't too bad
but a lot of people ask me why and the
thing is when you start dealing with
combinations of words and you want to
take this word and then this word so
imagine two lists of a thousand words a
thousand words isn't that much but that
creates a million
entries because you're looking at every
word to every word in the list and then
the second word every word in the list
um
you can do an attack called a combinator
three and i don't really go into that
one too much
but there's a utility called combinator
three uh in the hashcat utils and
you can actually tell it to do
three which makes perfect sense it takes
forever
um but when you're telling people to do
passphrases and stuff like that or you
know pick three words two you like when
you don't um that's how you're gonna
have to run it um
when you
when you're running it in full memory
it's it's
you know like a thousand word file is
only tiny it's a couple of kilobytes
not that big at all uh if you were to
try and write out all possible
permutations of it
we're talking petabytes
of size file like the files would just
become astronomical
i did a combinator 3 attack kind of a
halfway one so i took a thousand word
word file
um ran it as an output um to generate
one larger file that had the million
words in it
and then just ran rules against it so i
did a combinator attack with a
two word dictionary and then a third one
the challenge of that of course is um it
can't insert the word into the middle
because you have to try all different
three combinations so
you have to generate it twice and then
do it again
but they're little tricks and hacks and
things that you can do but they tend to
work for the most part
and i mentioned before we did the brute
force mask attack we're doing it a
little differently on this one
um
you'll see here we did lowercase across
the board and then two digits on the end
it only took one second
and we got 3.64 percent of the hashes so
we got 3000 passwords in just one sec
just from that so if you know what
you're looking for it's pretty fast and
easy to do a mask
and it's much more effective than brute
forcing because when you get into brute
forcing so if using every special
character and every possible like letter
and digit
you can see that exact same attack that
took a second
is now going to take me two days and
seven hours
so this and
so and and take a look at these this has
been running for 50 seconds and we've
only gotten two percent of the digest so
only 1900 so
um from a speed and uh capability
perspective this got much faster results
um with a lot less effort
and sometimes when you're pen testing um
you know it's a it's a roller coaster
it's as kirk mentioned yesterday in his
talk uh you know i love cracking
passwords so when i crack a password i'm
like yeah do the little happy dance and
love to see it ringing the shelves and
everything else um
but when i'm sitting there trying to
crack that like when you're looking at a
list of this and you've got you know
like 13 passwords left you want to get
that hundred percent you're like
right this is where you got to start
pulling out some of the interesting
things and taking a look and that's
where tools like pack and everything
else
come in really handy because it helps
you try and find what's left over
because some of the times if you if you
go back and take a look at
one of the previous slides with pack
you can see at the bottom you can see
the advanced masks and you'll see like
one percent of your passwords are 0.1
percent of the passwords are using this
mask
um so you might have another one you
might not but it
though those ones
typically uh take several hours or days
to run
and of course i said when
you know when all else fails sometimes
you just have to brute force uh pro tip
a lot of customers are coming down and
using 15 character passwords this is why
it's so important to use proper
dictionary attacks and masks
because if you actually try and brute
force anything over 15 characters
there's actually a math problem
and and you'll actually get an integer
overflow by doing it
uh so we had a question can you modify
change or modify your lists on the fly
once you start a cracking one um
it loads it up in memory and it creates
an index and so if you modify that file
while it's running it's not going to
pick it up
i do cheat once in a while by deleting
the index or
doing a pause on the thing when you
pause hash cat if you're in the middle
of a run it creates a restore session
file
and it basically just tells you where in
the index it was
and
um you know all the settings that you
had done well if they can't find the
index it'll rebuild it and it sometimes
it might start from scratch but
depending on how
um how far in you were like if you were
a month into it
you know i've seen pastor craft over a
month if if you're a month into it and
you don't want to lose your spot
you're probably better off just
checkpointing it stopping it
taking a look at the results and then
trying something else because you're
probably not going to get it at that
point
it doesn't mean it's impossible um but
you're you're typically going to have
those you know like 30 day crack runs
and stuff when you're doing a full brute
force not necessarily a dictionary
attack
um
like if you were to take the weak pass
the big hundred gig file that i did and
threw one rule against it
it's gonna take a couple of days um just
because that's
how long it's going to take to run
you know 100 000 rules against
168 billion passwords
i don't brute force often
but you know if there's a chance
um
one of the better ones that we find are
actually a hybrid attack so very similar
to the mask one but what you're doing
with this one is actually saying i've
got a known word so things like company
name
or
you know name of the season
and just you can say i want
every word in this file so as seasons as
you know it's got spring summer fall
january february march april may um and
throw all the digits on the end of it go
done
uh speed dependent on gpu or cpu or both
typically uh it's gpu dependent um when
you're loading up very large dictionary
files it loads it into memory so
having more memory helps more than your
cpu
you can
include your cpu uh in password
crackings but what happens sometimes is
then the operating system starts getting
a lot leggy and stuff from i o and
um
so i i typically don't unless i really
desperate for just that last little bit
of performance
um
but
for the most part yeah
if you're gonna get a box like if i were
to say
add another gpu or add another sticker
ram or add another cpu i'd say
gpu first
ram second
after that it's all about io for ssd and
stuff for for pulling these files off
the list so like for me i've got
um
all my stuff is using internal static
the six gigabit per second stuff and
anything i've got plugged in on usb is
all using like usb 3.1 so it's you know
i've got
40 gigabytes per second of throughput so
it's usually pretty decent on that one
um so i mentioned about the association
attack before and so this is really
really works well for very large salted
hash lists for example bcrypt
um it doesn't work so well for ntlm um
and the reason is when you pull an
active directory database it's so
ntdbs.dip file there's one salt for the
entire thing
and the association attack has to needs
the number of words in the word list to
be perfectly in sync with the number of
unique salts if there's a one like if
you have 99 in one file and 100 in the
other it'll just stop
um
so on this one what we did uh for this
example is i i decrypted
uh a thousand names
i took here's a word list
and then i made that word list decrypted
them all
and then fed them that same name
um i'll get to that question stop in
just a sec
um
when
so you have the salt you have the hash
what happens is there's a hint for lack
of a better word so the hint of the
username might contain the same kind of
thing and in this case you can see we
ran a full 10 000 names in one second
success rate uh because well obviously i
mean kind of cheating a little bit
because we had the known decrypt hashes
but all we did was set it the name of a
file and it went okay and went
and just to make sure it wasn't
perfectly like i sorted and shuffled and
all that stuff and the reason this is an
important one and i wanted to bring it
up is because people tend to use names
as part of the password the number of
times we've been on a pen test and the
service account password
is the name of the service account with
like one two three exclamation on the
end of it
happens all the time so if
so commonly what i do is when i'm
cracking stuff
i'll pull all the usernames out so when
i extract like the ntds file for example
i'll pull all the usernames and search
accounts and stuff out and i'll use that
in an association tech if i have to
or if i'm even throwing it back at it
during the password cracks
because it it works
don't run into this one often just
because of the kind of hashes that we're
running into but things like decrypt if
you do have
um
certain logins and stuff that have been
exposed it's gonna find it really fast
if that works
uh actually before i go on to that one
so slava um
cloud gpu instance ironically i just
finished setting up an aws crowd
clacking crap crap
cloud cracking incident for a client um
they wanted to get some password
cracking they're looking at enhancing
some password policies and things like
that so they wanted to see how bad it
was um so i worked with them to set up
an aws instance using um
like uh aws machine learning ubuntu
image
throw a bunch of stuff on it it's
actually for using a one large was all
that we set up now
because we're able to get so many
password cracking efficiencies
we didn't have to go to like a four
times large or anything so in that has a
tesla v100 and i was getting 100 giga
hashes a second out of that one so my
home rig was getting 160
and the single tesla v100 was getting a
hundred
gigahashes so 100 billion per second um
but using the combinations of like
dictionary attacks and and everything
else that we did um i think i've got 26
success rate out of
and have to understand there's like
because they had full 12 character
password history there's something like
120 000
password entries that we're cracking and
i've already got 20 i got 26 of them in
like an hour
like uh obviously going through the
history the history 12 is always
a easier password to crack than history
six because as people create better
password policies you know they always
change but it's interesting because when
you start analyzing the password history
it gives you a chance to figure out what
their new password might be you'll see
those things where people are just
incrementing a number one or adding um
some people realize oh password one oh i
gotta make it past for two well let's
make it a special character so they just
go shift and the second one is the
second key and the third one's the third
key and yeah and that's just going crazy
on that one
um
another interesting one is called prince
so
prince processor purple rain attack and
basically what you do is you just feed
things back in so instead of taking like
a combinator where you're taking too
wordless and going you're taking one
word list and then it's just kind of
like
chaining all of the words together and
just throwing them in to find out uh you
can read more about the purple rain
attack on that one it's pretty effective
it it basically like if
it's probably one of the ones that i do
about like number five or number six uh
just because i want to have a good list
on it and one of the things i always do
is do a poor person's prints i always
take my pot file spit out the password
so
you know
colons in your password will screw up
workflows uh commas work great for data
breaches um this command here will
actually just it flips the um the string
around and then describes the first one
so you're not trying to grab the end one
which you might have a
this one goes right up from the first
one so if there's no
uh colon in it then
it grabs the whole file
and then i just keep running it again
with all the rules and everything else
yeah i've got a really good um uh link
that sans actually had put out on
setting up an aws cracking instance
um i'll try and find it um actually
i'll put it in the um in the chat here
as well
we actually followed that one pretty
closely there was a few things that it
didn't have
but for the most part that was pretty
informative as well
um and then so yeah with the four-person
sprints like i'll pull up my password
file and i will just keep using it again
and again and again and again and you'll
find as i go through different rules so
i'll use one rule and then i'll use like
the dead best 64. and then i'll go use
like generated two or whatever i'll just
keep going back and forth and you'll
find um as you get more passwords
exposed you get more success and more
success and you start pulling up some
really weird ones that way
i wanted to give a couple neat little
tricks and tips and stuff um near the
end of this one
i do a lot of ctfs just because why not
it's a lot of fun if you're cracking a
password a dictionary you need to create
a rule because when you try and crack
the password is always not just like the
word rock or you know like rocky uber
summer 2020 it's always wrapped in the
flag so um
you know curly bracket flag calling
password
so you have to create a rule to actually
wrap
anything in it so the problem is when
you create a rule it actually applies it
in reverse order
so you would think you know i need to
write
flag
well you actually have to go opposite
way so semicolon g-a-l kind of thing so
your rule looks like that
you know flag that rule looks like this
boom and then you can run it against it
so if you're doing a ctf and you need to
crack a password um 90 make sure your
flag values are set to what they're
looking for and you'll have a lot more
efficient on the password crafting on
that one
because typically on ctfs they do two
things they always wrap in a flag and
they're always using rock you so
little things people for things like
passwords for files um you can you i
mentioned microsoft office files because
you can actually pull out the the
encrypted file and brute force it that
way i
get asked to do that all the time um
some people are losing things like
bitcoin wallets and passwords and stuff
like that how you get the hash is
up to the mind of the reader um
but basically create a file with
what you think your password is going to
be or what you think it might have been
or what you might have typed or if you
know it taps lock accidentally on kind
of thing
and then to start creating a whole bunch
of permutations of it so
basically read in the rules put it out
and then it creates another file with
here's all the permutations of it based
on the rule
and then just
start banging on it
eventually you'll get it this works more
often than i'd really care to expect
if you have no idea what the password is
then yeah just kind of throw everything
at it um in this case it was a 7-zip
file
you might get lucky
i mean it doesn't work too well against
things like
things that you know you only have five
chances before it deletes or itself or
something so um obviously this is mostly
taken off like for an office file
there's you can run a command and john
actually there's um
was it office to john
and it'll just pull out the encrypted
hash and then you just run it
i wanted to obviously i've
had to go through this a little fast
but
practice
it's the best way i mean i can't always
predict that i'm going to actually you
know get demanded men on it on a
customer and stuff and we have limited
engagements so when you're cracking
those
you you only have so much time you know
we've got a week to do the pen test and
stuff so there's a you know you want
what can you get an hour go
um
corelogic runs a cracked me if you can
contest every year at defcon
the nice thing is all of the previous
contest files are always available so
everything going back to 2010 are there
so if you go and download the contest
files it's got you know whether it's a
list of different hash types that they
want you to crack or anything else last
year
they threw everybody for a loop and
actually just provided an ova file of a
windows domain controller and said here
have fun um and then you have to go find
everything
right and so that's you know like
grepping through ntds for um you know
clear text passwords and descriptions
and stuff like that it was insane um but
it was a lot of fun
and so you can go and
you know download the contest files go
take a look at them
um try cracking them yourself and see
how good you do and then then go look at
the
at the explanations and all the
write-ups and stuff and see how close
she got and then try it again and then
you know practice practice practice try
and do it um agile bits a company makes
one password actually puts out some
password cracking challenges once and
all on their github page um
they're kind of fun
but if you're looking for ways of of
things to crack that are beyond like the
the rocky
file that um pvat put out was fantastic
great for demos and stuff like that
um
but when you get into some of the core
logic once they start throwing weird
loops at you where they're you know
they're inserting two characters into a
word and you have to kind of like write
a tool or something to figure out how to
crack that so it lets you play around
with a lot of different kind of hash
types and rules and processing so going
over some of the
like the combinator attacks and the um
the hybrid attacks in six and seven
those are ways of cracking a lot of
those passwords and that's why they're
doing them
they're taking passphrases they're
mangling them they're um they're
throwing leap speak at things and things
like that so a lot of fun to do and a
lot of really interesting ways to
practice
so
and with that
that was it perfect we got time for q a
do you have any q a
that's awesome chris yeah anyone who's
got any questions now's the time to ask
you can put it in the chat window or in
a q a poll i actually do see something
that just went into the cuny ball
how secure is bcrip considered as a
hashing mechanism
it's actually pretty good bcrypt is
really nice because it's very fast to
encrypt and very hard to decrypt aws put
out a or amazon put out a fantastic
write-up on
on how they implemented bcrypt for aws
and it
they did not pull any punches they went
through all the deep technical specs on
it um
and it is hard to brute force it and
that's where things like the association
attack are so powerful because
it lets you
get a a potential
up on that one because it's such a slow
um decryption
i saw another question up here too as
well it was
here's one here can you send the
passwords to encrypted file or do you
perform them in a veracrypt container
uh actually usually just directly in the
file so if if i'm brute forcing like a
7-zip file or anything like that
um
like i'm extracting the password hash
from the file
brute forcing it is just a text file or
something on my rig and then i'm going
back to the 7-zip and typing it in
manually
um
there's another question here it was
when creating these setups what
prevention methods do you take to ensure
that these passwords are not exposed so
there's a lot so for example the aws
setup um absolutely firewalled
completely off the internet um i had to
to to do this
i created a
nok
and i threw in a storage array on it and
put all my files on it and there's a
cali vm on it um so all my dictionaries
and and you know public stuff is on
there
and then i have to vpn in uh using mfa
and everything to to a jump post
connect to that cali box which is
firewalled off and on a special
management network
then i have access they put firewall
rule in for me to get up to the aws
instance again with mfa and everything
else uh and i had to run everything
through that
uh the passwords never left the box and
like when we moved them off the domain
controller it was a coordinated effort
you know we encrypted the and the zip
file and the registry hives and
everything right on the server threw it
over
and then no password hashes or anything
were decrypted until everything was
firewalled off and ready to go
so
excellent question
someone was asking can we get a link to
the slides afterwards um
yeah and and we will be taking this
presentation and be putting it
up on our youtube channel so i'll just
add that right now in the chat window
feel free to subscribe to that so you'll
see it when it
goes live
and then i've got a pdf of this one so
excellent so there'll be a pdf as well
blast it out on the twitters and
everything and you know
we'll get it to you if you need it
any last minute questions we still got
some time
yeah we can go back over anything or
anything anybody wants here's another
question from alan um would a mining rig
work well for cracking also not sure if
they're optimized for this purpose or
not or does it depend on the scenario
ironically uh my password rig when i
first was setting it up uh i was gonna
start this is
right before the ethereum wall got hit
uh so the plan for it was i was gonna
sit there and mine ethereum all day and
then when i needed crack passwords i
would flip it over and then go back
uh but yeah these rigs are exactly
that's exactly built for it um
you know if i had to do mine again i
might put it in a better location
because um my lab does not have quite
the ac that i need
um
loudness wouldn't be much better either
for that well it works great in the
summer not so much in the winter um
but yeah it's pretty good um but yeah a
mining rig is exactly perfect um if you
if you're doing that then you can easily
flip back and forth between them
um
and you don't necessarily mean i mean i
have this big rig because i need the
speed um you don't need a big rig to do
this you can force cpu usage it's
obviously going to take a little bit
longer um but
a lot of laptops um even some of the
smaller ones with like the ends and
stuff
they work they're just going to be a
little slower and not so much
i i have a surface book and i use vms
for everything and i can never use hash
cat i have to use john
because in the virtualization i just
don't have the right uh
uh oomph for hashcat to run well so it's
all about what you have and how you use
it i guess
yeah i mean i went off and grabbed
another gtx 1080 and threw it into um i
have a server
thing that's running a bunch of torrents
and everything else and so i threw that
in um
into there just so i could you know if i
have a little job that i wanted to run
while um the big jobs are going on i can
just kind of jump over and do that
um
[Music]
anything else i'm just just checking the
q a q
nothing more in there the chat looks
pretty open
wow i guess it gives us a little time to
grab a quick bite or a coffee before our
next session
let me just do a quick check here
yeah manny's in our next session
excuse to expense a gaming tower
absolutely
unfortunately for some strange reason
when i started getting into passwords i
don't play games as much
well now it should be your vr setup
right yes actually so that's the reality
of it all is you can say that you're
building and you need the compute power
and gpus so you can do vr
might get that written off that way
or or i can try and you know because my
uh my kid's teacher um uses uh oculus
and stuff for um acron like this big
squirrel attack a tree game and stuff so
i you know i can say hey look let's fun
time for the summer
but anyways yeah if anybody has any
questions and stuff like um you've got
my twitter and
everything else hit me up send me an
email whatever the case may be and uh
glad to answer any other questions you
have
it was awesome thanks chris appreciate
all of your work that was great research