all right i think it's time for me to
start here
hey everyone welcome um thanks for being
here today
i'm doing a talk on online privacy and
risk management
and let me just pull press play here
oh let's
get right into it all right let me
introduce myself so my name is ritu gill
i'm an open source intelligence analyst
with 14 years with the canadian
government specifically with law
enforcement 12 of those years i was with
the royal canadian mounted police
canada's national police force
i am a ocean enthusiast
you can find me online on twitter where
i go by the handle oset techniques um
i'm also an advisory member of osync
curious
which is a group of some
you know amazing ocean people uh i work
with many other um great ocean people uh
teaching those um
who want to learn about open source
intelligence uh we post blogs
10 minute tips and other content um for
those that want to advance their ocean
skills
i also have a website uh ocean
techniques and i started writing courses
for verified investigators on cyber
training
so what are we going to talk about today
the agenda today is to talk about some
basics like definitions of ocean opsec
threat modeling might heard some of
these terms before i will go over
examples of how people compromise
themselves online and then i'm going to
discuss ways that say you can stay
secure and i'm going to share some
resources that could also help with
discovering your online footprint and
then
find ways that you can remove some of
this information
so open source intelligence
it's a process of collecting evaluating
and analyzing publicly available
information with the goal of answering a
specific intelligence question so this
is my full-time job and
how it fits in with privacy you might
wonder well if people did a better job
of managing their online footprint it
would make my heart my job a lot harder
it would make it really difficult
and so let's talk about opsec what is
opsec it stands for operational security
and the objective of opsec is to prevent
sensitive data uh falling into the wrong
hands okay so we first want to identify
that data that can be compromised and
then we want to take the steps to reduce
the exploitation of that data
so think about it like this a bad actor
could use information you're sharing
online and do something nefarious
like break into your house while you're
on vacation because maybe you shared uh
photos with your family saying that hey
you're all away from the house so it's
empty
so
some questions to think about
and let's start here is
what can an adversary or a bad actor
gain from looking at your online
footprint
where do you expose yourself too much
online
how can you minimize those risks
these questions will help make your
assessment
for you having better opsec might
might mean preventing
somebody with bad intentions um from
identifying you online or knowing where
you live or work sometimes you don't
want that information known
but there are some of you that need to
take it like another step further and
you need more protection because of the
type of work you do okay
so a threat model i talked about some of
these basic terminology some of these
terms a threat model is a method of
evaluating security and privacy risks in
order
to mitigate them that's the point
everyone's threat model will look
different
and there are different levels of threat
models okay so some may only need to do
basics like password protect devices use
use strong passwords use two-factor
authentication where some of you might
need to take it a step further and
actively remove
some of that public data from the
internet
so you might be thinking well okay
um
how do i figure this out well to figure
out what your threat model is
you want to find the answers to
questions such as
what information do you want to protect
so
your house address your work location
family members your assets these are
things we typically want to protect
what are you doing now
um online
or what are you doing now that exposes
you online you have privacy settings on
all your social media what do you post
online
and then who might want to gain access
to this information
this can be in the form of people you
don't know who are looking for a soft
for example this can be in the form of
say you apply to a job and a recruiter
searches for your name on social media
to see what you post
to get an idea about your character
right it could be simple as that
somebody wanting to get information
about you
so from there you would conduct an
assessment like this it's a good
reminder of how your online activity can
impact you
you may move into a job where you need
to reassess your threat model that's why
it's important to think about this often
and reassess as necessary
and one thing i always like to point out
here is
risk factors
definitely you are a risk factor and
what you do online but also family
members friends colleagues they can
inadvertently expose you online some
every some of you might be thinking well
what are you talking about okay well i'm
a ocean analyst as i've mentioned
and i search and find information about
people all the time
there's an incredible amount of
information
people post online that gets used um and
to give you an idea
of what i need to start with well here's
a list
so these are the things you want to
protect okay um all these things allow
me to find out more about you so whether
it's your name or
a username your email addresses
employment information i call these
digital breadcrumbs
and they help build a pro they help
build a profile on a person or a
business or whatever it is um at the end
of the day the more private someone is
the harder it is to ocean okay the
harder it is to find that publicly
available information
so remember these are things you want to
protect
and yes some people make it really easy
so this post caught my eye this person
made it so easy to find information
about him
uh
on facebook
posted his current workplace his job his
past uh job where he lived um where he
was from he had even had a he tagged um
something on facebook that said his name
so let's just say his name was john and
it said john's house and it had a
location
uh and so that was probably his house
address which was really not great to
post
furthermore he had
notes posted where he had tagged his
mom his girlfriend
in general just too much information
um and of course this post caught my eye
because you know he evaded police and i
was like oh interesting
but at the end of the day
no privacy settings right
uh the reason i'm showing you these
examples are
they're takeaways for us people like us
right we can learn from other people's
mistakes
and then
you see ones like this
it's a facebook group somebody finds a
driver's license
and
they post it and i've purposely blacked
out a lot of blurred out the images and
stuff so i don't further expose that
person but
this is not a good idea uh that's por
offsec as written on that slide that's
what i i wrote there i drew that on
there um
it's just that wasn't necessary to post
somebody's driver's license on uh open
facebook group not not great right too
much personal information but again
people aren't always thinking about
these things
let's look at an example of um something
i just call leaky documents where some
people might not realize their google
drive
is not always secure so using
a google search here and a site operator
that's what i've done in this example
you can look for resumes on google
drives these types of documents are
sensitive as they contain so much
personal information
it can include your home address right
phone numbers emails employment
information um and more
so this is a good reminder to
ensure your settings are secure on the
platforms you use not just google drive
but in general but ensure your google
drive is locked down um but always check
your privacy settings
i posted a link on the slide
for those of you that want to learn more
about search operators
how to narrow down your search when
you're using uh search engines because
that's a
that's a really helpful
skill set to have
to find the results you're looking for
all right this one so from the ocean
mindset
barcodes can provide us with important
information some people don't realize
that barcodes contain personal data or
they can right for example people on
social media love posting their boarding
passes
okay
um so in this example
number one
i was looking at someone's instagram
post from
post of their boarding pass
uh which they posted with a hashtag
boardingpass
so
that's a thing some of these hashtags
they just um they're again
great for finding information but really
poor optic
um there this person was using an alias
on their instagram account so i didn't
really know their real name i was like
okay and it wasn't actually a name um
it was uh just some sort of some sort of
username um not related to the person i
guess
um
and when they posted their boarding pass
they covered their name with their thumb
which is shown in
uh
in the image too obviously i've had to
crop it out and all that kind of stuff
um they obviously didn't realize that
there are online barcode readers where
you know people can use which is say
number three that screenshot um that
will
scan a barcode and tell you if there's
any data in there and so i did because
you know i'm an osin and a privacy
person and i'm always curious what
people are doing online
i took the barcode entered it into the
barcode reader and in image four is the
result so it revealed this person's
first name their last name
the departing airport
the destination airport what airline it
was flight number
um
sometimes it will even give you like
their frequent flyer points uh their
number or whatever access um you might
think so what well hackers are known to
look for this information and they can
hijack accounts moreover they can gain
more personal information about that
person so this is just a small example
to show you that even barcodes can
expose you
in different ways online
here's an example of how people
inadvertently leak information about
themselves so social engineering
questions
you've probably seen them on social
media
uh
these questions people keep answering
they're a prime example of over sharing
sensitive data online
and sometimes some of the questions are
not too big of a deal but then there's
questions
and you'll see on the right screenshot
here uh where people provide too much
information so where someone somebody
could use these answers to guess
security questions so like hey what are
your siblings names what's your favorite
song um
it can go on and on right so not all
these would uh maybe um fall into you
know trying to access somebody's account
but there are several right sometimes
what's your favorite color what's your
favorite band important important dates
um even you know uh to do
with schedules or when that person is
this is just poor privacy when you're
you know answering these questions and
then people will repost them and then
other people will answer
so most people know not to post pictures
or credit cards or pictures of their
credit cards or disclose sensitive
information online but a surprising
number of people will post their phone
numbers and home addresses on social
media it's shocking i see it all the
time
so again you might ask what's the risk
well somebody guessing passwords uh
social engineering attacks against you
maybe physical harm etc
so the takeaway on the slide is pretty
much what you see on the left screenshot
stop giving people your personal info to
guess your password and security
questions bad idea don't do it
so you're probably thinking wow okay it
doesn't stop so no it doesn't end there
there's more the past couple years have
been terrible for over sharing people
posting uh their vaccine cards
it can tell a lot about somebody and i
just use this one as an example
regardless of what kind of card it is
but this is kind of more i guess in a
recent
thing uh
depending on
what your vaccine cards say if you if
you are vaccinated what it says it could
include your date of birth it could tell
you about somebody in terms of what city
or what country where they're from um
your name and
depending again where you're from how
much there could be a lot of information
exposed
not only that
there was a huge issue with people doing
counterfeit and that kind of stuff but
you're making it really easy by posting
that card there to just grab a
screenshot and go from there the second
example
packages so
people again
uh we love shopping we love our amazon
all that kind of stuff but a lot of
people get the boxes they throw them out
throw them in recycling or wherever they
put them um with their addresses their
names on these boxes
again
i mean
people are dumpster driving whatever
people might be looking for hey i need
an address and a name well just go in
the recycling bin if you're if you live
in one of those buildings uh
one of the shared buildings that kind of
thing third example
in this third example a male was seen
wearing his work uh
badge when he stormed the capitol uh
last january
so again and i i believe from the news
article he was fired but again why would
you do that
why would you do either
and then we have um things like i just
call it sketchy text messages you'll you
likely have experienced those phishing
text messages
uh where they want you to click on a
link in this example
i received a text message where there
was an ip address noted and a mention of
a netflix account so when i searched
that ip in urlscan.io
it was tagged as malicious
activity so there was a huge red flag
right there
not that i would have clicked on it but
i just wanted to know what it said um
also i don't have a netflix account in
my name so i knew that was a phishing
text on top of it so the takeaway first
thing don't click on unknown links or
addresses via text or email
a good website to check for malicious
content including searching for websites
or ips
uh is
urlscan.io the one i showed in this
screenshot
okay so i know this example um it's not
about online privacy but i felt it was
still important enough as a reminder
because a lot of people will post about
these same things on social media posts
so not only
that
uh
but what you have to remember that what
you put on your say vehicles they can
impact your physical
physical security as well so car
stickers can give away a lot of personal
information so whether you're driving
through town or your car's parked at
your residence think about what you're
advertising okay so about your kids what
activities they're involved in
expensive toys say you have in your
garage um if you have a pet their name
where you live work where your kids go
to school that kind of stuff again
anybody can easily become a target for
different reasons but these are things
to think about and i'm not trying to get
people to be paranoid but i think it's
important to
care about your privacy
so
be mindful of
what's in the back of
your photos you know whether you're on a
video conference call that way you just
have more control of what you expose
okay so these are some tips just when
you're sharing content what you want to
think about
privacy settings don't always work on
all platforms
facebook for example is leaky privacy
settings on facebook are not black and
white okay and i'm telling you that from
experience years of experience uh using
facebook um for investigations
before posting you want to ask yourself
if what you posted was leaked would it
compromise say your location if it
mattered uh your family
and then proceed with your actions
before i post anything on social media
privacy settings or not i ask myself
this question and then i proceed i
consider all my social media
interactions as public
even if i have a private social media
account um
i always think of it as uh
you know if it gets out in the public is
this going to be an issue for me um
also i consider and you should consider
what you post as permanent because
whether you're using snapchat instagram
whatever platform you like people take
screenshots so even though something
might disappear after
whatever seconds or you know after so
many days or or whatnot
there still could be a
record of it
it's easy to overshare online and
overlook the risks um but a question
think about is what might a fraudster do
with this information
and the last thing i want to say is
remember that everything that you're
posting online is building your digital
footprint that's really important to
remember
sorry uh so some basic tips so what can
you do to protect yourself
um
these are some general tips that you can
start with for better online privacy and
security
you can use strong passwords
you know using strong passwords that
passwords manager is a start
but also think about your browsing
habits and
you know using maybe a secure search
engine like doc.go or
startpage.com
that don't save and collect your
personal information
um and the next few slides are about
your searching habits so
to get a complete list um you can scan
this qr code i know that sounds super
sketchy for a privacy talk um but
don't randomly scan qr codes because
they can contain like on the street i
wouldn't just go around scanning these
codes because they can contain malicious
content this one
is just a link to my website because i
didn't want to put all the tips on the
side they didn't fit um it just links to
osentechnics.com
um and that's all that is
other things you want to think about
though is you know don't leave your
devices unintended when you you know go
to a coffee shop do you just walk away
um you know do you lock your screen
when you walk away do you use webcam
covers do you use a privacy filter
sometimes
it's important for some of those some of
us to care about that kind of stuff
so let's talk about search engines
like google chrome that save a lot of
information about us
and i one thing i do notice is there's a
lot of confusion about what incognito
mode is
um using incognito mode doesn't really
protect you it won't save information on
the computer that you're using but your
isp your internet service provider and
other websites can still see your
searches
so
for me it's
i'll use incognito when i'm using
somebody else's machine you know you're
over and you need to borrow somebody i
would be like okay i'm going to use
incognito that's when i would use it
this prevents your history and what you
search and the cookies from being saved
on that particular device that's all it
does
so what else um browser fingerprinting i
want to mention this it's a technique
used to identify people based on
their device settings your browser
always divulges some information to
websites you visit such as hey the
browser you using operating system the
exact version of say the browser
so whether you've left it um not updated
that kind of thing
if you want to see what your browser
fingerprint looks like you can use one
or a couple of the following free
services
um
coveryourtracks.eff.org or say
am i unique.org
it you can find out say you know see
what they see the your ip the type of
browser that kind of see it's
interesting to see what you look like
when you look at websites especially if
you're looking at like personal websites
that somebody might be monitoring um
i look at it from the perspective of if
i'm investigating or researching
someone's website
i would like to cover up who i actually
am versus who i want them to think i am
um so some of these websites again they
give you the insight into how identify
identifiable you are
to sites and people um and sometimes
it's worth to do a comparison like i'll
pick a couple just to see what uh the
different sites say about you
um again after using some of these sites
you might say well what can i do to
maybe fix this or change this
okay this is an example from
miunique.org
so again
it'll help you understand what's
collected about you when you visit a
site
and you'll see the the higher the
similarity percentage um the better
for you because you blend in um so
that's kind of interesting but you can
give this a try
and see how it works for you um another
site that i don't think i have on this
slide or on the last slide was um is
device info.me
so device info.me that's another site
that also does something very similar
so some browser extensions that you can
use to adjust your privacy settings
there's many but i'll cover these three
quickly um there's https everywhere so
they this will encrypt your
communication with many major websites
so it'll make your browsing more secure
it will switch a site from being
insecure so the http
to secure so that's h t um
https the s being for secure privacy
badger it will block advertisers and
third-party trackers from
secretly tracking where you go and what
pages you visit so that's another good
one and then we have something different
user agent switcher
this extension changes the user agent
which is something that identifies what
browsers browser you're using so you can
you know and what version and what
operating system so
with this add-on it helps you change
your browser and your operating system
footprint
i could be
i could be using an ios device
on chrome but spoof these details with
this extension that's what it does
all right so let's see here
what else can you do to secure yourself
what are some solutions
simply security
by absence okay not posting the
information out there in the first place
you can't get hack through what you
don't have you know through the services
apps that you don't actually have this
is a good reminder that if you stop
using certain apps sites or whatever it
is
you want to make sure you delete them
don't just say hey i'm off and just
leave it there because that information
still can be used by people this is part
of cleaning up your digital footprint
i've conducted security assessments
where i often will find a user's old
accounts they never deleted but they're
like oh i stopped using it um but they
contain
a lot of
information such as photos
associations to people and all that kind
of stuff that's why
you want to care about that
disinformation there's another technique
it's called disinformation where you
plant some fake information to mix up
your digital footprint you can create
fake accounts especially if you do have
a unique name maybe
if you have a common name like mine it
is common people sometimes are confused
by that but it is common um
it helps me kind of hide in some ways
but if your aim isn't common you'll have
to put in more effort and disinformation
is one of those techniques
say for example you search your name and
you find information false information
about yourself out there
perhaps leave it there that's what i
would do right um i wouldn't try to
correct it maybe
the goal is to make attribution to your
name difficult
educating those people around you this
is really important letting people know
how they might be compromising their
privacy and security and why it matters
there's a cool little video here um
which shows it's called data to go and
some of you may have already seen it it
shows how easy it is to obtain
information about people online it's a
quick few minute video
um but again it's uh you can if you
don't feel comfortable with visiting the
tiny url i created i created that
you can just go into youtube and enter
data to go
and check it out
what else can you do there's so much you
can do data breaches they're constant
have you checked if your accounts have
been a part of a data breach troy hunt
has a website called have i been pwned
where you can search for emails and
phone numbers
to see if they're associated with
breaches so go run your own and see if
you were part of a breach
this
uh service all also allows you to sign
up for notifications so any future
breaches you'll be notified if you find
you've been in a breach make sure you go
change your password you might want to
even go delete the account altogether in
some situations it's all about
minimizing the data out there about us
some useful websites i'm not going to go
into details here as i'm getting close
to my time um but these are some
resources and i've explained what they
do
uh another one that's not on this is
called
privacytests.org it's a web browser uh
privacy it's a comparison essentially
but you can go through these different
sites allow you to do different things
they're just some resources for you
and there's an exercise you can do
number one tip is that majority of
awesome people start with ocean or a
search engine so
try searching your data on google and
bing and find ways you can remove this
information you know through the contact
information on a website if it's there
this is one of the easiest ways uh to
see what your digital format looks like
so start with what you use your name
your usernames your emails search your
home address and quotes use quotes
around your name um add a location so
you know uh whatever area you're from
and
also think of search engines as that low
hanging fruit
next
the next thing you want to think about
is those manual searches when you're
into social media go go see what those
look like as well
and again some more resources here um
if you do come across things there's a
couple of resources here uh i have
there's one from michael bazelle the
first one
um another one from mike micah hoffman
who's web breacher on twitter and joss
josh huff who's learn all the things on
twitter they provide a bunch of useful
tips to clean up your digital footprint
um i understand there will be challenges
depending on what country you're from
like the united states where they
don't um
they have a lot of public information
about their citizens so it's more of a
challenge but it's still possible
and for those of you that like
documentaries and that kind of stuff
this was or is available on netflix
the social dilemma is a good awareness
film and it shows the many ways social
media
platforms influence society um it's also
interesting that a lot of the former uh
a lot of the people they interviewed
were former employees of facebook google
and whatnot
all right
final thoughts
okay so remember threat actors can use
information to their advantage and we
need to do better to protect ourselves
don't be a soft target
by exposing too much personal
information or details about your life
online
and this last one here so here's a recap
of my presentation which i will post on
twitter
if you guys are interested i hope you uh
enjoyed my presentation and learnt a few
things
here's my contact information
feel free to reach out
on twitter or you can email me as well
at this email
address and
that's my presentation
any questions