thank you ashley for the introduction
and hello everyone vishakha here
so before we begin i will just introduce
myself quickly
really quick because i don't use slides
after this
so i am vishakha jan from india and i am
the director and indian ambassador for
cyber security global alliance and i
work
as a senior consultant with ibm as my
day's job
and i'm also the associate lead of
education and awareness for wise india
chapter wise is ibm's community its full
form is women in security excelling
and i am the brand ambassador and
advisor for the women in cloud network
and i am the ambassador for the
international imposter syndrome
awareness day
and i also serve as the council
representative for the public safety and
security council west bengal india so
this are the few credentials that i hold
in the industry and
that's about me
and now coming to the topic cyber
security
mindset a ceaseless erudition
so let's break into uh the topic as to
what is cyber security first and then
i will go about explaining why on earth
it's a ceaseless irritation and what
does evaluation means it means learning
and
as a cyber security practitioner one is
supposed to be a lifelong learner
because no two days are the same and
you have to think the unthinkables and
do the undoables
and stay vigilant every day is a new
challenge and it's it's exciting as
as long as you're a lifelong learner
so coming to cyber security what it is
cyber security it is a state of being
and it is defined as people powered
perpetual innovation
in the book called cyber security
leadership by dr mansoor haseeb because
while technology dynamics keeps changing
it's the human factor that serves the
weakest and the strongest link in the
world of cyber security which happens to
be a very deep and vast ocean in itself
there are empty earth number of ways you
can break into cyber security and that
is why i say it's a ceaseless erodion
because it's not a state but a process
and
earlier
it used to be information security which
used to be the 1991 model of
modern dynamic model
in such a model data used to exist in
three possible states
transmission storage and processing
because cyber security seeks to maintain
confidentiality
integrity and availability
of systems and information
we use three tools people policy and
technology to achieve cyber security
goals and people are the most critical
element as i already mentioned
and as a matter of natural
security the critical role of people and
innovation and cyber security
must be recognized and accepted
and
that is why there is a major policy
persistent in minds of many people that
cyber security is a stem discipline stem
equals science technology
engineering and maths it is not it's a
business discipline
because disciplinary diversity of people
is essential for a successful
organizational cyber security strategy
people from almost all disciplines such
as sociology linguistics psychology
political science language arts business
law
finance criminal justice and foreign
whatnot can succeed in some aspects of
cyber security and they are
most welcomed in this
field
and
those who
adhere to the jaundiced view that people
are mailing to be the weakest link
resort to more control cyber security
programs and surveillance of people
which creates a police state and stifle
innovations
you have to be very smart
when
working as a cyber security practitioner
because
there is the exploration and
exploitation trade-off that is the
fundamental dilemma wherever whenever
you learn about the world by trying
things out
and since it's interdisciplinary you can
explore it to no extent if i share my
own story
i
was
first a technical person super technical
person doing penetration testing in my
first organization
then moving on i
got into
management i pursued a degree in
cyber security mba
came to my recent organization where i
served
various
roles
i have been an auditor i have been a
simulating fishing
expert i have been a pre-sales engineer
when time was required
an educator a public speaker because
that is why and what makes me here
so there are multiple hands that i have
done
education
what kept me going was
the
mindset of exploring things because
there are so many strengths that we as
you uh individuals have
but to use those strengths
at appropriate places to help you walk
the long
run run the long run and walk the long
mile
is required and in my case i have been
fortunate because i used to enjoy
writing so that helped me as a person
who used to contribute blogs
i learned technical writing in the
process i used to love speaking or
listening to people once upon a time i
also aspired to be a journalist
so now i get to do all the public
speaking
i have been fortunate to train so many
people
and
the fact that
this all was possible was because i kept
exploring i
remained a student for life
and i
i learned one thing very
very beautifully that
anything that you want to explore if you
have the mindset of a hungry person
who wants to
explore break the things so when as a
technical person i used to work
all my
bosses taught me
was
that i got to break the code
because
it's very myopic if you think as a
tester all you have to do is pass or
fail the case
test case so what i used to do was i
used to
explore this
code syntax
could be different logic is very much
important so now
people are
always saying that technical skills are
difficult
that is not
if you explore the technical aspects of
cyber security technology is nothing but
but ornamental mathematics so if you're
good at calculation
and if you're good at discerning the
patterns identifying patterns it's the
right place for you
if you are somebody who loves to
bridge the gap between the technical
team
and the
business owners
and a person who can uh
be there out there help both of them
come to a common stand
cyber security is for you
and
if at all you are a person
that
loves speaking or sharing knowledge
against cybersecurity is you we have so
many great influencers around the world
we have so many people who contribute to
cyber security community and the fact
that you can start from wherever you
want and every expert is important
is what makes cyber security a very
interesting discipline
to be in
you will find help whenever you need you
can keep exploring whatever you want you
can go through identify appropriate
mentors who will help you walk through
sail through
the disciplines you are interested in
and that will make cyber security a path
you would wish to choose
it's ceaseless because
learning is a lifelong process
and ideas rule the world and knowledge
is power all three dimensions that i
mentioned learning
ideas and knowledge are quintessential
part of psy
of being in cyber security you cannot
choose to
go dinosaur with your learning you
cannot be a subject matter expert for
just one thing and ignore the rest you
have to be holistically acute and that
is what will take you
high up the ladder faster too
and to be holistically approved you will
have to constantly brainstorm identify
as ideas where you can explore different
mine
um
miniature mindsets and also ask for work
be proactive
because that goes a long way if you can
understand the side of both
both the side if you can break the
things and then
think from the mind of a hacker if you
can think like a hacker if you can think
like a person who solves the problem
if you can behave like a resilient
person who is not afraid
to
fail and then bounce back cyber security
is for you
and also if you are somebody
who loves to explore and also meet new
people
cyber security is again for you
because
we as cyber security practitioners are
super privileged imagine me
sitting at india at 3 00 am in the
morning and talking to you all the way
at vancouver that's a privilege because
i belong to this domain i have the
privilege of learning from the most best
minds in the world and
also
giving back whatever little i know of
this
thing
all i can say
why this is a ceaseless irritation is
because
ignorance of basics
is not a good idea you
as long as you have your basics right
there are infinite possibilities for all
of us to explore
all we have to do
is make our hands dirty try
because
having the hands-on experience a
demonstrated history across various
domain is powerful
it makes you wiser it makes your concept
stronger and it makes you
a strong professional
because you will be never be ex afraid
to explore and you will never be afraid
to take up new challenges and be a new
person every day so that makes cyber
security a ceaseless irritation do we
have questions
i would also like to add a very
beautiful learning that my mentor taught
me
her name is dr angelina garcley she says
when you stop thinking the attacker
starts thinking continual learning is
the key to effective security management
so
you trust nobody and yet
you trust that there are tools which can
help you cover the un uncovered and
explore the unexplorable be a new person
every day be a hungry learner every day
and just be enjoy the process it's
too much fun to be here
also
you can connect to me over linkedin and
you can find me
on twitter my twitter handle is euphoric
bint
and this is my linkedin
link let me share in the chats
so that was my time
if
i would love to answer any questions
if you have any
and if if there is any way that i can
help you let me know
so yes that's my time and that is why
cyber security is
easy simple people powered and
comes with a lot of advantage and
privileges
this is my linkedin and this is my
twitter
thank you john
um
you