so oh my name is crystal viola and my
last thing is really hard to say thank
you for getting that right I'm the
Associate Director at the international
fact-checking Network and I kind of I'm
gonna spend like a really short time
trying to explain what the IFC na is
because I might you might not know what
what it does and I'm sorry for my
English and Brazilian so I will spend
more time than 10 minutes Andrea just
said it's okay so well this is way worse
and this is me we are running the
fact-checking Network since May and
we're trying to spread the word around
we're trying to get fact checkers
together and to work together as a team
because we really need to collaborate
with each other because we have so many
different people trying to fight
misinformation around and there's so
many levels of development in that field
that we need to share knowledge and we
need to work together to strengthen the
field this is what we do in a daily
basis we are more than 180 fact-checking
units around the world actually
yesterday the Duke reporters lab just
came up to their senses just went up to
210 platforms around the world which is
amazing when I started fact-checking
back in 2014 we were only 40 so it means
like in five years this is how big the
movement is growing we do buy at the IFC
and we trend everything that is going
around the universe of misinformation
and this information and we try to
approach governments and platforms and
and to work together and see how we can
help either platforms and tech companies
and fact-checking units to make their
work better right we advocate for that
and we protect fact checkers because you
might you need to believe that I have
just changed my entire life because in
2018 I was threatened to death in Brazil
either by Lula's supporters and by votes
and other supporters because in Brazil
right now you just it's really hard to
be a fact checker and as as it is in in
Turkey as it is in in many other parts
in Venezuela as it is in many other
countries so we
to protect what is being done we have a
code of principles we believe that
fact-checking is a really powerful tool
and there are so many people wanting to
become fact checkers but fact-checking
needs to be done in the right way right
you need to have you need to be
transparent you need to be to have a
public correction policy and you need to
apply it whenever you have something
wrong and you need to be clear about
your funders you need to be you need to
follow a little bit of ethics when
you're trying to tell the truth and
we're trying to teach that worldwide so
that's why we also do workshops and we
also do offer a global fact which is our
largest it is the largest summit in fact
checking the next one will be in Oslo
June next year so you're all invited to
join us and we also keep a huge amount
of information being published every day
we have the if' sans website is hosted
at the pointers website and we do have a
weekly newsletter it's called factually
I really appreciate if you follow that
too and we also celebrate the
international fact-checking day I don't
know if it's in the UK you have the full
day neighbor first and but we do in
Kampala the word so we decided that
since April 1st is Fool's Day
fact-checking day would be April 2nd so
here's what I said when when I started
fact-checking back in 2014 we were 40
platforms in 20 countries and this was
in Cape Town our glass global fact and
these guys in the back were all there
the globe lead lead stories and Paciello
politic and also a little below and this
is the team we're growing you we're not
gonna stop we're not gonna stop our work
right we have so many challenges ahead
but we're going to keep fact-checking we
keep saying that the the fact-checking
community keeps growing because the the
misinformation probably problem keeps
growing too so we just keep working but
the I have seen since we're all trying
to find a solution for this information
and misinformation problem we're trying
to make the IFC and a group that is not
a us-based it's a heterogeneous group
right we need
different people thinking about the
problem so this is how the F scene is
composed there is a Turkish director a
Brazilian co-director and there's an
advisory board made out of Americans
Argentinians South Africans Indian
Spanish and I mean born how does that
say in English from Bosnia is a good
wine how or the person who was born
there
okay that's it so and we have different
interests in that group some people only
do two bunks I mean they only deal with
hoaxes there are spread online and you
don't know who was the first one who
posted it and there are some others that
are only doing fact-checking
like political the ones that you
probably know who said the world or who
said the claim so and their different
goals also there are those fact-checking
platforms that are only dealing with
politics there are those are only
dealing with health issues those that
are dealing with climate changes
questions right and and and there's so
many levels of access of public data I
mean I was just talking to full facts
yesterday here in the UK and we were
just comparing how easy it is to reach
data here in the UK and how hard it is
to reach data in Brazil and I was just
laughing at myself I'm like oh my god I
wish I had that in Rio de Janerio but
wait we don't so and I'm trying to show
you how different misinformation is
around the world so we when we think
about the solution we have to think
broad as one solution is not gonna solve
the entire problem this is the state of
fact-checkers this is a kind of senses
that the the IFC and does this how we
look like right now in 2018 we are
mainly a non-profit world right and now
we're turning into a profitable world
the fact-checking community is getting
money which is unbelievable right
journalism make me money yeah we kind of
but not not a lot that's why I asked
about the ads in the previous
conversation we really need more we are
more people we have more effort we more
work to be done we're more platforms but
we are not getting that much money so we
still need to work on that
and right that um Connie and Antonia
they asked me how different is
misinformation around so I'm trying to I
selected a few examples of platforms
that are in the IFC and world to show
you how different it is so once we talk
about solutions we think of them here's
Amman and I don't even know how
to pronounce that correctly it there
they're working on the I on Iran but
they're not in Iran right the guy lives
in Toronto because he just can't live in
Tehran he has a fatwa does that say
there's the word in English for that
okay he can't be he changed his name he
can't be in the photos that's why he's
not in the photo of any global fact he's
the one taking the pictures always and
he uses telegram because he thinks this
besides being the most used platform in
in in Iran this is the supposedly the
most secure system to talk in Iran right
and there's very low access to public
data in Iran so can you imagine that
being a fact checker in the with the
notion of distance and having a father
against you and your family that's
pretty hard so this is Congo check in
Africa right they have all the issues
with health the health system is
cracking under their tenth Ebola crisis
in 40 years they had thousands of deaths
and the problem there is that it's
really really expensive to even get an
internet connection they the ones that
really get a phone with internet they
are the truth tellers and guess where
they go online when they have the
opportunity they go on Facebook and what
is whatever is on Facebook is the truth
so what Congo check does is a fact check
and they deliver the information offline
they handle papers they print out stuff
and they go mouth they talk mouth my
mouth and then Daniella Mendoza and
verificar dough teeming Mexico they're
having the toughest time ever because up
lop is Manuel Lopez Obrador with the
Mexican president just created a
fact-checking unit from the government
which has the same name but if you
hello I mean maybe fika which is kind of
crazy the guy kind of stole the brand
from from the fact checkers yeah two
minutes not gonna work
then there's great Africa check on the
other side now let's let's kind of show
like the big ones Africa check is fact
checking in to big languages in local
languages too
I just heard boom saying yeah we have
this regional problem yes Africa check
does too and there wow they're kind of
managing to work that out right they
covered Kenya Nigeria and South Africa
and they just created this wonderful
they call it app cast it's a voice note
show five minutes long and they did bunk
information and they only spread that on
whatsapp it's like just for this to your
family friends group right and and then
it's a five minutes very not heavy a kyv
and then people can hear the latest
about what is right and what is wrong
and internet and they of obviously as
everything in Africa they deal with
health issues - and the nearest few fact
here in the UK they're I mean they're 22
people they're big and they have Lourdes
in their advisory board I mean really
it's just amazing right and they're they
have so many so many people working
automation they're really capable of
getting whatever is being said in the
house on the house of in the parliament
and then automatic automatically getting
that onto the paper like speech-to-text
machines and you you don't waste that
time so misinformation for them is
something else right they have it's
funny because when we talk about the
topics while while in Africa health here
you're worried about migration you
probably worry about economics a brexit
story right and then you have in other
situations so what do we have in common
and I really really want to struggle
that again it's the code of principles
it's something that it's very much
needed in case I don't know if a monster
some new platforms trying to exist or
trying to be born soon but please if
you're trying to create a fact-checking
unit don't forget that you need to be
committed to non-partisanship and
fairness I know it's hard but please
develop a methodology and to be no
Hardison and fair you need to be
transparent of transparent about your
sources so fact checkers I mean I always
get that that question I probably all
fact-checkers in the back get get that
question to who fact check the fact
checkers and the answer is easy as you I
mean you just have to give people the
opportunity to click in every link and
review your factor so be transparent
about your sources the same thing for
funding in organization just reveal
where your money comes from it can't be
that hard right because if the
journalist needs to be the
accountability in journalism needs to
shift and then transparency of
methodology why your fact-checking this
and not that just tell people that
that's not no no big deal you just have
to do an agreement with your reader just
explain why you do local news and not
international news just tell them in
advance and and then be honest and
correct whenever you are wrong because
you will be wrong fact checkers are
allowed to commit mistakes yeah and
that's it thank you very much I'm sorry
Andrea
[Applause]