okay we're back
uh we're back with ayush who's going to
talk about finding little secrets in
code
um with you ayush thank you
hey guys uh so i'll be speaking about
hunting secrets in code
uh i am ayush i am a deficit ops
engineer at a company called lapseco
and i'm also the coordinator for windjas
etf
so before we begin there's some jargon
that i'd probably use during the talk
so just to get give you guys context see
when i say
secret secret is essentially a sensitive
piece of information such as credentials
uh api tokens
something like that secrets management
is the process of storing and using
those secrets in your application code
and like other places
wherever like such as automation when i
say scan specifically for this talk i
mean like scans to identify secrets
in code compute is any service that you
can like run code on
essentially and infrastructure is just a
system of uh services tools whatever to
achieve a certain goal let's say deploy
an application
scan for stuff build your dependencies
things like that yeah so challenges in
secret management
how do secrets get leaked in the first
place so uh like
the way that we are progressing right
now people people want to do uh
automation right for everything that
they can like get their hands on
uh essentially to like say let's say
improved uh speed of delivery and other
stuff
but to do that we have to enable our
code to perform actions on our behalf
and because of that particular reason
we add secrets to our code let's say you
want your code to access your database
you need to give it the database
credentials right
that's so that's perfectly fine giving
your code credentials that's not the
issue the issue arises when you start
committing those
uh secrets to your code essentially with
like a version control software such as
git
and gate never forgets because uh it it
it
creates a history of like all the
changes that have ever been made to a
uh source control repository right and
because of that even if you in future
commits you let's say remove your
credentials and
like whatnot i can always like if i have
access to a source code obviously
i could go back to that particular
commit and scan through all those
changes that you've made and still
figure out what those secrets were
and if you have not rotated them then
you're in a world of trouble
so why scan for secrets i mean uh
the best part being that it's it's not
something that
people are not aware of like we all all
know that credentials get leaked
every now and then and scanning for them
is extremely important because
i mean hoping that they never get leaked
this
is pretty much wishful thinking at this
point so uh this is a code that google
sremoto
which is like used by google sre folks
uh i mean this is for them to like
maintain up time and other things but
like i think this applies for a whole
bunch of other things as well such as
like scanning for secrets
and why would you also scan for secrets
because they provide you the backbone of
authentication and authorization so they
they allow you to like impersonate
someone so the point is that credentials
that get leaked
are meant to be legitimate right they
are not fake credentials that were
generated by a
malicious actor they were meant to be
used
in the right way by a developer or
someone else but the
moment that they get leaked i can use
those credentials as a malicious
actor and then i can like impersonate
that person essentially and then uh
it also allows me to uh access certain
actions and operations right
so it also reduces attribution
attribution is itself like already a
difficult problem in
infosec but like the fact that leaked
credentials uh create this ambiguity
between if
it was the person who was intended to
hold the credentials
and the person who might have gotten
access to these credentials to
some or the other accident or something
like that which creates this ambiguity
and essentially
in essence issues for incident response
so what can happen if the secrets are
leaked
the most obvious common thing is account
takeovers let's say i
get hold of someone's twitter api token
i would try to post
let's say on his or her behalf if
someone's ssh credentials get leaked
let's
through part of this uh their deployment
uh setup let's say
so i can put in crypto mining tools and
some something like that that can
like mine currency for me while you put
the bill for it and there's obviously
other kinds of monetary damage if aws
credences get leaked i can
launch expensive resources uh make you
pay the bill and everything like that
so available tools so you
obviously don't need to write a scanner
for yourself because this is a solved
problem this is not something new people
have
solved this issue through two mechanisms
essentially
one is uh like an entropy scan and the
other being a regex based signature scan
so entropy is essentially a measure of
how random a certain string is
uh let's say your password like a
typical good api token or a password or
something like that should be extremely
random and based on a threshold
you can tell these tools that hey you
know what if this secret is random
enough
sorry this string is random enough let's
call it a secret and then it can
identify those things based on those
thresholds
the other thing is where you can define
patterns so a lot of secrets have
a specific pattern let's say aws
credentials uh like that you use for
your cli stuff
is always start with the four characters
aki and then they're followed by a 16
uh character alpha numeric so you can
create a pattern for that same goes for
like your
google auth tokens which start with a
aiza and slack tokens and a whole bunch
of other things
so you can create such patterns and then
based on these regex patterns regular
expression patterns you can like uncover
secrets hidden in code
and all of these tools do a really good
job of scanning through the history as
well so you can sell it
ask them not to do that but like the
best part about them is that they scan
through the entire history
so that even if there were secrets at
some point in the code
and not currently it will still find you
them i personally have tried these out
but there are obviously many more
i prefer get secrets and truffle hog
secrets because it's a
really extremely fast and it uh
integrates with the existing git command
as well so once you've installed it it
becomes git secrets and then all the sub
commands like scanning and other things
and truffle hog because it's extremely
easy to install use
as well as it has the uh like about 40
signatures already present in it
so you don't need to go craft your own
signatures to like scan scan for secrets
coming to proactive action so i mean we
know that we can scan for secrets we
know that code will have secrets uh
the point is where do you scan for them
right
so do you need to run a scan every time
you push your code
before you push your code to like github
or wherever your code is supposed to go
so do you need to no because uh as of
right now most
modern companies or like most companies
handle their code in certain ways where
there are multiple checkpoints that all
the
application code passes through this
could be your automation server such as
say jenkins or we'll obviously have a
place where all the code is stored like
github or bitbucket or
maybe a self-hosted tab server so all of
these places
can be used to scan for uh secrets so
essentially you don't need to like scan
every time you push and obviously we can
also have periodic scans this could be a
part of where your code is stored
and then a periodic scan is triggered
every now and then to scan all the
repositories and such
the issue with like periodic scans is
that
there's a time gap between the two scans
right and if
in between that gap or someone pushed a
code that had secrets and
got deployed it will trigger it will
only uncover that
the next time it's the scan run so it's
not uh immediate
uh whereas in integrated scans uh you
can run it every time essentially
during the build time but the issue is
that it will increase your
delivery time so it's kind of a
trade-off
so coming to should you scan every time
you push your code so
i would suggest yes but we'll get back
to this in detail later
so do you need to pay for a new server
or something to like
essentially scan for secrets in your
code so you know again
github actions is something that github
released now a little while back
it's been a while uh it's essentially a
compute service where you can run
something called workflows which is a
set of instructions that you can give to
github actions and it will
run those instructions against your code
in your repository or even other places
you can like do a whole bunch of things
uh it's as simple as writing a workflow
creating this directory committing the
workflow and triggering the event
so this is a sample workflow where then
i will trigger this workflow on a push
on the master branch or main if you've
been following the news recently
and i define a job called scan which
runs on ubuntu 1804 i check out
essentially like go to the repository i
install python i install the tool and
then i run the scan and that's about it
and this will generate the results in
the form of workflow and
under under the actions tab in your
github repository and then you can
do whatever you want to do with that but
what happens if you already have a setup
let's say you already use jenkins or
let's say circle ci or something like
that
in that case also it's still doable if
you don't want to integrate
let's say github actions in your
pipeline that's perfectly fine because
then you can just install
the tool on your jenkins server and add
that
as a build step or something but if you
do want to offload all of your tooling
to a different server and
like to avoid let's say dependency
issues you can use github actions you
can like code on your machine send it to
github jenkins will pick up the code
from
github and trigger a scan on github
actions because that is
some that is an even that you can
trigger manually as well
then it can fetch back the results and
then you can do whatever you want if
there are no secrets then you can try
you can essentially deploy if there are
secrets then you can block and
alert on those secrets so
uh scanning obviously is one way and we
will be talking about scanning itself
but there are other places or other ways
to mitigate stuff as well
so git hooks githubs is essentially what
i was kind of uh hinting towards earlier
when i said should you scan for before
you push so manually scanning
secrets every time you add changes to
your code is going to be handful
i mean like at some point you're going
to get bored of it right and so video
developers so
the nice way to do it is add a github so
one time once it's configured
uh git hook is essentially a set of
commands or a command
that can run on a certain specified
event so pre-commit hook
would be something that if if uh
someone commits changes uh that command
would run in in our case a scan
and if there are secrets it can just
stop the commit from happening and if
there are no secrets it commits as usual
no changes there similarly for pre-push
push
rejection is on the other side of the
spectrum wherein uh
let's say you have a github enterprise
setup or you have a self-hosted gitlab
server
so whenever you receive a push you can
trigger a scan at that point and
that scan could like then specify
whether if the code has secrets and then
you can reject the push or accept the
push based on that result
the best way uh is to use the secrets
management process again in my opinion
there are tools to do this and there are
services to do this tools like hashicorp
services like aw secrets manager what
these essentially do is give you a
trusted space to store your secret uh
whatever they might be
and then they are fetched as and when
required so your code can have
placeholders such as environment
variables or
dot env files whatever you want to call
it and whenever the
like just the second last step
essentially before you deploy your code
and when it will actually require those
secrets to do
its actions that's when you fetch those
secrets and bake them into your code
in the form of whatever files or
environment variables whatever you want
to do
and that that segregates your secrets
from your code
up till the exact moment that it
actually needs the secrets so you
obviously can't have it in the
deployment state i mean like
post deployment so you have to have it
uh when you're
just about to deploy your application
code so that's where you can use the
secrets management process
this could be even more comprehensive in
the way that you can add scripts and
other things but
this essentially is like the base of it
one
common thing that people do ask me at
times
is that why not get use get hooks all
the time and why do you want to
have like a central scanning setup right
so why scanning let's say jenkins and
not have a
hook all the time uh i would say that i
mean
the ideal way obviously would be to have
git hooks so that every developer can
never commit secrets themselves but the
issue is that
let's say that you want to add a new
signature now that becomes a
pain to add it for all the developers
that are in your team whereas in central
scanning you add it in
in a single place and then it just works
for everything else right
so kit works essentially are a
developer's discipline
thing and like central scanning is
easier for management and like other
stuff to
like maintain your signatures uh results
and you can have a central place to
monitor stuff and like all sorts of
other things so that's why
people generally and i even i would
prefer like central uh scanning
but yeah i mean if you can and if you
can implement this git hooks definitely
are a
really nice touch to it because then
your secrets never end up in your code
as well so there's no
need for rotating secrets there's no
need for like monitoring for them
because they never end up in gold right
so yeah that so uh i mean
we've talked about secrets and you might
find that it's
pretty much theoretical at this point so
i did create a repo for you guys so if
whoever
wants to can go to this particular repo
i've hidden a flag here
you won't find it obviously uh on the
face of it but uh
if you run a particular scan you should
be able to find a particular
funky looking file and that should have
a flag and if you dm me the flag i will
send you some appreciation because
that's all i can send you
uh so yeah i mean uh feel free to like
check this report and use it if you want
to uh that's perfectly fine there's one
particular file that you need to look
for uh with that
i'd like to thank thank you guys for
listening in thank you beer farmers for
having me all the mentors for your help
and if you have guys have any questions
i'll take them though
okay thank you very much um thank you
we don't appear to have any questions
certainly coming from the room
um a couple of points yeah i just think
i just think no one can make the
argument that you don't know what you're
talking about that is
very technical and very fast my friend
nicely done
um what do you so overall like
what are your impressions of sort of the
code that you're seeing today and sort
of the quality of it do you see
improvements or do you see the situation
getting a lot worse uh
it it's kind of both in a way because
people
are like looking for automating as much
as they can so they are definitely
pushing in more secrets in your
code but they also realize that it's
like sensitive and
sensitive pieces of information that
they're pushing in so they're more
careful about it as well and
as all the news comes in like data
breaches and whatnot happens and
a lot of times these are very simple
things that have happened right
because of someone leaking their
credentials or maybe like
for whatever reason so they are more
careful as well so it's like a bit of
both time
i'd say
thank you that's great it's super yeah
sure
i had a question because uh a lot of
what you were talking about
is something that uh my team actually
tried to
tackle years ago before um
anything was available you you're
talking about probably the most
available thing was just a commercial
solution that cost thousands and
thousands um
so what kind of like what's your um
advice for especially smaller teams i
know you mentioned
something like faults and that that is
quite monolithic and
and big maybe some might see it too big
for smaller projects do you know of
anything that maybe is
uh more applicable or more useful for
smaller projects and smaller teams
uh so if you are going with the secret
smartphone process there needs to be a
central place so in
most cases it's volta but if you want to
go the service route there's obviously
secrets manager there's a parameter
store as well with aws and
even at this point right now with github
you also have see the ability to add
secrets to the repository as well as
organization secrets themselves
so that does not really cost you
anything so you can add secrets there
and you could use something like github
actions to invoke those secrets without
ever having to worry about like
where to maintain them and everything so
if you have like some central
credences such as ssh keys to deploy
your code that could be an organization
level secret so that all repositories
under that organization have access to
that
and if it's a repo specific secret it
could go there and then it would also
again be used under the github actions
uh space ah fantastic concert awesome
super so some great feedback um awesome
talk
cool talk great talk um that's from the
people that are watching online
so very well done ayush uh thank you
very much for sharing your time with us
um and we're done thank you