okay we're back
and uh i'm delighted to introduce you to
dan khan
who's somebody we know really well been
involved in happy hour for many many
months
a really cool guy he's going to talk
today about
opsec and social engineering so dan
welcome over to you thanks um
thanks for joining my first ever talk
thanks to the beer farmers for giving me
this opportunity as well
my name's dan khan i'm currently
studying a master's in advanced security
and digital forensics at edinburgh
napier
um and i've been coding for about eight
years and if you want to get in touch my
handles are on the slides there
so before i start i'm just gonna warn
you there's gonna be some strong
language
and we will be talking about things of
an adult nature such as coercive actions
under violence
and drugs and nightclubs so there aren't
any graphic images around that
but i just want you to understand that
you know sometimes you can get triggered
just by hearing some of this stuff so if
you feel it's unsuitable now is the time
to kind of
um do you know find something else um
okay so throughout studies there have
been points where i've kind of thought
wow you know i've been doing this my
whole life and
i've never really known there was a term
for it and two of those things have been
opsec
and social engineering two awesome
definitions are on the slides
and to paraphrase social engineering is
a means to obtain confidential
information about a project
and it could be protected by opsec opsec
is short for operation security
um an upset method to the steps taken to
ensure information remains confidential
and secure
so the way i like to think about them
both is you know they don't have to be
both present for for the other to work
but they certainly can use to counter
each other if they're both present
in a in an attack or defense so
this all sounds really pretty serious
right i mean why would i have been using
this
or even needing this growing up right
well here's a little story
let's go back to the 90s it was a time
of huge cabinet super clubs like cream
the hacienda the ministry of sound
where djs would play to filled arenas
it's a time of brick pop and indie dance
where the happy mondays
stone roses and oasis would be mad for
it in manchester while blurs swade and
elastico were pretending to be cockneys
down south
laden led that culture combined with
cool britannia was everywhere
and that and it was embraced rightly or
wrongly
and then there's little kid me and i'm
i'm at the moment missing out on all the
fun
i i used to read dictionary front to
back i used to read technical manuals
like novels absorb books on science and
history
but i loved it um now i'm not shattering
any illusions here i hope but let's be
honest you don't have pictures like this
if you weren't a little bit nerdy am i
right
however this little angelic nerd love
dance music he grew up with it he would
listen to it on the radio because wish
he was part of it
um imagine what a nightclub was it
sounded so much fun in his head
so i convinced myself i was going to be
a dj write music for a living
be part of this culture i've got some
really cheap record decks on my birthday
i learned piano i practiced loads
yeah let's go one slight snack you've
got to be 18 to be in these nightclubs
and
although at this stage i'm a little bit
older than that photo
i'm only 12 or 13. so let's see how that
would have panned out right
excuse me can i come in i'm 18 i promise
not this decade son [ __ ] off and that
was the response i got from most places
i'm rightly so you know hearing this
from many places didn't deter me you
know as we all know when it comes to
attacks
you only need one weak link um just to
exploit
and you know eventually that was found
excuse me can i come in i'm 18 i promise
what's your star sign
aquarius yeah in indigo
the doorman let me in like now was this
a feat of social engineering mastery
like did i convince the target that my
squeaky voice and babyface
might have belonged to someone who was
18 or older no i'm pretty sure it wasn't
turns out in the 90s many pubs and clubs
really didn't care about ids or letting
in children to drink there there weren't
the hefty fines for certain
serving underage kids that there were
today all the health warnings
as long as you could confidently provide
a correct star sign not a date of birth
a star sign that never changes year to
year
uq could join in the fun yes and
wherever that i could i definitely
embraced that fun i kept flies as
mementos
that plastered my bedroom walls and i
still keep them to this day um you know
the first memories of kind of living a
semi-adult life and i absolutely loved
it
now this wasn't going to happen every
weekend right getting in at this young
age is very
much a trial and error process much like
many red team activities today
you know just because something worked
like last week doesn't mean it's going
to work today
yeah i had to use reconnaissance you
know what people were on the door that
night did they let me in last time
do they look like someone has annoyed
them tonight so are they going to let me
in today
you know reconnaissance has helped me
decide if an attempt was worth trying or
not
and even when you get into the place
after a period of time
you might get thrown out or barred more
because you've upset other patrons
and they're threatening to report the
public club you know if they didn't act
so
this takes us to a first lesson of being
environment aware
i was fortunate enough that my godfather
was a pub landlord
so i'd grown up in pubs from near enough
birth and
was able to study how people acted in
them yo how do you ask for a point
how do you avoid getting barred most
important in this situation how are you
going to raise suspicion that you might
be underage
so looking sheepish in a corner eyes
looking up hunched over
you know sipping tim and beyond a pine
that's going to get thrown out after a
couple of weeks if you can't
then give id you know generally people
don't look like that if they should be
in
in there you know conversely you might
think being a bit cocky
you know a little bit arrogant might be
indicative of a young 18 year old but
everyone's going to think
you know they're a bit of a dick so you
know they're going to want id just they
can throw you out
you know just just as looking like
stereotypical hacker
probably will not get you into a
corporate building looking at a place in
a pub
is likely to get you thrown out too so
it's a social engineer whether that be
an office worker or a pub landlord
you need to look like you should be
there but your clothes don't look out of
place for the surroundings whatever that
is
and that you have confidence but not
arrogant so people take a dislike to you
don't set off people's internal
intrusion detection
so pubs and clubs are not the only
environmental awareness
the only place environmental awareness
can help an online use is with sock
accounts
there are some really good soccer counts
and many are harmless in jovial like
this one scoop magruder made by mclaren
scoot mcgrudy never breaks character and
he's even got photographic evidence that
he's real and scott mcgrady's brother
right seriously from this picture you
definitely think they were brothers and
that's because the best socks they
assimilate well
they have a good story and they never
break character
unlike this one andyo34945816
which try to arrest my friend lisa forte
they would dip in or something nice and
then start getting really nasty you know
as time passed it turned out they were a
terrible soccer count because they broke
character so many times
you know well to be fair they didn't
have much character to break which was
equally hilarious
so we thought we'd give them a bit more
depth their character by giving them a
more interesting story than their
creator could actually manage
we decided that andy was 48 he was an
accountant
he was happily married and he lived in
their home counties he hated commuting
who doesn't right
but we also gave him a proper name
instead of andyo34945816
we gave him the dignity of being called
andy numbers
and this slide explains the full story
let's digress a bit it is quite funny
we were so unimpressed with the
creator's lack of character we gave andy
numbers a credible story that was more
challenging to us
so all their creator had to do was make
notes go along with it
and he even screwed that up every bout
and asking this he would then delete all
of his history as if he would forget
everything that had taken place and we
would too
and that would never screenshot their
antics for things like this right
i guess they thought you know we would
have a bout of amnesia if they deleted
all their twitter history because that's
how it works you know a bit like
children
you know that hide on the premise that
if they can't see you then you can't see
them either
well anyway lisa suggested we should
play around with what
he had to say to see if he can remember
what he actually had written
in the past so we chose the name for his
wife
sarah and lisa persuaded andy number
that that
that was his wife's name we then changed
the css of the webpage and screenshotted
it to then call his wife helen and
that's what you see in the top right
then we waited uh the creator white's
all around his history
you know after being a bit nasty and
then wanted to be friends again and as
you can see he had no clue
of what he should have been saying they
couldn't remember and in the end slipped
up
after we suggested that his wife was
helen and and gave him the what
screenshot
and then afterwards he tried to
backpedal in the bottom bottom left and
you know said
sarah was an ex he got confused i mean
who else forgets their wife's name for
crying out loud you know
you'd stick to your guns you know andy's
creator forgot the name of andy's wife
because he was just really sloppy
um so sloppy in fact that some more
awesome people joined us
and through some ocean work traced this
all to a man behind the sock account
who i can't say anymore but happens to
be a ciso which was
another interesting story anyhow back to
our story
i digress um a year passes
my 18 year old persona has been built
and my target is a public employees djs
you know i decided i should give a demo
tape there and why not they think i'm 18
or at least they pretend to right
let's do it i got my first gig
at a pretty rundown pub not as bad as
the one in the photo but not far off it
to be honest
um it was quite common to see a ball
from the pool table end up in someone's
face most nights i played there
and when i first played there i thought
it was a really cool thing that the dj
booth was in a cage but then i realized
quite quickly it wasn't just for show
when i was getting a drink out the cage
i got very used to kind of ducking let's
just put it that way
now after the pub shift ended i'd
obviously stopped djing all the staff
would go on maps to a nightclub
um and there was one i really wanted to
go to but i've been rejected so many
times
um and i didn't want to get turned away
in front of everyone in the pub
risked not being able to play there even
as terrible as it was
um so if they were going to this
particular club i'd normally make
excuses slope off
um but after a few times a day doing
this the bar manager insisted i joined
and you know it's one you can't really
get out of so
i'm going along i'm hoping it goes all
right but i'm really afraid that the end
of my music career
has happened before it's even started so
we turn up at the nightclub
the doormen are in suits they look
serious if they were a tech company to
paraphrase the beer farmers
they would not need to tell people that
they took security seriously
we get to the door it's our turn i'm
trying not to shake i'm trying not to
sweat i'm trying not to be sick
on his nice black shoes we just go in
and turns out the bar manager knows
everyone right they trust him
i'm now trusted like a rogue certificate
in a public key infrastructure
at a very high level public key
infrastructure pki
is a way that the user's public key is
bound to an organization
you have root certificate authorities
cas which are considered trusted
entities
and because of this trust they then act
as authoritative voices
on the bindings they're aware of so they
do this by checking organizations and
issuing digital
certificates as a bond of their trust in
an organization
in turn cas that aren't aware of the
bindings consult root cas or another ca
that's obtained information from them
to check the integrity of an
organization and you can have many
different route cas
and the most prevalent use of their
trust is with the little green padlock
in your favorite web browser
but the important things to remember are
that any ca can be a route ca just
because one was trustworthy today
doesn't even mean it's trustworthy
tomorrow
and some don't even check their facts
before they trust something and this
blind trust
is what caused the komodo pki hack in
which allowed an organic ruge
organization to pretend where
they were google mail hotmail or yahoo
mail and loads of others
yeah they poisoned the pki and in a
similar way i poisoned the pki
of a nightclub human key infrastructure
hki poisoning right
um i was purporting to be an
organization that was 18 years old and
eligible to work
the bar manager where i dj'd was a
trusted entity for many others so we'll
call him a root ca
but they hadn't verified the facts i
wasn't 18 and
asking for a passport or another way of
verifying would would have shown this
right
from the h cairo poisoning i gained the
trust of the promoter of the nightclub
it gives me a staffy ip card great more
authentication and credentials
the door staff and bar staff now accept
i'm 18 through the trust of the bar
manager and the promoter and going
forward if i got asked for id anywhere
i'll just go no i'm afraid not but i've
got one of these present the card walk
in
the promoter also suggests that i should
come to an open decks night and for the
pre-club bar
so we'll win that i'm now a resident dj
there great so we all live happily ever
after the story ends and you wonder why
i've spoken more and more about public
key infrastructure that i have on up
second social engineering
no not quite yet we're just getting
started to be honest let's continue
see things are actually all right for
quite a while 15 16 17 year old me was
happy that people bought my story
i was 19 20 21 now for them uh
whether or not it was truly the case i
don't know but at the same time
i believe that my secrets my upset was
was robust
i kept playing every saturday in the
pre-club bar and there was a lot more
friend it was a lot more friendly and
better paid than the rundown pub
um there was still a bit of violence but
door staff made me stop that and people
generally friendly i played my chains i
went clubbing afterwards
then i'd walk four miles home absolutely
plastered carrying a silver steel record
box filled with vinyl
mainly chosen as a part prop to let make
sure other security teams had let me
into their clubs even if i wasn't
playing there i'll just carry it around
i'm not gonna get home between five or
six in the morning
um quite young i swear um but s
some time passed and i started getting
regular people come to hear me dj people
shaking my hand at the end of sets
also starting to get my first mentions
in local paper club life sections like
this one
um other than the very sexist
descriptions of various female customers
the journalist writes about there is
another problem
i'm 17 and i'm still underage and things
suddenly change quite rapidly and
new threats start to emerge so whilst
things are very friendly in the pre-club
bar in the nightclub above most of the
time it's fine
but every now and again things would go
well let's just call it a little bit
strange
um and if anyone's heard the story of
the legendary cassie and the nightclub
in manchester
you'll know that for a long time it was
an amazing venue providing the best that
music of that time had to offer
and you'll also hear that it had to be
closed in 1997 due to rival drug dealers
often in gang stabbing shooting not only
each other
but people that work there and innocent
punters too um i never went there but
i'm friends with people that did
regularly
and they talk about such fondness but
also so much sadness of how it ended
um with our nightclub above it was a
pretty similar thing
you know you had two gangs mainly made
up of grown-up men 28 to 38 years old
which now i'm around that age i find so
bizarre it's unreal
um and they all had pretty truly
psychopathic tendencies you know for the
most part they're all
very polite and friendly however
underneath that smiling exterior
you can see in their eyes you never want
to really make them angry if you can
help it
it's a really chilly free feeling but i
can't really express but it's on the
present when they took speed to you
um and when they look at you and
sometimes they just torment people for
fun you know
uh one minute they're joking then they
turn on the sixpence screaming at
someone's face they've offended them
then going back to joking to them for
stupid thinking that then if a person
might crack a joke
to go back they might put their arm
around them they might glass them you
never knew
and it really wasn't nice it's a bit
like social media sometimes but with
physical pain too
so along with dj and the three club bar
i've now got a job
in the club on the lights great so for
the most part things are happy
but i also see some really horrific
things you know one gang member
knocks down this scrawny little kid half
their size stamps the head into some
huge metal studs like that um which hold
the building structure in place and you
know luckily
the kid survived but he's a really
broken way he never found out if he
fully recovered but
you know it's pretty horrific so i've
had to build another persona
with a bit more depth one that's a bit
more tougher that could handle himself
i also took up boxing you know carrying
100 records four miles every week
certainly helped build strength as well
um but i had to start thinking about
strategies from not set point where you
know if things go too bad
do i use my rekordbox as a weapon now
you know if i need to
you know really quite dark thoughts
and one day one of the gang members has
a great idea while i'm djing
hi dan oh you you dj you never get your
back checked do you
right well if i give you some things
like you can go past security and you
can just give him back to me when you're
out yeah
and at this point i feel sick so i know
what he means by things and yeah i don't
want to do this
i don't want to end up in prison yeah so
i think i give him diversions if i smile
from the dj booth like this
and pretend that i can't hear him then
hopefully he'll just go away
and that worked and that was good but he
came back
every week week after week um until one
day
you know i decided i finished playing i
go out to get some money out from a cash
board down the road
and i see him behind me and he comes out
danny boy
i [ __ ] hate being called danny boy
daddy boy
about this favor mate you gotta do it
mate i don't know what you're on about
danny boy you know and you better do it
because everybody needs a favor right
and you never know what's gonna happen
next mate like don't be a [ __ ]
so he's now pulled out a knife and it's
not waving it in my face
he doesn't need to he's just playing
with it see let me see how sharp it is
and smirk the omnipresent chilling ice
there
seeming to suckle strength from me so i
take a deep breath
i gulp and i look i just go to i really
want to help i can't
um if i get caught with that i'm i'm
absolutely screwed um
i don't want to go to prison i've got a
lot of respect for you so i'm not lying
to you
and i really hope you respect that but i
just can't do it and i'm really
really sorry and i'm shaking while i say
this i'm i'm not sure if i
i could be sick but i feel very much
like it and i feel so known
that i don't know what the rest of my
body's doing
so he looks up to me and he's not really
that happy at all and he just goes
don't worry danny boy i'm only playing
with you
now he wasn't or was he you know i'll
never know
um but my upset now had to strengthen me
even more you know it wasn't just
lying about my age it was making sure i
never owed him a favor
because he wants to call her back you
know if he brought me a drink
without me asking i'd get him one
straight back um
anything that he could argue was a favor
despite me not asking for it i'd make
sure that slate was clean by the end of
the night like a gamer cat and mouse
um i needed to protect myself from owing
anything and i'm very wary of it
with other people that i don't know even
now because you never know
yeah contrary to popular belief thanks
films
criminals sometimes don't have scars
they sometimes don't look evil
sometimes they don't even sound anything
like adam rickman
and they look perfectly pleasant they
try and trap you into a situation they
try and convince you that there's no
option but to comply
they try and socially engineer you and
you need counter strategies
to prevent that and this wasn't the only
worry either
you see oh see the legislation called
the licensing young persons act 2000
suddenly increases fines for underage
drinking to 5 000 pounds
per individual involved in the sale so
instead of just the landlord
everyone gets fined the government's
really serious at stopping underage
drinking you know
pub raids on pubs and clubs happen this
makes everyone know
everything's going to change you know
many young bar staff now personally
liable
can't take a risk at losing that much
money insist they're protected
the door staff start asking doors for
everyone you know
passport driver's license get the [ __ ]
out luckily
thanks to my social engineering human
key infrastructure poisoning my vip card
still holds as much weight as the
government document
yay well for now anyway you see
a new doorman joined the nightclub and
they wanted things verified that were
told to them they were a proper root ca
you know
they did not work on trusting others
they took it upon themselves to seek the
truth
oh no based on the review in the paper
the pre-club bar also got some flyers
printed with my name on it and we had
special guests
would do the early part of the night yo
with me following and i thought this was
great i loved it
you know but i i didn't think how it
could actually be used against me
and that's my actual name on there and
i'm under 18 and there aren't that many
people with the surname cod in the uk
let alone sussex
so as a way of highlighting how much of
an upset fail this was
yeah here's a listing from 192.com for
dan j cons that it's aware of in the uk
and now there's four sussex addresses on
there and they're all me
um by the way definitely look up
yourself on oneline2.com because even
though
i've opted out of the open register
therefore should have none of my details
given to a business
192.com kept the data of my addresses
before i opted out
and it tells you where i have lived
according to the electoral roll
and for a few pounds you can get some
credits and decide to get an in-depth
background report on someone that
provides all of their full addresses
along with convenient maps with the
rough value of each house
and who else loses them for a pivot you
know luckily
to delete your data from there it only
takes 24 hours
now 192.com didn't exist when our
detective doorman was refusing to
blindly trust our human key
infrastructure
instead we have the phone book you know
the phone book still exists it's a
register of everyone's name address and
landline number
providing a nyx directory uh now i'm not
in the phone book and i certainly wasn't
this time
so that's great opsec right well not in
this situation no
just to paint a scene i'm now two months
off my 18th birthday
lots of pubs and clubs are demanding id
i've lost quite a few gigs now with
security and now demanding it from
people that you know rock up to gigs
um and even my still silver record box
suggesting to them
that i'm playing they're not buying it
anymore they're still asking why would
they do that
you know it's harder for me to get a
drink now than what it was when i was
14.
the only places i can get served without
hassle the pre-club bar where my
residency is
and the club joined to it so i'm
panicked all the time that i will get
found out and lose even those gigs and
then everything you know
i want i'm i'm worried about gang
members that i'm avoiding trying not to
owe them a favor in case they want me to
pay them back
my opsec has taken absolute battering
and i'm getting desperate just two more
months keep this
persona going then you can play in other
clubs legally always going to be fine
anyway this detective dorman says it's
weird you know i really can't find khan
in the phone book
i was like oh really i've got to think
of a diversion
um yeah yeah really
well it's not weird really you know i
live with my parents like a lot of 21
year olds you know
yeah but you're also not on the
electoral roll you know i've looked
there as well
oh really how'd you do that that's
that's interesting i did not plan for
that
well that's that's because i don't vote
you know
i want to see your passport next week uh
well you see i
don't have a valid passport you know
i've got it sent off to get redeemed but
due to the backlog of the millennium
millennium book yeah
um i still haven't had it back so it's
stuck in newport gwent where the
password
passport office is and you know i'll try
and find them and nothing comes back you
know nothing
um now this story sounds as implausible
as an eye test in durham castle right
um there was a processing backlog at the
time and is there still at this point
you know me giving the passport office
location sounds like unnecessary
fact trying to divert and keep authority
to a pack of lies but
you know he's not being social
engineered he's seen that this is a pack
of lies detective dorman smirks you know
he's not buying it but
he humors me well when do you think
you're gonna get it back
um what well you know i'm not the
government you know um
i'd imagine that two months time two
months really
oh well it better be and that was that
you know the agreement was my passport
to come back in two months when i then
finally would be 18.
i'm still using diversion and personas
to socially engineer people to allow me
to stay playing
i'm still trying to keep my secrets safe
through my very fragile ops second just
hoping no one digs too deep at this
point
um so yes quite clearly mistakes made
but i think i did
pretty well keeping all this stuff under
wraps for three years
um i learned how to create personas and
adapt them to convince people to form
actions that they might not have wanted
to otherwise
i stayed confident but not arrogant um
well maybe not in the final year i mean
what 17 year old isn't is not arrogant
right
but anyway i've i forgot about freely
available information and i forgot to
factor that into my personas
um you know using open source
intelligent ocean to find information
about yourself and what you need to
delete or change
is is really important you know we we
also learned to create believable
characters my 21 year old persona was
probably not that believable
andy numbers definitely wasn't
believable um
but most importantly don't do crying you
know i'm glad i chose not to i would
have had my life ruined at 17.
um and i wouldn't be talking to you
today i'd either be in prison or maybe
dead
um and it might not seem that way but
there is always always another
option if you talk to people so before i
leave
uh you know i just like to say thanks
for everyone's listening thanks to all
the beer farmers and sponsors for
putting this on
um thanks for awesome mentos goons who
have worked tirelessly putting on zoom
prep chats giving advice where needed
um you know and also our fellow speakers
who have been backing each other up you
know
letting each other prep in that
mentoring thing as well it's been truly
awesome
yeah special thanks to lisa forte for
reading through my slide so many times
and giving me advice to supec for even
updating the quote that you saw earlier
from his from his article in 2017 to
make it more accurate and
providing some good advice to team
standard day and crafting for your
awesome support
during lockdown and also infosec happy
hour for that
um but most importantly to my family
and to my wifey life nina who allows me
to do things like this prepare for them
and push me every day
um if you want there's some further
reading
um these are all places you know either
blogs or yeah articles are really really
good um so i highly recommend them
thanks perfect dan
thank you very much really good again
a story you know and and that's really
what
what it's all about we're sharing your
adventures
and and you're okay some of the
adventures have been pretty
bloody scary um
yeah but yeah it's been absolutely
fantastic have we got any questions for
dan
none came through from the audience
everyone was just laughing constantly
all the little subtle humor hints and
stuff
um just from my point of view i and i
think mike's and ian's
um the people that were ex-musicians i
guess or current musicians and kind of
drifted into infosec for other reasons
yeah i we've been in the same position
man we've been right there i've been the
underage kid playing in a bar kicking
other underage kids out because i'm like
if you get busted they're gonna start
asking me for id
and yeah we've we've been there man like
the the pubs i played in were equally
rough and i think i've told you a few
stories and
you know we weren't paid in cash we were
paid in a box of beer and a bag of
you know that was that was the going
rate for a band and it was cheaper than
paying his cash but no i've a really
really
brilliant talk um there is questions now
coming in people have actually went oh
[ __ ] okay get the questions in before
you do the question scott um
you can't see this but i've got a scar
that's about an inch and a half long
on my inside of my elbow here i got that
in the hacienda
really yeah yeah um
be careful be careful when you knock
over somebody's drink this is a lesson
that i learned that night but yeah scott
questions
that's a yeah good piece of advice for
life really
um but yeah from juan he's asked what
strategies can you recommend for
strengthening your opsec
what would you recommend as a starting
point
i would say first stop would be going to
that upset
is for everyone not just people
something hide article and do pretty
much everything in there that she
kind of recommends you know but going
going through certainly just googling
stuff you know google docs would be your
best one
you know seeing what what is actually
out there on you
and deleting it okay but also you know
kind of
you know being a bit sensible with it
you know there are some times that
you're going to need
to have stuff about you online you know
if you
you know i've got people that i work
with for example who have absolutely
nothing online but then wonder why
they have nothing to show maybe if they
go for a job interview or
you know you've got to find a balance
which is you know that you're giving
some information out but you're not
necessarily giving your address i mean
certainly
if you're on instagram or something be
very weary you know
take photos inside by all means um
unless you're going to give them cyber
viking or rag but
um you know don't do them outside your
house because
um you know your hou you're outside your
house is very
unique a lot of the time and yeah people
can find you or certainly yeah
quite easily
oh thanks um that's all the questions
from
slag just there's a outpouring
twitch of people just going laughing at
various comments you made
um or absolutely agreeing and
and saying someone just said the trip by
article was very informative
um no honestly like i totally get it um
it's not difficult to find me it's not
difficult to find past music
relationships it bugs me i've just
learned to live with it
um luckily i've got a brooder who takes
most of the
flack now which is excellent but um no
dan that was excellent mike sean
do you want to jump in
great talk yeah absolutely and it's all
another thing i'll say is that
it's always great when you can draw a
parallel between things in normal
air quotes normal life and information
security
because it it brings a narrative in a
context that makes it a lot easier for
people to understand
because you didn't really talk about
infosec particularly apart from pki
the interesting point was the hki stuff
okay yeah and that's the bit where you
draw the line between
human behavior and their information
security and their and their opsec and
obviously in the social engineering
aspects of it so
down it was brilliant absolutely hats
off to you and
thank you very much thank you i'm gonna
go and get a beer now
enjoy