good afternoon again back
with elizabeth marmola and elizabeth's
going to talk about
a career thing which is super cool
she's going to talk to us about moving
from an admin role
into becoming a security security
professional at buggy pardon
so without further ado welcome elizabeth
and over to you hello everyone
my name is elizabeth and today i would
like to talk to you about my transition
from administrator to security analyst
the graduate apprentice program and why
is also
an awesome thing for employers so let's
start with who am i
first and most important of all i am a
graduate apprentice security analyst at
quorum cyber
i'm also a student at edinburgh napier
university currently doing my second
year of cyber security
and working towards my bachelor degree i
am a mom of two amazing kids that keep
me busy 24 7
and i am a proud owner of two fluffy
cats
and one crazy pup and a year and a half
ago
i was working as an administrator in the
public sector
now you might wonder why would i want to
give up a job
and start the learning process from the
beginning well
in my case i was looking for a stable
career the public sectors are under
constant reviews
looking to save as much money as
possible my department in our local
council was also undergoing these
reviews
which in practical terms meant that i
was on a fixed term contract
and every three months i would wait to
hear whether my contract got extended or
terminated
and when you have a family to support
that's not really an ideal situation
so you might ask why cyber security
in my previous job one of my many
responsibilities was making sure
offices in my team were gdpr compliant
doing financial investigations and
audits
and i really enjoyed that
problem-solving bit of my job
looking for those tiny cash
discrepancies that made
whole budget reconciliations just go
wrong and cyber security seemed like a
field
in a way related to that so i could
transfer some of those soft skills that
i gained in my previous positions
now my journey i guess started around
february 2018
at that time i got promoted to a senior
position still fixed
term and around the same time i joined
google audacity front and web developer
challenge
back then i didn't even know that the
graduate apprentice program existed
and i couldn't afford to just give up my
employment and study full-time
so doing online courses and challenges
like this one in my free time
seemed like the only way to get my feet
into it
and make a slow transition after
completing the challenge i was offered a
place
on the google nanodegree program and i
think back then it cost around 900
pounds to do it
and i was offered it for free so i was
thrilled
and i thought that this would be my
turning point
however due to a series of unfortunate
events
my job turned from full-time to
full-time times too
my manager went off sick long-term and
there was just no replacement
so part of the responsibilities was
shifted onto me
plus i became the first point of contact
for our seven offices across town
so i had to give up the nanodegree
program to cope with the workload
and at that point i just knew that if i
want to make the transition
i just need to jump into deep water i
had to find an entry level position
that would accept me as i was without
much knowledge and with zero experience
in the field
i started my search from the most
popular job sites
s1 jobs total jobs indeed only to find
that the positions closest to entry
level were either graduate or junior
now even though i didn't meet the
requirements i was still applying
hoping that maybe a recruiter would spot
me and take pity on me
and then i came across an apprentice
position
that was posted by qa apprentice
i can't remember what was the exact job
title it was something related to it
i've applied and a few days later i got
a phone call and i can remember the
excitement
i thought this is it i got an interview
someone noticed me
the lady on the phone said that they got
my application and they would
potentially be interested
but she needed to clarify one thing my
age
because looking at my cv it appeared
that i'm over 21
and that was my first pitfall um when i
started to question whether maybe it's
too late for me
to to do a career change i mean
is the age 21 an expiry date for a
person's career
despite that the discouragement i kept
looking
but this time i focused on the word
apprenticeship
i came across apprenticeship scott
website
and that's when i hit jackpot
apprenticeship scott
is a website that provides information
about the apprenticeship program in
scotland
and lists available jobs back in january
there wasn't much jobs in i.t and i have
extended my
search to include glasgow and five
and not just edinburgh where i'm based
and i think back then there was maybe
nine positions in it most of them
were software development related but
one caught my attention
it was a cyber security slash
infrastructure graduate apprentice
so after confirming that my polish
education was just as good as the
scottish a level exams
i got an interview as part of the
interview i had to do a logical test
and answer questions like would i be
able to assemble a pc
in may 2019 i got the job
the job turned out to be more
infrastructure based
but it was a great starting point to
learn about networking
and how it departments look from the
inside
in september 2019 i started my uni
there was only eight of us doing cyber
security as apprentices
and i was the only woman over half of
the people in my group
already had some sort of experience in
i.t
and they were just looking to boost up
their experience and gain some
theoretical knowledge about cyber
security
that was a bit intimidating and i think
that at that point i
understood that in order to be
successful i needed to learn a lot and i
needed to learn fast
i felt that my work just wasn't able to
provide me with that
my team was very small and extremely
busy and there
just wasn't enough time to provide me
with a structured training program
and i felt that it would be unfair to
ask for more
when people were stretched above and
beyond with their responsibilities
in january 2020 i attended a
cybersecurity event
organized by napier university the event
was organized
mainly for future graduates and it
offered an opportunity to learn more
about the market
and meet potential employers that's when
i first met quorum cyber
and to be specific that's when i first
met our managing director federico
who at the time was talking about
personal well-being in cyber security
during the break i took the opportunity
to approach every company
and see if they had any apprenticeship
openings
um quorum cyber was the first company
that i've approached um i went over to
federico
i've explained my story as briefly as
possible
and that was much briefer than what i'm
doing right now and
i've asked if they had any graduate
apprentice openings
uh i was asked to get in touch with bill
who is our
head of talent i sent over my cv with
a few words about me and my situation
and in february 2020
i was invited over for an interview so
at the interview it turned out that
quorum cyber did not have
any graduate apprentice job openings
they never ever
employed a graduate apprentice but i
think my story caught their attention
and they wanted to learn more about the
program and how it works
in april 2020 i officially became part
of corn cyber
but i think the story of remote
onboarding on
training of new employees during the
pandemic is a topic for another session
so what is graduate apprenticeship
basically
you work get faith and study at the same
time
it starts with you finding an employer
or working for an employer
who is willing to support your learning
the employer then fills in an
application
and sends it over to the university that
has
an appropriate graduate apprentice
program the application
isn't complicated it's just to confirm
your education
company details and personal details the
university then applies to the
government
to get the funds to pay for your
university fees
in scotland this is done through skills
development scotland
then at the end of every academical year
the university fills in a progress
report together with you
and your employer and returns it to the
government to keep the funds coming
a very important thing to remember is
that the funds
for your tuition fees are linked to you
as a person
not to your employer or to the
university
so at any point during your journey you
need to change universities or employers
it is possible assuming that the
university you're moving to
has a graduate apprentice program and is
willing to transfer you over
or if you're changing the employers
assuming that your new employer will
support you
and your learning process and will
provide you with a release from work
to complete your university studies
so how does the program work i've
mentioned that the employer needs to
release you
from work to complete the university
studies now the
apprentice program is designed so that
all of your university modules
are compressed into one day so
effectively the employer needs to
release you only one day per week for
you to go to university
however don't be fooled thinking that
it's only one day that you need to
complete your degree
on top of that you will need few hours
every week to read through material
or prepare for assessment review for
exams or code
the modules that consist of your program
will be different depending on what
university you're studying at
so cyber security at napier will have
a bit different modules compared to
glasgow university
now you might think how is it possible
that you're studying only one day per
week
and you get the same diploma as
full-time students
well the graduate apprentice program is
built
around the learning experience and in
order to make this work-based learning
experience valid
universities created modules like
professional practice
where you document and write reports on
what skills and what experience
you've learned in your workspace you
don't have to be a rookie to do it
as i've mentioned in my group there are
people who already had experience in it
and they were just looking to boost up
their skills there's also an option to
start your bachelor degree from second
year
or you can do your master's degree in an
apprentice mode with a one day release
to do your university work there is no
upper age limit
and i think that this photo taken during
a group work
last year at university gives a great
image of the gender
and age diversity
now as much as i love the graduate
apprentice program
and as much as i want to sell it to you
all i need to come clean about something
now you probably heard of a term
work-life balance
and in my head it looks something like
this installation of a tight wire walker
in my hometown now in my world ever
since i became a graduate apprentice
there is no such thing as balance
and i think this applies to most of
people in it in the current times
with so many things going on it's more
about
tuning in or tuning out different
aspects of my life
sacrificing free time to learn and i
mean there is a lot to learn
so what's in it for you i've talked
about the cons
the workloads the sacrifices that come
with the commitment
so now let's talk about the pros first
of all
you earn money you don't have to give up
your employment to do a full-time
university course
how much you earn will depend on your
level of experience
and will be set up by your employer it's
a great networking opportunity
you get a degree and a diploma and with
the diploma you also have
four years of working experience putting
you way ahead of full-time students
and you learn you learn a lot and even
if you already have experience in it
there will be still new things that this
program will teach you
now a bit about the link in the top
right corner
whether you're thinking of changing your
career path or
you're already in the process just as i
am you will have your ups and downs
and believe me when i tell you um from
my own experience
everyone gets their downs and their
doubts and
what you need then is a good pep talk
for me
it's this video from a ted conference
well
mel robbins talks about how to make
changes in your life happen
with her mantra being getting what you
want is simple it's not easy but it's
simple
now in my case it was as simple as
quitting my job and joining the
apprentice program
it wasn't easy but it was as simple as
that
now this part of my presentation is
directed to employers
i could bore you to death with
statistics
and if your brain is just like mine
you'll switch off and wake up at the end
of the presentation
and some of you will agree with the
statement that there is a skills gap in
cyber security
and some of you will strongly disagree
um
and say how easy it was to fill in cyber
security posts in your company
but i think we'll all agree with an
opinion that the cyber security industry
is still in its early stages and will
keep growing and expanding
with every new piece of software newly
developed technologies
and new laws like gdpr there comes an
immediate need for
cyber security solutions to prevent
cyber crime or
misuse of technologies or data so
creating entry-level positions
like graduate apprenticeship will allow
the industry
not to be only dependent on university
graduates fueling the market
must i also mention that employing an
apprentice will save you money
and you will help the economy by
allowing people
looking for a university degree to work
as an apprentice while studying
you put them in the tax system four
years earlier
than if they would study full-time
companies will be able to shape the
industry by allowing people such as
myself
to re-qualify the word sustainability
is very popular and trendy and i think
it should also be applied when we talk
about
job markets and creating opportunities
during my time of work in the public
sector i've heard people complaining on
numerous occasions about
how software and technologies leave
people without
jobs simply because automation makes the
processes easier to manage
by creating apprenticeship positions we
are being sustainable
we are allowing these people who might
become jobless or are jobless
because of technology or economical
changes
to re-qualify and utilize their very
valuable skill set
skill set that many freshly graduate
students will lack
maybe in the future it won't matter what
university you've finished
harvard or oxford or napier or mit
but what company trained you to become
who you are
this is the end of my presentation but
it's just the beginning of my journey
and cyber security
i hope you've enjoyed my story and maybe
it served as an inspiration for people
looking for a career change or
employers looking to expand their teams
or boost their employees skill set
to make this presentation even more
memorable i have prepared a joke
where did the hacker go he ran somewhere
i would also like to give many thanks to
the view farmers
for accepting me as a speaker and
providing me with this amazing
opportunity
a big thanks to all the mentors and
fellow speakers
for all the tips and help and for
creating this
amazing and supportive community a huge
thanks to my manager at quorum cyber
david mckenzie who gave me the idea for
this talk and made
me believe that i can do it infinite
thanks to porn cyber for taking me on
board and providing you with constant
opportunities to learn new things
and finally to my husband and my kids
for supporting me in my journey
for believing in me and and what i want
to achieve in my life
and for being so understanding whenever
i say
mommy's going to have a conference
please go with daddy to mcdonald's
if you would like to learn more about
the graduate apprentice program
please visit these websites listed
i will also check them into the slack
channel and on my linkedin and twitter
profile
the first two links provide information
about the apprenticeship program in
scotland the last
two about the apprenticeship program in
the rest of the uk
if you have any questions please feel
free to ask them now
or message me via linkedin or twitter
thank you
fabulous what a wonderful talk brilliant
and
you know it's great seeing a journey a
career path
you know from where you were and some of
the struggles and difficulties that you
had
into what appears to be very clearly a
much better place you
obviously very happy in your career your
life in general you're working for a
great organization
so yeah kudos to you for being able to
make that leap
um but keeping everything in perspective
as well at the same time so yeah very
well done there
do we get any questions uh
none on slack everybody's just saying
this is a really inspirational story
um one anonymous person though did say
as an employer of graduate apprentices
they are also driven
by the awesome people who give great
talks so
that came from an anonymous person no
idea who it was just don't share that
um but no i i have a quick comment on
well people are probably going oh let's
get the questions in there um
you mentioned that um others already had
a grounding or a qualification or some
sort of background in cyber security and
wanted to just
kind of get that piece of paper or that
background or that additional book
um but you obviously came at it from a
different angle
do you think that was advantageous to
you
whereas people were kind of stuck in
this mindset and you were kind of open
and just like a sponge taking everything
in
um it's it's difficult to say i mean
some of the people
for example had a networking background
and i think in cyber security
it's important to understand the traffic
flow of information
and it can make it easier to detect
stuff when you know how networks behave
and what's expected and what's not
expected um
for me everything is new so sometimes
there are subjects which
um the guys with the id background will
roll their eyes
and think oh my god we have to do this
or this is pointless to learn
programming or scripting and for me
everything is new and i want to just
inhale
everything that i can and learn
everything that i can
so i think the advantage of not coming
from an i.t background
is that everything's exciting for you
i i think that's that's that's really
nice though i mean can
for example the boring stuff that we
have to do day in day out it can get
quite monotonous but working alongside
someone that's like oh my
god this is so cool even if it's boring
to me like that would
really you know it could spur you on so
that's that's awesome i think
sean had a question yeah i i had one
um so scott kind of touched on this
in our opening remarks that the industry
is often seen as very toxic
you got gatekeepers and that and there
certainly are instances of that
i'm just wondering from your perspective
since you've come into the industry as
a new person and you don't
have that sort of background associated
with yourself
what's it been like for you have you had
any issues
um i think my biggest issue was just
putting my foot
in the door and getting this
first opportunity to to start the work
in it it's difficult when you don't have
any sort of i.t related background
or like a feasible
level of certificates or knowledge to
convince the employers that your soft
skills are valuable
and that you're willing to learn stuff
and
um i think that my background i mean i
worked in customer service i worked as
an admin i worked as an optical
assistant at one point in my life
and i think that all of that experience
uh
made me a good employee in a way because
like doing this talk
did not freak me out as much as it
probably would freak out
anyone else who didn't have any working
experience
i'm good with like sorting stuff and
organizing stuff and i
love looking for like you know
irregularities because of my background
um so i i also love
the the community and cyber security um
i mean when i was working as an admin we
didn't have these groups we didn't have
confidences where people talked about
you know
reconciliation of budgets uh but in
cyber security it seems that
those small communities are very lively
and
they're very welcoming at least from my
perspective
ah that's that's awesome um because so
often there's the negativity that drowns
out
the positivity and that to me at least
the negativity is only a small portion
just look at today there's huge amounts
of people involved
and it's just nothing but positivity so
it's really encouraging to hear that
so thank you 100 sure um
and i guess the last point i'd like to
make is that you are living proof
elizabeth
that people can make a success of a
career
from any background okay so you
we do often hear about people coming
into information security through
really interesting stories and yours is
equal to anybody's i've heard
and so well done to you and
congratulations and yeah
i hope your career flourishes so yeah
brilliant
um i think unless we've got any more
questions then
elizabeth thank you very much
on behalf of the bear farmers everybody
involved and the people watching
listening
thank you very much for your time thank
you very much have a nice day everyone
take care thank you
you