and we're back
um next up we've got gerard's who
is going to talk to us about the impact
of data breaches to insurance fraud
before he starts his talk though
massive massive beer farmers could us
and respect uh jarrah's been one of the
people that's working behind the scenes
to make sure you're all calm
make sure everybody's in the right place
at the right time collecting questions
helping out
um he's just been there since like
this week came up with this idea and
said yeah whatever you need
i'll help out so massive kudos because
you're also speaking
so massive happened to you for that
massive respect
take away gerard thanks for the intro
scott
um so my talk is entitled the impact of
data breaches to insurance front
just drawn back on my own past history
and
got my twitter handle there as well i
was inspired
for the talk um having started to nosey
around and infosec twitter
and seeing all the people complaining a
lot about data breaches but
all the talks never really went any
further than ah
gar you know evil data breaches um
but i got to see in my previous role i
am quite a lot of the things that kind
of happened to victims
and people where the data breaches
actually were applied
by criminals so i'm going to give you a
bit of an insight into that kind of
thing so we can
learn a bit from it together
um so who am i i was actually a
chemistry student um didn't
stumble in or graduating anything to do
with financial crime or fraud or
criminology or anything like that
i did a chemistry degree quite a few
years ago and finished up moved to the
uk
couldn't find work um because i managed
to plan it in 2008 when
everything went put in the world and
so ended up working customer services
insurance
large insurance company and moved around
there in within the same company and
eventually landed
in financial crime and investigating
application front
so not the crashing cars together but
more of the applications that are being
put in
um i do have a disclaimer i need to
start before
i go too much further please don't do
this at home or at work
or anywhere else for that matter i i
wasn't brave enough to put my
collaborates a little video in of
don't uh into this slide because i knew
i'd break my
my slides but please you know learn from
this
but learn it in order to save people and
so a couple of terms are going to throw
out um things like policies
brokers ncd a lot of you will drive
already some of you won't
i'm quite happy to answer any questions
you've got afterwards if i'm throwing
out a term that i haven't listed here
and no claims discount is one that we
see a lot of fraud on uh
because it's someone trying to obtain a
discount they're not entitled to
by falsifying documents if you drive a
car and you run a full gear without
actually running into anyone
and then they'll give you a discount for
the following year you can take to
another company
and a lot of people like to frequently
apply those and send them in and i think
one of the best ones i've seen is where
we looked at it opened up a document and
folded it out going the number of years
looks a little bit strange
and everyone laughed as we saw the
little bit of paper fall off the number
of years
because someone had just written down
the number of years on the document
glued it onto the page and sent it into
us hoping that we wouldn't notice but
they put it on the fold so
it just started to take itself off at
that point
um but that was a you do get to see some
rather interesting ones going around
and the abi a lot of the british
insurance all the immersion showers will
report into them um action fraud where
if you
say you've been a victim of fraud the to
the police the police will direct you on
for all to make the report and i also
reference cyphus as well who are uh
for prevention service in the united
kingdom and they do a lot of work
in putting a lot of information out
there to help victims of fraud as well
and that into the effect
um but to give you an idea what used
happened before data breaches
um because i managed to start financial
credit before
we started to see all these data
breaches going out we had the likes of
false rule addresses so
i'll use the uk as my examples because
that's where my experience is
for insurance where you live is very
important um
so a lot of the fraudsters in order to
make sure the prices were quite cheap
for an insurance policy
and would pick rural addresses so the
likes of aberdeen
inverness cornwall exeter i think the
worst i ever saw a house hit was
about 130 insurance policies taken out
at the one house in aberdeen
um which i felt rather sorry for the
person living there but unfortunately we
weren't able to put a stop for it
um but the reason they like to make sure
that the prices are really cheap for the
insurance is because
you see the sec point down is payment
fraud they're using stolen bank details
to actually put
the deposits in so if you're using a
stolen card you want it
to not hit any triggers of the banks so
you want to keep the payments as low as
possible coming out of it
and you also want to get more mileage
out of the cards so it will continue to
to be used as much as possible which
made sense for them to then target
the cheaper areas of the uk obviously to
keep things cheap
wouldn't tell anyone anything about
claims or convictions at all and you
know
i already told you you see a lot of
faults in the claims discounts
coming in or povs some people like to
call them as a proof of bonus
um but the main culprits for a lot of
the
organized fraud that we would see are
people called ghost brokers
you see the definition that the
insurance fraud bureau has thrown out
there
um defrosters few sellers sell drivers
cheap
apparently cheap motor insurance deals
but issue policies that aren't worth the
people around that is that is about as
spot
on as you can actually get with them and
they will go about
and buy their policies from a company
using false information
and before the likes of the data
breaches they would then docked into the
documents and hand them out to people
who
would see their names on the documents
and think oh everything's absolutely
fine
um with it i'm moving on but with the
oven the
bridges they they changed their their
act up a little bit and
the thing is why would someone actually
go and use one of these ghost brokers
it's not going to find them on the high
street you're not going to find them on
the normal websites at all
the reason comes down to pure costs and
a lot of people who are targeted are
young people
so you can see there the average cost of
car insurance for someone aged 20 to 24
so may have been driving for a couple
years
you're looking at over 900 pounds a year
for them and then if they're even a
slight bit younger someone coming into
their first car confuse.com reported
last year
that you were looking at nearly 2 000
pounds for someone who's 18 years old
to drive a car so that's that's going to
put them in quite a
you know a bit of a pickle how many 18
year olds are going to have that kind of
money to be able to pass out they may
have
spent all their money trying to get the
car that they wanted and they're going
to
really find a struggle to get the money
um
but the ghostbusters also target
vulnerable people so they'll turn
they'll be targeting the people who
may have moved to the country recently
where english won't be their first
language
so their reliance on contacts already
there
so you can we you see a lot of it in
communities
where people there was a lot of a
tight-knit community where someone was
held up as an
example of this is the person this is
the go-to person you want to get this
sorted
but what was actually happening is that
person was taking advantage of all these
these others and the the polish
community the north african community
people where they just didn't understand
the documents that were being shared in
front of them
but they were reliant on a community
member to support them and unfortunately
the wrong community member on occasion
would be the broker who's setting up
these policies
um they do obviously you know these
people are organized criminals
and so they do like to advertise
themselves they
got a couple of examples for you if just
taking quickly from
instagram and you can see what they're
looking for to lure people in
needing car insurance convicted driver's
insurance
and so people you are certainly get
insurance because maybe they've got a
drink driving conviction
um young drivers 17 plus and up to 50
not really sure what they're offering up
to 50 off but maybe you go to them with
a call
and they then go and try and get up to
down off as you can see in the last
example and those hashtags are
can lead you down a bit of a rabbit hole
if you start looking at them on
instagram by the way if you see all
these
all these dodgy people offering
insurance um
which lures people in uh logistics
insurance and cheap insurance are
two ones of well why are you using
instagram to go and find your car
insurance but you can find
quite a lot um on those and it can be
quite interesting to to track the people
you're tracking when you see them and
the policies coming into the business
you can then trace them back to seeing
the screenshots these people are sharing
of i've just paid for this policy for a
customer
um but given any other kind of numbers
we're not talking
small isolated cases and there was
nearly three quarters of a million
application fronts reported
to the association of british insurers
in 2019
now that can be anything from i believe
left
off a conviction that i've had in the
last five years be it going through me
of speeding
or you know being caught on my mobile
phone to living off claims
to be connected to organized crime being
post-brokering and having a faulty
policy set up
and but action fraud then are reporting
the year before the average cost
to a victim of ghost broker is you know
769 pounds so that's a victim handing
over
that kind of money on each case of it of
a ghost broker
um policy on average and sometimes they
could be more
because the vulnerable people you get
taken advantage of quite a lot i still
remember speaking to someone once
and they'd ended up handing over 1200
pounds because every time they wanted
the broker to correct the information of
the document they charged her 200 pounds
um to make a change through and people
do like to complain about
admin fees and insurance company being
20 or 30 pounds but
these people were charging fairly
serious amounts of cash to
to make their changes
but the government gave us a trial run
to dealing with people for identity
theft
because they freed the data one
company's house
so in june 2015 we started to see a rise
in identity fraud cases being passed
through us
from customer service and a lot of it k
actually came down to the fact that
this existed so there's a beta service
company's house any registered officer
in it
on a company you can now get their name
most of their date of birth
and their address which is great from a
fraud point of view that you can just
start impersonating people
and we started to see things ramp up
from there which um
give us a bit of a a taster of what was
actually to come
from a volume point of view and because
the fraudsters still have to go in and
pull that information off a
company's house but then we started to
see all the data breaches
coming through and all the information
getting shared like we've heard of all
the big ones the echo facts
talk talk british airways obviously
quite a giant one mom's net
flag facebook server because that was
one that when i was having a lot of
research
through i hadn't actually heard about
that particular one but it turned out
facebook had left an unprotected server
uh with no password on it and 18 million
british people's
information was left on the server and
you know how much people
tend to over share on facebook so
chances are there was a whole lot of
information that was uh
thrown up on there um which as a result
you know all that information went into
the ether a criminal
gets into the system and steals
everyone's personal information
they don't have the technology and the
the infrastructure
to actually deal and go any further with
the information they've stolen other
than to sell it on to other criminals
which is what
exactly what they do you then put that
into purpose
um being used for identity theft and all
sorts of
you know things can be applied for
mortgages mobile phones
my experiences and motor insurance
and so that will help delve into my
example keep my examples there but
it can be used for a multitude of of
reasons
um but the idea is well how much is
these payment details actually worth
so there was a study done a couple of
years ago and these are the up to date
figures
that privacy affairs have shared um
they did the work with cyphus back in
2018 to release a report
called rules at the end of the internet
which is definitely worth the read
um after beer con and having a look but
privacy affairs kept going with the
updates for the dark web price index
and those are the most recent figures
they have so you've got the likes of
mastercards and visas and american
expresses so you can buy
and you're not actually paying that much
for them and the one in the end is
probably one that you wouldn't have
come across as a term and that's a false
so that's someone's full identity
so they're saying that for forty two
dollars you can buy someone's complete
another identity and impersonate them
um which you know in the grand scheme of
things doesn't exactly put a whole lot
of value on someone
um so after the data breaches
we found that they were starting to
target local areas because
the ghost brokers who were setting up
these policies these organized people
were fighting a lot of complaints
from the folk that we're setting up
insurances for if you pretend to live in
aberdeen but you're
living in the likes of london the police
cottoned on quite quickly
to the fact that well if this car is
registered in aberdeen and i pull this
guy over because he's driving around the
northland and i'm going to have a little
chat
and and they hand over the driving
license the driving license is also in
north london
they're going to ask a lot more
questions whereas now they were offering
a service where
they were impersonating a local person
and
um having the having the person driving
around um using a stolen identity as the
policy ultrasound
this person is responsible for this and
again they kept with the same
the attacks they're still using paint
stolen payment details to
to pay for it and no information on
claims or convictions history for the
people who were driving in the cars
and there was a slight change with with
the false documents getting through
definitely noticed that there was a lot
more um utility bills and the like
were being provided through as as false
documentation from people who are
who are sending things into ourselves um
but to give you a proper visual of of
how it works and work in the example of
this kind of thing
so you get the likes of someone who's
recently moved to the country
and looking for mark just bought a car
alan he's young
he's needs some insurance to get himself
sorted so he does the right thing he
goes around looks online that is where
everyone says this is this is the
cheapest place to go
for your insurance um so he goes to sean
and sean from the national beer farmers
union
gives him price of two thousand pounds
for his insurance and
thinks right this is this is you know a
bit too much i'm
i can't i can't afford this at all so
honor later that night is he's having a
drink with his pal
because you you share your pals all your
stories and rag is just telling look
i i use this guy i found him online
instagram great guy scott insurance like
he's sorted me right out and go on to
him he'll you sort of give us a discount
um on on the details for what you're
having to pay and i don't think so
are you okay i can i can i can i can do
that let's see how much money he can
actually
and save me through um scott's not scott
scott school aim not not genuine
insurance at
all and scoot goes through the chat of
saying look
i've got this i've got this pal mike
mike can sort that your insurance he
knows
he he knows how hard it is for young
people he feels really bad insurance
companies are screwing you over
you know it's you know he will allow you
go on his insurance he'll keep the price
down because it's in his name
and you'll be sorted you can just strafe
her into police and anyone stops you
you know what michael sort that out you
just direct them one tell tell mike's
your uncle any you know they'll go
from there and they'll they'll leave you
be um so alan thanks god this is great
gets his insurance for three four
hundred pounds hands it over as a bank
transfer or even
in one case of affirmative met someone
in a railway car park and handed over
cash
and gets himself his documentation uh
mike's names on it but
alan doesn't mind because he's already
been told mike's mike's fully aware
it's absolutely fine um so that michael
sort anything out if there's been any
problems with the insurance
um but same this you know
has its like problems when you're
targeting local people
um alan gets into bother and he gets the
wrong
police officer who pulls him over and
goes you know what there's something not
quite right here
and in one case we actually had a police
officer phone us the morning after a
stop
where the in this example alan was taken
to mike's house
and left in the back of the car and
they've chapped the door of mike's house
and said mike
do you know this chap in the back of the
car to which mike obviously has
absolutely no idea because scoot has
bought mike's details off one of the
data breaches
and says no no i don't know this guy at
all
and that's how alan was was nicked for
impersonating someone as well as
the insurance fraud for the the false
information that was used
um now you do get the odd person who
does know that you know what i'm going
to look this gift i'm not going to look
this gift or something
there's something quite wrong um but i
won't ask any questions in that way i
can't lie
when i go through the details because we
did have someone once who
a month after we his insurance was
stopped for
be appearing on a policy where the
identity was stolen
insured themselves and their own name
sorted out themselves obviously
knew there was something dodgy but
decided right i'll go my own way but
when challenged on it the fact that well
actually your car and your name and your
details appeared
under under mike's insurance and mike's
already phoned in to say
he has no idea about this his identity's
been stolen
then tried to claim that they had no
idea how that possibly could have
happened because they'd never seen the
car
until the week before and that they'd
taken out our policy never mind the
month
before but when obviously pushed we're
kind of going well they had your name
your date of birth and
it's the car you're currently after
buying so the chances of that
actually happening are slim to
absolutely none
and but people will still chance it and
see what they can talk their way out of
um which is unfortunate but in a lot of
these cases it's
allen is also a victim as well someone
who's been he's been conned over
um so you do have quite a bit of falling
allen's obviously paid over
fake insurance he's also handed over his
personal information to a broker who's
now being paid and has gotten a new
identity he can use at a later date
to forgively impersonate alan and if the
insurance gets
stopped down all the contact details are
wrong on the insurance policy so
he could be hit with a fine of a
thousand pounds his car could be taken
off
and end up with six points in his
license which in the uk for the first
two years that could be your license
gone
and then having to reset your your your
test again
and so it could be quite problematic for
for young people and vulnerable people
who've
only just recently got their licenses as
well mike's obviously got the problem
but he's got unsolicited mail which
doesn't sound
that bad of uh it's just spam mail
coming through
but a lot of insurance companies
nowadays what they do is they don't
actually write down anymore
they do a lot of it online so the first
time that mike can find out that his
identity has been stolen
is actually when the police writes him
to say that alan's been speeding in his
car
and the penalty notices get sent to the
address that the
the insurance is set to um which is
obviously problematic and disturbing for
anyone as well obviously given the
confirmation as identity's been stolen
but if the policies aren't picked up
because sometimes they're not
um and they can get through the process
and set them up in a way that it doesn't
look
because if they've stolen all likes
details and everything matches
on the automated checks then you'll end
up with a case of
that might could find that that policy
is actually run for
a month or two months and the bank
details don't work anymore so then mike
actually then gets chased for the debts
that he's got
on his on the policy that he do nothing
about um
and that could be a rather upsetting one
where you get a bill in for from a
company that you've
possibly never heard of as well as um
for a policy you never to get the first
books
but that's only small fish this
that's only a site like for a lot of
these schools brokers who are setting up
policies
a lot of them well all of them are
criminals um but they will
all have links back to organized crime
um
and they're saying quite a lot of
activity goes on with regard to it
because
criminal gangs don't want their cars
being pulled over you know they want to
be able to travel
with ease without anyone bothering them
or asking them any pesky questions like
where do these people in the back of
your car come from why is there a back
of tools in the booth of the car and
you can see there's two the top two
points are transporting people and
people trafficking
there is a difference between the two
because the organized crime groups want
to be transporting
their staff we'll see around the around
the uk
um we know um from
law enforcement that they actually can
fly people that some organized groups
will fly people into the country
put them up in a hotel then have them
commit burglary or other crimes and then
fly them back out again
um the following day which makes it
quite difficult for them to actually
track these people down
i had a rather interesting case once
where someone whose
bank details have been used as well as
their identity they've been stolen
and we had a chat and they gave me the
the details so it could go phone their
bank to see if we could line up any
information
and kind of work together with regards
to like sharing
and which is what a lot of companies do
try and do and
the president of the bank started
laughing because the bank card that had
been used to set up the insurance policy
with ourselves
was also used to book a flight um from
the uk back to eastern europe and it
turned
out that as i was on the phone the
flight was due to land
um and gave him a little bit of a
chuckle when he was thinking about just
that one card was just absolutely hammer
there was takeaways on it they booked a
you hotel it's done all sorts with
regard to the details just almost keep
it as a single
enclosed case for it and but you can
only guess to what the person who was
flying back had actually been
transported over to the uk to actually
do
um with regards to people trafficking as
well it's it's quite ominous when you
get a phone call from the police and
it's it's from people trafficking and
child's exploitation because
they want to move people around an area
where the car show is insured
well when you're a criminal you're not
really going to use your own money to
pay for anything so you'll
you'll have someone else pay for it even
if they don't know they're doing it
um but in the uk as well there's
quite a big problem with the the drug
gangs in the large cities
moving drugs into the rural areas and as
you heard me say when the data breaches
came in they started the target local
areas
for their for the insurance policies
and what we actually found having spoken
to the police in
the kind of devon cornwall area was that
they were insuring the cars down there
to show us there but what they were
doing the car was doing was going to and
from that area and
london doing the transportation of the
drugs and moving them around the country
that way
um which is a quite a quite a way i did
get a call once where
someone says that car and you've got on
cover and think yeah yeah we've got that
we're just
about to get it off covering it's like i
wouldn't worry about it driving anywhere
we raided the house yesterday in london
and it's up on bricks
um and the front garden outside um which
was nice to know the car wouldn't be
involved in any accidents because that's
that's the last thing you want to hear
when you're when you're dealing with
these
someone's been hurt um that they've been
involved in an accident but it was nice
to know that the cars
was up on up on bricks
the thing is how can we help and the
insurance for our bureau
um run achieve link um
so you can if you've any concerns that
someone's committing any kind of
insurance from the uk
you can actually report it to them and
they take all that information and share
around the insurers
just in case something then tweaks for
someone that they can actually
have another human eye take a look over
and go right that you know that that's
worth another question
and and go through doesn't always lead
to anything but it's certainly worth
helping people because it will save save
everyone money in the long run
um but also tell two this is the whole
idea
you can see our two it's normally a
teacup when you're talking about tell
kelty the social media
campaign you know tell two over brew i
think it being the beer farmers and beer
con
it needs to be the the two fights tell
two friends
share the stories with them and let them
know um
how they can keep themselves uh wise
to any of the scams especially young
family members
um who might be starting or if you come
across someone who's just recently moved
to the uk
um and then moving on from um and just
you know keeping friends and family safe
as much as you can and
i've told several of you if you go and
tell two people each if we cut a few
lines out of the pyramid the idea is
that
one person tilts two and so on and that
person tells
two more and everyone tells two by 26 27
people don't we will be well in line to
tell everyone in the country
and how to keep an eye out for all these
scams that are out there
um so that brings me the end
i want to say thanks to the beer farmers
for letting me help out let me speak
and the mentors have been absolutely
incredible
over the last four to five weeks and the
amount of time they have actually spent
um mentoring everyone and spending the
time and the fellow speakers as well
everyone's just pulled together
and we're all rookie speakers and to do
it and everyone has just
hung out and um had an absolute laugh um
getting everything ready for it all um
sue
that is me all done want to follow up
with me hit me up in the slack or
you can follow me on twitter as well dds
jared
well listen thanks very much for that i
know uh
we we kind of met through your previous
um employment let's just leave it at
that i guess um i wasn't
sc insurance just want to point that out
and that's not how
but um no i i i thought it was really
good we
often get siloed it's kind of like
talking to james earlier
um you get siloed and you you look at
date breach or you look at a
hack or wannacry and you don't think
about you know
the people on the ground that are
actually seeing this stuff live
in person going i can literally track a
piece of data from here
and see how it's been used and it almost
has a blast radius it's not just one
victim it's like
five four or five victims around that um
have had a couple of questions in
um i'm gonna do just had a couple more
questions come flying in
uh first one is from sp coulson
uh who asked due to due to gdpr
uh we no longer have who has records on
domain names
um how has this impacted research and
incident analysis into fraud markets
if at all i don't have an answer for
that to be perfectly honest
and a lot of my previous role was i
essentially found the particular
policies um a lot of people
because i suppose what i was saying
about the vulnerable being targeted
and these ghost workers are being are
quite organized and doing everything a
lot through
through instagram and like and they
actually
kind of what's the best term for it they
um
they put the fear of god into the people
who buy policies from them
um you're going to trust if you've just
moved
to here see and you've been introduced
to someone
as a pillar of the community to be told
this is the person you go to to sort of
your problems
if i then phone you and say there's a
problem or somehow i managed to get hold
of you and say there's a problem with
your insurance
the person who's bought it for you has
done something wrong
yeah i immediately get your back up and
you defend the person
who's screwed you over which is a bit
unfortunate
and can be very difficult to break down
um
we had you know on occasion but it can
be quite
quite rare to actually convince these
people that you know what no all these
problems you're having isn't because i'm
the insurance company cancelling your
insurance your problem is is that you've
paid 600 points to someone in a car park
and you really shouldn't have done that
um to get your your details through
um but yeah the who is the who is stuff
we
did rarely rarely came across um being
able to track down the particular
websites in that um with regard to
how my job was quite siloed in that
fashion um
so it wasn't something that we
particularly sold often hopefully that
kind of starts to answer the question
for you sure
there are a couple more questions in
slack um do hang out
but um yes i can pick them up in slack
anyway for
running short then anyway sure um if
anybody has any more questions please
you know
directly message or or my friends like
but
um i just want to relay some of the
feedback from the twitch chat which is
uh
from angus i ricky talk my arse um
you smashed it
genuinely everybody's been smashing it
today and you've done no differently um
massive respect again i think sean mike
ian
john we all agree that you guys have
um you've had it rough because you've
been sitting in the green room all day
so you you see a lot more of what's
going on you know what the audience size
is you know what's going on and
that can be easy for you so again
massive respect
that was good cool thanks for having us
no worries