welcome back everyone
um we are lined up next with james hare
and he's going to talk all about
patching something
many of us on the beer farmers are very
passionate about so
take it away james hi i'm james hair
and uh let's get this action started
here
all right so i've worked in information
technology for about 20 years
um i started uh in 1997
working as a help desk guy for a
regional internet service provider
and worked my way up through a number of
positions
i now work as a systems management
expert
um primarily doing government
contracting
uh with federal and state governments
here in the united states
um i've done some uh consulting
with private business primarily in
government at this point
um when i am not patching systems i
try to do a lot of snowboarding uh
and then in the off season i like to
bicycle hike
and camp and since we're talking about
beer i really love
beer my favorite beer is an american
beer called
hedy topper from a little brewery called
the alchemist you ever get a chance to
go to vermont great spot in
stowe vermont
just to start off a little bit of an
idea of why we patch um
so one of the bigger ones for me just
looking at it is uh the maersk line
incident in 2017 uh this is a
a ransomware incident where they got hit
with the noctua ransomware
um and that ransomware made use of the
eternal blue exploit that was a
wonderful invention of the nsa
that was uh was disclosed by the shadow
brokers around march 2017 it was written
immediately patched by microsoft uh but
then even in june
2017 three months later we see it being
successfully exploited to cause over 300
million in losses
um it took down mayor's shipping i think
for two or three different two or three
days
so a very serious incident uh just last
year
uh baltimore city in maryland got hacked
with the exact same malware
exact same eternal blue uh exploit
uh the city ended up paying over 18
million dollars in remediation costs
and the the folks who who did the the
after-action audit
made it very clear that by not patching
their systems for over two years they
basically
left their door open to an attack by
just about anybody it didn't take a heck
of a lot of skill to use eternal blue
in may of 2019 to exploit a system
then finally we've had a real uptick in
ryuk ransomware attacks
in september and uh october of 2020.
uh one of the more recent ones here in
the united states was united health
services got hacked
uh they haven't really given a lot of
information but ryuk has previously used
uh ie and acrobat vulnerabilities that
were patched a very long time ago
so these incidents show that patching is
something that
that you know you got to do it you would
get caught with your pants down if you
don't
and when you open a support call with
just about any vendor one of the first
calls or
questions they're going to ask is are
you up to the current patch level so
it's something you need to pay attention
to
not just for these incidents but also
make your life easier if you need
support
the rate of vulnerabilities has been
increasing every single year
in 2017 there were six thousand four
hundred and
or sixteen there were six thousand four
hundred and forty seven cves
the next year the rate more than doubled
uh
and we've had steady increases each year
uh this year in october we already have
209 publicly disclosed cvs
so there's i i believe the number i read
two three years ago was
50 or more discovered a day obviously
that number has increased quite a bit
just looking in the windows world this
is the last three months
october 2020 cvv cbe
2020 16 898
this allows remote code execution just
by transmitting an
uh specially formed uh ibv6 packet
and that's present in every single
current release of windows 10
and windows server to uh 2019.
uh the 16 947 is an outlook bug
allowing for rce if you get a specially
crafted email
september 168.75
is an exchange flaw that allows for rce
with a now formed email i know a lot of
people aren't doing
uh their own exchange anymore thanks to
office 365 and other hosted services
but here we go if you've got if you're
hosting an email you might be
uh looking at this uh and then
uh 1210 is a sharepoint vulnerability
where
a uh specially crafted application
package could cause remote code
execution on your sharepoint server
and finally in august we had uh
20 1472 which was the zero login flaw
uh zero logon flaw which uh sounded
really interesting i haven't actually
seen any uh
information about it being exploited in
a while but you know another
issue where where authentication is
basically useless on a single
computer and finally uh this 2028
1380 is a flaw in internet explorer
which is still out there
still on every windows 10 computer and
this allows for rce when you
get to a uh it's a drive-by rc from any
web page
so the the it's not just that we have a
large number of vulnerabilities
they are very very serious allowing for
real code execution but
real serious problems especially when
chained
with a uh privilege escalation attack
uh you you can get a wormable uh malware
very easily with just a couple of these
vulnerabilities
so that's why we patch our systems
so the patch cycle at least as we do it
here uh
is really a three step process but each
step
is is going on continually the first
step is discovering where
we're identifying any new or old
vulnerabilities in our environment
we are assessing our inventory and
discussing our and discovering new
systems
and we're researching that inventory and
we're researching uh
what's out there uh patchwise to
determine what's needed to mitigate our
vulnerabilities
the second step is mitigating those
i think the most important part of this
step is actually
testing the patches before they're
deployed while microsoft and all the
other vendors make a real
honest effort to test every single thing
that's out there
your environment is going to be
different than their test environment
you may have custom line of business
applications they've never seen
so you need to make an effort to test
before you deploy to production
so you don't have issues cropping up
after patching because one of the
biggest issues i've run into
in getting systems patched on time is
business units requesting that
they'd not be patched at a certain time
because they're concerned that patching
is going to cause disruption
the only way that you can avoid that
issue
is to work with your people in ahead of
time so that they're not concerned about
patches causing issues
finally we need to report on how our
patching has gone we have to
verify that the mitigation steps have
gone properly but we also need to be
aware of how the process is gone so that
we can continually
improve our process we want to make sure
that we are delivering patches
as quickly as possible as accurately as
possible with as few
issues as possible and that means we are
continually looking
to improve our process going into a
little bit more detail about discovery
so in a perfect world every single
inventory record in your inventory
management system is going to link to a
specific user or business owner
um i have yet to work at any
organization where that's true for every
single asset
some do better than others but
for patching we need to know as much as
possible we want to know 99.999 or
whatever
so that we aren't running into systems
either road i.t assets or assets that
didn't get into our management system or
whatever
we want to make sure we know those so we
can use our existing data
uh you know we may have an active
directory implementation or other
directory implementation that gives us
data about
our our endpoints we may have antivirus
or other systems management tools that
will give us information about our
inventory
and then again we may have an inventory
management product
we want to make sure that all of those
existing data sources
agree on what's out in the uh in the
environment and we also want to make
sure
that all of those data sources are
updated as new assets come into the
environment
and then we also need to do active
discovery now in most cases whatever
management tool you're using
uh um maybe sccm uh titanium
hcl bigfix uh norton
there's so many different ones out there
that's one of the difficulties with this
talk
they're all going to have a similar
discovery process and that's going to be
usually some kind of pain sweep uh you
know
i use nmap a lot for discovery i've used
lansweeper
and and all the the commercial tools are
going to use a very similar
technique just pinging everything in the
network to try to detect systems
and then doing a little bit of detection
based on the response to try to detect
what an operating system is give you a
confidence
interval about that so that you can
determine what to do with any unmanaged
assets
the other thing we need to know is that
discovery is a constant process we're
not just doing it right before patching
we are continually discovering new
systems we're continually aware of
things in our environment
and we want to be sure that we're
communicating with other business units
who may be adding new pcs
who may be bringing on a new office so
that we're aware of those changes so
that we can be prepared to patch them
properly
so when we're doing our research the
first thing we have to do is have an
up-to-date patching status of the
systems in our environment
it's not as important these days with
windows 10 because microsoft now
delivers all of their patches in a
cumulative package
but we still need to know what's out
there we still need to know the patching
status and we need to know
especially with those cumulative updates
where we may have to deliver a one
gigabyte or larger update to a large
number of pcs
uh we may be engaged in vulnerability
scanning if you've got something like
tenable nessus
uh that information can also inform the
patching process
uh one thing i've run into in in some of
my engagements has been that
you may not necessarily be able to trust
your patch management
uh product entirely because it may not
be aware of all the dependencies
involved with a specific vulnerability
so you may find from a vulnerability
scanning
program that you do have an issue that
your patch management program
isn't actually uh identifying so we want
to make sure we're using all of our
inputs
we need to make sure that any remedial
patching is addressed as soon as
possible
those are your biggest problems you know
if we looked at the the baltimore city
a real remedial patching program might
have saved them from that issue
we need to remember that microsoft is
not the only source of vulnerability or
patching needs
uh adobe and google both release patches
uh on patch tuesday uh google chrome
very often uh has security bugs beyond
just
including adobe flash uh adobe flash
thankfully will be going away as of
uh december but um that's something we
you may need to actually keep in mind
that there are some users who may have
applications that still use
flash that have not been updated to
remove that flash component so another
thing you need to be aware of
while you are researching what's out
there is where you may
have to exclude systems from patching
where you may have to
to kind of apply a light glove
on on very important users or developers
who may need their systems in a very
stable condition so they don't run into
issues with their applications
and that's what we get to where it's
it's not just about what patches need to
be deployed
we need to know what business units need
a little bit extra
care when we're deploying patches we
need to know maintenance windows
we need to know uh practices in
individual business units if there's a
business unit where they tell everybody
turn off your computer on friday when
you leave the office
that's something you need to be aware of
if you're sending a patch package
uh over to that system while they're
gonna be turning their systems off
so you need to engage not just with the
the software tools but also
with your personal communications tools
reaching out to stakeholders reaching
out to everybody who's
involved in in this patching process so
that they are aware of what's going on
and so they feel like they have some
ownership of it because otherwise
if anything goes wrong they're going to
point the finger at you first even if it
has nothing to do with patching
the next step is testing
as i said earlier i think testing is
probably the most important part of your
deployment
just from a standpoint of keeping uh the
the
uh audience involved so to do this we
need to be aware
of where we need to do extra testing as
i was saying earlier are there
developers or other super
users that require specific
configurations i know
in one of my engagements we had
developers who
needed to have a specific version of the
jdk
or they couldn't do their job and we had
to
kind of tiptoe around them because
normally we wanted to update the jdk to
the
most recent version and that involved
setting up exclusion groups
communicating them and knowing when and
where they might be ready for an upgrade
so that we were making sure we didn't
disrupt their development activities
uh you need to be aware of any critical
line of business applications
uh you know just a week and a half ago
at an engagement
i found out that we had passed a system
with
a very important uh i believe it was a
critical bug for sharepoint
but that critical patch had broken a
line of business application
on that sharepoint server and we had to
pull it back very quickly we didn't even
know we
had sharepoint on that server because we
hadn't engaged
in the kind of research and testing we
needed to so we ran into a problem
is there a standard system image for
your enterprise
in most cases there should be so you
should have that and be testing against
that
now if you're capturing an image from a
vm well
you should have a copy of that vm so
that you can test against it
we need to be prepared to test as soon
as possible uh
microsoft releases their their patches i
i think it's 10
a.m pacific time which isn't really the
most convenient time for a lot of folks
um some of the management tools require
a little bit of time between
the patch release and their actual uh
deployment of the patch in their system
and obtaining them and
bigfix at least need that um so you may
need to
actually use whatever automatic patch
capability
your patch program has in order to run
that test
if it's if those patches are being
released outside of your normal business
hours which you know i
i assume one one pacific is is not
normal business hours
in the uk and then finally when we are
testing we need to make sure that the
systems
that are used in testing are assigned to
users that we can trust
to make a report of a problem and to
actually make a useful problem report
they don't all have to be i.t workers
but we want to make sure we're working
with people who
will actually test everything they're
supposed to do and will get back to us
if it's an issue
and finally the mitigation steps after
we've made sure that we're
we're safe we want to deploy them to our
production systems as quickly as
possible
when we're doing that we need to
consider bandwidth usage both within
our wide area network of our offices and
external network bandwidth
most of your patch management systems
are going to end up downloading stuff
into a central store and distributing it
but if you've got a smaller branch
office that that
is served by a t1 link or or something
even worse
you may need to consider that before you
do deployment to ensure
that there is a distribution point or
some kind of peer-to-peer patching
available at that location
we need to make sure that we communicate
to the users when patching is going to
occur
and what their responsibilities are we
need to let users know
we will be patching at this time please
log off save your work whatever you need
them to do if we're going to restart the
systems we need to let them know
because again the more we communicate
with the users the more we bring the
stakeholders into the process
the less problems we're going to have
down the line when
uh you know if we have an issue they're
ready to report it to us
and we're ready to work with them to fix
it
finally we need to work we once we've
done all of this patching
our endpoints should report back their
status and we should report that status
back to concerned business units
i know i've got a bunch of server
administrators that i send out a patch
and pat
uh status report every month they
probably never want read it but it's a
good way to make sure that they're aware
of what's
going on and and that everybody
is on the same page and then after we
finish our patching status report for
one month
that is our preliminary input into
discovery for the next month what
systems need to be patched
what their current patch status is and
then
you know where we're going as we move
forward
and so for process improvement this is
where we're looking at stuff like
if we've got a severe bottleneck where
we've got a business unit world where
all the systems are not receiving
patches in a timely manner
we need to research that talk to those
people uh either
make process or software changes to
support them to ensure that we're not
taking
a real long time to patch um if we have
business units with persistent patching
issues we need to speak to that those
business units and ensure that
uh their behavior is not causing those
issues as saying earlier you have some
instances
where uh even if you've communicated it
to everybody you may have an office
where people are told to turn the
computers off on friday night
and uh with this continuous
communication and
don't just warn users about patching we
need to be available for comments
afterwards
uh you need to be available not just for
comments about the patches but for
comments about the process so that
people feel
the door is open with the team and they
can work with you to make it work for
them
we need to follow up about special
requests if you've got developers very
important people
anything like that follow up with them
afterward to make sure whatever
software or process
changes you put in place actually worked
and you need to make sure as i said a
bunch of times
that all of our stakeholders are owners
of the process
because if the stakeholders are not
owners of the process
they will kick back and that's when you
end up having
one group that hasn't been patched for
six months and then all of a sudden
you're talking to the the security
incident manager about why that system
wasn't patched
and the real reason it wasn't patched
was because you hadn't built that trust
you hadn't gotten everybody involved in
the process and you weren't using
all the tools that are available to you
because one of the most important tools
available to us as information security
professionals
is communication we really do have to be
constantly communicating with the people
we're working with because otherwise
it's edicts from on high from folks they
don't know
instead of uh helpful suggestions from
colleagues they trust
so that's the basics
um if anybody's got questions i'll be
happy to answer them
i know this is a little bit conceptual
not as much talking about specific tools
that's mainly because i work with one
specific tool and i don't really want to
leave things
uh really really uh
tied to one tool i think the process is
the same regardless of what you're using
most of the tools offer the same basics
so uh really uh
any questions awesome talk james
um and you you spot on like to me
tools are only part of the thing a very
small part of the thing
in my opinion um it's the the culture
the process and all of that that forms
the biggest part of it
tools only just kind of fill in um in my
opinion
so there are yeah questions um the first
one about managing stuff that can't be
patched
um you know i've run into a couple of
instances
uh the first thing is making sure it's
properly documented just because that's
important from an auditing standpoint
um if you have a system that can't be
patched you need to have
every single exception in the world like
that completely documented
uh in line with whatever your internal
security procedures are
here in the states most of that stuff's
written by each company
so it depends a great deal
from a
software standpoint uh that is a device
that needs to be segregated from the
network as much as possible placed in a
a network segment where it can talk to
everything that it needs to and nothing
else
um and and the the other thing is to try
like heck to get rid of anything that
can't be patched because
uh that device is just waiting to be
made a zombie
and then with patch prioritizing um
again it's a little bit easier when
you're working in a in a government
space because uh the the i.t security
manager tells everybody what they're
gonna do
and they follow it so uh patching is the
priority that we want it to be
um we've had to fight sometimes to try
to get patches deployed a little bit
more quickly
but generally it's not a big deal of
getting uh everybody in line
um in private business
i found the easiest way to get other
business units
to accept the priority of patching
is really to force them to document any
exceptions from the patching policy
because if they want you to wait two
weeks well then they need to be the one
who
who uh demonstrates the business reason
and also the people who sign off on it
because in the end
then any any responsibility for
that decision to alter your patch pro
program
is on them not you because in the end
that's your only way you can really
cover your ass is making sure
that exceptions from security policy are
documented and
that somebody else signs that
documentation so it's not on your head
yeah i i totally agree so i did warn you
uh before we started i had a question um
so recently we we've seen
some articles i'm not going to go into
who or what
but there have been articles stating
that
maybe you shouldn't patch or at least
wait weeks
before you patch i think it's more from
a consumer point of view but i think
many can still read it in terms of a
certainly a smaller business
what are your thoughts on that um i mean
you've covered some topics but
what are your thoughts on those saying
that kind of thing
you know it's a challenging question um
working
in the government space there is
certainly
at least the perception that we are in a
much more active threat environment
um so there there is the impression that
things need to be out there quickly
um
you if you would ask me that question
this time last year i think
the answer would be a little bit
different uh because microsoft really
had some
some serious difficulties uh delivering
patches without
serious issues um basically from from
april till about august or or
september of last year um and
even with with very high level microsoft
support
um we were running into issues that that
were causing
significant problems in production i
remember one we had
uh over 1200 people who couldn't open
outlook because a patch had changed how
microsoft rendered uh a custom logo
in a password dialogue and that was
causing outlook to crash on us because
yeah a password dialogue should
definitely crash because an image
doesn't load properly
so um from a private business i don't
think there's really any security and
obscurity
um these guys who are sending out
phishing emails aren't really being
particularly
uh discriminate about it the
overall cost may be lower from a dollar
standpoint but it's still going to be
very disruptive
so as much as possible you should be
patching on
on the regular schedule that microsoft
is putting out
especially with with windows 10 because
uh if you patch each month you're you're
delivering a package that's about two
three hundred megabytes
uh if you patch a little bit
less uh then the deltas may not apply
and then you're delivering a cumulative
package
which for the 64-bit versions of of
windows 10
uh that can be i've seen some i believe
that we're over two gigabytes simply
because
you got every single dll for 32-bit
you've got every single dll for 64-bit
that's been updated since the original
uh release and with with some of the
like 1607 or or i think that's actually
eol
but like 1709 uh that's been out
in the wild for three years now so
that's three years of patches being
delivered in one huge package
so it's it really depends on your
organization but in almost all cases you
should be pushing
to get this stuff out as quickly as
possible yeah the
the way i view it is i'd much rather
have an issue
have full control over my data and
systems be able to roll back
versus something like travel x at the
beginning of the year you lost complete
control it's like a month
to try to regain control well microsoft
has made it challenging with delivering
everything in a single patch package for
windows i know
back in the past it was sometimes if you
had a
net package or something else that was
causing an issue you could hold that
back and that's not available anymore
but
it certainly is easier to manage so
it's trade-offs yeah um they're
really well put um yeah and i noticed
you just drawing do you
have anything to add or ask
i don't think it's really fair because i
did come in at sort of the cube part
of the questions as i was traveling
today on work and now i'm in
sunny ports uh hoax down
near bournemouth on the coast
okay um thank you james thanks for
a really informative talk um even to
someone like myself who's
knows how important patchiness but some
really good points on
um how to make patching better or the
process
of patching a lot more seamless and
less troubles arising so thank you
thank you for your time