HECO hotel welcome to the last day of
hacker hotel talking English interesting
talk networking 102 so please enjoy this
talk and give it up for the speaker
welcome everyone welcome on this will be
a networked hacking 102 I did the
session network hacking 101 during the
previous hacker hotel and a special
request of Dimitri I came back with yet
another talk about network protocols
network hacking and how protocols work
how they should work and what can be
done to abuse these protocols I want to
stress out beforehand it's for
educational purposes only if you abuse
the knowledge you learn here you're on
your own see how long this takes
well the good news is this talk is
scheduled for an hour and I don't have
enough material for that but I wasn't
hoping to fill it it this way excellent
I want to talk to you about heroes well
not these clowns of course no real
networking heroes who have you knows who
these two people are the one on the
right it was part of the pop quiz
yesterday so it that's heard X ray he's
obviously well known but lady on the
left anyone here familiar with it no
well the one on the right is Professor
Ezra Dexter inventor of the dextra
protocol used in Dexter algorithm used
in several networking protocols and the
lady on the left is a dear Perlman
inventor of spanning tree protocol the
reason I brought up these two persons is
because the spanning tree protocol and
for example OSPF are two widely young
widely known and used networking
protocols their open standards a lot of
fenders are implement these and I'm
going to talk to you a bit about span G
protocol and the open shortest path
first protocol I will give a brief
overview of these protocols what are
designed to do
and how they work this is not going to
be an in-depth session because we need
quite a lot of more time than one hour
but let's start with the basic scenario
you are on a campus with basic
networking in place the network's uses
open standards spanning tree protocol
open shortest path first and very basic
configuration what could possibly go
wrong a bit of history on spanning tree
protocol it's been around for quite a
while since 1990 it's a loop prevention
protocol what happens even Ethernet
frames get sent and bounces around and
around the thing with Ethernet it does
not have a time to live for any other
mechanism in place to make it die out
after a while it keeps on going so
that's why spanning tree protocol was
invented it's a loop prevention protocol
there are a number of standards that
basically perform this function there's
the basic spanning tree protocol it's
the rapid spanning tree protocol a
number of standards it works by building
a tree it elects a root bridge and then
builds the tree without any loops that
might cause Ethernet looping broadcast
storms and all sorts of nasty things the
way it does this it exchanges
information in the entire network will
searches BPD use bridge protocol data
units are exchanged to make sure that
every switch knows the best way to the
rule bridge and a single way to the root
bridge this is important to prevent the
loops and port Network port on the
switch can have multiple roles and
multiple names
there's the blocking listening learning
and forwarding that start with blocking
if the spanning tree protocol detects a
loop it can place a port in blocking
which means it does not transmit any
traffic but if for some reason and link
somewhere else fails it can put the port
in forwarding so besides being a Lu
prevention protocol it can also be used
to create some form of link redundancy
when connecting a new switch all ports
that are in blocking after a short while
and the time this is depends on the
protocol a full cycle with the original
spanning tree protocol can take up to 50
seconds when traveling to the other
implementation spanning tree for example
rapid spanning tree it brings it down to
about 6 seconds so it's quite a lot
faster convergence it listens it listens
for B videos it does not learn any MAC
addresses of any connected house it
listens to be produced to determine what
is going to be my report the shortest
way to the root bridge after a while it
goes to the learning step which means
it's still not going to forward traffic
it does learn about hosts in the villain
and if the topology allows it's going to
the forwarding state which is actually
actively going to forward traffic then
there are a number of ports roles the
root port a switch has only one report
which is the port that's always in
forwarding which is the shortest way to
the root bridge the port can also be in
designated state which means it's going
to in the going to be in the forwarding
state but it's not the shortest path
through a bridge then there's the
blocking state loop prevention
later implementations add a few morals
for example alternate route port which
means it's in blue locking but if the
primary port goes down that will roll
takes over this is quite a bit of boring
slide sorry about that but I have some
pictures which should make it a little
bit more clear first let's go to basic
connectivity where we have Alice who
wants to talk with Bob they're in the
same subnet and a couple of switches are
involved
Alice starts by sending an ARP I want to
send traffic to Bob I have is IP address
but not his MAC address so Ellis will
send a broadcast source by her own MAC
address of the network interface card in
your machine which arrives at the first
switch what happens the switch will
learn the MAC address of Alice it boots
it down Enzo MAC address table and says
this port on the Left I know that it's
connected to host Alice with this MAC
address it then looks at the destination
it's a broadcast it goes out of that
link and travels to switch to which in
turn does the same says okay I receive a
packet that's been sourced by the MAC
address of the machine of Alice it
learns the MAC address of the machine of
Alice and put its in its MAC address
table then it's broadcast it sends it
out over every port
it has except the one wing on which it
received the broadcast so all other
ports get broadcast except the link to
switch one it sends it out to Bob Bob
says hey this is my IP address here's my
MAC address it sends an ARP reply at the
moment the machine of Bob since the may
reply switch true will learn the MAC
address of the machine of Bob
it done knows hey this destination is I
know that it's the machine of Ellis I
know which port to send it out on it
sends it to switch one switch one says
okay this is destined for the machine of
Ellis I know this destination and sends
it out of the port connected to the
Machine of Ellis quite straightforward
but not very redundant what happens if
we add another link Alice sends out an
ARP same scenarios last time the switch
then sends the broadcast out over the
upper link to switch to and the lower
link to switch to if you don't have
spanning tree protocol what will happen
switch you will receive a broadcast
packet on the upper port it sends it out
on all other ports and so it sends it
out to Bob but also towards the lower
port the broadcast received on the lower
port gets sent out to every connected
port except the low port so that means
to Bob again and to the upper port in
effect one broadcast will keep
performing it if you keep running it
this way and one will keep running it
this way and that's only a single
broadcast there is relatively low
traffic volume on broadcasts but it does
not die out so if Alice connects to
three other machines there are six more
practice running in here
and if for example Alice is going to be
rebooted is going to forget about MAC
addresses they learn and don't you start
all over again the broadcasts here if
the links are not disrupted keep going
keep going keep going and you have a
broadcast storm on your hand
that's nasty because it will saturate
all the link it all CPUs like on the
switches and basically going to crash
your net
work it's usually not desired there are
a few ways around this one logical link
if you tell your switches there are two
physical links but they're going to act
as a single logical link if L is going
to send a broadcast switch one is going
to forward it over either of these two
links with switch two will forward these
links only over the side to Bob and not
back over the other link because it
treats it as a single logical link if in
this scenario spanning tree is activated
the first thing it will do is block one
of the ports for example this one here
on switch to the bottom link that will
also prevent a broadcast or or a loop
but you have only one usable link and
that's the same basic scenario she had
in this previous slide with just one
link so you add another cable and you
get nothing in return so adding bundling
these links into a single logical link
is going to improve your bandwidth and
your redundancy because if one of those
two physical links fail the logical link
stays up now let's go to a basic network
design this is what I call a collapsed
core we have two core switches and to
access switches the core switches are
interconnected and each each axis which
is connected to both core switches I
added two priorities for the root bridge
in the back of your bridge in spanning
tree protocol the lower value wins
so the upper-left score switch quo one
is going to be the root switch in case
something goes wrong with course which
we want to have a little say in who gets
the backup root bridge so that's why
the course rich stew has a priority just
that's just a bit higher than the other
one it's generally not a good idea to
have one of the excess witches wear
which are basically usually quite small
and not up to the task
to get these selected as a road bridge
since the default priority is 32,000
there's little to no chance that the
excess which will actually become a real
bridge now for the rolls
this is route bridge and all ports going
out of them are going to be in
forwarding state they're all going to be
designated ports each other switch will
have a root port which is also going to
be in forwarding stage which is the
shortest path to the root bridge and
then a number of ports are going to be
in blocking mode your prevention again
I've been going to switch if my wireless
if there's all things in essence this is
what it looks like on a physical side if
you take away the blocked ports this is
what you end up with no loops whatsoever
so that means if traffic is being sent
from access routes to to access which
one they're all going to go through the
bridge
what happens if you add another switch
we have a very curious hacker here who
is interested in traffic going through
one of the XS switches usually towards
the data sent towards the core switch so
it's going to plug in it's on switch
plug it into X sweetie 1 plug it into
access routes - with an evil lower
priority 0 the lowest value possible
then this will become the new routes
which what happens all traffic from XS
which - towards the place where you're
usually your routing is in the core
switches is passing through the hacker
switch which means you can intercept
traffic you can manipulate traffic you
can listen in on everything you can are
the first one to inject all sorts of
nasty things many in the middle attacks
stuff like that so if your target is on
access routes - you're done but since a
hacker is only in control of its own
switch and not the rest of the network
what happens if he was curious about
traffic on access which one how to solve
that well just add another switch make
the route it was taking a bit less
desirable than the previous scenario
it's still the new route bridge all
roles are distributed again with the
hacker switch ethanol bridge
and this will be the new topology all
traffic from access which one to words
the place for routing is on the core
switches now traverse a stacker switch
so we did not change any configuration
on the core switches index switches we
just editing two more switches something
to think about
a this does not matter what is on here
but the feel and this devices in vielen
this devices in all traffic now go
through here there are a few mitigating
measures possible what to do if you
manage the network how to prevent this
the first if think about this in the
design phase of your network implement
multi to see if a channel which
basically means I have two core switches
have two links going down to each axis
which but I want to treat them as a
logical link normally portugal's can
only be done between two switches that
means two chassis switches but there are
some tricks to make an uplink of a
single switch to up links to two
separate switches act as a single switch
multi shall see if a channel there's
also a technique called
route guard if you configure that on
your network if a switch receive a
better BP deals from another switch that
says I want to become routes which it
gets ignored and another technology 802
dot 1x which basically means everything
that gets connected to my network has to
be authenticated that can mean a PC a
printer an IP camera or another switch
if it's not no it's not going to be able
to access your network
there are also a few alternatives
spanning-tree
as we just saw is quite old and does not
have the fastest convergence 30 to 50
seconds is not uncommon it still happens
so a number of alternatives are thought
upped drill transparent interconnect of
lots of Link's so not the successors of
spanning tree protocol it actually uses
under the hood the Dijkstra algorithm as
well shortest path bridging another
standard that's also being used as a
successor or spanning tree and the
excellent and other an encapsulation
technique which uses a routing layer to
transport if in a traffic one of my
personal favorite training if you're
going to be managing a network you need
proper training otherwise you're going
to make a lot of mistakes which you
usually incur a lot of risks a lot of
impact a lot of downtime training is
really important to maybe to be to be
able to make a proper design and to be
able to troubleshoot a proper design
another one logging all network devices
in an enterprise environment are capable
of sending multiple types of logging
they can be SNMP traps it can be syslog
send them all to send to a central
collector and parse them whenever
something happens that's the best part
reading the logs if you are sending all
logs to a central repository but don't
do a thing with it you might as well not
be even be logging anything
and there's another nifty feature port
security bpdu guard which basically
means if you're expecting a host a PC or
a laptop or whatever connected to that
particular switch port and not another
switch you configure bpdu guard which
basically means if another switch for
example our hacker switch is connected
to the network it's going to send that
BPD use for the bridge selection we
talked about peer earlier
beep you got kicks in and blocks the
port it sets it's an error disabled to
make sure that's manual intervention
needed to prevent an officer out
switches being hooked up to the network
it's a rather effective way of
preventing this particular attack this
is the spanning tree part of the
presentation any questions so far anyone
awake still after the first part of the
presentation excellent excellent
now for the second part of the
presentation OSPF the open shortest path
first protocol it's a routing protocol
the previous protocol was purely a if
net frame based and routing protocol is
a bit higher on the OSI model it's about
IP routing it's an AGP it's an interior
gateway protocol basically means you use
it within a single domain if you're
responsible for a network it's a single
domain it's a link state protocol which
means that every router in the domain
knows about the entire network so every
route we're running out EF is going to
share its information about every single
link it sees each router builds his own
topology database and then calculates
the best route to each route there are a
few official RC requests for comments
from the IETF that described the
standard in detail every single router
knows about the entire area after it
gathers this information it's going to
run the shortest path first algorithm or
the Dijkstra algorithm to make sure it
actually elects the best route and adds
these two routes to its routing table
the best part it's a very scalable
protocol if you have 200 rooters in a
single domain OSPF is more than capable
of handling that it's a loop free
environment there's always a single best
path if that fails
the DEXA algorithm kicks in creates a
new best path and not a single time
there's a loop if you have to equal cost
routes to a thermal destination
it even has equal cost load balancing
implemented and there's a reasonably
fast convergence it's at Sears if it
sees an actual link going down the decks
algorithm kicks in at once if not it
usually takes about 30 seconds it's
configurable you can have it up to a sub
second level to detect a link failure
and it recalculates the area this is all
bit boring and a lot of text what does
it mean in practice
here's a handful Reuters what happens if
I have a host on connected to land a who
wants to talk to house connected to land
B what's the best route anyone going to
beat up route or the lower route anyone
the lower route so for me it's one two
three hops from here it's one two three
four ups so the lower one looks best
right
but what if these links are very low
bandwidth and this is okay abit network
then I think the upper route looks a bit
better a protocol needs a way to
determine the best route for OSPF it's
called cost you can configure the cost
for each single link but usually if you
don't configure anything to influence it
it's going to use the bandwidth of the
link to use as a cost for its
calculations here's a nice one what
should happen we have a router to here
which is connected to the server park
with a very familiar p address it runs a
DNS server connected to root of one
which is connected to client networks
this is just a small network here in
between connecting new - one two three -
and the client access as this one this
subnet here what should happen router
one knows of the link to router 2 and
the link to clients networks it sends
that information to route or to route
the two knows of its link to root of one
and the link to the server park and it
sends that information through to one so
both rooters know of all the networks
here in the picture
so here it is route 2 1 the left tutor
knows about the client learn the
connection to route or two and a server
long this one is directly connected this
one is directly connected and this one
is being learned through our PF routing
table fluidity to it knows about it's
directly connected link through to one
it knows about it's directly connected
route to the server park and it learned
through OSPF the client network
everything right so far right everyone
can configure OSPF it's not that hard
route or OSPF one we add a route ID it's
optional and we say network everything
is going to belong to this area this is
all this works trust me it's a very
basic configuration shove it in here and
it'll work networking is not that hard
what could happen
a hacker adds its own router connected
to the client that network with also the
eight eight eight eight IP address but
what is slightly smaller netmask this is
a 24-bit netmask this is a twenty five
bit net mask which basically means that
this network is half the size of that
network the hacker router also runs OSPF
what happens now the hacker Rooter will
connect to route 1 using SPF they will
exchange routing information and this
network will get added to routing
interface at the routing table so this
will be the new routing table on route
or 1 we still have the directly
connected client network we still have
the network to route or to
but now we have two eight eight eight
networks one with a 24-bit netmask
learned through the links to - later -
and one with 25 bit netmask leading to
the client at work usually Reuters look
for the best match in the routing table
to route traffic so for the IP address 8
8 8 8 it's going to look at the routing
table and say ok I have these two
networks in here but a 25 bit netmask
one is preferred because it's a better
match it's more precise it's more
specific so that will be the one that I
want to take the routing table on router
2 it knows about the client network
learn through OSPF it has the directly
connected link to Row 2 1 it has the
directly connected 24-bit netmask to the
8 network and it learned through OSPF
the 25 bit netmask network of 88 this is
really interesting route or 1 sorry Ruta
2 has the 8 8 8 8 address configured on
one of its own interfaces but still if
you do a trace route 2 8 8 8 8 it goes
through 2 1 & 2 the hacker router
because of the more specific netmask so
even though it's a local address is
going to send it out to one of its
interfaces away from itself
this basically means the hacker has now
control of IP address 8 8 8 8 for all
sorts of DNS nasty things
there are few mitigating measures how to
prevent this you can make sure that
every single OSPF packet gets a hash md5
has to make sure that the password you
are configuring on all the routers in
your domain match up and unauthorized
Reuters do not establish a neighbor
relationship and are not able to inject
false information into your network
another one you can configure OSPF in
links to be point-to-point it means it
only accepts a single neighbor and the
best one if you're not going to be
expecting a neighbor on a single
interface put it in passive that
basically means if you configure OSPF
the way we did within a large network
statement of zero zero zero everything
it means it's still going to advertise
the network but it's not going to
establish a neighbor relationship over a
specific network until you say it has to
do it if it's a passive interval default
it will not try to establish a neighbor
relationship over it any of its
interfaces but it's going to be a good
idea to allow it to be a built neighbor
relationship between root of 1 and root
or to another medicating measures we
already discussed this training make
sure you if you're managing a network
make sure gear train and the standard
protocols understand the configuration
understand the consequences of your
design be able to make a proper design
being able to implement a proper design
verify proper design and manage and
troubleshoot it and there's the logging
previous like previous one if a new
relationship is formed is going to show
up in your login if we're going to be
browsing through your logs on a daily
basis you're going to be spotted if
you're sure that there was no failure
and no plan maintenance and not anything
will you see a new neighbor relation
showing up you need to take action
in short this was a very very brief
overview of the spanning tree protocol
and the OSPF protocol
this was not an in-depth one in protocol
wise are there any questions so far it's
clear what sort of interesting I know
there's been quite a bit call for a next
hacker hotel do you want more of this I
see a number of people go talk to Dimity
no questions well here's the thing I
just showed you a few screens of for
example the routing tables I lapse all
these scenarios out and I brought the
stuff with me if everyone if anyone
wants to see this in a def in a real lab
with real equipment in the room below I
have this built out if people want to
see this we can do a live demonstration
yes
these protocols or these these protocols
are widely used and it's specific I'm
okay I'm a bit of a Cisco fanboy and
Cisco has a number of proprietary
protocols but the protocols I discussed
here are open standards used by every
vendor there is so purposely discussed
open standard protocols so it's every
vendor supports this and is able to run
this this is enterprise great networking
users spanning tree users OSPF there are
the protocols possible of course but
these two are widely used in fact it
within our own company we use this as
well about securing them not everyone
has skilled stuff unfortunately and I
just showed you if your basic standards
again for educational purposes only for
lab environments only but these attacks
do work that's where I'm willing to let
them be I have to build a labs built
below to show the configuration yes it's
there to like you see yes it's possible
to inject the root work with or without
adding the hacker devices it really
works this way so this is not
reconfiguring target devices this is not
affecting the target host this is just
manipulating the network in between to
get a house to do some certain stuff for
you so you don't touch the host you
don't touch the network he just use the
protocols what they were designed to do
for that's the parcel at best part of
these network hacks you're using
existing protocols you just let them
work for you
yes you mentioned to talk at the next
hacker hotel is it within the scope of
the work that you do to discuss the
differences between you mentioned Cisco
but the comparison between that and some
of the controversy around the Huawei
routers and dd-wrt and whether to go
with open-source router firmware and and
what the advantages of going with each
would be it's a broad question I know
basically there's quite a big amount of
politics involved in those discussions I
know for example I'm a Cisco van boy and
I don't deny that but I want to make
this talk interesting for everyone so I
chose open standards but every network
friend there has its own pros and cons
and it usually against to a level of
either politics or fanboy ISM of other
people I know a couple of people are
vehement unipi users and I don't see
that say that uniform or who I is a bad
network equipment there is controversial
and use of the talk of controversy
that's going to be a lot more politics
on a lot less technical I guess the I
realized that everybody has suspicions
about everybody else's home-built
routers is there a more objective
arbitrary way to measure the relative
security of these different types of
companies routers and the standards they
use and if you were to use that
equipment what steps could you - to help
make sure your network was secure with
them well that's a good question
I think there's multiple steps involved
first we have two protocols this can be
done by by design but usually especially
when we're looking at things like
encryption there's also standards
involved but it's usually not to the
algorithm that's vulnerable you
but it's the implementation that's
vulnerable and an assess Co
implementation of OSPF is going to be
slightly different from a Juniper
implementation of our spear is going to
be slightly different from huawei
implementation of OSPF it's usually not
the protocol that's vulnerable its it
may be the implementation and the
security measures I showed here they're
part of the protocol and are basically
implemented everywhere roughly the same
so this is it I can make a workshop of
how to secure these but what I just did
the basics for both pantry and OSPF I'm
not sure I'm going to be able to fill an
entire workshop on securing Network
protocols so in that regard if you you
know given the crowd that you're
addressing today many people would be
very mean able already to open standard
type of router firmware and other things
do you think that it would be
appropriate for you to give and sort of
out an introduction to securing router
is using dd-wrt for example if it's out
of the scope of what you do in your job
then then that's okay that's the basis
of my question I don't know many
Enterprise who do use a dd-wrt for their
enterprise networks but the securing
part of the network of the protocols is
yeah as part of the the work I do but
securing specific implementations and
that's going to make it less interesting
very quickly for a larger group and the
group is not that big to begin with it
might have something to do with Lausanne
it's pop quiz but I'm not sure it's
going to be interesting if I do a
workshop on how to secure w/e dd-wrt I
can look into it
okay thank you I think I think my my
further questions can be addressed if
you have the equipment downstairs I'd
love to see your demonstration any other
questions and I would like to thank you
all for attending and have an awesome
day
[Applause]