[Music]
well like I would say today we are still
using this this transaction channels but
the question is would all be in the next
decades
well in banking history we witnessed
several several serious crisis when
people were asking if banks are gonna
stay alive and it's or it's the whole
industry will go down first of the big
crisis was in 1825 in the UK where 70
banks failed
of course Great Depression of course
World War of course the I would say the
whole second of the last century and
mortgage crisis in 2008 as well well and
it's it brings me to the next thing I
would like to talk about and it's a
development of recent financial sector
the recent financial sector has been
shaped by several very important changes
in the last 100 years because banks as
we know them had to face a big
competition from non-banking financial
services these non-banking financial
services institutions providing
non-banking financial services benefits
especially from lower level of
regulation this links to this links them
to higher profitability of their
products with high risk but rational
ignorant customers are not able to
evaluate risk and benefits as we know
and of course more flexibility in
implemented changes this
process is called disintermediation
disintermediation of the banking
services
well the process of disintermediation
had taken place since 1850 and in the
year in this year like few few guys in
UK start to think that it's not
necessary to have a bank written on your
house to provide similar services like
banks so what is disintermediation
disintermediation
means a loss of sovereign position of
banks in the financial intermediary
their meaning and weight have decreased
banks have lost their position as a
institution number one where people go
to deal with financial services this
loss influenced traditional business
model because banks lived from interest
margin credit versus debit interest and
at the rise of competition enables to
implement to the banking business model
something which we know until today and
it's called fee fees and competition
fees and commissions you know what I
mean fees like for transaction
Commission as a provision from
transaction we can divide this
disintermediation phase this
disintermediation whole period into four
phases in first phase of
disintermediation client bank deposits
where we draw by investment
mutual funds pension funds and life
insurance funds we can say that these
financial funds were compete with banks
and traditional banking products for
people's well this non banking
institutions provide products with more
flexibility left level or less level of
state control more anonymous product
products and more attractive interest
rates and this process correlates with
another process regulative process where
central banks in all countries begin to
regulate banks plot the second phase is
very similar because on the financial
markets households and especially firms
have more and more opportunities how to
acquire funds to finance their
activities I'm speaking especially about
IP IPOs initial public offer where firms
started to offer shares in their
companies on the second primary and
secondary market and that was a great
substitute of of the standard banking
loan for for firm banks suffered under
the increasing volume of regulation
supervision and like a lot of changes
especially related to something which is
called consumer protection you know that
I'm talking about and also
special laws securing banking stability
less regulated financial institutions
develop new products of course with
attractive risk and return ratios and at
the the banks were pushed into the
positions that they're there in interest
margin as well as interest income
started to decrease dramatically so they
the in this second phase we are talking
about a special soup process which is
called diversification and this
diversification means that these fees
and commissions was a stable item in the
pricing strategies of banks and it
started in the second phase the first
third phases linked especially to
technological progress and this national
technological progress and breakthrough
the wider like enables more and more
subjects to compete with banks you don't
you didn't need billion dollars to
establish something which could provide
loans or financial consultations etc etc
and the technological progress I'm
seeing especially about telephoning
about online banking and online services
definitely influence the fact that banks
are led to the fact that banks lost
their bank branch network advantage
banks has like quite high level of
overhead overhead costs related to
branch branches and branch network
this operational costs like from 70 to
80% related to cash and I think that you
have to sukira cash you have to collect
cash you have to like you have to secure
that all branches will have enough cash
for their clients and which means that
this overhead overhead costs are rising
and rising but since the third until the
front face of disintermediation process
the branch network was a great advantage
of banks with the technological progress
and rise of telephones and online this
advantage was lost so the third phase is
related to technological innovations and
the fourth phase is related to online
and Internet arise is the enduring the
fourth phase the technologies definitely
changes the distributional channels when
selling financial products products and
enables very small subjects - I would
say copy and paste results of big
banking investments well this is a
picture which like illustrates the whole
process of disintermediation in the u.s.
the picture the graph pictures shares of
financial institutions at the whole US
financial sector assets
it's a in percentage this is the
commercial banks share this black column
is comments with a commercial dialects
here
since 1862 1993 and we can see that
there is a substantial decrease of the
rate of assets US households and firms
has in having commercial banks on the
other hand we can see that saving
companies insurance companies investment
companies and pension funds especially
these pension funds like rising their
their position on the financial markets
and this the this process illustrates
the the disintermediation process on one
picture
this is Czech Republic and we can say
that in the Czech Republic the process
is quite different
yeah because assets in commercial banks
are very stable yeah you see the
difference and the question is why and
the answer is I can hint you the the
correct answer because I can use the two
things two words D system and M system
there is a pretty big difference between
between the organism organization of
industry in financial sector we have two
kinds of them B system is the system
with strong banks banks are like
monopolies or oligopolist banks provide
most of financial services both banks
have
natural ability to charge mantra more
transactions and employ people easy to
mount multiple clients because people
are used to come to bank deal with the
financial transactions if you need
anything with money you go just to the
bank
the another system is AM system AM
system or managed system is pretty
different
because banking houses are subject to
level a higher level of competition
there are pension funds there are
investment companies there are saving
companies there are hedge funds there
are like many of them and people used to
like diamond various services from these
various institutions that there is a big
ratio of diversification in in in this
system of course we can illustrate it on
the easy graph here is a Czech Republic
and Czech Republic as well as other
post-soviet countries could be quite
mentioned as classic B system system
financial system with strong banks and
with high relation of clients demanding
various services from banking on the
other hand we have for example Finland
Finland is a strong M system because
less than 20% of households assets are
held in commercial banks this is the
this is this this blue blue light blue
is like part
of the wealth held in shares and
investment infants etc etc and you can
see that the ratio is pretty different I
have yeah this is the another picture
providing the very similar very similar
conclusion investment and fun shares of
households as a part of GDP and as you
can see this red red columns
this is Hungary Czech Republic Poland
and Slovak Republic so we wish a grab
for all post-soviet countries and very
very low level of investments of
households these green columns are
countries of Western Europe I am I know
that it's very small letters there so
this is Belgium Germany Italy Austria
and France and what I'm just wanted to
say is that in the traditional banking
business models analyzes it's very very
important to think in what kind of
system are you just active if are you
activists if am system you will you have
to be ready or high level of competition
from non-banking financial services and
if you will implement and your pricing
strategy you have to think about one
conclusion that fees and commissions are
necessary for you to stay alive if you
will do your financial business in
be systems like integral public slovakia
etc your pricing strategy will of course
implement fees and commissions like
non-interest non interested returns but
this will be a premium for you and I
will show you this this table I'm sure
it's in check I didn't have enough time
to translate it into English but it's
pretty easy
this is Czech Republic this is Germany
and this is Austria these are like big
biggest three banks in every individual
country so in Czech Republic it is
Cheska's putana
chess uber and commercial banker in
Germany is Deutsche Bank Commerce Bank
and Banking Group cafe in Austria
it is our state group Bank Austria and
earns a big group this is the net profit
in 2011 and 2012 in millions sorry in
yeah in millions of national currency so
like for Cheska's potala here is like
thirteen point five billion Czech crowns
four point three billion euros etc on
the at the second section we have the
same profit deducted by fees and
commissions so if you will like just
drop your fees and commissions to the
zero what will happen in Czech Republic
quite nothing of course your net profit
will be significantly lower but no of
this free biggest bank
will lost their profit without fees and
commissions and profit of all of them
will be higher than billion Czech crowns
with zero fees and through Commission's
to the whole to the all banking clients
it is pretty impressive if you do the
same for the German banks you can see
that dirty bank with a profit 4.3
billion euros in 2011 will would go to
the lost
- 7.2 billion euros - 11 in the next
year - 2.7 - 3.0 the only the only
exception is this bank do you know this
bank no it's a state-owned Bank like
saving company I would say the Roosters
Elsner of chess COO and it is
characterized by like I would say non
market implementing of pricing
strategies yeah this this Bank is like
significantly cheaper than others
because it's like stayin owned in
Austria it is very similar to these two
examples like all these banks will would
go from profits to loss or from loss to
much more bigger loss
this is decrease of the profit and
percentage which is which are pretty
huge numbers and it could like show us I
will I'll talk about conclusion later
but it could show us how
our traditional banking models Bill's
traditional banking models are built
differently in two types of countries in
which country in in first group of
countries which could be called B
countries of B system countries the
banking business model contents of
interest income and non-interest income
this non-interest income is a profit
premium in M systems the traditional
business model contents also two types
of income interest and non interest but
this non-interest income is like break
even income this income which help your
institution to go from red numbers to
black numbers let's see another picture
with is like time line of banking items
in in Czech Republic and sorry in France
and in Austria
I have no Czech Republic on this graph
but which is very interesting this is
the share of net interest income and
share of net non-interest income to the
assets this is net interest net
non-interest fish and commissions and as
we can see the share of interest income
I mean the interest margin which is
traditionally historically the only and
core business business
I would say business and thinking about
them
the right word and eternity no never
mind like let's say that that
interesting come were the only only
business business model item like since
the third phase of disintermediation and
in last decades significantly winds down
non-interest income fees and Commission
significantly goes up in France you can
see that even non-interest income is
much more much more important than
interest one yeah
these crafts we already saw this table
is pretty similar to the graph I showed
10 minutes before I would say household
investing activity as a part of GDP in
the red column retina of red color we
see Czech Republic Hungary Poland and
Slovakia with numbers like thirty five
sixty sixty sixty one there are seventy
to ninety eight ninety three ninety one
hundred and twenty one hundred and five
one hundred and twenty one in the Czech
Republic and we have Western countries
like 345 332 180 200 260 290 I mean that
it proves also that the investing
activity is much more higher in M
systems than in
systems well and now about the FinTech
will the fifth phase of the
disintermediation happen I am saying
definitely yes it will
and we witnessed the fifth phase right
now because the relation between
financial technologies people with
experiences from banks and ability to
provide file faster and cheaper services
conclude - the only thing which is the
rise of FinTech FinTech I am pretty sure
you are familiar with this blend of
words financial technology is
progressive industry with providing
disruptive innovations to the banking
industry
why because users of FinTech are b2b b2b
for non financial entities b2c for
consumers and of of course consumer to
consumer platforms you wanna make a
photo well google trends analysis and
two words to you Turner's FinTech which
is blue and driverless cars or Altona
most cars in rats and we can see that
the bubble under the word fin tag it's
much more higher than bubble after
but bubble realizes two driverless cars
well let's briefly see the top ten
finding startups in 2016 okay I will
have felt like two slides yeah this
these are top ten finding startups in
eight out of this ten are related to
services providing by banks social
finance refinancing student loans bill
guard detecting bank charges controller
consumer spending
so financial consultations square
processing small card transactions
robotic investments consulting portfolio
management online trading peer-to-peer
lending payment system that use mobile
applications to scan the cards
application that enables creditors to
effectively manage receivables
investment into growing companies before
I pose possibility to finance specially
special projects in in public space I
mean those are literally fields that
banks have a monopoly in last decades
but they are losing them they their
their positions FinTech business models
is based cashless and facing traditional
financial financial services as I said
because thin tech business model have
five very special items it is definitely
low costs it has emphasis of innovation
combined with know-how of founders many
founders have some experience from
banking
under the lower level of regulation
significantly lower level of regulation
and of course driven by investment
bubble which is related to any any
industry which is like very medially and
and financially attractive in a brief
comparison of these two business models
we can see the very clear advantages of
FinTech it lies on line needs no
branches has very small overheads some
global companies have more than sorry
less than 50 employees so in comparison
with banks there is a significant
difference and FinTech companies
implemented very efficient very
efficient pricing like payment per
transaction complement income strategic
partnerships which is pretty different
in comparison with banks so to make a
conclusion I think that traditional
banking is over or gonna be over because
these FinTech business models will take
a part of the traditional banks banks
are like banks in M system have no space
to cover the loss with fees and
commissions bank banks in B systems have
some space so the change will take a
longer time here but we are leading to
the FinTech world with cashless society
and I will just
I will lose few words about this this
idea which is very provocative here in
this room when I said cashless society I
mean like society without cash like we
know it today fiat money cash cashless
is not fiat money cashless but cashless
means like with digital money and these
digital money could be crypto digital
money I don't mind and III believe it
will happen but this revolution will
change our wallets no not our thinking
economic theory says that cash demands
motives are free transaction one gaseous
medium exchange precautionary one Cash's
tool to cover unexpected situations and
speculative one cash weights risk
resulting from ownership of other
financial assets like diversification of
risk and this FinTech solutions can
cover any of these free motifs so that's
I mean that internet in integration of
FinTech ideas is completely digital and
it will company spontaneously squeezes
out cash transactions from the market
because this is not regulated regulatory
based but this is market oriented
revolution so that's that's just I
promise that I will I will cover off
also the the topic cash flow so that's
why here right now yeah that's pretty
pretty end for me and I'm open to your
questions or comments of course
[Music]
thank you thank you very much for your
speech and I would like to have the
first question to you okay you were
talking about the beat system and about
M system I want to ask you what do you
think it's behind it it's religious like
that
some of the countries are just rich so
the households can can afford to to
borrow money or do you think there are
even some other influences which
determines if the country is in the NP
system or M system yeah this is this is
a good point and smart point because if
you have no money you can invest no
money no money of course but I did
research on this field and I found quite
strong correlation between factor
post-soviet like Eastern European
country and B system which led me to the
fact that this 50 or 40 years we lost
under the communism with only one state
bank and with no experience with the
like financial diversification of your
household portfolio has a significant
effect here and we have to add another
thing that in 1990s where we got the
freedom to invest many of households
were I would say misled by some like bad
bangs but coupons bad shares because
they had no no information and their
first experience with investment what
was totally bad so that's why like
biggest three banks in the Czech
Republic's have I would say 2/3 of
household assets on their accounts so if
I understand it
it's probably more about mentality than
about having money yeah I would say
thank you this is thick now if somebody
have a question I will give the
microphone that is also extreme
opportunity for vendek's yeah like to
write about that for me personally
that's one of the reasons i co-found
FinTech company which provides prepaid
payment cards to the public and combine
it with bluetooth low energy
technologies like beacons you know
because this location based analytics
and location-based services combined
with approach on the banking information
which will provide PSD to and with
people holding your payment it's a big
opportunity for Fortis fintechs and I
had several talks with several banking
managers and they they they are very
afraid of PSD to if you talk to any
owner to FinTech company
these people are extremely happy yeah so
this is the reason of one of this
research FinTech report and it says that
like 73 of bankers fear that FinTech
will dominate consumer banking 73 of
high top top managers of banks 89 of
banks want to integrate some FinTech
companies into their business structure
and 73 of bankers think that FinTech is
the opportunity to reduce their costs
yeah
so 32 banks are planning to invest into
FinTech companies so I mean this all
like
provides the the to put long story short
yes PSD to will be extremely opportunity
for FinTech and it will be a big punch
to traditional business model model
issue
P neva t.o.p neva t.o.p know what 0p no
RTO is a company providing this payment
cards and retail track is the company
oriented on the on the location based
analytics and location-based services
yeah you talk about the cashless payment
at the end or do you think that will
work out do you think that the bank will
agree on another money that will be for
example a Bitcoin you think that that
can work out to rate or not yeah I lose
power you know they will lose power if I
understand clearly if the Bitcoin and
other cryptocurrencies will suit to my
like prognosis of digital society right
yeah absolutely yes when I mean when
when when I said that I am believing in
digital cashless society I said that I
believe that all these all these three
all these smart smart people and all
these hundreds of investors investing
hundreds of billions dollars every year
will make the change happen because it's
a market oriented but I am pretty sure
that all these companies are ready to
implement any crypto or digital currency
into their business because it's just
it's just a matter of demand and supply
so I'm definitely like pro Bitcoin and
fro
all other cryptocurrencies and I think
that this will definitely take place in
the digital revolution we are witness
what strikes me is that for example if
you take the GP Morgan CEO uh-huh
it's saying that bitcoin is shitty let's
say but on the other hand is really
investing into crypto currency or crypto
blockchain projects so you know it's
like on one hand they want to invest
into FinTech but on the other hand they
don't want to lose the controller on the
money well I'm I I don't know what would
this guy said but I know and other
bankers in digital public and in Germany
for example they are saying like shitty
things about Bitcoin and
cryptocurrencies but they own their own
like crypto money and they just saying
it on purpose because yeah because like
the their business and their positions
are related to traditional banking and
every year you will you will stay alive
in this top position it could like mean
substantial income for your for the next
generation let's say so I would say that
many of these many of these
like speeches are on purpose and the
system will change the mind like this
when when the time come well I wanted to
already end it but here is one last
question so I will just ask you for a
really fast question and a really fast
answer it was the next talker come fast
answer on the regulators I think also
connected to the bit coin and crypto
coins like in the UK they are providing
some kind of sandbox where where they
can get in touch with the fintechs and
adopting chemical relations like I like
maybe now right regulators regulars in
the UK for example are providing some
kind of sandbox and hon there's talks
about that in Sweden too uh-huh talking
to finances bakunin they have a wish
provide a sandbox okay to invite
fintechs and adopt two cryptocurrencies
and getting a dialogue on the issues and
the question is if this same happy
Republic yeah yeah I'm like I was
attended several events like this and I
must say that like for example my fin
tech company and I know that also other
fin tech companies are not very happy to
come to these events because in one such
even there were a problem with with with
know-how and with like in NDA
and like one bank starts to develop our
product because we just presented the
product on the
like this so I would say that many
fintechs we'll just go separately and go
in touch with with banks or other
institutions
just in case the stay away from the
sandbox yeah yeah yeah and that product
is when one product is in marketing so
it's okay but but in the face of like
seed capital it's better to keep it just
in your head or in your computer I would
say okay thank you very much thank you
very much for your speech and have a
nice day everybody
[Applause]