okay so today I'm gonna talk a bit about
this peer-to-peer decentralized Bitcoin
exchange so how many are familiar with
bisque
how many would say they're very familiar
with bisque yeah maybe they just don't
want to say right so I'm gonna talk
about what bisque is why it exists why
did we build it how it works and before
I do that lets me hi so I my background
isn't in cryptography it isn't in
distributed systems my background is in
enterprise software development building
open source libraries and toolkits and
frameworks primarily for the Java
ecosystem on the JVM right and bisque is
a java application that's one of the
things that first attracted me to it
back in
well 2013 and so on when I was falling
down the rabbit hole with Bitcoin like
probably all of us have here in 2014 I
heard about this project to build a
decentralized peer-to-peer application
in Java
bisque right which was at the time known
as bit square so I got involved then and
I've been one way or another involved
ever since
in the meantime by the way I've also
spent a lot of time with larger open
source organizations helping to helping
to organize how they work write
distributed teams working all over the
world so lots of work with you know
github processes and so on and that
background has kind of fed into how
we've designed this Dao so we'll hear
lots more about that in a moment ok so
what is bisque bisque is often described
as a decentralized or a peer-to-peer
Bitcoin exchange and that's all true but
because there are many ways to design
such a system and because those words
like decentralization can mean different
things to different people it's better
to describe bisque in terms of its
component parts so first bisque is a
cross-platform desktop application it
allows anybody to buy and sell Bitcoin
in exchange for national currencies and
for other crypto currencies second it's
a trading protocol that allows
individuals to exchange to
rectly with one another over the
internet without you know eliminating
the need for trusted third parties
exchange services etc thirdly it's a
peer-to-peer network formed when bisque
applications discover connect to and
work with each other to implement the
best protocol and that network is fully
peer-to-peer in the sense that there's
no centralized no centrally control
servers there's no single points of
failure so all together bisque is a
desktop application a trading protocol
and a peer-to-peer network they all work
together to form a decentralized
exchange and finally bisque is free
software it's all licensed under the a
GPL and bisque is just software right
there's no company there's no startup
there's no foundation
it's just code in a github repository
and a github organization with
individual people collaborating together
to build it that's it it's becoming a
Dao right we'll see what that's all
about a decentralized autonomous
organization for anybody who doesn't
know the acronym we'll get to that in a
moment
why why did we build it why does bisque
exist
well bisques mission is to provide a
secure private and sensed and censorship
resistant way to exchange Bitcoin for
national currencies and other crypto
currencies over the Internet right every
one of those words matter there are lots
of ways to exchange Bitcoin in person
and over the internet that are not
decentralized or less private or less
secure etc but those words can mean
different things to different people -
so let's define them right when we say
secure we're talking about the safety of
users funds today most Bitcoin exchanges
are centralized and that requires users
to store their Bitcoin for at least some
amount of time on the exchange server
and when thousands of users are doing
this simultaneously that creates extreme
incentives for those servers to be
hacked for those bitcoins to be stolen
and we all know the greatest hits here
it happens time and time
and time again right every year for the
last five years at least we've had major
hacks with otherwise trusted exchanges
right the beatings will continue so
private by private we mean you control
your own information so we're referring
to users ability to control access to
their own data
today most centralized exchanges require
you to create an account to divulge
personally identifying information with
that exchange and in turn those
exchanges then link your trading
activity to that identity right this
practice creates extreme risks - risks
that your personal details your
financial information will be stolen
leaked or otherwise used against your
own best interests alright we need look
no further than the last couple of
months for examples right Equifax 143
oops hundred and forty five million
people's data breached every single
yahoo account if 3 billion people's
information at risk probably a lot of us
know this story right
the IRS issue the so-called John Doe
summons to coinbase asking for all of
the information about all of the users
on coinbase from 2013 to 2015 and
fortunately that's getting worked back
you know but this is exactly what's at
stake right when we give up our personal
information ok and when we say
censorship resistant we're talking about
users ability to voluntarily trade with
one another without interference from a
third party today centralized Bitcoin
exchanges are highly susceptible to such
censorship not because they're bad guys
right but because by their nature they
have to they have to operate within some
legal jurisdiction and that puts them at
risk of being fined or shut down if they
don't comply those those restrictions
those regulations tend to include
restrictions on who can trade what can
be traded and almost always require
include requirements to collect personal
information
as we described earlier right so we need
to look no further than recent news
about China to see what that can look
like when by Fiat exchanges get shut
down or told what to do it's usually not
so over the top right that's you know
you must stop doing business but much
more often it's more subtle right you
have to collect this much more
information or something that users
don't necessarily see or care about so
that's why we built this right to
provide to provide that functionality in
the world private secure censorship
resistant trading of Bitcoin for
national currencies here's how it works
let's say imagine you want to buy
Bitcoin in exchange for US dollars in
Bitcoin in this terminology you're a
buyer right Bitcoin in exchange for US
dollars so in this terminology you're a
buyer of Bitcoin looking for a seller of
Bitcoin who will accept US dollars as
payment if you were going to complete a
trade like that using bisk you'd follow
a series of steps similar to these all
right you download this you'd run it on
your computer
you'd configure bisque with your payment
details now this is not registering your
personal information with a centralized
service this is putting information into
bisque where it's only going to be
sitting on your computer encrypted write
about ways that you can pay in u.s.
dollars in this case right so you have
an okay pay account or you have a Zell
account or whatever it may be that's
going to be information that's necessary
for your counterparty to know so that it
when you're paying them for their
Bitcoin they can verify okay that came
from the correct
zel accounts or whatever it may be all
right so you'd configure disk you'd then
browse bisques offer book looking for
other sell offers that have already been
created by sellers who already want to
sell you a Bitcoin and then maybe you
take
their offers you could also place your
own offer to buy but let's say there's
an offer to sell that you're happy with
so you take their offer to sell let's
say 0.5 of their Bitcoin for yeah point
five of their Bitcoin for say 2000 of
Euro dollars so then and this is the
part where you see my slightly
incomplete slide deck that I was
finishing right up until the last moment
but never mind that it works just as
well so you would then send those
dollars from whatever account it is that
you have right Zell in this case or okay
pay or some bank transfer or wire
transfer or whatever it is and then in
bisque you would click the payments
initiated button you tell your this
client I started the payments on the
other side the seller is going to get
notified of that the seller is going to
say okay your counterparty said that
they initiated payment let's wait until
the payment arrives waiting right
however long Zell takes or however long
a wire transfer takes some payment
systems like faster payments in the UK
are pretty fast right might happen in a
in ours right some are really slow might
take days but that's your choice you and
your counterparty how you want to do the
payment right so we wait however long it
takes the seller then receives your USD
right and then clicks payment received
and bisque at which point you receive
the sellers bitcoin right so here's how
it might be obvious how bisque is
different already
right but bisque is quite different than
trading on a centralized exchange so
here's some of the ways right no
automatic order magic on a centralized
exchange just login you say I want to
buy a half a Bitcoin and it's done right
and that half a Bitcoin might have come
from any number of of you know
counterparties being sliced and diced
and chopped up centralized exchanges
have lots of functionality if they're
available to them to make things quick
and efficient and fast and all of that
but that's not the way this works right
no automatic order matching like we saw
you find is there an order I want to
take okay I'll take it from that person
from that counterparty or you place your
own so in this way it's really
peer-to-peer right you're directly
exchanging with somebody else bisque is
just facilitating the two of you meeting
so the protocol coordinates out-of-band
fiat payments there's no magic right
bisque isn't somehow making fiat
payments work like blockchains it's a
protocol that coordinates the steps that
human beings need to take to interface
with legacy systems and talk to banks
right so there's no magic and settlement
takes longer then on a centralized
exchange but in return trading is far
more secure far more private and far
more censorship resistant then you would
get otherwise
so how so right this helps keep your
funds secure in several ways one it's
entirely non-custodial with regard to
both crypto and fiat there's two of
three multi-sig escrow with the third
key held by an arbitrator so you have a
key to that Bitcoin multi transaction
that holds your Bitcoin your
counterparty has a key and an arbitrator
has a key
your arbitrator won't have anything to
do with that trade unless something goes
wrong can't see any information has no
custody over anything the happy path is
that when the seller clicks I receive
the buyers payment that multi-sig
transaction is paid out because this
coordinates your two keys working
together to sign it right finally like I
mentioned the multi-sig escrow with the
third key held by an arbitrator and
there is a complete decentralized
arbitration system in place to handle
those disputes okay so how do we keep it
private that's how we keep your funds
secure how do we keep your data private
one
there's no registration no identity
verification so there's simply less data
to keep private in the first place right
- every bisque application is a tor
hidden service so bisques peer-to-peer
network sits on top of
to our network and every best client is
a tor hidden service third there's no
central servers no databases to record
data we couldn't even record the data if
we tried because all the data on the
peer-to-peer network is encrypted not
just by tor but the messages themselves
are encrypted to your counterparties
public key right to your counterparties
tor service public key so how this helps
you resist censorship now one a fully
decentralized even properly distributed
p2p network to our peer-to-peer network
like I just mentioned inherits tor zone
censorship resistant tor is pretty good
at being censorship censorship resistant
and we just get all of that for free in
a way by riding on top of it the third
thing is it biscuits just code like I
mentioned the best network is just
people voluntarily working together
right so there's no company or other
legal entity to squeeze or pressure with
censorship current status of the project
is we've been in production now for
about 18 months as I speak since April
19th 2016 so in that 18 months of
process thousands of trades worth
millions of dollars without any downtime
without any major incidents so the good
news is it works it's still small
biscuits but it's been growing steadily
so you're looking here at coin dance
they give us a nice visualization here
along with a couple of other
decentralized exchanges you can look it
up there at coin dance but this is
bisques transaction volume normalized in
u.s. dollars so this is basically the US
dollar value of all Bitcoin transactions
that move through this con bisque every
transaction includes Bitcoin Bitcoin is
the base pair right you might be trading
for dollars or Euros or ether or
whatever right but there's always a
Bitcoin in the mix
this is the US dollar value over time
every week since our inception money
going through you know exchange volume
going through bisque and you can see in
the first month April of 2016 we did
about thirteen thousand dollars worth of
trading volume and this last month
September of 2017 we did about two
hundred and thirty thousand so we've
been doubling roughly every three point
five months since our inception and
looks like the trend is continuing to
head that way we'll see can't predict
the future but it's been a nice
trendline so far and all of that growth
has been organic that very little
marketing it's just people telling
people and so on how that this project
is funded today is the trading fees
right so every time someone initiates a
trade both the maker of the offer and
the taker of the offer pay a fee and
those fees are paid in Bitcoin and paid
out to arbitrators for the service that
they provide arbitration services are
mostly passive most trades go go
smoothly but when something goes wrong
there's a bug or there's a
misunderstanding or something like that
then the arbitrator gets involved but
for the service of being there and being
available arbitrators are paid on every
trade so that's how its funded now the
total of those funds is just about a
Bitcoin a month spread across to
arbitrators so it's not exactly enough
to fund we don't have a lot of costs but
it's still primarily funded out of
pocket by by the founders and there's no
decentralized way currently to
compensate other contributors so
arbitrators have a nice incentive right
to do their job but if you're issuing
pull requests fixing bugs helping out
with documentation what-have-you this
feels today more or less like a kind of
normal open-source project it's just
people help out if they have time and
that has scaling problems right we bet
it's difficult to grow that way how the
biskits
project is governed is a there's a small
team of contributors over all right now
and since its inception maintenance and
administration and operation have been
pretty centralized the whole time and
founders are the primary decision-makers
so we're bisques technology is
decentralized bisques governance isn't
yet let's look at the status of the
mission I said the mission of the bisk
project is provide a secure private
censorship resistant way of exchanging
Bitcoin for fiat right well let's check
the box on secure of course you be the
judge nothing is perfectly secure all
those disclaimers but in terms of being
by comparison a very secure way to trade
Bitcoin over the Internet fundamentally
because it rides on top of bitcoins own
philosophy be your own bank never put
your private keys in anybody else's
hands that's the way bisque works so if
Bitcoin is you get to be your own bank
bisque is be your own exchange so we can
check the box on secure we can check the
box on private for all the reasons that
we talked about censorship resistant
only part of the way there right we get
a long way riding on top of Tor and
other protections like the encryption
that we add on top and so on but funding
and governance are big holes in our
overall ability to remain censorship
resistant over time what do we need now
then
well what's needed is a continued
trading volume growth that trend line
actually needs to continue so that
eventually revenues can cover expenses
doesn't work if somebody has to reach
into that if certain individuals have to
reach into their pockets to keep the
thing alive that's essentially a
centralization risk too we need to scale
up contributions to keep improving
bisque to keep adding new features etc
which Foster's and facilitates that
growth the better bisque gets the more
people want to use it right so we need
more contributions more contributors etc
we need a decentralized compensation
model to incentivize those contributions
and we need decentralized decentralized
responsibility model to avoid censorship
like I was just talking about so enter
the bisque down so here's how the bisque
doll is designed to help first we
introduce a token bsq designed to
facilitate a transfer of value from the
traders who are using bisque to the
contributors who maintain it bsq is our
own custom implementation of the colored
coin concept how many people know what
colored coins are at least in concept
yeah about half the room or better so
the 25 bit coin the donators have
submitted supporters have donated to the
project over time since its inception
right so over the last few years we've
gotten 25 Bitcoin worth of donations we
take those 25 Bitcoin we color them at
the rate of a thousand satoshis per bsq
into 2.5 million vsq and that
distributed to 144 past contributors on
the basis of merit alright so one of
these people contributed to the project
over time and they get a proportional
amount distributed to them from that
initial set of bsq the SQ is not
associated with an ICO very important to
say these days nor will there be a crowd
sale nor is this any kind of
crowdfunding events in fact the price of
B of bsq over time is by design a freely
floating variable in the system we do
not need be sq to be you know worth tens
and hundreds and thousands of dollars
in order to fund the system and you'll
see why in a moment but that's very
important to mention the SQ is as
mentioned above a token design to
facilitate a transfer of value between
the traders who use bisque and the
contributors who maintain it today
without bsq traders use bisque and pay
trading fees in Bitcoin contributors
work to improve bisque and bisque in
turn gets more useful over time it's
traders this causes more traders to use
bisque more often as it gets better
right and a cycle of growth occurs that
cycle can describe what's gotten bisque
where it is today right that growth that
we've seen so far that doubling every
three point five months that must be
because bisque keeps getting more useful
right we added support for alt coins
other cryptocurrencies and so on along
the way it's gotten more and more secure
and all the bugs have been fixed and so
on sweet that's a virtuous cycle that's
a good thing the traders as they use
bisque like I mentioned pay trading fees
in Bitcoin those trading fees like I
mentioned get paid out to arbitrators so
arbitrators are automatically
compensated in the system so payment to
arbitrators is already decentralized
it's a function of every trade that
happens right so all good so far what's
needed though is a way to compensate
everybody else in an equally
decentralized fashion so that's not
possible with the current arrangement
that's why we introduced bsq so there
are five use cases for the bsq token
within the bisque down the first is
trading so using the bisque exchange
stakeholders sell vsq traders by bsq why
why would a trader by bsq because as
they're using bisque now instead of
paying trading fees in Bitcoin they have
the option
to pay their trading fees in bsq at a
steep discount right initially it'll be
a 90% discount that will fall off to a
degree over time but a steep discount
designed of course to incentivize those
traders to buy vsq okay 3 the third
utility of the token is compensation
contributors a submit compensation
requests to be paid in bsq and B when
those compensation requests are approved
by voting they actually earn the SQ so
the fourth utility or function of the
token is of course voting itself in
which stakeholders people who already
have bsq vote on whether or not
compensation request should be approved
the fifth function is bonding so
contributors can post a bond in vsq in
order to take on higher trust roles in
the system like roles in the system for
example arbitration or say running the
bisque website or managing bisques dns
things that if they mess it up can cause
harm can cause damage to the network
into the project they can put up a bond
in bsq that's time locked and and so on
that they can't spend right but can be
confiscated by voting if they somehow
screw up right and in order in
compensation for doing that not only do
they get to issue compensation requests
like anybody else for the work that they
provide in that higher trust role like
arbitration they can also earn interest
on that bsq bond so this is probably the
least important of the five but to be
complete those are the five utilities of
the bsq token in the bisque Dao
so there's one issue though you might
wonder okay so how does it solve this
problem of a decentralized mechanism for
paying all the other contributors notice
that I grade this out right it's still
possible to pay trading fees in Bitcoin
we're not going to turn that off and
those fees will continue to be paid
directly to arbitrators okay but what
about these fees paid in bsq where do
they go how does it solve the
decentralization problem it does not go
directly to compensate contributors in
any way what does happen is that when
can when contributors issue that
compensation request a little bit
technical but just if you think about
this is a colored coin right so in order
to create any new colored coin any new
bsq in this case there's got to be some
satoshis backing it right there has to
be that underlying value and bitcoin
backing it
so when contributors are issuing
compensation requests what they're
actually doing is issuing a Bitcoin
transaction in the amount of Satoshi's
equivalent to the amounts of Bitcoin
excuse me the SQ that they want to be
paid so this is where bsq gets created
right compensation in the bisk doubt is
issuance so if my compensation request
is approved I basically what's been
approved is the creation of new bsq and
the network validates it accordingly so
that has the effect of increasing the
total supply of bsq over time starts out
at 2.5 million bsq and then grows with
every compensation request that's
approved alright so after a month let's
say we let's say the value of bsq is $1
currently and we approve as a dhow
through voting voting with bsq mind you
right we approves let's say a hundred
thousand bsq worth of compensation
requests so now the total supply of BS q
is not 2.5 million but 2.6 million okay
this looks like a runaway train this
looks like a bad idea
we all understand inflation isn't so
great
right for the value of a token okay well
what about those trading fees on the
other side trading fees are actually
destroyed right the bsq that's paid and
trading fees is burned which of course
has the effect of decreasing the total
supply of BS Q over time so this
mechanism allows for allows us to have a
kind of monetary policy function within
the Dow right you know ideally naively
you might think okay
deflation equals inflation right we're
spending as much on BS q trading these
traders are using BS q at some rate and
that's all the more compensation we can
issue right so a hundred thousand is
getting spent every month okay we could
do a hundred thousand of approvals of
compensation requests right well what if
it's actually otherwise what if it's a
hundred and fifty thousand a month being
spent lots and lots of traders using
using bisk but all that's needed is a
hundred thousand or 125 thousand worth
of compensation requests this would have
overtime a deflationary effect right a
gradual deflationary effect that you
might think of as a deflationary
dividend to all of the holders of BS q
so that would be like a goal state right
not just equilibrium but a slightly
deflationary situation it also allows to
intentionally inflate to intentionally
run at an inflated rate right well we're
just getting all this started and
trading volumes are still relatively low
and there's only so many users in the
system and so on we might intentionally
run higher you know run at an
inflationary rate greenlight more
compensation requests then there are
trading fees to back them up
understanding that that's a good idea
right now right to help build out the
network to help build out the
application and so on but we would only
do that if we thought that all of the
stakeholders were in it were in
agreement and understood that right
otherwise people would lose faith in the
project if we just inflated it into this
into the stratosphere right
okay so that is the bisque down in a
nutshell now there are risks to
everything right but there are risks to
just flipping on the switch we've
actually had a lot of this implemented
for months and months and months and the
question has been okay when do we
actually turn it on right when do we
actually take that 25 bit coin and
distribute it on Bitcoin maintenance to
do that and then we and then we stopped
right because every time we think about
it there are real risks involved and we
want it avoid those risks for example
right valuation risk let's say we turn
it on well the market has no idea what
this token is worth we don't know what
this token is worth it could fall too
low to be viable it could fall right
down to its underlying satoshi value
right that that won't work it could go
through the roof
because of hype right that would also be
a problem though we bring all kinds of
attention and heat to the project that
we don't want so call that valuation
risk you could talk about control risk
right this is by design from the ground
up of meritocracy think about that
initial distribution to past
contributors initially the people who
hold bsq are the people who built bsq
right in accordance to the value that
they've added to the network
that's a meritocracy but we don't want
this to become a plutocracy we don't
want Wales to come along and just buy up
all the vsq there's all sorts of things
that could go wrong so call that control
risk censorship risk well just because
we flip the switch doesn't mean that
we've achieved full decentralization of
governance and funding on that day of
course not it's gradual so we run the
risk of founders being pressured right
people get wind of this they say I don't
like that project and they shut it down
too early and there are others right for
time you know just I want to make the
point here that we've analyzed all of
the risks and there are many and they
are mostly existential right any one of
these things going sufficiently wrong
could kill the project completely at
least kill bsq and kill the down so what
do we do well we introduce what we call
phase zero
the bisque roll out the bisque doll
rollout plan had five phases initially
this is a phase that comes before those
five phases so phase zero but it also
has the effect of being kind of like a
zero dot version if you sort of think
semantic versioning for the developers
in the house right a pre-release phase
for the Dow the goal of that phase is to
bootstrap the Dow now immediately while
mitigating minimizing all of those risks
and here's how we do it essentially
those five functions that we talked
about trading access compensation voting
and bonding we take out of the picture
completely trading and access so you
can't buy sell or trade bsq on this
during phase zero nor can you pay your
trading fees in bsq during phase zero
what you can do is earn it through
compensation requests getting greenlit
you can use it to vote and you can use
it for bonding in this way this during
phase zero remains a pure meritocracy
the only way you can get your hands on
this token is to earn it so what's the
approach overall in a nutshell we begin
by like I say prohibiting bsq token
trading during phase zero but how do we
do that
first we initially issue an initial 2.5
million vsq tokens on test net right on
biscone Bitcoin test net not on Bitcoin
main net so the underlying value isn't
there because test net tokens are not a
value but it could still like escape it
could still theoretically be traded so
we every month rebase to 2.5 million so
like the the in this phase zero the
supply will only grow right because it
can't be sold it can't be traded etc so
the supply will only grow it will only
inflate on a month-to-month basis so we
rebates that back down to two point five
million but taking into account
everybody's state changes proportionally
right so if you did some work and US you
to compensation request in October and
you got a hundred
bsq or whatever it was that's gonna be
accounted for in the next month's test
net Genesis distribution so we're
actually gonna issue Genesis
distributions every month rebasing them
back to that 2.5 million won it's good
practice right but - it really ensures
that the token has no value right we
also release a new version of bisque
that treats that New Genesis
distribution as the Genesis block right
every month all right so that's all for
the purpose of prohibiting trading and
we start with simple high trust tools
and buy high trust I mean like high
trust in the bad sense right like we use
spreadsheets to track voting and stuff
like that but we're dealing with play
money here so it's an option to do that
right
like I say voting track by spreadsheet
compensation requests or happen on
github right eventually all of these
things happen in app and on chain by the
design that we've already put together
right we know how to build all of this
stuff we've built a lot of it already
but we haven't built all of it and we
certainly haven't built all of it such
that it's free of critical bugs right we
can't know that without trying it so be
iterative right if we've learned
anything over the last 20 years of just
software development in general right
agile methodology all of that stuff
iterate be iterative right and iterate
toward those low trust versions toward
those on chained versions of all the
functionalities of the down and continue
hopefully growing exchange volume
organically so that we're making sure to
have enough money over time to cover our
costs as we compensate everybody in a
decentralized way okay so the roadmap
when does all this happen well the first
thing is the inception of phase zero is
right now actually just late last night
we did our first test net Genesis
distribution show you some screenshots
in a second so it in a very meaningful
sense that this cow begins now
the duration will be at least six months
hopefully right around that but at least
six months why at least because we want
it'll take at least that much
to have a significant additional
redistribution of bisque to new
contributors right the founders have you
know so so much bisque now and we want
to reduce that amount it's already you
know less than 50% with any one founder
but we want to reduce that as much as
possible have as many people engage and
they'll take at least six months to
really get that started okay and
completion will be marked with that same
kind of genesis distribution but the
final genesis distribution on bitcoin
main net of course not on test net and a
release of the best client that supports
trading and fee payments in vsq okay so
here's the test net distribution that
just happened last night right and
there's our own Explorer actually so
that's looking at the Bitcoin blockchain
but that's looking at bisque right as
colored so that's a colored view on the
Bitcoin blockchain specific for looking
at this transactions all right process
and tools so we're gonna follow a/c for
like process for people who know zero
I'm Q and Peter hint jens and all that
stuff will use github slack matrix just
sort of industry standard standard tools
for all of this and so in conclusion
right so how to bootstrap it Dow of
course I'm sure there are many answers
to this question many valid answers to
this question our answers so far are
build a useful decentralized app first
right that's what we've done for the
last 18 months prove that the thing is
actually of use to anybody that anybody
wants it then build a Dao around it be
iterative have a zero dot release phase
phase zero like we're doing consider
restricting the trading of those doubt
oaken's right treat them more like an
equity vehicle only allow earning only
allow voting right design carefully from
meritocracy don't lose that it's easy to
lose that and that's about it so you can
join us follow us here there'll be lots
of news to come in the days that follow
and thank you very much
[Applause]
how much time do we have yeah okay we
have about seven minutes I think for
questions
so very quickly keep your questions
short and hopefully answers kind of
short to go ahead of the mic so this
mean less money for arbitrators does it
mean less money for arbitrators now that
we you know spread things out right so
arbitrators will still like everybody
else issue compensation requests for
their work they'll continue to get paid
to the amount that people pay their fees
in Bitcoin they'll also get those
Bitcoin payments directly but hopefully
there will be far fewer people trading
paying fees in Bitcoin so we'll see but
they at least have the potential to earn
just as much or eat more hopefully yeah
other question I would like to ask her
about the difference about the beat
square because that's what you were
describing it's I hurried a year ago in
in this place and that's exactly what
beat score is doing and actually don't
you think all these basic token isn't
this overkill to fund the project isn't
it wouldn't it be much easier to just
take Bitcoin fish and redistribute them
somehow yeah yeah so two questions right
how does this differ from bit square in
name alone it is bit square we renamed
bit square four yeah certain go reasons
basically - so why introduce a token at
all the goal is to is to decentralize
the funding and governance of the
project so couldn't we just do that with
Bitcoin alone and for time but we could
go back to the diagram but essentially
in theory yes right we could take all
those Bitcoin payments and put them all
into a multi sig transaction that gets
paid out according to some sort of
dowloading process right in theory in
practice right now you're not getting
much more than single-digit M of n right
so you're not getting much more than
single-digit M or n in in in multi-site
transactions right - if three is common
you could I think you can do
seven eight nine not 20 not a hundred
not a thousand right so it's just not
possible now mask this Merkel eyes
abstract syntax tree stuff that's coming
along
looks like it might make that possible
but we're not waiting around for it
there's also how to destroy it
on the other side is I mean so not
needing to destroy or create maybe
that's all possible but but we just have
to wait for a Bitcoin technology to come
along yeah and also just allows us to do
so many other things right our own time
lock our own bonding logic our own rules
around voting it gives us the freedom to
do everything that we need to do that
we'll figure out over time right without
being constrained by Bitcoin last time I
looked at Cola coins was in 2014 it was
quite painful but it looks like there's
been a lot of progress there that they
explore and stuff my question is around
the creation and voting is this creation
of the new issuing of the coins that can
like control by the voting in some
cryptographic matter or is it you still
need to trust some administrator to
actually be nice yes yeah so on the
colored coins front I didn't mention it
but this is you know that there have
been different colored coin
implementations and kind of attempts to
maybe standardize and so on this is none
of that this is totally bespoke it's our
own coloration logic we don't have a
dependency there by the way and the
second question just remind me it's it
though voting is voting is voting
basically on a sort of on chain event
yes it is right so if you and that's
very important because people actually
pay to vote right voting costs bsq
itself and when people will vote is
basically there's basically a sort of
field of bits that can accommodate 256
votes right and people are going through
the compensation requests and checking I
approve that I disapprove that and so on
that all gets put together in one
transaction on chain being validated and
so on by bisques coloration logic and
that's how we know what valid bisque is
right because there was a transaction
that came along before that greenlit it
yes a Mike over here or do we have time
I'm some of it okay
uh-huh okay my questions about the
control risk so you talked about the
whales coming in buying up all the
bisque which i think is quite pertinent
since it seemed like a few of your
revenue streams being earning interest
from the bonds and also earning interest
from the from the compensation depended
on having bisque so how does kind of
ignoring that section in the phase zero
control for that after phase zero yeah
right so so how do we control for
control risk after phase zero right
phase zero just prevents it because
nobody can buy it right but afterward
yeah people could start coming in and
buying it up of course that's throttled
by the liquidity that's being provided
by stakeholders right I mean just one
thing to mention that doesn't prevent it
at all right but the second thing is is
that again part of the design is that is
that voting right is actually not simply
stake based so it's not purely a
function of one one bsq one vote but
rather it's weighted by a reputation
right so it's about a 70 percent
reputation weight versus 30 percent just
pure stake weight so people can buy bsq
and can have a meaningful you know
ability to participate in the governance
but 70 percent of that weight is people
who earned it right and we have
mechanisms to do that with the
coloration okay was that the last
question yep that was it so once again
everyone thank Chris beams for the talk
very interesting thank you
[Applause]