okay well thanks for coming to my talk
and well I am truly honored to be
invited here because this this
conference has been a lot of fun for me
so far so thanks a lot oh this talk is
about how to nap the most there's a
napping competition and I'm gonna tell
you how to win this talk is not about
health but it's about it's about how to
make good investment decisions and I
think that if you prioritize napping
that that's a good good idea so I'm
going to explain why but I'll just I'll
just give you a spoiler right away you
should prioritize napping as you make
like before you make decisions
you should prioritize napping because if
you don't you're working against your
own long-term best interest so a lot of
the conventional wisdom that we learn
growing up is for for for working
because you know you have to you have to
make money at a job that means you have
to work but the that the habits you need
to be a good investor are kind of the
opposite in some way so if this is about
why laziness is good so I don't know if
there's anything really original in this
talk but but this is this is stuff that
needs to be repeated people need to be
reminded of this sort of thing regularly
and if you fall asleep while I'm talking
that's good that's a compliment that
means that you have absorbed the message
so I'm Daniel Kravitz and you know in in
2012 some of my friends well I got some
of my friends interested in Bitcoin in a
libertarian group and we kind of decided
amongst ourselves
that anybody who is a libertarian should
probably just get a little bit a Bitcoin
and then you know just in case and stop
then not worry about it and if it works
out then they'll be rich and you know we
learned a lot about Bitcoin in our in
our discussion groups and then when we
finally engaged in the Bitcoin community
we were like wow this place is crazy
okay they really need our ideas so we
decided to make the Satoshi Nakamoto
Institute page for two basic reasons one
was that there was kind of a kind of a
sentiment in Bitcoin to put the
cypherpunks under the rug kind of forget
about him because they're too
controversial like nobody would buy
Bitcoin they knew it was anarchist and
the other reason was that we didn't see
a lot of Austrian economics in in the
Bitcoin world which was kind of
surprising so we wanted to bring that in
so one one thing that I noticed in
Bitcoin is that everybody is very
anxious all the time there's always some
kind of thing that people are worrying
about and usually it's something that
doesn't doesn't seem to make any sense
so that's that's why I started writing
articles so people would say like there
are too many hoarders people are
hoarding Bitcoin so I wrote an article
called I'm hoarding bitcoins and no you
can't have any because it's you know
maybe Bitcoin would fail but it's
certainly not because people are
investing in it which is just what
hoarding is and people would say you
know
bitcoin is too volatile that's terrible
so I wrote an article called I love
bitcoins volatility because it's like
you know well I'm twice as rich again
this morning so horrifying you know
that's that's kind of what I would write
about oh also I I I should mention I
work for a company called stash crypto
now and where we're about to release a
new version of our wallets so you should
go check that out I forgot to say that
right let's start so the advice that we
wrote about at the Satoshi Nakamoto
Institute was very good because
basically every every article I wrote
said just stop worrying about this thing
and just keep keep holding the bitcoins
and if you had if you had followed our
advice and bought bitcoins in 2013 and
then just not done anything you would
have done great you would have done
better than most people who tried to do
something else and that's kind of that's
kind of the key because our advice was
not perfect but it was very good and it
was very easy to follow and people who
try to be perfect usually don't do as
well okay so the best advice that I ever
gave was in a comic strip then I
published in 2013 which probably most
people didn't see so I'm going to show
you some of that and here's here's how
it begins this is this is kind of my
character and this person represents the
other character represents the guy who
was always interested in the latest
thing who was always excited about
whatever the new thing is and he looks
like Garfield because he's totally
boring and unoriginal that's kind of why
I did that so
here's here's my best advice ever I said
that's all all you have to do is buy all
the coins you can and then take a long
nap and it's kind of obvious that I
wasn't thinking that this was my best
advice ever at the time because I just
kind of have it buried in here so I made
a new version of this panel this is the
this is the new version it's more it's
more clear okay so feel free to it feel
free to use this and so recently I've
kind of been thinking thinking back why
why was this the best advice why like I
would never have had to even write an
article if I had just said that
it's almost would have been more
efficient to just do this and not write
about all of the specific topics I did
because one of the problems that I had
is that the scams kept evolving okay but
Bitcoin is like you know there's one
great idea at the center and then
everything else is like traps that are
trying to get you on your way to the
bitcoins okay and the scams kept
evolving so first we had alt coins and I
remember when when like crane light coin
when I first learned about it I thought
you know this isn't going to last very
long but I was wrong about that
and then then people started making app
coins so now we have all of this ICO
craze but these are basically app coins
anyway I wrote wrote articles about lots
of different things but they're kept
being new new twists you know so my
friend Michael wrote an article called
everybody's a scammer so that was very
good because that is kind of more that's
more abstract right you just kind of say
everybody is trying to trick you into
taking on more risk than you need to
so everybody is a scammer that's kind of
a general problem that you always have
to deal with no matter what happened
so but anyway this is this is my best
advice and I've been trying to think
about why why it was so good so here's
here's what I came up with if if you
prioritize napping when you make your
investment decisions that forces you to
be an independent thinker and it forces
you to be more intelligent okay because
you are you are constrained by the need
to be able to fall asleep at any time
okay and that forces you to avoid risk
and it prevents you from getting excited
by con artists who are trying to you
know get you interested in something
without you thinking about it enough so
when when you are considering making
investment decisions you need to think
about well you should invest like you
have narcolepsy right you should think
like if I were to just fall asleep
randomly nothing bad should happen I
need to invest in a way so that if I had
narcolepsy I would be fine okay and the
way you do that is you know you have to
decide you you have to have your own
ideas about what your going to get
excited about okay so if some some
outside force is trying to get you
excited you need to resist that you need
to go into situations already with some
kind of preconception of what what kind
of thing you're going to get excited
about
and if you don't have that then you're
easily manipulated so if you prioritize
napping then you are constantly
distancing yourself from the situation
and you give yourself a chance to to
think more on your own and and you also
have to be more creative about how you
invest because often the more the more
abstract kind of investments are they
make it they make it easier to nap so so
for example I really like the show
Bitcoin uncensored and you know the bet
back before they split up the two people
have made the show they always used to
talk about index funds and you know most
most people can't do better well nobody
can do better consistently than in an
index fund right so index funds are good
for napping because you just buy it and
then you know the economy grows and then
you wake up later and you and your
Richard you don't have to to think about
it so the index fund should kind of be
like like your default it's kind of like
your null hypothesis and it's good if
you don't know anything you know if you
don't know anything you can buy the
index fund then if you do know something
you can you can buy something more
specific okay okay so if you want to
have the kind of peace of mind that
allows you to take naps a lot you need
to avoid risk because if you're too
risky they
you're anxious and you can't sleep so if
you prioritize napping you have to avoid
risk and that's good because it's easy
to forget to avoid risk okay risk is
always the risk of an investment is
always less obvious than than the
potential benefits
it's more difficult to think about
because the person selling you the
investment certainly isn't going to make
the the risk obvious is he is going to
put he's gonna make it look as good as
possible so you have to think about you
have to think on your own to figure out
what the risks are okay and risks are
dangerous because over time risks matter
more than then then potential gains and
the reason for this is your net worth is
always closer to zero than to infinity
right so there is always a chance that
you will make enough mistakes in a row
to bring you down to zero or down to a
point where you can't invest anymore and
even if you don't go all the way to zero
it's it's it's hard to recover from a
series of mistakes in a row it takes a
long time and eventually that'll happen
right eventually the the risks will
compound and you'll make enough mistakes
in a row so that you're at a point where
you can't recover but in the short term
in the short term the people who take
risks or at least some of them some of
them will do a lot better but eventually
as time goes on the more risky people
will be eliminated even if they go after
bigger gains so what you should do is
you should try to try to find the trying
to look for the best
gains subject to the constraint that you
can nap a lot and that will force you to
think about the risks so that you can
have peace of mind so that you can sleep
a lot the the lazier you can be the
better let's see now
so now I was thinking about why why is
this such a particularly good idea for
for Bitcoin and I think that the reason
is Bitcoin is the kind of thing it's
kind of like an index fund it's kind of
the kind of thing that you would want to
get if if you wanted to take naps okay
and if if Bitcoin reaches its potential
if it gets you know if it gets big
enough that it's at you know its
equilibrium point its
--ml kind of grow with the economy
because it'll be used for for staying
liquid hey cuz you know an investor
wants to be liquid some of the time and
then he moves into stocks when he wants
to take risks right so the the need for
so so Bitcoin will serve the need for
for liquidity and that will kind of
that's that's dependent on the size of
the economy right so that's what that's
what Bitcoin will be for so it's kind of
like it's kind of like like an index
fund it's kind of like a thing you would
buy that'll just go with the economy and
you don't have to think about it the
only difference is that if there was a
stock market bubble an index fund would
go up whereas because you know with the
stocks whereas Bitcoin wouldn't as
people the stock market bubble means
that people are systematically moving
out out of cash and into
stocks and if then if there's a crash
then an index fund would go down where
as bit Bitcoin would not so in in
general you know if if you don't get
into Bitcoin with the idea that you're
going to sleep a lot it's kind of like
you know what what's the point it's not
really it's not really doing its job so
I tried to think of somebody from
mythology or literature who would
exemplify this principle who would be
like a role model okay so I found a new
role model and that is Tom Bombadil he's
my new favorite role model he is like
the best investor okay because he
refuses to take on risk he'll it's other
people do it okay so if you're not
familiar with he wasn't in the movie
okay but if you're not familiar with him
from the Lord of the Rings what what
happens with Tom Bombadil is that he's
not affected by the Ring of Power he
puts it on and he doesn't care and he
won't join in on the quest to save
middle-earth he just says you know
whatever the orc problem will will take
care of itself
okay he just wants to stay back in his
magical forest okay and that's that's
what I like about it and everybody well
everybody in the whole world but
especially everybody in Bitcoin is
trying to trick you into taking on more
risk than you need to okay they're
trying to they're trying to get you to
go on their quest okay and I'm my new
this could be my second greatest advice
right now is never trust Gandalf okay
because he's the one he's the one who's
telling Frodo
to take on risk right he's like the con
artist
whereas Tom Bombadil is like somebody
who is diversified because he says
humans when orcs win I'll be fine either
way
that Nets so so that that's I think
that's the best mindset for for being an
investor now examples so I think that
this attitude is great for being in
Bitcoin but it's great for kind of
everything to know this is a political
conference all talk politics one of the
ways that the ruling class stays in
power is they trick the the people you
know the working class into taking on
risk and then they don't take on risk so
in in the United States a few years ago
we recently had Ron Paul trying to get
elected to president to the presidency
right and lots of people put a lot of
work into the campaign then nothing
happened okay
so they took on risk and then all of
that work was lost and then they got
discouraged so they all voted for Trump
the next time around okay so by contrast
there was a great talk earlier today
about anonymous insurance companies now
that's great that's a way that ordinary
people reduce risk and they make the
government take on more risk that's how
you win you make you trick the other
person into taking on more risk so I
really like that one
well well I'm through with my notes how
much time do I have left
it's okay time if you have more what do
you what do you want to say you can or
we can do Q&A well it's to Q&A Q&A I
kind of got through everything I hope I
hope you thought that this was useful I
mean I I I'm not really sure you know if
I really you know made my point very
well this is just what I've been
learning recently myself so okay thank
you to NATO for your interesting
presentation so now is the time for
questions I will take the first because
I hold the mic you obviously think that
the bitcoin is the the one why do you
think so and why not other coins okay oh
well so first of all my definition of
Bitcoin is all of all of the chains that
derive from the Bitcoin Genesis block so
I don't think that the the Bitcoin core
chain is exclusively Bitcoin I think
that it investors decide which chain is
going to be the most valuable one and
that whichever one that is that that
should be called Bitcoin and the reason
that Bitcoin is the one is that it was
created first so it had more time for
for the network to grow so if an altcoin
were to defeat Bitcoin what has to
happen is the entire the entire group of
Bitcoin investors has to sequentially
take on extra risk by buying the
coin not saying that that's impossible
but that's a big big hurdle and I don't
think that I I don't think that any of
the alt coins are really are really
showing that they can pass that hurdle I
think that they're mostly trying to make
people not think about it okay so you
have to people have to systematically
take on risk one one by one until
they've all moved over into the alt
coins and that's very unlikely because
with the smaller Network isn't isn't as
good at being money the the best money
is the one that the most people have
agreed is money and well Bitcoin the
bitcoin is beating the dollar because
people know that they can evade capital
controls and to open you know all kinds
of other things with it but a an altcoin
that was going to defeat Bitcoin would
have to have it would have to be as much
an innovation over Bitcoin as Bitcoin is
over the dollar not which again not not
saying that this is impossible but that
is a that's a far-fetched proposition
question over here um I have one comment
and one question so regarding your
latest statement that reminded me of
article in Forbes from 2007 or 2008
where the author made a proposition that
myspace is the ultimate social network
and due to social network effects nobody
will be ever able to compete with
MySpace because everybody is on myspace
already but we know what happened then
so I mean I would be careful with the
proposition that Bitcoin is first and
that's why it will be it will remain the
best one for ever and the second kind of
comment or question is that even if you
make the point that risk should be
avoided at all costs despite the fact
that kind of people have their own
preferences over risk versus reward
even if you define your goal as avoiding
risk like any finance 101 course will
teach you that diversification of your
portfolio is the way to make the risk
lower but if you like why are you so
sure that bitcoin acts like a
cryptocurrency
S&P 500 like maybe you should make your
portfolio more diverse and the guy who
followed your advice in 2012 and bought
bitcoin and slept till now for example
miss an opportunity to invest in a
theorem which grew a thousand times
right well I don't write well no nobody
can be perfect right the idea is you
have to what there was too much in that
question for what was the first the
first thing was about MySpace right so
the difference the difference between
social networks and Bitcoin is the the
value the value of the network is what
it is now okay because and the value can
change over time because it can add ads
or something right and then it becomes
more annoying and like whereas the whole
the the reason that a currency is useful
is that you can you can hold it for a
long time right it's about having old
stashes of coins amazing little bit like
the main part of the question that I
really one kind of you to answer is why
do you think that bitcoin acts as a as
in the index fund in cryptocurrencies
yeah this was kind of Demoman question
oh oh okay I didn't make my point clear
I was what what I said was that or what
I was trying to say is that if Bitcoin
reaches its potential and it gets you
know it reaches its equilibrium point
then it will act like a an index fund
for for the whole economy okay because
people will move into it to be liquid
and then they'll move into stocks when
they're done being liquid and you know
people people have their own preferences
about about risk right and I'm not
saying that you should avoid risk at all
cost but my my point is that people
don't think about the risks risks as
much it's easy to fool yourself and
forget about them but if you prioritize
napping you have to think about them
because you can't you can't you you
can't feel good enough to look away and
just sleep for a while unless you feel
like you know you've taken care of
everything
next question please
is there any questions because if not I
have several so think about your
question you talked about it in some
time in the future there will be it's
going to be in the equilibrium because
it will reach the saturate the economy
so I would like to ask you what is in
your view your target equilibrium price
for Bitcoin and or if you do have
something every stick about this how
large Bitcoin can get oh no I don't have
a target I mean I guess how would you
tell that's a good question how would
you know when it reached its equilibrium
point I mean I I guess I would say if I
start to think if I start to like some
stocks better than Bitcoin that that's
when I think it's reached the target I
just don't know how you would tell when
it when it reached its its
point-like self so far I don't I don't
see anything that's limiting it
particularly but yeah I've been watching
for that I don't know the answer well
the maximum target point I can think of
it's like the the size of the global
economic like eighty billion dollars or
trillion dollars oh sure yeah this is
like the I can imagine yeah a B maybe it
could be even more valuable because the
economy will grow in that time so but
then I think of the use cases like in
black market and the part of the command
can't be regulated really so maybe 10%
or 20% of this global economy if you
have any any ideas about that or well
yeah the the target should be
proportional to the size of the global
economy I just don't know what the what
what the proportionality would be but
yeah it should be something something
kind of like that okay thank you
still no questions because I have two
more okay
I heard you argue about altcoins that we
really don't need them but that we don't
need these this bad experimentation and
come around but in my view it's it's
like natural what must happen I view it
if bitcoin is like a sand and we need to
build power we really can't put one
grain on next and expect that it will be
stable we need the pile of the of the
sand and to keep the the top of it so I
see all the all the experimentation and
all the height points we need to like
saturate all the low pass to do every
but but thought that experiment before
we can really come back to Bitcoin and
say okay
it was Bitcoin from the beginning also
what do you think about this because you
often say that these are all scams
altcoins
or next to scams and don't invest oh who
don't invest then because they have no
value right well I mean obviously I'm
not against people creating new
cryptocurrencies and trying to trying to
get them to succeed but III think that
that the the people you know pumping the
old coins are not giving me very good
arguments to want to buy them and I also
think that Forks of Bitcoin are better
investments than altcoins so they people
should have been forking Bitcoin instead
of creating alt coins this whole time
okay
yes question so if I pick up I we run
across the hostel several times
yesterday today what we run across in
the hostel several times oh it's raining
today so I came to your presentation but
if I don't get your message is basically
the confidence and trust and be passive
and I think you can outperform this by
doing an active management and being an
active manager just knowing what you do
and even reducing the risk by hatching
not putting all X in the Bitcoin basket
and the question is or the art is
basically to define to develop how you
do this how you select the interesting
projects when you get in when you get
out and what your strategy is yes yeah
okay so I agree with everything you said
and I would say that what what you're
talking about
is what what you need to do to be
confident other other than active
management I mean but you you need to
you need to have your strategy your your
exit strategy and you need to hedge
because that that that makes you know
that you're fine even if you make a
mistake so I guess what what much of
what you were talking about is you know
exactly what you would need to be able
to take naps so thank you
next question is here behind the pillar
hi thanks thanks for the for the speech
was great what do you think is the
biggest obstacle for Bitcoin in future
is it like technical thing is it a legal
thing from the government's is it
monopoly from the miners or what do you
think consider like a biggest biggest
problem oh well yeah the biggest problem
I think is I would like to see a more
investor controlled Bitcoin because
right now I don't think that the the way
the way that Bitcoin development is
getting enough input from the investors
so what I would like to see is there
should be options market for Forks of
Bitcoin so that we know or for future
Forks I should say so that we know what
rule changes will maximize the value a
Bitcoin and that's how that's how we
know what what to do so I you know III
think that the investors should make the
plan and then the developers should
implement it and and of course maybe the
developers make the best plan
but the only you know the thing that
would be most convincing to me would be
to see that the the investors agree with
the plan you know on the the options
market or or prediction market
so Paul stocks told me that a a
prediction market is is equivalent to an
options market in in some way but I've I
haven't learned enough about it to know
exactly how they're similar but we
should be able to see that a proposed
rule change is going to make Bitcoin
more valuable and you know then that
that's how we should know what what to
do and you can't really have an option
for for Bitcoin rule changes unless you
do hard Forks rather than soft Forks so
I like hard Forks better because that
gives me investment options to say what
I want so speaking of the Forks
I read your recent article where you
like took the position about Bitcoin
cash if if we should sell it if we
should if we should solve Bitcoin and
your point was don't sell anything in
long term you will be on the winning
side either oh yeah so you know I I
really think that what's happening in
Bitcoin now is another trick to trying
to get people to take investment actions
they don't need to do because to me like
it if people can fork Bitcoin and you
you can just stay diversified then you
just say whichever wins you know great
and people say like you know maybe some
someone is going to try to corrupt
Bitcoin by by changing the rules but you
know to me the value of Bitcoin is
the its ability to enable people to
resist capital controls and inflation
and if somebody were to fork Bitcoin in
a way that made this impossible then
that fork would not be valuable whereas
if somebody were to change the rules in
a way that made it better then that one
would succeed and it should succeed does
that answer your question yeah I was
just asking about your no inactive
position which is quite in agreement
what what you said no yeah actually I
should have mentioned that while I was
talking but I missed missed it so thanks
for asking so if there is not another
question I would like thank Daniel again
for the talk
[Applause]