thank you very much for for inviting me
here these conferences also and I'm very
happy to give this talk and this is a
very nice palindrome date nice
I'm Jocko I have been already introduced
now I am CEO of Block C lab just want me
to tell you what ok if somebody is sick
for the prezi movement just use the
vomit sex bags next to the chairs this
is what we do basically we take money
from the financial incumbents banks
insurance and other kind of people we
use this money to fund and help
development over bitcoin few years ago
when we started we were saying
blockchain in order to have a better
marketing but now we are more harnessed
about that we basically do only stuff
about Bitcoin and we use this money to
have this project in return we get
knowledge from these experts and we use
the knowledge for consultancy so this is
what we do whatever I'm going to talk
about today is not technical or business
is basically politics I'm talking about
political attack factors on Bitcoin and
common political misconception just to
start one minute to review the fact that
in my opinion which is right bitcoin is
not merely a technical event but is
mainly a political event with this a
mean that bitcoin is the fruit the fruit
the final fruit the final outcome of a
process that what mainly political in
its origins and also because introduces
some changes that are mainly political
or and economical more than
technological in itself of course I
don't have to explain to you here I mean
this conference organized by a set of
crypto Anarchy the roots of all the
world that led to Bitcoin finally so the
crypto Anarchy manifesto and team
and everything the cyberpunk culture mix
it up with some other political culture
like libertarianism goldbox
Austrian economics free banking so there
is a huge mix ters mixture of political
even Milton Friedman usually I played I
played the video but I'm sure that you
were all done based presentation so you
have already seen the video that the
sentence is awesome mr. Friedman
predicting basically Bitcoin I think
that the internet is going to be one of
the major forces for reducing the role
of government the one thing that's
missing but will soon be developed is a
reliable ecash a method whereby on the
Internet you can transfer funds from A
to B without without any knowing B or B
knowing a yeah it's possible and also in
the goddess's block we have politics we
have an explicit reference from Satoshi
Nakamoto to a economical political event
a bank bailout just after the global
financial crisis caused by monetary
policies and stuff like that so it's
it's undisputable that bitcoin origins
are political also the specific
technological piece missing in the
puzzle that bitcoin added to the
previous set of technology is not really
technological or cryptographic
mathematical is mostly game theory and
in a way politics we started with I mean
p2p distributed databases and
open-source technology already in cash
and the digital signature so this big
Bitcoin didn't invent digital signature
beacon didn't invent proof of work
neither transferable proof work already
present in the bomani concept in 98 by
we die so what the current reduce was a
way to put to take the chronology of the
transaction put it inside the proof of
work and in this way to
an economical and political incentives
to have one single consistent consistent
and immutable chronology of all the old
a alteration of the of the database so
it's basically a an economical political
innovation this is just the introduction
the introduction to to say that somebody
may think that the region the regions
are political but the implication are
mostly random alliance to just business
and technical implication I mean many
internet innovation where highly
ideological at first burnout they are
just used to do normal business Eddie
they've lost much of the of their
political charge I do think that Bitcoin
will not intrinsically lose mass of its
political potential because many of the
things that can be brought up by this
technology are intrinsically game
changers from a political point of view
they cannot be anything else
renormalization of this technology under
political status quo is technically very
unlikely because I mean you'll know that
it's centralized blockchain or a private
blockchain permission blockchain these
things that doesn't make any sense so of
course here I use tracer but if I give
this talk in Perea we use a ledger here
so as always written language is a
digital people jockey so I'm talking now
about political political vector attack
vectors technical sabotage political
band political normalization and
politicized AI jacking the first one is
something that they will not discuss at
length because you all know about that
many of these political scenario
political attacks scenarios were
discussed yesterday during the fox of
Crito crypto Wars talk so the government
want to stop this technology so the
government or the government or the
central banks or the Khmer
banks controlled by the government or
the tax agencies or the year or the sec
or whatever they try to stop the
technology hacking it violating it
putting backdoor into it this is not
really easy to do in Bitcoin this has
been done at least with Internet itself
Internet is not very secure from
political act or attacks you think about
centralization of DNS centralization of
ISP Internet is quite vulnerable to that
you can shut down websites in catalunya
you can basically shut down whole
internet in North Korea so you can do
stuff there with Bitcoin people is
starting more wary than people who are
doing the first internet development so
people here is more thinking adversary
early so I think that the eventualities
of a technical attack on Bitcoin nz's is
not really I mean it's something
probably comparable or less dangerous
that what already happened with the
internet which is still pretty a pretty
game changing even if compromised in
many ways internet is pretty much a game
changing technology from a social and
political point of view so let's move to
the second kind of political attack I
don't hack it I just ban it governments
we start to coordinate to ban Bitcoin
this is first of all this is an image of
a prohibition of alcohol and he's here
to represent the fact that even if you
ban alcohol in all the United States the
price of alcohol goes up yesterday in
the forks of crypto operative or talk
smuggler said that is likely the
opposite but I think Steve that when you
prohibit usually the price goes up of
the good anyway this is difficult to do
because many different governments have
to coordinate and because many
government already committed to some
kind of a legitimization of Bitcoin for
example u.s. marshal Seoul
Bitcoin from Silk Road and whatever to
people they didn't soul drugs just
Bitcoin kimono is not super easy to
revert these possible because they can
do they what they want but not super
easy my point is that if you ban Bitcoin
like you ban drugs or you buy like you
can ban how cool you don't really
destroy it probably you destroy my
company you destroy the interview
exchanges research startups the
interfaces but not the technology itself
which is anyway have been born just for
that just a bit of it just to be
resistant to that if it's not possible
for for it to resist it's pointless
all the technical complexity of Bitcoin
is just to avoid this scenario there is
another scenario in which then I call a
political renormalization in which I
don't hack Bitcoin I don't burn Bitcoin
but I try to renormalize Bitcoin I try
to get people to stop using the
disruptive politically disruptive
feature and I and I used Rolly let them
think that's it this is actually the
opposite of the other scenario because
it's so legal that you don't need
censorship resistance anymore I mean
everybody can operate in a clear light
of the day so why not blacklist
addresses why not centralized mining
little bit I mean you don't need four
nodes you don't need to go over tor just
use optical fiber everything is normal
so finally you can use Bitcoin except
that nothing disrupting a political it
is wrapped you in Bitcoin is still
surviving anymore this is not a strategy
that this strategy does exist people is
trying to push for that there are
startups startup CEO's that are pushing
for a keyway C on Bitcoin or maybe even
from a you know Bitcoin is disruptive
mainly from two
point of points-of-view says so sheep
resistance I can spend my money wherever
I want privacy is just a part of
censorship resistance because if I spend
my money and they pay WikiLeaks and I
can do that but then you can to my house
and you put me in prison that's ex post
censorship because it will prevent me to
do that again and other people to do
that in the future so that's another
form of post facto censorship the second
one is a sound monetary policy which is
different which is something concerning
more maybe the central bank's because
it's changing the usual way to do
monetary manipulation basically these
two characteristic of Bitcoin could be
changed by the renormalization for
example I don't know how many of you
watch mr. robot there is the e curve
evil guy in bed with the government and
he says yeah bitcoin is too free we will
launch an alternative which uses the
same technology but is controlled by us
as monetary policy or as financial
tracking and financial control this is
possible unlikely I mean you can do that
in two different ways one way is there
is the permission and blockchain push
sorry provisional blockchain nonsense
and that's that's a way I tell people
that this is a new technology it's not
this is a new way to use the existing
technology in a new disruptive political
fashion and economical fashion the other
way is to create a fake cryptocurrency
that you can actually discuss about with
Vladimir Putin because you control it
entirely you can do bailouts you can do
everything you want you just walk in the
garden with Vladimir and you discuss
this is another renormalize political
renormalization I mean people talking
about this kind of favorite occurrences
they don't talk about censorship
resistant very much I mean the point is
the technology right we want to do we
want to do shiny new startup like things
we just want to buy Lambos creating new
apps because that's
that's we just want to have fun we don't
have to we want to have the gloomy a
libertarian aggressive approach where
everybody is trying to to get to us we
are just happy people playing with state
rich statefulness so this is one I don't
think that this kind of attack is very
worrying because you face this problem
this technology is useless if not used
for ease in tennis its intended purpose
so this is a traditional trance based
system drive it by horses
this is a first automobile so this is
Bitcoin of course it's not perfect it
smells it can change in can explode but
this is called a / vagin so basically
during the Great Depression the people
took engine out of the car and they put
horses there and the man here this is I
mean this can work this stuff can go is
not that it doesn't work it just doesn't
make a lot of sense because it's very
heavy for the horses and it's not very
comfortable for the men driving there it
was not studied for that
the car was studied to be a car with all
its pros and cons so let's move and
parental advisory here let's move to
another kind of a political attack this
was a political attack corner a
normalization in which I tried to
instill into Bitcoin something that was
politically at hearts with the original
Bitcoin let's call it ideology so
bitcoins about privacy
what about qlc becomes about some money
what about inflation so I'm just trying
to counteract the ideology what if
instead I try to completely follow the
the ideology the libertarian son money
free-market censorship persistent
ideology Bitcoin and I try to hijack
that to distort to manipulate that
ideology in a way in which I will not
seek support from
socialist professor at Cornell
University but I will seek support from
libertarians and free-market champions
and maybe on our trip to anarchists at
at crypto Anarchy Institute's what if I
can twist some libertarian ideas in
order to have a political attack driven
by that side internal political hijack
sorry I had to do this this is a this is
a this is a cover slide for the
political hijack attacks of course what
I'm about to say here is an alert
tinfoil hat alert this could be an
attack that is happening now but even if
you think that I'm crazy that I'm
paranoid that I am at the time occurs
peanuts is theories and this is not
happening now not it may be an organized
way that's completely possible what I'm
saying here is that this kind of attack
could happen it could happen completely
driven by the side or equal grow
internally organically or it could start
internally and be somehow triggered or
amplified or used or leveraged by
external entities so even if you think
that this is not happening now and
everything I'm saying now is not
anywhere related with a rate with a
coordinated attack let's just imagine
that this is a possible political attack
surface that could be more dangerous
actually than the other one because they
did the distance between Bitcoin and the
statist central his policies is so clear
that this technology is not going
anywhere anywhere with the normalization
when this attack is more subtile so I
think that these disk IO of course this
attack will not try to change Bitcoin in
a way that it directly loses its
characteristic but it could be if I mean
it could be possibly theoretically a way
to facilitate after a technical sabotage
so if I am part
this attack i will tell we need khcom
bitcoin if I'm part of this attack I
will I will just say in order to a free
market we have to change all the core
devs and then we have to finish with one
implementation that connects with the
nodes of three companies in order to
bootstrap and so we get back to
technical support edge facilitated by
the internal political sabotage
convoluted complex and realistic
probably I don't know maybe I just like
conspiracy theories so I think that
there are two main political
misconception that can be used in order
to perform or trigger or amplify this
kind of attack in theory and they are
actually on the on the difference and in
different ends of the same speech
spectrum it's an interesting because
there paradoxically use it at the same
time but they are actually very very far
apart as a concept
the first kind of political
misconception is the market versus
central planning core devs are
socialists central planners because they
want to decide on a single rate on a
single repo they want to decide how
becoming must must work while every
characteristic of the software must
emerge from the free market I mean we
are all crypto energies we are free
marketeers we don't want central
planning this is a very powerful
argument especially for people that is
not so strong about political science
and it can be suggestive for a I mean
prima facie libertarian guy I mean I
won't free market why I should listen to
a central planner like Bitcoin core
developers which will be of course
centralized hierarchical organization of
course it's not they think that the
misconception here sorry this pictures
not very sucks because I took it from
from distance but this was about the
speech yesterday the speech about
positive libertarianism I don't know if
the speaker is here but it was very very
nice
and there was this part of the speech
that was the market is an abstraction
there are people and companies working
on innovation they're the market that
does not solve any problems people do
the resulting interaction our
interactions are then called the market
by saying market will solve this you
mean other people what about you so this
is a nice concept right the market is
not something that happens without
anybody taking responsibility to try to
create propose assume leadership do
something the market doesn't exist in a
purely entropic state where everybody is
just a crazy partisan without any kind
of organization the trade-off is not
between order and statism and violence
and free market and crazy crazy cows
that's not the trade off the trade off
is violent order or chaos versus
peaceful order and voluntary order and
chaos actually the market is every kind
of system with free interaction no
coercion and not aggression from this is
usually always emerged there is an
emergent consensus from this which is
usually some leadership Authority
spiritual philosophical there is some
specialization division of labor nobody
can do everything you must rely on
something something else
someone has doing this stuff better
because that's how you can have to
improve and build a society
transactional cost minimization I don't
know if you are familiar with Ronald
Coase when I could say is economics that
that won the Nobel Prize studying how
from a free market something like a firm
a company which is not free inside the
company of contracts I have rules I have
I have Cherokee's the reason it it is
born is that it lowers transactional
cost so in the free market there are
emergent higher islands of
and here key and organization also
coordination when we want to coordinate
for language protocol we do create some
kind of restriction or farley but it's
not the violent restriction is a
market-based restriction of the unfolded
degrees of Liberty degrees of freedom of
course what's what is what's keeping
this system honest and and what keeps
this system from degenerating into into
totalitarian dystopian world is that
these islands of organization they can
fail they can be that they have
competition from our side
I create my company I hire whoever I
want but if I'm wrong I will fail I will
pay skin in the game feedback loop of
course if there is a we are not in the
market anymore if any of these
organizations start to eliminate the
external pressure with coercion of
aggression so if you have a set the core
developers which are not an organization
by the way by the Jews that I let's say
you have a company working on Bitcoin
that's completely legit but if this
company starts to kill or to put to
kidnap people competing with with it
like a government will do if you compete
with the government of same territory
then you are out of the market and you
are in the realm of brute force and not
cryptographic of brute force so this one
side of the debate and it has some
interesting interesting corollaries like
technically emerging consensus inside
the program versus artificial limits so
you know the argument here is no 1
megabyte is an artificial limit let's
let's just market the side and you could
do a you could actually go on and say no
10 minutes is an artificial limit let
the market decide and you could do that
with any kind of piece of software
because software is actually a set of
limitation proposed by the author of the
software
the software is an example of artificial
limits that are useful for your goal
what is the best I can give you a box
and I can tell you this box is so nice
it is it contains a program which is so
flexible that you can do anything with
it it's more than curing complete and
state full rich state full it's after
you can do Facebook you can do Google
you can do any program because it's an
empty car disk and you can actually do
whatever you want because you just
changed you just change the single
clusters and you can do everything but
Apple is more useful when I provide you
with limitation if they are not enforced
on you if I propose the limitation to
you and you choose to run that software
then it's actually not in artificial
limit it's a itself software works so
this is a consequence of the first
misconception another one which is a
completely separate as Kingdom but it
has been used in the same kind of debate
is free speech versus censorship if if I
ever if I am a publisher of a newspaper
and you come into my office and you
pretend to use by my journal my
newspaper
my newspaper in order to publish
something that I don't believe in which
is again with my editorial line or
against my my beliefs or against reality
I do have to host your article
otherwise I'm censoring you of course
this is a this is a very serious
manipulation of the world censorship
this is completely different from what
usually we mean when we speak when we
speak about free speech and censorship
to be fair this kind of misconception it
not is not just present aside political
Bitcoin block size whatever debate this
is a misconception which is used it is
used in a very broad way in universities
in television
there is a lot of misconception between
a situation where I prevent you from
speak with your resources and your
strategies and your journal and your
your forum or you're ready to submit it
or the the fact that I just decide to
moderate my single-channel communication
the hell in what whatever way I want
because this is a private initiative and
there is competition here somebody else
can come out with another suppress it
and maybe it would be so wonderful that
everybody will leave our Bitcoin and
everybody will go on our b2c right
that's what happened when when you have
bad mothers your policy and you have an
alternative or not if it's not bad so
these are two declination of this kind
of political attack and this kind of
misconception there is another one which
is interestingly actually at the at the
other end of the spectrum so the after
the same people sometimes are saying
what's wrong with one company one guy
producing all the ethics in the world I
mean aren't we free-market capitalist
it's just normal that just one guy can
compete what do you want government
fixing quotas are you a socialist it's
it's been it's nice to have I mean yeah
this implementation of Bitcoin connects
with nodes of three companies all
participated by a single investment
group I mean what's wrong with that we
we are changing the protocol based on a
meeting of 12 people inside the hotel
married in New York I think that's
capital is we are CEOs so we are free
market that's interesting because it's
as you can see that the completely
opposite spectrum but still used by the
same people in my theoretical not
existing attack scenario and and it's
based on the basically three
misconception three sub misconceptions
the first one is the sensitization like
a company a vertical company ok the
separation is
legit is not against free marking having
a market monopoly of Asics of everything
is completely legit from a libertarian
crypto anarchists anarchist
anarcho-capitalist whatever point of
view what is what it is is not legit
it's legit but it's dangerous because
it's very easy to censor and it's very
easy to corrupt so you cannot use the
argument that creating a company that
controls everything in bitcoin is a anti
libertarian it's not but you can use the
argument that it doesn't work because
it's happening with a cash with eagled
with linden dollars with people when
they try to create the currency without
the centralization you are completely
legit you can be a free market
capitalist but it doesn't work because
if you are trying to change the status
quo too much you will be censored or you
will be paid off you will be corrupt you
will be both so this is basically also a
misconception that that comes from
another misconception about what
consensus really means people some
people not very expert technical in
Bitcoin they think that Satoshi Nakamoto
delivered a magical magical trick that
somehow can technically solve the
governance problem and when you have to
agree the protocol change the rule after
you just use the consensus but that's
completely not true the comodo consensus
is used to solve a very specific
government governance problem which is
chronology of the transaction what
happens if this kind of consensus goes
wrong what happens is a double spending
risk censorship the solution is proof of
work so proof work is the solution for
the double spending problem is not the
general solution for the rule changing
problem we don't have an automatic fair
solution to this proof work can be both
and can be bought by purchased by
attackers with without problems actually
it could happen so another thing is that
protocol coordination is very
to bootstrap this is also something
related with and I go to finish in and
two minutes this is also related with
monetization and profit Satoshi Nakamoto
cooled have just pre minded the Bitcoin
that was or or I've done an IC o---- for
VidCon
there is nothing ethically wrong in that
if it's I mean if for cheap rate is not
scam and it's if it makes sense but the
promise that Satoshi choose not to do
that because otherwise bootstrap the
trust bootstrap the network would have
been extremely difficult so we can you
cannot use the classical your article
company structure for everything because
we are trying to construct a free open
global network also Bitcoin may be
unique may be an experiment which is
very in difficult to if not impossible
to do again if it fails the interesting
thing about the unity of Bitcoin is that
even if I'm I even if I'm wrong I'm
right away because let's consider a
classical objection to this no guy
Bitcoin is not unique we need to change
Bitcoin quickly or our coins will take
over the interesting logical consequence
of this sentence is that incorrect as
you can read here very correct because
if Bitcoin is unique then our coin
cannot take over because it's unique
nobody know I'll know as tentative
network can provide the same value
proposition at least in the long run but
if it's not correct and because it's
easy to replace a replicator then what's
the problem
we can still not cheat Bitcoin some a
coin will take over and we will be happy
about that because we will have the
final value proposition that we were
seeking anyway so this point must be
considered must be considered anyway in
the direction of concern conservation
and protection of Bitcoin
this is the last reside just to tell
that these two misconception
I will not analyze the slide in
but I just want to try to give you them
the suggestion about it there are two
different layers one layer is
infrastructure networks protocols like
languages money internet in these layers
you even if you are a free-market
anarchist in this layered layer of
products service or firms or company you
want disruption change rapid change
evolution you want competition choice
multiplicity you want also
centralization and profit they are
completely okay and and in this
different layer the layer which is
underneath actually it's a degree of
course you can have the classical
example you have candy crash the
Facebook game then your Facebook then
you have the web then you have the TCP
and HTTP then disappear ap bitcoin is
down here is a protocol and open
infrastructure proto is not the product
and when you have an open infrastructure
protocol for very real or various
reasons you don't want change disruption
continue crucial you want a stability
reliability resilience you want
cooperation and convert convergence
instead of competition and multiplicity
and you cannot have easily
centralization and profit not because
it's not legit but because it doesn't
work sorry it was a little bit longer
than I expected questions
[Applause]
so thank you is recommend for this
insightful speech I really like it's
Italian speed so what is your questions
it cannot be
show me the nude again I will not any
questions yeah there are thank you for a
wonderful talk do you think that the
recent merge of possibility to who these
guys as s2x clients as s1x clients will
somehow affect people's minds like do
you think they will wake up and see that
s2x
is fraud which kind of which people the
people organizing these are the people
the people pushing for this the people
who think that s2x
good idea so I think that there is not a
unique answer to your question I think
there are very different interests here
for example I think that people with a
lot of economical interest in Bitcoin
ecosystem will probably chicken out and
save face somehow before the death
before the disaster while some people
that has nothing to lose maybe because
it has not strong commercial interest
but just reputational interest they
could be incentivized to go on anyway I
give an example I don't think maybe I'm
wrong but I'm no sorry I don't know
maybe I'm wrong but I don't think that
before be cash
Chien who were really willing to four to
split Bitcoin because I mean who's the
dangerous move for a minor to do what
happened what happens that after a
conference some developers that I see I
believe are not strictly related with
Jia who the they decided to split
anyway and with the strange funny
difficult adjustment anger it and then
the miners started to play with it to
play games but they will probably didn't
with be xtxt they didn't do that with be
classic they didn't do that with be a
limited probably they were they weren't
going to go on with Bitcoin ABC or
whatever but some somebody has did and
they started to play with it something
similar could happen with the bit wax
series company that understand that this
attempt to political takeover has failed
I mean if it was possible to succeed
they would have gone over but this is
clearly failed they will probably step
back but maybe some developer that as as
bad always reputation on this book if we
go on anyway and some minor will play
with it so I think that the split is at
this point still possible maybe with as
market cap comparable to I don't know ha
maybe they will play with the market cap
of big cash on some data it was a very
good one
my question is what can the Chinese
government do to corrupt the minor for
example and perform an attack and the
other one is what can central bands do
to attack Bitcoin for example by
printing money to buy a lot of Bitcoin
and and selling them or something like
that
so I think that both both adversaries
can do something which is anyway
temporary not really long-term damage
but in short short term could be use
damaged government Chinese government
can burn Bitcoin mining for example but
that will not be really a smart move
what I suspect they are trying to do is
to nationalize Bitcoin mining somehow so
I mean how many payment companies how
many I mean how many every kind of
company to account big ones in China
usually one with a strong participation
on the government so that's the day
this style of crony capitalism so it's I
mean I don't know I'm not an expert of
China and you know anyhow so I think
that they will try to reopen exchanges
and to smoothly switch they consistent
from distributive one to a centralized
one the kind of attack you can perform
when you have control of our mining is
basically censorship for some time and
that was pending off your own money
both things can damage Bitcoin the
short-term but then the long term you
just put you just give a competitive
advantage to two little no Chinese miner
or very little anonymous Chinese miner
or - outside China so you just destroy
what you try to control it's like I mean
empty cause at 90% of the market okay
what can you do if you control empty
cause you can change the price with
weally you can do a lot of things but
eventually you will just destroy your
your toy so in the long run I don't
think that there is a even if you I mean
you are the Federal Reserve you print
money to buy some trillions of Bitcoin I
mean thank you and now okay now you sell
okay I mean somebody that the traders
will be okay my question is what about
her fourth good question yeah I didn't
spell it but yeah I put antifragility
many people says that bitcoin is
antifragile
is nice it's nice to think that we also
have the tissue
the fragility from scaling Bitcoin
mantra probably Bitcoin at this point is
more robust than ante for the market
around Bitcoin exchanges the miners are
antifragile context the protocol itself
is not a differential it is robust if
you you cannot break it but if you do
break it you probably create a lot of
long long long run damage in my opinion
so if ad coins were possible you would
have actually an anti fragile system the
problem with alkynes is that when
Bitcoin was born it was so little that
it was ignored but and when it was known
it was so big that it was very difficult
to attack no alkyne can replicate that
in a foreseeable future it can face
every alternative will be compromised
since day one or will be just shut down
immediately it's very difficult to
imagine a situation similar to Bitcoin
also the disappointment and the delusion
will the broken delusion will will play
a role in the trust of a next system so
I don't think it's possible to create a
new Bitcoin that's it
there are defeat there are different
problems with an alkyne one of these
problems is distribution of the initial
wealth for coins like the result of
splits they have a better with the
solution that puerile coin they are more
legit on that point of view if in my
personal in my personal rankings I will
say that the most scam II think that you
can do is is a new al coin with a new
token to bootstrap economically a new
proof of work to strap technically a new
code base to construct
I mean computer science wise and and
that's that's actual you are you're just
destroying all the network effects of
bitch and the new capitalization of
course well if you do for example merge
mining you like
named coin did you are saving one a
torque effect if you're doing
you are saving at least one other
network effect of course the best way to
split the value will be to a packed side
chains where you can obtain switch
between different Bitcoin implementation
conserving the market cap the market
depth the price with minor with minor
arbitrage of course while the fork is
like a diverging price I mean it's very
complicated question so the answer
should take a lot of time but I think
that if for a harness for coin is better
than another coin unless it's used as a
phishing attack so you promote it as
Bitcoin or to create confusion and to
steal other kind of network effects so
we have the time for last question
previous question is do you think
there's a possibility of a market base
that icon Bitcoin where you know the bad
actors don't interact with the Bitcoin
system they just manipulate the prices
through like the futures markets and you
know maybe if Bitcoin cost $400 today
and be cash cost $4,000 today people
would have different opinions about you
know which fork is the right one you can
manipulate the market you can always in
every kind of market but it's not and
you cannot do that indefinitely forever
and to infinite you can do that usually
following trend or you can do that again
strength but burning a lot of money in
doing that so if governments could
manipulate everything always they will
just avoid when they create a subprime
housing mortgage bubble they will try to
prevent the purse but they can't they
can just a can just pump but when the
bubble burst they cannot do anything
with interest rates they manipulate
interest rates then interest rates
explodes or inflation they play with
inflation but when inflation explodes
they cannot stop it in the power they
cannot stop in
by my Republic they cannot stop it
anywhere else so of course they can
manipulate short term and up to a limit
Bitcoin price in order to take it down
or to or to or to pump it up but if they
against that we are trend the cost of
doing that will divert diverge over time
and even if they can bring money they
cannot do that without consequences
otherwise we would have to we would have
that there they receive for happiness
for everybody okay one more question of
mine how do you see the Segway 2x attack
will play out according to how do you
see the situation yeah I partially
answered I don't know I really don't
know I think that the most probable
scenario is a scenario which major
responsible player with strong economic
interest will find a way to save face
like they did with you a you a safe they
save it face just merging people naughty
one they will in order to not suffer the
UA SF they will try something like that
they will try I don't think that is in
the interest of digital currency group
to actually move the pieces over null
coin so they will probably withdrawal
partially ambiguously delaying while
some people like the developers like
guards equal whatever I don't see for
them strong incentives to back back off
right now they will probably go and to
create their art coins because I mean
it's that's what other people did in the
past
okay thank you Jack come on
[Applause]