I'm very happy to be here to be back
here and I'm very happy there is this
productive partnership between school I
represent and parallel police because
indeed there is a lot of room for mutual
cooperation first few things about my
background I am president of a private
college private small private university
located in Prague in the very historical
center of Prague the college is private
so we get no money from the government
at all I have to compete with heavily
subsidized public schools and to do it
our very recent achievement was
accreditation of a program which is very
unique locally meaning in the Czech
Republic but also perhaps on the
European continent we started a program
called PPE philosophy politics economics
and within this program to which by the
way students from over 25 countries from
all over the world came and study you
can specialize in many things one of
them being what I spend some time to
developing in the Czech Republic and
that is the ideas of the so-called
Austrian School of Economics so this
branch of economics which is very much
in favor of competition freedom private
property and like my talk today will be
devoted to the problem of anarchy and
maybe the title could be confusing for
some people I call it anarchy as a
conservative program I believe that many
people not necessarily in this room but
generally believe that anarchy is first
associated with chaos and second that
it's about some sort of rebel
revolutionary change
I will claim that both of these
statements are not correct that actually
there can be an often is order producing
anarchy and second that the ideas behind
the argument in favor of Anarchy are
actually far from a revolutionary that
as you will see hopefully we will we
will show that very conservative
common-sense the horrible ideas are
perfectly fine to justify social order
which can be characterized as anarchy in
the twentieth century
we lived through a horrible time the
reason mostly being that people for some
reason wanted to experiment with
monopolization of state power that we
went through all these horrible
experiment of international socialism
National Socialism and today at least
here we are in this face of democratic
socialism or as many people call it
participatory fascism simply that
nominally we have around us property
owners people nominally are listed as
those who actually decide how exactly
let's say to run their businesses but in
reality it is not the owners who decide
because in more and more instances those
nominal owners have to do what the state
tells them so
at least the horrors of national and
international socialism were replaced by
a society which is freer however still
far from achieving full peaceful
harmonious cooperation among people
we've learned some lessons so far at
least namely that experimenting too much
with institutionalized violence doesn't
bring us good life rather than ending in
the world of prosperity and peace we too
often end up in the world of violence
and poverty so at least in this country
we've learned the lesson of maybe
attractive idea of central planning
Island communism but hopefully people
now understand it's not the way to go
that rather than having central planning
it's better to replace it by individual
planning rather than having political
means as the cool way how to get income
meaning rather than having access to
other people's money it's better to rely
on economic means there is production
trade peaceful voluntary exchange rather
than having society based on coercion
it's better to let people decide what
they want or another perspective can be
rather than having no choice that is
rather than having monopolies monopolies
stick providers of
Services is actually much more
preferable to have competition so this
is the lesson which shows us that when
we eliminate those top-down relations
and replace it with horizontal relations
and bottom-up development we actually
can see the beauty of individually based
societies which is nicely characterized
by this quote by Robert Nozick which
which says that in a free society all
capitalist that is voluntary acts
between consenting adults should be
legal this is what freedom means
grown-up people can enter into
activities which they both want
irrespective of you know the sort of
morality of it as long as these acts are
peaceful and voluntary should be allowed
now such a society shows us or can be
described in three different dimensions
the first is manifestation of freedom
that is in such a society when voluntary
capitalist X Act among or between
consenting adults will be legal people
pursue their lives and pursue their
happiness and people persuade different
goals and different objectives can
peacefully live next to each other there
is no conflict
it gives such society people choice to
pursue their virtues and vices that is
in such a society and only in such a
society people can do these generous
acts of charity and show that they
actually care about other people on the
other hand they can do things which are
not necessarily super nice they can you
know take drugs the taking drugs might
be you know problematic for your health
however does not contradict the concept
of capitalist acts between consenting
adults being the building stone of a
free society and as long as people have
freedom to do both good things and bad
things and then they decide to do good
things only then we can actually show
what you know true civilization means
that we have the right to do things
which are not nice and we don't then we
do not do them because we decide not to
and indeed this manifestation of freedom
in such a society means that I can
associate with who I want
and indeed the flip side of the same
point is that you know I should have
right to disassociate with people I do
not like I be it employees be it buyers
be it business partner seems simply
freedom means the right to have yes to a
contract and it also means the right to
have no to a contract saying no is a
peaceful act it is a capitalist Act
between consenting adults you know I do
business with someone I consent to some
trade and I say no to someone else and
this should be true
in a free society in all spheres of
human life as long as it is peaceful
when people have this freedom then
indeed they can generate prosperity and
the whole science of economics and I'm
an economist is about is about it so
once people have freedom to do business
to be entrepreneurial well then they
produce prosperity division of labour
happens people specialize in different
things people are innovative people have
incentives to satisfy other PR people's
preferences and so on and so forth
so not only do we have freedom in such a
society but we we become richer and
again in a free society this
manifestation of freedom production of
wealth improvement of life should be
allowed in all spheres of human life and
has to be done in all situations where
economic problems exists that is we have
limited sources or resources and we want
to achieve a lot of goals so we have to
find smart ways how to make our life
better well and the third dimension of
such a free society is that it actually
will be a just society people exercise
the rights the rights are respected and
protected and all people have the same
rights nobody is above them so so there
are such a society is a society with no
privileges right only voluntary
exchanges happen and if somebody wants
to exercise violence then he or she is
stopped
again if we want to have a free society
it has to be done in all spheres of
human life
now economists have known this at least
since the time of Adam Smith he
advocated the system of economic Anarchy
meaning absence of politician of
production with the result being order
so ordered society produced by free
activities of individual and Adam Smith
at the end of the 18th century said that
nothing more is needed to produce better
life then peace is a Texas and tolerable
system of justice and these things only
for the two reasons or four or tooth yes
two reasons which are first you have to
eliminate predation so he believed the
state should be here to catch criminals
thieves and robbers and second in the
public predation also should not be
allowed so he believed the state should
be very small that's why easy Texas and
the rest is you know markets people's
cooperation only so Adam Smith advocated
economic anarchy and saw a small role
for the state the wall of the state was
to eliminate predation
however the consequences in the 20th
century at least was that the state did
many things and among these things he
was killing people I make a reference to
this book by Professor Rumble who
calculated how many people got killed in
the 20th century only
by their own governments during
peacetime right and it's quite a lot of
people so isn't it kind of naive to
believe the state will do good things
only if we have this empirical evidence
and hence not only economists but
political scientists and other people
started to go beyond Smith and said well
we actually have to study or extend
Anarchy beyond what Smith believed is
the proper room for Anarchy and hence
this whole project of analytical
anarchists will get started by several
people I have here professor peter Beth
gift from George Mason University who by
the way is the one who is the director
of the Austrian specialization in our
PPE program here in Prague and you know
very recently a lot of books got
published on Anarchy by leading
publishing houses Oxford Cambridge in
this case and those books simply say the
obvious you know if we somehow believe
it's good to have peaceful cooperation
in order to have quality services then
it's good for all services including
defence security law and so on and so
forth and indeed a lot of scholars
historically devoted their scholarly
afford to explanation of these things I
have Murray Rothbard here at David
Freedman David Friedman Nobel Prize
winning economist Vernon Smith but also
more than authors such as damage car
Beck who studies social order in
American prisons this is all about ways
how order is introduced without
political authority and indeed a big
maybe the biggest classic of all is good
stuff the more inari who would mid 19th
century who was a French economist and
he said well you know if we are all in
favor of competition how come the son
it comes to security production we say
hey here we have to have monopoly and
somehow believe you know good results
will follow why
if monopoly is bad then state monopoly
you know it's bad too if we meet in
every society a service which is called
provision of security elimination of
predation well then we have to have a
good quality service of this sort and
and hence you know the argument is well
just use the simple arguments in favor
of competition two things which even
classics let's say of political economy
or political philosophy believes it
should belong to the state no and now
here is why you know the argument for
anarchy is conservative because it's
arguments in favor of order harmonious
existence of peaceful people and the
peace and prosperity as we mentioned is
created by society and society is a
completely different animal than the
state so the argument is you know
society which means individuals and
families and you know Association social
elite and so on they jointly engage in
mutually beneficial contracts
cooperation trade and so on so there is
nothing like crazy and you know it's not
an argument for experimentation it's
just a good argument for when you allow
peaceful people living next to each
other they will help each other out the
argument
is against experiment to entrust power
and upward privileges to some you know
political entities why should we ever do
it especially given what we know about
the you know potential disasters
potential of state activities the
argument for an arcade rests on the
claim that in a just society people
should have equal rights I have and
should have the same right as as you
independent of the job you do unlike
today if you work today for the
government you know you often have
higher or more rights than what I do if
you work for you know tax collecting
authority you can come to my house take
my money so you know this is not equal
rights for everyone so the argument be
it the old molineres arguments for
private production of security or some
sort of modern equivalent of it is
actually a very simple and traditional
argument in which which says that if you
have a right to protect yourself against
other people robbers and thieves when
you indeed have the right to delegate
your right to someone else
so this for the same reason why when I
need shoes I go to a shoe maker because
he's an expert on providing what I need
by the same logic when I need protection
thieves and robbers I should have the
right to go to an expert who will
protect me private Protection Agency you
know it's simple division of labor
given the right I have protect myself
against violence and indeed if I have
and I believe I have and all of us have
the right to disassociate
so if I have the right to say no well
then logically apply to its ultimate
conclusion it means the right to
secession so now if some people claim
that we have the right to secede from
the European Union as the Czech Republic
well then you know part of what today is
the Czech Republic people who don't want
to live under the political authority of
the Czech Republic should have the right
to secede then cities should have the
right to secede from larger units then
individual city districts should have
the right to secede why not
well then ultimately you know an
individual has the right and should have
the right to secede from a political
authority which he doesn't want to live
under all right if not tell me why and
it is not a radical idea it's simply a
logical application of at some level we
all believe that no such a right exists
and all this argument in favor of
competition secession individual rights
and so on can we apply to other indeed
many other spheres of life and that's
why we have this call for depolarization
of money
you know free money the nationalization
of money or Bitcoin same can be applied
to the protection of environment which
today many people believe all the state
can give us you this service protection
of environment No
hence free-market environmentalism you
know and so on and so on
to sum up I believe there is no logical
consistent argument in favor of power of
some people over other people hence we
have a strong argument for anarchy which
however rests on all those old-fashioned
principles such as individual autonomy
right to contract right to defend
yourself and so on and so forth and if
it we are not somehow able to put this
vision of social reality into our life
at large well at least it's good their
things and places such as peril any
police where you can have islands of
relative freedom thank you for your
attention
[Applause]
thank you very much for a call please
for the questions wait for the mic with
with your question
I have on 2 possible questions for you I
was just wondering how do you justify or
give an authority or not even Authority
a justification for property rights or
what defines someone's right to property
and yeah if you could answer that at all
well it's all the right from the plain
fact that people own should own
themselves so is the self ownership
something which I guess it's not only
common sensical but it's also rooted in
the tradition of you know Western law
let's say and the right to property is
an extension of the right to self
ownership because we have something to
do with an entrepreneurial activity of
my body which I own and the interaction
with unknown resources so if nobody
claims a piece of nature around me and
I'm the one who transforms that into a
product then the product becomes mine
then if you want it you have to come to
me and try try to make a deal with me if
I agree then the property gets
transferred to you
so they put from different perspective
the strongest case on a an old piece of
nature around me kind of obviously I
believe has the guy who is there first
rather than the second or third or
fourth or you know one one hundreds or
something
so this is a simple general argument how
unknown property becomes somebody's
property whereas John Locke
explained it property emerges when you
mix your labor with unknown piece of
nature or land okay another question
thanks for the talk first you talked a
lot about like shared values and things
that anarchists and conservatives has
done common are there any issues or
values or positions where the two
movements actually are separated or
would have yeah would need a discussion
on and three by the two movements you
mean well anarchists and conservatives
like classical conservatives classical
anarchists well what I'm trying to argue
here is that this anarchism or
anarcho-capitalism or uh narco
libertarianism is simply a logical
extension of classical liberals slash
conservative argument of the 19th
century what today constitutes textbooks
and the the only difference in play is
that the classical liberal argument says
you know we need this non-market
framework which will create room for
then peaceful coexistence and the
framework is what the state should do
and those anarcho-capitalists
libertarians say well what if not what
if what if the state is here to protect
me and is actually attacking me then
shall I do I have an argument for not
entrusting those huge powers to a
monopolistic agency and they say there
is a very good argument not to do it
especially given the empirical evidence
of the 20th century
and before right so I would say we can
we can argue that there was hope
by the way formulated in many historian
historical documents such as the United
States Constitution that if you somehow
manage to tie state hands to do only
those few things which allegedly has to
be done that then somehow peace and
prosperity will follow and we see that
there is no like legal constrain which
can prevent States from growing
irrespective of where the states are we
see what is happening in the United
States and in Europe and elsewhere
states which were supposed to be small
and just provide security and peace
consuming a little fraction of people's
income you know suddenly take half of
what people make and do do a lot of
activities widgets which have nothing to
do with protection of people their
property peace harmony it's more about
you know taking from majorities and then
you know like subsidizing minorities
rich minorities so the state became a
tool for very few people who managed to
somehow manipulate the state in their
favor so it became the tool of getting
money and wealth which they would not be
able to get just by offering some
products to people because simply today
very often big businesses not all but a
lot of them are at the same time biggest
recipient of subsidies and all the rest
of it and you know who came who can
actually meaningfully advocate
bring forward arguments in favor of such
a system I guess it's very difficult and
we have to just be realistic about it
you know I have a kind of a basic
question although I don't know if I have
a very good answer for it so I'm
wondering what you think about the idea
of with with violence and hiring private
security forces and stuff how do you how
does anarchism solve the the concept of
just you know the kind of protection
money mafia style thing where there's
crime that's happening and then they're
like oh we can protect you from it
yep well good question and indeed and
maybe it's worth it to mention that
indeed historically you had honor keys
who somehow and by the way communists as
well who believed that you know first
you have somehow to change people so
that everybody is good or something and
then this new system will work this is
not what what this analytical anarchism
is here it is indeed assume that people
are both good and bad there are thieves
around us and robbers and crazy people
around us and maybe that's why it's not
very useful to privilege some people
because the thieves and robbers and
crazy people can become governmental
officials and then what do you do how do
you protect yourself right so this is
one one take on it and what is like the
alternative or you know how else can we
say have how else can we have security
well you know contract division of labor
so private agencies who will be
contractually bound to provide only
services which you know they promised to
provide for specific amount of money
right then if the private agency does
something else or wants to charge you
more money well you have a contract in
your hand and say no now you are
becoming a
because this is not what you were
supposed to do you you do not have claim
over my money but this you know you may
say well but you know the states also
have some kind of legislative contract
with you yeah but the contract is
constantly changing again empirically
but you see historically you know what
started small became big government
started to claim more and more money and
started fighting more and more wars
against people who were no threat to you
know the population the government's
were supposed to protect
so private agencies now you may say well
what if some agency will behave like a
state okay well then you know that's the
worst scenario that the private agency
which will be contractually bound will
behave like a state but today we have
the state already so like the worst
scenario is current situation and very
good reasons why and there are books
about it indeed you know this the worst
scenario that means monopolization of
originally competing agency why that
would not happen
argh a nothing is sure you only can
analyze and do this the whole project
analytical anarchism is well let's
analyze let's say the stability and
quality of services including security
services provision of money and so on
when you have private competing system
and monopolize system and that's all
what it is and you know then you do the
research if you want to argue for
monopolistic provision of money
okay well try it you know I wish you
luck given what the central banks have
done in the 20th century right would any
private provider of money could could
anyone behave you know any any worse
than what the state
it and I'll do do believe I mentioned
this 260 million people killed by
government during peacetime you can
imagine that the private agents like
coca-cola private agency you know
killing 200 million people so you know
just I call for realistic evaluation of
possible good and bad outcome under two
different institutional scenarios
competition contract versus politics and
monopolies that's all I think yeah okay
good yeah thank you for for starting
that bit about the private security
versus this state security I'm trying to
imagine the scenario where well the
private security if I'm rich enough
I'll get the private security will
secure me my more of my rights better
against this small guy over there whose
private security is not as well equipped
not only the the smoke I will just have
to I'll step back from the line between
you know if I say my my garden ends over
here because I have bigger guy your
garden will end over there will start
you know because you have a small guy to
protect your garden so in the state
there is supposed to be this this
political feedback where the state
actually lays out these these evils are
evenly distributed are more even lesser
another you know there are more email
distributed then those evils who are
localized to the big guy versus the
small guy well what do you have to say
to that again I mentioned several
authors who devoted their life to study
historical instances of legal systems
which were not monopolized and you know
you have a strong argument for believing
in the market process or elimination of
these crooks
from the system and the competition you
know it's is more easily to be imagined
in commercial activities so the whole
let's say medieval law merchants was
actually privately produced law because
traders traded you know over long
distances so there was like they were
like National League monopolistic legal
systems that those parties of the
contract were from different states so
actually you know they didn't have
anyone above and hence mechanisms how to
resolve conflicts developed so we have
historical instances of that we have
wonderful books written of I will
mention one by Terry Anderson PJ here
it's called the not so wild wild west
which actually talks about the u.s.
towards the was a 8th of the 19th
century the western frontier where
formerly was American government but no
American a governmental agents but there
were actually activities commercial both
commercial and general social activities
and sometimes conflict happened and they
had to discover you know solutions to
the problem to eliminate predation to
catch thieves and robbers and it's
nicely described how how it worked
sometimes the whole countries worked
under under the system you know Ireland
before British took over medieval
Iceland and so on and so forth so there
there is a lot of cases and today we
have like instances not on a national
scale but more like a club club scale so
sometimes stock exchanges operating
under private truths all that but both
the books I presented at the beginning
published by Cambridge and Oxford Peter
alysom and at stirring him they they
actually address these issues in
different circumstances people who never
maybe thought about it or read about it
will be surprised how many activities
today in the world
the world of states are actually
organized by private rules right
so maybe you can rephrase the whole pro
the whole debate about like anarchy it's
a debate about how well private rules
operate how do they emerge and how do
you enforce them right and then it
doesn't doesn't sound radical at all
because we all have a lot of experience
with a lot of systems of private rules
be it you know like things like you know
Visa card PayPal or you know these these
things where all cases like you know
when Jewish traders trade diamonds and
when they have conflict they never go to
the state court they have mechanisms how
to have to do it so there are tons and
tons of instances how private rules
actually work better than you think
which is the subtitle of one of those
books hi
so I hope my question won't be very
primitive as I'm not very good in this
discussion but in what our family the
pace on ask I asked it so much a
question I didn't get a satisfying
answer so I'm going to ask you that's
assuming that based on what you said
that if if I owned some some something
first like a land first
I'm the owner so I have a land and
suddenly I found a very big source of
oil in it and so I'm afraid in this
world of Anarchy I'm afraid that my
neighbors want to attack me and get my
land and with my source so I'm hiring
mmm private army for myself and but this
money that I have is endless somehow
when I have oil oil so how what would
protect me against this army how much I
should pay them the best idea is that I
pay them half and half so half of that
would be mine how that would be then but
again what would protect me against them
to kill me and get my land in such a
world
again just you know take a look at the
reality of today's world our world is
full of government's who perform like
mafias exactly the way you described
that you know natural resources found on
somebody's land and then the state army
comes and takes over and all these
dictators then you know have a source of
living for years so it sure it can
happen it's not in one system only where
it can happen it can it can happen at
you know it both well with like system
of private rules and system of
monopolize governmental services that
was the answer that I got from tomash so
satisfied and then you you know you have
to if you want to compare realistically
well then the history of is full of
examples there isn't there is no
question about the fact that you need
the rule of law you need legal
protection against robbers and thieves
if you want to live in a peaceful
society a civilized society but then the
question is how do you get more quality
peace better cheaper services of
protection and I'm just saying that it
is not that the obvious answer is
governments will provide it because you
know sometimes they do sometimes they
don't sometimes they behave like sucks
and mafias so I just want to bring a
comparative framework and not state as a
solution as a default solution
we hint we have time for one more
question
Thanks hi so what from what I understand
is the individual is the center of
Anarchy and that makes responsibility of
the individual the backbone of anarchy
so my everyday life experience many
people that are unable and the vast
majority that is unwilling to take over
responsibility for their actions so
let's talk about change we are living in
the current system that is far from
anarchy so if we're talking about this
very nice idea of Anarchy we also have
to take into account that we need to
change the mindset of people which is a
very very from my point of view of a
very hard thing to get people to take
over responsibility so is there any
discourse or philosophical idea or
research on how that can be accomplished
from getting from this system we're
living in today into this very
responsibility centered system of a net
panicky well I don't agree with the
premise of your argument I I don't
believe we first have to change people
to establish a peaceful society this is
this utopian either socialism or on our
kids and now we have to work with people
as they are many irresponsible behavior
today is a consequence of all sorts of
feel that they use social programs or
socialized medicine people then once you
can behave irresponsibly and let other
people pay the bill but then you will do
it and the more generous very often
states are in helping people the more
irresponsible behavior they create so
what I am calling for is not changing
people its
it's protecting rights and hence you
know then I will create situation when
people pay for their own mistakes it's
like you know if you have an insurance
of your car and you hit the wall then
it's bad but you have insurance you kind
of you know thought about it before if
you don't have an insurance and hit the
wall well tough luck you lost
you know the car and you know maybe get
injured but it will be you who bears the
cost of your irresponsibility at the
same time the system which I'm talking
about is a system where you can have
communities of people living peacefully
next to each other you can have
religious groups who will you know let's
say believe in certain virtues how to
live your life and you will have out the
group's next door who will simply behave
strangely seen from the perspective of
the first group and they still as long
as rights are respected they can live
peacefully next to each other the
problem arises when you start democracy
with those two groups let's say and then
you have like you know majority voting
you know what will be supported by
taxpayers money you know and then the
first group was that you know view you
have to have let's say you know religion
in elementary school and the other group
says you know you have to have you know
sex education or something and and as if
there was one good model of how to live
for our people it is not and we have to
you know take that into account you know
we may strongly believe into something
other people may have the complete
opposite view well that's what society
is people are different
we have to have our autonomous little
islands of our own
which is called private property that's
what that must be the core value and
core social institution thank you for
your questions thank you for your
answers but in the first place thank you
for your talk Thanks
[Applause]