my name is Justin and a good afternoon
everybody
I think one of the most interesting
things about working in and around bit
coin and crypto finances all of the
interesting people that I get to meet
and everybody has an interesting story
or anecdote about how they they became
interested in Bitcoin so what what
brought you to Bitcoin and so I have I
have two anecdotes I'll share with you
personal anecdotes about how I got
started and and maybe that gives you
some insight into how I think about
cryptocurrency so a couple years ago
banks and financial service institutions
they started offering a product called
online banking and this was a little
while ago but it was really convenient
and so I I didn't know much about money
and I also didn't really care I was the
type of person that didn't keep much
food on hand in my cabinets I ran my
life as a just-in-time factory so it's a
it's a Kanban system and I would go to
the grocery store when I needed food and
so one day I ran out of food and and I
go to the grocery store and I went to
pay and I used the credit card and it
didn't work and then I used the debit
card and it didn't work and you know the
other interesting thing is that I didn't
have any cash on me at the time because
I thought cash was was inconvenient I
thought it was sort of dirty and just
was ancient why would I use this when I
have this digital system and and also
the bank made me pay to take out cash so
this was a strong incentive to not use
it so I I realized at that point that I
didn't have many options that I couldn't
eat until I got in touch with the bank
so I laugh
the grocery store hungry and now annoyed
and I called the bank and I said what's
what's going on with my with my cards
why don't they work and and the guy said
oh well we froze your accounts because
we're not sure we have your current
address and I said that doesn't make
much sense
I said I'm you have my address you know
I gave you my post office box or my post
my post account and he said well no we
have to have your residential address
and that's the point where I started to
really think that's that's strange
I said why do you need to know where I
sleep and he said it's because it's the
law we have to know your residential
address and I thought that was really
really strange so basically they were
holding my my money hostage and me
hostage because I didn't plan ahead and
I was hungry and so now I was totally
subject to the whims of my what I
thought was my business partner I
thought I was sort of doing business
with them but actually there was
something else going on and and I
realized later that this is this is soft
power it's a it's a form of control and
and it's wielded as a weapon today in
certain circumstances and you know I I
just sort of stumbled across it
unwittingly and so what ended up
happening is I started using cash a lot
and I closed down my my bank account
with them and now I I use cash pretty
frequently now
what I learned from this is that
financial sovereignity is really
important and a short while after I
started really getting into Bitcoin and
Bitcoin is really nice because with
Bitcoin I know that that that
circumstance can never happen to me
again
so I know that it will always be there
for me and it will always work I know
that that it's absolutely resilient and
Censorship resistant and and I like that
very much about it it's it's very much
financial sovereignity and and that's
not optional so the other concept is
that by default bitcoin is going to be
there for you and defaults are important
so there's one other kind of interesting
thing or anecdote that happened and and
this also helps shape my my perspective
or my world view on cryptocurrency I was
I was travelling back to Chicago one
time through Miami and I was I was
selected for some additional screening
and I went over to the the desk and the
guy puts on his gloves and he very
carefully goes through my bag and he
spends a lot of time he's really looking
and hoping I think to find something and
I was I started to watch him very
carefully too because that I started to
become suspicious that this guy might
put something in there maybe he's
looking for a promotion or maybe he had
a quota or something I don't know that
I've never really thought about it until
that point and and so after a while he
sort of gets frustrated and he goes over
to a computer and he starts typing and
he types and types and then at some
point he looks up and he says what what
were you doing in Bangkok last year and
he says and then what were you doing in
cool and poor a couple weeks later and I
that with it's that's also really
strange I guess I shouldn't be surprised
that someone has access to my flight
records but I never thought it would be
this guy and I didn't think it would be
wielded as a weapon like this I felt
like I was I was being attacked and and
so the the incident sort of closed
without much without
much adieu I mean I eventually didn't
find anything and he was sort of
dissatisfied and so was I and so the
relationship ended in mutual contempt
and and I left and I wrote an email to
to the department and they apologized so
that was nice I give them credit but
what I realized was that at this point
financial and and in your data privacy
is really important because you can be
caught in an uninspected unexpected
circumstance and somebody could start to
use that against you and and and that
made me also very uncomfortable so one
one thing with with Bitcoin that I knew
from the beginning was that privacy in
Bitcoin is a really fragile thing a by
default if you start using the system
it's ok it's it's pseudonymous you know
if you don't have your identity linked
to your activity then then you can sort
of use it safely so if you always use
cash and you always use a VPN or tor or
something like that
well maybe it's ok but the reality is
that at some point we all kind of fall
we all we all sort of give in to some
sort of temptation whether it's an
airdrop or you know there's a fork that
happens and so you want to sell the the
thing that Forks off of your Bitcoin or
something like that at some point you
end up either wittingly or unwittingly
giving up your ID and then you paint all
of your Bitcoin activity and I think
that's really dangerous also most of the
ATMs the Bitcoin ATMs are tracking
everything that you do and and I find
that's also dangerous so essentially for
me privacy in Bitcoin is is completely
gone so I know in Bitcoin everything I
do is being tracked I know in the back
of my mind that I might get caught at
some point and someone will ask me about
everything that I've ever done
Bitcoin and that that really bothered me
so for a number of years I was looking
for a tool that had had some nice
privacy properties to it and I looked
and looked and I was never satisfied
dark corn dark coin came and went and
black coin came and went and all of
these things came through my filter and
and IA ejected them for one reason or
another and it wasn't until earlier this
year that I had lunch with a friend of
mine at Google and Zurich and and he
said hey get a load of this thing it
started as a scam and and then it was a
scam started by smart people and then
there was a coup and the smart
developers kicked out the previous
developers and they took this coin over
and then they underwent the fatal
privacy flaw that is inherent in in a
totally private coin the the unlimited
creation problem and so they found this
flaw and they fixed it right away and
and then they told everybody else that
was on that same protocol about it and
nobody else fixed the flaw only they did
they said it it's called Manero check it
out and so I did and and I was really
really happy with what I saw so I still
have of course some some technical
concerns but that's true with with all
all things in technology you know I
approach things kind of from an
engineering standpoint and so we we
think in terms of probability and and
overall I think Bitcoin is really nice
because it gives you financial serenity
but Manero is really nice because I
think it gives you financial serenity
but it also gives you privacy and and
and Manero the the case is that neither
is optional so but default your private
and
that was really important because for
normal people and for companies privacy
is key so one thing that I think most
people will overlook or aren't really
aware of is that in the banking system
today especially in Switzerland you can
actually buy privacy and you can buy
quite good privacy you need to have a
lot of money but if you have the money
then you can be very very private
exceptionally private and the the
problem though is that that privacy is
not infallible
the problem is that humans are still in
control of that system and humans are
infallible fallible so the there are a
couple very high-profile cases over the
last few years in Switzerland of private
banks losing client data or giving up
client data and I mean over a hundred
thousand private bank clients have had
their data either stolen or sold or
something like that either by insiders
or by sort of foreign governments
extorting them or something like that
and and that's that's a problem right so
even if you can't afford privacy and the
banking system for the for the few
people in the world began even that is
not guaranteed so what we really need is
a technology that solves that problem
anyway the other problem with banking is
that banks have an adversarial
relationship with their clients and what
I mean is that the bank is going to try
to get absolutely everything it can from
you and give us a little back as
possible so it's it's pure profit driven
pure greed which is fine but in today's
system people give the bank all of their
money in the first place
and then the bank takes even more as
much as possible and and and that causes
all kinds of problems and and so I think
again we have technology that can solve
some of these problems so I think with
technology the the banking world is
going to change significantly and and I
think the role that banks play will
change significantly
so in today's world I don't know of many
people that are satisfied with their
banking relationships my guess is that
most people still have bank accounts
even here it's hard to live off of
Bitcoin at the moment it's hard to live
off of Manero it's also hard to live off
of cash if you're in a developed country
you're sort of on the fringe if you
don't have a bank account and I but I
think that will change significantly so
I have an idea of how banking changes in
the near future and it's maybe maybe we
could call this my roadmap for for
private banking in the future so I think
the bank of tomorrow will start to do
some interesting value-added things I
think banking today is a cost or a tax
on the productive economy and I think
banking tomorrow is actually a
value-added industry it not only is a
third of the global GDP sort of
recovered but now we have something on
top of it and I think the bank is going
to start doing things for their average
clients that that most people have not
really thought about yet there are some
quite progressive banks that that are
already thinking down this path so I
think first of all I think your bank
will start to audit your wallet code I
think they will hire smart people who
will look at open source software and
they'll be able to tell you whether or
not there are backdoors and
not there are certain bugs in it that
you know expose you to certain threats
and I think that's I think that's a
valuable service I think the bank will
also start to provide backups and
restoration services so actually I got
an email from UBS this morning and it
said dear mr. Smith did you know that we
can help you manage your passwords and
keep them safe with our safe storage
locker service and I thought that's
that's nice I use Mac pass but I compile
it myself
and but the problem is that most people
can't compile software themselves so it
makes sense to me that the bank would
reach out to its client base and it
would start to offer a software
management or a password management
solution I think that's quite nice
because I think most people here that
that are experts do you recommend that
people use a password manager so I think
that's that's a fantastic move forward I
also think that banks will help train
their clients to be safe online
I think they'll help people protect
their identities I think they'll help
people control what kind of information
they release online and I think they'll
help also to provide identification and
notary services so no matter how we try
to slice this pie in the real world
there's a human that has a link somehow
to a physical object and we call that
link ownership and we can see it in real
estate today so the question is in the
digital world if someone is trying to
sell a house and you want to buy that
house how do you actually verify that
the person trying to sell the house does
in fact own the house and so that's a
difficult problem that we have and I
think banks will help solve that problem
by by providing this identification and
notarization service now I think finally
and most importantly banks will use
Manero and
I think they'll recommend mineiro in
some cases and I think the more astute
banks will only work with clients using
Manero and not Bitcoin because banks
today don't really like Bitcoin but for
a lot of reasons but why won't they use
Bitcoin number one it's too easy to
learn the identity relationships and
actions of your client in Bitcoin it's
just way too easy and that knowledge is
a huge liability so I grew up not too
far from Chicago and Chicago you know
for years was well-known as it's kind of
a rough place and and there was a mafia
that was operating in Chicago and the
general advice when you were there if
you're walking down the street is to
walk like this so you don't want to be
looking around up at the buildings or
the pretty architecture or anybody else
and what they're doing you just look at
the direction that you're walking if you
hear gunshots and screams just keep
looking and just keep walking and the
reason is that if you become aware of
the activities that are going on around
you you could be called to testify to
your knowledge of those activities and
if you are compelled to testify then you
could end up dead so you don't want to
be party to any information that you
really don't want to be party to right
it's all about context it's all about
controlling the context so knowing is a
huge liability and I think that's why
thanks we'll use Manero it's because in
monaro you don't know what your business
partner was doing and you really have no
idea so if somebody compels you to
testify as to what you know you don't
know anything
so what do I like Manero and I'm in sort
of a general sense I think Mineiro is
sort of like cash in the mail so when I
was growing up they maybe just before
the the internet came about there were
some times where you wanted to pay
someone at a distance and you wanted to
send them cash but you shouldn't really
send people cash in the mail because you
could have a malicious postman or
anybody else that just takes the cash
out of the envelope and then there's no
evidence that you paid it's really
difficult in the u.s. they still use
cheques and that has its own problems so
we end up with this kind of terrible
credit card solution for our distance
payments or distance money transfers we
have Bitcoin now but but again bitcoin
is not quite the same as physical cash
in the mail because in Bitcoin somehow
you can taint the transactions
the other cool thing is that with Manero
you can still prove that you sent it so
if somebody ever says we'll no I
actually didn't get the money you can
you can prove that you did send the
money mathematically and that's also
quite nice that's a nice feature and
then the other thing is that if you're
walking down the street and euros fall
out of your pocket most likely you're
not going to get them back and unless
there's a good Samaritan that that helps
you but the odds are low so with Manero
the money of course is stored on your
hardware and if you lose the hardware
you can restore it and I think that is
also quite important these are things I
think I think most people here know but
it's nice to just put it in a general
context so I think most people here are
very interested in when all of this
happens so yeah it sounds nice that the
banks become useful and valuable
and we want it to happen yesterday and
so the cool thing is that I think it's
all happening now so in Switzerland the
national rail company has ticket
machines all over the country and there
these things are in every town and every
village generally within walking
distance and these things have become
distribution points for different
digital assets and one of those assets
actually is Bitcoin and so now with any
SPB ticket machine you can put cash in
and you can get Bitcoin out so my
favorite use case I use this quite
frequently if I travel to Italy I have
euros when I come back to Switzerland
with euros the first thing I want to do
is get rid of my euros these are
worthless so I put the euros in the
machine and I get Bitcoin back out now
it's something useful now I can buy a
VPN or I can buy a VPS or I can register
a domain name now it's useful the
problem is that when I use this service
I have to enter my phone number my phone
number in Switzerland is linked to my
passport this company actually has to
use a tracking system by law and it
tracks every transaction that happens in
Bitcoin that it can that's what the
regulator's are after so I think the
future of this thing also the the core
idea is that that's a huge cost for
these companies they don't want to be
doing it they're not actually profiting
the companies don't profit from this so
the future of this whole system I think
hinges on the mobile device because the
way we use money and the way we interact
and do commerce now and in the near
future all happens on our mobile device
and the key kind of missing component
right now in the crypto ecosystem I
think is the mobile wallet I think once
we
really nice mobile wallets with a really
nice user experience then we have
something we can work with then it
becomes consumer grade then banking
changes so I been working on a project
for a little while and we have a team in
Switzerland and we have been working on
a Manero wallet for iOS and that's
called the X wallet and the X wallet is
is a really fun project and and its
really gotten some attention and I think
that X wallet is going to change quite a
bit in Switzerland and and around the
world
so today not many people can access
private banking only the wealthiest
people in the world can can do private
banking in Switzerland but tomorrow I
think private banking in Switzerland can
reach over a billion people because over
a billion people have iPhones and all it
takes is a couple taps now to download
this application and start using one
arrow so I think that's really where the
revolution starts that's where this
really becomes big is when we reach a
broad consumer audience and we form the
right partnerships and we really build
the ecosystem so and if there are things
thank you guys
[Applause]
[Music]
okay Thank You Justin for the
presentation and for the great news
about the exfoliat and now we have some
time for some questions from the
audience first fine thank you for your
talk
I'm also Mona a fan I think it's one of
the useful projects in the
cryptocurrency industry one of the few
however you mentioned that like banks
will work with Manero instead of Bitcoin
first of all I want to ask if you really
think so because menara is also
associated with our markets quite a bit
so this reputational flow can deter like
legit banks to use it and my second
concern is that right now there are a
lot of developer teams around Bitcoin
working on similar things to similar
projects as a monorail to create
fungibility and you know anonymity
around Bitcoin as well and I think these
projects are pretty legit there are
smart people working on them so don't
you think this is a threat to Manero
being the only private cryptocurrency
thanks yeah good good question so
two-part question first is the darknet
market association is that an issue I
think no I think you know everyone here
and people around the world authorized
their governments to create an issue
physical cash physical cash notes and I
think that's where the the argument when
any darknet market is involved stops so
when you show me a government that does
not produce physical cash that can be
used in this way then then we'll have a
discussion or a debate about that but
there aren't many governments in the
world that I know of that actually do
not print physical cash so that means
that they also are supporting darknet
mark
it's they've been doing so much longer
and they're implicitly supporting
darknet markets even to this day by
continuing to print cash so that that's
my first thoughts on that and then the
the second part of the question is what
about the other interesting projects
related to privacy and Bitcoin I read
these things are quite quite interesting
the problem is that Bitcoin by design is
an open system and when you engineer a
system in a certain way then it's really
really difficult to come back to that so
you know we talked about Bitcoin and its
scaling issues Bitcoin was designed in a
certain way and if you try to shoehorn
it into doing something that it wasn't
originally fully intended to do then
then it's difficult I guess I guess what
I'm trying to say is that Manero
basically takes Bitcoin and then adds
privacy to it by design and maybe some
systems maybe some some pull requests
can can update Bitcoin and make it just
as good if not better but I don't see
that happening in the next five or ten
years to be honest I think I think the
pace of development in Bitcoin is is
fairly constant at this point I would
certainly welcome the change though I
mean options are what it's all about
good options or what it's all about so
if there are good options for strong
privacy or perfect privacy in Bitcoin
then yes let's let's have it and we'll
build on it but at the moment I I don't
really see how how that would happen
I really see Manero as being a special
purpose vehicle just for privacy and to
behave more as a cash like system I
think you're going to have other trade
offs that happen in Manero
and this QA probably isn't time to talk
about it but there are trade offs and
Bitcoin will remain resilience in ways
that Manero I think cannot
I have a question about the wallet well
if you are ready to release anytime soon
so I hope you expected this question and
also the other question is if you're
writing in in some portable framework
that would allow it to be ported easily
to Android or some other platforms thank
you yeah great question and so
originally when I started this project
it was it was a personal project so I
didn't really think much about it I
thought I'd be a fun sort of Swift
project to build a native app and take
advantage of apples native features and
the the thing that happened is that the
project scope grew really fast and it
attracted more people than I ever
anticipated and that really surprised me
and even even now more and more people
are coming to the project they're
interested and they'd like to help and
not just on a technical level but on a
on a business level and so my focus has
shifted now from just getting something
out there and dumping something into the
App Store which was the original plan
and I had hoped to do that a little
while ago but now the now the focus is
actually on building a company that can
that can build and support a
commercial-grade application for you
know the real future so I mean basically
my my time frame for this app shifted
from three months and then release it to
what will it look like in ten years so
my perspective really changed a lot just
in the last few months so it's being
worked on for sure maybe even more
fervently now than before and it's going
to be more robust than the original plan
and I think when we launch it will have
a number of partnerships and
opportunities to use it that we would
not have otherwise had so strategically
this this ecosystem is being built now
sorry my time yes I think it's
intentional actually it's a conspiracy
[Music]
we should do some I don't know miss
prediction markets to again yeah it's a
great idea it's a great idea I said I
forget the other part of the question
actually is it portable no no it's not
so it would be dedicated to iOS why
strategic reasons okay other questions
so you mentioned it's supposed to be
like Cash Money mo which means that I
would like to be able to pay for coffee
however various transaction fees issues
which is coming to the question what
about second layer of options like
lighting network for more narrow and
such things is it is it too early to
speak about it or is there any answer
about it yeah it's it's a good question
so you know fees have been a persistent
thorn and every one side now for a while
it's it's been in the Bitcoin community
and you know my behavior changes too
with fees and the thing that I realized
though is that with a project like the X
wallet yeah the idea is that what we're
doing is democratizing private Swiss
banking and if you put it in those terms
I mean you went from only servicing
people who had you know half a billion
dollars to put in their bank account and
now pretty much everybody in this room
can do it in the same way I mean if you
put that in perspective some guy was
paying 500 euros for a private or a
secret wire transfer and what are we
paying now to get much better privacy in
our financial transactions so I don't
think that this is a retail payment
solution I mean the number one thing we
all think of is how we use these
technologies in our daily lives as as
retail payments or as consumers and this
really is not the solution for retail
payments mainly because you know I don't
I don't really care I would never pay
more money for a transaction where I'm
just buying coffee
that's a non contentious transaction for
me but if I go to Indonesia and I buy a
beer maybe I'll pay a little bit more to
keep that one private yes yes hi
my question is you are your ex wallet
applet is it an open source application
yes it is the source code available yeah
so it would be MIT licensed and as soon
as it's in the App Store we'll release
the source code
mainly we just went to make sure that we
have the brand established first and
then we release it so that we don't have
all kinds of malicious actors deploying
right away I mean iOS software and I
think I RS you have something that's
called secure in class so all the fights
on the iPhone are kind of encrypted so
that also has the problem that you
cannot really verify a deterministic
build right so why should people trust
you with their financial privacy because
all the transactions that they do they
will be recognized by your application
and I think that your application needs
to have a connection back to some kind
of a Manero full note because you cannot
store the vault the whole manner of
blockchain so how do you make sure that
people can really feel safe and they are
not monitored by your wallet or your
services in the cloud yeah it's a good
question so this this kind of comes into
the technical world of how a Monaro
actually works and so you may be
familiar with with my Manero
the sort of web interface that most
people use when they first start using
Manero
and this one is a full trust environment
right the the backend basically is is
parsing your view key your private view
key and originally when the project
started we had intended to use an open
Minero back-end as well where the users
view key would in fact be transmitted to
a remote server and then of course
there's all kinds of questions with
around that and I really didn't like
that idea in the first place because I
really don't want to run a server
back-end
I don't want to see your view key at all
right I don't I don't want it don't want
your view key keep it keep it to
yourself same thing with the liability
question right don't want to know what
you're doing so basically I just want to
provide an entry an ice wallet service
and what a nice wallet experience for
you so what we what we ended up doing is
we've shifted tack now and so
what we're going to do is is it's going
to connect to a remote node instead so
the entire client is actually stored on
your on your phone and all your keys are
on your phone and they never leave and
what you're doing is you're actually
just requesting data from a remote node
and and then really the only question at
this point is okay we want to make sure
that your remote node has the
performance that we want it to so we
don't want people waiting too long
that's one of the problems one of the
big technical challenges Manero is the
speed right people are used to tap and
then response so millisecond response
times are what people are used to in
condition two
but really now because of the the
cryptographic overhead and z cache has a
lot of you know challenges that as well
we have to really manage that user
experience well and so we might end up
running a performance back and but it's
just a performance remote node basically
so I mean maybe in the future there's
even possibility of having dedicated
hardware or something like that but
again it's it's a development challenge
yeah
either thanks for the talk what is X
wallets business model since you're a
company all do you get profits from it
yeah that's a really good question so
how do you how do you monetize something
like this how do you if you're a crypto
crypto finance or cryptocurrency company
how do you make money if your app is in
the App Store well number one you're
gonna compromised all of your values and
those of your customers if you're
charging money through Apple's App Store
because you have to pay with a credit
card through that right your identity is
immediately linked and it's it's really
not what we're after
so then how do you how do you make money
off this thing it has to be the way the
Swiss private banking works today right
just on a different scale and that means
that we take a small percentage of each
outgoing transaction so the current plan
is one percent of the outgoing
transaction and it's capped at around
one euro so it's again it comes back to
the coffee problem there are a lot of
people all day you know would not like
this this concept too much because they
intend to use this for retail payments
but in fact it's not for retail payments
you know maybe Lightning Network as it
matures what will have a solution for
that but ultimately that's that's our
business model is is we take we operate
as many Swiss banks do today does X
Wallet require that you will run your
own back-end or does it support that or
do do you have to use X wallets back-end
yeah the idea is that when you can
connect to a remote node the original
spec called for being able to select
your own remote node so the idea
hopefully with the first release is that
you'll be able to type in the IP address
of your remote know that you're running
and connect to it and then you'll be
responsible for your own performance
then at that point but yeah I think
that's important to support
other questions hi great talk
if you don't Maya if you don't mind I'd
like to criticize the privacy the so
called privacy of manaro a little so
let's talk about Ring City but I was
still contributing to manaro it seemed
like this is the best governance model
in cryptocurrencies that I've ever seen
except for the fact that fluffy and
Luigi likes to hide the fact about the
security parameter of secret city there
is this low in cryptography that
promising privacy is much worse than
storing stuff in plaintext and this is
what ring city is about because the
security parameter there ring signatures
only protect me from nasty three-letter
agencies from differentiating my
transaction from a group of people
strange ex transactions and that number
is really low so like an RFC standard
for security parameters is 1 minus 1
divided by 200 power of 256 and for
Manero it's 0.9 that's like unacceptable
so first before adopting Minero into
swiss private banking we have to make
molero private and ready what's your
opinion in this accusation of mine yeah
I'm always open to the technical
questions that I also have have
questions and you know I think it's a
really important question to ask because
it's still very it's still a very young
technology yeah it's it's it's a
challenging question and my answer is
that most people don't like the 1% fee
but it's there to basically start to
address some of these questions so we
need to be able to figure out for
ourselves how to provide clients how to
provide our corporate partners with the
assurance that they need that
in whatever probability you know nothing
nothing comes on the radar essentially
it comes back to this question of what
is a bank's role in the future and I
think that's part of the bank's role in
the future and that's a that's something
that really we have to finance and we
have to work on and we have to bring in
outside eyes because I agree with you
there are systemic risks that we need to
we need to address last question thanks
I'm gonna ask you what's your opinion
about hard law bullet implementation of
moliro yeah it's a really good question
it also kind of hits on my strategic
direction so I would love to have the
convergence of hardware and software
happen on the iPhone and that's really
where I'm headed with this thing so I
think that it's good to have other
options you know I love love my
treasures and and I love hardware
wallets and they definitely have a role
and and I think that role becomes only
more important in time but I think for
the consumer experience we need hardware
that we can we can actually trust and I
think Apple is moving in that direction
too okay so thank you very much for our
presentation hope you enjoy
[Applause]