welcome to the Lions Den I think this is
the best way to greet our panelists who
with the exception of one if I'm not
mistaken represents a more traditional
approach towards finances and money we
have a central banker algae we have an
investor - Jakob who is money theorist
and the only group other kids among us
young and my name is Midas touch K which
I'm not power loop attack as you can see
on the on this flight we don't have such
technology that would allow us to change
tender that so easily
I represent the Czech FinTech
Association and I have the pleasure to
host the the debate on the future of
money so most of us are not freedom
seekers in the census was mentioned by
Paul Rosenbergs in his novel a lodging
for the way for a wavering men who aim
to create an alternative society a book
that probably most of you know and book
that was recommended to me by Pavel when
we were discussing the content of the of
the panel
contrary to Crypt anarchists most of us
want to use technology to change about
functioning financial system in a more
incremental way a system that most of us
and I think this is something that
connects us we perceive the system as as
being broken the panel is meant more or
less as a combat and as every cultivated
combat
has to have some rules so the rules are
the following in the first part of the
fight each of the panelists will flex
their muscles telling us their way of
how they perceive the current financial
system and money being transformed by
technologies also adding their their
imagined they the way they would like
the technologies to to change the system
the second part will be devoted to or
will be a fight over to approach it's
toward towards money because I guess we
all can agree that if anything is it's
to be perceived that money will be
digitalized and the two approaches are
towards course money is digital currency
and the question who will issue with
whether this will be a central bank or
any public institution or on the
contrary alternative institutions or the
well maybe the system will be
decentralized and in the final round I
would like to I will invite each and
every one of you to fight to join the
panelists in a total combat so your
colleague vice governor of the Czech
National Bank recently in an interview
mentioned that unless unless something
changes and happens he does not think
the the center of the financial system
will change do you think that financial
system as we know right now serves its
purpose and do you think the techno
technologies and new
currencies as as a pure will not change
it at all okay so once again good
afternoon I'm representative of the
Central Bank awesome I'm expected
probably to defend the fired money or
the legal tender so please don't insult
me okay if my views may somehow
contradict to your perception of the
future of the money let me start with
one single hour one important I think
observation our financial system is
based on the central bank money it means
that there is a institution is called
the central bank and this institution is
responsible for managing the legal
tender actually I realize that you
violate the trick law because the Czech
koruna are not accepted here so whether
we can do something about it or not okay
so so this is the first point and I
would like to stress one important thing
the central bank money has a very long
evolution and it is the same as in
animal world okay the evolution selects
the strong animals and at the same time
the weak animals disappear so the
history of the central bank money
sometime goes back to 16th century even
more there is for example very important
history of you in the United States
so-called free banking I had the system
without the central bank where each Bank
was allowed to issue its money
there and of course it created a lot of
chaos the people had to calculate a
different exchange rate between
different monies of different commercial
bank from different states different
district there were two attempts to
create a central bank and for populist
reason all these attempts failed but
after big ups and down chaos and havoc
in financial system which of course had
some impact on the weakness of the US
economy at the beginning of 19th century
the Federal Reserve System was
established so the free banking is
really a very nice and instructive
episode what our financial system can
look like if we don't have one single
institution responsible for some legal
tender if I switch to the current
situation I think that our world is one
way more dangerous and at the same time
more safer what I mean by that it is
more dangerous because if we look around
the universe of cryptocurrencies almost
everybody can issue its own money
everybody who is experienced in
computing and have some good background
can try to issue the money I think there
is around 1,000 cryptocurrencies just
now so they are competing among selves
so the potential for chaos if I compare
this situation with a free banking
episode in the United States is a quite
big but at the same time we are in a
very comfortable situation that those
who are not interested in in this jungle
sometimes okay who will win or who will
be defeated
they have the option they have the
option to resort to the central bank
money which is I have to probably agree
with me more or less safer of course we
have a Pepa so higher inflation recently
we have a result of deflation so
problems are always with us some
problems but the track record I think is
a vast success successful so I know I'm
not afraid I think I welcome that the
central bank money have a strong
competitor so it's up to you okay to
provide the society to other people
whether you are the alternative okay
whether really central bankers should be
threatened and terrified that they will
you will lose cop okay as a result of
this for for time being okay I'm not
persuaded that cryptocurrencies are
serious competitors of central bank
money so let me mention some reasons the
first one is the volatility one a key
function of money is a store of value
okay so households should trust that if
we if they have a one unit of account
that it would say one year time two year
times the purchasing power of the money
will not be eroded by inflation or by
fraud or like that so for example
compare the situation if Bitcoin ok
recently the price of the bitcoin reach
almost 5000 US dollar okay then we saw a
dramatic decline so this is the most
volatile asset I think today so this is
a very serious handicap in the
competition with the central bank money
so the first supposition is to make the
money more stable the second
I'm really astonished about the
environmental cost of the Bitcoin is it
really true that as far as the number of
transaction the Bitcoin let's save
serves the need of some CTL let's say my
wife is from her it's a put from or it's
a spot Kirk annachi okay so this is a
medium city and I was told that as far
as the number of transaction the Bitcoin
can serve would say this small city but
as far as the consumption of electronic
energy it is like a Belgium is it really
true I was really facilitating that so
much energy is wasted for powering and
cooling computers of miners okay and we
live in a period where the environmental
thinking is arising okay so I'm
wondering how this dilemma can be solved
and I think it's really important and of
course there are some other minor issues
I'm not expert in cryptocurrencies I
have to admit that I read only one book
okay about it and some articles so
alignment in this area but nevertheless
I I think that I captured some problems
okay how the cryptocurrencies cannot be
exception from the rule that we should
fight the criminal activity yes tax
evasion so everything will be regulated
which somehow tries to misused some
system for this activity and the
anonymity of course of cryptocurrency is
a wonderful I have to
but it cannot serve these purposes yes
it will be definitely raise some
regulation okay to wait it and there are
some other issues for example let's say
if I do a mistake and I send my money to
a wrong account so I can claim and the
the banking system will arrange that my
money will turn back is it something
possible let's say in in Bitcoin yes if
I agree with the transaction so my money
is a way and even though I but I have to
admit that really I noted a big okay the
brain okay in this area so this is my
intervention I think that you I didn't
disappoint it your expectation that I
try to erase some arguments okay into
this debate for the fight okay with my
colleagues maybe I will be shaken okay I
cannot I can say that it cannot happen
in this interesting debate I think that
you were blasphemous enough because I
saw
[Music]
I saw a companion smiling whether you
were using all the arguments all the
three arguments of the energy
consumption and Almaty and the
volatility of cryptocurrencies just when
a question - - what you've said yeah I
mentioned the beginning that your
colleague the vice governor umple said
that the central banks as long as they
do their jobs right they won't be they
have there is no chance that they will
be that their position will be attacked
by cryptocurrencies do you think the
current financial system as is regulated
and Andover's overseen by by central
banks and other institutions of course
as well that's the right job I'm sorry
that my English is not so good that I
can translate one saying from the Bible
okay maybe Maria can translate Vinnie
[Music]
[Laughter]
well who is the person who is without
fault can has the rights to to shoot the
first stone so it means I guess we need
to understand everybody do it's mistake
okay so even winkers from time to time
so
could you be more specific
okay so we have robots in the bank okay
sometimes the central bank's under
pressure of the government okay to
finance government expenditure and
tourism as a result the inflation is
rising therefore I think the important
step in the history of the central bank
is the divorce the Chinese war between
the government and the central bank so
as a central banker we are independent
and this is a very new phenomenon it was
very difficult for some countries to
accept the idea that some non voted
technocrats okay can decide about such
important policy as monetary policy is
it for example in France or United
Kingdom so the independence of the
central bank is relatively new so I
think that we try to from the the
messages we have different monetary
regimes okay but these are technical
details but I would like to say that the
most important thing is not whether we
do mistakes okay the more important
thing what is the alternative what is
the alternative to the system which
sometimes commits some mistakes okay and
my perception is that even if I take
into account that from time to time the
central bankers also may commit some
problems the system we can learn okay
there is an evolution and the system is
still the best one according to the
alternatives I cannot do anything but
I'll else but ask Yong to present and to
convince all this that there is an
alternative the future of money as
as you perceive it it's not only the NFC
chip that stats you that you burn in in
your body but you as a group the other
kids you definitely have a plan to
abolish central bank's could you
enlighten us how do that yeah I'm I'm
gonna disappoint you immediately I don't
have a plan I'm not a central planner I
just wanted to have an environment where
we can freely develop the society that
we want to achieve and I'm not going to
tell you how to do it you will have to
go and figure it out but I can tell you
what I think about the current financial
system I think that it's fundamentally
broken it serves only a small percentage
of civil society repeatedly in the
history of humanity
the people who are in charge of money
have failed they will always fail if
they have the possibility to control the
monetary system and I think it's because
of how how the system is set up all the
trick was talking about the free banking
history in the USA and when when someone
is using arguments from the history
before the internet I always I always
say that it's really hard to compare
what was what was then and what is now
because it's the same with governments I
usually say that the central banks and
governments and all these central
authorities they serve their purpose
when conveying information to our
society was much more expensive much
slower and so on then this central
authorities brought
certain level of efficiency but nowadays
when you have the Internet we can convey
this information on a flat hierarchy
basically no hierarchy peer-to-peer and
we can build much better system of money
on top of the internet which has no way
for anyone to control it centrally so if
there is no way how to how to abuse the
power because no one has the power then
we avoid all those failings that
happened in history I think that money
should be permissionless and censorship
resistant so that no one can tell you
what to do your money on or prevent you
from doing what you want with your money
it should protect your privacy because
privacy is safety
it's not about hiding hiding someone or
something because you did something
wrong it's because you are trying to
protect yourself and it should be much
more secure than the current monetary
system well this looks like a vision
that I guess everyone would subscribe to
but how do you want to achieve that
public key cryptography that's probably
one of the the best person to address
about the change of the system and I
guess for you to convince him you would
yeah that's what the idea about crypto
currencies I don't have to convince
anyone bitching because I don't care
about the political way of changing
things I think that we are free to do
use whatever you want
and thank you and I don't think that
it's possible to change the world by
telling people to do they have to do it
themselves I don't think there will be
one single currency for example Bitcoin
or any other currency and everyone will
be using it because there will be no one
to force everyone to use one currency
there will always be a competition of
few currencies probably not so many at
least not so many of the of the
currencies that are used in in the real
life because it's efficient to have only
few currencies but there will be more
than one and they will compete among
themselves to provide the best money for
the people so that they want to use it
and it's not so much of a problem to
have multiple currencies in in the age
of cryptocurrencies because we have
technologies like cross atomic chain
swaps we have decentralized
cryptocurrency exchanges and these
technologies together can do the
exchange rate calculation and trading
can't everything live during the
transactions we already have centralized
services for this like shape-shift and
nowadays if I have I don't know light
going you use Bitcoin I can pay you
immediately and I don't care that you
don't use light going well I guess all
the words that you just throw at us at
least those who are and who come from
the more traditional part of the society
they don't really resonate you can
either of course I want you to follow
you or you can choose the power of
Attraction but for a layman
those terms and names that you were
mentioning they mean nothing so how
would you I know that you don't like the
word plan but still I'm trying to get
access to get an answer from you how do
you would attract the system to change
it's the same as
if you are asking people and I don't
know 80s if they want to use the
Internet and stop buying newspaper and
stop sending physical letters because
they can just hop into the command line
and write the email is there more them
to send it over the Internet
well back then the technology was hard
to use it was really new but we built
more layers on top of the technical the
internet layer and it became much more
user-friendly and the same thing is
happening with crypto currencies we can
already see it the level of innovation
that's happening and I'm quite confident
in a few years it will be really easy to
use I think even now it's it's almost as
easy as using internet banking or
something like that
well is it it's probably but not so
widespread that I can now get everything
I want
using the cryptocurrencies well the uses
under eyes the volatility which others
of the otic mentioned is decreasing if
you look at the history of volatility of
Bitcoin it's much lower than a few years
ago and it actually isn't the most
volatile asset in the world even some
crypto currencies are shittier than
Bitcoin just look at Venezuela I don't
know if you call that a good store of
value the Venezuelan currency so once
people realize that Bitcoin became
higher-quality currency then some of the
government issued currencies they will
start using it because it pays off to
use it and in some countries they are
already reach to the level where it
became much better to use crypto
currencies instead of government
currencies thank you so we had all three
who proposes incremental change of a
centralized system we have an opposing
view of cryptocurrencies now I would
like to
as a coupe about a term I heard him
mentioning in one lecture which is the
term helicopter money and in a nutshell
as far as I understood it make up their
money it's is a way to build alternative
money system and it says whenever
money's issued it should be distributed
to everyone for a layman it made sound
like now we want to distribute
unconditional Universal income to anyone
so I'm really wondering how you would
how you see and how you would like to
see the future of money using that term
okay good afternoon thank you for having
me I am a money theorist I'm a
technician but at the same time I
probably admit that I like alternative
currencies and I am supporter of crypto
Anarchy - helicopter money basically
means distributing money directly to the
people so the money goes
not through to the commercial bank but
they go to the people it doesn't mean
necessarily alternative currency or
alternative monetary approach in the
time of the crisis in order to fight the
crisis to boost the aggregate demand or
to stimulate the GDP the government can
just give money to the people by raising
indebtedness and it's nothing altering
that if it's not really something new
also the universal basic income is a
fiscal issue it's ready to be it's about
free distribution you just collect taxes
you steal money from the people and to
give it to other people or to all the
people and it might be a good idea maybe
not maybe maybe yes I've read some
studies on that topic and if you want
you a the universal basic income from
the taxes it doesn't actually work not
now the
would have to be higher maybe there's
some mistakes in the calculation maybe
the whole city of money would go up and
maybe you could finance it from taxes
but it is not the thing I would like to
speak about the other option is that the
newly created money goes directly to the
people and this is a solution proposed
by Thomas Meyer a formal CEO of Deutsche
Bank and decided today how money is
created according to the endogenous
theory of money commercial banks issue
new money by increasing their balance
sheet so they react on the demand of
businesses of firms and individuals who
take credit mortgages and like that in
money coming to existence created in the
commercial banks there are limited
perhaps by reserves they need to get
some money from the central bank's to do
that some money's from the central bank
but again the power of the central bank
to influence the money supply the power
to influence or to perform the monetary
policy is limited by that because in
fact the central banks usually
accommodate they always provide the
needed research and you need the
commercial bank needs to get the
reserves in advance so this is a shaky
system that we live in right now it's
very flexible and my it might be broken
it's still existing it has been there
for decades much longer than most of the
monetary systems in last century so it's
not super bad it's for just like any
other system and maybe there might be
alternatives so it would every dollar
that we create we also create one dollar
in that we need to repay we need to
repay that we need to repay the credits
and then the money is destroyed so it's
like a bubble you
putting air into the bubble and then it
it gives backwards so what if instead we
go to central bank or any other
authority created to Mali and
distributed directly to the people so
instead of the middle we can avoid the
middleman we can avoid the pressure to
downside pressure that's destroying the
money and might be such a system could
work as well and the distribution of
money would be equal everybody will get
just the same proportion or we can avoid
the central authority and we can use
cryptocurrency to do the same thing so
without a central authority the money
distribution can be also a new issue of
the money can go directly to the users
to the people there are some technical
difficulties with that and I've
participated several projects try to
overcome them and I think
technologically this is possible so it
might be a community project not driven
by any regulator we can see so we find
this correctly in the future that you
propose the money is being created by a
community of users yes exactly
well every cryptocurrency is created by
a community of users some of the
cryptocurrencies are pre mind so there
are no minors and among the money supply
is fixed but again everyone everyone can
treat money there's the hard thing the
trick is to persuade the others to
accept it to use it so you need the
community to you need to pursue it your
community that the money has value and
you don't have armed force to do that
Paul Krugman's had not seriously that
the u.s. dollar is backed by men with
arms by an arm bitcoin is not so why
should it have any value but the market
it has a value much higher than you know
$1 let's change the topic a little bit
Eilish apart from being an investor into
a fund managed by an algorithm you are
quite often bring unusual ideas to the
political and economic establishment
recently you call third an article where
you laid the arguments for establishing
a blockchain Republic is then blockchain
the future of money as you see it thank
you guys
[Music]
so before I answer this question we say
just Sony to two points first you know
this one it's 100 100 check around there
it's a banknote I can show it here
because we are not in around policy in
North Africa so this is this is a medium
of exchange it's a medium of exchange
it's only medium of exchange
it's a like standard it's it's a
standard assuage so make note medium of
exchange it's a standard for the PI's so
I can buy two beers for this for this
piece of paper
I bet that the next week I can buy here
two beers we will see I said that I was
done yeah so I can buy two bills here
not not empowering boys for somebody
it's a piece of definitely yeah but
still it's medium of exchange there were
many kinds of medium of exchanges a
change in history for example stones
yeah skin form animal or shells so in
the future there will be something else
than this paper something else
definitely does anybody remember what
was the medium of exchange during the
war in Yugoslavia what was the medium of
exchange gasoline and cigarettes
definitely so maybe in the future
cigarettes will be medium I've changed
or Bitcoin or something something else
so definitely there will be something
new or maybe some something from us
there's some piece of rock from us or
something else so that that's the first
key point second second what what what
is interesting is a system of payment so
let's keep the debate about the stock
value but for me it's a medium of
exchange exchange and system of payment
and this is the everything is about this
debt centralization and centralization
centralization is central bank are like
all three it's a center ization and that
centralization is broad chain so for me
if you know the history of human and how
history sometimes we like period of the
centralization like a Sex Pistols and
something like that and
sometimes you like period of
centralization so I think it in the
future book change book chain can tell
me the future so I do not believe that
the Bitcoin it will be the future but
system of payment and blockchain can be
can be the future it can be something
like the sometimes the third movement of
debt centralization in our esta way
first moment is democracy or anarchism
yeah something something else then the
Queen and King second movement is a can
be the Internet and third block chain
and that's why I like the book chain and
that's why we wrote with honza on the
horizontal oh right now he he doesn't
know me okay so so that's why we vote
because that Bojinka can be the future
for example for the car registry in the
Czech Republic again let's create some
startup project small project and let's
create congregation car registry using
blockchain technology that's it
so I think the only thing we can agree
is that I think as far as understood all
four speakers that the only thing we can
definitely agree on is that the trend is
incremental digitalization of currencies
are we on the same page on that good so
the second main question of the debate
is if the future of currency of money is
digital second question is then who will
issue the money and here we arrive at
the at the next part of our debate who
should be the the money issuer should
central bank's
inspired by cryptocurrencies issue they
own national digital currency or well
the cryptocurrencies have the power to
circumvent circumvent the system and
make it obsolete
okay now I would like to come come back
to you and ask your colleagues from this
time from the Bank of England have been
testing and simulating the introduction
of a national digital currency and they
came to several positive outcomes
including a rise of the GP GDP also one
of one of the benefits would be the
getting rid of intermediaries because
then the national bank would be the only
the only one who could more efficiently
implement monetary policy and what the
National Bank would not need financial
intermediaries like it does right now as
we heard that so banks are actually
those commercial banks all right
actually those that print and produce
new money do you see a place for
cryptocurrencies in the current system
of central and commercial banks because
most of them they are not even allowing
for crypto currency exchange I'm sorry
that I didn't read the study okay you
mentioned of the Bank of England but I
read another interesting book as the
author was Rogoff and it was the curse
of cash okay and it's the result
actually the paradox the paradox means
that we are in digitalized age okay we
speak about the cryptocurrency digital
currencies electronic currencies but the
cash in the consequence in the
circulation is rising okay if you if you
see the graphs about the cash in United
States in the
of course in the Czech Republic the
utilization of cash is on the rise okay
there is absolutely no trend towards
limiting the cash so this is this is a
puzzle okay and of course the president
might have a thorough explanations okay
the the author of the book is persuaded
that the reason is that cash is used for
trafficking and criminal criminal
activities so he would like abolish all
high denominations actually for example
we could see that the European Central
Bank stopped putting into circulation
five hundred banknote okay so this is
one important thing in we in the Czech
National Bank would be happy okay if the
demand for cash is declining because now
we are in precise at the time that we
have to decide whether we should
modernize our system of machines for
handling the cash and this is extremely
big investment okay but our working
assumption is that the cash will erase
at least by one percent per year okay so
this is the matter of fact despite all
the baits that we are heading to
cashless economy and the
cryptocurrencies will remained our
universe so this is one point I would
like to stress you mentioned the digital
currency in the hands of the central
banks yes you are right there is another
problem that we exactly don't know what
do we mean by central bank occurrences
one point is it was already mentioned
one possibility is that each household
or each citizen
may have account in the central bank
this is the one possibility
today's it is the privilege from the of
the employees of the Czech National Bank
okay so if we allow the citizens to open
the account in the Central Bank okay
it's a kind of digital currency because
it's an electronic currency that could
be used for payment and so on but of
course at the same time I can list a
number of drawbacks or problems we
should save I think you mentioned how
the today system works and that the
money is created by credit expansions ok
the banks are extending credits and it
means that the money is rising but of
course the credit is extremely risky
activity and the banks are specialized
how to handle the credit expansion does
it mean that the central bank should be
involved in credit expansion as well by
issuing the money it's it's a big
problem if the central bank starts to
issue the digital currency it means that
the banking sector will be deprived of
primary deposits the most stable part of
banking liabilities should we undermined
the stability of the banking sector that
we will complete with the banking sector
for a primary deposits big issue ok
unresolved so far
another point is helicopter money ok
nice idea I wonder why no politicians ok
I raised this issue before the election
it would be wonderful social benefit ok
to get free of charge ok some monetary
of course the backside is that it's a
big big blow for the balance sheet or
for the central bank okay it would
create quite a big closed so the
question is should government to
compensate the central bank for for this
loss is it compatible let's say with our
membership in monetary union when there
as I said is a Chinese wall between the
government and the central bank and the
helicopter money is a kind of social
benefit so does it mean that the central
bank is doing something which is the
Ministry of Social Affairs should we
while awaiting the independence and
monetary financing my point is okay let
me conclude we have there are bright
ideas how to improve the current system
but we should not forget about the dark
side about the problems many problems
are unresolved and that should be taken
seriously so from what you're saying I
don't see the chance of seeing a digital
check crown anytime soon however we
might be surprised by an experiment that
is currently being prepared in Japan
where several banks with the support of
Japanese central bank came up with the
project of je coin which is a national
digital currency that should be
operational at the times of the Olympic
Games so maybe this will be another
inspiration for us also for the Czech
national natural bank it's one or say
about this
j-jake on
probably you know that a couple of let's
say weeks ago news circulated that the
Estonia okay is a preparing the coin but
I can I can say seriously that it is a
rumor okay it is a lie
the project of s Cohen is a completely
private project it has nothing to do
with the Estonian government or the
Estonian central bank
I'm not sure whether the G coin is the
same rumor or not frankly speaking I'm
not aware but there is a lot of debate
in the central bank community about the
future how to exploit this potential but
we are debating we are still debating
without any concrete recommendations
yeah could be were nodding well chief
mentioned that uh national digital
currencies are fake or are not feasible
to be introduced you as someone who who
is analyzing the money theory how do you
perceive the fight between the debate
between alternative cryptocurrencies and
national digital currencies yeah thank
you for the question of not just the
theories I also invest my money into the
old coins I need to think twice and
think harder what to do about it and
I've studied this situation since 2013
when the first altcoins
emerge and some of them claim that they
are national currencies and they will
help the national economies an example
can be or a coin in Iceland
so Iceland is a country in financial
trouble let's say you know they had a
crisis and they thought that your work
on kelp hello can help to solve that all
such projects where scam I would say
first thing as he said there are rumors
that the government is somehow involved
and usually there is
they are not and they are pumped and
down scheme so the price goes up in the
beginning and then the coin goes down
because it has no real value it has no
real meaning then governments or central
banks like the ECB together with Bank of
Japan they are all commercial banks they
are trying to play with the blockchain
technology and that's all I said well we
don't like Bitcoin but we like the
blockchain technology the book chain
technology is great but the blockchain
technology itself is a very expensive
phone if you don't know how to utilize
that if you don't know how to use that
and it's powerful usually when it is
community driven
if it is driven by a central authority
then it has no meaning to use the
blockchain
or the meaning is very limited and I
think that the first country to ever
speak about having a currency on the
blockchain basic photo Ecuador has no
national currency they used the US
dollar because their fiat currency
bankrupt basically and people stopped
using that and in the end it turned out
that they're just speaking about a
virtual currency meaning the currency
similar to empezar or Amazon coin or
something like that it's not a crypto
currency it doesn't use the blockchain
ledger it's just a centralized database
even though it's digital and it has no
cash form so what I recommend to
investing or to really think about other
currencies cryptocurrencies which are
community driven but supported by some
officials in the government's that might
help to establish the currency example
keeping them in Japan it can be near
when China or waves in Russia so how do
you manage that
quite surprisingly to me there is a
rising interest in cash cryptocurrencies
at least most of them they are based on
pseudonymous known not
but actually anonymous systems yeah yeah
how how would you how would you
sustained anonymity that's many of us
who use cash would like to see in
cryptocurrencies yeah thank you for the
question uh first let me let me get back
to to what all six at about the cash
being on rice well that's not surprising
at all because if you don't take the
crypto currencies in account and you
look at national currencies and do you
have a choice you use cash which is
anonymous it's permissionless if you
hide it well no one can take it from you
it's still bad that it's affected by the
monetary policy but it has some good
properties and the other alternative is
that you will have only digital currency
which is always surveilled by the
government they can see how much you
have they can see what you buy they can
see where you get your money they can
take your money of a they can forbid you
what they can forbid you from sending
your money away and so on so this kind
of easy choice that cash is better it's
maybe a little bit less convenient but
the benefits are much higher in crypto
currencies we already have a few of them
that are called to digital cash for
example Manero and as you said bitcoin
is not anonymous it's pseudonymous and
if you want to preserve the level of
anonymity that cash provides you with
you need to take some additional steps
which are not so easy for for casual
users but their service is being
developed for bit going to become more
anonymous and thus fungible because
fungibility is something that's
collective
with the anonymity of the digital
currency fungibility basically means
that each bitcoin is is the same but
because bitcoin transactions are public
as probably most of you know then
bitcoins that were connected to for
example crime can have lower value
because some people might refuse to
accept them if the currency is fungible
like Manero then this problem doesn't
exist because there is no history
associated if each each coin or part of
the money so we already have currencies
that behave the same way as cash and
those currencies and that don't have
these properties are at least in the
process of getting new services which
provide them with these properties
another and I think we will have to quit
in a couple of minutes and before that
before I open the floor to questions
from the audience I would like to
address another question to to Jana
because why cryptocurrencies are not so
widely used because there is no third
party that guarantees that whenever
anything goes wrong with the transaction
that protects the customer could you
give just one example of customer
protection within cryptocurrencies well
the thing is that the cryptocurrencies
are a base base layer you can build on
top of them you could even build similar
institutions as you have the current
financial system you can build them on
top of Bitcoin then you can get
guarantees you can get insured deposits
and things like that but the whole idea
is that everything that you have to pay
in the current financial system
you have to pay for for it it's opt-in
in crypto currencies you don't have to
no one can force you to use them so if
you want the bank that will guarantee
your deposits and take care of you and
sometimes steal your money
then you can but you don't have to and
there are not many consumer protections
in Bitcoin maybe because people don't
want them but I can think of at least
one benefit of crypto currencies
compared to the traditional
government-issued currencies if I lose
my bullet like my phone or TAS or
something like that
I can go home or somewhere else I don't
know when I hide my backup of of my
cryptocurrency wallets I can take it out
I can recover my my money and I didn't
lose anything
except for the device if I lose my
wallet if cash I miss everything and I
cannot recover it anyway and it's kind
of unfair to compare government-issued
digital currencies with crypto
currencies because they properties are
not the same as I said in the previous
questions you have to compare cash and
digital currencies the crypto currencies
fine it's good to know that your backup
codes at home here so thank you for this
man no but I welcome I think this
discussion can this discussion can be
simple because hey right now let's start
from Monday ask your boss to pay your
salary in bitcoins and then you can
fluently just change your money from
Czech koruna
US dollar to two crypto something yeah
and revolution will be done everyone and
it's it simple everyone in peril and
policies paetynn cryptocurrency school
they just asked asked more and more
people and then the world would be dead
center as ice
hey that's it all this is over final
question if you were to describe the
future of money into one sentence
wouldn't be hours yes make a conclusion
you know it's up to the people they
choose Bitcoin will be Bitcoin they
choose stone it'll be stone no bitches
hurt you'll be oh I believe in evolution
if the cryptocurrencies are already
strong is there is a powerful engine and
if they will house the central bank
money okay I wouldn't protest but I'm
personally persuaded that it'll be very
hard to fight for the currencies to
perform outperform of the central bank
money yeah go in the future people will
not use just one single currency but
they will use more currencies for
specialized functions yeah taxation is
test
now on serious note I think autonomy and
freedom is the future if we yes I will
collect a couple of questions if there
are any from the audience you wanted to
ask the man in the black t-shirt I just
wanted you to repeat what you said at
the end you mean the taxation is theft
now I said autonomy and freedom is the
future do we have any other questions
you have the one and only chance to ask
a member of the Czech National Bank yes
I do not this question who is who is it
for but I'm a businessman I work in show
business somewhere else but I would like
to move to crypto and I'd like to know
what's next for the legislative and and
what do you think is going to be you
said it's really easy as you're opposed
to pay I would like to pay for people in
crypto well I earn 99% of my money in
Euro and and I actually am in the
taxation system right now somehow
connect it and and I would like to pay
everything in crypto but I need to do
the transfer and and to not pay not just
lose money if I play something in crypto
I cannot put it in my accounts so what
do you think would be the way or what
are the next steps if I want to do if
you have any ideas like I'm asking for
advice as a businessman who makes
business in Euro and would like to do it
encrypt or maybe just find an accountant
who is able to work with two currencies
there are people like that the the
question that the the fact that you said
that you don't have crypto currencies
but you would love to pay your employees
in Thibodaux currencies the easiest way
to get cryptocurrency is to accept it
for your work you don't have to buy it
you just have to offer your service
for crypto currencies and that's it just
start gradually and you will see if it
works or not and let's hope you find
some employee in place and also you
don't need to ever get to touch the
Bitcoin you can just pay with euros and
then the receiver of the payment will
get a Bitcoin using a service of a third
party so there are the our service is
doing just like that so that I think in
the future people will use different
currencies we don't needing to know
about that and they will just accept the
currencies that they prefer so some from
the officials so from the the legal
point of view the crypto currencies are
not the money okay they are treated as
commodity which means that they are not
regulated if for some reason the country
crypto currencies will spread and become
more popular i can i can i came sure
that they will be regulated okay so this
is a trade off okay from the amount of
transactions the crypto current the
market with cryptocurrency is a marginal
okay that's why the attention to this
segment is a quiet small but on the
european level of course we have
commissions for everything okay there is
also some working group which i know my
situation
tries to analyze the trend and so far
the perception is that there is no need
for some regulatory initiative to
regulate this market thank you for the
very interesting discussion i would like
to know one
issue on the crypto because on the
transaction and all those things are
very clear we always know the central
costs we never know the decentralized
costs no meaning so kind of II know that
national money supply for a Czech
National Bank is expensive but how the
costs for each individual user bit of a
spread for example on cryptocurrencies
extremely wide but my question is how to
ordinary people get created in crypto
because if you have a family if you want
to buy your home you need credit to get
your accommodation how does that work in
crypto elevator coop that's a difference
between credit which is a company with
money creation and credit and loanable
funds loanable funds means that no new
money is created you just needs to
borrow it from somebody who already
earned the money and it is possible even
even in crypto I think so and the other
thing is that I don't think that the
cryptocurrencies will completely replace
the existing fiat currencies I don't
think that I think that the boost that
both of the systems will coexist and
they will merge to some extent for
instance the Lightning Network is
something which comes basically from the
fiat world or from the normal table
entry bookkeeping system and it's now
affecting the future of Bitcoin and at
the same time the blockchain technology
will be more and more used by the
government so that the world won't be
black or wild I think that there will be
more options and also there's place for
credit as always place for credit but in
the fiat world we can barely distinguish
between money and money substitute as
well there is nothing like the primary
issue of money actually because the
reserves created by central bank's they
react on the video
every issue so I think that there will
be fiduciary issue credit issue even in
cryptocurrencies in the future and there
already is there is basically there are
assets which are denominated in Bitcoin
and just accounting stuff I remember the
story from the Hungary 15 years ago
there were big interest rates on
mortgages in Hungary 15% and more so
people ask for different money different
currency they ask for mortgage in Swiss
franc so I can imagine the situation in
the future there will be big interest
rates on mortgages because of the
inflation because of something and
people will ask banks for mortgage in
Bitcoin or something else and that's
that's the demand which can change
change it change the map change the
media change to change how we think
about this and make pressure to the bank
to offer mortgage in something else than
in Czech koruna he was doing great it
did very badly because yeah
people could not afford then repay they
are kind of cheap interest but high
exchange rates and if the salary will
stay in Czech koruna but both mortgage
will be in Bitcoin then there is problem
Arizona with the exchange rate but this
is not the end of the story hello yes
the big issue was what happened when the
foreign depreciated and at that time how
the lots and those who borrowed in
foreign currency we were in terrible
troubles it was a big issue for the
Hungarian government's okay because they
had revenues in domestic currency then
repay the loan in foreign currency and
the exchange rate is weaker okay it's
many enterprises defaulted so the
government had to push in central
commercial banks will take part of the
exchange rate lossy losses and of course
it's nothing it's very similar to the
Bitcoin okay if you if you have a
currency mismatch okay your revenues and
income is in different currencies your
situation is very fragile you are
dependent on the exchange rate movement
and it can kill you yes not so much
about the currency so but the trust that
we put into the currency I would like to
conclude the debate and I think that the
future at least the new future ahead of
us is a world of multiple currencies
sort of developmental fight among
themselves and we we don't know if the
strongest one will be any of the crypto
currencies is promoted by the
Cryptococcus or one that will be issued
by the government we'll have to see
thank you thank you for joining us for
the debate
you