thank you for the
is a company that brought you treasure
we've been doing treasure since 2012 so
it's quite a long going effort now when
it comes to compared to other Bitcoin or
cryptocurrency projects but this talk
will be not about reserved like if
usually is but it will be about crypto
space in general and what to do and what
not not to do so my talk is called
security or slash insecurity of crypto
space and security of data has never
been more important when you lost some
data like 20 years ago it was usually
some photos from vacation it was sad but
it was not fatal today usually when you
lose some data or somebody stole your
data when it comes to the data related
to creep the space this is fatal you
don't have access to your money or
somebody else has already stolen them so
there are various threats and of course
there are various methods have to avoid
these threats and we will go through
these types and hopefully give you some
advices what to do and what not to what
not to do
so there are data theft protocol errors
implementation errors Hardware attacks
political attacks and we will go one
after each other so data theft this is
nothing new you probably know that in
2011 Bangkok's exchange was hacked by a
security breach half million bitcoins
were stolen
then btc-e 2012 Palani x 2014 bitpay
there was something interesting about
this attack that it was not like a
regular security breach it was a social
engineering fraud when somebody
pretended to be chief chief finance
officer of the company and he wrote to
the seal place top up our hot wallet
this is the address and the ability that
but it's also something like a security
breach and with Phoenix 2016 what's what
these things have common is that they
really are not tied to just the crypto
space like these kind of attacks happen
outside of the crypto space as well so
that's why I'm not going to go in
further I will focus on attacks that are
mostly just specific specific for crypto
space but I will give you some takeaways
anyway
for each section there will be two sets
of takeaways if you are a developer of
such thing there is a one set and if you
are user of such thing there is another
set so if you are developing a service
please use secure operating systems I
don't think that needs any for the
recommend use second factor
authentication for accessing your
infrastructure that's very important
because attackers can deploy codes
without you knowing it and it's a big
problem for a reason of course then
provide second factor authentication
also for your users so they can access
your service securely SMS is not a
second factor authentication because you
you can get easily hacked when mobile
operator collaborates or is attacked on
the really low level of of this
infrastructure and also it's quite good
to hold regular meetings in your company
to challenge your security protocols
like meet and have a discussion like is
everything we do right correct rack
isn't there any possibility and it has
proven to be a really good thing too
one thing is to create some security
protocol but then you have to constantly
challenge it to yourself like if it's
still good and also I think there's a
good point and nobody really talks about
it socialize with your co-workers so
we'll know them better like if if we CFO
of your company sends you an email hey
please do this and you know him like
really well and you are like it's
probably not him like what he's doing so
Trust is fine but if you exactly know
what the other person does it's even
better and for users so use services
that follow these security practices and
others use these security features if
they are provided by these services then
use it read blogs follow the ecosystem
and educate yourself so we will know
which service is good or bad then we
have protocol errors these are errors in
design of the cryptographic protocol and
they are mostly logical errors by
omission like the designer of the
protocol even thought about that
particular eventually T that hackers
came up with and exploited there is a
problem that these errors are not tied
to a particular implementation and
impact all clients that implement this
protocol because they are just doing
what the protocol does one good example
is transaction vulnerability it was a
big thing like two or three years ago so
how does it work transaction ID is a
hash of the transaction including the
transaction signatures but for every
ECDSA signature which is a couple of two
numbers are NS the signature R minus s
is also valid is the same signature
but is a different this different number
and this number has a different
representation also if you pay these two
values from left with zeros this value
doesn't change but the representation in
the computer changes like we it's no
difference if I gave you four apples or
zero zero zero zero four apples
so the
transactions with the same meaning have
different IDs they have basically the
same signatures and same the content is
the same but this signature have
different representation in the computer
so transaction ID is different and this
can read two doubles pens like one park
of the network thinks that this hasn't
been spent because it sees a different
transaction ID so this was solved by
tightening the rules for s so the other
minus s signature was no valid anymore
and also we use canonical their encoding
so there is a rule like if number starts
with numbers let several zeros then it's
not a valid number because they are
really not needed there then we have
implementation errors so these are
errors in implementing the protocol and
this usually effect only one
implementation but we have open source
today and open source really encourages
code reuse so usually you have like open
source library that is used in lots of
projects so even if one implementation
is affected all these projects that use
this library are affected as well and
also this open source Internet is code
reuse also between languages for example
if I am writing some Python code and I
found a JavaScript version on stack
overflow
I was just rewrite it blindly and it's
of course not very good because I also
copy not only the code but also this
implementation error so that's what I
said there are a couple of really nice
examples well nice for us but not nice
for people that encounter them so first
of them is black hole basically cones
are sent to destinations where no one
can spend them from if you are using
UNIX then dev now is something that is
being compared to two
so who recognizes this address okay
only one so let's address in Bitcoin
address that has like empty pub key hash
in Bitcoin you have a public key at the
new hash it and then the you convert is
hash to address if something fails in
the process like for example hash
function says like I cannot do this do
this it returns zeros but if you don't
check for the error code and work with
the result again we will end up with
this address so how how much bitcoins
are on this address today what do you
think no it's not 2000 but it's 60
bitcoins so it's quarter million of
dollars and it was happening all over
the years people sending bitcoins there
by accident because that it was not
their fault but the implementation of
the software they were using a similar
case is this address that someone
recognized this one so it's a similar
story if you have a public key of zero
which is not a valid public key it
probably some ECBC ini burritos like
there was an error and I'm returning
zero and if you hash it and convert it
to address you get this address and
there are like for bitcoins today but it
has a lots of transactions I think even
more than the first one
then there are weak random number
generators so if you are doing ECDC
signatures it needs a strong random
number to create a signature because
it's that's how it was designed but if
you have two different messages and you
are assigning them with the same private
key and for some reason the random
generator always gives you the same
number then your private key is
compromised
just just by signing two different
messages with the same key and same
random number by the way this is how a
PlayStation 3 was wrecked
because they had a weak
Oh generator and they were signing games
so there were a lot of signatures out in
the world and they were able to perform
the haka but this will not happen
because of the space is just too big
right well my station has shown that
it's not too big if you have recurrent
on the generator but we are talking
about crypto space and unfortunately
exactly the same thing happened in
Android in 2013 the interesting thing
was that the author of the Bitcoin
library for Android they decided not to
use their own random generator but used
the secure random generator from Android
which turned out the pit was not so
secure so I think all for Bitcoin
wallets for Android at that time were
affected and around 60 bitcoins were
reported stolen at the time then the
smart people came with something that's
called RFC 69 79 deterministic
signatures and what they do is they say
let's not generate a random number K but
let's create a function that takes a
message and a private or secret key and
generates a random number from these two
and that's this basically guarantees
that you cannot generate same random
number for different messages when the
same private key is used so this we used
immediately in treasurer since the
beginning not only because of the
Android fail but we are illustrating our
craft crypto library from top to bottom
and unit testing is really impossible
when signatures always keep changing
like you will gave the same input like
same private key and same message and it
always returns a different signature so
that's why we decided to use the
deterministic ones and suddenly all the
ECPA see
cryptic code was testable but then even
after tracer was out everybody knew that
RFC six nine seven nine is late to go
Bitcoin Jas was affected and some other
projects like counterparty or even
blockchain info very using this library
so they had the same problem and the
problem with this is everyone can see
that you messed up because the
signatures are public in the blockchain
so I can just look into the blockchain
and wait until you make a mistake and
there are some people in the world that
were too English and one of them was
rockin sitting Sanger there and what he
did he preemptively swept such coins
from the blockchain info and store them
in treasure and then sent this picture
to blockchain and to affected people
like he didn't know who they were and
said like your bitcoins are in this
treasure and if you prove the ownership
of that affected address and give me a
new one I will send them back so that's
[Applause]
so so that was our first contact with
the ocean and we've been the
collaborating happily ever since he is
doing a lot of stuff for treasure like
you will see on the next slides but
there was one particular company that
thought like you can't have weak random
number generator if you don't have any
so what they did is it was a black chain
again so they had to Android wallet and
they said what if we used spoiler alert
so I will get back to this so what we
use this web server is random.org api
which generates random numbers so we
don't have to implement any and we are
saved because random were clicked it's
very very safe but what happened is they
switch to HTTPS and suddenly this HTTP
URL started to return this and what they
did like they always just hash to the
response and use that to generate
address so suddenly all requests were
hashed to the same data and when you
converted this hash to the address it
was this never like 45 bitcoins on this
address of course they were like
immediately swept away and basically a
lot of people suddenly saw a new address
in their wallet which was exactly like
this so then there is another group of
implementation errors which were
introduced in Bitcoin unlimited and they
had some memory leaks
triggered by specially crafted to user
inputs or transactions so I could create
a transaction which was broadcasted to
the network and when it hits the Bitcoin
unlimited node it started to eat a lot
of memory and then the kernel sells like
a bit canal limited you use a lot of
memory I'm going to kill you so that was
a problem and another problem a couple
of weeks later was discovered that there
we are so called
reachable asserts again by specially
crafted user inputs so let me tell you a
little bit about how that works so in
some programming languages like for
example Python or C there is a thing
called assert and basically a programmer
says like this condition which I write
here like for example block size is
always less than one megabyte should be
always true and if it's not true so the
assert is right broken just don't
continue and abort the whole process
this code this assert is usually used in
development build but it really makes
sense to use it for production build of
such system like Bitcoin as well because
you don't want to have code which uses
the data that programmer didn't really
anticipate it so it's probably better to
just shut down the node then to keep it
running if you have a game is a little
bit different like if there is a broken
texture you can still finish the level
and then restart the game is not a
problem
but for for Bitcoin you don't want to
keep it running if there is some
inconsistency so but even if you are
using these asserts in production code
there should not be like a path from
user defined input how to trigger this
condition and that's what was possible
in Bitcoin unlimited again some hackers
they created special transactions which
after processing triggered this path and
you can see there is the graph of the
node count so I think that this first
fall was this memory leak I was talking
about and these two Falls and it was
like from 700 nodes to almost almost 200
so like to first
Network were just down because of that
particular hack so then we have smart
contracts you probably knew about parity
multi-sig problem parity is a client for
for a theorem and they had implemented a
multi signature contract but there was
an error we probably also know about the
dow i will not go into the details
because it's like maybe topic for a
separate talk but there is a nice
write-up by vitalik here about how we
should really rethink smart car smart
contract security and the code is law
unless it's not so from for some some
problems they decided just to somehow
rollback the actions i don't really want
to go into the politics but study is
fine reading so some takeaways if you
are developer
always peer review your code don't
blindly copy paste the code unless you
understand it first don't use languages
which make it easy to interrupt his
backs so PHP javascript see and
basically every other language don't use
them but if you have to follow the best
practices so for some languages like
Perl or JavaScript you can enable strict
mode comment code so others have bigger
chance to understand in the code review
and if you are users avoid using
solutions with mouse or short or bad
records so you can not judge how what's
the quality of the code look at how
active is the developer community around
the project because it's very act if
it's very active then probably the
implementations error are not saying
they are not there but there is a high
chance they were fixed and also look at
how developers react to
constructive criticism like if you are
if they are in denial then run away
there is another section hardware
attacks so you can have get good
protocol and it's flawless
implementation but there are hackers
that are still able to attack the
underlying hardware which is performing
this code and if they understand it very
well they could make it perform what
they want not what you want treszura is
open source both hardware and software
and because it's open it attracts a lot
of lot of hackers not only the good ones
but also the bad ones
the good thing is that Whitehead
good ones are winning so we received
some security reports in the past and we
were working with the reporter and wider
community to fix them I don't want to
sound of course that only tracer is
affected there are a lot of other
security solutions like Intel SGX
secure elements which also they have
their flaws but I'm not really
interested in their flaws because they
are closed and I cannot fix them anyway
so I'm what I will give you there will
be a couple of examples of how we found
out about the issues and how we fix them
because that's actually doable with open
design like treszura so what you can do
is side channel analysis again it was
done by Johanna in 2015 and when he was
reading the code he realized it's not
performing in constant time so it what
is what it what it does mean is that if
you have zero in a private key somewhere
it skips some portion of the code and if
there is one it performs it and it
it's basically leaking some private data
by how
long is the code running and how much
power does it use and this was used this
was fixed in software by using constant
time operations so basically you go
through the code and every on every
place where this is happening you just
replace it and how do you can replace it
it's being done like this if there is a
zero in some bit you still perform the
operation but then you discard the
result so the tech early doesn't know if
there was a zero not because the code
always runs and also pin is asked before
any operation live secret data so if you
would like to perform side channel
analysis you would need to know to pin
first and then it's it's a problem
because it's not a lot just some random
hacker that found rather on the street
this was his tool it it's a of civil
scope and he attached to the USB cable
and was able to measure the power
consumption as and this is written on
his blog he could see like which
operation takes how much time in in in
this time time domain ok so then there
is a glitching there was a talk at Def
Con this year by Jessica and what he was
studying was VCC glitching so basically
basically what you do is you identify
some critical operations like writing
the wrong pin number tries in the flash
and when this is about to happen you
decrease the voltage on the
microcontroller so it's not able to
perform the right but it's still in a
voltage so it doesn't shut
and this is called visa glitching so
basically you make microcontroller to
scheme skip some operations which are
critical because it doesn't have enough
power and there are various ways how to
fix that so there is something called
blown-out detection so there is a part
of the microcontroller controller that
is watching the voltage and if voltage
goes under some value then it just shuts
down the processor and also you can
check for every critical operation if it
really happens so if you are writing
this wrong try number in on the flash
you write it and you wait after it has
been written you so you constantly keep
asking flash like are you done are you
done are you done and even you are not
going the further until it's not written
and then you again check like is there
really increased number of written there
so we read it back and if it's there is
a mismatch you just say there's
something really fishy going on and
there is another group of attacks called
clock glitching and basically there is
on microcontroller there is a usually
and some external crystal which takes at
some frequency so so microcontroller can
work with USB and other peripherals
which require high precision and what
you can do is somehow
glitch this clock again so you like in a
similar fashion so microcontroller skips
some instructions but doesn't shut down
completely I will show some example and
this can be avoided by enabling clock
security systems so again in
microcontroller there is a chip which is
always watching at the frequency of this
external crystal and if it goes
if he's not like eight megahertz like it
should be but I don't know half a person
bigger or smaller than it again it shuts
down the microcon tomorrow so this is
the tool called chip whisperer which is
able to perform such attacks there is an
FPGA here there is your testing
microcontroller here so imagine this
part is off and you will attach tracer
with micro controller and there is a
library on the chip whisperer website
which says like if I want to make this
micro controller to skip seven
instructions perform this VCC or clock
glitch and it will jump seven
instructions for example so what George
was trying to do is to perform so called
out of loop glitch
so basically when treasure is waiting
several seconds because between pin
entries we wait for some time if you if
you manage to mess up so this is the
code that waits for a couple of seconds
until it continues track is the
frequency of the processor basically and
this is the number of seconds you want
to write so if you multiply the
processor of frequency of the seconds
and you perform this infinite loop and
if you are able to glitch this so just
skip one instruction that goes at the
beginning of the loop you can basically
click out of this loop completely
basically eliminating the delay but what
Josh found out that we used this code so
we we have this inner loop which waits
for one second and we have this outer
loop which waits for second seconds and
it's much harder to jump out of two
loops at once and you can do these kind
of optimizations or it's not really
optimization it's
is the opposite thing you make the core
code more complicated but for a very
good reason so I wanted to mention some
political attacks the redditor you
probably know a lot about this but I
don't have a lot of time so just in a
nutshell there are always some group
which are trying to persuade you that
this their version of Bitcoin is better
than the others they usually use the
argument we have bigger blocks so there
is a big bigger throughput of the
transactions again there is a lot of
things that can be said about this if
you want to talk just grabbed me outside
and we can talk so just some main
takeaways so stay vigilant educate
yourself don't be afraid to ask like
there are always people that are smarter
than you and they don't really behave
like assholes so don't be afraid to ask
you might learn something and also
always analyze others people thought
before you adopt them so you will learn
if that's really making sense
social don't be on beep so this has been
my talk this is my Twitter account my
email and probably a lot of people were
thinking that this will be Tresor to
talk but there are a lot of people
around the Congress from satoshi labs so
you can ask them about Tresor okay we
have some devices here you can have a
look and there is a lot of material
written about Reza on our blog and it
will be updated more and more until the
treasure is released which is will be
probably
the first question you asked now so it's
going to be released in well not in two
weeks but this year end of this year so
thank you and
[Applause]
so thank you very much fertile we have
time for a few questions so please raise
your hand and I will remember the order
and I will come to please wait for the
mic with your question but before that
is Jochen sitting here if so could you
stand up please
so please applause for this great guy as
well
so first question yeah thanks so much
for the presentation child paid pays for
parent replaced by fee and support for
manera what are the timelines so at Dyea
so timeline for replaced by fee and
sharp eyes for parent is soon like Carol
who is sitting there and laughing has
been working on improving dissent
dialogue for a couple of weeks and
months already but he could really be
derailed because of some other stuff
like Bitcoin cash and others so it's
really in the queue I maybe it was
already merged but it's like coming
really really soon and Monaro
its we are working on Manero right now
but we are at least this my personal
opinion we don't I don't want to go on
the internet and say I'm working or me
out my company is working on Manero
because then people are asking like a
tie tied so we are working on it and
once it's finished then it's finished we
are definitely not ignoring it but yeah
that's it I don't have a tab so that's
why I'm not saying we are working on it
there are some challenges I know there
are a lot of melero people here just
come to me and I will I will I will
contact or I will give a contact person
who's probably he already contacted you
who is working on that
[Music]
hmm other questions
so I released time for my question so
could you tell us maybe some of the
discussions behind the scenes in in
Satoshi Labs regarding the security
features in in reserve like for example
yesterday risco we discussed the thing
about the mnemonic features ok so the
question was like what are the
somethings we are cooking and are not
well-known yet or can you rephrase the
question yes so I will like what are the
discussions that even in such a
relatively small team you have differing
different opinions on the same thing ok
so we we are trying to come up with a
different manner monic scheme because
the current one which I implemented with
Slash three or four years ago has some
flaws and still I think it's a good good
thing to do because every basically
every bullet now using that is using
that and so they are interoperable but
we would like to add some more features
in it and one of the features that is
really critical for me is this Shamir
secret splitting so basically you during
the initialization of the device it will
already give you like several sets of
mnemonics you could back up and it's
really hard to do it right because I
don't want to screw that because if you
if you mess up with one mnemonic then is
a problem but if you mess up with this
multi signature scheme that it could be
even bigger problem because you will
recognize it just when it happens and
there are a lot of discussions both
public and private and various groups of
people want to put different stuff there
like for example
SBV implementers of all odds they want
to have a birthday in it so they already
want to know from which point of time
they need to scan the blockchain so they
don't want to scan the whole thing and
some other people just don't want to
have birthday in it because they are
leaking some info which probably might
or might not be shared if the others so
there are a lot of a lot of points to
make during this standards creation
process sorry wait for command
completion is there for this there is
not a big number yet I'm discussing with
some of the wallet implementers first to
get some something at least like a rough
idea and then we will ask for for a beep
number another question do we have other
questions so you are of course all we
have
[Music]
all right so my question is you say that
people might make these tags when
implementing protocols and things like
that so is there something like os4
blockchain so the question was my
parties maybe it's me who is making them
to hear me so the question was there
might be some errors introduced by
protocols and whether there are there is
some group of people like Ava's who are
working on
now the question if the cause if there
is something like a wasp is for
application if there is something
similar in the world of cryptocurrencies
right well for for Bitcoin obviously
there is this Bitcoin improvement
proposal process so there is a there is
a github where these standards are being
discussed and later implemented for
other cryptocurrencies I don't know but
I would expect they have similar process
like this and when it comes to like
protocols like even abstract protocol
not to tied to some some particular
cryptocurrency I know there at least
there are some working groups in w3c and
also IETF and for example in IETF there
is a working group which is trying to
standardize so-called co-signers
or a great signature aggregates so if
you have like several signatures signed
by several keys you can perform an
operation which is able to create one
public key and one signature which which
does the same thing as a group of
signature and group of of public keys
and this process also takes time I don't
know a lot of about the details but my
really outsider's view is that this
standards take like ten ten ten years or
even more and I don't think that's
really applicable to this kind of
cryptocurrency world but of course it's
it has been shown like in my slides as
well if if you don't pay a lot of
attention to this protocol process you
can introduce bugs which are really hard
to be spotted
until they are ready discovered in
production and then it's usually real
late so I don't know of any super body
in crypto space but w3c and IIT are
working on some crypto graphical
standards which can be applied in
cryptid space or in cryptocurrency space
as well we have time for one more
question
Allah thank you for presentation good
any thoughts about scenarios when there
will be no properly protection during
the two works hard work well there are
there are some ways how to split coins
even if there is no proper replay
protection and it's one trick is to use
a lock time where basically say this
transaction cannot be spent before block
ABC and you submit you created
transaction if this is work time and if
one one blockchain is in advance of
another you use this higher number so it
can be mined only on one block chain and
once if his mind there you will create a
double spend transaction on the first
chain which was send it to another
address but that again it's it's durable
but it's not like super easy for regular
people so if there was a proper replay
protection strong one it would be much
easier like Bitcoin cache they
implemented this stronger replay
protection a couple of days before the
fork and it was not the fault was not
flawless but at least there was not
problem with that so there are a couple
of ways how to do it but again I didn't
want to say like
we do it that way because maybe tomorrow
they will create strong rippling
protection and again this statement
would be like of no use anyway okay so
thank you very much thank you very much
for questions for answers and in the
first place for our interesting talk
[Applause]