hey welcome everybody I'm working in a
pen test Department so we are pen
testing what applications we're pen
testing IT infrastructure and maybe
sooner or later we're gonna passed
blockchain since you know blockchain is
becoming kind of a theme people are
running around and telling hey
blockchain might be useful
Bitcoin is using it and it might be
useful for like some supply chain for
notary for whatever use case you can
imagine blockchain there's a solution
and what I tell you as well is that
watching some only a solution its
dissolution why because it's secure it's
immutable and it's just awesome and as a
security guy you're wondering is it
really secure and then there are
headlines like this there hacks
multi-million dollar hacks money is
getting stolen all the time pretty every
week they're stealing money in like
budgets that you couldn't imagine
it's not about privacy it's just about
pretty much just money it's getting
stolen and you wonder like is this
technology really secure and when you
dive deeper they're not having the
blockchain so this is kind of boring
this is like application hacks they're
hacking your wallets they may be hacking
your database they may be hacking the
framework they may be hacking just the
simple WordPress whatever so this talk
is not about dollar dollar Bitcoin hacks
okay
this talk is about a blockchain
blockchain protocol so if we go a step
further further the application there is
a comparison simplified a left-hand side
is the weapon
there are there's the application layer
which is pretty big and you all might be
familiar with that there's like the
googles and the Facebook's and the
Amazons we all know and they make up the
big application layer on top of the
Internet protocols they don't even have
logos they're like pretty basic layers
that exist for a long term and on the
other side we've got a blockchain and in
the application layer you might use this
hopefully every day whatever there's a
coin base there's electron there are
lots of wallets and exchanges and
services that utilize the blockchain and
down there there is the blockchain so
why is the one Square way bigger than
the other that is because the well you
captured and - well you generators can't
be compared like this the one you've
generated in the web applications the
one who captured the guys who take the
money home and the web is the googles
and the Facebook's the money-making and
the money generated in the blockchain
world as a protocol lover at least this
is what what is division like the block
chains being the - web 3.0 and the
blockchain is gonna distress
so I was thinking let's hack the
protocol and not just the borrowing
applications on top of that so I was I
was having a look at the blockchain
protocol and I was having a hard time
like what is the blockchain protocol
there are a lot of demos idea and these
are not art coins these are not just
simple forks of Bitcoin these are not
like taking the Bitcoin repo and
rebranding it these are like proper
blockchain frameworks blockchain
protocols and
trying to solve all pretty much the same
problem so there is no such thing as the
blockchain protocol and so I was
wondering are there any standards in the
web of course you might know the RFC
standards defined by the internet
Engineering Task Force and they are like
pretty yeah pretty technical standards
and you can implement them the way you
want and that's fine and you can say how
you implemented it right or wrong
and blockchain is a little bit different
since I grant yeah that's the new
technology but still they're like no
property foreign standards no RFC exists
for blockchain technology there are
those white papers next steps the yellow
paper there are community defined
standards like the B IP Bitcoin
improvement proposals if your
improvement proposals the lots of well
documented wiki's where technical
descriptions are written down there are
documentation and usually DISA reference
implementations but that's not what a
blockchain standard should look like so
how can i how can i hack the blockchain
so what is what is the point I'm I'm
going forward so first I was I was
trying to to make sense out of all this
and and I'm here by proposing a standard
to categorize blockchain and it looks
kind of like this there is a consensus
design transaction design and a block
design and those make up the blockchain
design and each of those primitives
those design primitives they have some
some subcategories some specifications
in there and defining on how you put
those parameters an attack vector will
work or will not
work so for a consensus design you get
the consensus algorithm you might know
proof of work proof of stake proof of
authority whatever notification is there
any handshake is there any encryption
between the peer discovery how's that
working governance as described as how
is the code maintained who is the
maintainer of the project and
transparency is the public permission
less or the private and permission
blockchain and if transaction is a
design is what what it's called a chain
code and it could be a bit conscript
this is like a theorem byte code and
this is like are the transaction any
hall programmable and there's a
cryptographically aspects of the
transactions so how is the transaction
executed and how can I execute any
transaction and the block design is
actually the data structure so how are
the blocks store a local notes what is
the block time between the blocks which
includes the difficulty the coin supply
is there any generic token on this
blockchain and tokens refers to can a
user generate oaken's on this blockchain
so this is still kind of boring what I
wanted to add is like application design
is not a matter of fact in this kind of
characteristics so the characteristics
of each protocol would look like this we
got some kind of frameworks we got the
design primitives so we look at the
characteristics of this protocol and we
we see proof-of-work no peer
identification is decentralized in
information less okay I guess you get
the idea you fill out all the
characteristics for those blockchain
frameworks and that you've got kind of
an overview of the landscape that's just
a taking state as it is that's fine so
next step you have some blockchain
protocol attack vectors and they're all
well described they are defined and they
work on
or the other blockchain framework but
why do they work and what do I have to
change this so that they don't work
anymore so I just take an example like a
51% attack as an attack where you need
the majority of computational power and
there's the blockchain block zero block
one then the attacker takes one block
and manipulates it in any favor so that
usually he has an advantage like he's
changing any transaction and afterwards
the chain is giving mind block after
block eventually since he has more
computational power he his chain is
getting the longest and is getting the
truth in a network and it's getting
accepted by other notes so the
conditions for this attack work is that
the network's permissionless and that is
utilized as proof of world consensus
algorithm so I would call this consensus
design attack okay next example would be
a transaction malleability transactional
ability really briefly explained is
inside transaction there's something
called the script signature and the
public key of this all gets hashed and
they get a transaction ID okay this
transaction gets published to everybody
in a network every node assets
transaction you can take it and modify
it modify it in a way that it's still
well lit but since it's modified a
little bit the hashed value changes
there is transaction malleability and
the design conditions for this attack to
work is that you need to have chained
code in your blockchain and you need to
have a transaction signature so I would
call this a transaction design attack
the last example is a spam attack up
there you got a transaction mempool
the transactions coming in getting
processed into blocks and the blocks are
getting full up with the transactions
okay so block after block now the spam
attack works like this not like you
might know from email I'm just pushing a
lot of cheap transactions into the
mantle and the member was getting full
but as you might notice the blocks are
not getting fuller block stay the same
block after block in bitcoin is roughly
ten minutes every ten minutes and block
with the same amount of transactions so
the conditions for this design is how's
the block time and how is the data
structure inside this blocks I would
call as a block design attack okay so
what do we do with that okay
fine enough we can categorize a block
block change we can categorize the
attack vectors and attack vectors are
categorized like this we've got a theory
on transaction design there are all
possible transaction design attacks and
there is a chain code exploit what I
would call this for example is Dawa hack
would be a chain code exploit and a
botnet via botnet via chain code is
actually quite fancy attack you could
ask me later for that if you want so
those would work for aetherium you can
check out the whole list on this github
down here if you want yeah and you can
also fill out the whole list for what
frameworks which attack works in which
framework and the reason why I'm telling
you this is can you hack blocks with
protocols yes you can if there's a
problem since I've told you in the
beginning that the all applications rely
on protocols does this is a problem and
since we are here to talk about
individual freedom and crypto Orakei and
crypto freedom and blockchain might be
to go with that this is a even bigger
threat to that vision to that idea and
so I would give it a definitely yes so
what can we do about the problem I my
answer to that is give it any kind of a
standardization and give it a major
approach to security research and I've
seen a lack of security research in that
field and I urge you all to give it a
push and not just say that security by
design is something that blockchain
inherits so there is no standard for
blocks and security just yet
so this emergent call is going to all to
all of you guys there
there is a github out there you can
collaborate and there is no standard yet
nobody is it made a real effort to
standardize anything I would like to
give a shout out to all of you guys
collaborate and create something we can
build the well you on properly and yeah
make the next step in the blockchain
evolution Thanks
[Applause]
do we have questions somebody yeah so my
question is and how is the Bitcoin
network going to be secure when the
block reward goes away how is the
Bitcoin network secure when the block
reward goes away but that's like an
economical attack I would say and hmm so
then that's more like a political
question right not a real technical
question well I mean it's good the
attack cost will be the sum of the
transaction fees right which would be
probably quite low so doesn't that mean
that Bitcoin will be quite easy to
attack in the future I would say it's
lowers the attack cost like I said
definitely and so the security goes down
as well and that's not a good idea to do
that who is planning to do that actually
I mean the reward halves every four
years so in 40 years we'll be like a
thousand times less in 80s be a million
times less so it will be essentially
zero in the long term
yeah yes that's correct
so I guess the the hope is that by now
the transaction fees goes up or Bitcoin
will be more valuable
I don't think valuable will make a
difference they quit because the
transaction fees would be roughly the
same because you know people who play
when it's two dollars and you can have
your finite number of transactions I
think maybe we're gonna have to change
your consensus do you think so see
Bitcoin is not only like a technical
concept it's it's an economic concept
and the economic building and up until
now the economic incentives are set
right and it's still working and it
might be happened that in one point in
the history
sentence don't work anymore and in that
points yeah we're screwed
so that's that's right we cannot see up
see that's in front so hopefully it
works if not we are betting on the wrong
horse
hi what about the life hacking announcer
on the program I'm yeah I've seen it
other conferences that some hacking
against against blockchains
weren't discouraged or like weren't
encouraged I've seen some really
negative feedback against life hacks
some really negative feedback so I
decided against that
after I I wrote up for that sorry for
the click baiting I guess now like
really guys I really tried to show you
something and then decided against that
I was actually trying trying to show the
transaction malleability you life egg
but to be concrete like active breaking
big co-conference there was life egg and
afterwards he like got yeah kind of
really hard feedback from the community
that he was attacking Bitcoin and
like that
so I tried to get out of that I usually
I try to get out of the political
discussions of Bitcoin you focus on the
techniques so I'm not doing that sorry
on a technical level would your life
hack have worked sorry on a technical
level would you alive hack have worked
yes yeah so if you wanted to know like
its yeah it was transactional
malleability against Bitcoin and it was
putting a inside script inside the pop
sick script putting a hopped-up code
extra op top code and afterwards off
drop code um yeah that was the
transaction malleability instead works
the day if you don't use that word apo
considered combining more than one in
tech of those you were describing like
using a spam attack and another one on
top of it
a little bit louder please sorry I mean
if you considered using more than one
attack vector for chipping and attacked
that's that's an interesting point
like you could you could like details
the the the poles okay if you did us the
the the Bitcoin poles the hash rate goes
down so 51% attack is much cheaper hmm
that's a valid point
the the intention of this research is
actually not to to find new attack
vectors or to break Bitcoin it was at
first to find why the blockchain
protocol is vulnerable and after that
yeah describe a protocol level or define
any kind of standard that withholds the
most attack vectors that is like the
fundamental
the research that needs to be done in my
opinion to go anywhere near standard
what I take work this work because of
what reason so how should be a standard
described that is kind of year bevel
tests that are kind of good to go on
with and I have to say this all excludes
any use cases or any political or any
likely to scrub any economic incentives
does exclude all of this this is just a
tip technical security research has just
one way to approach this standardization
process yet community can do whatever
they want with us so I would like to ask
if we heard the team is planning to
switch to consensus yeah do you have
information on what your opinion if is
it going to be as safe as it is it is
now or I heard this like two years ago
as well so a lot of stuff up until I see
any code I cannot judge this sorry yeah
you brought up the topic of
standardization in cryptocurrencies and
I had a discussion with Bitcoin core
developers some time ago and their
consensus was basically we can't tell
probably because yeah we need consensus
between all nodes and if the standard
gets something right the standard has to
be amended because of all the old nodes
and we basically have a standard
implementation and not the formal
standard what's your opinion can we
change this or do we have to stick with
this I would say that's a political
question since a Bitcoin core
standardization is hard one for me
this is about blockchain standardization
not about Bitcoin standardization the
Bitcoin standard is defect though the
Bitcoin core standard up until today and
I don't want deep dive into that one
sorry
yes hi I'm the text that you're talking
about I think that they are not really
comparable to other security attacks
because when they're protocol attacks
then you're broadcasting them in the
network so it might in my opinion you
can maybe for a short time disturb the
network at any in some way so lower the
efficiency but in the long run if if
it's a big network and there are many
many people on that network then they
will identify your protocol flaws and
then they will kind of fight back or
change something I mean like you cannot
carry out this attack without other
people on the blockchain noticing this
but that isn't that true for most
security attacks that you eventually get
identified and they will try to shut you
down and end your attack and try to
chase you afterwards so if there's a
tech ongoing and they reveal it very
early in the early stage you will fail
and if you get into a database stay
there for a long time the profit will
rise like I heard that some guys got
into LinkedIn database and stayed here
for two years so cuz they went
undetected so if the question is for
detection right the blockchain community
has probably the ability to detect an
attack vector or an attack in the early
stage the probability for that Rises
actually you
since it's an open blockchain and since
there's an open network um that's that's
true yeah what do you think about the
security of Bitcoin pretty sacred enough
to sacred now that the signatures are
separated from the block is there extra
attack vector for that and that all not
all notes are required to keep the
signatures that's again like a political
question but just know can we talk about
this later
yeah like I'm getting filmed and it's
not gonna be on the Internet
cool thanks okay some more questions so
maybe I would have want to so team you
to mention that there are a couple of
different by consensus mechanisms so is
there any that you consider to be most
slash least secure for for public
blockchain proof-of-work proof-of-work
is the way to go and I haven't seen any
other consensus algorithm that works
good if the premise is that we want a
decentralized system that's not a
premise then there might be other good
solutions for a decentralized boots on
teen fault-tolerant system I would
always suggest proof of work today okay
and maybe are there any in a way two
kinds of consensus mechanisms that you
may know of like they are not so common
usually implemented
in the public book chains you know some
something interesting in this great guy
some of them some secret horses sorry no
okay so any more questions yeah can you
talk about the book that attack sorry
attack oh yeah yeah lovely like there
were some guys researching this and the
idea is that so you have like a mall
where and you spread it and like
conditioners that you have some
mechanism to spread that and why are
mail or whatever your favorite porn site
so you've got some infected machines and
they have your malware and they executed
inside it more where is like a bit
compliant of our client connects to the
Bitcoin network and as well hard-coded
your public key your Bitcoin public key
okay so what do you do next is you send
some transactions on the Bitcoin network
and inside the Pitkin transaction there
is some scripts execute it and the
script is actually why people call it
programmable money like that is three
that is the way I send you money or I
defined it is emoji signature
transaction so whatever there is one and
function inside the script and it is
called op return and inside of return
you can store some some data okay and
you store inside the stator you store
the commands for the bot okay
and so you push on a transaction the
board just listens for the public key
and he knows our s transaction for me he
goes for the OP return takes the
functions and he has got some decoding
mechanisms this this function goes for
okay
whatever I I get a new command I get
like I get this data from here over
there like fetch some data get some data
so all the commands for the body are
included here and you can use anybody
out there with their existing commands
and their existing command control
structure and so what you basically did
is like a usual bot bot net is made up I
am the commander control server and you
are all the bots I control so what the
FBI usually does is kill the command and
control server the central part cut it
off and then it's all that and
essentially the Bitcoin network becomes
your commander control server they
cannot shut down Bitcoin or they haven't
been yet so that's kind of kind of
sneaky I guess and there's actually a
proof of concept for that they call it
zombie coin and they pull it off so
there's a botnets via chain code attack
I called that and I love that one that's
cool yeah thanks for the question more
questions ok so maybe I will the last
one so regarding the 51% attack so
there's something that I always
encountered it is a discussion about it
so there is like maybe sometimes
misconception like both actually an
attacker conducting a 51% attack can do
and what he cannot do so can you
elaborate on that but he can't change
anything in a block he can reject blocks
meaning he can reject transactions so
that's basically what he can do he can
change history and she can manipulate
future or like have an impact on the
future if you control the network you
can decide what the chain will look like
you can decide what is truth in the
network and through the truth in there
and the past and truth in the future
that is his power yeah so I think that
51 is enough to control the network
yeah okay I think I don't I would say
that this is like a realistic attack for
Bitcoin because as soon as we'll see
somebody pulling off at 51 per se then
the economics of Bitcoin won't work
anymore
and people will dump the bitcoins but
again this is like an economic
discussion for Bitcoin that not like a
technical discussion and like I said I
want to get out of political and
economically discussions because I'm not
really I don't know too much about these
topics but just stay out of them but
technically as possible okay thank you
yeah so any other questions if not so
please one big applause 14
[Applause]