as if I said from actually hear from
piranha Poland's
where we two years ago we found it a
makers lab a 3d printing makerspace
right now you don't see any 3d printers
anymore because we moved two weeks ago
it was too small for us so we had to
leave two different premises but makers
lab was co-founded here we're two
co-founders two years ago we bumped into
guys from from piranha police who were
founding the the whole concept and we
figured we we would move in without 3d
printers and we start doing our 3d
printing here today I am gonna be
talking about how 3d printing will
democratize manufacturing how if one day
everyone will have a 3d printer on his
desktop which I believe that one day
will happen will lead into into
interesting interesting ways of being
able to to manufacture things ourselves
okay what we do in in makers lab we're
doing a lot of teaching we're we're
doing workshops where we teach people
how to 3d model how to how to create
stuff we're basically we're helping to
create from digital to physical we're
teaching how to use 3d printers we're
teaching how to assemble your own 3d
printer open source open hardware 3d
printers
who has seen a 3d printer before is
there someone who hasn't seen a 3d
printer you all know what 3d printing is
right I'll just repeat the very basic
concept is 3d printing is manufacturing
where you are adding layers of material
on the top of each other and that's how
you build your objects it has certain
advantages and disadvantages but that's
the main concept it's not you know
painting text on the paper it's
manufacturing stuff there is different
3d printing technologies I'm not going
to go into the detail today into the
technical stuff of different materials
and different 3d printing processes and
technologies but I want you to know that
there's various various materials that
you can be 3d printing and depends on
the on the actual technology that that
is used and it's all being worked on so
there's new and new materials and new
processes and technologies coming up
back to this one this is a violin that
we 3d printed in makers lab on desktop
3d printer like like this ok so I
believe that the future of manufacturing
is gonna be local and on demand and I'm
gonna explain what it means I in my view
the 3d 3d printing is leading into into
decentralized manufacturing because
today you can buy a 3d printer for a
couple of hundred dollars let's say I
don't know 600 bucks or 1,000 bucks
depending on what kind of painter or a
3d printer kit you're you're buying and
whether you're assembling your own
printer or whether you're buying already
assembled printer
and it means that anyone or almost
anyone can buy a 3d printer now and I
can start producing stuff right and
producing stuff with a machine that
produces for yourself you can have a
workshop at home or next to your house
and you can have tools and you can start
producing stuff as well but 3d printer
is a machine that's building the stuff
for you okay so you don't have to be
present while it's being manufactured
that's an important thing we also going
to be talking about digital distribution
of files so or of the products and
things because if you guys have a 3d
printer at home and I have one and I
want to share a thing with you I can
send it to you by email which is quite
interesting because we were used to we
were used to or we are used to thanks to
the internet we used to share texts or
videos or music and thanks to 3d
printing we can start sharing things
what is why I use the word on-demand I
believe that the future is gonna be of
producing that stuff or you buying stuff
I think that in the future the when you
buy something it's not gonna exist yet
it's gonna be manufactured on demand
only after you make an order okay like
in the pin in the bust and we're gonna
go to that to there later it's also very
flexible to 3d print some different
kinds of stuff so on one machine can you
can make almost anything you want
so let's start with the traditional
manufacturing and how it works you're
used to you know huge factories
somewhere in Asia from the Crypt of all
we can say centralized manufacturing
somewhere in Asia China mainly right and
today if you want to make a product you
just have it manufactured in in a
factory in Asia and you wait you wait
for I don't know a couple of months in
order to be due to manufacture the
product it it takes it takes a long time
and also it is it has to be shipped to
your to your premises so you are
distributing all the products and you're
also manufacturing in low in high
volumes so you're you're making I don't
know hundreds of thousands of pieces of
your product then you ship it on these
kind of containers if you're a big
company you need a lot of containers if
you have huge volumes and you ship it
all over the world and then you need to
start them you need to stock it locally
and then you're able to sell it so now
with 3d printing this is all gonna
change okay I believe that with 3d
printing we're gonna go back to local
manufacturing like in the past you see
the artisans they were located local
close to your house in your hometown and
there was many of them and it was all
like distributed manufacturing and they
were also working this way you came to
the artisan and he said I need something
and they produced it for you
you paid for it and they
said it's gonna be ready in a week and
you came for it and and and took it
right and that's the way I think it's
it's going to be with really printing
here you see a desktop 3d printer on a
table and there's there's people more
and more people now owning a 3d printer
and they can manufacture anything they
want on their desktop these days okay
what it means for the distribution it
means that there's no longer container
ship that needs to cruise the Seas in
order to deliver the goods you are
digitizing the way you distribute your
your products two years ago I think two
or three years ago in the summer they
shipped a 3d printer to the ISS
International Space Center and they
tried how the 3d printer would work out
in the zero-g in zero-gravity and they
used a regular desktop FDM printer that
prints plastics and they tested it and
it worked well so today if if an
astronaut has a problem on ISS they call
hey houston I got a problem and I lost
my screwdriver or whatever and Houston
says okay we're sending you the tool by
email and you can use it so there that's
very powerful now you can you can the
cost of distribution of things for you
with 3d printing equals to zero there's
no cost you're distributing things the
same as you're distributing software so
that's a big change I was showing the
stock that for example huge companies
like Amazon they have huge stocks and
they their know-how is how to how to
shift it back and forth and so on
with 3d printing there's no stock okay
there is only a database and you can
store anything any model or any product
you want in a database you can argue
that you still need the base materials
right you will still need the materials
you you build your your products or your
your things off and that's right so
you're gonna still have to be able to to
maintain a stock of the raw material
this is what I see as a as like an
office where you can you can print your
your things in makers lab we have
something like this we have printers
that are not as pretty as these we're
using open-source desktop printers they
print just fine
but we realized that if we want to to
scale the production we need more than
just you know two 3d printers on a table
I'm gonna get in the next slide I'm
gonna get into how how we're solving
this problem but here I want to say one
more thing that today the major desktop
3d printing is FDM and you're basically
extruding plastics through a hot nozzle
and this is not the only thing that you
can print only plastics in your desktop
there's a lot of companies that that are
working on desktop 3d printers that can
print out of even metals or other
materials so I think today it's the
early days of off desktop manufacturing
desktop 3d printing I think in the
future it's gonna change and we're going
to be able to really print
more and more products that are now
manufactured in China we cannot print
electronics obviously but I think the
future of that is that we one day will
be able to do it the question is only
when it's gonna gonna happen I always
compare today's desktop 3d printers to
desktop computers right when I was a
small boy I had a Commodore 64 you guys
remember that 8-bit computer and I was
playing games on it so it was good for
games I used it a lot and I also could
start playing with the basic programming
and I could learn actually basic that
was the programming language so I did a
small program it was what was it was
like education where it was asking me
for the capital cities of of each states
around the world and I had to answer
anyway so this is where we are right now
from Commodore 64 it was just for games
you couldn't do anything else with it
and today's desktop 3d printers are
mostly people would ask me what what
should I print okay when kids come to
makers lab they're always very very
creative they know they're like Thomas
and can I paint a horse can I put in the
house can I print anything I said yeah
sure you can you just need to learn how
to 3d model or download your model and
with with the computer it was the same I
was able to program but I was not able
to to do more stuff with it because it
didn't have the capabilities
today's desktop computers we're working
with them every day we can do almost
anything with it at the time no one
could imagine that will be you know that
text editors we'll start and this will
be you know taking off and and we're
gonna use the computer for everything
and I think the the what's gonna happen
in the future that's you're gonna be
you're gonna be equipped with a big 3d
printer at home and you're gonna be able
to manufacture almost anything including
clothes that's where it's it's heading
however if you need to create more stuff
not only for yourself but imagine that
you need to serve and produce more more
products then you need to scale and what
we decided to scale is to build like a
small farm and we're building a factory
of 3d printers it's going to be a
distributed factory so it means that
there's gonna be 3d printers here in
Prague some in Brno in Berlin in
Budapest and people will be able to make
you know we're gonna be able to produce
locally you're not gonna have to ship ok
I have some applications to show you
what is interesting what we can do with
3d printing and for large-scale
production what what are the the major
what's the major stuff that's being
built with 3d printers glasses are very
a very good example where people are
building applications online where you
can you can choose and you can customize
you can pick your glasses you can change
the size you can put some you know text
or anything 3d printing enables you with
mass customization so you're gonna be
able to to create the products as as you
wish this is the team these two guys are
from our makers lab and
Massena is his nickname he had a pair of
diet of the glasses and he 3d modeled
the order lens actually and he 3d
modeled the the frames around it and
printed it from him for himself and then
he created another glass for for his
colleague and it's for me it's amazing
that you can do this with with a machine
that you have on your own your desktop
the only disadvantage is what I realized
would I be able to to manufacture a
glass like this and I answered Oh No
why is that because I don't know how to
3d model very well so in order to be
created in 3d printing you will gonna be
have to be able to to to do the 3d
modeling and to learn how to 3d model so
now I'm back to to the parallel with the
Commodore 64 I was trying I was trying
to do some little programming right so
with 3d printers what I'm doing now I'm
trying to learn how to do 3d models so
that I can I can come up with with stuff
like this and I can do my own designs
and be creative I can also go to
websites where I just download stuff and
print for myself but that's not the that
doesn't spark the creativity that that I
want now this is medical application
that's being used the inner hearing aids
you know like if you have like hearing
this disability you can you have you put
hearing it into your ear so that you
hear well these are being manufactured
with 3d printers today they scan your
inner ear and
there's millions and millions of hearing
aids being manufactured per per year so
this is an example of a large-scale
manufacturing with 3d printing that
already exists but a lot of people just
don't know
another one is basis they take a scan of
your mouth and there's a company that is
producing like a series of different
braces for you so that in in a week it
shifts your teeth a little bit then you
change it for another one so you have
like 10 customized braces for you to use
for the next two or three months mmm
that's also amazing this it's all
customized so anything that can be
created for your for your body because
we're all different it's very
customizable and it's very nice to to
start producing with 3d printing to have
a best best fit we were trying to print
some shoes from flexible plastic
materials we're experimenting it's good
for ladies but if we want bigger sizes
we need bigger printers so for for now
we're just printing shoes for for ladies
and we're gonna have to develop at the
moment the plastic is still it's an
experiment it's still not wearable that
you would just take it and walk in it
because it's quite quite hard but they
will come up with new materials and new
things and I'm thinking right now to
produce small shoes for my son and and
see like flip-flops if Werner is gonna
work or not we'll see try
there's also insoles that's also an
interesting thing that you take a
picture or scan or a picture three
pictures of your foot and you can have
your
in Seoul that's made for for you to fit
now I have I want to tell you about the
marketplaces that exist already online
and what they provide if you are a 3d
modeling guy or a girl you can open a
store online and offer your products to
the public and they can buy pay for it
and then it's manufactured and shipped
to you
okay it's not decentralized yet these
kind of markets marketplaces but it's
starting starting to be very interesting
and for me this is this is amazing
because in order to to to have something
like this you just need a database and
you need the 3d printers
I'm also comparing this this model to to
the Google Play Store or the the App
Store on your iOS if you are a
programmer you can program a new game or
use a new software for your phone you
just publish it
on the on the store and then you let
people to buy it and they can download
it and this basically is pretty much the
same thing if you are 3d 3d modeling guy
you can do a 3d model and then just
publish it and and let people buy it
this is a picture where it's it's
printed on on desktop printers and
that's like a new thing that you can
print from many colors so in in one
layer as you can see in one layer you're
able to print up to four different
colors on the printers that we have
and I want to show you here with this
picture that it's also evolving right we
were used to have prints that were only
one color and now it's shifting I think
the future is color printing so the
printer in the future is going to be
able to do print with all sorts of
colors at the moment we're with four
colors this is this is also interesting
because some people are saying well why
would I need colors I say oh look at
that
why not it's it's a natural evolution of
of the brands and if I show you this in
one color and there's an four colors
it's a huge difference right I don't
remember how this this guy is called but
isn't mini on this one
yeah yeah okay okay so this is this is
the future and hopefully right now
right now with the color prints it's
still kind of slower than a regular
prints but I think that's gonna be
solved as well in the future so
hopefully hopefully we're gonna be as
fast with color princess we are with
with one color prints thank you for
listening and you have any questions
I'll repeat your question yeah yeah
hello hello yes what's your take on the
increasing it's like 3d printing started
a lot as being an open source thing
bought by bigger companies like the big
players that had the 3d printing all the
time yes it's funny because if you look
at the manufacturing like on the whole
manufacturing right even the big players
in 3d printing if you see from the whole
perspective of manufacturing are very
small fish okay just the perspective and
these are buying you know even the
smaller that that are but the
interesting thing about open source and
I like open source and I'm I hope they
will be more and more open source
printers or they will continue to be
open source we are working with open
source printers and the desktop printers
started because a patent expired of one
of the big professional printers and
that that was the initial explosion of
of the 3d printers themselves right the
the technology is 30 years old but only
six or seven years ago the desktop
printers started and and only like
automotive was using 3d printing for
rapid prototyping they even didn't call
it 3d printing it was called rapid
prototyping rapid manufacturing and it
was used for prototypes mainly for cars
or airplanes and and these kind of stuff
and then the desktop 3d printers came
the open-source printers open source
hardware and open source software and
that enabled people to build their own
machines and to start forking
the machines and create their own types
of machine one of the very popular
machines is the Prusa i3 in 3d printer
yeah we are working with them as well so
there are good printers and it's still
open source even the latest one that was
announced a week ago it's the i3 MK 3 I
think and I think for me it's I think 3d
the open-source 3d printers will remain
and they will they will definitely
remain in makers labs and in in places
where you want to scale where you need
more and more printers because the cost
of the printers is is is lower in terms
of user user interface or user usability
some manufacturers went to close source
the reason is that that according to
them they are protecting their their
investment into into development
open-source movement is slowing down it
is if you don't see it I see it
it's like the new processor but where's
the others it's like well there's I see
I see even people are closing while
sourcing like everything they're not
sharing like they were like five five
years ago or six years ago so that's my
concern
I see I see our concern there's less and
less but what I see is and what I like
about the open-source printers is if you
patent stuff it's for me the old-school
thinking it's the old world
I will patent it in order
and the state or some Authority will
give me a certificate that only I have
the right to use this kind of technology
and others only if I sell it to them or
I can sue them with the with the
open-source printers I like the stuff
that there's no barrier right there's no
barrier of entry if you want you can
start producing your own printers you
just fork it and if you're good enough
you will succeed succeed in the market
if you decide to you know to develop a
printer and and put it on the market and
go on and I think if it's open source
it's it's a harsh environment and only
the best will survive and it's
guaranteed because only the best stuff
will go through with patents it's not
this way because you are protected by an
authority because you were first maybe
even you were not first but it was
granted to you so you have like a
protection of 20 30 years or whatever to
do your stuff even though there's better
guys even though there's guys that can
do it faster cheaper and so it doesn't
make sense right that's why I think it's
it's old-school
I think open-source and sharing and this
kind of stuff it's it's cryptocurrencies
are also open right it's all open source
I can see companies opening also their
their products so I see the future of
any product will be open source why
because because we can trust it and we
have the freedom to modify it if we want
to any other questions
I've seen like a year ago some
presentation on that where they used
some 3d printers using ultraviolet light
and some hardening glue which was really
fast and very precise do you have
experience with that thanks for your
question yes it's it's a 3d printer
that's using laser and that's a
hardening liquid and this kind of
printer was supposed to be ten times
faster than the other SLA is sterile it
ography printers but it has limitations
on the types of materials you can print
out of okay so it's not it's not it has
certain use cases you can use it for and
it's good for but it cannot be used for
for other stuff and there's more this
was a desktop example of a desktop 3d
printer and there's more printers
professional printers that are coming
there are also like an order of
magnitude faster than than the previous
versions so we're definitely shifting
into more into faster printers and into
like volume manufacturing right it's not
gonna be like just one thing but you can
you can scale we are scaling with the
number of printers but if you make
printers faster and quicker you can
scale this way as well did I answer your
question was it
Star Trek or you know 3d printer like
you go there yes okay I want this I
think that's the ultimate 3d printer
that's the starter replicator that you
come to a machine it doesn't have to be
called a 3d printer anymore maybe they
will you know will be renamed or
something but the ultimate thing imagine
you have in your bedroom you have only a
machine replicating machine and when you
wake up in the morning you will just
select in the menu the kind of clothes
you want to put on and you put you push
a button and it will manufacture your
clothes so maybe it will be one day but
who knows it also means that the value
of things the value of anything will go
down will decrease because you will be
able to manufacture almost anything that
printer is close source isn't it that
one yeah
hello do you think let's say a company
like Apple would ever use 3d printer to
you know produce iPhone or bakbox or
anything like that and if so in what
kind of a time frame are we talking so
companies like Apple or or Samsung they
are using 3d printers now for
prototyping okay for building their
prototypes it's being used for four
years already but for production of ant
and parts like the the phones that we
have in our pockets it's gonna take a
while I don't think because there's
electronics inside and there's all kind
of different materials you know you have
glass you have chips just the chassis
that's already that's well you can you
can create a cover not a chassis but I
can see it could come the other the
other question is does it make sense to
create it with 3d printing why because
if you're building high volumes of the
same thing it doesn't make sense
economically to to do it with 3d
printing the cost of one thing in 3d
printing is the same the cost of
something for example a phone cover if
you create one or if you create one
thousand pieces or one million pieces
the cost of one will be the same in
additive manufacturing 3d printing but
with conventional technologies the cost
of one is very high and the cost of the
millionth if you build 1 million of them
then it's very low so economically it
doesn't make sense these days maybe if
the printers if it starts shifting so
that the intersections of these two
lines are
you know in in millions then it will
make sense but it will take a long time
I think I don't see them depending on
what you want to do there's special
applications where we're 3d printers
because you're adding material layer by
layer you can do special special
geometries that are impossible to to
manufacture with CNC so imagine lettuce
structure like a metal lattice structure
lightweight strong for example for
aerospace industry so this is something
very very interesting but new designers
new you know new designers can we'll
have to come up with with these kind of
solutions or you can start designing
things with a computer algorithm so you
just put constraints for example what
kind of strength you are applying from
which directions and what kind of shape
you have it you want to have and then
apply a generative algorithm that
creates the shape so it's not created by
a man but by a computer and 3d printing
can create any of these shapes or almost
any of these shapes so it depends
sometimes CNC and 3d printers can be
competitors sometimes there are
scenarios that it doesn't make sense the
the advantage of a 3d printer comparing
to CNC as I see it now is that with 3d
printer you don't need any setup you
don't have to change the machine in
order to create one day shoes and
another day a hearing aid or or a
bracelet or anything you just send
another file into it with CNC you have
to do some some
preparation works and so on I think to
maybe further answer your question there
are some things because 3d printing as
with many technologies we're very
excited about it and we think it's going
to take over a lot of things but there
will always be a place for traditional
manufacturing methods you know for
example even when we get to metal 3d
printing we're never going to exceed the
mechanical properties that you can get
out of a forging is it's just that you
will never achieve that I am very sure
about that based on based on material
density and grain flow but with that
said I think it is important for us to
explore these technologies and see how
we can as you said decentralized
manufacturing