look attractive to the surrounding
knowles K
with respect to the other line cosmetic
you can see an example here
on the left you can see the topology the
network before that type
here so you see that pulled the nose
have chosen the department's
and that of course not to the pasta was
the base station
key now one step back is starting to
doze me think
over here you can see specially crafted
messages but I'll give the other line
call the public on
eventually what you see here look almost
forward the messages
to that like an old K so again that i
cant cuz
boxes to the ball a methodist but the
bookcase
since you are very legitimate parliament
key go out and know that they're
supposed to forward the messages
even the occasional but we are using
encryption the connection because the
congressman's
they send you think it messages but
after a while
what the user's social networks like
cost seen and contains
they will send you to keep you because
you aren't you the bottom two
at some point you have school before the
messages and you have to do that the one
visions will be sent to the key key
novice
a doctors who was one of the officials
wouldn't want your successful network
key but in order to better understand
how this war
we first public talk a little about the
routing layer model
crucial their routing protocols that are
used in sensor networks
at the same the asking all other
wireless networks will give their dues
for constructing communication of from
all over the North's
so what's the base station no session at
worst there appears to be
to be a great day vested you this
routing protocols would be but most of
the existing ones
infection I don't think that the this
will change in the near future
usually quite the calculations of the
rocky coast method
so what they do is the Noles
jus us the bottom the immediate bottom
24 with the admissions
but wants to reach the destination to
the node was the best
link while K if you got way they believe
there are two people what's the base
station
now hereof put the two examples the
summit the most widely used
welcome for the call sheets instrumental
from these days even in the
invasive unification Zwicky this marked
the homes for some cities
this summer the put together they are
using soul
whip up to meet all and the mood quite
right
the fest wonderment alt use this link
want the estimates
again us there knocking Coast metric so
what does
if these calculations the are based
on the bike it at a rate key shown the
Norge
30 or the commitments made specific
methods
called welcome date key and all of their
neighbors
the over here this transmission that out
the dates would be the
estimate then in quality based on the
packet loss
well this motivates key so that %uh
published top secret number
you should buy something that ought to
go to call you hover
I could see was number one two three if
you lose five six seven
them to cover the have created their
functions to become embedded inside the
nodes
games you can find finish the mission of
the quality over the issue understand
key this is not a very I could
estimation cue because
the musician it was a special message
from it which
which are in the they don't PubMed
strong and a nice
to go home for good luck wild pitch no
one saw
it's one of the notes maintains a
neighborhood BBQ inside its memory
Mukundan show love the idea of its
neighboring nodes along with the
corresponding week while Kris
so every time since use but something
changes
inside the statehood but us to be
something like a really big chains
like the pot and died so I talked to
delete it from there
neighborhood they've been alright see
but mike got in
bottom link what these really bob's so I
felt better in quotes a minute with a
blue
movies to be just the pun intended
mechanism not to talk to choose
your pipe know the mood to open tryout
protocol again operates in a similar way
but it goes to the dogs cause
a better indicator it for the talking
about the cosmetic
what is the difference is that the link
want the estimation
calculation actually is based on their
own pocket when
but the Cubs the sense from the old key
so up to this
the the most guys 'cause this kind of
hard work so what they do again the
North's periodic
but will be going to just meet the
methods called Bacan show only exception
all of the other neighboring nodes boss
this message to his hard work
okay again the public function in the
extract the link quality
novel equality response to another
function
not from these the country meet the cost
of the past
obviously wiki the the relation between
the cost
and the Equality case you missed the
proportion key
if the new quality is better than the
butt of course will be small
the minimum possible so you can find
such political Lisa the number fifty
the important think about that often
called the coaches up there
all of them they are all designed public
stop using mine meaning that once
the Cubs created that out in three so
what's the base station
key they want to stick to it they don't
want to have many diseases
inside the sale completed why this is
done first before because
whenever a group are you think you're
fine tunes in mechanism B school
standards
invent it is very important instrument
which and also
if you make a lot of changes previous
may lead
blogging sites because when you choose
your part in talks when you don't know
if the skies above the base station okay
so this may be per cycle
so the hospital because we all good news
for help with the search
not avoiding they didn't happen but for
the leading the cyclist but this is
really costly
so they don't want to hardware such
rocks items much wine or the food chain
25 attained
he sighs the smoking three we might come
up with two reasons first before his up
got important type for some reason
doesn't have any energy at the white
died so you have to change your of
school which was another part
the authorities on is that if you find
in your neighborhood David another
neighborhood mold
key but the cheating quality seventy
percent better
done they want to comment on posts key
so I should understand
it must be really better than the
current one
in order to change your departing this
release it does this week look like
the more difficult for them thank you
okay so now let's describe the
the most the known waste but the night I
can come notes that she called
in a social network know the first
Sarkozy is really simple and actually
it's a pretty
your text or but woke up was admitted to
doing there fucked on
because it's really easy to will be
detected if the social network
house any guidebook for defense mickens
or security protocol even the simple
lost mission this one
so what the like a gun blues actually
it's going to start with ties a very
highly
1/4 cent is solely index intense fake
messages
fake updates wilkey advertising
the high slick one-two between itself
and all of its me buttons
if I sleep while the is 255
but as we said this may be no this may
not be enough
to trigger the pontoons in Macon is ball
of the other
to enable notes because even if that I
can transmit some estimates
advertising content while feels 255
if their neighbor knows schmitz et cover
pardons with Nick 121 same it'd be this
is I don't think this is a bad person so
that we looked
to give the pontotoc megan's sure what
the possible
to the tough to make the other notes the
got in parliament the
all of the content parlance good to make
them look but
good pubs for you wanted what's why baby
special Mideast notes
key she's they concede that will see the
sparkle the network
key obviously also love the other
neighboring nodes basie
that up a bit of all of the neighborhood
so the knoll
what to order the bottoms of which one
other note and what are the mean one
sure you she cheered up like a
confession made each one
over the bonds inside the neighborhood
key and Oxford nice
early but I think was different said and
with six children
the us about this obvious can be used
only four other protocols
the problems that often cost me think
link while the estimates
key not calculation like that the more
the public artwork but this time it's
about the
us we said with a mean throws the
because folks why
this is what that's like you used here
to pick up on the sofa because it's an
estimation
and actually you can convince the other
know that this my estimation
key that's why the passionate and the
consent fake link Wildcats
but it easy to detect the sooner we said
because the seems the Nord the some
think about is not legitimate
special mission she can be easily
detected by your neighboring nodes
especially for the cover protocol
the cosmonauts make sandwich cooperate
to two other
not identified the so's police the
impersonator
you then they will call to social now
the second strategy
again this is simply and
in order not to be depicted that i could
think twice by the fact that the pubs
a really strong content okay so what the
bus
B dubs advises the transmits
the Commission's with the minimum cost
well what's the base station
key so the mean cost is $15 so what it
says is not
I the only one hope away from the base
station
goodbye cover the milk of of course so
love you sent the message to me know the
full with them
to the base station so he can send
again fake messages even if it is not
dachshund