published action sporting the government
morning you can execute them
you can played with the program content
and then would go to the government
you've got a fun heart of the picture
devices
okay program and don't remember spaces
office can you separate
okay so in Parliament artificial devices
to come not
public comments sent messages conveying
the destruction of the payload
and factually execute them sold
would be what she did him on a solution
one missions
okay containing two or three sections
could depending on the mission size but
they're usually the message size insist
on it with a small
marching the default like it which is
used most of the pic is from spent four
bytes
you so you can actually send 45 months
and execute the commands
but which sent throughout this message
the
then Vista guys that come from France
okay I will not try to save their names
been demonstrated
because detection devices with the
following a few picture but the
because of the nature of this kind of
pics with us
limitations would be fished before this
we said you cannot execute
you call destructions but can be sent
three messages
so what they demonstrated this actually
call to execute
the sequence of instructions but already
stored
inside the program emotive the note give
a call the city got its
key chauffeur's what they do is do find
the memory model for the note in the
fine selection sequins
not the kind used like sending gets all
the credit from God's its
and that they showed that if you can use
it anal began executing
this god's its you can actually inject a
fake stock
decide the note okie bye bye bytes and
then actually texting you for coming
months
but that is the the the big think use a
seems you inject a fake stock which is
really big it's like good 256 bytes
bite bite bite you can imagine how much
time stakes
so obviously something that I can be
detected by the Administrative
okay and the it's not the
okay you cops to find okay specific
instruction sequences
inside the remember him up if you cannot
find this action she pushes you want
so we've there is a guy that knows what
these functions are used in a forensic
spate good
stocks so you won't be able to do such
chemical detection a doc
info about that for a device okay so
that's why we target the
also have only one pictures okay but why
you use the most guys in for devices
us remember the cob them as people for
the microcontroller
key which is it's based on them when
women are
picture so what we did is we took one
step further that work well for tribes
which beat
and factually -2 injecting execute a bit
tonight in Long Colt
not call this auction will come to send
only 31 message okie
and then we do still in development this
of each one essential knowledge
and actually create a self-replicating
warm okie
that propagates the Cottonwood
throughout the whole network
so what we achieved by infecting only
one node
good which takes effect seconds p
eventual you compromise of 3rd two or
three minutes because we help them some
this Google compromise environmental on
its ok with more about this
so as we said we'd target devices
following the only one that the pictures
be the selection who got us talking the
same members face
get here you can see the memory mop of
them is before 30 Michael controlled
who used to date back in order to find
these things now the heat
behind being able to to inject arbitrary
long called
inside the network is not sensor nodes
do not support dynamic memory allocation
okay
show all memory but is needed for duck
boat
my love this function key his phone and
allocated
during a violation you but on the other
cons
she's this is a typical embedded system
would be the company's if memory space
for the heap key piece for the dynamic
memory allocation
so he purrs over here both and goes
upwards
okie sold peacekeeper members pay such
release
remain unused in this initial netbooks
throughout the call
lifetime of the network okay and not
only thoughts
the other thing is that even if you take
the note you can take the cold
and you publish a copy to the say MMO
space between you two said the nodes
the cold over there will not be a racist
K
the tough specifically say to the Nord
slush
organ memory otherwise the vindiction
called will always be there
so what we did we found the memory but
the heap starts
gates 25 74 it was gross supports
and then we used this member space
in or did to go pee or malicious called
K so you can do something we're going to
go pee a really big
shove called bus always keep in mind
but you don't have to you must not
override the stock
okie which glows long words consult from
this others
because otherwise the sensor most good
will the will not do anything we got
bounced a they remain there
for that if it's like because it will be
better okay
so the other important thing he's up
I'll come up in income
muppet me about pockets so watcha Lee
agencies we don't have the number and
location essential knowledge
all memory other sis but I reject for
specific functions
the other the same shocks from the many
others which is used by this mission old
for storing it achieved by Kent remains
the same for specific programming much
day independent of where you are
compliant get the memo the others
you too remains the same so by again by
using its a duck
you can find these the this other ish of
where
the the doctor inside the pain of a bike
at are stored
in again to come play with it you can
actually be a buffer overflow
overnight and other social survival
function pointing to but the address
okay and then actually execute your
money she's called
the most important thing here is this
restoration of a little
okie so what this means is actually if
you want to inject
a big piece of code York from POF
synthesis of malicious bike YouTube
according to Google
show when you sent one missile defense
missiles
you overnight there have been other
stuff the run up a function you point to
the official where the duck up
over the missile distort show you
execute them on issues call decide the
mission's
Austin these you have to be careful to
restore
the control flow to stop it special no
box its normal state
because otherwise you're gonna send any
other missions mortgage to lock cyli
windshield inside every message you we
must cover but once a month
key for making the point that the
program convert the point buck
to the with instructions no
this does not look good in the required
steps his first full
to ponder something we dwell over this
is what device but we're going to target
key will be some little things that we
said you must find
Esplanade others of the many which
largely the others not the cheap stocks
and you have to find the memory I'm
gonna solve the reception at a fund
with the venue of it does mission of the
offices of my pockets containing the
cold but this
to be coping into the heap good so what
you actually do
is a mid-stage buffer overflow so which
one of the pockets before lunch buffet
with your talk
and then send the specially crafted by
kids okay for changing the program
counter
to the obvious it over a cold YouTube
he partially no this is how it works
guy wheeler go through it fast because
I'm running out of time
socially the fact that with so much you
okay so the first to visit when you
achieve the no decision methods
the bottom function he will publish
their coping case called
okie so what this does is take the
available to mention its advice to cope
with
inside the buffet soul with 12 a buffer
overflow
but the security whenever this reception
funders call
is called so the second step is over
here
uses Republic buffer overflow that it
did not show this to cope with function
is over even by obvious you wanted
okay so you put the others also the
I see you you can see the work you put
the other ish of where demolishes called
inside the pocket
distort keys and you know this %uh this
so
this is the third step you execute you
execute all the cold
but no keep in mind that seems to want
to go pure gold
decide to keep wiki the payload before
this message will contain
move months cute because you want to
move your gold
into the keep so this is an example
such a payload with of the box
the first box contains without us of the
this thing so if you have money school
destructive side the bike it
so this is used for overnighting that
they're not official this BB
miss you the second part which actually
contains more instructions
okay with the fall like its eyes affairs
social network you can send
three more months key in this is the
final instruction for storing the
control-flow
so actually two bombs for months okay
sold you are hoping to call these trying
to keep the
memory in the final step is actually
sending message with a buncha month for
setting the program counter
pointing to the fathers were here before
stopping executing the cold
now once the program companies which
he's over here
key you be texting cuz you called
usually put some dumb
inside so in order to execute in more
than one times so we cannot go bike
to its normal state it's impossible the
moment
but Sussex a good thing you're cold it
cannot receive another message is
accused