my name is so nice and it's like I'm
from Greece
so sensitive not been secured the group
a doctor's permission technology
and I'm also doing my beats the apps UPS
University
you know go them at the day's topic
would be able discussion describing and
a thoughtful that's capable of
compromising the security bro fight
well for wireless sensor network its
basic functionalities
EP would awesome on opening of the
section on doctor
actually slifer and most importantly the
ability to launch bodies kinds of bucks
against this network's what's one more
important characteristics that you can
be applied to
differences were fun with us from swatch
into reportable
but before we describe the school we are
going to talk with about the field in
back on the door
so we're going to talk about some other
good services networks but can be
exploited by and i cant
and we will describe all the doctor but
don't want to pick up some way up to
and actually used in order to extract
important
met with information about its
functionality
know the addition such stop and the
also since hopefully the
drive tool to do a last name of the dude
okay we'll see
I have a toy network with you so we'll
see what the
is this a top of the store network
official first before starting with a
brief overview of 12 social networks
the whole many of you know about this
kind of networks
he saw clearly Wireless is from old
is in an embedded system it with the
microcontroller development and the bus
today the United
yes you can see the figure because all
of the components will fit the pic on
embedded system
the different stuff over here on the
sensors and actuators
which are actually Conklin form ongoing
and not the good of interest in a
specific area and
the corresponding colors for funding the
fence coming from the central what he
sees the energy
is not one of the strong gospic
substantial knowledge agreement with the
case went out to go
underlying protocols our daily lives
when conventional memory Invenergy
you sold the most of the times these are
all time low carb devices
okay you can see some some food
public blossoms word using the third one
school team on skype we chose this
article critique some
actually because this is the talk with a
marxist my universe that they will be
here
now work with a concept
of successful no two will deploy them
not serious of interest income but one
decision at work which is able to SoCal
figures if
and adopt to different kind of changing
this is really important because usually
would deploy system os
the Sun deployed to follow since and do
something that is above not easily
accessed
my few months so we need them
once deployed to be able to configure
the same stop to it working
and actually adopting vitamins and
teases motifs
and pissed off intentional communication
with health
mood hope I'm into one communication
between the nodes
in touch with a local SBA more than one
of for communication between the North's
and the destination which actually the
base this before so we promise
networking
example application Sharda smart grid
sense from a crush on the really used in
the military
special another base wiki and didn't
think a wildlife for structural health
building one drink and old age that
strengthen social networks
days the using them in combination with
ought to fight these
in order to build the so-called smart
environment
smart homes much fifty's the last think
use a why social networks are good for
us okay first performed I think the most
important is because with a relatively
small amount of money
she's most commercial notes are to be
we can go over lots head of
international interest
and more including a number of a of a
huge through vents
physical she did to be a really robust
against North link fails
because once we said recover mesh
networking so even if an old
phase know what was being out there not
just of from another note to the base
station
can finally as user
can have access to the data inside the
network from wherever she wants
it's not necessary to be close to the
network would be so special that will
support the credential did for depicting
plus
like a duck and complications become
provides Florida
then special striking in order to
identify and Mon began moving object
and also even in the case of an orange
but you should not amount of data
that out look of our group but on inside
the nose but provides information
integration and other one
station peaceful this was
the the overview the center networks so
let's move on
to the theory behind the food official
actually first
with the sky the security challenges of
this network
if they're not a good summer they ought
to be the most important with unexploded
buy that bike if
O'Keefe s the votes in Seoul and
or transmission something wirelessly you
got exposed for bucks likes
eavesdropping interception alteration or
deeply about the
and injections of money just like its
called injection
week essential molds are the most
usually operate in another department so
again that exposed fiscal up actually
can be seen compromised by now if I
could
with all them to see the actual known
about it now when we deploy since when a
group
again most of the times we don't have
any problem on its
of that the portage so it's totally
random again this can be used by a
specially
because it contains the positional the
nose and factually leave
and many of the network empty so there
will be a possible communication between
something which
besides he said to finally talk to
protect them
against the inside a box gay because
once deployed and I'd like to go there
to a compromise in order used to just
like they won't be able to deduct
for gaining access into the needs memory
key
V Scarlets to post modification of
memo recalled wanna believe this weekly
which in turn can lead to attacks like
board's action
so Harvick all these things in mind the
research community what the dude is the
proposed several defense mechanism
okay but try to prevent and protect this
networks however to get specific a touch
do but the smoking of every day is a new
day for that I cancel there are always
new kinds fucks
the existing affectionate everyday
shopping with a different and better way
so secure the course always exist so
that's why they moved one step further
movie started to implement intrusion
detection protocols
which actually don't prevent that talks
from taking place
the village them popping $1 billion type
montel
abnormalities you the network
functionality shoeless I could find
something is wrong
King however both police megan is
you move more movies megan's by 75
degrees
post to the next level for this Yazdi by
they are not be too for the doc inside
the metal p
show what we've done first before you
that we can be made to sniff n
for capturing and holding all these data
not available
in a sensor network show we overhear the
network traffic
key we've got really wanted it we'll all
get and
we then who tried to process all over
the transmitted by kids in order to
extract
important information about the network
no chain uses
looking Sohag on the sniffer can be used
in order to compromise the security of a
social network
official phone the and i cant use
the Cardiff frequency in order to Lowes
aside time to talk
and try to identify the network
underlying social hard work
showing up talkin can use either
spectrum analyzer
or different special hardware attached
to the love to run the ball
like in this case you like without
substantial note
do so and then she can find the
communication frequency used to the
network
once a disk or words of key scenes
commercial notes you specifically which
is
to communicate she commanded then what
is that the manpower
and then she can use all the political
abilities but I used
with this specific on work
second think is love by observing the
mission's rate inside
up in size inside this social network
you saw this going to be an important
information about the network
publication
a defeat miss you for longer events the
this much closer to the soviet threat
because for some special obligations
macbeth wandering
again which is a hot trend know they
should using sensor network streaming in
health with about this morning you want
to the patient's
you go this can reveal this can lead to
a violation of the user's privacy
work also it with the missile drapes key
and i cant can use this new for in orbit
to estimate the rate that she overhears
messages come from a particular area
you that way she can estimate that the
Suns
from the source to vent you there are
those papers and research has shown that
the
the message the section eight increases
us that the sums to the north the
actually reporting the event degrees
and finally what we are trying to got
through
inside this new friends is that ok
information
the this up like a sexually abused by
the autumn underlying protocols
in a social network the actual values
for all stuck to the communication of
between the notes