and the second thing is I don't worry a
little bit less about information for
them
because I don't think about the future
to be done medic even the places that
have done that
are beginning to purchase sometimes have
chipping away from that
and than a good thing is that I worry a
lot more about port security
that and I think this is going to come
or more important as a
for Anna in 2004 a
Nikita Borisov golfer character room a
paper
called off-the-record communication or
wanna
to use PD and their
observation was pretty straightforward
what they
noticed was there on if you look at
okeedokee works probably you know almost
seems like I was never use pgp but must
feel
no how it works right which is and let's
say that I sent an email to Bob
I get off public key and I'm tripped my
email about public key
and I senator bob found it on another
note about
I use Bob same public key
and get that an upset about on and on
and on and
the problem is that if and any point
bob's public key is compromised
then every email that you never sent
is in that he is now also compromised
that
if I send an email to Bob today it is a
cure
but if even 20 years in the future
someone mentions a compromise
ability that ella is now past so
becomes that one key compromise fast all
previous four spots is that a promise
that you're in this weird situation
where the secrecy of what i right is
dependent on
door security practices just have the
opposite a while
you know I'm sorry can I am like what I
think our stringent security practices
but I
don't really know if that's true for the
people that was funny I would like for
my security practices to protect the
secrecy of the things that I might
and but the problem is that you have a
fantasy
with her calls like he he you don't have
to nine billion and so what that means
is there
if I write this message hey Bob I was
thinking that you know the realtor
he had any point that messages a
compromised
there's no way for me tonight and
I absolutely ruthless a
its and would that that's partially nice
read it does bother see this message and
he knows that it came from me
but I would like for about another came
from me but also to the other
some point say that wasn't really me a
the promise that is undeniable at it as
it is and so
I'll these I photographers were
proposing that paper
a something called off-the-record
messaging and the way this works
is there everyone continues to have a
public/private key pair as
you know we're familiar with but the
difference is that those the those he
cares I never used to encrypt actual
data
instead their only used to sign an
ephemeral key exchange
that you do a between buffers so
else about change ephemeral Hughes which
they sign
using their key pair so that you know
that you have a fantasy
really talking to the right person then
you use that Amaral
he care to actually exchange messages
and
what you do is there every time you
change a message
you also include past other key exchange
one hard to keep the change
so appended pippen did learn that in
your message is also a key change
which means that every time you exchange
messages and
you get a new
key exchange which means that the key to
your using to exchange messages can
continue rolling forward
and so not only are using a penalty is
but also
every time you change a method you have
in your Jeep but ultimately falling
so there's not any one key they can
never be compromised to affect
on your previous messages because that
he is constantly changing and animus
toward anywhere from 11
furthermore CMS's I think that with this
session
and instead of using digital signatures
to authenticate that message
years message authentication code and
Mel message authentication code is
he'd ahold the session its a derivative
the session so this decade signatures
are undeniable
because they only have one possible all
but
max have to pass a law that's right
because
to most people no the key that is used
to construct the matter but Alice and
Bob soap opera see the message
he knows that you know he wrote it for
Alice read it and since he knows that he
didn't write it
you know that without but if at any
point you present this message and says
house wrote this isn't up to the
Allison say no that was %uh and there's
no way for anyone to differentiate
whether as one of the other
what's more since this other
message authentication he is
attributable to seventy
and the session he is constantly rolling
forward it means that
the Mackies a constantly growing forward
as well and 10 forward to a new mackey
and it is no longer censored the old one
a is candy given away it doesn't matter
if you keep it secret wanna and so they
explicitly
publish it a openly in the clear
in the spare parts every time and that
he becomes obsolete the publisher
white which means that now anyone could
potentially have been watching this then
and unusable mackey to my or four
channel message
which means that a this cannot be used
to inject
new messages which would be received by
Bob up indicated a secure
because they moved on to a new mackey
but if someone presents a message
chaos but this is a fucked up you can
say not only well it might involve
but also Canada any potentially shopper
but it was better this message so now we
have authenticity
and we have a really strong national
tonight building
so the nice thing about otro is that one
key Hamas does not affect
all previous messages but also that you
get authenticity
entitled so I think that particles like
this are going to be
very important in the future that as in
the forward anytime at: secure protocols
the first things that theirs is the
sport secure
because we're moving into this world
where key disclosure is becoming more
more
more and more mission so another project
that I started
with a people from the Institute for
Development Studies
is this project public assistance and
we're trying to do
is combine and fourth secure protocol
into mobile phones which are Anderson
is to trans that I'm interest in working
on the future
this place where were asked to make this
choice that i think is a good choice
and also a where fort secure protocols
are gonna become more and more important
I'm so a to think that we're working on
right now
are first a a scripted Voice application
that uses for it secure protocols and
readiness for
enjoy just the easy thing to do first
and look you know there are other for
device applications and have been on the
market for a while
but what we want to do is this should be
something for free that is
extremely extremely easy to use we want
this to be as easy to use
as making in Omaha that it should be
integrated into existing tile on your
smartphone
the Asian of depression should be based
on existing phone numbers
and it should be as easy for you here to
make your call
than just to make an Omaha the way this
works
a is playing using that the data channel
you know WiFi or 3G actually transmit
the voice communication
and so is this question doesn't know
what's up
and the answer is usually yes but and
the reason that I am think if that's
usually comes down to signaling
so normally in some weird situation you
have two parties to try and communicate
and you also have to at some point sir
like nafta sheen the sand on the ceiling
and this means we have to
Mangini connection like a TCP connection
already connection
to the report server at all times
and in the context a mobile environment
this is really
can be sure that and because now I have
to maintain a constant love and passion
to
some server somewhere on the internet
which means your phone can't ever go to
sleep
and also means that as yours for the
moving around
you like going out network connectivity
the connections to break one party might
not notice that action is broken and I
had this for
have been situation and things start to
work poorly so but we've decided
is there a lot of in the mobile
environment a lot of signaling can
actually be pushed onto the existing
signaling infrastructure that is used
for telecommunications
that this is really nice ceiling
mechanism
its fall the phone company but you know
that
a you know they know how to address
devices on the network
and their pretty good at and so what
we're trying to do
is leverage that existing bank to a
use the signaling in our opposition and
so
a initially and what we're doing is
using the signaling using SMS
so whenever you want to go another far
he just send an SMS message
and the a pull your information at that
and connect their a over the TV channel
to your phone directly
see you have this point to point on mold
the
little with connection and you don't
need any
long-running actions to some ashford
server somewhere with some
user name configured probably won't
and so the upside other your phone
doesn't mean
a constant never fashion winter from go
to sleep
you don't need if they want to Skype ID
you're offering an idea anything's
the phone numbers are funner you know
that's how you're dressed
if you know someone's phone number you
know how to phone securely and that you
don't miss Mina blitzer
you don't need some server are some
Harbor anywhere and just installing a
and I'm ready to go readiness circles
and and that