that are required by law to reveal that
information to
eavesdroppers and governments worldwide
on
so what's the difference meters
you can lead to something at home but
you probably don't
it's not mandatory red
red choice this is the difference
you choose to carry a cell phone
whereas you would be forced to carry
a tracking device why I have a little
fun
never in my wildest dreams did I think I
would have a fun
10 the mobile tracking device it
communicate different your protocol is
potentially a mobile Bob
and yet I have so did I cheat
to have a little fun maybe I think you
look at the weighted
people and organizing groups and
communities they're often
sort informal communications networks
that bind together
that allowed to communicate make plans
for detective
and introduced sorta something like the
Jess and cellular network a
to this router and if I start using it
I am on subject to something that's very
well known for the new network effect
right where I'm the only one with the
Sahara
it's really not worth much that the
value
the network isn't the number people that
are connected to it and that if
I'm the only one I can really
communicate with anyone however if I
somehow managed to get everyone
to start using my communications network
it becomes very effective and very
valuable but there's an interesting side
effect
which is that the all informal
mechanisms the people use to communicate
ivory disappear that they are destroyed
by the introduction a technology the
technology actually change the social
fabric
help people communicate important Anna
and mobile phones there many obvious or
two you know many examples right
and people use to make plans right to it
said
I meet you on the street corner at this
time on this day
and you know will do something another
say I'll call you when I get enough for
and all tested and
if you don't have a mobile phone can't
really participate in just
type of organization and so you began to
find yourself
on kinda low because if I now
make the choice not to be a part of this
so the network this sort of an
interesting thing where
once again I am subjected to the no
network effect because
the network that used to exist this
informal communications channels
have been destroyed so yes
I made a choice to have more fun but
what kind
a choice too many and I think that this
is so interesting phenomena where what
happens
is a choice is introduced and it starts
as a very simple choice a choice whether
or not to have a mobile home
a simple is a technology but slowly
things happen
to expand the still have that choice
until eventually
its sold a as to encompass not just
whether you have a little fun in a
but whether or not you want to be a part
of society that in some ways
the choice to have a mobile phone today
has become a not necessarily
just what do you have keyser consent
like consumer electronics in your pocket
but whether or not we're even apart
society Anna
much better choice and needy not one
that we should have to me
or at least not one that's really it was
all so i think is having a small
choices the coming the choices is
actually everywhere at once you start to
look at
and I've arts my most favorite
recent example is with this %uh Firefox
add-on call
Adblock Plus people familiar with this
very popular
it allows me to block at and
who
the way this works is by a defining a
and with regular expressions
which specified euros like to talk andy
is with great expressions
you can probably at Target most at the
euros that will be
serving at the problem is that like
these URLs are so accustomed to change
into that network server
introducing new things and so you wanna
be's updating and maintaining this
the list of things that you want to
block and so not everyone wants to
simply keep on this game
and so what at what class is done is
ideally the system up subscription
we can subscribe to a list that someone
else maintains
up on euros that are likely at
and this is a few populist
and then there's also a few populists
for blocking traffic
so these are things like web clubs and
stuff they're tracking your movements
around the internet
and so I and tried to list that's on
updates you know the your health for
the tractors that I would like to block
and one day
well and so of course wanna be major
things in this list I was interested in
walking is a Google Analytics
because you know what is worse
then what tools are you doing that
Google Analytics anywhere monitoring
your movements on the internet even when
you're not listening and services
and a so one day
Google Analytics disappear from mine
subscription lists if you think about
the whole way
know so the old world you imagine that
there was some Google all executives who
and I found the maintainer this list and
you know showed up with a briefcase full
of cash in a shook hands and
you know the has bad 2009
convinced the the guys making this list
to remove Google Analytics
but as far as I can tell that's actually
not what happened
and Google Analytics works the in
javascript
where you if you wanna hold
be trashing the people to visit your
website new import a little the
JavaScript for me
you're eligible hosts and automatically
the statistics are crude
and what Google started doing was saying
all right you're putting this javascript
and as long as you're importing and here
are a few
such as useful JavaScript functions
that's a
many people will probably want just to
make their
website work just if they're going to
employ some jobs within their website
and will just put some useful functions
in our
dressed up in the air are importing
which you can then use for the
the actual functionality your website
you know for the convenience than
you know they're going to do it right
now mister friend and but so this
is very interesting because what they've
done is expand the spill
a choice you have to me because now
if you block Google Analytics you're not
just stopping
the statistics from accruing you're
actually breaking the functionality of
the website
because now the website doesn't have his
bout JavaScript functions that it uses
for its core functionality
and so what happened was the person was
maintaining this list
and had to remove Google Analytics
because to block it was actually
breaking web sites
and services diabolically clever
on happened to the right has weathered
understand discover the choice you have
to me
from not just whether or not you want to
participate in the statistics
a accumulation Google Analytics but
whether or not
you want to use the Website at all if
you
don't participate Google Analytics you
can use the Website anymore if you want
looks like you have to present the
violence
souter why is the significant for us
all this man's name his john poindexter
is incidentally
a the person was found to be mostly
responsible for the alarm contra scandal
he was convicted of lying to congress
but
of course I never went to jail and 2002
he introduced
a government program call Total
Information Awareness
and a in the United States and
he on gives each one was injured in this
program
and he says dealers unit made available
in large skillet other words with
enhanced
semantic content for easy analysis
what he was proposing is that this
government program with just store
all email to all amtrak all credit art
history
all everyone's medical records that
works let all this
without worrying about analyzing in real
time or pulling information out to
figure out what's going on just dumping
and all into one
large saying and then they would develop
the
technology or the algorithms to really
efficiently
mine data at the Spitfire to build the
profiles
and a generator statistics on
relationships
that they might lead a lot and so this
was sorta the totalitarian future it was
a psychopath night
and it was what they have been preparing
for what they had imagined
that we were going to get and why they
were so interested
any promoting photography in first place
but john poindexter announced this
program
people freaked out and I mean this is
looked totally scared right now it's a
it's pretty that even you know congress
was a little what's going on here
yeah he a and cell
it the program was actually a stamp to
was cancelled
also why did people forget first evolved
there doing it all wrong that clearly
from some people right they don't
understand how things work today
this was their actual program logo
this isn't like non-union came up with
something wanna this is what they chose
they have the I am got up on the pier in
an economy on the bus on a shit
with the email light shining on earth
itself
that bin Laden under their means
knowledge is power
and is nazar yeah
they clearly don't understand how this
works if your gonna start like a scary
government program like this you really
like to