she was built out from I just wanted to
to come show the scale that kinda
challenges that we had
um would have built up the team
I had two tracks one was armed security
that's a response team
and the other was the law enforcement
response to you and that those are
people who
a law enforcement comes to with
subpoenas warrants and ask for data we
go to the
and missus I'm I'm found any other
company that's really done it this way
yet but the reason we did it this way
because usually law enforcement era
group legal under Lawyers
third they're treated as compliance not
really as a as security
reason we did it this way as I thought
the security answer response teams going
to proactively look on our site and five
what people are doing try and figure out
what the underground economy is around
us disrupted
that way but we can also gain a lot of
information about what criminals are
doing on the site because the police are
gonna come and tell us every time they
give us a warrant or subpoena
and bring those two pieces of
information
those two information collection
mechanisms together has actually
produced wonderful results and the tools
that we build
we can simultaneously built for both
teams so the same tools that they might
use to respond to
or request or subpoena request we can
use internally
to investigate attacks in incidents and
it'd be a less than $50 million number
is that was about the number of users
before we started building up the stream
until that point you to these boxes
represent one person sorry about three
people doing this job
as you got greater than 50 we built out
and
did we split the security that's a
response team into three separate silos
I'm malware does pretty much what you
expect it does is we
we go and get about where the targets us
we
reverse engineer we analyze it random
boxes above
if the box we try and give command
control network to to see what they're
doing
all that kind of stuff investigation
is pretty much what you expect it's
developing cases against people
I am looking attacks analyzing what
they're doing
and trying to to figure out how to how
to circumvent them
and intelligence is in the middle
because it is a little bit in the middle
it's not only
analyzing the attacks are people doing
against us but looking at the whole
value chain
how do how someone able to pull out this
attack what is our ultimate goal
how to do has a community feel about us
are they afraid to love us with a not
are people planning attacks is someone
shopping around for particular script
that's what we doing intelligence have
some great stories are what are you up
to
if the hit me up later this evening gets
diplomatically did
so this is a big one that values also
from the very beginning
is compliance is in security and
but I'm gonna call old PC as once back
but the everyone knows is
there's a lot more specs and a lot of
organizations I think we'll
have security organization that comes in
and really views the world from an
information security perspective so
they're gonna have a suspect
they want policies around its they're
going to implement
password controls in eighty access
controls and things of that nature
really from the outside world the real
threats that we faced
maybe your organization's buffets those
who really do anything
you can be fully PCI compliance still
get actors
as has been proven many many times so
home when your small you're moving
faster you have a lot of very dynamic
attacks against you
in my opinion the time you spend on
compliance above and beyond what you
absolutely have to
is time wasted okay
a.m. here's a little bit of a model how
we think about the world
and CEO
will still works call this diagram the
triangle for obvious reasons
it's gonna be a triangle a so the bases
vulnerabilities in the way that we
define vulnerabilities is
every piece of software every
device every building every everything
really
has some mechanism to get in we all know
this
we just maybe don't know what it is yet
but there's away and/or around
everything if I could make the base of
the triangle
infinite I would because that's the way
that I think about it
and if you spend time going after every
single ability or trying to find a
reasonable ability in your network in
your application
in your physical plants the
anywhere you're spending a lot of time
going after and
trying to categorize an infinite set
maybe not the most useful time
threats are
I am the way we define threats are
their vulnerabilities that are actually
would be harmful
if they were exploitative years in your
room
in your environment so understanding
which are the water abilities are
important
are you threats versus those better just
their
in prioritizing accordingly is really
important this is hopefully not
something that is new to everyone here
I'm because I think that's that's the
way we all we've all thought about
security for a long time
but I think most up the security
organization especially compliance
a.m. a specifications
really said in these two layers of the
at the triangle
and they don't go further than that but
the
because without a tax threats and
vulnerabilities are phony
if you take a XP machine that some
patched and sit in a room that no one
can get into
I'm and don't worry about the output
have only one person come use it and you
never connect to the internet or do
anything
if you're printing paper offer there's
probably okay it's not a huge
a huge issue I'm but as soon as you put
that in
to the Internet you have a tax and
a especially when you're thinking about
things to do
XP box to be put it on the internet it's
almost as if you think about it as a
force of nature
that you click the box and it
automatically attacks are going to come
in eventually the box you don't
and that's kinda just the way it is so
the way to approach that is be very be
very strong at the
level between threats and attacks hardly
that so that
you can be attacked without the box
kitty getting owned
you could fight of such attacks
I think that that's some that's valuable
and obviously the
you want to do that a lot of players but
if you have
the most leverage way to attack attacks
is that there are people behind them
they're not forces of nature
every one of those attacks comes from
someone who has an agenda
a motive something that they want to do
and
if you go after them if you love them
home
you reduce the people that are
specifically targeting you
I'm and that's what we decided to do
or skip ahead actually it was a perfect
fit talk about things that we flip you
decide to do it
I think a lot of people folks
unprincipled abilities especially
complaints
attacks are a great place to understand
how she's reportedly go of reactors
wonderful site okay so from
the way that we really dealt with this
is
and this is this is pretty much our
policy still is
we don't pay attention to the
vulnerabilities I'm you we keep track of
them in terms of love
knowing what's out there and knowing
what's relevant so that we can assess
what's a threat or not
but if we see that there's something on
and
any of the millions list so we hear from
any of our our vendors that this is
relevant to us
we're not automatically gonna go Pasha
think we're gonna we're going to a
threat assessment first
and the threat assessments are really
based on
overall in the company what's important
and what's important to us is
protecting user data keeping the site
running at making people feel secure
with freemen data
so if there's a thread that's going to
say address
I'm something that's not necessarily
related to
for the production website its internal
I'm
and we don't think there's any way it's
gonna if it was compromised so what
access
user data we're probably not going to
get to that one right away
no man
the some really important thing to us so
was watching attacks
and identifying attacks because if you
see
if someone's attacking you that's really
the best mechanism you have for
identifying
who they are going after them you can
ultimately expand at a soap opera
medical
in later slide to other mechanisms to
identify them
but at the point when they're attacking
you you have
a bunch of data that you can if you
build the site directly but your data
that you can get
that will help you identify an attribute
that first even if you don't necessarily
know they are the real world
you can collated accident later
attributable to someone
and go after the actor so the way that
we decided to do this is will
everyone has a motive figure out what
the motives are and frustrate them
so a we talk about spam a second
obviously the spammers their motive is
making money and if you destroy the
economics of spammy for them
a.m. them the legal
it
them by the way if your judgment free
for seventy million dollars can someone
you're destroying economics is family
for them
did so some
one thing that we really be on a
facebook also is distributed help
from in this is probably actually
affected a buncha much people through
it's not security related but its
philosophical thing
we decided to translate the site into