- (upbeat music)
- Okay,
our final contestant,
surviving intrusions
in cloud native environments,
please welcome co-founder
and CEO
of Araali Networks,
Abhishek Singh.
(upbeat music)
(applause)
Hey Abhishek, welcome.
Thanks for being here.
All right.
Abhishek, your time begins right now.
- As security practitioners,
headlines like these make us cringe.
In spite of our best efforts
we are unable to prevent damages.
It is because one single mistake
allows intruders to sneak in.
The trick is to realize
that perfect posture
is unattainable.
It is essential to build
capabilities to survive intrusions.
Dealing with cloud API is, is complex.
As part of the shared
responsibility model,
you're supposed to securely
program those APIs.
If you're dealing with cloud resources,
you have to go configure
IAM with least privileges.
Kubernetes brings its own set of controls
and whole new configuration paradigm.
When you're dealing with
applications of virtual machines,
you have to deal with legacy controls,
like virtual firewalls
and security groups.
Misconfiguration leads to
over privilege that attackers
abuse to move around
in your environment
and cause material damage.
Correlating logs from disparate sources
and taking timely action
is equally complex.
That is why we took a plug-in
based approach at Araali.
We create normalized
identities for all services,
regardless of where they're running,
On virtual machines, in
Kubernetes, even behind APIs.
We combine endpoint context
with network activity to build a graph
of how these services
interact with each other.
You can allow good interactions
and deny malicious ones.
Assets protected by
Araali are unexploitable.
Defending inside out,
we don't talk to strangers,
even if they have solemn credentials.
We prevent both file based
and file less malware from establishing
back doors, or interacting with
services in your environment.
Denied by default is aspirational,
the hard part is policy discovery,
which we automate
continuously and consistently.
New code comes in with
policies pre discovered
in DEV and deployed alongside your apps.
For existing code, we help you shield in a
prioritized way by identifying
your highest risk assets.
With Araali, customers are
taking their own control
to the cloud, so they
can operate confidently
with deep depth in their defense.
Our founding team has industry
leading experience in areas
like Zero Trust Micro
Segmentation, Wireless Security
and Endpoint Security.
With Araali in your arsenal,
you are ready to defend
against the whole class
of attacks that has been
in headlines recently.
In summary, with consistent controls
deployed in a DevOps friendly way,
builds two resilience
for cloud operations.
(applause)
- Nice.
Excellent
(upbeat music)