(upbeat music)
- Our next contestant,
bringing incident response
into the cloud era.
Please welcome CEO and
Co-Founder of Cado Security,
James Campbell.
(audience claps and cheers)
- Wow.
Man, this is-
- How you going?
- This is serious, man-
- I know.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you very much.
- All right.
- [Host] Your time begins now.
- Remember the eighties?
The Apple IIe, the DeLorean, the Atari,
oh, and mix tapes.
I used to spend hours
making the perfect mix tape.
I'd wait for my favorite
song to come the radio,
press a record with those two
really hard to press buttons,
and wait for the whole song to finish,
and then I'd repeat the same
tedious process 20 times.
So what has this got to
do with cybersecurity?
Well, when I think about
how we do incident response
in the cloud today,
it kind of reminds me
of making a mix tape.
We collect each system, one by one.
We process the data for
each system, one by one,
just like a mix tape, one song at a time.
Sometimes it takes weeks
and sometimes in the cloud,
you can't even get access to the data
you need for an investigation,
and today, that's just not good enough.
There has been significant investment
in cloud prevention and detection,
but when it comes to
investigation and response,
we're stuck in a mix tape era.
With incident response,
every second matters.
Why wouldn't you use the cloud
to accelerate investigation and response?
For decades, I've been on the front lines
investigating sophisticated
cyber breaches,
working with every
agency you can think of,
and from NotPetya to Cloud Hopper
to breaches I definitely can't
disclose publicly here today,
we've funneled this
experience into Cado Response,
the cloud investigation platform,
to bring into incident
response into the cloud era.
Cado has helped some of
the largest organizations
reduce investigation time by over 80%.
Instead of manual data collection,
Cado automates data capture
across cloud container and
serverless environments.
Instead of relying on
processing systems one by one,
Cado delivers parallel processing.
Instead of relying on
a hodgepodge of tools,
Cado unifies data sources
across cloud provider logs,
disc memory, and more.
With Cado, what used to take days
now literally just takes minutes.
Cado automates seamlessly with
existing security products.
As soon as suspicious
activity is detected,
Cado captures critical evidence.
This automation is essential,
especially with all the
serverless environments today
where data can disappear
in a blink of an eye.
We have such an amazing team.
Collectively, we have founded companies,
we've driven acquisitions and IPOs,
and we have decades of
experience in cybersecurity.
Now, we've united to change
the shape of cloud security.
Cado is bringing into incident
response into the cloud era.
Thank you so much for having me today.
Thank you.
(audience clapping)
- [Host] Wow.
19 seconds on the clock.
Man, I love the mix tape analogy-
- Yeah-
- I think.
- I was thinking of wearing a
mix tape but it was too big-
- Yeah, you should.
(James laughs)
That's allowable.
(upbeat music)