(upbeat music)
- There is so much room left
to innovate in our space.
And I'm hoping over this week
those of you that are here,
those of you that are attending
virtually get inspired,
inspired on how you can
contribute to security.
And I wanna also begin by acknowledging
that we did have a virtual
innovation sandbox in 2021.
How many people attended the
virtual innovation sandbox?
(audience clapping)
Come on, I know.
Okay, a few people.
Okay, fine, fine.
I'm not gonna take it personally.
It was good, it was good.
It was not as good as
this, but it was good.
It was virtual, amazing companies.
And I wanted to allow the winner
of the 2021 Innovation Sandbox competition
to come up here and be recognized
because it was a real,
really tough competition.
Lots of, you know, lots
of amazing companies.
And so without any
further ado, let us roll
the winner announcement, go back in time
and acknowledge our 2021
Innovation Sandbox winner.
Roll the tape.
(drumroll rolling)
Paul, who is the winner
of Innovation Sandbox
at RSA Conference 2021
Virtual Edition, Paul?
- The judges are really
pleased to announce
this year's winner is Apiiro.
(energetic music)
- And we have our winner
here with us, Idan.
Come on up, come on up.
(audience clapping)
Good, congratulations, man.
We had to give you time on the stage.
- Thank you, thank you.
Thank you very much.
- How's everything?
- Exciting, a lot of progress and-
- Good, well, first give us
a one sentence of Apiiro.
What does Apiiro do?
- So we secure the entire
software supply chain
from design, development, and deliver.
Apiiro basically helps security teams
and developers proactively fix risks
in their cloud native applications
before delivering to the cloud.
- Wow, man, very timely, very timely.
And so talk to me about what's happened
since the innovation sandbox.
- Everything changed.
- Right, this is some serious.
- We built-
We built a top-notch team.
We grew the business by 398%.
- 398%?
- Yeah, small, small growth.
(audience clapping)
We took it from 20 people
to 90, across the globe.
We have amazing customers
from small shops,
like 50 developers, to 25,000 developers.
We contributed to NIST,
to the security software
development framework,
and to the software bill
of materials standards.
We found some interesting zero-day
software supply chain vulnerability.
- Responsibly disclosed, I assume.
- Yeah, absolutely, absolutely.
- Okay, okay, just checking, yeah.
- We worked with them,
and we helped them fix it.
And we launched our
partner program last week
with Google, HashiCorp,
NetSPI, and other big names.
- Fantastic.
Well, congratulations.
- Thank you.
I wanted you to have your moment on stage.
And bring the photographer.
Come on, man, we gotta do
a dramatic reenactment.
(audience clapping)
Apiiro.
- Thank you very much.
(audience clapping)
- Thanks, Idan, thanks
so much for being here.
(upbeat music)