>> ANNOUNCER: Please welcome
Executive Vice President
and General Manager
Security and Collaboration,
Cisco, Jeetu Patel.
>> JEETU PATEL: Hello, everyone.
Isn't it great to be
in a live audience?
Yeah.
You know, a little
trivia about Rohit.
So, Rohit and I used to work
together and when I had my
daughter, he was the first
coworker – I used to live in
Chicago at the time and we were
working in California so I was
going back and forth – and when
I was on paternity leave, he was
the first coworker that came
out there to see my daughter.
So, it’s so nice to
share a stage with him.
I know.
Look at that.
So, you know, it's great to be
in person but I used to have a
superpower and I
have kind of lost it.
I used to have a superpower
which was seven minutes flat, I
could pack my bags to
go for a weeklong trip.
I don't know if any of you folks
feel this, but I’m feeling it
right now because yesterday it
took me about seventy minutes of
staring at my suitcase and I
still forgot a bunch of things.
My entire product line for
my hair was like – I left it at
home, so it took me
a while to get ready.
So, if – today if you feel like
I'm a little disheveled, it is
because I left my hair
line products at home.
I'm feeling a
little disrespected here.
That wasn't a joke.
That was the truth.
Anyway, it’s good to be here.
And you know, if you take
away the jokes though and just
actually take – rewind back a
few years and what it was like
and just booking travel.
And the amount of
work that you have to do.
You have to make multiple calls.
You would have to go
on multiple websites.
You would have to go to multiple
companies and deal with making
sure that you get
your hotel done right.
You went to your
car rental place.
You also got your, you
know, kind of flights booked.
Today, you don't
have that issue.
Today, you actually go to a
single site and you have got
this fluidity of exchange of
data and everything is pretty
interconnected and you’re
able to go out, in a matter of
minutes, just go
out and get your,
you know, reservations booked.
And this kind of
interconnectedness is
something that most of us
have learned to expect in our
day to day life, whether it be
within your personal situation
or at work.
And what you are starting to see
is that there is a tremendous
amount of benefit of having this
interconnectedness, but what
you also see is there is a fair
amount of security challenges
that come along with it.
And so, if you look at, you
know, malware or phishing
attacks or ransomware, these
are growing at double and triple
digit kind of, you know,
rates as you move forward.
And this interconnectedness
itself is actually – it’s not
just something that’s impacting
you but every single member of
the supply chain,
your customers, your
suppliers, your partners.
When there is something
that happens to them,
it impacts you, right?
And so, there is this kind of
ecosystem that we are living in
right now, and in this
interconnected world, there is a
simple but massively overlooked
problem that I want to spend
this session talking about.
But before we do that, what I
wanted to do was make sure that
we talk about three specific
trends that our 300,000
customers are
actually sharing with us.
And by the way, this is going to
be kind of a stacking of trends.
So, Rohit went
through three trends.
I am going to go
I’m sure there’s the next
person that’s going to come
that’s going to go through
three trends and you can then
stack, rank us, and
tell us which one is better.
But the reality is that there
is a key set of trends that we
actually have that are – that
are becoming challenges in the
industry that we really have
to think about collectively as a
society rather
than individually.
So, let’s talk
about the first trend.
The first trend is the fact that
we as businesses are competing
as holistic ecosystems,
not as individual
organizations by ourselves.
What that means is that you
yourself might be materially
impacted in the way that your
production line works, in the
way that your supply chain
works, in the way in which your
demand cycle works based on what
happens to the other members
in the ecosystem.
Now, what you’re starting to see
over here, and a great example
of this is a top auto maker
recently, they had to stop their
entire production line because
one small component parts
manufacturer was not able to,
you know, protect themselves
because they had a
potential security breach.
And so, you had to have the
entire production line stopped.
Now, what specifically are
companies doing about this is
they are starting to take a much
more measured approach around
risk and making sure that they
can assess risk and say, well,
you know, if I'm going to have
vulnerabilities, the reality is,
is you have newer and newer
vulnerabilities that keep coming
up every single day.
But of the known vulnerabilities
– here’s a statistic that’s
fascinating – of the known
vulnerabilities that an
organization knows, only 20% of
them actually get remediated and
patched and fixed.
Only 20%.
Think about that.
And so, what we need to do is
make sure that we take a much
more risk-based approach
to vulnerability management.
That is what’s happening
and it’s what more and more
companies are doing.
And they’re starting to make
sure that they take a more
informed decision based on which
specific vulnerabilities do I
need to patch based on the
highest amount of risk rather
than first in, first out so
that I can make sure I have a
better security posture.
So, that's the first trend.
And associated and tied very
closely to that first trend is
the second trend, which
is everyone is an insider.
And what I mean by everyone
is an insider is firstly, humans
are pretty easy targets to
go after for cyber criminals.
And attacks are becoming much
more bespoke and personalized.
They are going after Jeetu
Patel rather than going after
the entirety of the
population that you might have.
And so, they are getting much
more personalized and more and
more of these individual
targets, whether they be, you
know, employees, but you don’t
just have employees anymore.
You have employees
and contractors.
But you have suppliers
and customers and partners.
So, the amount of people
that can go out and impact your
security posture is getting
larger and larger and larger.
And so, everyone is an insider.
You are starting to see that.
But specifically what is
starting to happen, and here is
another interesting statistic,
is 56% of the breaches that
happen, happen because of an
unknowing employee negligence
act rather than something that
is actually malicious in intent.
56%.
Now, if you really start
thinking about this and go, no
one's going to be working to
plan to be negligent when they
come into the office.
No one says, hey, I'm coming
into the office and I'm going to
be negligent today.
Right?
But mistakes happen.
And the reason for that is
because the friction is too high
and because of the
friction being high, the
efficacy goes down.
And so, you have to make
sure that those get balanced.
In fact, an example over here is
the Metropolitan Police, there
was an employee that
accidentally deleted 87 million
– 8.7 million records and
slowed down prosecutions that
impacted 17,000 cases.
Just out of pure
negligence, right?
And so, when you start thinking
about these pieces, the way that
we are actually going out
and attacking these problems is
through zero trust.
We’re saying, well, let’s make
sure that we actually have the
least privileged access that
we can provide to people, and so
there is a zero trust
mechanism that is in place.
And customers continually are
needing to assess behavior and
grant continuous assessment of
risk and then grant trust rather
than making sure that that only
happens at the time of log in.
So, what you are now starting
to see happen is rather than
saying I'm only going to verify
whether you are who you say you
are and give you access at
the time of login, I'm going to
assess your behavior
on a regular basis.
And if you are doing something
that’s anomalous in nature, even
though you might have logged
in, even though you have access,
I'm going to make
sure I can intercept.
And so, that's what’s
happening from a, you know,
zero trust standpoint.
And the third major trend that
you are seeing is something that
we have all have lived over
the course of the past couple of
years and it is
around hybrid work.
People are going to
work in mixed mode.
Sometimes they are
going to work in the office.
going to work at home.
Sometimes they are going
to be somewhere in between.
And when you actually see this
mixed mode of working, what is
going to happen is you are
going to be accessing data and
systems from any device, whether
it be managed or unmanaged.
You are going to be accessing
applications that are either
sanctioned or unsanctioned.
And you are going to be
accessing them from
networks, whether either
secured or unsecured.
And you need to make sure that
while you are accessing that,
what do we specifically need to
do so that we can make sure that
the risk of breach is low, the
risk of intellectual property
theft is low?
And this puts a lot of
pressure on the SecOps team.
It puts a lot of pressure
on the NetOps team.
Right?
And so, specifically,
what are we doing to go
out and address this trend?
And what’s starting to happen
is rather than point solutions,
you are starting to see
integrated architectures take
more and more
prominence in this market.
When I talk about innovative
architectures, I'm talking about
networking and security coming
together rather than being
specifically separate
islands by themselves.
And to simplify management,
we need to make sure that the
management is simplified not
just for the SecOps person but
also the NetOps person, and
ideally do it in a way that’s
fluid, and also make sure that
user has the lowest amount of
friction, because what you have
now started seeing is what Rohit
was talking about, you
don't have to tradeoff
security for convenience.
What you’re starting
to see happen is when
the friction does down, your
efficacy automatically goes up.
So, you’re starting to see
this integrated architecture
come into place.
Those are the three major
trends that we’re seeing in our
customer base, which
is businesses are
competing as ecosystems.
Everyone is behaving
like an insider.
And hybrid work is here to stay
and is actually causing far more
challenge in how you can
secure an organization with a
tremendous amount of pressure.
So, what do we start to do
about this entire area and
what is the big challenge that
we are starting to see have
happen that I
talked about earlier?
Well, the big challenge we
see is that we need security
resilience just like you need
business resilience and just
like you need
operational resilience.
There is a need for
security resilience.
Because there is a
massive ripple effect.
And the weakest link in your
supply chain can bring down the
entirety of your
entire ecosystem.
So, what is happening today?
Well, we have this construct
that Wendy Nather, who, by the
way, gave a great – she
was participating in the
rap music earlier on.
She’s right there.
She is the Head of
Cisco's Advisory CISOs.
And she coined this term called
the security poverty line.
What does the security
poverty line mean?
It means that there’s a baseline
level of minimum security
posture that every
company should maintain.
And when companies don't have
the right level of resource or
knowhow to go out and
maintain that, that’s when
they fall below the
security poverty line.
And what that does is
puts the entirety of the
ecosystem at risk, right?
And so, what we want to do
is make sure that when this
happens, you don't ignore the
smaller companies, the not for
profit companies that are
participating, because 60% of
small businesses that do have a
cyber-attack actually go out of
business in six months.
And so, if you are below the
security poverty line and you
are actually participating in
an ecosystem, not only are you
going out and putting
yourself at risk, but the entire
ecosystem is at risk.
Now, we collectively
have to make sure that
this problem gets solved.
And so, to talk a little
bit more about that, what I
wanted to have was my partner in
crime, Shailaja Shankar, who is
the SVP and GM for the security
business, to come over here and
talk about the dimensions of
the security poverty line and
specifically what we need to do
collectively as a group to make
sure that we can go out and
address the issue, because if we
don't address the least prepared
in the world, for going out,
preventing for themselves,
the most prepared will suffer.
So, with that, let me
make sure that I invite
Shailaja Shankar on stage.
Shailaja, come on up.
>> SHAILAJA SHANKAR:
Thank you, Jeetu.
The security
poverty line is real.
It is present.
It's complex.
And it's multidimensional.
When you think about the
security poverty line, there are
multiple factors
for us to consider.
Number one, first
and foremost is budget.
Organizations that are running
on razor thin margins will be
hard pressed to invest
in security the way large
organizations are
able to invest in them.
Then the second
factor is the expertise.
When – even when organizations
are aware that they are at risk,
they may not actually be – they
may not actually be – have the
dedicated skills, they may not
have the expertise, they may not
have the experience to actually
go attack the problem head on.
And the third aspect
to consider is capability.
When you think about a
capability, you are really
thinking about knowing what it
is to – knowing what needs to be
done and being able
to actually doing it.
It's about the knowing-doing gap
that we are trying to bridge.
So, what you will find in this
domain is organizations, while
knowing what needs
to be done, they may be
faced with constraints.
So, constraints in
the form of outsourced software
or outdated hardware or even
regulatory controls that they
have to address.
All of that puts a – puts them
on the back foot in being able
to address them in the time
that they need to address.
And finally, influence.
Large organizations are able
to negotiate the right kind of
terms with their vendors,
suppliers, and partners the way
the small organizations
are not able to address.
So, when you put all this
together, the budgetary
constraints, lack of skillset
and expertise, and the
capability gaps, as well as
the influence that these small
organizations are not able to
overcome, these tend to have
far reaching implications.
So, let me give you
a specific example.
Think about the
ransomware attack that
we saw with Blackbaud.
Blackbaud is one of the
world’s largest organizations.
They deal with education,
administration, fundraising, and
financial management systems.
That one ransomware attack on
Blackbaud has impacted over a
thousand organizations,
and many of them happened
to be nonprofit organizations.
Think about the
ripple effect of that.
When I think about nonprofit
organizations, I actually think
of them as
critical infrastructure.
When nonprofit organizations
are not able to attend to the
victims of violence, they are
not able to be there in times of
disaster, and when they are not
able to feed the hungry even,
then we are all impacted.
So, I'm not suggesting by
any means that the nonprofit
organizations are the
only ones that are below
the security poverty line.
You must consider
the critical infrastructure.
Again, let me give you
a real world example.
Most of the nation's drinking
water and water waste management
systems are municipality owned.
So, think about the margins
under which those businesses are
running, what – their
operating revenues are
really very, very low.
And it is really hard for
them to invest what is needed
to invest in cybersecurity.
And compound that with
what happened with another
real life example.
The Department of
Justice recently indicted a
former employee of a rural
water management authority.
And that former employee was
allegedly – or he was accused –
or allegedly – allegedly
accessing or attempting to
access the computer to
tamper with the disinfectant
levels of the water.
So, think about how the digital
world is connected to the real
world and how a lack of
knowledge, lack of capability,
lack of expertise, lack
of budget impacts not just
businesses but also
impacts societies at large.
So, we must stand together.
Jeetu alluded to it earlier.
Let me quote a
Native American proverb.
"We do not inherit the
Earth from our ancestors;
we borrow it from our children."
We must think of the future.
We have to work together.
This interconnected problem
requires an interconnected
approach to solving it.
Shared risk calls
for shared defenses.
As an industry, we
owe it to each other.
I feel it’s our civic
duty to do this.
For the past thirty years, Cisco
has been at the forefront of
connecting people and data.
And Cisco is committed to
making the world a safer place,
a more secure place.
Here are just a few things
that we are doing to attack this
problem – to
address this problem.
We are helping
in times of crisis.
We have partnered
with thirty-plus critical
infrastructure organizations and
running security products 24/7
supporting critical
customers in Ukraine.
This is us lending our expertise
to – to an area where the
expertise is needed the most.
We are sharing intelligence.
As a founding member of
the Cyber Threat Alliance, we
partner with
more than thirty-three
global security vendors.
We share our intelligence.
The focus here is to make
sure that customers of all these
companies are protected
while we are also defending
the digital ecosystem.
Next, we are helping to bolster
the critical infrastructure.
Here let me give you
another real world example.
We recently partnered with
another county water authority
in the rural part of the
United States with the goal of
automating the monitoring of the
utilities industrial network.
There, while at the same time,
we are also helping them reduce
the water loss in a
water scarce environment.
That is helping the critical
infrastructure with the – with
the help that they needed.
Now, we are taking
it a step further.
We have recently announced
a five year, $15 million
partnership with NetHope.
We are strengthening their
efforts in cybersecurity in the
non-governmental agencies.
We are also doubling down
our security product charitable
grants going to
the nonprofit sector.
For the first time in this
program, we are also including
our cloud products.
We are including
secure access by Duo.
We’re including Secure
Endpoint, and also our Umbrella
Cloud Security products.
The challenges facing the
organizations that are below the
security poverty line
are so large that no single
organization can
actually address.
I welcome you
all to work with us.
I welcome you all to join us in
making sure that we do the right
thing for this
interconnected world.
Join us in contributing
what is needed to help these
organizations get prepared and
help them respond in times of
crisis or in case of a breach.
I say it again because we
do this because we owe it
to each other.
We do it because
it is our civic duty.
Together, we
can do great things.
Together, we can make the world
a better place, we can make the
world a safer place, and we
can most certainly make the
world a secure place.
>> JEETU PATEL: And folks,
we are in a hyper competitive
industry right now.
I think there is a
bunch of vendors
in the space, in this room.
There’s a bunch of
customers that are in this room.
And when we talk about
competing with one another,
competition is good
because it makes us all better.
But the real
competition isn't each other.
The real competition
are the bad actors.
And let's make sure
that we can all join forces.
I think there has to be a
business model shift to make
sure that people below the
security poverty line are also
kept secure so that the
entire ecosystem is safe.
Collectively, we think we
can defeat our adversaries.
We’re going to do
our part at Cisco.
We are looking forward to
partnering with everyone.
And thank you all for taking
the time to come attend this.
And make sure you go take
a look at our booth as well.
And Shailaja Shankar,
ladies and gentlemen.
>> SHAILAJA SHANKAR:
Thank you.