go grab them hopefully let them finish
before you
tell me when you're ready since about
hey Rach you're walking hall and ask
everybody tell thereby were fixin start
if they're going to come in and there's
a Bob talks I actually will explain that
you
sorry were they doing just hanging out
screw it we have video they can watch
the play back printed see blind i guess
the alignment done everything i heered
like two minutes of a fired-up
we are you going to stand up here you're
going to sit down and stable yeah hang
around here fact you want to plug it in
might as well I mean you shouldn't jump
in right behind which one them behind us
right here I'll straddling
you
a clicker thing they're they're
literally I'm just impressed if I were
fancy enough to use slides this is going
to overtake the no no did you have your
yourself there no II don't get a kick
over whenever it pulls it you go ahead
and set it up so the last thing
basically explains the whole thing look
at the neighbor diagram you've got my
whole top you see blind coming back or
what
alrighty then you're gonna fire it up
we'll start recording hi everybody hey
let me record that for my ringtone set
your phone ringing hi skydog so is Emma
having a good time excellent excellent
if I well-fed have you eaten there one
hi huh hahaha bitch beer anyway well
excellent so I'm skydog if you don't
know who i am i'm the one who's legally
responsible for all this fiasco i
believe unless you count the hotel then
it's scott um so I'm going to I'm going
to kick off the Bob talks who knows what
ted talks are who likes the TED Talks
right i love the TED Talks the downside
of the dead dogs none of us will ever
sit in the audience at a TED talk
they're supposed to come to nashville
and i believe it was like 30 grand or
something you had to pay some outrageous
fee to be able to live stream the stuff
off the web to be able to watch it in
real time honestly I can do that while I
work and watch the stuff after it's been
post processed and all the neat things
have been put in it so why am I going to
spend that money I really like the idea
of the TED talks some of them are two
minutes long some of them are 15 to 20
depends on what the subject matter is so
as how most things actually take place I
was bored one day for a good 30 seconds
or so and I thought you know what would
be really cool to do did I just say that
geez what would be really cool would be
to do something like ted talks but then
i thought i really don't want to start
another conference well maybe I do I
don't know so I thought let's do Bob we
had inner zone now there's outer zone
there's Ted now there's Bob so they said
that kick his ass
d actually make a good point but anyway
we called it Bob talks um someone
actually suggested breaker build which
is kind of a take office and the stuff
that schmuck on does there a different
track so i really like the the idea of
the short staccato those things because
some people won't be able to come up
with 45 to 50 minutes worth of material
for their their talk and would like to
do something short sweet to the point it
is not something where start to finish
you explain everything have this big
long drawn out conversation with
everyone in the crowd it's a hey here's
what my idea is this is a general thing
catch me later buy me a drink and I'll
explain the rest will collaborate on it
so it's kind of the general idea behind
it so I have to take a little bit of
crap because the website wasn't updated
as much as it needed to be if at all but
hey listen man you're a tough crowd um I
didn't get to a lot of the things that I
needed to get to this year in the time
they need to get to him so next year
we're going to have a web sorry I think
I've actually found somebody who's going
to take care of a lot of the web stuff
for me so that it takes some of the load
off main because I'm not a web guy I'm
you know I build infrastructure and
things like that I make a really really
directed to the point website with no
flashy graphics so I'd like to thank
everything my image folder has like nine
images in it two of them are me so I
wanted to say thank you to all of the
people who first of all actually
volunteered to do a talk here second of
all the people that volunteer to do a
bob talk there it only listed two of
them on the page I had several people
come up and offer to do them we had
several people who were slated to do it
but I actually one was having to drive
out here at the time so I couldn't have
to a website spending about seven hours
in transit which is a lot of fun so I
like to say thank you to everyone who
you stepped up and said I'd be glad to
do it a bob talk and so everyone round
of applause I'm kind of hoping the
distal end up being something we do
every year we take an hour or two and
they're there nice quick staccato talks
and everyone kind of gets to think
something up not that I want every talk
to be that way irony can stop after 30
minutes but just kidding he's actually
going to do another one we can't get him
to talking one contiguous block so we'll
break it up um so who gets the movie
reference it's good to be the king this
remote part one who is the actor but no
one could tell me what the launch code
was for the missiles in war games come
on guys killing me it's good to be the
king everything's so green so since it's
good to be the king I'm actually going
to do my my talk first because im mean
that way um we have six people are
actually going to get up in or six
groups people they're actually going to
get up and do the Bob talks myself cp's
got one coming up Madeline's from free
side you're going to do one iron geek
and then the group of Sporus naudia and
possibly k see if he's awake I haven't
seen him yet today and then Arafat's
going to get up these good a few minutes
he wants to talk so they're very quick
and staccato there about ten minutes
long at most we've got a couple minutes
in between to reset for laptops and
things of that nature so we'll try to
shuffle through them really quick i will
stop yammering if anyone claps I'll
smack you there's one in every crowd so
I wanted to do a talk and there are very
few things that actually I'm a subject
matter expert on that I can feel
comfortable about standing up and
talking and I've already done all those
toxic on so well I'm working on the next
one but this is it so what is a hacker
and everyone in the room I don't know if
we want to split everybody off and you
know we'll do this hand raising everyone
will go from one side of the other there
have been several people that try to
categorize us the media which most of
them are assholes yeah hiss boo
ourselves if you've ever been to
shmoocon some of the other cons they'll
be either panel talks or there'll be
guys standing around and we're arguing
about it what we call each other your
white hat you're a black hat your gray
hat which I don't think anyone ever uses
those way back in the day it was you're
a hacker you're a cracker nowadays I
think we're just hackers and criminals
so take your pick which one you are I
think terrorists yeah you remember
maverick went to bna nationals airport
and one year at freaknik our t-shirts
said I'm a hacker not a terrorist and it
was right after nine eleven so he was
walking around through the airport to
pick someone up hold his hand over the
logo because he was afraid that they
were going to tackle him in for him to
the ground and actually probably have
been a good idea to do that to maverick
but what can you say um so we have a
hard time actually kind of categorizing
ourselves and I don't think that one or
two or even three tags actually
categorize who we are and what we do I
know there are a lot of words used to
describe me did oh you are me so who
knows who Ashley Schwartz alia is a few
of us she put a DVD out she did a
documentary where she went to to work on
and she went to DEFCON i believe and got
a lot of video and hers was a DVD called
hackers are people too and it was kind
of funny because a lot of the guys that
I run around with the DEFCON shmoo work
you know they're just kind of informal
interviews and and someone said it best
I think it was actually annoyed that
said
you know we're just like everyone else
you know we're not dark shadowy
characters you know in a basement locked
away somewhere working on something you
know we do our laundry we my our yards
we have to do that stuff so we're just
kind of standard people we just look at
things a lot differently than the rest
of the world does so I I'm the president
of the hacker consortium which is our
maker shop in Nashville Tennessee um we
have a lot of different people there I
who did basic okay some of the older
guys um I did basic added Pascal in
college you know I'm not that big of a
programmer I do it when I've got a gun
to my head and I have to do it I'm huh
well actually I never mind um I don't I
don't code unless I have to if it's
something where I have to figure out a
way to get data from here to there and
it requires me to open a book and figure
it out so that's not really my gig now
air that in the back arafat programs and
Ruby like nobody's business I've never
seen someone flipped between screen
sessions as quickly and as efficiently
as he does that's his gig he's one of
our resident programmers wrench is
another one so we all kind of have our
own strengths and weaknesses I'm a
physical materials kind of guy i weld a
lot of the things that you see floating
around the boxes that you see up here
that have the projector on it I custom
built all those myself painted them the
whole nine yards welded up the base for
it yeah no no it's just something to do
i guess to waste a lot of time but um we
kind of have our own specialties i guess
i would be considered a maker and a
hacker to some sort i have other
projects start work on every one of our
little slides here now has vanderbilt
university's logo in the bat grounded
until they programmed that into the
projector so i actually worked for a
university in the south and i'm not
really sure which one it is
can't really tell you so if the
consortium we have a lot of
collaboration someone comes in is this
man i really wanna learn how to weld
well you know i fire up the welder we
figure out how to really screw up a
piece of metal i can come in and say you
know hey i don't understand what the
hell is going on with this can someone
look at this code so it's really nice to
be able to collaborate in that way
because honestly if it wasn't for that
all you could do is google and look at a
book it take a lot longer to get things
done I'm kind of a visual guy point to
it tell me what I'm doing so we kind of
see things a little bit differently um I
have a project that I'm working on where
I am intercepting data at a large
southern university that's coming in on
us na on a single subnet and then I cut
down that data and I'm looking for any
probes anything it's a TCP connection
from Russia Iraq China and Romania and
oddly enough from those four countries i
get about thirty thousand hits where
they're trying to make a connection
there the only trouble is with 30,000
bits of data it's really hard to
visualize what's going on so i've
collected the data and discovered a lot
of patterns my problem now is I got to
find someone who can help me actually
visualize that search for patterns
things of that nature and since I can't
get ahold of Al Stroger to save my life
I can't say hey would you write
something for me that really does
something neat so he's a little bit out
of pocket um we all kind of see things
differently like I say I'm a materials
kind of guy when you say hey I want to
do so and so a blank look will come
across my face and I'm thinking my way
through this is how we're going to make
it work other guys like I keep using
Arafat when he codes you know you say
something to him he looks at you like
dude you're doing it Ruby we time at
Pearl Ruby do it in movie so um the way
that we look at things in the world
we're not I guess for a large part no
one would quite understand what we're
doing here
weekend you know you go back and you got
somebody floating around the office and
they say so what'd you do this weekend
did you tell them you know my boss is
hey you're taking time off for the
weekend where you going I'm going to
Atlanta to hang out with 120 of my
favorite friends and party all weekend
and talk computers and he's really you
guys do that yeah yeah we do just you
know I'm a plumber don't ask you know um
so it's I think it's important that we
not worry so much about what a hacker is
what the the moniker is you know what
I'm gray hat black hat I'm a blue hat
with Hilla print cuz any when Scott and
take your head off you might know who
that guy is so it's important that we
don't specifically search for a name to
classify ourselves it's important that
we kind of keep the spirit of what we do
you know we're not going to be
understood by everybody like a lot of us
kind of like it that way I like being
the weird guy that comes in the room and
wears black all the time so thank you
right jerk hey Mike on thank you so it's
good to be the king um so in summation
so anyone in the room were you a jock
when you were in high school all right
kick the out if Billy Billy you get
in the kitchen should kick that you in
the parking lot of the way out so very
few of us started out as jocks or the
extremely popular crowd well the fun
part about the way that things are going
now is we're very important and as time
goes on honestly we used to be the guys
with the pocket protectors in the
basement everything and now guess what
their companies just absolutely
clambering that's it he who controls the
data controls the world so I think it's
very important that we spend a lot of
time there's a lot of would it be cool
if that are wonderful but it's also
important that we we spend some time
figuring out what we need to do
as a group to actually further what we
do the year of do is you know now people
are looking to us other than just to fix
their home computer it's important that
we figure out what we're going to do to
help society you know if you you're a
member of InfraGard or something good
feel like that um you know if you if
you're able to sit down and help someone
understand what an attack is like and
what's going on and how they should fix
their systems in their business and how
you can make $125 an hour consulting
doing that then you need to do that
definitely but I think we should all
kind of sit down and think what we can
do to collaborate spread information
kind of bring the new guys in in
straight you got to find the new guys
you got to keep them from getting into
too much trouble and you got to find
them that quarter million dollar rate of
your job doing something goofy that
they're really talented at so um we need
to kind of concentrate on that the con
that I run here is like I said not a
money maker but it's more a way for
everyone to come together and have a
good time but my goal is for you guys to
get together okay maybe do a couple of
shots together but to find someone who
does something that you need to have
done or someone that you can teach what
you do and share your skills and
collaborate and kind of go from there if
there's anything I can do to facilitate
it if there's anything about the
conference that i can do that you think
would be a great fit or if you just want
to tell me you know you think the con
sucks you can send that to dev null at
outer zone org uh if you do have
comments and things of that ideas you'd
like to do talks you'd like to do send
it to skydog at Alderson org I promise I
will actually respond to emails from now
on out shut up
yeah I got your shmoop I'm in trouble
for that so on that note i will be going
to crawl into the doghouse CP is going
to come up and do his presentation
ladies and gentlemen thank you for
coming out I hope you enjoy the rest of
the con so my entire can be summed
up in two network diagram slides so I'm
just going to kind of tell you the story
of how it kind of came into existence as
soon as I get this set up just to kind
of add my two cents of escada I was
saying we need people ask you what you
do or you know what your interests are
do you tell them you're a hacker or do
you cop out and tell them you're on the
information security specialist I do
network security so who calls themselves
a hacker and network security okay I was
just curious I for one think that it's
important that we're proud of the word
hacker even though it's misconstrued in
so many different ways I'm a hacker and
I'm proud to be a hacker that's why you
guys know that
yeah I'm not gonna recover thank you all
right so i did my my slides and ms paint
on the plane
oh you can see that can bring the lights
down a little bit maybe all right is
that better just a little bit maybe no
oh well you know project floodgate with
badass slides I originally wanted a way
that I could take my laptop or any
computer any embedded device an iPhone
my Dreamcast anything that can connect
to my network and i want to send all of
this data through tor regardless of
whether it has internal proxy settings
that allow you to do this or even has
proxy settings that you can trust you
don't know if the device or the
operating system is going to send phone
home calls or update request via outside
your proxy settings so initially I just
wanted to send all data from any device
that was network accessible to tour and
become as anonymous as tour gets so like
I said I'm going to kind of work through
the process of how it expanded is in it
as to what it is now so basic idea was
will take a device and just set your own
IP address you're on the subnet one and
two 1689 for dot whatever non DHCP list
you just customize it yourself and when
the router gets that data it's just
going to pass it on to another box on
the network called the floodgate box
well flood gate does right now is it
takes all incoming connections and it
uses IP tables to divvy up the TCP
streams over multiple tour instances so
floodgate can run anywhere between 1 and
100 for instances depending on the
hardware limitations you have we found
that about 50 was a good was a good
limit based on how many nodes that are
in the Tor network which is about 1753
somewhere in that range so I mean it was
interesting you shouldn't send all data
that we have through multiple tour
instances you're not going to see an
increase in overall speed where you're
going to find is you kind of have a
thicker pipe that you could do more
devices on as opposed to all devices on
the network on that subnet being routed
through what single tour instance it
gets a load balanced over multiple tour
instances
so it's a little bit nicer to not have
to waste your bandwidth with other
clients on the network so that basically
is what it comes down to like I said it
can pretty much just be summed up as
this what we then thought about is what
what bit of software uses a bunch of
individual TCP streams that don't have
anything to do with each other Victorian
no I don't hit BitTorrent and no I don't
hate poor I just think it's beautiful to
marry them together so what we entered
were doing with something like this this
works in very interesting ways because
the TCP streams that get routed over
each of the tour nodes randomly right
now by a few tape iptables we're going
to weighted load balancing later just as
kind of it is what it is right now
because of how bittorrent works you know
the TCP streams go out give divvied up
to each of the tour networks and the
tour exit nodes all have different IP
addresses so all the exit nodes join the
same swarm and the swarm now thinks that
instead of seeing one new client it has
50 new clients 50 peers so instead of
allocating bandwidth and resources to
send bits of data to a single client
it's now sending data to 50 clients
which all in the end route back to your
client so theoretically you could get
faster speeds over floodgate then you
could be a single BitTorrent connection
on a regular internet connection in our
test case we were downloading in a boom
to ISO at 2.4 megabytes per second which
was kind of approaching the speed limit
of my internet connection just as is and
through flood gate we used 50 tour nodes
and we found that we're getting about
1.4 for 8 megabytes per second download
completely over tour yes this is kind of
shitty to do to tour and a bit torrent
like I said I don't hate them I just
think it's an interesting idea and I'd
like to see where this could evolve and
maybe change yeah what's cool about that
is I think BitTorrent already can tell
when it gets redundant data and just
discard
before it brings it back in also what
we're doing what's its kind of doing is
it's not broadcasting the same packets
or so I'm just going to rambling right
now I don't think we're gonna have a
problem with duplicate data as is
because the way the load balancing works
is it takes incoming tcp connection
streams to to floodgate to the IP tables
and it just randomly chooses a tour node
to send that TCP stream to so it's not
breaking apart the stream it's still
having it to the handshake and the
little bit of data so in bittorrent
tells the swarm hey I want data it just
doesn't go over the same IP address it
goes through excuse me goes through its
its own kind of tour instance
oh because there's because I think like
I said I'm not a tour expert I'm not a
bit for an expert this is kind of a
half-assed harebrained idea we threw
together like i said i'm pretty sure
bittorrent will just discard duplicator
as well as I don't think it's a big of
an issue and I can't really relate why
but you come find me afterwards and we
can talk about that just because I'm not
good at talking in front of people sorry
guys I have my water that's good water
no tour will only do tcp/ip streams and
what it does actually is it even strips
of waste a lot of the IP headers and
just maintains a lot of the core data
that's in the TCP stream run of thing I
can't hear you speak up
the question was can the will this allow
us to make more than one connection to
the same cedar yes because of the way
bitch horn allocates resources in the
swarm inherently it's going to see each
exit node as its own clients we has done
pier so like I said theoretically we
could surpass the download limitations
that you get from only connecting from a
single client to the swarm using 50 exit
nodes and this is 50 BitTorrent friendly
exit nodes which is a different story
entirely because they do a bt filtering
on ports by default the swarm now sees
multiple clients which it thinks are
individual clients in themselves but in
reality they all route back to us over
the Tor network I'm pretty sure I'm for
getting some so just find me afterwards
websites DC night Fernando org slash
project / floodgate you can download our
source code right now it's just a script
that does all the iptables all the tour
instances and just it's a lot ball for
you you just need to install Torre
install iptables you can't read that
we're on DC dash 949 on f net my email
CPA DC 949 org people who couldn't make
it but we're involved jeff ball mr.
Gordon Dexter virus dr. Nichols and jolt
cola are there any more questions
yeah it just kind of grew into the
bittorrent so it's still really handy
for regular I haven't found him
explicitly but I mean when you really
think about it there has to be something
out there that I mean come on Microsoft
for chrissake there's going to be
something out there any kind of embedded
devices because I have those embedded HD
gaming devices that you plug in I'm
pretty sure you can't do proxy settings
so you wanted to reverse engineer that
but you didn't want to have it hit your
home I pay you just do it over tour over
the sub over the floodgate setup yeah
now nothing specifically came up like I
said kind of like yeah I didn't find
anything but i'm not a bt expert on
monitory expert this is just kind of an
idea i had and it kind of manifested
itself into a really interesting project
like i said the source code is available
at DC nine for nine at org slash
projects / floodgate if your interest
it's it's all in bash right now yeah the
whole thing runs in bash it just
basically sets up I p tables the IP
tables and it starts and stops it tore
instances does all the all the routing
stuff yes I'll put them on the website
future improvements are going to be to
do weighted load balancing just because
right now it's just randomly choosing a
tour connection so we don't really know
which porch catchers are being used to
well as well as we would like to glean
BTW friendly exit nodes out of the tour
system by setting up our own tracker and
just connecting hundreds and hundreds of
hundreds of times over tour and gleaning
out the BT friendly ones and then
specifying those exit nodes in our
startup script
it's all automatic right now like you
just run the script and if you have it
installed you're good you have sea tour
and iptables installed that's all you
need to do oh I did forget one thing if
you run the code yourself right now it's
not set up to do the subnet routing so
on the network all you have to do is set
the gateway to whatever the floodgate
box is that's it and that so there we go
thank you guys I couldn't tell you oh he
ran off
hello I don't actually I wish now I wish
that I had water in there let's see if
this works how did you switch it over
it's beautiful all right hang on guys
I actually made slides which makes me
think that this talk might be longer
than it should be I'm Madeline I'm also
known as Kiki I'm also known as creative
taboo I'm not an infosec tech person I
am a media design person i am the pr
director for free side or PR Czar's
ducky so fondly calls me so I when we
were talking earlier and I've been
talking to people here from various
hackerspaces um one of the things that's
been coming up a lot is how to advertise
the space how whether or not i guess the
resounding debate whether or not media
is good for you so i'm going to talk a
little bit about that um my disclaimer
is that I'm not anything to do with PR I
like it I'm good at it I know people
that are professionals and they help me
out and so I do this stuff for free side
it tends to work pretty well I don't
guarantee it if it doesn't work for you
um so I'm gonna skip over the what's a
hackerspace I think we've done a pretty
good job and the earlier talks about
that I know a majority of you know your
local hackerspaces are parts of them all
of that jazz so in regards to media in
regards to hackerspaces I think the
biggest issue that people come across is
goal setting and it always starts and
you tend to hear these stories of a
bunch of people getting together and
saying hey you technology are you hacker
I'm hacker Oh awesome let's start a
group and it goes from there and you
start dealing with monetary you start
dealing with nonprofit status and it
gets messy and traumatic and people cry
and it hurts and by the end of it you
have a neat little organization sort of
what tends to happen is you start
getting together you lose sight of the
fact that it is a non-profit and that
the goals of a hackerspace and why we do
it and the fact is is yes it's fun and
we all like to get together and just
break things take things apart build
things but it also is about community
bill
it's about education and as scary as it
might be the best and easiest way to do
that is to start dealing with people in
your community and usually through media
so one of the things that I've talked a
lot to some PR directors whether
officially or non official in other
spaces and there comes a time usually
about once a year when there's time to
reevaluate what the goals are why you're
doing what you're doing so these are the
questions that we build is you know we
have to rethink every time what are you
trying to accomplish is it community
education and is it doing startups you
know what message what are you trying to
convey there's a lot of hacker spaces
that are perfectly fine being with each
other and being in their own little
bubble and not really wanting to bring
new people in and teaching each other
and not really wanting to do anything
with the outside world and that's just
fine but that needs to be part of
whatever you're trying to accomplish and
as the goals one of the big things that
gets a little sticky is short-term and
long-term goals what happens is what
turns into we focus on the short-term
goals like hey I came with this really
cool project let's build it and you
forget that a year down the line that
there's other things that need to get
done otherwise you're going to build
this really cool project and you're
going to have absolutely no
infrastructure whatsoever to show it to
people and to build on it and to let
other people other spaces the media
whatever see it say hey that's cool you
what else we could do and so there's
this little gap in time and so the
important thing is whenever as an
individual when you're working on
projects and as a group you need to
think okay I'm starting this now what am
I going to do later with this can I
publish it somewhere can I have another
space work on it would you know this is
info sharing here the other little thing
matching strategy to budget we talked
about this a lot and free said when we
want to do big events and suddenly we
realize that we have no money for it
there are ways to do it for cheap and
free word this is the perfect crowd to
be talking about doing things for
cheap and free just remember that we're
all so you're gonna have a nice nasty
little surprise in your budget leader um
and talking what we talked about earlier
the media is not out to get you
generally I was listening to the talk
earlier and realize that yeah you do
actually have to be kind of wary we've
had a couple people approach us
reporters and it's been very obvious
that what they wanted was you know that
stereotypical hacker in the basement and
you know doing really sketch things stay
away from that it's really hard to pick
up the pieces but point being is
hackerspaces are this big bubble and
it's really cool and people talk about
it all the time and they want to know
and the only way that they're going to
know about it is if you tell them or
they tell someone else most of what
we've gotten has been through contacts
of one people saying hey I just did this
article and they see another article and
they want to write an article that's how
we get our members to when we had a
creative loafing article come out at
freeside the amount of people on our
mailing list doubled in about a week so
a little goes a long way and again one
of those things is why why do you think
people want to cover it is because it is
a non-for-profit usually and it's about
education and community outreach and
people generally care about that just as
they would for anything else um media
sources just generally surprisingly
hackerspaces org does not get as much
attention as it deserves there are
plenty of places for you to advertise
your space if you have advanced if
you're doing the hackathon if you just
want to put your information up there it
is the best and easiest way for people
to contact you hackaday make crafts
surprisingly has gotten into a lot more
technology-based two things they will
either seek you out or you can find you
can submit to them interestingly f I'm
big on blogs anyone that has free said
noticed that like I her ass everyone
the blog mostly because I'm going on
there's the more lately what the reason
that I am so bothersome about the blog
is because the sources like hackaday and
make and craft will hunt down the
biggest spaces that have the most blog
hits and they will pull your articles
and they will pull your information in
your projects and they will post them on
their site so if you blog they will find
you it works that way local papers
magazines podcasts op-eds surprisingly
anything keep track of what's going on
in your town and if there's something
that relates to technology or what
you're doing it does not hurt to just
paying someone to send out a press
release to send makers local did a
wonderful press release for the
hackathon that is I think still on
hackerspaces org it's a great example
little thing keep it out there submit it
share it goes a long way the other big
thing that we do is our schwag um people
are good on this it goes a long way we
have like thousands of these stickers
I've been handing them out and leaving
them places all over in Atlanta and it's
really great when you're driving and you
find one on someone's car you have no
idea who they are and they have no idea
who you are but they think what you are
school things like the water bottle
anything that's free and cheap people
will take the t-shirts people like
t-shirts I wear my t-shirt Luke wear
t-shirts member projects people I know a
group of public station one was looking
about doing heat not pumping station one
one of the spaces that I can't recall
actually does 3d printed logos to give
out to people which the 3d printer was
built by one of their members um dan dan
the man from earlier has suggested home
brewing beer and giving it to the faces
so coffee if you roast coffee the term
we use at a curfew anything like that is
really really beneficial and the
important thing really and I'm probably
gonna just stop here is involving
members and involving other spaces
you're
numbers are viable for information they
know people they know other spaces if
you give them the information you give
them a press kit you give little blurbs
a little go a long way give them access
to your blog let them do their thing and
yes I'm psyched about blog classes and
events the more you do them and the more
you repeat them it's its stability for
the for when people look at it and they
see that something's going on every week
every month it sounds its credibility
and they want to attend that and then
involving other spaces there's been a
lot of this with conventions now and
just people talking and wanting to do
communication via email IRC groups just
visiting other spaces talking to them
seeing what they're working on the
synchronous hackathon has been fantastic
in getting other spaces working together
and there's all sorts of collaboration
on projects and competitions I think
that's particularly fun to do
competitions with other faces on
projects on time whatever it feels like
so and that is what I'm doing if you
guys have any questions if you are
starting a hackerspace if you are in one
you want to talk to me I'm around
is it live now all right hello everybody
this is gonna be a quick talk about a
project I tend to take a little bit more
time to talk about but uh let's go do
this and second part of my first
presentation but I'd end up not doing
that anyway uh basically little
microcontroller project I'm working on
my name's Aidan Quinn sure enough about
me have we gotten food all that in the
previous talk a little bit story
shmoocon 2010 i was giving something
called a phantom keystroke or as a
speaker's gift that's not looking to
sing and what does is it toggles on and
off caps lock moves and mouse around us
cred like that just to be an annoying to
the person who has it plugged in it's
basically a practical joke but I started
thinking about it what would happen if
it were tryin I'm tryin to start with my
best buy co machines man in personation
right now I thought about what had
happen if you could program it it's also
cool things might be able to do this
will gadget so I started looking around
saying hook in this well while I was
there I happened to see Darren kitchen
from hak5 someplace i was like i don't
need unlock the you three thumb drive i
was like you know what you feel some
drugs auto button is turned off by
default when so many machines now it'd
be good at way if you can do like a usb
hid device human interface devices you
just plug in automatically throws the
keystrokes you want and you'll get
around those problems where autorun is
turned off well he told me well me and
Robert are kind of working on a project
similar to that well I start looking
around like okay cool i'm looking
forward with the guy coming out but i
got impatient and start looking around
for a product that would kind of do it
and I found something called Kinsey if
you want something if you want to wait
for the product to come out it's come a
little bit more professional than
stuffing about the show the USB rubber
ducky will eventually be up on hak5 org
and Robin wood of digit inch of fame and
curse situ and all that stuff is doing
the development on the coating on that
but if you want just play around there
the idea and you're not wanting to go
professional if you ready to willing to
go ugly early as they say then I think
this way of going about creating
yourself a little USB HID device might
just work first of all a few notes I'm
new to microcontrollers so bear with me
if I get some things wrong i'm just
getting new into the hole Audrey no and
a be ours and the pic chips and so forth
I also suck at soldering is just going
to become you know all right as i like
to say i like the eye
soldering skills is like an epileptic
alcoholic with the DTS sobbing with an
aluminum baseball bat I also apparently
stuck at using rotary tools I just
generally suck but I had an idea I
wanted to create this thing all right
why would you want to program a
keystroke device you know I first got to
explain the most people is exactly what
this might be useful well likely you can
type a lot faster than you can type I
actually has a question on paulette com
mailing list recently if you were the
flash and you could type it and human
speeds and you had like a few seconds on
someone's machine what would you type in
books even if you have sweet usually
autorun is turned off which it seems to
be the fall to think in vista and Ford
isn't it I mean is off of removable
storage I flip they turned it off in
Windows 7 by default I'll have to check
later on we was if you if you install
something like VMware it has attenzione
that off a lot of people also just
turned off because of the security
features it's also likely to draw less
attention and sing down in front of a
terminal would like you know the person
turns ahead for a second you plug in
this USB device you pull it back out
it's a way issued the commands you one
of the command prompt you can also be
set to go off on a timer if you want so
if you know someone whose importance can
be logged into a machine in eight hours
you plug it in and set to go off eight
hours actually you plug it in so an
admin is not in it logged in now but
they login in eight hours boom Bob's
your uncle you now have an account with
some other process fired off and does
something on the network with their
credentials yippee just use your
imagination all right sort of four
commands that issue at a use I mentioned
before run any old program copy files to
your thumb drive I have I can show you
later on how to actually make it find
your fun side by volume label because
when you plug a thumb drive in you don't
necessarily that's going to get but
those ways of finding it out if you know
the volume label which we do because we
set it all up also you can make it go to
a certain website like you know this
person uses soon bank account or you
know to use Facebook and they probably
cook e stored for it you can have it
automatically a certain time go out and
go to Facebook and make a post or do
something silly all right so what's the
name I had to think of a name for this
particular project because you know name
is important in marketing isn't it so
first thing Mickey pwned because the
first thing I put it in so I'd have the
space and Bobby this is gonna be
contacted
smaller is an Altoids can't 10 but you
know I thought like the ADA might you
know sue me for trademark infringement
owner the next thing I thought about was
a dipstick because I just trying to make
a smaller version of it where I started
on a dip and I basically put this all in
a nicer casing something like this make
most fungi sighs but I start thinking
about that dipstick this one to see what
the thing is so then I thought well how
about something a little bit more
descriptive like programmable hid USB
keyboard mouse dongle but that's a
mouthful so let's just see if we can get
a decent acronym out of that mmm okay
yes I think we got an acronym what is so
that's what I'm going with currently uh
okay we have some names but uh but not
how to build one so I did some googling
around for something that would let me
do this found some limited items with
easiest thing I found to do this on is
something called a tinsy now 10 C is a
1.2 inch by 0.7 inch device AVR
processor running at 16 megahertz scat
like 32 k of on-board storage for your
programs doesn't talk much but you can
do a whole lot of that with that on a
microcontroller program over the mini
USB port that's on it so it's but
simpler program cross between eighteen
to twenty seven dollars like this little
one was just eighteen dollars burnt out
some leads done and I'm anyone's project
but it still works um you better i got
cold solder joints a USB HID supports
the big thing and you can get it all
from a pj RC calm I I have a little
simple wiring diagram here for the one I
created it's in the box I'll explain
what the photoresist of this for in a
second you have analog and digital
inputs on air the digital inputs I just
have set for switches all go into a
common ground so basically goes to
common ground is considered on in the
particular case of this and I have it
all set up using some code to execute
something when I'm ready and I explained
that photo resistor in a stick like i
said here's a really simple bit of code
which is probably too small to see that
uh just tells the LED to come on just as
a diagnostic and then sends keystrokes
in this particular key in this specific
case all it does is bring up notepad and
says Aidan was here all this code and so
forth will be on my website when i get
back home from the con a little bit more
complicated example would be something
along the lines of the modern dipstick
here
hear what I've done and where if you
have an 8 a selection of dip switch
that's impossible of 256 combinations
you could do I'm only using 5
combinations because I bunch out some of
my leads you might wanna buy this thing
for me later on so I can buy a new one
for doing research let me know I had to
turn on pull-up resistors they have
built-in pull-up resistors inside of the
the chip which is nice so I'd turn those
on to make them automatically go high
and basically I check if anything goes
low if something goes low and by the way
I'm doing this in their Adreno
programming environment because see see
you can do it all and see but it's gonna
be a little bit more it's gonna be a
little bit more details that you'll have
to bother with to hear the details are
more hidden from you alright so
basically this one but command bar bring
up notepad Aiden was here this one right
here does a ctrl alt delete and I have
all sorts of different commands are the
one for actually finding a thumb drive
is right here use a form command and
wmic and I can find my particular thumb
drive by its name and Bob's your uncle
I'm in let's see but actually
demonstrate this thing real quick I
thought I had more readers on me
eventually I'm gonna have this all
packaged up in something much nicer but
like i said i'm having some bad luck
with dribbling the things out that i
need the dremel out but let's test our
few toes functions let's bring that up
first time your chest out is just the a
dhryn was here and basically the idea is
I can set the dip switch what I want to
do plug it in real quick pull it back
out remember these things i'm showing
use timers as if yet but right no reason
they can't use timers number four is
control too late hit enter i'm not going
to show that off because of time reasons
obvious number six is just moves the
mouse around and clicks which is just
annoying and walk me to my next door
screen
also you should turn it off before you
try to go continue I number seven opens
up a website and this could be like the
Facebook example in this case I just
have autumn and go to my website but
since I don't actually have an internet
connection right now as you can see this
will be maddening in some cases did you
see a thumb drive me pop I brought up
here Oh bingo and the final one I have
set up on there is you'll find a thumb
drive by its volume name in this case I
had this thing called my thumb so that
whenever i plug this in boom issues that
full command poof WIC and it runs this
and it can run any other thing that you
want obviously you want the time delay
to be less than that I just turned it
very low for the sake of showing it off
here and it can find a script knows what
scripts running from start copying files
bring up calculator that's the classic
notepad regedit so on so forth but I
think you get the general idea another
thing that I've come up with was and
this is the reason i had that photo
resistor set up is uh oh that's why I
had that one the reason I had the
photoresistor setup is so that you can
hook a sense of up to it you have a
analog input in this case let's hope
this work and then the wires came loose
so you can have it set to go off as soon
as someone turns on the lights in the
office or five minutes after they turn
off light to know turn on the lights in
the office whatever you care to do and
see
now I have way too much crap open
luckily I know about shift f5 that's
basically the internals of it no max I'm
looking on a smaller one I got the
altoids tin for some stuff it's booked
in progress otherwise I have embed a hub
and spread of storage so you have it all
in one nice unit because then you could
just have one thumb drive satisfying the
head storage on it and you can
automatically do what you need to do
leave around like a fun drive package
and hoping some unsuspecting user will
pick it up and use it people do that
with usually thumb drive so I no reason
they wouldnt do it this Trojan hardware
give someone a cool glow in the dark
rubber toy or give them some hard drive
or why say it's a wireless device and
have it wake up after a certain amount
of time issue these commands but you
give to them as a present they just
think it's a regular USB toy but it has
this kind of hidden functionality in it
and if you have do some kind of cover-up
thing I mean no one suspects when I
computer squeaks out a little bit they
just think it's one of those things
people don't necessarily pay attention
also if I were doing BIOS boot password
boot forcing but I think Scouts right on
that one that's probably if you have
that much time to access in front of the
Machine better Dolphus whip in the drive
out all right few links for more
information eventually hacked files can
be having something out like this I'm
gonna have some of my web page before
too awful long tin see product pages out
there and the code will all be out there
open source on my website before too
awful long by the way you can also set
up the vendor ID and the product ID i
set mine to be like zero six six six and
13 13 and the name of the product was
like Cthulhu keyboard and mouse events
which i talked about earlier and i would
say any questions but it with me later
because we had to get the next person up
I come up talk to me in a bit if he
wants to physically see the stuff later
I got it all here yeah I want to over
that one
1024 x 768 yeah we should introduce
ourselves is everyone looking at our
floppy sticks hello is everyone looking
at our floppy stinks okay well we should
do some quick introductions I'm sporos
i'm nadia and okay Casey and we're gonna
get to talk about yeah yeah we're
talking about guys come on get
with it get with it okay so as you all
know there was a film set last night
where was a film getting run and we
actually got to go on the set we got to
take a little tour we got to see
everything like floppy sticks like
floppy sticks the grips took us in they
showed us around and we're going to tell
you how they came to trust us and love
us so last night I'm sure there was a
few of you that were in the group that
decided to go out and see if we could
mess with the crew and our little group
of three decided to go separately and it
actually worked for us unlike the rest
of you yeah who kind of got kicked off
which brings us to our point one when we
go and you're about to sneak somewhere
or your way somewhere you have
to know when to ditch your friends so
let's say your friends are coming along
and they're being obnoxious are you are
these people with you we don't know what
maybe maybe probably not obably not yeah
how do we get there how we got to be
with the griffs okay we were walking by
we were trying to go straight to the set
security guards like hell no you can't
go to the set so we started walking away
what we do everyone pretty much
the same generally speaking society as a
whole I'm sure all of you have taken a
sociology class we all kind of have the
same basic principles what you want to
do is you aim for somebody's quirks we
saw a grip dancing what did we do dance
with him we danced with him that grip
thought we were cool as so what's
up yeah oh yeah if they want to bang you
it helps too is there any question as to
how cool I am because if there is we can
take this outside so we're in we
rejected our friends properly and
because of that we got to see some
pretty cool like oh yeah and the
minivan here show them the minivan we're
actually proving to you that we actually
did you that's just in case you did
doubt so there we go this is us oh gosh
this is like two in the morning if you
see there's a guy hanging from if you
see really close I don't know how you
can see how there's a guy hanging from
the minivan melee after this looking at
the grips I want my turn now I want to
ride on the freaking minivan of course
you're alive hahaha all you need to
stick them how many people know what
stickam is okay two of you did you know
what stickam is you did I know but I
wanted to write on the freaking ban so
we go up to the front because people
have seen us talking to the grips for a
while so half of them think that we're
now grips and we saw a guy with a
headset on what are we you we happen to
say we say to each other man i wish i
could give some stickum yeah look over
the guy hey where's some stickum well
there's there's some extra cans of 77
over there okay we got our word
association stick them it's something
that sticks your hands to a minivan it's
in a can and it has something to do with
77 this may or may not have come off the
set if it is video
this is being videotaped it probably
didn't come from the set so anyway in
cleaned you we may or may not have
grabbed one of the Kansas stickam and I
may or may not have said here put this
in your pocket and he may or may not
have been holding this for a while
because he didn't know how to put it in
the pocket before giving it to let's say
KC hypothetically where he then put it
in his pocket during all of this we got
in the way we definitely got in the way
we noticed that they were moving all of
the equipment the director's chairs and
everything out of entrance to the hotel
where they had been sitting and we were
thinking they were just packing up
because the movie was over little did we
know they were moving them so that they
could film in that location so we're
just standing around awkwardly holding
the Sekhem wondering okay what do we do
somebody comes up no no no they're just
guys guys get inside now and so we're
inside and they're like oh we're sorry
they were just getting they were very
polite to us they were very apologetic
it's just we're sorry guys we just have
to get you out of the way for a second
because you know we're shooting right
now they're very sweet to us they had
good food inside as well yeah and five
hour energy drinks all for the taking
they may or may not have been taken so
we go around an actress goes over to KC
is like whoa she's like I'm glad we wrap
today I'm like sure yeah good job guys
okay so we got just get a nice and we
view of the comfy and we could show them
the comfy in comfy and suites which I
would i would love oh I think Humphrey
murder Oh comfy night in yeah this is
when we went in a chilled with the
extras after they they were like oh you
guys come come back out now really yeah
good job everyone that's a wrap so then
we decided to hang out with our friends
the grips the new grips and because we
were now part of the gang we actually
got to go up in the truck with them
so getting in the truck was a lot of fun
one of the security guys ran up as we're
climbing into the truck and he says
y'all can't go up there that's that's
just for people working on the set one
of the grips good no no it's okay
they're cool yeah no but we do know that
i think tomorrow they'll be at the
applebees in sewanee if anybody wants to
run into ya definitely ask them we said
if hypothetically and he was confused a
little bit by the word hypothetically
but if hypothetically we were to spend
the night in the truck where would we
wake up in the morning he said he pulls
out a piece of paper from his pocket he
says the applebees in sewanee okay
awesome so this corolla pulls up then is
like oh I'm sorry guys I'll get out of
your way in a second they're being very
sweet but very nice to us and um this
whole time uh what was the phrase you
are using a lot we're used to it it's
like they kept apologizing to us for
things and stuff like that yeah we're
used to it and so this one guy he was
talking to us and we told him we are
hackers with the hacker con he thought
we were bullshitting him he thought
these genuinely thought that we were
bullshitting about being hackers and
that we were grips just messing with him
it was um one of the one of the
grimssons going around to the different
grips giving them hugs shaking hands
saying yeah it's good work and with you
I'll see y'all around stuff he turns to
me and gets this confused to look on his
face I think you're not who are you and
just walks would
and a lot of these concepts you can
apply towards other things like sneaking
into concerts I know I've snuck into a
couple concerts before I I got um one of
the guys from flogging molly once to
give me a solo performance on his
squeeze box just by going up to him and
saying hey can you play something for me
it's all about not being insecure
blending in and oh you can't look too
nice you have to look just sketch enough
it really helps with the shaggy beard
the weird colored hair and the multiple
piercings you put the three of us
together they're like you know these are
the kind of people we would hire they
were basically like a bunch of carnies
so big about such carnage yeah they even
did really cool we could go with this so
if you have the drunken Haggard look
you're in and as you probably could tell
from that picture of me on the truck I
was probably still a little drunk at
that point rip fun right on that hole
right in the hall the floppy sticks go
right in the hole very carefully and as
you can see we spent a whole lot of time
on this presentation yes so any
questions comments or concerns if the
movie is going to be called Hall Pass
it's starring owen wilson Alyssa Milano
and Christina Applegate and it's being
produced by Warner Brothers no you can
actually go to the IMDb database and
even even though we're not yeah via the
grip our main grip buddy his name was
Keith Carrie Carrie Carrie yeah we can
put faces to half the people in that
list because we shook hands with them
danced with them God yeah like that some
of them helped me off the truck
I don't sign anything yeah maybe in the
part where it says wannabes we will be
in the wannabes section apparently we're
over we're over enjoy your next