and Madeline do you like your full name
Madeline color Kiki does kinky kinky
Kiki it is a hugger though please take a
seat go for it all right well I guess
we'll start and then hopefully other
people will come in all right so we got
some quick announcements first thing is
a here at one o'clock the the DS
tournament is starting right now in the
other conference room that we're using
so if anybody wants to compete in the
d/s tournament then and you provide the
d/s what is the game mario kart mario
kart DS with no hacks patches cracks
whatever it's you got to be real no
nitro carts with everybody else with a
little tiny CC carry all right and the
next thing is t-shirts are going to go
on sale they are starting already right
now this is what the t-shirts look like
so it says outer zone this year i'll say
outer zone six this one says outer zone
five on it and then when you turn around
that board that everybody is signing out
there next year the t-shirt will have
the names on it from this year so the
next year sales have the name from the
previous year so the outer zone six will
be like this one with the names on the
back from last year so if anybody was
here last year you'll get one with your
name and it has the barcode with outer
zone on the back of it they are fifteen
dollars now they make this shirts while
they're here so what ends up happening
is you do pre sales now you go down
there and you buy ticket and then they
will exchange your ticket this afternoon
for
shirt so you have to pretty much buy all
the presale by 3-330 for them to
actually make your shirt and then those
shirts will be ready now you can still
buy shirts all the way up to six o'clock
but they're going to close down the rig
after six o'clock for making shirts so
all the shirts that are going to be made
are all based upon your pre sales so you
guys need to get down there and buy a
ticket for your outer zone shirt to be
made later this afternoon okay everybody
clear on that I don't think they have a
visa machine here I give them in there
yeah yeah what's that yeah you can go do
whatever you want to get yeah Rick takes
anything so if you get Rick anything
he'll give you anything back yeah as
mine it was mine actually so all right
so this is the free side talk this is a
ducky dan and Madeline and so they run
free side which is a hackerspace here in
Atlanta it's been about a year we run
and i will i will let ducky take over
and tell you about free side and what
they're doing and how they're
hackerspace runs thank you Scott first
thing I'd like to thank outer zone and a
sky dog for letting us talk about free
side Atlanta and just putting on this
great con this I've been to a few outer
zones it's this awesome that's great
that's here in Atlanta I'm ducky dan I'm
doing the man hi first of all show hands
how many people live here in Atlanta
awesome yes of course we did who has not
been the free side atlanta yet great
great great well maybe after this talk
we can get you to come down all right
free side Atlanta your friendly Atlanta
neighborhood space so really overcome
some of the basics here first you know
what is a hackerspace this talk dictates
that I go over this just for those who
might not know what hacker space is
Hector spaces are basically community
collaboration
where people can work on projects
together share ideas learn new skills
etc you know the basic idea was to kind
of get out of your basement into a
community area maybe you don't have
enough space to do stuff at home the
wife wants to get all you to get rid of
all the junk you know where do you go so
people started doing these hackerspaces
started probably i think in Europe you
know it became real big then it's now
starting to boom here in the US it's
very cool yeah anything that took um
it's basically where you can do whatever
the you want to that's legal sort
of exactly all right so about freeside
Atlanta talk about our space freestyle
Atlanta we have over 5,500 square feet
of raw power hacking space we are
located in West End and the metropolitan
warehouse is what's so funny you forgot
the into the photo I know I left hander
no no you forgot yeah there isn't a
photo of our front door I expect
everyone to come out and see that
yourselves no I knew I did that it was
late we're located in ways off the
metropolitan avenue it's a you know it's
a little risky getting there but once
you get there the West End yeah once you
get there were located behind some good
secure iron gates they got a security
guard we've been incident-free the let
me talk a little bit about the the
Metropolitan warehouse is I don't know
if anyone's ever been there we have real
one of the decisions to put the space
there is the neighbors we have some cool
neighbors the whole places community of
artists metalworkers auto mechanics our
direct neighbor is a machinist he comes
visits in matter of fact he C&C to our
front door sign we do a lot of trade we
do computer work for people and they
peddle their wares to us so the big
thing about it is at a lot of the
meetings we have a lot of our neighbors
come in the canola the conglomeration is
very cool there's actually a party in
that complex tonight at the big tower if
anyone yeah if you're looking for
something to do if you're not the cool
thing about our space is we continue to
find interesting objects and inside the
walls whenever we tear down the wall
we've found everything from large dildos
to heroin needles and that's kind of a
treat so it's kind of like an Easter egg
hunt but our space continues to grow and
thrive and we're still even after being
open from as a year now we're continuing
to build it out anything that Chiefs all
right don't you guys love my powerpoint
skills my they I'm not the most artistic
person in the world so this kind of raw
so how we came to be basically here in
Atlanta three of the founding members
eater raeford and James shin han moved
up here from Columbus Georgia and they
said they ran a different kind of
collaboration space down there it was
kind of some sort of free internet
conglomerate a conglomerate in some sort
of library basement it up yes I can't
say that were
I think it went pretty bad and then when
they came to atlanta they said let's
start a hackerspace so what they found
out when they put their feelers out is
there were a lot of other groups talking
about starting hackerspace DC four of
four was talking about starting a
hackerspace the atlantic's linux
enthusiasts groups we're talking about
finding a space a bunch of groups and
what happened is they put the feeler out
there and then next thing you know we
were having immediately these meetings
at manuel's taverns of over a hundred
people to start up this hacker space
this is one of the probably I think one
of our greatest accomplishments is a
hacker space is we start it up with over
100 people interested and had an actual
waiting list to become a member we
capped the members at we capped the
membership around 50 to start off with
and had quite a long waiting list so a
lot of our members come from a lot of
different groups and that went pretty
well together the first thing that was
on our agenda of course was to find a
space I don't know how many of you guys
are involved in your local hackerspace
who if you're outside of Atlanta but
finding the space had to be the one of
the most difficult feats yeah we started
meeting in March and we didn't find a
suitable space until June yeah 2008 yeah
2,800 it wasn't on no I'm sorry we
started meeting at manuel's tavern
around October of 2008 and then we found
the note and then we found finally found
our space of March last year 2009 and
moved in and gin okay trust me i was
there i was i was there too and I
thought it was made dan dan wasn't you
were there but you weren't there
okay there was a lot of drinking and
shenanigans during this whole time yeah
but yeah that was probably one of our
most difficult feat because now we had
50 potential members of 50 people
looking for 50 different spaces and at
50 different locations on 50 different
sides of town so that was probably our
first big challenge as a hackerspace
because you know you had 20 people up
should be over here 20 people like
that's not even in Atlanta should be
over here oh no that's a crime zone etc
so we finally we finally decided on the
metropolitan area because of the raw
square footage and for the price and it
was cheap it was cheap so it was very
affordable oh we rent it I'll field
questions at the end of our talk mr.
no thank you all right all right Dan
I'll let you talk to that song I'll talk
too much okay so um one of our main
things is were community we meet every
tuesday night to go over any kind of
daily bit like weekly business monthly
business that we need to do talk about
and it's every tuesday night at seven
thirty it's usually short you know half
hour 45 minutes when he's on time and we
kind of get together drink beer and talk
about you know you know what are we
going to be building out you know what
projects are people working on and then
after that we kind of dissolve into a
spatial social event to where you know
you can meet meet all of our members you
know work on projects show off your
projects that you're working on we do a
monthly hackathon we actually have one
going on right now and that's a
synchronous hackathon and Kiki can talk
more about those yeah we are part of the
group that does the synchronous
hackathon hackerspaces org we are in
process every once in a while we get
cameras up on Ustream and you can watch
from wherever corner of the globe you
might be we also one of our newer events
would be f three which is first friday
flash talks they're a bunch of
five-minute presentations from members
non-members just generally interesting
people that want to talk on a variety of
topics and we asked questions and drink
beer and it's so fun and then I one of
the parts of big parts of a hacker space
in our hacker spaces teaching classes
and workshops we encourage non-members
to do it if they're interested in
becoming members we all have had you
have deigned of circuit bending I do
sewing we have welding yes yes welding
robotics soldering and
next weekend we're going to be doing a
carbon fiber and fiberglass fabrication
during my second class room good boy
okay check our blog right yeah it'll be
a video posted so sometimes the meetings
don't really you know the kind of boring
so we just kind of break out into
socials sometimes but that's always
going to be tuesday at seven 3pm i want
to re-emphasize the f3 flash talk that's
probably one of our key keith little
brainchild there that that's some real
fun there it's just you get up you do a
five-minute talk you don't even have to
be a member you do a flash five-minute
flash talk on a subject of your choice
one of the things that we're talking
about doing also is if you don't have a
presentation will give you one and it
can be about anything and you'll have to
your way through the
presentation and we're going to kind of
do that as a karaoke flash pot it's a
great way to teach geek social skills
and rice public speaking skills right
but yeah we've talked about just getting
a whole bunch of presentations throwing
them together and make fill them with
or maybe real facts you don't
know what you'll get I think we're
calling that PowerPoint karaoke yeah how
our play is that what he decided yeah
all right sorry Howie okie okay oh geez
redundancy every Tuesday night 730 p.m.
everyone's welcome please come check it
out and bring beer bringing beer this
Tuesday however i'll be out of town so
it'll be a social so bring more beer
submarine beer yeah we we do uh allow
beer in the space of right yeah we have
a kegerator it needs a keg so if you
want to bring us a present feel free to
bring us a full keg right r open to the
public we're very much about people come
to the space and visiting so don't ever
feel shy and we're going to talk about
membership
later and we happen network wireless
please don't sit outside and try to hack
it or just connect to here be dragons
man oh here here's the UH classes again
I was a little tired glad i made this
presentation alright i took Danny
presentation I wrote it all and then you
weren't even supposed to modify it well
that's what you get Kiki it as a sewing
class that's awesome if you want to
learn how to sell uh I can L circuit
bending which I don't know if you're
familiar with that it's it's breaking
toys and making them make weird sounds
right so you like short circuit like
speak and spell and make it sound like
the devil yeah so one thing is um we're
also open to non-members actually coming
to teach classes so contact us if you're
interested in it we'll do a class on
anything basically I think someone was
going to do a rave dancing class there
is a rave date there is a rave dancing
class it doesn't make the slide I didn't
know about it and when our oven starts
working we'll have an end soon we're
going to have a puppetry class on how to
make puppets we're partnering with an
art collective in Atlanta and kind of
posting allowing them to use our space
and in turn they're going to be starting
to teach classes for us and one of them
is going to be how to make puppets so
bring your kids should be fun alright so
other things that we're doing at the
hackerspace our projects so all this
before we go on to the pictures of the
hackerspace we'll talk about some of the
projects we have a very our members
consist of a very very unique group of
all walks of life we have biologists
people who
hack the mind we have network security
people we have welding people we have
architect architects who else people
that so students students at all things
alcohol works yes alcoholics and then we
have managers that don't know anything
that's me so some of the stuff that we
have going on projects right now soil
electric conductivity LEDs play that's
why one of our biologists she's
basically making a project that will
measure the conductivity of soil now
there's a lot of biology in this that I
don't understand so I apologize if I
butcher your product your project up
here basically it has something to do
with the stuff in the soil I think she's
gone for like moisture content yeah
moisture content well depending on the
plants giving off nitrogen wrap that
changes the conductivity of the soil so
yeah it's a bummer MX yeah right but now
she's gonna measure it with LEDs and
tried to do some artwork to get Oh make
actual displays using plants we have an
LED grow box uh yeah it's it's a it's a
box where where one of our members is
growing plants via LEDs what kind of
plans I think there's some some grass
and cacti what do you have in there Tao
yeah our members actually sitting out
here we have grass herbs cacti you know
things eat girl in a grow box
yeah UAV drone one of the members is
actually just trying to still research
and is now just purchasing parts for his
UAV drone which will fly all over
Atlanta and spy on people can we put
missiles on it ducky yeah we can this is
being recorded we have a foundry of
project a lot of the metal workers there
they've been making their own homemade
foundry out of buckets and cement we've
done a little bit of aluminum pouring
one of the big things that pre said we
recycle a lot so we take lots of stuff
old hard drives broken hard drives
instead of giving them the scat we take
them apart and take the aluminum casing
and melt those down and make aluminum
cupcake now that biscuits so that's a
really a cool project and I'll let Dan
talk about one of the next project
that's happening at the space um the
artificial presence is something I'm
working on with with with tau we're
looking at giving the space a
personality and also something you can
interact with that can also automate
several activities like turning on
lights and and turning off lights if no
one's there because we kind of leave
lights on every now and then and also
like monitoring the temperature in the
space and making sure we're not we're
being efficient with our power usage and
whatnot it's still kind of a work in
progress we're trying to figure out what
we want to do with it and the next one
the audio synthesizer modules that's my
personal project I I'm an analog gear
head so I built analog synthesizer parts
and make noise with I'm right now I'm
playing with digital logic and making
oscillators with with NAND gates and
inverter chips it's kind of fun right
right
Thank You Becky yes um boy the motorized
couch project yes one of our members is
going to make a couch drivable that we
will drive in parades yeah he was he was
just given a 50cc scooter engine to
power it he was originally gonna make it
electric electric but now it's gonna
have a gas engine so it should scoot
down the road yeah guess it will make
facilitate are getting from the couch to
the refrigerator without actually
getting off the couch right then we have
one guy working on persistence of vision
yeah what should we actually have a cool
picture of it he likes to play with
lights on wheels good kyo sohma at Kiki
Madeline oh no we were talking about
LEDs and I am as part of the sewing
series of classes that will soon to be
into fruition is a soft circuitry so
making plush things making clothes
making just anything that wouldn't
normally expect to be lit up to light up
with LEDs and possibly attach sensors
motion sensors heat sensors that sort of
thank you sir yes
yes okay there are a lot of other
projects going on that I didn't list
this is the only thing I can memorize at
the time all one asked me about it 1030
at nine yeah there's of course a lot of
project spaces like every good
hackerspace the hackerspace has never
done so you know we have people who
constantly running wires and finding new
and interesting ways to open the doors
from the inside so next I'm going to
walk you through some of the pictures
and try to explain them thoroughly their
pictures they can't be explained yeah
there might be a few of the ducky insert
a picture here this is uh there's me how
did I get in there yeah this is early on
our founding president eater here's the
left talking to me about hey you don't
want to become president this place man
it's tough and I didn't listen to them
this is when you first walk around the
first corner of the space this is the
front half the space basically the space
has two sections we have the main part
of the space that contains chill out
chill out lounge and all the work
benches do it yourself it's AC and
heated then we have a whole classroom
section that's still being built out
just to host any kind of large classes
that we want usually the classes that we
have just happened in the main area but
we're trying to come up with a more
formal class system for anybody that
needs some class space here in Atlanta
that doesn't want to pay you know 90
grand to rent a hotel for the weekend so
the first that's the first half of the
space it's hard to capture then when the
back half of the space it's a little
fuzzy picture I took this out of a
creative loafing article that's from the
top of the balcony in the back but
basically this is where the actual
workshop or all the woodwork metal
work at anything that's going to create
dust and havoc that's a cnc machine on
the last table and these in the corner
or two 3d printers that aren't working
and and we got a welding station over
there Welding state welding station work
benches a junk that people won't stop
dropping off and 3d printers and people
a big drill press yeah big drill press
junk more junk and behind this wall we
have the guitar bass so you could put
your car in and change your brakes or
change your oil or dismantle it and swap
out an engine to rolling up garage doors
so more more space in the main of space
we basically that's where we store
everything this is a gravel shelf so you
can go up there to assemble whatever you
need tons of electronic components
storage for project dan so if you need
like an op amp it's probably going to be
on one of the end one of these drawers
if you need you know a parallel cable
god forbid it sits there anything and
everything that you could think that you
might need we probably have it and if
not someone will bring it in in a week
or so yep now this next picture is a
let's put it in here because it's cool
it's our intercom system that a shadow
here that shadow made is the old world
war two army phone with a hand crank
that you have to basically crank and it
rings the other side which is located in
the back of the warehouse and then you
can communicate with whoever's back
there if they choose to answer and
that's how the phone works
here we have one of some of our members
doing some metal work I think they're
building the foundry here this is in the
early found reconstruction that was
actually before we had our tables yeah
another big part of free side is you
know we're open anything including
artwork we have a lot of artists that
come by and do murals on our wall and I
don't think we actually have any members
that are really good at painting or
drawing other than other than that
laughter we haven't paid anything it but
yeah we kind of just have people come in
and do artwork a lot of people complain
that this is a ninja and there's no
pirates well there's this whole pirate
vs ninja so didn't your better half do
this one yes my woman did this one I
guess I'm a ninja guy yeah and didn't
your woman do this one or some like that
he knows her yep so that you'll find
murals and interesting artwork all over
the space it's fun here's the POV the
POV project he basically take any image
and then put it on his little bicycle
wheel welding class you don't have if
you remember you can weld anytime you
want but welding classes are usually
once area once every three weeks we're
probably schedule to have one soon but
we have all the safety equipment as you
can see there's a empty fire
extinguisher right there
and you know it's a security through
obscurity we're safe yes yes make sure
ensign a liability way yeah so when you
come make sure you're pretty much loaded
and then we'll hang you a welder we have
mig welders arc welders yeah everything
yeah we have waivers to so be sure to
pick up a waiver but I'm going to keep a
high member to finger ratio so watch
yourself yeah today I believe were zero
accidents is that correct we've had a
couple nicks all right nobody is lost to
Lumia or a retina or anything like that
no one no one's lost an eye or finger
yet yeah it it's very important when
you're starting hacking space to get
legal counsel and waivers um this is up
yeah this is uh from the mystery box
today we we love we have a member that
collects money from other members and
orders these big huge electronic mystery
boxes and then we from electronic gold
mine from electronic gold mine and then
we just have a freakin geeked out field
day opening it up and finding out what's
in it and sorting it so we probably have
like a few thousand capacitors laying
around and other stuff so in their mind
don't thank the dressers too yeah this
next picture there's a member sitting in
the audience working on as a LED gray
box on the table and he's probably
trying to explain somebody this is not
what you think it is inside here we took
we tend to cook hot dogs using the power
outlets and sing all the cool stuff we
can do with it and of course here's a
hot dog being cooked with
a 120 volts and mystic LEDs and I'm to
see what kind of cool lights we can get
out of a hot dogs yes yes it's cooked
all the way through they have a funny
taste to them I don't know if you've
ever tried but uh it's real fun mmm YUM
man I don't do this you got to talk to
the guy to cook hot um we actually ran
the methods it's more efficient to use
to use this method than in the microwave
but it you don't want to eat them we
just don't know about the health factor
yeah we can't get over that hump yeah we
have some members who again are in the
audience shadow that like to bring
explosives to the space which is
perfectly okay and they make rocket
engines using sugar and potassium
nitrate and other stuff I don't know how
to do it yeah so we have a lot of fun
and don't piss us off some excuse me
speaker net one turn off cell phone
press we were on the front cover of
creative lifting if anybody saw that did
anybody see that yeah nr8 guess who's
lovely hands are on that cover in your
and mine we're official hand models and
basically we're just sorting through
about to jump there's nothing actually
functional in that class there's there's
an AVR programmer right there so we have
a couple of those laying around if you
like to play with a vrs and other random
toys right fun alright so what is it to
become a member at freeside what do you
get from free of club membership we have
a key card access system that i will not
fully disclose here that it gives you a
24 hour access you gettin all elections
we are we are a nonprofit organization
so we have a board president the
treasurer all that and we diplomatic
leave it for all those people you get
access to shelves the punch shelves the
parts which i think i showed you guys
we're always looking for members there's
i believe some slots open now we have
two types of memberships we have the
regular member and if you've been
jobless for a long time or your college
students we do have a starving hacker
rate becoming a member and all this is
listener vici basically you just need to
come hang out for a while we have to
gotta get to know you and what you do is
you find a sponsor and the sponsor
basically takes responsibility for you
and so if you're a complete screw-up
that sponsor will be hazed and beaten
accordingly for sponsoring somebody who
shouldn't be sponsored once you get a
sponsor two people have to be fans and
then you're kind of just voted in some
of the things that you have to do go
ahead Dan youyou will be hazed yes by
having to do drywall or
running ethernet drops or we need a coax
drop to our television right now so if
anyone wants to come over and do that
we'd be your you might get a fan or two
yeah if you have a truck truck yeah
we're always looking for people with
trucks so that's like half the battle
truck or a trailer or both right right
yeah crane so we're you know we're
pretty a tight community we have about
50 members right now it's a lot of fun
and it's everything you would expect a
hackerspace to be and more I think you
know in square footage we might be one
of the largest hacker spaces in the US
with 55 although i think the geek or
second the geek report not sure how big
their spaces but it's pretty huge but I
say we might knock the wall down and
start invading our neighbors space if it
if that's what it takes down to the
largest so I think that's it does
anybody have questions I'm going to feel
the floor for questions please ask
questions you sir
as a meeting no no no um if you are an
alcoholic we can help you with that we
do have beer at the space okay yeah of
course you know you have to be of
drinking age to drink the beer of course
and you cannot donate or give us money
for that beer but you can give me money
for that beer yes you can't get free
side money for that beer yes how are you
yeah we do have a website it's at the
very beginning if you missed that thank
you shut it yes our website is WWE
Atlanta org and we have a blog on there
which our members will blog about the
projects or whatever's going on we're
probably we've blogged about outer zone
and we have a wiki at WWE key free site
Atlanta org which there's a link off of
the main site to get to the wiki and to
the blog let's go check it out sure I
knew someone's gonna ask that monthly
dues are about 3,000 per member the
starving hacker rate is 2900 now uh
right now membership dues are eighty
dollars a month starving hacker rates 40
it's certainly slightly more expensive
than a gym but a lot more beneficial but
right now we're working on ways we are
working on ways for people to get
bonuses off of their tooth like the
person with the highest blogging rate
for the month might get half off etc yes
we're working on it and and another plus
side is there are several couches so if
you get kicked out of your house you can
you can crash there temporarily
temporarily not allowed to live there we
do have we do have a shower or we did
it's about room the new shower is about
to go in we have two bathrooms we have a
full functioning kitchen no we don't
somebody come fix our kitchen we have
what looks to appear to be a full
function Egyptian functioning oven
please get in contact with us and how
well we have a hot water tank we just
need someone to hook up the hot water
tank yeah Bristol we haven't even been
around it for a year and we're still
we're still building out but the one
thing remarkable about free side is
we're very everything is paid for we're
very self sustaining we have we have a
good cash cushion and our bank account
we can really operate we can operate
with very few members for a very long
time so free side will be always be here
around the stay I'm sorry right that's a
project that somebody's did a class that
someone's going to be doing for things
that deal with the mind the gentleman is
actually sitting right behind you and
he's sending you my kinetic stuff right
now these using is Jedi a Jedi is
happening your mind right now telepon
care could tell you but you know we have
a lot of people that are into breathing
methods yoga you're hacking the mind and
body you know some people yeah that's
that's where their skills lie like I
said it's a very diverse group I walked
in space and their do some funky yoga
stuff the other day they look like
acrobatics and I was like what is going
on huh did I miss hacker yes when was it
yeah it was really interesting you
certain the blue in the back
it's yet yeah yeah it's ad hoc pit on
the main on the main website at WWF is
Elena or if there is a calendar where
you can just pop it there and look we'll
post the classes usually we try to keep
them pretty consistent like you know a
third week every month on Sundays four
o'clock will be welding class etc and we
haven't had a welding class in two
months but we're due for one this month
actually we're good we'll try to the
robotics i think is once a month they do
like a six-hour like workshop type thing
and one of our member null set runs that
with the Atlantic's or Atlanta robotics
club and I'll have to talk with the
puppetry stuff the puppetry steps
probably not going to start up until
April or May the art collective that
we're dealing with our working with has
a show coming up on april 9th in
casselberry so it's going to be after
that show who is that who is a our
collective were working on that their
dodeca put dan dodeca buzz yes they're
kind of like the same thing they're
trying to do the same thing bits for
artists yes artists only but will accept
artists and we'll have hacking of any
tight and you hack a paintbrush you're
welcome at our space yes we take well
what type of donations are you referring
to yes we're kind of very picky now
cousin I'm nothing older than a p4 for a
computer um SSI and if it's any kind of
other interesting network gear or
something you know something cool yeah
we'll take it yeah we have a lot of
Pentium to
ready and CRT monitors strange yeah
we're not a dump we had to put a sign up
and said no dumping so we try to
regulate that because that will get it
doesn't matter how many square feet you
have what are 10,000 3,500 once people
will fill that up um we yes we take
recycling to the Grady recycling days at
grady high high school and Atlanta they
do I think it's every third Saturday we
have one shelf dedicated to the back
that is this is going to be gone on the
third Saturday so take what you want or
it's going bye-bye so yeah right there
that's a we have a very big we have
ordered on the shelf of when it went on
the shelf and everything gets cycled
from front the back so everything on
that back shelf goes to recycling if
nobody's used it and in most of time
it's you know old 486 some other boards
or things of that nature so it's old
gear that we don't need if it's aluminum
then it gets melted yeah into biscuits
immediately and if it's the processor
we're gonna keep that and if it's them
has a motor in it Spahr will rape it
take the motor out matter of fact we
have you have to put notes on some stuff
spark please don't take this apart
please don't take the motor out of my
motorcycle please a Kiki hatta we were
afraid and Don will tell you we were
afraid that a yours when you brought
your sewing machines we had to tell spar
not to take the motors out of the sewing
machines that they were actually for
classes sorry any other questions all
right we got a couple I'll give it a
trivia then yeah we've got a couple
t-shirts to give away and if someone can
bring me another beer they might get one
uh can somebody tell me who's not a
member of free side please you're not
where are we located yeah but what
haunts me the I can't hear yell it out I
accept the hood hey we have it's
actually great great the stipend glare
it's the strip club that we pass on the
way from the marta station yeah like
they are always armed yeah there is a
huge smokestack the tiger talking about
we're going to talk about getting up
that's the strip clubs Magic City I
don't think you want to go there yeah
yeah you're not gonna hurt ya but know
about the cardia we're talking about
trying to scale it and do some sort of
wireless up there when the the herp hurt
yeah cool hey we have more t-shirts for
sale ten bucks that are in the main
registration route 5 goes to five
dollars goes to to benefit free side
than the other five of benefits outer
zone so please help us and outer zone
for putting on this great conference and
that's it my name is stickers cheers
and some of the members of free side are
also members at DC 404 so DC 44 is the
local Atlanta Def Con groups if you guys
know about those guys they we meet every
third Saturday of the month at it's the
vortex off of peachtree midtown and it's
is great usually something between
anywhere between 12 and maybe 30 people
will show up at anyone talk or anything
that's going on but if you watch the DC
404 org website you'll see that Taylor
who is the leader of that group would
have been here today except today he
went to the hospital so he's got some
pinched nerve in his neck or something I
don't know how bad it is so they're
gonna stop by apparently he's probably
gotten some Demerol and he'll be really
good who needs to share that no they do
in the mix well so he's got heroin and
he'll be he'll be over later so anyway
so at least they wanted to welcome
everybody BTW 44 and maybe some of you
guys who made it here might want to try
to get to the to the meetings once a
month or so yes i bought
when Glen Taylor gets here with his
heroin you can ask him and you can just
go pound freeside Atlanta like that's
better on freenode go to pound freeside
Atlanta yeah yeah yeahs o freeside atl
sorry yeah yeah sorry don't know yeah
yeah no and I think Linux was there once
a while or something T right that's
about it so so anyway also on t-shirts
and stuff the outer zone t-shirts are
made while you're here so you have to
pre purchase them and they will be
available all purchases up to six pm so
if you guys go into the other room and
buy a shirt that's basically how we pay
for the con we pay for this room we pay
for the equipment and the giveaways and
stuff so so please go buy a t-shirt or
something or donate money there's a
donation thing in there also so skydog
puts this all out of his own pocket
pretty much and so if you don't buy a
t-shirt we basically don't have any
money for next year so anyway up till
six o'clock and they will make your
shirt while you're here so you'll get it
kind of hot off the press and stuff and
you'll be able to come back and exchange
the ticket and get shirt so so I I know
they're going to start making shirts
here in the next couple hours so up to
six o'clock go ahead and pre purchase
and get all those in and also again like
free sod is donating half of their
shirts so if you want a free side shirt
there's plenty of Atlanta clubs and
locations here
quick one
okay for the manga guide to physics or
in atlanta georgia not far away from
huntsville alabama what were the first
words transmitted from the lunar surface
of the Moon a stepped in dookie do what
the first words were well words plural
houston eagles landed geez how we break
that one
here's one I don't know if you guys are
our hard drives for medically sealed it
was the first person i have a large you
shake that shake that off