sequentially down the disc as it's going
it is laying the data back out exactly
in the same order that it came from but
it's laying it out in the destination
disk so the destination disk is actually
almost instantaneously sector by sector
as this is being read is being written
directly to the destination disk so even
if I pull the plug on this right now it
would pick up where it left off so I can
do that but then I'll read the
configuration in this entire map I mean
literally I can like stop this I can you
know quit a program unplug the equipment
walk away and start it back up and it'll
be right where it was where it left off
and you'll actually be able to continue
from where you actually left off and it
will continue back from that exact
location that's correct it writes the
profile a depth it actually has a flag
has this map and it's an lb a map and
there's actually a flag for every single
sector and it tells what the status of
that flag was and that configuration is
loaded into device every time it starts
and it does it by identifying the serial
number and stuff basically of the
original device so when that device is
bound to this device as long as those
two devices are the only ones that are
online it reads the original
configuration file if I put a new source
drive on then and I told it to do that
it would say they don't match and it
would just automatically overwrite the
drive again which is normal in a data
recovery process the that it can do any
drive but this process that i'm showing
you only supports MFDs right now so it
only supports ntfs normally I would tell
the imager to do the entire drive and it
will do it like I said kind of in any
order but including damage or whatever
so right now we're at the end of that
particular chunk of data now at the end
it'll turn around and go backwards it'll
do three passes with different changes
in between each paths I can do four
passes and make it do anything I want
and I can tell it turn off power if I
have a failure I can actually program
steps in between so I actually have the
ability to choose like a what if
scenario so
actually say how fast what time how many
milliseconds but if I actually got a
sector that actually had a particular
type of error which I've covered in
other talks that have actually done what
types of errors I could actually tell it
then to power off the drive I could
actually tell it then to power it off
and turn the drive off and turn it back
on again so I don't have to be there to
finish the job then it will continue on
from there so so and you'll see like I
said at the end of this it'll turn
around and go backwards it's going to do
a pass backwards which will change how
the cash actually works on the device in
case there was a problem with memory or
something on the device going backwards
actually kind of in effect disables it
even though we can disable the cash
directly but it does do a bike
comparison during what's called an ECC
pass if the drive actually returns an
error most equipment will actually just
fail it will just say abort and it will
not return a sector but you can actually
request the sector back with certain
pieces of hardware so you can get the
you can get the sector back let's say
512 bytes maybe one bite was damaged you
can actually request that back and it'll
do a bit wise comparison and you can
tell it how many times you want to read
I can say read it 15 times compare them
and figure out what the most probable
answer is so quite a complex scenario
all right so anyway so it's done it's
actually going backwards i have no
errors at this point for the files that
I care about so I'm going to just stop
it I'm going to turn the thing off then
I'm going to take the original
destination disk again the destination
just got wrote all the data to and I'm
going to bring it back online
and so now it comes up and you'll still
see I have a deactivated MBR it's
exactly the same state as what it was
except that now I'll actually have my
file content so I'll actually cute my
image explorer unfortunately the project
doesn't do a whole lot at the moment
select my drive
so I'm just getting the list again and
you'll see all the green sectors like
wherever I click around on on a drive so
we did this let's say we did this porn
LOL directory so there's a folder called
vixens and so i can actually um you can
actually look at the map and you can see
the file that I'm highlighting where all
these blue dots are in the bottom of the
green so the greens are successful it
copied this file and the blue dot means
they belong to this file so you can
actually have others like I can scroll
around anything that's green I would
actually have a copy of so like if I'm
scrolling down through through the drive
like all this space there's nothing
there I didn't copy any of those sectors
so so anyway so I can actually go back
now let's just say i want this folder
this is the one that actually has the
data now on the drive so if i save these
files that will now save them in this
folder and i can go even while it's
writing them to my destination it's
storing them on this local machine I now
actually have this configuration and
while it's doing that I'm going to go
look at them so so so these actually
came off of that destination disk so I
can go look at them and thumbnails now
the program still actually exporting um
it could be anything that's wrong with
drawers from a standpoint of media
damage head damage or certain locations
of a drive that actually have physical
damage to them um this one is not that
bad it's not very bad but if I had a
very badly damaged drive I mean keep in
mind i'm trying to do it at demo here
dude I wanted it to work while I'm here
if I have a very badly damaged drive or
something like I have one on Friday that
actually rebuilt the board and rebuilt
the head assembly and had to actually
resolder a chip on it and it still ended
up with 1,600 errors at the end of it
but I was sixteen hundred is nothing i
mean that's you know eight megs or
something so so not much to deal with so
I've exported just those folders and
again I did some other so we could
actually go back remember actually
selected earlier say this guy in
did my documents and I did the hot
chicks folder this one is kind of a demo
drive at the moment I didn't want to
show too much bad stuff so but I've done
many of these the same way in the last
30 days so but I can export the data and
then go look at it
well the second most seen hard drives
besides and like ntfs literally as like
ninety percent of what you get HFS is
probably most of the rest of the ten
percent and occasionally linux or Nast
boxes are about all that's left this
will image all of those drives but it
will not do this function finding the
individual files yet they'd only do that
on ntfs that won't do it on any of the
others so but that's that's typically
the majority of what I'm looking at from
that standpoint so so anyway that was
just demonstrating it coming from that
drive and getting that process but I
think that this is a pretty profound
process that we're actually drilling
down now with the same device same tools
the same equipment unable to actually
try to drill down specifically to
individual files and actually get this
done so yeah deep spar is the vendor but
they also call the product deep scar
disk imager so they named it like
microsoft office you know same thing so
so they use the same tools the same idea
to do everything now as a matter of fact
this up to Gary that came free like I've
owned this box for like three years now
this upgrade came free and they
everything that they've done so far
there's been upgrades with the exception
of changes to hardware has been free so
if there's a change to the hardware
which is only happened once and it
wasn't necessary you didn't have to have
it so that's the only time they've ever
charged anybody anything so all the
software that's on the box has been
updated for free so what's that I don't
know exactly what's inside of it other
than the fact that it's probably just a
flash device that also can control the
physical power itself is probably
related to the power switch and stuff as
well I mean it's basically doing all its
commands through the ATA command set and
then some enhanced knowledge that they
actually have with regards to individual
vendors because one of the other things
that this tool can do which is the only
tool in its price range that actually
does this but me
it doesn't matter it can do all of them
including zip drives and everything else
the only problem right now is actually
solid state because solid state drives
don't conform to the standard 80 a
subset yeah they're just digits
Bridgeport's for all of them yeah you
need a PI license to do this especially
if it's on a forensics job right inside
joke or outside joke everyone good