so I'm going to go to my destination
disk then I'm going to deactivate the
MBR this is basically so that Windows
doesn't blow up so I deactivate it it
turns it off and now i'm going to just
turn off the machine so now what I want
to do is now I have this catalog I'm
going to take my actual destination disk
and I'm going to take my destination
disk off of the machine and i'm going to
plug it into windows let's see if this
switches screens correctly
okay so now I've got it plugged into
Windows and Windows wouldn't be able to
see anything basically all I would see
at this point well if it comes up
the dr initializes and shows up yeah
okay so so basically our how an
uninitialized is no MBR and it just has
just the all unallocated space but the
piece of software that goes with this
device knows that I have a table and it
knows where this table is so what I
should be able to do now this will look
a little beta and so you visual basic
people will kind of know what I'm
talking about here
um
yeah it's USB external hard drive
for that for the imager the imager talks
through all the ATA commands and
actually does all the work at the at the
actual imager level itself the this now
i'm actually just using windows all it's
going to do is read this table and i'm
going to be looking at this table so
this thing starts up is called image
explorer now here's its really beta so
here's the story I'm going to just
create a no I did not build this this is
actually part of deep spar stuff so I
have this thing called Explorer and
basically it sees the two hard drives in
the list when I hit the two hard drives
it's going to go and it will see that
there's a partition and now I can
actually do something that's called
scanned file system all this does is
looks at all my mft records over here on
the right and it's building me a table
and then once it's done i'll actually be
able to go down through the table and
now you'll actually see all the
directories that are on this damage
drive all i've got is an mft there is no
data only the catalog nothing else so
you know as you're looking down the list
and you see something you care about so
if i go say into the documents and
settings folder and i go to Bob Pell
amante then a bob has my documents
folder and maybe Bob's pitchers oh look
I want I care about hot chicks I want
hot chicks as I go back in the list you
know maybe on some porn oh it's porn
music will take that we go back down the
list here let's see what else we got so
porn porn LOL I'll take that one too all
right so so I've selected some porn off
his computer I don't want the window
system folder I don't want an allocated
I don't want anything else all i care
about are these folders yeah the
important stuff important the important
what's that it will be able to export
them and I will be able to look at them
but what's going to happen now is I have
to update the catalog i have to say hey
give me a catalog and put it on this
device so imma selected for imaging so
basically that's what this nail does is
it will go through 357 commands now is
going to add them to the list and it's
going to crawl through it
it's going to update it you can see it
doing the list actually right there
processing and then it's done so it's
selected them all so now all I have to
do imma save my project and I'm going to
close and then I'm just going to unmount
this disk which probably won't do
anything because there's no OS on it so
I'm turning it off and then i take this
again my destination disk i'm connecting
it back to the machine and I will turn
this thing now i'm going to switch back
to that machine so you can see what i'm
doing next what's that no i never did
get my camera working again
alright so now the machines booted I'm
going to I'm going to run my application
which is part of the hardware and yeah
then this I'm hitting f11 to turn the
power on this device will now turn the
power on and keep in mind that there's
like all these functions that have
existed on this thing for like three
years before we got this far that does
whole bunches of other things images in
Reverse skip stuff does all kinds of
damaged areas I'm just going to focus on
what these files are and if there's
damage in other places on the drive that
because ftk wouldn't make it through
this job it would die in all the all the
unallocated space and all the other
stuff I would normally have to copy so
so now i have my device selected and so
now i still have the same status
everything that was on my device before
is still there i can basically do an
imaging job you know like you can't do
this with ftk you can't just like stop
and come back later so i can actually
stop an image in process put it on the
shelf do another job put the two back on
in the configuration that comes from the
destination drive will maintain all the
status information for everything
anything that's already been copied it
will never do again anything that needs
to be copied it will still have a table
too but right now it just has a table
that basically says I want to image all
those files that you selected so I will
be able to actually start all over it
again in the beginning of the disk and I
will be able to tell it to go ahead and
it will only select those files that I
image and you'll see it's skipping big
chunks of data so you'll actually see
what it's doing is its building the list
across the bottom you'll see it going
through physical files headers blah blah
blah and as its crawling through the
disk it may take it may take five
minutes or so for this to actually work
because this is 160 gig drive and it's
got to make it from beginning to end but
it's only touching the sector's I told
it for the folders that I cared about so
it's actually imaging those sectors ya
been
you ever done an md5 on a damaged hard
drive you well they the piece of beta
software that I showed you a minute ago
their plan is to actually be able to
tell you percentages of individual files
that were recovered so for instance if
you have a bad sector in the middle of
the area that you care about it will now
know what the file is and it will give
you a report that part is not done yet
it's still in beta and so they're still
working on that piece but it actually
has a reporting mechanism to even show
you the physical files in the directory
structure that you're working with so as
it's going through the process that's
the plan now you can still go back and
empty five those or have a report that
actually tell you the percentage of that
but it'll skip it will skip
fragmentation there will still be some
more later on I think we select another
directory so it's skipping all the stuff
that we did not allocate yes sir um it
counts and it sees the pictures and so
see it has right now 532 pics it
actually has that built in the problem
is is that the screen refresh rate is a
100 milliseconds but it's reading these
at 10 millisecond blocks so you're not
seeing all the screen refreshes I can I
can drop that down but as a programmer
you're probably well aware that if I do
drop that down the machine is slower so
I will increase the speed for it to
write to the screen and decrease the
speed of my actual processing you can
you can just say what you're you can
make it so high it won't count but so if
you wanted to to slow down screen but
you know it is kind of really
informative as you're going through it
in a lot of cases you might even be able
to tell what it is that you've actually
got or what your file system is and keep
in mind it's also doing this by cluster
it's not so it identified the cluster
from the operating system so you're
going to get some slack space and stuff
with those files and things as well but
for the most part everything here will
be what we care about from a file
perspective so and it'll skip like I
said it may take 10 minutes or so for it
to get this there's some point like
after fifty percent of the drive that
there won't be any more data for me to
care about but anything that's
fragmented or anything that we selected
later is going to be probably further
down the disk but because this is also
sequentially like when you mount a hard
drive in your file system and you start
trying to copy stuff off there's a lot
of mounting and fragmentation and the
heads basically thrashing around in this
case because all of the LBA blocks were
laid out in order it's actually doing it
sequentially from beginning of the disk
to the end of the disk so it's not
calling into that thrashing around or
causing the head to do anything but move
see