Oh unique and different and I'm going to
do something with a demo and then
following that is Brian Wilson he's
going to do Doc's darkest docs docsis
docsis doc says coolness and then Bob
talks so and then we'll keep on going
press my belly Hoffman and then a
contest giveaway awards and stuff
tonight so uh so welcome PBR 9bx thank
you thanks Scott yep happy birthday old
man someday we all be your age speaking
of hacker cons well I was really happy
to be able to speak here today and
thanks for everybody coming out on a
beautiful weekend and not being outside
of the park or whatever being in here
with us troglodytes so today what am I
going to talk about i think most of
y'all are probably familiar with social
networking sites social networking
applications of these kind of things
they're actually coming up in the
mainstream media more and more
frequently you're going to hear you hear
lots and lots of stories about failures
information that's being disclosed on
these applications so we're going to
talk specifically about Twitter and some
about Facebook as well some scams out
there some software vulnerabilities that
have been exploited on Twitter and some
of these other platforms some ways
people have misused these platforms for
command control or data exfiltration
sort of purposes and some areas that
would be ripe for some future research
including exporting these client
applications that some of these
platforms are using and exploiting api's
so social networking right I kind of
already introduced it how many of y'all
out there use one of these social
networking systems or applications or
sites Facebook are have a profile for
instance linkedin facebook myspace all
those things hmm yeah right so a lot of
people want to admit it okay but when
you think of the social networking in
terms of like computer security a lot of
it it's essentially a social disease in
terms of that there's a high interaction
model here there's pokes there's iams
messages a lot of these platforms have
ways that you can plug in web
application widgets into your profile
that essentially blobs of javascript and
flash so really one of the problems here
and people are utilizing this a lot for
social engineering is this misplaced
perception of trust and intimacy as you
go about your interactions in these
systems and that's really one of the one
of the maid fails here and it's a human
failure in that sense as I mentioned
this is lack of boundaries there's a
lack of you know technical security
boundaries and that essentially on these
websites your browser's enforcing the
same origin policy however Facebook and
Twitter and the Facebook in particular
is sourcing rich web content from all
sorts of third-party application
providers so really the trust and
security boundaries are just not there
well then as I mentioned also there's
sort of a personal or human level where
there's personal boundaries and people
just don't seem to think through what
they're exposing out there you know you
can people have been analyzing social
networks from sort of a graph
theoretical perspective as well in
computer science there's some you know
core algorithms and theories about how
you can color a graph or divide a graph
or find in degrees and out degrees of
nodes in a graph and really these social
networks are essentially graphs in the
computer science sense and you can apply
a lot of these same algorithms to
mapping social networks in terms of the
ants degree of separation between nodes
or on average how many how many friends
are you away from a malicious profile
that's spreading exploits for instance
um so you know a good academic kind of
paper on that is Krishna Murthy and
Will's they submitted a paper to the
ACMs workshop on social networking 2009
I think if you google for that you can
probably find their paper and they did
some analysis of the kind of personal
information that can be found on these
websites ways you can mine it and the
kind of inferences that you can make
from all this information and you know
some folks in the in the industry and in
the community have been talking for the
past couple years about using these
networks for open source
information gathering using it as part
of the reconnaissance phase for a full
spectrum penetration tests gentleman by
the name of Chris gates formerly of
Northrop Grumman who's done a lot of
talks on how to how do you can utilize
open-source intelligence-gathering to
make a more successful pen test and of
course the same techniques are going to
be used and are being used by the bad
guys we'll get on to that top a little
bit later but also these social networks
are now being used for political
repression in that for instance the
authorities can map people's social
networks when they identify an
individual of interest they can then
infer their social connections and
social networks and and then put those
individuals under further scrutiny for
instance I mentioned before it's a rich
web environment a lot of these
applications so it's all the classic OS
kind of top ten vulnerabilities that
you're going to be exposed to cross-site
scripting particularly because of
dynamic content being sourced from
multiple sites you have a more exposure
to cross-site request forgery sort of
post interactions they're all the rich
content browser plugins multimedia
players flash player shockwave it's all
going to be exposed in these kind of
social networking applications so it's a
great environment if you're looking to
perform wholesale exploitation of
particular client site vulnerabilities
or wholesale exploitation of just social
weakness social engineering essentially
as a social engineering right these are
great target-rich environments for both
penetration testers but also black hats
in terms of us fishing spear fishing and
social engineering attacks through these
networks these are not these don't even
have to be sophisticated or targeted at
all I'm talking about what later we'll
talk about the koobface worm which saw a
lot of success in 2009 spreading via
particularly facebook messages and the
propagation mechanisms of some trojan
horses such as koobface utilize twitter
facebook and these other systems to
propagate direct message
is instant messages containing links to
exploits and social engineering attacks
and so that's been a very very
successful way that black hats of use
these systems to propagate malware
trojan horses and that kind of thing are
all favorite you know URL shorteners and
there's there's some security
implications here to URL shorteners it's
kind of hard to assume that the average
user inspects the URL before they click
it or even inspect the URL that the
hyperlink is to and their status bar in
their browser however this is you know
definitely introducing one complete
layer of obfuscation in terms of a URL
and it's kind of training people in some
really bad habits you received this
little opaque URL from your buddy and an
instant message direct message whatever
and you click on it that can be a risky
step to take we'll talk about a little
bit later about the month of Twitter
bugs from Abby Roth and he uncovered a
lot of xss and a lot of other
vulnerabilities in third party websites
to integrate with Twitter including some
of the URL shorteners so I don't know if
you in September of last year you follow
this at all but there was the month of
Facebook bugs this is a one in many of a
series of month of bugs kind of a month
of vulnerabilities exercises so
anonymous security researcher by the
name of the Harmony guy identified 9700
vulnerable facebook apps in the month of
sep tember it turns out it was I don't
know how he managed a responsible
disclosure process but as far as I can
tell he performed responsible disclosure
of the 9700 vulnerable facebook
applications as well and by the time he
went public with this they had all been
patched essentially so six of the 10
most popular applications and eve's were
found to contain this nasty combination
of xss and a cross-site scripting and
cross-site request forgery now when you
have when you combine those two you can
do a lot of really fun and interesting
things with a Facebook API is and
facebook application so the Harmony guy
kind of dubbed this combination of two
vulnerability classes to be facts fa XX
facebook application x SS plus x srf for
cross-site request forgery so those
those popular applications that he found
that had this flaw had 218 million
active users per month that had these
widgets running in their Facebook
profiles as a huge user base and people
don't really consider a vulnerability
and some little crappy Facebook plugin
is going to expose hundreds of millions
of users to this kind of vulnerability
also seven of the top ten developers had
these issues so that is a registered
Facebook Developer you have to register
with Facebook as a developer and half of
these applications were facebook
verified applications they had been
through Facebook's review process here's
a facebook fail right July fifth 2009
mi6 is the UK's domestic intelligence
agency i believe and the head of mi6 is
his identity has always kept secret he
goes by code name so this gentleman I
don't have his I can't read his name
right here but if you google for it
you'll find it he was promoted and he
was promoted to run mi6 the British
intelligence service well his wife was
very proud of this and went on to her
Facebook and shared this information
that I'm so proud of my husband he's now
the in charge of mi6 she believed that
this was restricted to her group of
friends however she had joined the
london metropolitan facebook group which
over road some privacy settings so
there's this kind of complex interaction
between privacy settings for
geographical groups versus the privacy
settings for different groups of friends
that you've defined so she inadvertently
shared that information with the Greater
London area and her husband's identity
was revealed I'm not certain
I'm not certain he may have assumed the
title and the role but he you know it's
I think it's a rotating position he
won't be there forever link didn't fail
this one's not that cool but October
night 2009 Robert Morgan the Microsoft
researcher posted something about he's
working on the next generation 128-bit
windows kernel on his facebook and the
press kind of grabbed onto this is like
microsoft revealed a secret they're
working on 128 bit kernels you know a
realistic person might think like well
yeah they they better be because 64-bit
is consumer grade now so to jump kind of
jump topics here Facebook privacy
settings this stuff is complicated you
almost got to be like a ccie to like
figure out like how the interactions
between the various granular policy
settings all fit together when you're
using them to their fullest in terms of
defining different groups of friends you
could have work friends social friends
friends and family parents and how do
you apply policy essentially across all
these different groups and keep your
information compartmentalised how you
want it not easy task so on December
10th 2009 everyone logged into Facebook
in the morning when they got into work
and they were greeted with a request to
update the privacy settings for the new
quote simplified privacy system of
Facebook in reality the privacy settings
were being made more numerous and more
granular however they sort of introduced
like this wizard to set the recommended
privacy settings as recommended by
Facebook so you were presented with hey
we've introduced a new simplified system
do you want to set the defaults or do
you want to do a whole bunch of other
work and try to define your policy while
you're just trying to get to facebook so
what was the default simplified privacy
policy it was to make all your posts and
all your pics public to the web for
indexing as well it was to make more
data available or to make more data
available than a lot of people's
profiles already configured for so it's
this is a
smart business decision I think on
Facebook's part right the value of their
company or the value of their service is
really based on the amount of
information they have how well they can
index it how well they can target
advertisements and things of that nature
to their their user base so the more
data is available the more the value of
facebook service increases so the
alignment the interests of Facebook and
the interest of their users privacy
weren't quite a line there and as you
can see Mark Zuckerberg misunderstood
his new privacy settings now he claims
that this was intentional that that he
exposed his photos for a day or two but
these were private photos the new
Facebook privacy policy rolled out and
for like a day there the founder of
Facebook's embarrassing college pitchers
were exposed on the web and index and
here they are right a couple of them I'm
not sure what that is but some sort of
glassware I don't know so this is this
is the founder of Facebook here if you
research him more like that there's some
stories coming out about he's kind of
like this sort of robber baron but I'm
not sure it could be sour grapes google
buzz ya betta so google buzz because
someone get me a water some remind
anybody so februari night 2010 google
rolled out there buzz service 20 though
it essentially was already made 150
million user social network that wrote
on top of gmail and so here's a quote
from the official gmail blog from google
that announced the introduction it's
built right into gmail so you don't have
to peck out an entirely new set of
friends from scratch it just works if
you think about it there's always been a
big social network underlying gmail buzz
brings this network to the surface by
automatically setting you up to follow
the people you email and chat with the
most so previous Google is very
interested in getting in this space they
have quite a previous efforts in this
area they launched the or
good social networking service in
January 04 they released this OpenSocial
set of AP is in November of seven that
are being used by myspace linkedin orkut
plaxo salesforce com and others so
Google is pretty active in the space and
I think they see social networking is
very strategic to their success and they
just couldn't resist this opportunity to
create a hundred fifty million social
net user social network from scratch
yeah I mean I don't think that's unusual
too that's probably not an unusual
clause in terms of service however if
you are a comcast or a broadband
residential subscriber read the Terms of
Service of your subscription to
broadband internet and as I read it
essentially you grant them a global non
exclusive right to redistribute any
content you put over that pipe right so
if you're imagine your author and you're
sending your manuscript to your editor
publisher right well based on not a
lawyer's reading of this contract well
the comcast now has a global non
exclusive right to reduce your
manuscript I don't know thank you
appreciate that so Google Buzz was used
to share posts and notes with people
that you follow it was kind of a
confusing system because you
automatically were following the people
that you emailed and chatted with the
most and by default this list of first
followers as in first degree of
separation was made public as a public
profile item so essentially it exposed
the network of email and chat contacts
for individuals using gmail so not only
was it pretty disastrous to some
people's privacy and security it was it
was viewed as a large PR blunder by the
media and by Google they kind of
miscalculated that people didn't really
want to turn their email contacts into a
social network so two days after the
rollout Google deploy google rolled out
some fixes in about two days after this
so here's some press clippings
showing the kind of reaction the media
was having to google buzz right
right so the point being made is it I
probably was a little bit kind to Google
and using the word default in reality
this was kind of turned on there was no
there was actually no effective way as
far as I can tell in the first two days
to disable it so yeah it was voiced it
upon a lot of gmail users but ok so the
details I understand is whether you
accept it or not your followers were
exposed but since I don't use Gmail I
don't know so here's that they rushed
out the privacy related fixes in like
two days flat pretty pretty impressive
reaction but not so impressive debut
right so here is one change it made the
people that you follow excuse me it made
the option to hide the people you follow
much more prominent they claim that
option existed i'm not sure but here you
know it's like in bold text right so now
it's more visible ok Oh certainly yeah
you turn something on for a hundred
fifty million users many of them won't
notice what just you know there I'm sure
that there's plenty of users that have
it wide open as it was on day one it
they added link so you could block block
users in more places so before you
couldn't previously you could only block
users that had a public Google profile
so if someone had never created a google
profile but was a gmail user which is
very common buzz turned on you guys had
communicated your they're following you
automatically now you couldn't block
them you cannot remove them from your
list of followers because they didn't
have a Google public profile now so they
introduced the ability to do that and
here
well like I mentioned before right so
there's a lot of inferences and this
information is valuable too for lots of
different purposes you know I have
first-hand instant responder kind of
knowledge of incidents where attackers
all they were after was your PGP web of
trust they didn't even take the secret
keys all they wanted to know is who does
this individual communicate securely
with all right so if people are willing
to go do a targeted attack just to
snatch your PGP web of trust this is
like this is pretty useful too and you
wouldn't even have to explore anything
you just like harvest the profiles on
the web yeah so here and here the other
change they made was it now breaks out
and makes clear like who has a public
profile and who does it of the people
that are following you so like the day
it came out no februari 16th like our
snake on hackers org someone um a guy
going by the handle train wreck who is
supposedly the guy that like exposed all
and Mairi Miley Cyrus's photos or
something didn't didn't follow that one
but he emailed our snake like hey check
out this XSS and yes sure enough there
was XSS in the location services of
Goethe of buzz so you could you could do
some interesting things there though the
cool thing of the what makes us a little
bit worse than the average XSS is that
this was in the court google.com domain
it wasn't in Google Groups com it wasn't
in wasn't in the other Google brand
domain so if you can get XSS on google
com it's more valuable and also the
excess and the xss worked over HTTPS so
really sweet get a nice google XSS there
um right political repression you know
we talked a little bit about you know
what's the value of this information or
what kind of risks people are people
that supposed to when this information
is exposed
so during the back in June of last
summer the Iranian elections happened
there's controversy over the contested
presidential election some widespread
protests took place in Iran so a lot of
this was some of this was being played
out on Twitter and some of the other
facial some of the other social networks
so there was a kind of a battle going on
between the opposition or the protesters
and forces loyal to the government
iranian revolutionary forces and so
there were sock puppet profiles being
created there is entrapment going on you
know of false profiles being used to try
to lure in folks sympathetic to the
opposition disinformation being spread
and of course mapping of social networks
and mapping of contents and associations
so here's a I think this was generated
with mount ego I'm not sure this is from
a blog Petronas analytical and this is
the this is a node this is a graph of
Twitter communications during the
Iranian election protests and in the
middle that that central node is a je
underscore producer and it was an
individual or someone that was claiming
to be a producer for Al Jazeera's
english-language television network and
thus as the story goes this individual
was impersonating a producer for Al
Jazeera's television network and was
requesting and reaching out to all the
people they could find that were
expressing opposition sentiments and
requesting that they reach out and
contact them via cell phone or email so
that they could get their message out
through al Jazeera we don't believe that
that was a real al Jazeera producer so
that diagram shows a recent recent
direct communications with about 20
other Twitter users and then their
communications out to the next node
so here's another graph of Twitter
traffic during the protests you've got
to sock puppets I ran source 45 and I
ran source that were allegedly
disseminating disinformation in relation
to the opposition protests and they're
the dominant nodes you can barely make
it out you can barely make it out but
there's little teeny nodes surrounding
that all over like spokes and similar to
this one and you see that pattern when
you graph it because these individuals
were sending tweets directly to other
users and we're replying directly to
questions but weren't like publishing
stuff on a public timeline kind of thing
and then in the middle there there's
five users that were like sort of anti
spammers on Twitter trying to counter
the information that these two nodes
were pushing out
I think this is this these individuals
contacting the people that this person
contacted to say hey they're fake ah I'm
not sure um yeah BOTS finding bots could
be good big the historical tax on social
networking right so the big three
facebook myspace twitter um anybody
familiar with the Sammy my space worm i
think i gave a talk about it like outer
zone two years ago so i'm probably like
blast do it this is like as far as i can
tell is the first real in the wild xss
worm to spread through a web application
so Samy Kamkar was behind this and it
was kind of you know I don't think he
intended to obviously been intended to
get in trouble but there may have been
some innocent you know kind of hacker
mentality oh my gosh look what I can do
I want a million friends and I think I
can create a million friends over one
evening so the author created this xss
script he updated his profile with it
when you view this profile it would
export your profile make you his friend
you post a message saying like he's your
hero and then you then you send messages
to all your contacts 20 hours more than
a million users fastest spreading
computer virus in history at the time
and then my space suit him in civil
court I believe you know he got in some
trouble but as far as I can tell he's
sort of like a legit security researcher
these days he goes to conferences he's
doing some interesting work good for you
Sammy you're my hero myspace warm
propagation this is a it's not a very
good graph but you know you can see the
hockey puck or the hockey stick kind of
thing this is from his own blog he was
like live blogging his exploit and he
posted this picture his screenshot from
his profile and he's like look kick-ass
I rule I got a million friends uh she
wants me that says they're mad photoshop
skills
yeah well it was pretty clear like after
the post instant forensics would have
shown like his was the first profile he
posted this payload and then it took off
from there so I don't think even if he
was like silent like it they could have
traced it to patient zero I believe I
mean even if he doesn't yeah I mean if
he didn't do the friend payload if he
just trash people's profiles them so
twitter twitter is a big fun sort of
research project for security cool i'm
doing pretty good on time how they grow
it like twitter is now like their
primary strategic growth is all SMS
based like forget the web apps forget
the fat client applications like they're
expanding globally via SMS so they sign
an agreement I don't have the date you
know the past 6 12 months with Bharti
Airtel it's the largest wireless
provider in India has about a hundred
and ten million subscribers like a year
ago to allow full SMS Twitter
interfacing with all their user base
access Indonesia which is the largest
gsm provider in indonesia which is you
know rapidly growing his sign a similar
deal you know Twitter's work with
partnerships with MySpace and AOL so
that's kind of our growth there so this
here I don't know any people don't is
the fail whale so when Twitter like us
down or it's over capacity or whatever
you can't get to it they like throw up
this gif and there I oh you know we're
down but it's cool because we had like
good graphic designers so april two
thousand eight you know this is kind of
a history of some of the vulnerabilities
there McGrew security sounded like a
super super simple CSRF film and you
could just when you visited their page
would just post a message to your public
timeline like you know thanks for
visiting magery security you got pwned
twitter staging server so Damon p
cortesi who's at da court you'll see
like some screenshots and some sources
that I credit to him he's done a lot of
work on Twitter security check him out
so july two thousand eight
he found like Twitter had their internal
staging servers like sitting on the
internet without any authentication you
know you could like look at like it was
like my sequel monitor the status of all
their my sequel databases like it was
essentially the control center for
Twitter and it was sitting on the web so
he responsibly contacted him and said
hey you guys might want to like put this
behind a firewall and they fixed it
except they forgot to like add
authentication to the HTTPS virtual host
so he said oh but whoops try again they
fix it of course they implemented the
fixed with HTTP basic authentication
Twitter rank this was like a little
social engineering experiment he did
where you just like create some totally
bogus story like you know if you give me
your username and password to Twitter
you'll you know i'll increase y'all give
you your Twitter rank just some score
like see how cool you are so he like
Damon Twitter rank was done by somebody
else Damon's like can I crank it up a
notch kind of turn it to 11 Twitter
awesomeness all right look how just get
over this website looks as the name
implies Twitter awesomeness is to see
how awesome you are on Twitter tell me
how awesome I am twitter user ID twitter
password check the box tell everyone on
Twitter how awesome I am disclaimer
right there red I'm in your Twitter's
stealing your creds it's ok 259 other
people gave their passwords to please
note if you haven't noticed this doesn't
really calculate your awesomeness so we
got like hundreds of users like he
didn't even advertise this crap like he
got hundreds of users in there like
giving him his passwords giving them
their passwords not really a Twitter
fails at human fail um
yeah well I don't think he's well the
question instead of saying are they
automate I just asked like our people
get me their real passwords I don't
think he verified them because that
might be unauthorized access but um so
yeah you could type anything you want
and get your awesomeness score for free
so the user search feature they like for
a long time their search functions kind
of sucked so they debuted in December 08
like the ability to search users whoa
xss fail right oh noes that's the alert
right there information disclosure is
right December 08 like until December 08
any third party site could just use the
Twitter API to determine when you visit
the website what your twitter if you use
twitter and what your user name was and
like there's the json call back right
there it's super simple you just like
call Twitter it basically utilizes like
the credentials that are cashing your
browser and and it just said Prince the
username in alert box that's the proof
of concept there so any website you
visited if you use that same browser and
you didn't really use private browsing
mode or whatever as mitigations they
could as soon as you visit they'd be
like oh you know he's PBR and on the X
on Twitter their administration in her
face got pwned in May you probably
shouldn't use the word happiness for a
password and the way I got pwned I think
is that one of the founders or Jason got
with allegedly Jason Goldman director of
product management with Twitter was
using like yahoo mail with the same
password and got phished maybe it was
spearfishing I don't know they tried
their like maybe his yahoo mail
passwords the one to the whole twitter
you know brain in the sky and it was so
so this guy I can't mad yeah I don't
know if I have his handle in the note on
one of these I think he was posting
these two french language underground
boards but like so he went into their
internal administrative interface and
started taking screenshots I was like
everybody's like internal Twitter
profile so like in the administration
interface you can go to a profile and it
gives you a lot of information like what
IP addresses are they authenticating
from what users have they banned how
many how many follow Tim so they doing
per day the use of the API rates like
how much are they using the API are they
a bot it's we don't really know i mean
the director product management at it
i'm not sure but i think their internal
support staff this is the application
they used so you can look at the notes
there's like tickets tickets and alerts
and this is the handle oh the other like
big fail is that the account night the
accounts on the internal administrative
system are the same accounts that the
twitter employees used on twitter so
like at at cool jill is also like the
way cool Jill who works for Twitter
administers the whole system so you've
got like Twitter at men's with user
names like crystal Connie cat you know
so and here you can see whose side is
this so this is britney spears profile
right her gmail address IP address she
walks in from or her PR team she has a
real problem with like passwords getting
reset by another user like three times
on the fifth of january and once the
prior day and you can see some support
notes and what you find is that the
celebrities like get gold or get white
glove service from twitter they have
their own representatives like account
at zex at twitter that their PR people
work with when their account gets
hijacked every day so you know like
you'll find these like support histories
and it would be like you know their
passwords like poem it doesn't say how
they don't do any incident response like
you're you know again and again and
again yeah and they have a phone number
she's like oh you can call me highest
crystal you can call me on my cell phone
if your password gets pwned again
tonight um who's profiles is ashton
kutcher's profile
um so he you can see he uses AOL com
email address and he likes the tweetdeck
application and he has blocked Perez
Hilton drunken stepfather Ashton's
father Ashton's daddy and other
variations of this is the user sees
block I don't I haven't like done a real
investigation of Ashton but I think he
might have some stuff with his dad in
his background oh I've obscured it it
actually the screenshot i received off
of one of these outlets was already at
secured here's my ears um President
Barack Obama's Twitter account you can
see like there's tons of password resets
in early January 2009 like here's the
seventh January seventh eighth eighth
eighth eighth eighth eighth eighth ninth
these are all password reset by another
user we're like they've lost control the
account or something either that or
there's like a war going on inside
Obama's PR you know department of who
has control of their twitter profile and
so here on the 5th crystal in service
you know crystal seems to handle a lot
of the celebs and politicians user
account hat someone not me probably biz
restored account to normalcy and as soon
as I don't so you can see Barack um he
joined Twitter on May fifth 2007 he's
thinking ahead and and the first user he
banned or at least the first user listed
in the banned list is KKK for life um
here's my key Twitter worm so we talked
about the Sammy Sammy my space worm
April 09 like a little less than a year
ago stalked daily which was a competitor
to Twitter a worm hit Twitter spreading
a message about joining stalked daily
and the link will take you to a
cross-site scripting attack payload that
was exporting excess session the Twitter
website it caused the profiles to send
the similar message out to their
contacts and here's like a screenshot of
a bunch of people's tweets that their
profile had been pwned by this worm and
they were propagating the payload to
others and here's the actual attack
payload like it went through many
variations so like every time Twitter
would fix the xss who is using he'd like
evade their filter like five minutes
later and then they go fix something
else and then he'd say screw it i'm
gonna use another parameter ha and then
they'd fix though is she oh we got
XSS and this other parameter they add a
filter he'd evade that filter so his cat
and mouse for like a day there so he's
basically just doing little Ajax payload
with a cross-site scripting here's he he
he confessed to what he was up to Mikey
and so he put a message on the stock
daily website that he had he I have came
clean and have accepted the
responsibility for the worm read the
interview here and he was interviewed
with some news website hello you might
not want to click you might have learned
by now don't click links from mikey and
here's the post on Twitter's website
about what was going on they called it
the stall daily.com worm they said
reassured no passwords phone numbers or
other sensitive information were
compromised as part of this attack we
only share that a lot of business
partners cleaning up Mikey so if someone
launched another worm that was like
removing the militares payloads and
fixing the profiles and so here's the
cleaning up mikey worm that was launched
and and so what it would do it also had
a little messaging payload to spread
itself but it said Twitter hire Mikey so
someone was looking out for him you know
he he'd be more productive in on staff
at Twitter than in jail probably
and here's a picture of the perp right
sort of goffe looking kid maybe
adolescent I'm not sure he's working the
angles you know that pit so I mentioned
cubeface before the koobface worm is a
really prevalent piece of malware it's
been spreading for like a year or two
here's just some pictures of like tweets
that the worm sends out when it when it
pounds you it'll grab your Twitter
credentials and will start propagating
itself through your Twitter followers
you ever seen this stuff have you seen
like links arrived and Facebook or
Twitter that's just clearly not really
from your friend here's like a lot of
its social engineering so it'll take you
to a website that looks like a YouTube
or Facebook and it will say oh you need
the new version of flash to play the
video or you need this multi media codec
I think codex we're a couple years ago
flash was 09 and now a lot of the we're
seeing more and more move to like true
on web browser exploit kits to push the
Mau on you if the exploits don't work
then it will pop up a scary message and
try to social engineering Twitter
internal documents right uh or exposed
in July 09 this is still like beating up
on Twitter I'm sorry Twitter so the
founders account got compromised and
they're all using like google docs for
domains or something like that and so
this guy who goes by hacker Kroll sit
like 300 dots to a bunch of media
outlets and it was someone was lame
stuff like lunch orders and you know
like catering and oh my god Twitter
likes roast beef yeah and uh but but
some of it was interesting stuff it was
like partner agreements right like who
they're putting in DA's in place with
phone logs of employees calendar meeting
calendars who's meeting with who
financial projections right and there
was a controversy one of the TechCrunch
TechCrunch actually published
a batch of these documents in Kwazii
redacted form and there is this whole
like is that responsible journalism
debate going on or whatever so is that
aneta oxymoron months of Twitter bugs
I'll be off I mentioned this earlier he
so there's all sorts likes whole
ecosystem of websites that integrate
with Twitter like you probably a lot of
people use twitpic one of the most
popular well there's all sorts of like
other third-party apps and websites that
you know you integrate with your Twitter
profile and make it cooler and more
awesome but they all were full of
cross-site scripting and sequel
injection and CSRF but the surprising
thing from this whole exercise is a lot
in fact the majority of these
third-party sites were very responsive
when Abby Ralf contacted them they were
deploying fixes in like 24 hours you
know or less on frequently so yeah
they're right and web applications
they're going to be vulnerabilities
kudos for fixing him pretty quickly in
when they were disclosed to them I don't
know if Dave Dave's in here but he runs
a errata security runs his twat guard
service where it's kind of like
monitoring Twitter for abuse and
exploits so how to hack campaign is sort
of a viral campaign to spread some
malware know it all linked to a
malicious flash player exe with a bit ly
shortened link this is a social
engineering scam here call best
followers and it's like change its name
again and again it was like greatest
followers like I don't even know all the
names but it's been changing its name
but it's basically scam to get you to
like provide your Twitter credentials to
them and in return they promised like to
create tons of followers so this is an
attractive service to like someone in PR
or marketing or who's trying to use
viral marketing techniques to sell
something or to generate leads and if
you work with like PR and marketing like
they might do you think they could fall
for it no comment so if they have a
disclaimer it says our site does not
fish accounts any content on this site
may not be a hundred percent accurate
by using this site you agree need
followers calm the one point is need
followers calm is not to be monitored or
involved with any legal matters that's a
reasonable reasonable terms of service
right so here's like and the website
looks pretty ghetto and to like opt out
or to close the account you have to
provide them your password again so it's
like if you would like to close or opt
out please enter your username and
password that you signed up with if you
don't remember your information it's the
same as your Twitter information and
then they have so it total scam right
and what happens like you don't really
get lots of followers but you send out
lots of messages when you join and all
the messages are saying like I finally
found the best way to get tons of
followers for free ok didn't quite work
out Twitter porn name this is another
social engineering scam and it was i'm
not sure like who started it but it was
a great way to get people to reveal like
sort of like security questions and
stuff so they were like hey everybody
tweets your twitter porn name it's the
name of your first pet and the name of
the street you grew up on or perhaps the
name of the head teacher in your school
so there's definitely a union there
between like you know the authentication
questions that you use with financial
institutions and things of that nature
or to reset passwords i'm not sure if
this was actually just malicious or just
plain stupid so here's like the tweet
you know the twitter porn name right you
can see Dave lamb his porn name is
Pimm's Dave and it's okay though because
why it saves any personal info being
given away I don't know what that means
cool that the Russia Georgia war I guess
was it August last summer oh yeah I
guess that's when it was so there's a
denial of service attack excuse me
shooting is that the war was not august
last year i don't recall the date of the
war but there is
attack that took Twitter offline on
august sixth 2009 and it was related to
the conflict of the Russian Federation
in the Republic of Georgia so there was
a profile on Twitter called c YX y mu
that was sending out pro georgian sort
of georgian nationalist tweets and some
hacktivists sympathetic to the russian
federation in there cause didn't like
that and decided to silence this one
Twitter profile they're going to just
dost Twitter and they took Twitter down
for part of the day and I was never able
to get details of how the dots work with
it just like a brute force like
bandwidth da so did they find something
interesting to do to Twitter's
infrastructure to cause it happen and a
court this was written up by Brian Krebs
formerly of the Washington Post we're
going to got about 15 minutes left we'll
get into like how you can actually you
know like subvert some Twitter
authentication stuff here so Twitter the
legacy authentication mechanism is HTTP
basic auth which is essentially just a
base64 of the credential user name colon
password that soon as HTTP header
essentially the simplest way to
authenticate using the HTTP protocol and
it completely relies upon something at a
lower level and protocol stack provide
for confidentiality and integrity like
ssl/tls typically and so the the the way
they promote authenticating is oooff
which is sort of a ticket it's not
really like Kerberos but it's sort of a
ticket based authentication mechanism
where you do not have to provide your
twitter username and password to the
third party site instead they request a
ticket on your behalf from twitter so it
like sort of like a view familiar what
how Kerberos works so and then third
party client apps or sites that want to
use OAuth have to register with Twitter
which is a step that you don't need if
you want to write a client out just
using basic off but we'll write one in
ten lines of Python right but to use
OAuth you need like an OAuth
authentication account that's been
reviewed by Twitter
but it's a huge challenge for them to
disable basic off there's there's like
10,000 client apps or excuse me there's
tens there's thousands of client apps
out there so it's it's the user base
problem right so one thing needs to
happen is more more pressure needs to be
put on these sites i guess in the app
developers to fix this and move 20 off
as you can see how this fails so the
coolest fail of the basic off stuff was
I don't know if you followed November
the disclosure of the ssl renegotiation
gap this is a vulnerability from ray
despensa or marsh ray and Steve dispensa
of phone factor and they responsibly
disclosed this it's a essentially way to
do ssl renegotiation to it to be able to
post a request as a man-in-the-middle
attacker through SSL and this Turkish
researcher i'm really i'm sad i don't
have a name handy security goose i think
is attainable he published is really
cool proof of concept that actually used
it Twitter's HB service supported new
renegotiation they had not turned it off
yet so he used that celery negotiation
to compromise people's Twitter
credentials over when they were sent
over HTTPS it was pretty cool but oh off
is not perfect either you know it's it's
the permissions are just read or read
right so and so either you grant the
website the third party website or
application the ability to read your
profile or you have to grant it full
read/write access that's not very you
know granular and most of these services
are going to require right permissions
to like offer the cool value that they
put claim and read permissions include
direct messages so reading they can you
know if you when you grant read
permissions to OAuth enabled service
they can go through all your private
messages everything you've ever sent
through direct messages and pull that
out right so you really have to trust
these things it includes like who you're
following
that's protected so people that you've
the following relationships you have
that you want to keep private well
that's included in read permissions and
the third party client apps instead of
storing the username password they just
store an OAuth token but it's not it's
not clear at all like that you can't
just like kidnap that token and use that
somehow a Twitter botnet commanding
control like there's an open source
project out there and you can delete
control botnets via Twitter tweets or
also JPEGs with commands in them or tiny
urls kind of cool Tom Easton and Robin
would have worked on this they presented
it edit last summer at Def Con 17 they
also gave some additional information on
it at mu con 2010 when they released
version 3 and added linkedin support so
back to this basic auth like as a few
months ago Twitter would always expose
the session cookies ok like even it's so
like when you go to the Twitter website
even even if you type in HTTPS twitter
com boom it loads up securely you log in
it posts it via HTTPS and it falls back
to clear text now I've been able to use
no script which has an option to force
ssl on certain wild card domains and
such so I've been able to use no script
to force it into SSL but unless you use
no script you can authenticate with your
username and password to their website
that's the cell but then your session
credentials the session cookies are just
getting passed back and forth which you
know there's all sorts of tools out
there fair at hampster whatever that can
do session side jacking session
hijacking cookie hijacking all this they
do have an authentication token annonce
built in to prevent CSRF or attempt to
prevent CSRF but if you have if you've
observed the whole session you know what
that is because that was sent down as
part of the JavaScript that loaded the
forum
so there's Twitter CNC stuff like this
open source project is cool but like in
August 09 it was there was real Twitter
cnc being used by a Brazilian based
botnet you know it was a bot controller
was like posting tweets that were base
64 encoded URLs and the URLs led to a
blob of text which was pkzip archives
and then the PK zip archive had a upx
pack info schema Trojan inside of it
that was boosters boozes Trojan so if
someone briefly was using Twitter to
control a botnet and distribute stuff
there's a screenshot of it the name of
the Twitter profile was update and hacks
or oh yeah so I was talking about
Twitter website off got like eight nine
minutes so it's loaded via HTTP by
default if you use HPS explicitly it
will load it but there is no HP redirect
and https redirect in place so here is
the form right it uses the HPS URL to
form submit it does include this
authenticity token which is a randomly
generated nonce as in a mitigation again
CSRF and that comes down as part of the
form when it loads the login page but if
you understand like CSRF sand exercises
you know if you can find an XSS a good
exercise in the application then this
not sand this token isn't really it
doesn't prevent you from like doing
anything because you already you can
access it via the Dom I think
it's not gonna I mean you can code
around this right i don't think it's
maybe there's two reasons i do it the
the obvious reason is this is the way
you're supposed to mitigate against CSRF
the not so obvious reason is hey we want
a walled garden right and we don't want
BOTS running them up on our service and
harvesting information but that's not
really true because they offer all these
api's and they make deals with Google
and Bing to index everything and make it
available as real-time indexes so I mean
I'll just use the API right but this is
I think this is there to protect against
CSRF and they have some hidden form
fields and I'm not sure how they're
really used yet whether it's like oh you
haven't liked it sends a random form
field called Q for instance when I
tested it or sign in underscore Q and
maybe if you don't submit that bat it's
going to say hey he didn't it's not a
real browser on the other end and after
log and it falls back to http so your
session cookies and I'll Senate the
secret authenticity token is being
passed back and forth in the clear the
sort of session cookie is called under
Twitter underscore sesh the Aspire is
set to 0 ok I think Google like years
ago when Maynard and Rob Graham like did
the side jacking stuff like within hours
of their talk at black hat Google
cookies had expiration on him but when I
like look at this it's like inspire set
to zero and that cookie it's good for
ever hopefully when you log out and
validates the cookie somehow in the back
end but otherwise that's a perfectly
valid cookie for forever client apps
most unused basic office till they don't
use OAuth right a lot of them don't even
use SSL you know I'm not going to name
names but I tested one of the if you
have if you just like want to use a
twitter client app and you're running a
bun too well that app is going to fall
back clear text so all you got to do is
you want to pound somebody's basic off
we'll put it in a firewall rule to send
a reset back
the twitter has one IP they don't do
they don't do complicated DNS any
casting or whatever you resolve twitter
com you get IP address back put a farmer
rule in there for a reset 4443 des port
when someone uses that Twitter
application and a lot of Twitter apps
are going to do this it attempts ssl it
gets the reset back and it happily just
sends the credentials in clear text
there's no visible indication to the
user whatsoever unless you're sniffing
the wire you would not know that your
username password just went out in the
clear all because someone just blocked
port 443 to Twitter and it suppose your
password haphazard validation of ssl
certificates when it does use ssl so
there's a lot of problems there you can
attack these apps like you uh you can
attack these apps there expose a big
attack surface I've set up a peach
fuzzer as a rogue Twitter service like
us it fuzz's the clients and so
basically you can fuzz Jason RSS Adam
XML parser inners all that stuff is
exposed in these client applications so
it was a pain in the ass to get peach to
actually fuzz client applications but it
can be done or you could do some
interesting evil man in the middle
attacks like make you know change
everybody's timelines to say I hate PVR
90 x so you know all of a sudden you
login to twitter and there's 200
followers and their tweet is just they
hate you you know or they love you twit
tweetdeck had some issues they had one
call one API call that they forgot to
use ssl on whoops in tweetdeck yeah but
remember i mentioned stuff about like
silently falling back to clear text and
like doing haphazard certificate
validation test it it's an exercise for
the viewer sektor conference wall
ashamed Twitter credentials all over the
place from this tweet deck bug that's
all i got i just wanted to give greets
out to the folks of DC for 4 i'm not a
free site atlanta member but i wanted to
say thank you to all them and i was good
to see them out here and and plug-in
that and many thanks to skydog Scott
Kevin everybody who's made this possible
who's videotaping it it's good to be
back again i skipped outer zone last
year and thanks for coming out