breaks so first day on money
a body for being an especially thank
everybody for having me here it's always
great to come
to this way
wanna talk to give a row
applause for putting on such an awesome
con through the great but they are
putting on a con is not an easy task in
how well run this is is amazing you know
we run
Derby Conn and a few other ones and I it
takes a lot of effort a lotta work so I
mean serious acute as everybody to make
this happen
it's a it's been really smooth really
awesome Nick the talks have been great
the speakers I mean everything so
again shall not only them in a possible
here I just a couple quick slides on on
myself
I got to do some fun things I meaning
for me on the news to you
kinda owning everything that I like to
touch I and us that wasn't running
congress
okay although most times by the
Democratic Party they don't like me at
all
MuscleNerd amor Doctor Who fan
I like hugging cuddling and I was in
Paris and few other places
I was a marine I like to blow stuff up
lot of things to guns am also one of the
sexiest
Iron Man Alive apparently as it does not
photoshopped that is 100 percent
what was on TV now the funny part about
this is that saddam
when when I was on TV as another in the
United States come to Katie Couric show
and a out on session funny mediating
shown
a little later I got time but I IBC got
done
packing into arm someone in the audience
is computer an able to webcam and I was
looking at her daughter and stuff like
that and and also stuff
and there is an actor coming up next in
if you know the show Sherlock
others again income up assets like the
actor and so said
up next won the World sexism in lebanon
then remove the up next in Tennessee
defeated right there and then it just
left that with my picture up there
so I'm keeping it i like it like to
think I'm gonna
my title sexy
and most importantly letting our friends
and meeting new people so
you know is always great that talk and
hangout folks here in last night we had
a great time in Switzerland
I'm so it's always great to get to see
friends and hang out and party
out don't get to do a lot more always
traveling a lot so today
you know that this talk you know I look
at education awareness programs a lot of
companies and and I think education when
it's been a really big focus for
a number organizations because it's
really important
see a lot of attacks happening through
fishing or social engineering or
whatever you
you want to call it and you know the
techniques that we use in industry
aren't the same
what we see in a while and what's
interesting is our education awareness
programs are based off how we test
as and testers are as researchers or
whatever
and so for me personally we have to
shift the dynamics of how we do things
on in pen testing and social engineering
everything else to emulate what we see
out there in the wild what's going to be
coming up later on
and you know I've been doing a lot of
the stuff you know I
it was funny when when I first got into
you on the security issue at work for on
the record in intelligence i'd and I got
out and social engineering wasn't really
a big thing you know known as we doing
as far as a
partner Pentastar know companies were
focusing on education awareness was a
huge threat around teaching uses around
security
we really change a lot which is a great
thing we really have to focus on making
it the right type of
research right up education because
without that gonna get on for a long
time
and there's no way to stop everything is
no question about that we can deftly do
things that at least attacked
certain things must like you do on the
network side and so today I'm gonna be
you know so you can we do for education
awareness what we're talking to cation
awareness
on what we do is paint astor's kinda
blowing all out on the water
and on the show you some some cool are
techniques the new version above the
social engineers architects just
released our version 6.0 to
I yesterday was funny I'm you this was
given a talk on
on how to protect against jobs anybody
in any see that one few people great
so in the middle this presentation one
of his defensive mechanisms was to you
on
arm remove the header are the user agent
string PC user it's your job to deny it
so I rewrote the Java applet another
user 83 now the emulator explore so the
job happen now calls out via Internet
Explorer
and now you you know got around to data
released a new version 6.0.2 yesterday
don't turn it awkwardly with typical so
fun times
so you know we have today now starting
off I'm gonna water or talk are we were
taught
when water really works and there was
gonna mess and stop of America thrown a
lot a misconception that we use like for
example in my favor wants to do
on is innocent exploitation you look at
you know I guess the latest and greatest
sexy exploit and it's very difficult to
fire off an exploit on organization
like for example on a compromise with a
knife easier day I need to do a lot of
research in Homer
beforehand to make sure I understand
what version they have to they have
things like
and installed or whatever protection
mechanisms them place and
most organizations is already had the
same exact version of IE across your
entire organization
no right so you're limited on on your
attack surface and we're actually gonna
go after
and so for me personally I don't ever
really reliable exploits anymore to
compromise an organization
II use methods that there are legitimate
that I know if they have certain things
install on I can take advantage of that
without actually triggered something
like is your day or an exploit
and be honest with you you know in the
real-world scenarios the chances of you
getting burned by is your day a very
small
your most people want to burn is your
day and you because what you have
so we'll talk about different techniques
that you can use it if the a lot of the
stuff that's out there were gonna we're
gonna get around things like application
whitelisting were you in a row next
generation firewalls gonna get around
arm hope to see an america that's the
kind of joking and suffering on
will get around anything they can
possibly imagine I'll get on and it will
get around everything
nominees in this topic bacall and
additionally my favorite one
they were taught which is the harbor
right so we're all taught that you know
if you get a email you can watch
Survivor hover over a link to make sure
that it's legit
you hover over a link it's good right
over to defeat the hopper today to
so gonna get around 100 on and actually
no compromise people with a legitimate
link that
looks legitimate but as we go into my
bedside so look at today's
fishing we sent hundreds of emails or
whatever
sometimes got misspellings really
sensitive because we don't wanna
to arm no impact emotions inside a
people's organizations
and we train people on on who click
stuff that you click something may go to
like a a website says hey
you publish an eclectic here's a nice
video on on things that you should look
for is an indicator right that's kinda
far
education once today in what's
interesting about this concept here is
you this is pretty much universal across
the board were gross what country and
wherever missus can a white
are de facto you know education
witnesses if we go with things like
you know I'm companies that provide
services fishing and you know education
awareness is pretty much what you get
and what's interesting you know when we
do arm so sincere Spearfish is for
organizations special the first time
I warned I glisten our fish is gonna
piss people off
people are going to be really hurt and
upset and they're gonna be yelling and
screaming
we need to understand this is for the
right purpose an STD this one you go
through all the shit
after that make it a lot easier if you
do it over and over and over again to
let your
key people know like BP's and stuff like
that because of those the ones that
usually throw a big because if it
especially like in person in each arm
stuff like that
on but really you know it's it's for the
better
now this is today right real-world
if I'm gonna go after company I'm going
to target a few people like two or three
max
so I'm gonna do fish I'm going in a
senate like two or three people that I i
kno have high confidence level that you
click on something that all target
folks that are necessary technical savvy
all got it. people right I go after
arm you know folks in sales for Human
Resources I want my favorite ones I did
a while ago
are someone in the eye on this company's
website and I'm still looking at the
press releases
an inner city had a point to contact
person that was there
on coordinator for all other
communications for me D and things like
that
they just released the a big player
post-a_b_c_ said
you know hey we were celebrating 100
years arm as being an american-based
company
you know billions of dollars in revenue
we've grown so much we're so excited
about this
so I took all the information I was in a
press release on the times gonna build a
fish office right
as the first thing I did as hiii
register domain name that was like from
Mike
no news media dock on or something I got
a sensor Newman like here's why let you
know
are you know we're going to do a story
on this and I think you know you know if
you guys are really awesome it's a good
testament to have a us-based company you
know all this other stuff
and so assessor email and she
immediately respond back to me know what
is that when he not tell me
don't think technically not technical
was 11 email from a person inside a
company tommy
whose address is that person I the
persons info but most importantly the
template other e-mail right
to 90 that their know the name their
title the colors at the use the phone
number schemes everything right just
that reason alone
is everything that I need to start
building something sent from their adult
a fish
that basically set up the press release
that was in their format exact form and
PDF attached that you have an expert on
now
no need to
the by doing that you can do whatever
you want you so
you basically have the right to do
anything at that point because it looks
legitimate
send any of the three people that was it
three it was a stupid fisher's like it
they want to do you like increase person
wants their worry about are making
people man
so Zr was a celebration of the hundred
years of being in this organization a
hundred years above a testament to our
employees and everything else
so were the first 100 people get
a free iPhone near the leasing greatest
at the time as the 4s right
and so when the colony when they got to
see me I listen to the three people
head like 300 people responsible people
forget to each other inside the bank
are inside the company to get it to come
back to make the sweet
so I like shells raining coming back in
everything actually people are like
in a row after a while they decide the
block in everything and and and we
remove their shells of to our systems we
still had access to infrastructure
the best part was like the ladies like
lady emails us at the email address to
send the United healing
hey our IT people blocked it assesses
security threat how can I get around
this
and I might although not as good as new
Secretary all you guys are so helpful
thank you so much we got hurt you
an arm was the worst ones about this was
I I got an email from a lady as they
I just love this company she's like my
daughter is so sick right now we can't
afford to get an iPhone in it this is
gonna make your life you know because
she's you know
cancer and also something like oh my god
I como worst person ever and swirls I
want bought an iPhone anyway
like the only person I've on iphone 4
arm but you know he's got a yetta
gonna test things out and just simple
stuff he can do as long as believable
but again only targeting a couple people
right
only in customizing it for that
organization when you look at a company
they bleed information the cutest girl
in 10 and it tells you everything about
a company like
hey we just implement our site or hey we
just implemented as you know the
specific PC technology are we had this
happen at a virus we do this we do this
to me
they give you everything about
organization because we all love
bragging about ourselves
link in my favorite I can have my entire
print how much your your
your modernization program it or who use
your MSSP
all that stuff is things that I need to
know before actually attack you we
profile on you do it
as we need to focus on on in an real
fish were also some examples
to look at today's training we go
through
I
to typically only online CBT training on
its boring a cell like I was a chief
security officer for ER fortune 1000
company United States
and you know i close to the CBD so Mike
Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next
Next finish no internet security there's
no way I'm going to the action that
stuff
is terrible maybe a one-day training
session if you're lucky
on like you have a guy in person session
they do training around I maybe he's a
third party
issue whatever but that's kind of what
we do for training arm
for our users you know when it comes to
online tree type stuff real-world
training
know if you look at some education
awareness you actually if thats haz
your users usually go out and say listen
we're going to attempt to go after nine
until mantle after
and you go after them you tryin train
all year long you to make it fun to
on like I do a lot of things with
training I wasn't at
and evil where we actually like Apple
people come and speak
we have make giveaways raffles we
related people
my favorite ones was you know like how
to protect yourself a facebook how to
protect your home wireless
protector kids when people can relate to
that at their home they start to do it
on the corporate side and let's not the
secular cells nobody inside an
organization
non-security cares about the company's
data the song care
occurs hours one fish that we did on
which are gonna sales guy
and the sales guy was like I'm like a
man can you going down as far as a
cashier easy I'm getting a virus warning
my daughter's right click on fire since
topping exit
is it okay cool here something exits me
runs and I get access to make a key to
the company's key just haven't seen the
type you can fit a candidate on issues
of warning rain is want to sale
they don't care about what you're
actually doing on and so it made him
realize that
are much clearer today is like a quick
drops were still doing USB drives
really that like the most ridiculous
things like 1984 shit
like I mean are abused his route then
but something like that right
run into but I mean autorad already
disabled anyway
I in most cases most organizations and
this is even still work understand you
speed drops
personally when I love doing is when you
actually go after company
use the mail system because the mail
system you can be anybody want you can
be an executive in that company to be
whomever
he read a nice a letterhead with your
company name on whoever your purse
meaning having do like step by step how
much to do they will do whatever you
want to because you can be anybody
watching hand-written letter or
you know letter had already sent to them
in the mail to send something the mail
knobs on the getting is just a turn at
the show's waiting though do everything
for you like
hey you need to go on update this and
you gotta go dollars fell double
clicking Ron
Hicks after okay good on you know you do
whatever you want in a leader's one-time
armory modified a keyboard I with the
TENS unit okay
and sucking on it in this arena basis
tiny and we we open at the back to this
keyboard
and I'll be soldered to tens device onto
it in line on
arts never too so we can you know
capture keystrokes all that what's been
done
but was awesome is when they were he
would be sent a letter head from a
company thing as part of a refresh
program this is now your new keyboard
plug it in news and everything else and
so we did is we
we did for the control to the sequence
and we captured using a password okay
and then you wait like until our there
was no key sequences type on the
keyboard
for about eight hours what does that
mean gone or something right
and meetings are gone home we detected
that it would who Jigga Jigga mouse
because you keep working late in the
head
and I'm so little mouse over scream come
on you take control
leader log with using a passer in and
drop a appealing to the system
government machine
do you really want to he will do
anything you want in the mail
awesome might drive USB device anyway so
still picking up USB devices and
plugging men and double-click any
seized up problems 1990s problems on
as the in person sees my my favorite
right so a season person
and person in delivery people in person
employees piggybacking I mean we we
started a so sophisticated look for
James Bond
Lake you know you know busting into
buildings evading security systems when
I need to do is just wanted to fund or
an act like you own the place and do
whatever you wanted
right system the key concepts we do
today
real-world make it easy simple you know
don't do anything crazy
on really you really need to using the
proxy MARTA bus in the buildings
this is an example I was doing a on a
physical for AR
a store store location for big retailer
chain United States
and literally Sosa Mike bogeys our
trophies to get for the organization was
to steal on one other point of sale
systems you know so they have a point
you love the points are returned in the
point of sale system in everything
and so the like a hypodermic on all of
it out
in so when I first started I certainly
sophisticated like I
I spoke by phone number coming from you
know this corporate headquarters and I
called and I said hey I have two
technicians coming in
miss you brother hard everything we we
meet you know I'm sure that look like
we're from the corporate headquarters in
everything
really sophisticated right did you do
any that so it gets
me seventeen store location with a Taser
this one works you know just fine
literally the second store I walked into
the store like
just dress like this walking to the
store I walked up to the register
at took the whole thing I walked on the
building now that
no one said anything on star me I just
don't have the cash in everything
there's like you know
two grand in cash in it I was supposed
to take about 30 cool
right something else they have good have
a good day
is this heavy duty I'm using is prolly
eighty pounds on Mike walk-up start
school
no problem don't have to do any crazy
sophisticated Sears or teacher users
right
I on the phone don't provide certain
information card each axis activity
eccentric Center what's great is it
could be anybody I mean phones moving is
obviously very is my six-year-old can do
it I
you could be anybody the company one
thing to be aware of those
impersonating somebody to the company
don't call her best friend it one day I
we're doing a a fish in this mutha phone
number and said hey we have two
contractors coming into one the book
obviously the data center
and so we'll you know my kids you look
at you guys into the data center blah
blah
is a good you you say you were my all
this is Paul like nope on our best
friends and he's like down the hall from
me
and I click you know sir get a carefully
impersonate but if you do you're
you protection especially could be
anybody wants on the phone it's great
easy stuff
not sophisticated now email
is my favourite users are taught the
harbors my favorite one of them all
because the harbor is like everything in
a secret organization I see Harbor
when you hover over a link it's got to
be a legit right you see that
that
however this league is going to gmail
dot com or whatever right it's legit
right you're good
that sort of trying need to be that
are you saying yes now you know before
stock in
but I mean your check domain name look
for suspicious activity center /center
center
so on the talk about arm set version
6.0.2 number to play a little game
okay and and this game is going to be
something more ominous show you two
scenarios
attack in your income how to defend
against so with the with the new version
ascetic senator listen
you know the lot of cool stuff and said
I can cover all
but this really cool stuff though just
that insanity that really proud of on
but really you know set design be havin
use that to you perform any type of
a fishing the new on attack vectors and
they're really provide a
high level of success I mean it's really
to test the effects on your program
which is that we're talking about here
insists that's the Arco die I rode arm
during you talkin pushed out that I does
the new user agent string
and one in one thing I was on costs on
his licence s just at all
and how you actually look an
organization hierarchy profound revision
what you actually build
is what's gonna make it successful just
using the stuff are set
I don't recommend build your stuff and
do it the right way because without it
is just a tool
you're just using its all your tool
right
so you know the proper a sense read on
homework researcher target know your
target
on develop your tax and based on what
you're going after mean that's what I do
you
that's what you have to do you have to
build a fantasy my whole goal was of
Engineering
is to make you believe something it's
completely bullshit right has no
relevance whatsoever is completely fake
but they have to believe it so we make
something a little bit writer good
just a demo
accuracy is OK screen good so this
attack was originally arm
are committed are by my name engines and
white Jeep who did this
on attack in Scala web checking attack
now the new version of set 6 entered
on 680 woman was released takes it to
conduct a whole new level it's friggin
amazing right
and I mess up the credit and white
cheaper for put this in there is is
really slick
as orders wanna go to the social
engineer on the tag when US number one
and wanna go to the website actors which
number two okay
now number two you're gonna slacks on
the web checking matter which number
five and i won a close eye on what's I
will do the trick on any website you
want to
okay so whether it's trust it's like
that calmer gmail or whatever company
you're targeting
you can clone anything you want to also
you can import your own
you make your own fake website or
whatever you can import that as well was
to say Connor
and then we're gonna do
II gonna are to my IP address in now
we're recommending this attack and we're
gonna see is just a really simple
example
wanna build this out I make it look
legitimate in every way
right and all registered to mean that's
very similar to it not swim in a
second-round defeat that
but we still want to make the user
interaction processes
as less suspicious as possible so no my
resume name for demonstration purposes
are not going to
and I was callin gmail now
resent to Gmail scott is a form yes
forms on it she could do whatever it has
a user and pass a problem times real
ones are like BP ends or exchange or
anything that's outward facing I like
benefits web pages for for customers
I was great to is like we send this
Michelle you can be like
telling them specific instructions like
me sure you hover over this link to make
sure is legit
make sure you do this initiation and by
the way make sure you're using a pass
for the log into your Windows machine
with
great its you give me instructions
everything you need to do
make it easy form because they're gonna
they're not gonna know so this is just a
a simple login field here
and sonic on the website
animals everything to you on the patchy
so under hard every time I W now what I
would do at this point one cyclone it is
that the web so you can see here's the
second
is really simple right so was critical
issue as good as real quick alright
that's not right
was messin means can become a cash
reporters caster
actually
and others stricken
I'm there
so not notice is a very basic site okay
when I would do is a very simple
is some of our make it look believable
onerous you perform
okay make it look like a legitimate say
make it look good in hearsay
make sure that you're going to a trusted
sec location making sure going to
dislocation when you hover over this
link
is we want to make sure that you don't
give fished read this could be a
phishing scheme or
the officials like these techniques
makes you hover over the link and miss
you validate what you're all you're
going to
I now again this is looking
look nice and pretty for whatever doing
I'm again benefits from years ago gray
wanna going after benefits website
things like that in the United States
on the common with the use or any to
affect sleep is important now look what
happened hover over this was assayed on
in the bottom left bc it's a little bit
big can you see that and we see that
its HTTPS call on 44 slash
accounts doc Google dot com is that the
jet
you're ready before I start talking
think that's a jet
yeah so again accounts dots
Google dot com right so it's legit right
so we click on this we should go to
accounts I go back on right
don't want to click on this link I want
you to watch what happens live within
the euro bar
is it going to be another tab opened
interaction gonna be at account at
google.com
iight your machine is actually in a
contact the council gonna come server
them into a quick switcheroo I without
any user interaction ready
so click it no magic unaccountable a
complex issue
to my username enter your password in
I'm redirected back to legitimate site
and over here
we got these and password game tell
Kenya
free messed up I was a lil dirty
about about that actually sister being
harbored
the next you're gonna see is the job app
attack in this guide the flagship attack
vector and Sat now
resides on the job app attack is because
it doesn't take advantage
I love any to exploit it doesn't use any
specific exploit in Java anything else
to take advantage of the great thing
about Apple its once the run
is the run unrestricted there's no
Sandboxie at the break out a there's
nothing you actually attacks were you
little in running a full access my
computer
now the new version is set actually has
predictive analysis
to see what the best method expectation
is so if you're running Windows 7 or
Windows just above
it does probability ratio say this in
the best run to attack based on what you
have installed as this method I'm gonna
use that as a matter for exportation
so it's mister of things that power
shower Excel back doors or
on using the Adobe scripture whatever
this multiplex petition at this address
procedures Windows XP is gonna try
Windows XP sp2 schmitz versus can
identify power shot in the arm on the
machine
and a partial injection my favorite
attack in all this is that our
again a meta Graber was a rough a
nominal partial guy came out the ability
to inject
arm of a commercial Cochrane to memory
so you have the ability through
PowerShell natively
to inject into r Memory completely
transparent without touching desk which
is really important
special for going after things like
application whitelisting or
is a memory now sISTAR it's great for
and what's great about this is I did a
talk at Def Con like
17 or something like that on partial
beta came out and when the first talks
impartially figure out how to get around
work on execution restriction policies
so they're letting us for different
excuse research and policy on all sin
sin
on remote in unrestricted or some other
chick unrestricted
and on even with the most restrictive on
execution research and policy can still
execute Power Shot machine and and
bypass execution restriction policies
so what happens in in the job app on
here on is it actually compromise is it
purely memory so there's no
touching the decision on our droppers
anything like that and they're also
on dozen Christian so it actually puts
an ASU his bubble in memory
around your show go so when it pops out
coming back in in a good performance
when I
so go to
number one wanna go to website expected
number two
and when he got a job applicant number
one and there were a cyclone number two
and ask everything at a port forwarding
man had no
to my IP address real quick and
I mean he's my own job at Apple which is
number two now
with Java 7 update 42 I believe
they remove the ability to use of signed
a jar Java happens
and the reason for that is because they
are inherently insecure has been a whole
progression economic seven years to do
this
are but what's great is that you can
literally do on register in this in the
US the cigarette's are as follows: a DVR
doing business as
which is like 30 bucks minutes go by
coaching search by the DB is a flake
verified publisher this this is a
legitimate up ap lit you know this is
secure please trusted you did you busy
as whatever you want to
and then used by coating certain is
legit so everybody in the wilds doing so
just
spent a couple box go get it goes
unanswered and then boom you have a
really believable
on fish their work on any platform
what's great about this I'm technique to
is again it does one expert but it gets
around too much every preventive measure
the nova gets run National Fire also
gets around
on application whitelisting its run
antivirus gets around
you know everything awesome possum and
challenging our technology the OP
rebels were deputy prevention general
but on
gets run almost awesome see a high
probability success so we had to use app
a number two
now when a clone distrust sacbee.com is
an example
to clone it
and here we have on payload options now
appeal options are kinda interesting
these were only trigger and fire
on if the other exportation methods feel
like power Shawn Jackson Excel injection
on eccentric centers or a fall back to
this is a very last mechanism
on if there's a buy on these are all ABC
can I get started yet or bombing and
picked up
my favorite to use like a multi-part
injectors number sixty
im occupy injector what you can do as we
know any compromise an organization
you don't know unless you already diary
con what poor co-opt rights egress
filtering
so modify jacks you can have a spray
multiple ports
you want to do if you don't be too loud
you can have a try 21 23 25
you know 80 443 and see which ones go
out you can also use Metasploit
is to be an easy PSP lot so that the
proxy where which is great so you can
use multi project is free on multiple
ports
and and when you get a are at home in
addition use modify injector
it automatically configures the partial
injection same way so when you export a
miss and video machines can use the same
type of show code
spree on multiple ports via power shawna
that works then it's not going to
execute the miners
on additionally with with with these
these these actual binaries a good drops
are nothing CNN com does nothing
inspected a guy ya 12v of firearms my
dad doesn't do anything
nothings to buy nor does nothing just
runs and exits however
you provide ates 256 the block
with a dynamic cipher key which gets
generated every single time and Sat
know the Antichrist all of that shoko to
run the show good for you you get around
things like fire on
I get as low as that which is beautiful
so there were 15
and others use a on its over Baylor
this is an example and identically Pasha
show perot times does not actually
generating mess which open every time
so I have all the shock on this damn he
passed with your IP address and port
on it before is a faster and that's not
what minutes late
and over here we're gonna go to our
website
notice it looks just like trust attack
in every way shape or form
right looks good an the Name field you
can make whatever you want
obviously I like ghosts on some in my
goats on
you can name the name feel whatever you
want to see it had to be the company
makes enter Sedra
the publishers what you don't have
control over so
that's where you would register doing
business as in the biosensor for
whatever targeting
so to get a doing business as any code
signing certificates but two days
alright because you have to register the
disaster today and
to get a verification call of that
you're doing but doing business as from
the phone numbers related to you
takes about a day as well again because
I think certain two days on in the
Polish community want to get that I own
like verified publisher
are trusted publisher this this Apple is
secure whatever you want in
doing business whatever the hell you
want to make a difference great in Iran
know what happens is it redirects you
back in the gym inside
so that the on victim doesn't know that
they're at a bushes in the first place
so now you're back in the genocide you
go back over here
unity have two shells now there is only
two shells as I i'm is a fallback option
and Sat
though they'll say listen still run the
peelers macias reliable exploitation
case something goes wrong so a lot and I
the pipe out two shots and $1
just make sure can sometimes get weird
issues with our communication transport
you see here we have a mature personals
so in essence the computer through that
and we can run exploit nice boy them
every re: stuff easy
you know issue of asset was set up
is this a couple minutes right long as
you did the rekon had time to find a way
russia targeting
and made a big enough pre-tax like tell
them about the applic to listen in order
to verify that your company owned asset
or computer you need to
run the Apple it that says you know
company name security check
call don't run build that stuff into
your pre-tax
they will do anything you want them to
you Moscow
area okay through play game
okay many requires audience interaction
I'm gonna give you a list the multiple
choice or talk about how to fix these
issues because our way stopping is that
attacks
so medium of choice ABC new you tell me
which one
it's going to be this could be the best
solution to pick multiple ones too okay
so for the job Apple attack specifically
as we just saw now
was that was the easiest way above
getting ready all the bar very good sir
very good
yes sir that is correct now for real
though
on
sorry had a good time last night I
a stock recovers energy efficient sir.
are so ABC or D ABC or D
all the above very good yes so all the
above minus
right so a dislikes kitchen tap
they'll stop are most now our my most
now rescued from tap it also stops job
updates by the way
on the job requires a time trying to run
again most horrible thing ever
on BAE dis allies accuse in from all
user profiles
again are commonplace for execution from
our now in sets
that will stop the binary dropper piece
because it uses temp the temp directory
never see all you fuckers using it I'm
gonna change the directory so to be
something different next time
but in the right now no one's ever
stopping times or to be as great anyway
so right now if you buy time to stop by
not driving portion
now see disallow regular users execution
partial
on Ryan in a and Windows Group Policy
actually have application whitelisting
built in a Group Policy
Scott app Locker it's free an app Locker
we can do is you can say
I do not want regular users from running
power to run Powershot in disallowing
you do at all with the group also right
now which means that the PowerShell
injection taking the just saw doesn't
work
really simple thing doesn't break into
any reviews every year a partial on the
user's
now so really quick we're doing it arm
10 jobber security possible
I one thing is arm you can actually
strip Apple Tachibana talk about that
yeah so most proxy support on work a
whitelist sites right
secundus allow Apple to mining from from
arm from actual HTML on pages
and that's why list I'm so things like
Cisco WebEx things in your wireless as
well as those
and a slow apples from everything else
you can actually rewrite rules to
sorry right Apple tax just replace was
something else in the Apple never
execute but you know what that nothing's
fool-proof I should ways a by passing
arm excuse restriction policies I'm
circumvent app Locker
on also run PowerShell code
on when ap lockers being restricted but
again as like more like a defense and up
stranger and multiple layers of security
which are the tribe's after getting to
be honest the on the box you want it'll
stop set
which is great arm this is a quick point
apricot
I think it's not hard to see visible
Picasa I got around on tap water with
this is our wanna hear once called the
magic Unicorn Attack
eyes itself free tools open source I get
home it was nice but this is where you
actually generates
on the power shostak usual stuff or he's
just a quick example to show you
so is very sexy
so I run your are you going to you I
uses of
uniform Union
there now area
I'm having some major I promptly man
okay ever happen for Iran unicorn
specify what people you want to you it
automatically generate the
the shocker for you and then it'll pipe
your shell back on the sport in this
on this this IP in sport what's great
about this is literally gives you the
copy in patients whose
the SEO are shell summer-like of a lot
I'm still using PS EXEC commands
and I'll put this into here not
piece/pieces commandments pointed to it
and it runs power Sean all the systems
for you get your shot without touching
desk
it's a little early for the strongest
man right here
my IP 343
an automatic into the shop on for me
it'll
export democrats RC five minutes before
you so I just wanna mess Boyd
mister Council Sr
unicorn RC that alone at the same time a
copy paste Michelle career
so here we have a show code arm its its
encoded began around excuse research
policies
and you see here that's just a man right
there just a command the paste into
a command prompt or whatever you back CD
a remote code execution
you just highlight this and their
leaders pasted in
sober person here this is an example
obviously in expectation scenario you
might have shell is based in the command
prompt an answer
as I suppose to happen
are some
some having is how it at all
America echoes
and capital thing so they overhear
yourself again not touching this handing
out early member resident running on the
process PowerShell
and you back to the computer was great
and other fun trick
and I'll use another way are is
like a monitor and you would allow the
next generation firewalls what they do
is nation firewalls are literally like
anti-virus for the network
that's that's it there they basically
right signatures at the dog behavior on
houses and stuff like that
but you make any changes or
modifications anything next generation
you're gonna get around it okay and so
what this is I want overkill on and
never have to use this because we're so
shitty any UN Security
they don't ever have to worry about
doing all this crazy stuff are but in
the event that we someday good
all releases on and what it does is it
takes mature printer
shoots in the memory case is over and he
estimates bubble
tunnels it over SSH over st. Pius
innocence polymorphic so every single
get post responsiveness these can be
completely dynamic every single time
I'm so you gonna see it basically tunnel
wanna do
I'm runnin so it just waiting for first
initial
on HTTPS connection then gonna
our check to see if there's a specific
unique code is generated and then from
there
its gonna dandy crib deaths each time
over local host and create app interface
for us
that we now have an answer for sale its
all ok on on the system itself
so worried here for the record the shell
I run this
so it's gonna argue member injection
can inject into memory for your in a
capsule in SHRs
a sleepy opting for their own IP address
and RS is it running
attack face one second rerun again
over here when triggers you see it
actually turn on here
the second secret identified sending
chancellor for response
verify watching Metasploit right now add
credit app interface are over that is
assist on all over its BS and then we
should have a shell in your notice that
the show's actually to be at
127 001 because we're telling over local
host
as a shell 127 001
rent hot stuff
as proxy or two it's great
I'm so expanding on that your point
after the powers of deduction
a receipt is added in version 6.0 doubt
one
arm one the most common techniques that
was given to you are single servers
and physical servers most common
technique is to you on the bed
are talking tough guy like that Khan 14
or something on-base you taking
inexcusable
converting it to you have to dust pollen
and basically pushing through
are Microsoft's economy can bring about
a binary on instead we used to use the
magic unicorn tech now
are within Microsoft CEO Nick cash to
direct power Shawn Jackson through
makers are seeking to show
I'm so that's a new version 6.1 our city
find
single serve you can use partial
injection for it again shelter Microsoft
sequel
so what checking the hard-won
are a three-city 30 what do you think
what are the
easiest way to stop it a BNC
so AB and C education awareness some
technological controls and sector
Uncategorized I'll talk more than a
second
I hear something to ponder what you
doing us on education awareness is key
me teaching people you know certain
things look for on this was really tough
because I look believable
two factor authentication as good I'm a
favor one artifact authentication is
when I
use an iPhone factor for infected my
favorite own your phone factor alone you
every single time period no question
about it and the reason for that is
because you literally implemented
two-factor authentication this trend as
we can possibly imagine because you put
the air back onto the human as long as a
question the use of actor before
try to not earning on there's a lot on
like this
will do is when you login with username
password that I just Fisher whatever it
has a prompt and says
I'm sending a verification tax or
calling your whatever to verify your
what is that use are gonna do every
single time I am
I'm probably login summer now yes I've
been on 8 individual pentasa form factor
I have not once had a unsuccessful
attack everybody's always said yes
that's me logging in
horrible so you put it back onto the
users emissions rake
are too good
on to a really good tobacco litigation
Uncategorized sites
on Uncategorized sites are official
letter Miami things like skin safe
arm Bluecoats on all them have
Uncategorized side
margins and those are were ninety
percent officials come from
people don't spend the time to actually
register the names and the Bluecoat or
arm you know skin safe as a
categorization sites be blocked those
usually stop by ninety percent officials
now funny story about this when the air
tommy was a
on you can actually clone one of the
major on what cattle terms on web sites
looking clone their own website
and it's a minute for proven actually
put you up as a content filtering
software company
it's ridiculous on
miss you should have access I am it's a
good 1i think about a kilometer
yesterday
artillery is one that's all that I wrote
has more on the defensive side any more
information
just gonna break down for not using it
really recommended
on I'm it can be easily bypassed it's
very very very easy to bypass and
I clearly the five controls you have in
place requires me to do a call on
senator return
at so I'm using robber made you a call
from religion to function
on API instead of doing a return
ones that this is an example though on
position but this your day is an easier
day I'm is it actually looks for the I'm
a daddy lol
of I'll never found it actually kill its
other one run so it's gonna need
so there are some good to get tougher
time any recommended but again it's
really trivial
offer for us to be able to read
something about it very trivial
so talk about fixing stuff we have to
stop the 1990s attacks
we have to focus on getting an education
that really works in it entertaining
people
are starting to believe in security now
is we're like the harpley stuff happen
right already seen on the news and other
stuff we're getting more by often we
ever have in history into a sec it's
phenomenal
we have to capitalize on that mission
people understand the ramifications
and some other ways to begin and armed
with the do things that relate to others
relate to people because a personalized
for me for me when I was in-charge about
the ski program into
knows a 30,000 employees shop on
the most important thing for me was
involved in management wasn't pen
testing
whose education awareness like if I can
mess any money period
in a in an organization wouldn't be on
Patch Manager
when being mean doing wrong as important
things would be focusing on education
awareness because it is to me
on the struggle pieces once I had in
Education honors program
to implement something Mac or something
else was trivial if you understood why I
was doing I wasn't that bad security guy
trying to ruin their lives with making
things more restrictive
years ago he remember them talking about
this the relation to protect us at
school
so it has multiple benefits aside from
just what we're talking about here
so if you look at building a program you
know according to Schneider
I and we disagree with them on this one
but he doesn't believe in Education
honors programs i think is effective
he said ass accused me through attrition
and through what you do as far as your
actions
I disagree on the first thing is you
know
creating a group on the Celtic Executive
Committee mean yet by often the top
levels American to build about
arm and then once you actually have a
program start building it out actually
do about on talk about securities known
right now cares about it I
when you build the program they'll calm
I mean I do a lot of fun stuff we did
talk ass in our company
I would equally newsletters out there
were videos we do like fun skits and
things like that the kinda keep
entertaining
arm be needed related information
employees like when target happen great
example
he is been a big target reach you could
be impacted you know should do this
issue this year this
looking after people big difference I
and then last you know step three is
really just testing the program actually
going in and seeing what you doing how
effective you are actually stopping
different types of attacks we need to
improve on
it's like any other program that you had
with the test arm and then lastly
you know deftly min team the promise of
mom
sorta kinda build out everything they
need to you to talk about this I'm gonna
skip to this part here
coming out I'm but are you nation
products to me are
are just a bunch of watch it doesn't
stop us as attackers and I
my funny arm thing about a national
finals let me ask a question
does anybody have enough money for
security SP program
me enough people the ski program unseen
hands okay
to this question we have only bring a
whole brand new PC technology in
you slap in what happens you introduce a
whole new set up one occurs if the whole
grains and complexity the fullerene
me it means a similar question you have
these guys have been ASA engineers for
ten years
right their phenomenal ASA
knobs on the panache in for one was
gonna happen there
the learn a whole new piece technology
seriously miss question is anybody doing
network segmentation environments
like make each are going to feature near
their specific things York apartment as
a shrine in the basics that women or
assets are at long why we in action
viral were well had are well below
we need to run out even be thinking
about this type of stuff we need to
focus on the basic things first
on some really cool stuff real quick arm
so election cool things
and I like it like like the build stuff
I'd on my big hard work I so
I was messing up horribly so i've a
funny story show arm
basically I've got a new Jeep you
cracker in this is my fourth generation
my
Jeep you cracker that a bill and saw got
a lot better since the first for
are Rev and the the fourth one so here's
the second time to be built and
I was actually really horrible on and
it's funny cuz like this he think you're
the metal hook on it
and actually sliced my finger in a drip
blood all over the mother born
so I take that back and explain like
aids to schema blood on it I don't know
what happened
on BBC here though the way that it he
thinks earning us the bad design because
it blows their on
pretty bad ways we bring those cards up
pretty quick third attempt as this one
on and so this reason the the video to
ninety axes
arms you know that was a the only good
one as early as it sounds
arm I wanna go big or go home right and
so
those are of 40 1990 axes liquid-cooled
and our getting about ninety billion
passwords for second right now
answering crackin anchored the passer in
a few seconds things like that was only
well
on this or my favorites I want to do and
it was funny but this one
is %ah when I first got this of
you know we like to play jokes on each
other and stuff like that and
I desire to say to make it was called P
contest so we couldn't p.m. till the
whole thing's lead with about you
okay in so we sat there it took us 12
hours
12 hours to get a bunt on the same so
love Ubuntu black screen don't have an
small black screen
bone or anything nothing just that right
to my account got a different version
due to a reason same thing black screen
spent 12 our senators on my way to pee
really bad
whose like listen man we'll get this in
the next hour literally gonna
die so it's probably a good idea that we
just not of that will mostly almost we
didn't
for some reason I decided to put a DVD
Drive on this is no reason for me to put
a TV drama never use a DVD Drive not be
called have a DVD Drive in here
soon as I am flooded or fine 12 hours
us on his back yet
no 32 gig Corsair Dominator only
daughter after the steps of palm CT
terabytes barracudas
this rampage this rampage NASCAR's has
four double wides
so you can fit on the %uh the pews in
there on and with our nine darling
calling you to the space
on is only 15 on what UGA supernova
which is nice
and surrogate 90 points are three
billion passes for second and the lamb
picnic here to passage last 20 minutes
acres in two seconds 33
a message or not so we have a on 20 amp
circuit and apparently that blows a 20
amp circuit
so be careful when you build this thing
both answer
anybody any questions well thank you
very much for having a really appreciate
it
I hope we learn something new