alright so
that's me I have some awesome kids
from I'm a
has been no hacker I don't know if you
guys know what that is and also marine
so why are we here
shouted out wise anybody here
learn we got learn light
nothing we're just we're just here to
sit in chairs
got it still laptops
awesome so
before getting team at I am I put this
together because when I was
doing all these contests I would do the
Pentastar give the report
and then the person who got the report
the cis or whoever
guy they go okay how do I fix these
things okay I told you how to fix these
things
which box do i buy to fix these things I
am
really is in a box is no there's no
wonderful solution that comes
and you pay for it most other things are
free
who's here herder he met good
more hands than normal this is awesome
so
email is you can if you haven't heard of
it it's basically this free tool
that is like a memory
down sir so he stands in front of this
this all this memory that year Windows
machine has and says no its not gonna
happen
the great thing about this is that it's
operating at a level
where most people don't really think
about
so you have buffer overflows for
instance a buffer overflow what it does
and most you guys know this I'm not
trying to tell you something the yard
no reno is it starts with
a problem in a piece of software once
that is a software
has a problem in it someone throws a
bunch of stuff in it
and it does some other stuff well the
problem is
that once it has that code execution
once you have
like where the bad guy is controlling
things
that's the problem not the software
so he might actually protects against
this
using somethings like
forced
Dec scho p
SLR all all these different protections
so
email has all these amazing protections
on it and you can
apply it via GPO and this is free so you
get all this cool stuff
it stops all the memory corruption
budget stuff so days it's great
but you can bypass it right
there's all these talks and stuff about
bypassing the net
here's another one
and you can you can take a picture that
QR code loaded up by
its fine in trust me we just talked
about trust REIT
but the problem with the
all the he met bypasses the scene out
there is they bypass one
or two or three pieces a or protections
that he met does
well the planning on
now so depending on the buffer for other
or the exploit or so
that can mean one of two things
they can either bypass some a minute and
that particular
application is either not protected by
met or it is in its only
I'll Adina couple on these protections
or they have to bypass all or months ago
so that's really hard if I am an
attacker
how much money do you think I'm going to
spend on getting into your organization
if I can just spam everyone and get into
a bun some organizations
not much unless I'm going after
something very specific
so he met is not a hundred percent
solution it's the ninety percent
solution
you can get ninety percent of dry bison
watering hole tax and all that stuff
that's going on right now
with 13 tool with you don't have to
worry about catching you can you can
stop at
as a that work for everyone
yeah no so
email we got that for free from
Microsoft and that smacks of stuff
and its windows stuff what about Java
most the job at things in under
unfortunately I'm saying this on camera
for whatever I am
mostly job things are are problems that
Sun created or
mister ellison created or Oracle created
or stuff like that
anyways I am so Java has problems that
are buffer overflows their
stupid problems in in
permissions or stuff like that so how do
you
how do you stop Java anyone ever
uninstall
it's a great honor so I put up these the
I normally get is packing that works
everyone was just patch job although it
to the newest version or good right
yeah really doesn't work in the
in a developer situation I was disable
the plugin in GPO let's just
make it so that there's all that stuff
doesn't work now works
or
the final whatever she wants to just run
Linux because Java doesn't work on Linux
right very
so everyone knows that this is
this is what all on your users
sent to every website that they go to
you
what version are dotnet the running what
version InfoPath
and all that this is all this this is
called the user agent if you haven't
seen the user agent before that
in HCV traffic and the crazy thing about
this is that this user agent
is used on all a website that goes
through but when it sees Java code
when something is written in Java for a
web application
it does something weird it sends all
that stuff
Mikes Mike softer whatever I'm browser
you use
says I don't know how to do anything
with this here Java plugin you doing a
Java plugin
since this across it says a
Java I'm gonna go through the proxy I'm
gonna request this thing
but sings it with a user-agent
thats way different than the one that
uses in the browser job W S 1.6 died 09
0:29 anyone know what we're a what
exploit works for that
about 1 626
170 45
alright anyways those shoppers regions
are
are going across the wire so why not do
something about it
so this is how it looks and this is what
I'm for
I I suggest to people block
Java at the firehall rather proxy you
even block it very simply by
going in Shiprock since a day it has
this job user-agent: don't allow
through that works for everyone
you guys are dead it's too early in the
morning right
Monday it
good excuse alright so if the user never
gets this product
then you win you never given the option
to click run
because people like Dave Kennedy have
sign their stuff
and they have the option and you know
click wrong so let's just not given that
option
we would you trust all users to
to to sign code in in your organization
always nice so this is how I said just
do it
there's two ways one you can
completely block all job user-agent: if
are all
in only allow specific exceptions
through this is worked out very large
organizations
already during this or
you can just block on the version so
like I showed it earlier that job
user-agent: shows you exactly what
version it's going
the way that I found that Iran fishing
exercises and saw hey
this job for you
regions getting shown up let me send
them that exploit this morning's your
let me sing bad actually so see that
read:
this is also three so
stop exploits the browser and they came
on
0 yes that last bullet there is no way
that I know
and I've asked a lot of people that a
attacker
can change the job the user agent before
the export kicks off
so they have to use that job usually do
there's no
ifs ands or buts about it they hacked
the user if they are pulling down code
now if they start training stuff like
I flashed a Java and stuff like that
that might change things
when and seen anyone use that yet so
after I posted a blog post on how to do
this with squid
there's a guy named easy on reddit that
said a
this works in sl2 so
user-agent: is sent across proxies
that use SSL Santana not only am i
blocking
all the memory corruption bugs with the
Met
unless they bypassed 30:40 a.m. I'm
blocking all love the job law are
problems with
with my proxy even if the attacker
decides to use SSL on their website and
trying ripped everything
I still blocking cool stuff
your the Monday
oh yeah and it helps with Max to
how many people just as a the as a a
show of hands how many people in your
organization have max on their network
right now
keeper and raced
how many have you guys put it down if
you don't have
group policy or or central management of
those
max every had McDonalds in these two
I
alright so we block all of these things
that memory corruption we bought
all this job stuff how many fishing
arm exploit or targets can you think of
that
are in those two groups 0
so not solved all your client I Klein
exploitation
problems right alright
so next topic on talk about is
is kinda one that's been be to death on
every other talk that I've ever seen
first one
one that I don't see very many people
talking about
is if PW don't is removed
from your I ask box in your DMZ is that
the end of the solution
is like if its
if you're AV guy comes up to you and
says hey all these things got moved
you like great job well done
no
if they got there somehow just PW dumb
doesn't just magically appear on I asked
boxes and lustrous john Ryley put it
there
I
so less let's start working on getting
all love the actively remove things
looked at and
and assessed log are learning
how many people in this room right now
have
something and fries that logs and alerts
on
successful log on the terms
to 3 BS you just raise your hand now
so
a tiara plus news is the only one that I
know thats paid in this whole talk
idiotic forces the only true that I've
ever seen that does is cause I was on a
pen test
and I'd successfully fish
into this organization Guardian
I started using the local admin Hashim
got found the domain admin
started using the domain and into
authenticate other places
I used that authentication three times
Adri plus
sent email to the domain admin are
our text message to remain anon domain
admin responded that text message
change password his pattern was
instantly change
on the domain controller from his cell
phone the local admin that I also use
was also change automatically
and I was dead in the water and all over
the Longhorns
that I had done reported to him via
email
in a matter of minutes I was dead in the
water
so idiotic pluses what is it true that I
he said that he used to do that which is
amazing I haven't seen anyone else do
that
I'm sure you can do it was flunking
every other thing that a
Rafi would tell us about I
hips now
this is a little bit of a sensitive part
for me how many people in here
have some kinda host intrusion
prevention system on their computers
right now
that's kind it's hard there's like five
hands
alright how many people in their
organizations actually enable
the prevention part not as logging
missed two hands
3.5 down it's you alright so
it's really hard for someone to enable
host Intrusion Prevention actual
prevention part because
those signatures can run the gamut
and and sometimes they actually target
themselves like mccaffrey's
I'll so how do you do this effectively
well
remember the PW them for example have a
let's just turn on categories:
like if it's a hacker tool let's enable
the Convention on that he nor the rare
long gold the other you know signatures
and stuff that it detects
let's just enable the prevention on
hacker tools like netcat
evil netcat an
Monday I what a body scanning
how many
how many in this room are Penn testers K
how many vulnerability assessments
people
not want North
what's the reason and that's awesome
voted early assessments I
basically morally scanning how many how
many in this room
dont have always can do about that
alright
how many people that had done that
police can have looked through every
single one of those results
really
for awesome now the problem I see here's
is becoming more and more common
as more people moraz asians your body
scanning
by default they hire people to do those
who then
generate the reports given to the people
who own those machines they fix these
how effective is that
right so formally scanning is
is what that rule dies and many more
people in it in
that go into those results and say
PHP CGI vulnerability that
is in this module that's never enabled
not important
or chrome or inability
that nobody publishes information on
and K ever be exploited yeah
I see some people laughing me know how
it is so
we need people in front of this many
people doing voted on the reporting
instead of just sending of this
stupid little report that get generated
by the damn thing
I and if your organization
doesn't have someone to do that
if they just had the person that pushes
the button and does thing
you know gives it off your pen testers
involved
a guarantee every single pen tester
would love to see your own abilities can
alright
Milan crowdsourcing security
I'm everyone knows that crowdsourcing is
right
and UK so crowdsourcing security is
is a is an attempt to change all of your
users
that bad word into shit an idea into
someone who actually wants to help you
so how we how do we do that first
was take this this its incident
program the security is referring where
someone reports a problem
and the don't get any feedback or the
report a problem and you say okay I'll
take care
in turn into something more mcgain
so I I believe there are a couple people
with that are talking about
demarcation are a different programs I'm
stealing the thunder right now
I'll but let's turn this into a reward
program
where the top users the people who
report all these
machine exercises are these these
attempts a
breaking into your organization get
something out of it
so you say pay si ESO CEO could use
enough this email to
the company require because getting
recognition from the
CEO the company that they were the
the top three people in the organization
the reported security vulnerabilities
matters it start making a
into a game starts making into like
greedy selves that we all are
and saying I want to be recognized I
want to be recognized I wanna be the guy
top and then you give them a hundred
dollar gift card
a fifty dollar gift card something more
than five dollars on its
if it's a five dollar gift card to
Starbucks no one's gonna care
so
once you do that once you make it into a
game once you make it recognizable
something that responds you start making
it
innings where every single employee is
an IDS
where someone wants to tell you about
the bad things that happen in any
organization and finally
the think quarterly think Evil games now
no olive you didn't just start into
security
I came at a college in like yeah I'm
gonna be
I senior Pentax direct company s no
we were all IT guys are or or different
you know
different positions in the company's at
some point and we all found ways
to get what we wanted we all found ways
to get to Facebook
when it was blocked we all found ways to
get SSH out or
my webserver selecting download movies
to watch it work
we all found those ways so
this thing this quarterly think you will
gain is
a one-time one corner deal
where you say if you tell me if you're
employees
you tell me about how you got around our
security
you you will not be disappointed all and
we will show you how to do it correctly
you'll get a lot of people telling you
all the little things that you didn't
know about
that there's a proxy over here in this
party organization
that everyone but you knows about that
can go out to Facebook
so if you give them the opportunity to
tell you without repercussion
or maybe even giving them part of the
reward
you start getting more intelligence
about your own organization than you
normally would
the second
crowdsourcing suggestion I have for you
guys is
internal Bongani programs how many have
you
have gone to an internal web application
are an internal and it was just that
with internal evaporation
internal evaporation and put a tick mark
and something broke
anyway
thing act next yeah
so if you have something
where someone can report those and say
K I found this and it gives me a sequel
where I don't know what this is about
but I think it's bad
or or I put I put in my password and it
said
no you don't that's the wrong password
the admin password is this
if you have a way for someone to report
those things
they will if you make it part of the
game they will walk to report that
they want those gift cards they want
those those little things that make them
more important in there
organization and if you make it easy the
key to this
whole thing is making the easy if you
right now do not have security at
company not Kong
for spam it's after company not come
you're not making it easy and if you do
and all it is is a is a folder in some
security guys like
in Boston ever gets like that you're
also making it part of the problem
so 0
real quick rules real awesome story
about that
so we're doing a princess one-time and
I we send 'em a bunch to these phishing
emails in
and
and one of the guys clicked on an
summit is username/password but we
didn't get any code execution
so we got all these passwords used and
passwords
we're able to log into the their OWA but
not a single execution came out so we
got as one guy's email
and he had sent and he wants an email to
us the security team
same is this legit this looks like
you know a fishy no and they didn't send
anything back
so we sent something back we said
yes it is please click and run it five
minutes later
we got to an execution it was awesome so
if your security program does not have a
response
a human response then
your partner from everyone knows is on
this is my favorite gonna believe all
time I get
excited when I see this hands down
the less for ability all-time in
Microsoft makes a default all the way up
to win is 8.1
water bodies there
the check marks automatically configure
proxy settings
guess know that means
anyone on that network that names their
computer W dad
that's my computer name and I think most
to yours as well
you name your computer W Pat just what
happens
windows will automatically say don't add
he's giving right roxie settings and my
group sessions as
okay here you go
it's very easy to defend against this
very easy in I had no idea why I'm
organizations don't
the simple ways nor out w hat
also had a you had %uh we've had
for ipv6 you can disable that BIOS
that's a great one by our anyone heard
of NB NS
by last name servers this is also a
great one
if you disable that last complete the
reorganization unless you have Windows
98 still going
you'll be fine how many organizations is
a room want to admit there
windows ninety-eight going here
yeah I it's also free
to solve this problem haven't seen s
this one
everybody doesn't believe me on this is
funny
so DNS turn it of in your organization
you can literally turn
DNS of you can say hey
if it's not Active Directory
DNS don't lower through there's no
reason why
your end-user knees tipping Google and
it resolved your proxy
and allow that resolution happen so if
you have a internal proxy
what and you can't be transparent that's
the one thing it has to be
non-transparent
fewer if you have a proxy and you should
your prosecute you all that resolution
now I stand behind this one because
I I went to an organization to work and
I was going on to a red team and I was I
i thought i was hot crack II was awesome
because I came in that red team like a
look at this new
DNS based Trojan I got it talks
all DNS normal ever see it Iran
inside the organization and guess what
he did nothin
it did absolutely nothing because it
couldn't get out
they had no idea how to do resolution
and there are more and more and more
more backdoors Trojan viruses or what
everyone calling
doing DNS these days for their
command-and-control
you have DNS turned off it it takes the
entire field
I'm badness out I'm play cool stuff so
far
okay toll-free how many people come up
to
like you at a at a vendor place or or
car speakers and say all of my solutions
are free fear
good are saying tell the
actually tried to present in our say and
they didn't accept me and there's like
why are you talking about free stuff so
I'm this when I'm stealing from Chris
Chris Cason
and anchors nickerson from Laura's this
the slide is amazing if you don't have
this
in your dictionary then you're not
endorsing correctly because
one of those will work every single
organization
I and probably some %uh view in this
crowd like that my password
this works somewhere
at least one account in your
organization as this right now
so how
on earth do you dump your own houses had
how do you how do you do pasture
management or at least
like how do you handle users selecting
bad passwords for everything including
or a girl can Oracle accounts like sis
sis
or database accounts
essay blink we need to do is do
arm password auditing on all of that
how do you do it your pen testers
involved
I guarantee any pen tester the coming up
to you new p.m. in the give your for any
say at the end
pay could you do a password on it
they're gonna be like
yeah okay is always a crazy
like that is we we take your password
like
yes give us all a min
and you're like really don't want to
I'm so
but honestly getting off on the Joe arm
your pen tester your rating/review
people who are doing that
will jump at the chance to help you
audit those passwords
after the penthouse is done just
say hey I'll let you are my domain
controller
don't the hashes tell us like let me
know what accounts you
you can crack in 15-20 minutes and they
will walk it out and and
I'm resetting tell the users that saddam
so John rippers a great one rock you
do that on this when I don't really talk
about too often
or are too much because if you're at the
point in your organization where your
were you thinking about honeypots you
are we
the way in trying to gain but
if you do want to talk to your caso
about honey pots and
I'm see XO honeypots normally they're
like you wanna put abort abort system in
our network
and you usually get lacked out the door
what are the ways that i've seen places
arm
do this though is on their printer
they set up a port for the National says
hey if you're coming into my main web
server
and my name answers only port 80 because
all it is is news about stuff
I don't really care about other stuff if
you're coming into it over SSL
443 iMac I will
port forwarded out to a limo or or
another bps
and have that running like an old
version of Word Press
now the bag I think that they're hitting
your main web server SSL
but they're actually hitting some DPS
somewhere and you never have to
let your organization be compromised or
put a viable system anywhere near
had alright
so wish we blocked although the DNS
problems
we've blocked all a little memory
corruption problems we blocked all the
Java problems
what about all your users that still go
through the proctor
go through a proxy in all the domains
that are bad
in all the the
now where that is proxy where well
authenticated splash proxies
are one solution to that now
what is an authenticator splash proxy
the 10
vindicated splash proxy so thick it is
flashed Rossi basically
is is a proxy that you have to
authenticate to you
has a special splash page on every
single day may not show you in a second
how that works
but if you have if you have
I'm a requirement for
authentication please
please please please don't make it
automatic
if you make the proxy take
in T-lam or base of vacation or any
other authentication that when news can
you automatically
so can I i if you're
proxy can take authentication
automatically so can the attacker
it's literally one line of code insider
see
to make it happen you can say use cash
credentials
done and I'll do it
so make it making a web for make it
something username/password
begin this is what I mean by indicate a
splash proxy
the one sure thing K have a
little splash page like this and the
splash page does something important
it actually creates a domain
white blacklist so you can stay
first-person into work goes to Google
dot com in the get this
and says a do you want to allow this for
the entire company
most people will shy away from that
very quickly if they're like on facebook
in there like you want to allow this for
the entire company
in no going to
pornhub dot com join allow this from the
entire company
mean
no so out on this you actually get a
awesome intelligence well Chris might do
about whether
I'm you get off in IntelliJ you get to
know
whose actually unlocking these things
you're getting a dynamic
domain block list automatically set by
love your users
now will NEC to on the planet know how
to use this
especially if its flash not a chance the
great thing is if you
as you cook the unblock button its read
it looks like a bad thing
it's psychologically freaking your users
out you have the block button
actually doesn't know really do anything
you not allowing your users to say
block all this right so it's just people
see you on that side
but how do you do that like how
how often do you remove everything
so when the company that I work for that
actually had this this list was
refresh every day now going into work
and having to click
unblock every single time you wanna go
to Google or or
anything like that sucks but if this is
an
company-wide this that makes it much
more manageable
so song goes in and says hey unblock
Google then good luck trying to block
for everyone
then someone goes in and says I'm on
facebook the first one
now at the organization I work four
hours daily
thats lil little too much for some
people
they don't want to to hinder stuff
all the great thing about this is that
it blocks ads to
automatically my arm the organization I
work for
I'm recently actually put this in place
for I'm every month
so this block this gets completely wiped
out every month
and you awesome status is on it cool
stuff
rare and okay well this is where
everybody like actually starts
having fun so these are the evil
canaries honey pots are hard
honeypots you have to monitor her honey
pot you have to look through and analyze
evil canaries you know so all of these
are ways that me or
friend that has told me the story have
gotten cut
now how many 10 testers you know that
tell you exactly how they got caught
right
I'm so domain user domain admin temp
so I was rrrr pen test in
we get on got in and the I got a list a
domain users and we like
domain admin temp awesome and then in
the
in the the description it said here's
the password for domain and in 10
John I N game over I'm done with his pen
this first day
tried logging into it again
again again tried logging in like 10
times nothing was going on
nothing worked because its long hours in
windows and actor-director set to 0
it could not login any point in the day
it said active I looked in the domain
account was active
was not locked out so I tried logging in
more and the two main
the actual demand in guys and security
guys were over in a corner gone
I
the second one really pissed me off
though so I was
I was doing the pen test when are look I
found the share called password audits
pic year gain on
and then I was allowed into the share
so I went into the share and there was
this bigness a
Excel document formation Mike game over
I got
double clicked it nothing happened okay
try to download it nothing happens
actress died
when you mean access denied and local
admin house in taxes 9
copy again well in Windows if you put it
in I'm rule on a
it overrides any of the nikkei are real
rule on it
so how many times
just as a guess how many times you think
I could come into being
here probably a thousand times
so again the security guy in the corners
on her
because every time that I tried to
access that file they had one ruin
in place that said if I listen 10
file access attempted log directly to
this
the Security Manager because no one
should ever be cooking on that
so they said it and for got it
they just let it go in and
never had to worry about it never had
even think about it past the one time
they had to set up those rules
secular third one
I was was a backup database
that had an out-of-date my sequel on
Windows
know if anybody knows about my sig along
windows basically that's
that's gold that's game over Penn test
done because
on Windows the plugin directory for my
sequels usually
completely unguarded so you can load up
any kind a plug in any kind of deal all
you want so as soon as I saw that I was
like
awesome game over so I logged in
authentication work great
butted didn't give me any kind of
problems
Mike it just logged in and dropped back
to my shell might
okay that was weird tried logging in
again back to the prompt
what happened so I tried logging in
again and again and again and trying to
figure this thing out
and kept trying to login what happened
was the Security admin had set this up
on just a a Raspberry Pi
are not apply our on a Windows VM and
removed the DLL
for the authentication peace so this was
just a
my single box just running out there
with the
the deal well that was needed for
authentication or are going faster than
occasion of
so no one could ever log into this thing
successfully so what he did was
he logged every 10 to login and send it
directly to the security manager
set it and forget it that's one of the
cool things about
evil carries like you just put these
things in place in every contest urs
less attacker on the planet will go
after them
with a hunger are
this was funny out I web developer
thought it was hilarious that he made
all of his
all the custom scanners like Nick towing
and
action action all over the web scanners
reply with a 402
basically means is like pay me
if you want to break into my web
application need to pay me
it was really knowing I
through the great thing about this with
a specific age the Access file that did
this
was that it correlated all the attempts
and said
a this looks like nickel and send it off
the IP address and everything off to the
security manager
so obviously I was caught
anyone ever been to get credit card
numbers dot com
everybody's like I'm not admitting that
I am so it's actually a great website
that generates fake numbers for you to
use
in test data so this one organization
took their payment processing database
this big honking clustered system and
put one
extra database name in there they put
credit card numbers
as the databaseName now every other
thing
every single other database in that
database error in that
whatever computer had
credit card numbers but this one like
real credit card numbers this one was
called credit card numbers
too soon as I got access the credit card
processing database I was like cool
when we looked OK ZX 501 whatever is
that like
I have no idea what these are 0 credit
card numbers
that's the 1i want so I
as soon as I access that credit card
number database I saw a bunch a credit
card numbers that were generated by the
stupid website
logged in like game over cent of the
report
security admins like
thanks to report credit card numbers on
where'd you get a up yeah great
we saw you and we learned on UN
and and those aren't real credit card
numbers so I'm
anyone ever use a June 1st VPN even use
it
yes so this there is the the website for
is pretty basic it's like username
password or PIN code and password
and and stuff like that well normally I
things mostly through burr and I look at
how they work so that I can try and
figure out other things around
so I put I access to this juniper
firewall or this year
re p.m. through bourbon saw username
default username/password
so unlike I just found the default user
and password for all juniper fire
for VBS yes no what actually happened
was the HTML source for that page
was edited by the EPA an admin to catch
bad guys
so as soon as you are able to log into
that like it was
actual user name password that you can
use soon as you are in the gene for VPN
didn't give you access to anything it on
an accurate the security a
manager and I was caught by they're like
block IP is automatically done
Mike 00 all over so
that piss me off yet
I am
in this one this one was really annoying
so we set of fish
in fishy no after this I organization we
had another guy doing web applications
so we set of the fish got 10
and username password for this
organization and we're like
yes we're winning we didn't get any code
execution
you know what web application guy said
he found a place that you can log into
the domain using the revocation
like awesome let's try out these using
password: see if they work
we tried it out it's it's s okay cool
that one works
tried it out so this success awesome
that works we tried
all ten of those and saw if those using
password worked
and then we try to 11th one
just to see you know guess if five
minutes ten minutes something I can see
there's two in smoke I'm
if the user and password
and that would work too is like way
okay let's try I'll one more astrid
bobbitt you know and in the past and Bob
that one successful to
how did that work so what it
when it happened was that do me the the
web application guide treated
a page that said you know here's how to
log into the main
and every single one those fishing I
using
passwords that we had were automatically
disabled
by that revocation when I used
so yes you can manipulate that if you
knew how to use it
if she knew that that's what he did but
we didn't know how what it was doing
and we're caught like instantly because
the
they'd found although the the I user
names and passwords in with fish
they found the fish that we use because
the they trace it all back
and we're we're game over before even
got to use those using passers once
so
on while that was loud I so
there was another one where there is a
machine this machine was listening on
on 23 everyone knows a 23 is telnet
so is this 923 I'm and
as soon as anyone talk to that thing on
it automatically alert its own because
any any faulty CB connection
this is actually story from the team I'm
on I'm
where we're caught by this and
I'm because we're caught because the the
guy was so great we actually hired him
onto the ready
better to have a
a colleague in an adversary someone like
that
so finally I
those are off on those are all how
unique are those are all things that you
can set it and forget
right but one of the things that we we
we do too much for getting is at the
helpdesk usually knows more than we do a
security guys
the helpdesk is usually the people who
get all the stupid calls
but fishy know about about their
passwords being used in faces
are about him being disabled and we
rarely rarely rarely talk to the secure
the helpdesk about
I what they're seeing what they are
you know you're experiencing high
volumes and calls because a
XYZ so let's stop leaving them out of
the loop
let's use the Help Desk as part of our
security infrastructure
and that
is it thank you very much and if you
want to see more about me leaving fun
stuff there