ladies and gentlemen who am i kidding
hackers hackers tried ladies and
gentlemen because rogue crowd seems like
the loudest noise coming from my
redshirts
staff how so hot fine good start but you
pay for all right
so closing ceremonies is about me saying
thank you guys for showing up thinking
the speakers very much for coming
through and for sharing their research
with us some phenomenal research I can't
wait to see the videos cuz I didn't see
many of the talks so I really hope that
we got everything on film me some thumbs
up for the back okay it'll be fine
yeah thank you very much for coming
again this year there were a lot more of
you than they have been previously and
it seemed to work quite well having two
different rooms the problem is we
weren't always sure which rooms we
needed to fill and we actually probably
need to mess this size for next year so
potentially we'll be looking for new
locations next year so if you have any
ideas feel free to put your hand up and
comes out to me or come find me - its
coffee or something afterwards and we'll
work something out
thank you very much for coming I have
some prizes to give away and I have some
winners too who already are happy
because they were little boxes that
people break into do we have somebody
from empty in here you want to come chat
or shake hands are the people that had
managed to break into the boxes we start
with a badge challenges and there were
two one was a one was supposed to be a
digital and analog challenge but being
hackers and finding other ways in is
what happens so should we start with
that I'm looking for someone to wave yes
the RF one
so Mike Mike will give a quick rundown
as to what was supposed to happen and
then then then our winner will come up
tell you what actually happened and show
you what they found inside the box and
the name team will shake a hand I guess
so this is the indestructible plutonium
box and you can only get into it through
RF hacking alright and unfortunately
that's not true so it doesn't so
basically what happened was I think we
tested it a little bit too hard so once
the locks were off and this thing got
wiggle around a bit too much I don't
know you could just open it so well with
a bit of force they are
also and andromaque tried really hard
and you got nowhere make next year
Android devices I guess yeah completely
insecure in patchable but ruta bull and
therefore we can do within what we like
there are two more there are two more
challenges at MTN responsible for some
we keep you up your fur but the second
challenge was the mechanical only
challenge and there were two locks to
pick to open a box just two locks on a
box where is the successful candidate
come down yet where is the box so there
are always two ways into everything
every person in this room knows that
you'll notice that the lock that's
impossible to pick is still on the case
it's because there's other ways into the
box
popped it open not the same key
just-just-just speaker it would have
been even funny if he'd actually use the
key for the padlock to do that but I
checked my pocket and I still have it I
I do a quick quick shout out to tell
space who provided all the locks 2x
coffee those locks will be a totes
coffee if you're trying if you want to
try and pick that lock feel free to
bring come down 2x coffee we will have
them there and we'll bring picks and
hope you'll get in what do you have in
the box then the last challenge where's
Dale the last challenge is the one we
don't actually know who the winner is
yet at least I don't
ok so the last challenge was who's got
the best blinky light
we decided that person who spent the
most probably the most hours coding one
and who's got the best animation because
I know cuz both Ross and I tried to do
this animation we can quite get it right
Andrew Mac so you managed to code snake
on his patch which you have tip nuts
okay that was three of the four
challenges we had with prizes today
we're I'm looking for enclose what did
you win Andrew a bag with something in
it
headphones okay where's enclose right
here okay
so how many you guys actually took part
in the sieve we had two successful
captures of the flag surprising results
here in second place with seven hundred
and twenty five hundred thousand events
Frank sorry Frank where's Frank sorry
Frank you don't want anything your
colleague Charlie Smith however with
three hundred and thirty three events
did win
oh come on up well done and we got a
Google home here I'm hoping they're
putting this in the TEL space office I I
don't know if there's microphones in
here or not I don't know
and we're gonna we're gonna walk through
the the capture-the-flag if anyone wants
to have a look at one of the paths to
capture the flag so join us we're gonna
do that just after the ceremonies now
somebody who needs to be telling me
where oh right I have two more things
that I need to talk about before I can
let you guys go the first is we have a
rite of passage I don't know if everyone
knows what that's about
if you don't what it is about is that
someone students in South Africa we try
and get money together for them to
attend to send them over we'll take them
over with us to Def Con and black out in
Las Vegas or Def Con and besides us
Vegas every year they get to work at
besides Las Vegas and try and pick up
some of the ways that conferences run
overseas that person ends up interning
for the besides organization in Cape
Town for the course of a year in payment
for that trip and then when they come
back they have to pass on that knowledge
to somebody else the idea is that I
won't be the one standing up here and
that some of the grey or bearded people
also won't have to keep doing this
forever and that we end up with a brand
new group of people who can who can take
on the conference and takes the next
place unfortunately well fortunately the
choice for that person was unanimous
this year so it's volunteer who
completely gave his heart and soul to
making 'besides happen who probably most
of you didn't see cuz he spent most the
time solving badges and they should have
a badge where your badge was broken and
you ended up back in the bedroom because
he pretty much got stuck there yes he is
well-known to our community I've gotten
his first name this is terrible
Philip Philip poison whoo yeah he's at
the airport he's flying where is he
going - ah he's a classic competition
anyway so he will be joining us at or
joining those of us who were going
through to Def Con anyway next year and
that's being paid for by those of you
who bought badges those of you
contributed to the the rite of passage
donation fund to a bunch of community
members who put money in themselves to
help accommodate and give him food etc
besides Las Vegas is actually paying for
his hotel room because they have an
entire hotel that they they have for the
duration of the conference stay in a
premium hotel room he will have to work
there in order to earn that hotel room
however and those of you who've done
that know how hard that can be
it's not a fun we should have actually
heard you do at least a lightning talk
on what it was like yeah so do you guys
want to hear what besides those figures
it was like can I give him five minutes
flat so so we can do Q&A as well yeah he
was fortunate enough to win right a
passage last year was our guinea pig
test subject and we managed to bring him
back mostly in one piece so we figured
we tried again it's true it has been a
few months you know I'm gonna hand you
this me on the spot of it I'm not so
good at this speaking thing yes I was
lucky enough to be chosen for rite of
passage last year just quite daunting
because they're like cool here our
tickets be at the airport and we'll meet
you in Vegas somewhere sir was a lot of
yeah well before besides Las Vegas
kindly decided to sponsor the room it
was more a case of there will be a couch
in someone's hotel
from somewhere maybe there are a couple
of jerks about sleeping under the bridge
somewhere it's pretty warm in Vegas I
guess that's that's okay but I did pack
a blanket just in case yeah so it was
quite scary to have to get to Vegas by
myself I haven't hadn't traveled to
overseas learn before so that was
interesting yeah got straight into
because of other commitments I basically
landed and then started working sir yeah
it was a lot of time and a lot of hard
work running around doing stuff and
being helpful quite overwhelming how
many people are there um like I feel
like this is the biggest conference but
apparently I don't know anything because
yeah that's the biggest conference yeah
and it was really cool working with the
be size people super friendly
the community is really awesome over
there and from then luckily I got to
stay in the hotel I also like it was
just overwhelming there was so much
stuff going on I didn't realize that
there was a shuttle going from Tuscany
to Caesar's Palace until about two days
in so I was walking every day the
shuttle drove past me at least two or
three times each time I walked sore that
was interesting sir I picked up a lot of
stuff about surviving in Vegas and these
Def Con and all that kind of stuff but
also about how the conference is run
what happens behind the scenes how
difficult the things that aren't even
problems here become when you get that
big like logistics and stuff just get
crazy and yeah it was enlightening and
DEF CON was amazing luckily I was just I
wasn't working so I had time to just
meet people and try challenges and
explore rooms and just go wild it took a
while for me to not get lost in Caesars
Palace because it's enormous but I was
amazing that you know there was nothing
that you could be interested in that was
vaguely related where you wouldn't find
a whole group of people working on the
same stuff that knew a whole bunch more
than you did and everyone's super
friendly and keen to answer questions
most of the
I'm yeah and they didn't let me die
which was nice sir
yeah it was awesome so thank you
grandpa'll largely driving the
initiative and other people who
contributed and microphone mercy
babysitting and making sure I got back
home yeah and all the sponsors I did put
a dollar in a gambling machine but just
because I had to do it I saw some
biggest I got no I got nothing back yeah
so I got I put a dollar in and sixty six
cents was used for the numbers to go and
then I got twenty two cents back in a
bun nerd so that was cool but yeah it
was really awesome and I'm really stood
up and hopefully I will also be joining
this year so I can um yeah hope you the
initiative and show me where to go in
yeah what to do for a complete noob in
things yeah
thanks to everyone your help to make it
possible so a bunch of you made that
possible on the website this year you
could buy tickets to come to besides you
could buy badges which these things
around your neck and you could also give
donations thanks Andrew Mac appreciate
the donation and for every donation your
name ended up going to this well-built
envelope which we printed out using
dimension data stuff very quickly
wireless printers are great I'm sure
they would have let us if they've been
here mean I dated people in the room so
I'm gonna draw a couple names out of
here we have some besides branded memory
sticks which I'm sure you all use and
they're kind of cool we actually gave
these away to speakers last year in the
hopes that those speakers would come
back and talk and use them I don't think
we saw anybody with them this year you
guys seen any flashing red lights and
people pointing at stuff with pointers
well you could be doing that if you
donated to write a passage hope you'll
also encourage you to submit a talk next
year um can I ask someone to come up and
draw names out of this thing
no I did I did do any of you actually
remember donating to write a passage
okay I see a few of you hope that those
the names we drew just grab a name out
of there by the way these these did not
require you to give names own email
addresses so Oh Dan where's Dan there's
Dan Dan wells there we go hey Dan thank
you very much all right next one
there's no in a drawer like ten names
people are not here mark where is Mark
walk was here earlier mark first do you
leave okay
pity when I test true I drew his name
out as well so he really has bad luck
leaving now is the odds of throwing it
again NICUs Ellen
and last one this one trying to climb
outside of the box Richard
I saw you earlier where are you no did
he go he's having the same bed like a
smokin Wayne Duane gone this room was a
lot fuller when we started this pervy
were a lot fuller when you started to
draw as well
I lost try this doesn't work we're gonna
give it up as a bad I have no idea that
GI ll is w that you I'm surprised that
nobody else came up with that idea
earlier today okay the last thing I want
to do is just thank everyone my team we
have a bunch of people wearing teal this
time around hopefully we'll see a lot
more of you guys wanting to participate
in that way as volunteers volunteers
worked really hard all of you worked
really hard and picking picking who who
gonna send to to Def Con was very hard
choice because everyone did contribute
as much they could and it was great and
hopefully we'll see some of you wearing
red next year as well but come chat to
me if you want to get involved in
besides please do have I forgotten
anything looking at anyone wearing a red
shirt have I forgotten about a bunch of
stuff
okay so so drinks well actually let's
start with after this is one of two
things either you're gonna play hacker
jeopardy and lose against me resign or
you're gonna go learn how you were
supposed in corner or you gonna go learn
how you failed at the CTF or how you
were supposed to participate if you
didn't participate at all if you didn't
participate at all I shame on you
I wish I had his Google Holmes awesome
and after hacker jeopardy
MWR are taking us out for drinks those
of you who want to stick around for that
we're going across to the river Club to
the river Club and yes I didn't thank my
team properly guys I really really
appreciate your help without you this
would just be impossible to run I think
we did well this year I don't know what
you guys thought cool then that's me
done so hacker jeopardy here CTF how to
walk through in the CTF room strongly
suggest that if you did attempt the CTF
and failed and have no idea why you go
see how it was done Martin I'm sure you
will put up a an actual how-to online as
well for everybody else to walk through
how to create those VMs in somewhere
store them
well judging from the number of hits
that you ended up with in that first
scan that that's that's a lot of vm's
alright and I'm handing it over to you
it's all you know yes sponsors yes all
of this couldn't happen with our
sponsors um I did think most of you
before
anyway I'm now but flustered read them
off my back this year we put all the
sponsors names on the honor shirts all
the sponsors that were silver or high or
higher on the on the list I joined up
with a lot of sponsors we had sponsors
that weren't mentioned today but they're
they're up on the website who helped us
in many many smaller ways and I'd like
to thank them because without them there
would be no well they certainly wouldn't
be in a badge because we needed sponsor
money to power the badges this year
thanks Mike it's amazing how much money
you can spend on building a badge by you
I mean you they need to make shifting
Michael the badge next year anybody
opposed to that idea of making the badge
simpler said certainty nobody who's
soldiering alright