I am even finished and today I'll be
speaking about using electro magnet in
emissions to intercept is 128
cryptographic keys from a raw speed
apart so basically as we know today the
volume of sensitive data just
exponential our devices are continuously
just producing exponential amount of
data daily and it's just it's our
cellphones as a IOT devices any device
that can transmit ages reduce indicted
today and however we are trying to
protect this information we would like
to have this information protected
theoretically but these so many
information allottee that that we track
particular information and one of these
ways of protecting information is
cryptographic algorithms these can store
graphic algorithms are mathematically
secured sometimes we'll use a
mathematically secured it it's not
feasible you can't crack it in one day
and normally if you want to break it
mathematically you need quantum
computing or at least thousands of years
of just breaking the Elven themselves
however they've been shown that these
algorithms are vulnerable the side
channel analysis this is basically the
study we monitor the side information of
the device that actually gives a
correlation between what it was
happening on the device and the side
information this side information can be
power iam radiation that can be anything
that leaks off for the from the device
as you can see this is just an example
of part of power analysis where the
adversary can actually as physical
contact to the device and its model
monitoring in the power waves while
something is happening say for example
the encryption is running so you just
monitor the power waves and then from
there you can actually find a
correlation between the encryption
algorithm and the power and the power
waves are ever we know that getting
sometimes getting physical access to
ones device could be tricky therefore
they moved on to electromagnetic devices
or literal magnetic attacks we you can
actually monitor the in frequency from a
device and you can use won't be able the
double units need physical access to
device so you can as you can see this
example is sitting in the different room
so someone could be sitting in the room
and just intercepting all our evening
from
and this is why this is more feasible
than the conventional conventional power
power analysis and this is one of my
favorite examples over here is as you
can see they hid a device to scan the
e/m waves in a pita bread so you go to
work you see someone sitting there with
a lunch we know it's not the Atlantic
but he's stealing your information and
as you can see this is an example of the
device ID in the pita bread and scanning
and stealing information from a laptop
so this is just specially a simple
example of power analysis this is the
artist I implement a ssin so the power
was captured while the Audis I
implementation was executed and what we
know from Oris is that they're square
multiply and then based on this they
were they could actually tell the
difference of actually recover the
secret information just paste it's just
looking at the power traces and then
from this they what this what you could
see is that the big power spikes over
here you can see this big wants a little
and so the big ones is basically your
multiplication and this little ones is
zero you're screwed and so you form that
you can actually recover the secret key
but I'll talk today we'll be focusing on
the attack in the age 128 our tack point
is basically at the subroutine of the
sub substitution box what we do is we
capture the e/m traces from the device
the beauty of the since you can either
use the input to the plaintext or you
can even use the cipher text you don't
even need to know what the key is so you
can either use the input or the output
ticks so what you do is you just plug
your information into this lovely
equation and you will get your answer so
basically what you need to know is that
the e says sixteen sixteen subkeys so
because there's sixteen sub kids you can
actually attack each sub key
individually so you can just say focus
on sub T zero sub T five and then
because we actually know what the sub
key is we can actually build our casing
entropy or we can determine a ranking
system for the sake the determine way if
the if the equation we use can get the
McCarrick sub key and then this is just
an example over here of the program as
you can see that the sub key normally
rises to the top of in the location
entropy zero
so from this we can actually evaluate
our results and see if we are getting
the correct subkey or not so this is our
setup what we did was we took two
raspberry PI's a fun cube dango thus
cost us about six six dollars so instead
of buying a $300 a car if we just bought
the six dollar SDR we connected to each
field prayer which squashes about ten
dollars as well and as you can see we
have a tacher the tech is Easter
Raspberry Pi and the victim is another
Raspberry Pi what we did for the victim
is we actually install the fully fledged
operating system so I think lubuntu 14
point Oh fours are an anomaly so they're
fully operating system that we use daily
and what we also did was we we limited
the Switchback to 600 megahertz this is
just to prevent some internal power
power saving features and then for the
attacker we did with everything stayed
the same we just use the device as ease
and we use basically canoer idea all
open-source gets to interface with the
funky dango this is just sulphate the
acquisition form as you can see here we
talked in the 600 megahertz range
because that's the base frequency of the
raspberry pi as like I said before we
use canoer idea to interface with the
SDR so we can see the first stage they
actually just pumped the signal through
a fast fourier transform and then you
can see what we also did was we cut all
the baseband from all the other side
because we just wanted to focus on the
600 megahertz and then this is the first
stage the second step is skip the slit
the second stage is to actually find the
region of interest so this is just
across time so you monitor the in
frequency across time then you execute
the AES algorithm and as you can see
here this big power spike or iam spike
that's actually where the a is 128
increasing algorithm is executing in the
third stage of data acquisition is to
actually do something noisy and removing
the unwanted signal so as you can see
that is the signal that we actually
captured in the raw format and as we
apply out the noise in techniques we can
see the signal curve becomes much smooth
and
so one of the the issues that we had was
trigger trigger Jetta and fry chef this
is because we are captioning the signals
at the at the answer it not
unsynchronized so the signal each time
you capture signal could good perform
the next one so there was a lot of
chance because of three Gidget and face
shifting and then we this is a actually
our solution that we came up with so we
took the signal we segmented it into
various parts so we take a third of
sigmet in three parts or a third a third
and then from that segmented signal will
actually a perform elastic alignment
electrical language is very interesting
it's a speech recognition technique
where they used to align speech
recognition so we can we actually apply
some speech recognition techniques to
align the signal once we do that we then
combine all three separate signals into
one and then we apply out the noise in
technique where we use various
mathematical operations but as you can
see here these various options to apply
so once once alignment is complete you
can add seen it straight to the tape
equation that I showed earlier or you
can apply the noise in techniques or
resyncing techniques and in another
elastic alignment so this will
continuously around and around
Anto falling Reese's are exhausted to to
determine Omni subkeys has been
recovered this is just an example of
misaligned data as you can see the power
trace the M traces are very similar but
they're all over the show however if you
throw it into our alignment solution
technique that you will see that the
traces actually become more aligned and
in this data is then synced as the input
data for the equation to determine the
subkeys and this is just our result so
as you can see if we apply now alignment
we've seen the traces as is we actually
recovered we can cover the one subkey
and this is fascinating because we
didn't lose apply in your language
techniques and it's telling us our ad
that in this signal the these
information being leaked out there is
subkeys coming and then we remember said
earlier we didn't apply the elastic
alignment we actually saw that from just
applying some alignment techniques onto
the signal
we were able to recover six subkeys and
then from that we applied that all the
other Dino Asian and all other possible
factors or possible combinations of just
recovery in sub keys and were able to
recover 12 South keys 12 of 16 sub kids
just using old techniques as being used
against Michael contra Willis as well so
then we actually applied our new
technique so we looked at removing the
frequencies so we looked at removing the
frequency between 0 to 5 kilohertz
within that captured signal and as this
example of how the signal looks now and
in Internet City the results over here
we recovered 12 1212 the subs 12 of the
16 sub keys as well
however in this application as you can
see it's different
12 different sub keys but just by
removing the 0 to 5 kilohertz we were
actually getting different sub keys in
the previous yes so what we did next was
we incremented the champ so instead of 0
to 5 we looked at removing 5 to think
alerts this is just an example of the of
our our signal and now once we remove
the 15 to 10 killers we actually we
actually were able to recover 15 of the
sub of the 16 sub keys as you can see as
we perform more data analysis removing
more frequencies we are actually able to
recover more and more of the sub keys
eventually we actually remove the 10 to
15 kilohertz and this is an example of
the new signal and we were yet again
able to recover another 15 of all the
sixteen sub these however on this
occasion you will see that subkey 9 was
not located in I think previously we had
yes
previously if sub P 4 was not recovered
so we can see these overlap between
removing the signals and the information
that we are actually recovering so so
what we did next was we just remove
everything from 0 to 15 killers and we
and we will see in the next slide we
remove 0 to 15 killers and that's our
new input signal this input signal gets
into our equation and then from that
this is a comparison so we started here
on the left that's our signal and this
is the new signal that we have now so as
you can see that by performing data
analysis removing signals
we got actually able to recover the
entire sub key and that's all this is
just a graph showing that as we removed
the various signals different sub keys
were obtained and as I said before if we
remove the 0 to 15 killers we are able
to recover 16 sub keys it's also noted
that we we didn't go about 50 kilohertz
so what the range we're looking in is
between 15 and 50 kilowatts so anything
above the killer s as well was removed
so as we can see that the entire sub key
is aligning the 600 meter frequency and
actually we remove the signals between 0
and 15 and anything above 50 we are able
to recover the full the full encryption
key so this is just some more tight n LS
as you can see we use we actually just
needed 50 traces of 50 the acquisitions
to recover the the the en key and this
is very easy so you set the day just
setting scanning someone as you set
outside companies though someone comes
out I'm sure that it's possible for 50
times someone who came out here just the
amount of people it works out in and out
of a company and you just monitor the
sign in the the badge numbers you are
able to easily acquire 50 intelligence
within a day and this is why this is so
interesting and easily of deployable
because you can easily capture game
signals so so easily without the user
even knowing that you're capturing the
air you can see that one of the
interesting stuff was that were to
figure out what subkeys two four eight
and twelve was located in in all in all
the traces as you can see we use linked
to the economic top 10 so we go 10 20 30
40 so this is just to show that by 30
traces we really got in 10 of 16 sub
keys so depending on your position or
your lineman techniques you can actually
reduce the number of traces required so
as you can see we did more analysis we
try to determine them the minimum value
of the of the sub keys required as you
can see once we got about 45 subkeys we
were able to get 45 traces we were able
to get fourteen of the sixteen sub keys
and then we use for the a traces will
get 15 and like I said we only use 50
50 traces to get the entire sake so from
this we applied more more analysis to
determine why why we need 50 traces so
what we did was we swapped the subsets B
and C around so substituting trace 20
traces 316 to 20 and traces 20 to 30
were swapped around interestingly before
on the other graph you could see that
the figures here in red are the ones
that we lost but previously when we keep
the dimple in this fund ABC order those
sub keys were found
however these ones here in green are the
new sub P that we were able to recover
so it shows you that actually if you the
data that you have if you actually if
you actually switch swap it around or
actually a bit the data you will
actually get different sub keys as well
and then what we did was we actually so
we keep the sub the second and third sub
P subsets the same and then we swap the
the for fourth and fifth one around
interestingly we can actually see that
this is the same as our first our first
result we all.we what we actually
noticed was that the 20th and 30th
analysis it's it's a place so once the
basis you sit the equation doesn't look
for the period the key that's already
found that looks for new keys so as you
can see the price of a day's been said
we we found basically from 0 to 0 to 2
and then 4 to 9 so what that what that
equation actually does is a box of
pointed nerves ok there's a key to that
look for it anymore so from that you can
see once the pays off the 30 set it
actually looks for the furthering my in
sub keys and then it goes back to our
previous graph which you can see over
here that once the place was hit on this
side and started looking on on that side
for the traces and then what we did was
as you can see it's a big red doctor
with a that was just the traces 30 we
note we actually were trying to figure
out that found sake 6 in 10 and 20
traces but then it suddenly lost it and
another recovered it again so we did
some deeper analysis and we actually
determined that in that subset there was
the data over they were just too a lot
into misaligned or touches there was too
many anomalies in there tighter so what
we did was we recaptured their data
and we just the beauty of this is that
you can actually capture the stained
traces swap it in with another teen
traces so up so this is so you can
easily eat the changes so you can so as
you take it out to and you put beta
trace alignment in there the traces in
there you are able to recover all the
six sub key was a capital out you seen
at the game so we spoke about we spoke
about intercept in Oak Creek a teens
hitting the dice have kids but now we
actually talked abut we actually
developed our own countermeasure to
prevent this subkeys what we focused on
was basically some basic arithmetic
sample Bonacci some just generating
prime numbers as an as a noise demon in
the background so why do you execute
your IES program or you encrypt the
program there's a demon in the
background just generating am noise
filter and what we did was we focus on
creating are they men or out there even
all the AES encryption in a threaded
environment so what we've because we are
running actually on a fully fledged
operating system we had access to all
the other traits such as p38 sea level
traits the TPP and the open mp3's trade
environment so what we we focus on the
multi-threading techniques because we
eventually we want to upscale this to
use on our mobile phones on our IT
devices because we we have so we have so
many devices that there's
multi-threading capabilities you have to
be not actually using it we sit with the
fancy phones and how many times do we
know that they're actually using all the
cores all the multi threading so we
thought that this will be a perfect
perfect opportunity to actually put out
a countermeasure on our phones as well
and our IOT devices we will despawn a
first-rate executing the payment so this
is just the iam signatures as you can
see these are the the different
implements the thread implementations
this is just as you can see the p3 the C
limit rates but you over here you can
see this boxes you were still able to
actually visually see the AES encryption
algorithm even though because in the
threaded environment and if if you know
if you can see it you can easily like a
shown before extract that data and then
recover the sub keys and then we then
implemented our countermeasure we will
just in
the background will the spirit will
scale collect prime numbers and probably
nachi numbers but yeah as you can see
here in the first sequence it was a
prime number calculation and it couldn't
be detected and then in the next
sequence the prime numbers was
calculating I mean the AES encryption
was depicted so we did further analysis
and we actually saw that we notice Queen
the Lok the Lok prime numbers you could
actually still see the the ACE
encryption but once the prime numbers
increase the amount though the
calculations also had to increase and
then that actually generated more
employs and just doing some low
calculations but this is as you can see
it's a Eton Mess so you don't want to
say Oh 60% of the time it will actually
prevent it so we actually moved on the
bitter formula we actually replace the
prime number calculations with the
secure algorithm so instead of
calculating prime numbers we will just
calculate some ashes and in the
implementation we focused on was the
like Crippler crypto plus plus new
mutations of securities this especially
just our operations or what the diamond
that so a generate firstly generates a
random string within ash that the random
string we split the ash into off then
there's a coin toss to depending so it
has a coin toss and opinion weigh that
with the coin law lens so that I take
the first off of the headstone the
second off of edge and then once you
take that off that often gets bet
flipped and anyway once you have a bit
flat let's flip off and gets added to
the first the first off that got what
segmented and then from that to
discontinuously do that in a loop and
toe
especially this increases the interplay
of the actions that we produce so one of
the issues of doing this is our CPU
utilization through the roof shaker and
because of that the device actually went
into a slow down state and then from
there slow down stage we could actually
see that we could still see that a is so
we we escaped in some ashes
some M theta but then device go into the
slowdown state so this was important to
understand that device as well so as you
can see this is just example of then you
guys can see clearly that these this is
the inspector many as you can see
the device at the end of the scenes
usage so you can actually see there's a
some some some missions are ID 18 out
then that's that correlate to that a is
so what we did was we didn't actually
replace the likely of the version with
the open SSL version of the just
sadistic calculator ashes and what we
saw was that the open SSL version was
actually using a hundred percent of the
CPU however didn't put the CP or the
device in that slowdown state so there's
actually doing some management way you
would calculate the ashes without
compromising the device or pushing it to
the limit and actually leaking out
information as you can see on the left
was the basically the likely of the
version and this is the open SSL version
as you can see this it's a nice there's
no in there's no spikes in in this
version and over there in that verse you
can still will be able to see the spikes
another example we can see we put the
the diamond is on so that's when we
running our new improved version and
then we put it off and we can still see
the AES so this just visually shows you
that you can actually see the is when
the implementation or execution when the
daemon is off in the diamond ISM and the
diamond is on you can't actually see it
so what we what we saw was that once a
diamond is actually on we try to perform
the CPA attack and we failed because it
was there wasn't any useful information
that we could extract there wasn't we
couldn't say pinpoint okay in that
Pacific region that's where the ACE
encryption is running so we couldn't
actually perform the CPA attack and that
that ID
so our countermeasure really prevents
out there so then what we did was with
perform statistical analysis of specific
attacks on this data so one of the text
was the stress create this and then this
is just the results of the of the charge
before as you can see the that's
countermeasures we called it the price
count Amir elbow freeze countermeasure
and as you can see these other two
friendlies the different counter means
of interaction so we went through that's
the prime numbers the prime numbers we
really could see the AES encryption and
those are just when we pump the the
the count'em is adjusting to a multi
threading technique and then what this
shows you that 95% there's a 95%
probability that we're not just using
the multi threading technique or the
prime numbers we it was possible this is
a 95% probability that that signal still
resides within the noise generator and
windus prime numbers where you could not
see the not actually see the AES
encryption algorithm it sure that these
a 50% chance that that signal still
lives within that with within the
countermeasure however if you use the
out countermeasure that we introduced
with the open SSL implementation that is
only a 1% chance that that signal could
be in Eden in the countermeasure so as
you can see that we actually use some
nice this is some action to actually
prevent the in the in capturing so the
significance of this is that we
developed the software countermeasure as
you know developing Nord we count the
misses this could be and as you
have to ask as a consumer on if he wants
to upgrade or update Assad where he has
to actually come in replace Assad we and
this could be tedious and the cost to
manufactures could be increased because
they had to replace hard we we as we can
do a software approach you can easily
just remotely update the software or the
device instead of the user just coming
in so what do you hope this will do is
that we hope that this would like
smartphones are IOT devices just as we
know that the age of we in the age we
want our information secured and we know
that everyone is trying to steal our
information and then this is just
another process to actually mitigate to
obfuscate the interception of it about
information through the EM spectrum so
as you can see we just introduced a new
based of attack and a new type of
countermeasure we we actually use all
techniques combined with new techniques
to actually recover the AES encryption
keys off of a Raspberry Pi as we know
that these devices are whoa he's
currently saturated in our ohms right
now that does our own automation so it
is very important that we secure these
devices and IRT devices and then this
hopefully these attacks can be prevented
now and in the future
thank you okay we just focus on the
near-field just to show the concept that
we are able to intercept but there are
other antennas that you can actually buy
just commercially just buy so the range
can actually increase tremendously so we
just focus on near field to show that
the concept of stealing from the
raspberrypi can work but they are in
tennis yeah yeah exactly yeah yeah not
that they there's been research out
there that's proven that that's just not
feasible right now as well so what we
were we're out my point was showing that
multi-threading can work but if you're
welcome to expand it and actually just
the research on that format or just
actually does not spawn in one spawn in
maybe depending on the course a 3G just
born in the random garbage is as well
sorry I think you can actually run into
all this poutine in as well because this
is just our first iteration or first
iteration as you as you could see but we
are trying to expand it as well so we
were looking at different avenues to
expand it and as I said to implement it
on different devices but that sounds
like an interesting idea to start
implementing it at boot time already
Thanks
that one yeah yeah yeah because I think
like as we remove the different signals
the the upper level got removed as well
so it's rare to actually zoom because as
we remove the signal where they actually
zoom in to see where the signals are so
this is just a more zoomed in version
between that course that one starts at
under erupted over as well but it's just
a straight line so you can yeah yeah
yeah 55 zero you know there can be
different yeah that's what I said we
over here
like over here as I said before we know
the sub key right so as we can compare
to our kitchen inter P because the
casing enthalpy will rank it so this is
it captures all four so we apply we
throw out fifty traces in there right
and then this will become this whole
this is our actual our answer so it'll
spit out the entire sub key like it and
paste on that so if you take some other
unknown subkey right so you can take a
random sub k and apply this as well it
will actually get you the critics out
because so we just knew that what the
sub P was but if you actually put our
unknowns up key and then it will
actually predict this the reco answer
yeah yeah we use the elastic alignment
yeah basically you can depending on how
big you want to make your radius as well
because our regional approach was to
look at the small codes so we basically
started on smokers but we saw after
world
it wasn't multi-threading support for
small codes then from that we moved to
microcontrollers and eventually to type
the iPod or I frequency devices as the
raspberry pi but yes I really read that
book so that's our first starting point
were the small towards not really
because no no not really because in our
earlier work we focus on
microcontrollers first we actually show
that our method outperforms the existing
ones as well so we did do a comparison
so if you interested in wanted to we can
do clear up some papers that we did we
actually perform the test on
microcontrollers to show a comparison
between the existing work and our work
as well
I think like GP at the beginning of the
year someone did the release paper was
showing demonstrating that they just use
the normal mobile phone to scan and the
SIPP data as well and there's no but you
can just even write your own application
because you have you can as actually
goes through the receiver and seen this
this is because these we actually wrote
that in a way that one of the options is
run in the daemon or the other option is
actually just making calls to the come
to the noise generator as well so you
actually can't call it from your
existing program as well yeah yeah
exactly yeah yeah because we were
talking about as I said like use it on
your smart phone for mobile banking and
then you start the mobile banking app
with us and then once you done with your
banking application you shut down the
app so depending on your your power
constraints you can use it as you feel
sounds but yeah okay thanks
[Applause]