Nick next up presenting is James he's
going to be telling telling us all about
teaching old malware new tricks wanna
cut everyone in the back can hear me
raise your hand okay
that helped so I'm from Pretoria so I'm
not used to capture I'm not used to the
Sun Also means my dad that's been
driving around on Holi front packed if
you drive on the body you get sunburn on
your knees also I just lift up my pants
and made you whole goodbye legs
so we ever thought it was a good idea to
give me a bike that's on you okay name
is James you can call me the five
because even though my parents don't
like me or they were drunk a price for
what fair enough so I work for a private
bank at least I assume that's what we do
even a private bank we do something with
deborah's it's fine that I don't know
because they don't know what I do my
today is even the thing is I know too
much at this point that I got home
anymore okay so back home I talked to
Julian Assange's well is that really
pale guy he's been stuck in the Ecuador
embassy for like five years who released
a bunch of documents am Jan or feb
released about seven leaks which
basically is the the CIA tradecraft few
standards and a lot of good stuff came
out of here 4.5 SEC say for example one
of the things that affect my interest
was just the fact that they reuse now a
way to avoid attribution so one of the
now we strange they used washer moon I
just read the oil industry a couple
years ago they used tickets which were
the rootkit
so they use code from their home and
today no one's actually came out that
they're doing this other factor the so I
tried to you know he's really pale so if
he ever leaves that embassy he's
probably gonna show up on satellite
image arrived so he can't leave so it's
gonna be this white blob unless that a
lot anyway okay so maybe overview right
says that if you want to reuse malware
and you use four different strains you
get quote four times that's fast which
is a problem I started off doing a talk
about this and then I got senator into
the realm of AV stuff which completely
bugged me over booked up limits when I
say a couple of months I mean I for I
was gonna work on this talk to a couple
of months and then knocked up the entire
thing in like a weekend because I
realize I got accepted
basically what a bees do they do basic
signature tix
advanced checks you know sticks and
boxing and you have European right and
I'll go into each one of these these in
a bit and then from an analyst
perspective you have virtual machines
and manual analysis that said that's
what normal heavy thing elicits and
happy McAfee just kinda rolls a d20
alerts or critical hits mm-hmm who knows
what a d20 is but everyone who doesn't
know what type of geek are you the
ammonia is a 20-sided dice so McAfee
basically guesses anyway okay basic
signature checked ran a check for like
some random string these are your own
rules that basically allows you to write
baby signatures yourself or just looking
for a specific policy if you know it's a
she can look for that exact file right
negative on signature checks that
actually takes context into account so
if you know that the start of the actual
code not just an entire any phrase if
you know there's some little blob in
Natick
beautiful it could be moved around you
want to go look for even that at any
location but if you know it's always
gonna start at the same thing in their
TV rebel section you can give a context
so you can say in the PE header it's at
the entry point and it has this value
didn't like it
right this is the wage wall though
equivalent or PO antiviruses weighs more
always wali I haven't been saving in
like forever
anyone Wally okay static heuristics it
looks for known bad indicators so do you
have read/write/execute
sections of memory do you have AP Isaac
what is normally used by malware things
like that is right
it's very CT making an educated guess
again unless it's like a peon then it's
just the normal case okay so by parsing
the aristocrats so use packers use in
memory in church and volume Orphic
engines just recompile because
signatures messes just a bit Clare other
encourage underage drinking you have to
be at least 7 just to make that clear
also a teenager ever asks you to buy
them alcohol by Bob can water and switch
it around then the teenagers pay for
your vodka and they still think they're
getting drunk towards really well here's
a lot back for you right there okay
sound one thing sandboxing was a
complete game changer right so basically
there on your code to see what it does
so what the guys did is they started
being heading their payloads with
polymorphic engines and then you
couldn't take the signature anymore
right
so at some point someone realized they
used in it Metasploit encoders
then you can actually make your coat
look different as anyone well this book
looks like awkward waiters waiters not
ready
where's Craig very good ah it's correct
Craig stop shingle Craig is a freak of
nature he is incredibly good at Linux
but he has social skills it's really
creepy anyway so this is a game changer
odd does anyone know why - building code
is by parts ad yes you you know we said
that Drake go ahead okay do you know
what Miller splitting code is actually
ball well not that ministry encoders are
made to make your chocolate look
different because you have bad
characters for anyone to watch misunder
so that's why see you write your
chocolate in any way you want but a
train code and it comes up working then
Hardy baby started flagging it of
sandbox because it actually I'm elated
and then people realized that if you put
it into an encoder like 50 60 100 times
then it doesn't flag anymore that they
were thinking well now it should be
encrypted which is not true then it just
acted as a as an execution bypass or
execution block but in sandbox an early
you're on your code for so long I mean
if you click on a button oh you see you
don't want to wait 20 minutes for to
actually run the track so you can just
wet it up okay so you get on to sandbox
bypasses which is really easy
so maybe sandbox is or in memory only it
never gets run it gets emulated right so
if you use if you check out uncommon
function something that's not documented
in Windows API or something the sandbox
is not going to know about it
and then you can use that behavior to do
something else right so the one idea
would just be to quit between the Avs
analyzing you a better idea is to change
your behavior so if you look at the
imitator and somewhere that actually
connects to fake CNC servers your own in
your sandbox you blocked
wrong servers and then you're still
getting in also for example when I'm
looking at bow in its around somewhere I
stop looking at this boring so if you
detect you in sandbox or something make
it look like around somewhere I'm gonna
go do something else right so much okay
virtual machines I did say it is there's
no it's okay so virtual machines are
mainly finalists you go run your your
code in a an actual environment check
what do that you get some really good
ones for example be extreme things like
that and it's just actually in the
freight fences if you want to power
positive as opposed to sandbox if this
does actually execute it also fun fact
if you're gonna request a fire will
change and make the comment want access
to the malware detonation system that's
not going to work
I got chatter dad a little bit so making
that comment apparently telling people
you want that system our way that's not
a good reason to get a power of
exclusion which out there a nerd anyway
in my defense I didn't have these slides
q ed and I did one additionally kids
here so I'm covered okay so do two
bipods virtual machine is run it's
actually pretty easy
check for environment differences well
it's gonna happen in environment that's
not gonna happen in the sandbox does it
have a sound kata does it have a mouse
if you openly bring your payload where a
word document is word actually running
if you know you who you're sending your
payload to make the payload check if
that's the actual user executing it
right stuff like that so if it's not the
sandbox gives up it gets nothing again
don't exit just change your behavior so
it looks like something else and send an
analyst down down the wrong road also I
might have another one of these slides
just because no one's stopping
please don't ban me I want to come back
here again you
God you know what I think was something
I can do what I want okay
we hope you're looking that basically
means that a bee hooks functions that
are commonly used by Maui and sees what
it's being used for if you're doing
stuff like create a remote Fred I've
been doing checking code into another
process right if you do virtual protect
and create or do you try to execute
stuff that means you're decrypting your
mouth with stuff like this
this is often dynamic eristic based
because valid applications do use this
you don't just block all of these right
up to actually power pastors avoid using
common law in techniques so for example
couple strike that able C to profile
allows you to turn off read write
execute
come on strength double strike anyway no
Craig double strike walls I stopped
shingle those who come to these that
card type of conferences on interesting
I was like you Gabriel you don't put up
your hand even waiting room Darryl oh
he's hiding I can form a quite a bit
guarding so Gabriel you steal in my boss
but apparently didn't like the slides I
made for clients I don't know why
someone please ask him and give me an
answer because apparently is not
speaking to anyone anyway
Oh one nice litigation for this they
work extremely well and completely
screws me over as you take it all and
you rip out the code on desk you inject
it into memory and then Windows doesn't
know where it is so you're a be gone ok
cut quits really walk and then I give up
and have lunch okay
so to recap what are we up against right
we want to bypass or arm our it's gonna
be scanned for static elements it's
gonna be emulated to reveal Packers it's
gonna be monitored for bad behavior or
known payloads
someone's gonna put in sandbox
eventually and it's gonna be
in base together so these those are the
things we have to look at run on the
plus side we do have a couple of tricks
up our sleeve each of these methods can
be bar cost in some way no the problem
this is the specifics of the code we
using actually comes into play and I'm
kind of working towards the point where
I'm gonna not only bypass stuff but use
the same engine to hook in different now
a strange so the idea is we used these
small disposable stops both because
they're gonna get burned and because if
it allows us to convince between formats
and they easy to switch our pad so the
first of the these are polymorphic
engines which does basically hides
occurred so you get accustomed trip this
you get come on strike that can actually
encourage your stuff as well Metasploit
encoding they're splitting code is it's
not what they made for what they do work
so polymorphic methods ICU really often
but no one actually uses engines for
they all coded themselves which is
stupid because every time baby flags
that they have to code up a new one
whereas you can just use a framework to
the sample it's effective it's easy to
create problem is so your code is
encrypted gets decrypt that on the fly
and executes about your decryptor can't
be encrypted the IV changes Flags static
signatures on that run getting into the
next when you get metamorphic engines
basically what it does is it takes a
piece of code and move into another form
that's exactly the same thing but it's
like a smaller text T to us so a bees
gone he's the flag down on fingerprint
track who knows the same thing honey
oh he's hiding okay then you get that
one
illegal morphic engines awesome okay
and ali kamal freaking cutting applies
your metamorphic engine only two
descriptions top of your polymorphic
engine so who just went what the
did you just say okay so your
metamorphic engine encryption pilot
decrypted on execution your decryption
stuff is always the same if you apply a
polymorphic engine to the decryption
stuff or stab of no metamorphic engine
the complete thing is completely
different every single time okay the
benefit of this someone is gonna
eventually look at your metamorphic
engine if you use this code as little as
possible it's less likely to get burned
quickly okay you get croppers and
ejectors we see this hell of a lot so
the common one is download and execute
so the actual paler that that gets serve
only download something and awfully
injects it into memory problem of this
is when it injects it doesn't know where
for example create freighters or any of
those function do you need something
that's gonna walk the import address
table and reconstruct afterwards which
is horrible and I sell it for me to
split because I'm not clever enough to
hit myself okay in the process hollowing
was precious injection so basically you
get two types of or two methods of
hiding your code in that process the
first one is you launch an executable
can everyone see what this picture is
we've got calculator on the left and
then on the bottom the important parts
so you take a process you launch it in a
suspended state you unwrap all of its
sections
meaning basically you repair its guts
you take your new executable you map it
into the other process you said the same
permissions and you do resume Fred right
so in this case either approve notepad
so you can see notepad is running
calculators on the screen it's because I
launched notepad ripped out its guts and
put it the put the code for calculator
in there right thanks guy pretty sure
that I'm see I'm so used to popping calc
anyway
minesweeper at least is inimical for do
for minesweeper it's not one caucus
I think of this right you can also do
this as a child process of another
process Internet Explorer launches the
print process for every tab as a child
process of the parent okay so you're
gonna be Internet Explorer as a present
I have the parent and then 50 tabs open
underneath so I'll launch Internet
Explorer to spend that I reported scouts
up with mine are way in there and I'd
point to parent to the main one you do
the process list and you see Internet
Explorer running a bunch of tabs where's
my mouth where you're gonna have no idea
right you can go look up this all the
settings for Internet Explorer it's
gonna look legit you've got night ever
Marcos running in there so that's a nice
little trick code injection basically as
opposed to hollowing and opens the
remote process locates a memory France
and cut into it and creates a remote
grid that a new code is running in
another process same idea different it
me so you know I told you I was gonna do
this again again please don't ban me I
want to come back
actually I'm a surprise doesn't mean
poodle stage it but in fairness you guys
are all geeks I'm good right he's gonna
pull me off stage no one that's awesome
okay just do whatever I want here it's
amazing I wish I had a t-shirt I can
give you it's gonna be awkward
okay so - and eventually someone's gonna
catch our shreds that's unavoidable so
you want to hinder them as much as we
can
there's a couple of ways we can do it we
can check the integrity of code so if
someone's modifying or looking at our
code we can just do something weird we
can stop them from debugging it we can
do deployment control so they don't or
we can lock our targets a specific IP if
it's downloaded from a different IP then
you won't get the payload you can check
for analysis tools someone's running
Wireshark when you're measuring it's
probably trying to pick up it today
right all you want to do is increase the
lifetime if your campaign runs for if
starts you three days then you get more
shells if it's run some weight and you
get like point one more between maybe
and then you get stuff like specific
bypasses and this was actually
documented in the vault seven weeks from
this year CIA as well for example when
your code gets and box tried so it's not
executed it's being emulated in an
antivirus engine that engine is not the
example you do get computer named his
first key that gives you that problem if
you do get your name and if that baby do
something else right same with AVG but
defender also BitDefender is the most
common AV on the market not because but
the fin is big because it's actually
been used but the vendor license is out
there engine to everyone in behaviors
just like the defender in the background
Lisa's not happy that I don't like what
you're used to having pick that up
you'll be protected from clever malware
almost no one does this at least I
haven't seen and that's what blind
signal Egyptian really ah
one guy thank you so someone really
clever did something cool so blind
sequel injection ism as a way to extract
information from a system one bit at a
time when you're not supposed to be able
to run so with this guy data arrives you
wrote like a little framework that
generates a gazillion exceeds of the fun
and he says this is where this
information comes from by the way and he
says is the first bit of the username
one of the earth if it's one he drops in
always trainer hey if it's generally
drop small waist rain beat now he knows
what the first bit of the first part of
the limit and he does this thousands of
times and that's how he actually
extracted the front which is amazing and
a lot of work so I'll probably not be
that that getting to what we want to do
so I created the project called captain
Eva that's basically an engine that
allows us to chain all of these modules
together and then addition chain chain
maille way strains together if you
remember what my talks call I'm not
going to keep it up that was the idea
I'm gonna reuse my way to your mock-up
attribution right so it's before we
start doing anything let's look at the
at the Metasploit module model they
started this idea of having a payload
and both a metamorphic engine and like a
delivery made the track so separating it
nothing actually yeah did that at the
time this is not easy to modify unless
you know there's anyone that one guy I
am terribly sorry for everything that
happened to me a lot to get you to that
point on the plus side you're not a Java
developer but I mean is that Java
developers the best I can do is say he's
no PHP developers
or everyone I have an offended yet maybe
you just live with it
okay I think I've got everyone now okay
Christian Christian I didn't mean it
he's done shank me later okay well a me
rephrase I apologize but it does mean it
he's gonna grab a knife and then create
a shank and stab me an alley
yeah is okay horrible
yeah that's what the minutes would
module buzzed double strike I'm gonna
put they hands now oh yes okay I don't
suppose that okay what a lovely on
suppose dad don't come you know
everything anywhere right I was thinking
we have hacker jeopardy later alright
it's something I could jeopardy let's
chase boxing between same person they
love they are how do we also right
it'll be like watching which is
important pretty amazing
Scrooge it buddy anyway oh sorry little
people love midget okay so I had a slide
so a couple strike it gives you a harder
packet that allows you to actually
change your ballot you can't change the
injection injection therefore the hall
you've got some memory modifies but you
can't really change it and then you have
your payload which you can change either
right so Carla gets there but not really
yeah let's make a better one it's a
restart of a pilot right so remember
this is gonna flag on static signatures
right off the bat that we need your the
modem polymorphic engine or medium made
a more for than one metamorphism is
really hard to get right the lower level
I was super convinced I'm gonna write
one that didn't happen till it's
increase the product let's see let's say
we add a polymorphic engine problem is
now the sandbox the IV sandbox can just
run our code or emulate okay it's the
final pilot
and then we buggy the people around and
we knew that no time off without a cent
much bubble and now we just forget it up
because the sandbox by parts is now
flagging on signatures which we try to
avoid in the first time right so we have
to be clever so we have to take a
metamorphic engine applied to sandbox
pawpaws then apply a polymorphic engine
possibly even apply our metamorphic
engines or polymorphic engine together
is isomorphic
Olle Olle morphic that one I said you
guys were supposed to remember the name
remember blame it
this looks promising right what about BM
analysis and many molasses because the
guys are gonna let look at what we're
doing so let's add some ncbi molasses or
other day and so the ABS call actually
co2 there and then we just look at what
it does right so we're gonna be looking
ahead learn my way we're gonna apply
small disposable stops and we're gonna
have rapid turnover so we can easily
spend new system front or new malware
you know I lied to one of you with my
talk because this is not about Korean
nation state now I didn't get back to
work
so I stuff as well it's pretty I'm gonna
sit up for a sec just gonna grab our
mouse anyone I have a good job done no
okay just you're leaving this up to me
that's a horrible idea
uh not dog
Joba wait did I just switch slide I win
badly you know what's the best place to
hide the body
graveyard I was thinking on the second
page of Google search that's way better
enjoy last one it's a baby seal walks
into a club okay I'll stop there I
promise no wait I need to show you code
first okay so this I created Krypton
Asia the syntax is way worse than for
all guys know you're feeling private and
how does a Mac work you ever get a
chance to get a Mac then okay so
Krypton Asia that has the idea of
workspaces right workspaces contain
modules and modules or little things
that you like to drop out over in my way
the let's go we're gonna read a file
we're gonna export the file at some
identifiers following agreed and the
spirits who knows what then dispirited
then the spirit is the GUI that's the
NSA leaked by accident for the attack
framework right there's a module called
a sobbing I'd allows you to convert the
off the chocolate so we just converted
give it a new name
give a new name but see told you what
the left take a specific function that
we want to call win me then okay so we
get to our be Empire passes so my first
try doing a being bad boss as I took the
code out of blocky that does that spend
three days on it and lost about a year
of my life look at the distant work so I
decided to do something else so this one
is from
paranoid fish so all of you know from
some other project I didn't write this
myself way too lazy for that time so
basically what it does it ask the CPU
what brain there is this and in the VM
it actually told you this
this is VirtualBox so then you can do
something else right so it's not
actually going around my pilot if it's
gonna be able when it fails in this case
I'm not gonna exit even I said I
shouldn't you can see it's it hasn't
been the fine so this framework actually
resolves your dependencies for you on
the fly you don't have to worry worry we
but it I'm gonna check for debugger
because I want the I mean analysis and
then let's assess someone say that good
for me analysts thank you I want the
analyst to be away all right I just
wanna see if they're using any butter
I'm gonna create I'm gonna use virtual
like it to create a memory so I can copy
a payload into I'm gonna use the
Metasploit hash API which was that
really clever thing I talked about
earlier that I'm not gonna do myself
I'm gonna use my metamorphic engine to
encrypt my pilot so you can't actually
look at it and then because of the sand
boxes I do you actually need a sandbox
firehouse right so now I've got this
nice little piece of code that uses
known malware bypasses that are using
that it needs from other malware or in
the same thing
I'm gonna embed it in an existing exe
I'm gonna clear because I was lazy when
I did the metamorphic engine app to make
my executable read write execute which
screwed me over I'll show you later and
then I'm gonna do a da stomp stomp who
knows what a gigs he looks like an
editor have you seen a little message
that says this program cannot be run in
DOS mode there's not if you take that
out maybe then it's a geeky because I
mean obviously an X he has to run DOS
mode or clogging X you drive anyway so
good measure and then this is all the
memory all right so then I'm just gonna
save it to it off okay so can someone
start chanting thank you
I think the memory guards after the demo
gods are gonna be pleased there was only
one guy who wasn't okay I think he's
lying
great stuff like even place me what I'm
a bad guy
I wouldn't place me for anything
I wouldn't even trust me you know when
you should really not trust you when
you're drunk
then when you're drunk and you're
thinking I'm drunk I shouldn't Drive
home that's a bad decision you're drunk
you shouldn't dress yourself you should
totally drop her right that make sense
also your danger to the people around
you so make sure you get home as quickly
possible just say there's another to
live facts I hope I help you up
the last time I killed my colleague in
the even before they map I don't know
what I did was that far because I was
trying to understand might be I don't
know
come on I showed your ads just do you
see what happens
can I run all of those things it's gonna
create a payload for me and I dropped
the payload right so because I have a
minimal fee engine but I can actually do
all my pillars are gonna be different
okay it's just beauty
I can sell it give me to pilot of that
entire chain emotions have contributors
so this is all good all the modules with
dependencies use you can see how it
resolves it's my god if you want to bug
it if you do I'm so sorry hundred bxe so
you can see you have a bunch of PhDs
there all the friends all the insane
thing but they let the printer if you
give each target a new vxe which is easy
to do yeah good luck for for the blue
team run salute you that looks like
they are we you know how you reached or
everyone has idea of success right what
what constitutes success
mine was someone buying me hide after
less license why would anyone pay for me
to reverse stuff considering I used to
risk anything anyway so I'm finally
success what got a lot of paralyzes
anyway this is my belly problem is none
of you said you needed semi oh thank you
take back that statement okay Jason okay
put up dating ban that guy who's
speaking he's a big fat liar you know
this in me really well okay so this is
just the debugger rod so it's my sandbox
my boss basically what I'm doing is I'm
gonna calculate any 5 hash 128 million
bucks which takes a long time basically
to a V sandbox just gives up right so it
doesn't actually get to the point where
it can scan on signature I'm not gonna
actually live a drumhead long look is a
day medic you have to wait 10 minutes
for born right so just gonna do a couple
only 5 hashes and move on to the next
stage yeah next date supply made a more
fixed up right so an assembly when you
go to jump the address of the next
instruction gets pushed onto the stack
right then what you see fairly often is
data mixed with your movie ok especially
in in shellcode which is why creating
metamorphic engines is so hard right
so I'm just gonna jump over it I'm gonna
pop the address off so I know where my
key is thought that's my key that's
random that's why every single saw at
the front so what I'm gonna do I'm
basically you can the fact that key
doing X or encrypting memory and then
jump to see what this looks like just a
bunch of even example you'll be
commenting EVP and then wiping its value
straight after so this is not that it
could I'm gonna run my decryption module
you can see now it's that okay so that
actually decrypted in memory on to my
sandwich fan so that a be gave up I
decrypted now the militia schedule
actually visible cookies some of it
this is the Metasploit hash api blob in
the middle okay in there come on as well
so are we gonna call my actual payload
it's gonna be back - sup this is
debugger check so remember who you
wanted to see if analysts could see what
our pilot does right so we want to check
is their debugger yeah you guys would
turn on chanting hard enough I'm living
you let's try them again
remember what I said she'd only run once
a run once
okay you know we're checking for burger
oh no a timeline so we're generating a
blob of memory so they can crop your
payload or actual play live in net that
is read read right right you never want
to make a piece of code executable that
you're at into eggies doesn't like that
at all
here's another jump another call so this
is a code I'm actually going to be
popping over this is why can't be
routine so I'm just driving along looks
like so the new block of memory I have
is this guy it's just empty and you know
a couple of copies back again I'm just
copying what used to be encrypted code
over to Neutron I'm gonna mark it as
read execute so that if you then get
upset and I'm gonna jump into so now
I've got a new section of memory that's
not in my accepted world or walking
compromise you know yeah and I'm gonna
jump right so here I'm checking of this
a debugger tells me yes because I'm
debugging it right the analyst was
looking at this and he didn't look here
for me you know what's going on just
exit okay it's fine move on to the next
section next section is our be my boss
so you can actually read the VM name in
the CP ID as I said strings you can see
the first one at VMware in Reverse
second one is in Microsoft but that is
our thing
VBox p.m. so you'll see as soon as I hit
this guy wants to jump because I'm
running this in VMware earth so if I
actually just run this pilot it doesn't
love him seriously because of debugger
the first one and now I'm up to the
point where I had think oh I'll run that
the or ow
is it all cheap they don't cheapest an
implant for than the spirits then the
spirits is the tool that's shadow Bocas
broker at least they stole from equation
group equation curve is the NSA so I'm
using nation-state now me along with
okay nation-state my way along with
stuff I stole from github project called
paranoid fish minutes point go a minute
put lettuce would lettuce put smaller
custom cryptography out of something
don't remember as well
this is PE pilots and panthan so nothing
of this I actually read myself I'm wait
you may be right okay so it's going
launch and spirits so you think the NSA
would have graphics design designers to
make this stuff a little
but infinite they did give us a total
blue so I'm not gonna complain too much
it's gonna start up now since I've
bypassed with the debugger all of the
debugger
yeah listen I'm thinking I'm blaming Mac
yeah though I'm just gonna hit ball
peddle cheap and they say then the
spirits which is what I'm using it's a
different policy listen that's right
yeah I stopped listening for something
and then I'll just leave my pilot
continue in the debugger I don't really
care anymore okay that's just a nice a
good and that should be completely safe
trip back to you Dennis birds you want
something anyone have better jokes if
you don't have better jokes than I do
you don't know any jokes whatsoever I'm
just saying I'm you're mopping in
something deeper I'm funny in which case
you can tell everyone about that or you
can tell us what joke you had we got a
thing except connection yes it's a
museum say so what just happened
right we used malware from different
actors goodbye potentially by policy if
you need to know yet and now you can't
actually attribute this to anyone right
no single person wrote this code it's
code used for from everyone
fun fact if you were on this it pulled
every single piece of information from
your computer awesome okay so the
original bailet ability virus settle god
knew every way right but our framework
is not done
metamorphic engine turns out writing
code that understands code is hard and
if anyone ever manages it that means
we're gonna get to butter machines in
like a week
that's basically Sinkin right no that's
not done yet based on race to the model
right to the Millan showed you with all
the blue blocks
how many detection do you think I got
it's not zero one decision Hey Oh like
it well almost I got G right I'm a
little bit insulted
I'll show that's unfair
anyway I'm surprised that in-game didn't
but then again in game it's completely
screwed in game is behavior based right
it looks like what the thing is doing it
other do signatures but if you take out
the dust-up
it doesn't care and I just put the penis
so silence is actually pretty good fun
fact the salons false positive rate is
at least twenty times as high as any
other AV so you know it's really fun
when silence deletes the payroll
software on the 29th of the man Sheree
story that was awesome okay so what we
miss why did we still get caught right
firstly in memory scanners pinellas
except for but it might be but the pen I
don't know of anyone that actually did
this
you can't constantly scan what works is
16 gigs of ram practical it could be
because we were hogging the CPU because
of that in d5 are we doing but that's
probably another I was thinking maybe
heard coverage but probably not and then
it had me the audible Code section that
should never happen a radical code
section means you're updating your
curtain real-time which means you're
using a packer which means your
ladies don't like it they can't flag
only on that but silence is like
you guys a little activity okay so now
what I cants convinced how could from
chocolate to come hard good at the
moment it's really easy to do I'm just
lazy
and B is better than work sir oh sorry
I'm gonna get some coffee yeah better
than work I still need some doing
functions so for example launch
something as as afraid and a minimal
forgetting like I said in just more
modules basically I just want to watch
the world burn because this would be
awesome and then I'd explain to my boss
why I'm a blue team member and I anyway
I should this the guys here I didn't say
that okay so we all bug it right so I'm
going to be releasing Krypton Asia
basically I'm why we can't have nice
things I'm sorry but that's not it
what does this allow us to do so we can
create a rapidly changing strains of
malware and we can't attribute this to
anyone
our payloads are unique not untraceable
from outside of something black sand
virus that'll we immediately know which
usually reported it we just then fish
that guy again you know we can easily
burn our infrastructure because we know
the defendants are probably gonna burn
all that infrastructure associated that
CT channel so bring all of that down
Margaret them somewhere else and it
makes hunting nearly impossible if you
look at their at the internet explorer
example I showed you that code is so
hidden that's and I'm that I still never
gonna find it right there the condition
we're using Norway's really easy
I don't know why no one thing it allows
us to do things we haven't seen before
and it's gonna be the big next hurdle
for flavie's except for Mike happy happy
is that one little kid sitting alone
eating you
but this really complicates attribution
right which is the point there is almost
no place in this place there's always
one and they suck so basically what they
do is they look at small little strains
of Norway and they're trying to link it
up against no no no way the one thing
that I managed to do is who knows about
the CCG in a hack happen a couple of
months ago right says the CC cleaner my
way use the little piece of innocent
code it wasn't a malicious that was
previously seen only being used by PT 70
which is China the CC clean a questioner
right because they reused code what
which is why you want to do this
approach anyway so these guys called
integer that actually caught them so I
got in contact I sent them a couple of
my paillards they didn't link them
anyway the CIA might be on to something
right it works really well and it's not
that hard and not that not this happen
or two weekends that's it
I could be completely wrong apparently
it happens a lot but these according to
my girlfriend it is these Oscar I'd be
really curious to know because the
brandy if I don't know she's not gonna
tell me anyway there's a lot of
fragmented resources the kind of leans
towards this but they haven't connected
thought top four books are really
good they are almost as good as the for
Harry Potter book I'm not sure about the
second Fifty Shades of Grey they're
probably about equal anyone thanks on
you just admitted to everyone that you
read it you know that right and then
there's a couple of cool sausage you can
look at as well they're touching this
who rate in this game you know one again
horrible weeks set for like the for view
thank you
the best teacher is the enemy go look at
Maui Hawaii Maui is amazing
also it's in this when I'm at work and
when I'm not working
that's indistinguishable if I'm working
it off which is amazing right because I
can play with no way look at my way it's
awesome and I think I'm over time who
knows what that movie is from please
someone
I command it's from kung fury I can man
hack someone back in time but then he
accidentally hacks too much time anyway
questions where's Mary
great yeah also it's going to be easy to
any questions not one yeah so what
happened 29 we got a call from some
panic people that's it said salons just
deleted the bearable system there was
not fun that that annoys some people
right Fallon says because it's behavior
based eventually it's gonna see
something it doesn't black see you don't
actually predict when that's gonna
happen or if it's gonna happen but
that's also the reason it is so good
that looks for behavior it doesn't look
for unknown things which is why I caught
me it's like you're doing something
weird I don't see anything weird in your
carrot but I don't like what you're
doing and it killed yeah so that's why
silence no which is the same thing in
game that but I had that door something
which is ended
that's our so now virus turtle that
basically that your sample attests that
against every single IV will up tonight
signatures which is pretty cool the
first one everything coated also
framework to open holder I'm still
painted about the matter but anyway