so today this looks basically yeah
[Music]
that's important is it just for that
yeah okay okay can you hear me okay cool
all right so this talk is basically
you're going to cover just a few
concepts we're gonna look at the basics
of what blockchain is and what makes it
theorem special we're gonna look at the
risk landscape of these technologies
we're gonna look at some historical
blunders and then no demo sorry guys
so I'm the co-founder of a company
called Isis IRA we do blockchain
security stuff if you're interested come
talk to me I used to work at NWR used to
hack mobile phone stuff and I'd like to
talk about investing in crypto stuff
because I know you guys care so let's
dive straight into the basics of things
[Music]
okay so who here owns Bitcoin or a
cryptocurrency of any type okay cool
the guys who don't earn any or like and
how many people don't earn any Bitcoin
know anything okay
okay cool yeah so the guys who don't
earn Bitcoin
I'm sure if you guys asked the guys who
do a Bitcoin it's a very very cool
experience just to receive a little bit
of it it's very easy process and if you
get on to it you'll realize that it's a
very useful technology to to be a part
of and now the blockchain the underlying
technology of what we'll be talking
about today
it's basically a public database and
it's all over the internet when all the
data's validated and
evidence okay a lot of people say it's
immutable that's not quite sure we'll
get into that in in a couple of minutes
if we look at the actual underlying tech
of a blockchain you start out with a
single block and there's a whole chain
of block before this all of the miners
on the network they'll try to form the
next block on the blockchain sorry who
here knows what about chain is cool
awesome so just the gist of it
as you can see transactions into a
single block are you gonna do some proof
of work and then you are going to attach
it to the chain okay so who here knows
why you have proof of work someone and
you want answer yeah to make it show you
can change anything the boss yeah
exactly so I mean there are alternatives
to this like proof of stake for an
example which a theorem is moving to now
or POA which is proof of authority but
what's interesting is that only proof of
work block chains are immutable in in
some sense they're actually tamper proof
because if you look at all these other
technologies are being implemented like
proof of stake for example they don't
have that same electricity requirement
or the hashing power requirement of
proof of work block chains so that's a
quite a nice distinction to make that
the next time that you're having
arguments with somebody over why Bitcoin
has value for example because
nation-states have limited just to see
and it's quite a unique blockchain in
itself
see how this process just keeps
continuing you from your blockchain
smart contracts who here knows about
small contracts just one engage the
level of tech I need to get in together
okay so not too many people so the basic
concept here is you take code you put
onto blockchain okay
the basic idea behind this is that you
have code that you can trust you know
what it's going to produce at the end of
the day so when you have something like
insurance or you have a wall that needs
to pay out when you die
I personally don't trust son time to pay
me when my
it's stolen but I will trust code on the
blockchain that's quite an interesting
distinction or like quite an interesting
capability of it this is all implemented
in people the most part sorry I feel
like I'm gonna so you also get VIPRE
which is kind of like a Python
implementation but most people use
solidity at the moment which kind of
looks like JavaScript you can see the
syntax of it here you put contracts and
then yeah it looks very similar to
JavaScript if you are familiar with it
then the concept of gasps so the ability
to make put code onto the blockchain
begs the question of if people all over
the world are going to be running this
code and they can say that you can run
any code that you want what prevents me
from just dotting the network by putting
some like for loop or a while loop in
the code so that's why the concept of
gas is introduced into the system gas
basically Associates a price for any
operation that's executed in the system
and that's independent of the ethereum
price so some of you might have heard of
gas and seen on like coin map market cap
for example that's gas form here so
that's a different use case gas in this
sense is only in in aetherium sense and
you don't ever actually transact in gas
it's only ever you only when you make a
transaction you basically specify the
gas price that you're willing to pay so
if you move up your gas price you're
willing to pay - more per transaction
that's that allows for certain attacks
that will get into later but yes if you
have like a very important transaction
that you need to do set a high gas price
you set the maximum gas limit so that's
how much are you willing to pay in total
for the transaction and then as long as
that is all less than a certain amount
of the block gas limit then that
transaction can happen and that's limits
on the amount of gas that you can use
makes ethereum turing-complete so like
Bitcoin for example it has a scripting
language that's quite limited
do certain things like have extensive
loops which you can do in aetherium so
that's worth noting so if we look at the
wrists landscape of it you should read
these quotes cuz they're quite funny if
we look at the basket who actually oh he
has heard about some of your tax like
the dowel hat for example okay cool
so yeah we're getting to this but I mean
it's a bit of a dog show right now in in
this space these are just small contract
hacks so these aren't even like BitFenix
getting hacked a couple years ago or
like websites getting hacked anything
like this is just small contracts so at
the top we've got the DA 3.6 million
ether that is close to like 1.5 billion
dollars worth of ether okay fortunately
they forked so it's worth a fraction of
that currently imperative multi-sig this
actually happens at the beginning of
November so I mean these things are
still happening today we're actually
gonna be diving into these top three but
I mean if you look at the hacker gold
for example $400,000 dollars because the
dev said equals plus rather than plus
equals yeah so the interesting thing is
that you've got this code that like you
put on to the box and you can't change
it and it's just it's holding so much
money so if we look at some of the risks
involved in this the first step is the
off chain risks so this has nothing to
do with actual ethereum technology it
just has to do with the way that you
interact with it so if you look at like
forum hacks getting or forums getting
have to like decentralized applications
getting hacked those that's happening is
like a high high level right you've also
got phishing attacks so if you've ever
participated in like an ICO for example
or sent ether to somebody to participate
in something you'll often times get
phishing emails because it's so easy to
steal the money and so he's it's so
difficult to actually track down who's
stealing it from you and then the last
point compromised Oracle's so an Oracle
in in the sense basically means if you
come back to the example
will you need to find out when
somebody's diet right so you can plug
into a database in the government which
will tell you okay this death
certificate has been registered for this
individual so you know that they're dead
but you need that API that untrusted
connection with the outside world into
the blockchain world and that's what an
Oracle is so earlier this year in Nasdaq
actually had a massive screw-up where
they were reporting the wrong numbers to
Yahoo Google MSN and so on so the wrong
financial details so if you had posted
financial contracts which said pay a
certain amount out when the stocks reach
a certain price all the small contract
would have broken based off of the
auricles and nothing to do with the
contracts then if we move a layer down
to the blockchain so this is quite
interesting to see about mining risks so
typical attacks like if you want to sent
attack where you earn most of the
hashing power in the networks you're
able to put in invalid transactions or
malicious transactions hard folks if you
look at like aetherium versus if they're
in classic what happened there or you
can get other folks like Bitcoin cash
versus Bitcoin where they've got
different philosophical outcomes
consensus splits again where people
don't agree on things dots attacks so
you can see again if you're looking at
the Bitcoin holes the saga with all the
folks what's happened on the main
channel is that zero value transactions
so if you make transactions with no
value - on truly incentivized to
actually places transactions in the
block so they aren't so it just clogs up
the network so people can just spam out
all these transactions and nothing gets
mined and this gets slow and it's
terrible and then you get protocol bugs
so in 2010 92 billion Bitcoin was
brought into existence through a bug
that was quickly sorted out but yeah
these things happen okay so last layer
down is just a small contracts
themselves so here you have immutable
codes so once you've actually put your
code onto the blockchain there's not
really a way to change it
the only way that currently exists to
change code on the block chain or on the
ethereum blockchain is through
upgradable techniques right so you get
something like upgrade delegate proxy
where you can basically say say now
you've got one contract that points to
another contract this contract can
operate as a proxy so it says if you
ever call me delegate it out to other
proxies and then you can just keep
changing where this one contract points
to so that gives you a way to actually
change your code base but now you've
defeated the whole point of the
blockchain right so this brings into
question governance issues of them if I
don't want to give the ability to change
contracts to small group of developers
how do I actually control the decisions
that get made so people are doing a lot
of work around this voting mechanisms
like carbon voting for example we can
like pledge tokens or value to say that
you actually you will put your money
behind something then you get EVM bugs
so EVM is basically the ethereum virtual
machine and there have been some bugs in
the past around that lack tooling so
again this is a very young ecosystem so
things like formal verification static
code analysis these tools are busy
developing but they're not they're not
quite there yet so it's a work in
progress and then last of all we have
the smart contract vulnerabilities so
this is this is actually why I got into
this in the first place because the
vulnerabilities that you find here are
very different to traditional bugs that
you get I mean something like
front-running for example where you know
only how I referenced the fact that gas
price by saying at high you can actually
get in front of other people so now
imagine you were to create a lottery
where you had a million dollar payoffs
right and all of a sudden and all that
care to do was guess the right number to
actually get the money out and as the
lottery owner I could just watch the
network for submissions when I pick up a
correct submission I just said a very
high gas price
I changed the lottery payout to be $0
and that's it
right so that's one example we're gonna
dive into some other examples of like
re-entrance ii
and what else is cool time or during
dependency as well so like say now you
want to create random numbers on the
through solidity for example this is
actually quite difficult to do some
people try to use time stamps for
example but miners actually have the
ability to affect time stamps they can
go plus minus 90 seconds out of all the
other miners so they can actually bias
random numbers in their own like what's
the word like a preference I guess a
favor thank you cool so no I guess let's
let's dive into some of the actual hacks
that have happened in the past so the
first one the parity hack so this
happened on a multi-sig wallet so the
idea behind the multi-sig wallet is that
you require multiple signatures multiple
people to sign for a single transaction
to happen so this would be used say now
you've got a company with three
directives and you require two of those
directors to verify any transaction that
were to happen alright so if one of them
gets compromised it's not the end of the
world right so you think that you're
actually secure as a result of this but
because you're adding code complexity
and additional functionality you're
increasing the attack surface and that's
a very bad thing in this system so
what's interesting is if you've ever
used like copay for example for Bitcoin
that's another multi-sig wallet but that
happens or chain but coin while it's
there are multi-sig are off chain
whereas sharing ones are Unchained
so they can be attacked and yes it was
500 14k ether so that's what's like two
hundred and fifty million dollars ish
currently the current price and then
yeah it's entailed a couple of bugs so
if we dive into it's at the top there
you see what's called a fullback
function sorry I don't have a point on
me yeah you've got a fullback functions
basically means if you look at all these
other functions you'll see how they have
like is owner has confirmed get onna
that one doesn't have an named as
specified so that basically means if you
just send ether to the contract or if
you don't if you specify a function call
that isn't
in this contract it goes straight there
and then it will say if there is
actually ether scent to it then deposit
it like you would expect from a wallet
otherwise delegate it to the library
okay and then at the bottom here you'll
see that there's a wallet library with
an address so that basically that's like
pointing to the wallets code so if you
ever get a call that's not in this
contract just send it straight to to
this wallet address now the reason for
doing that is basically whenever you
deploy a code onto the blockchain you're
charged gas fees for putting it bringing
there so you want to minimize the amount
of code that you actually deploy in
instances where you have to deploy it on
for every single user so like a wallet
for example where every user who uses it
has to have their own wallets so in
order to minimize that cost you put the
bulk of that code into a library you
deploy it once and then you make all
your users reference at one library
however that creates a single point of
failure so it's a bit of a trade-off so
if we go into oh sorry so just to
clarify so there's a delegate call into
your wallet library so if we go into the
actual library now we'll see the init
wallets function which take note of the
slide we will be coming back here later
in the second half oh sorry yeah in the
second half so if you look at this it's
actually quite simple they had a couple
of major issues that shouldn't have been
there if you see this code here the only
many owners so that syntax that it's
called a modifier so solidity has this
really cool feature in it where you can
specify a modifier that will run every
single time that a certain function is
called and only if that call is actually
valid will it continue on with the rest
of the code in it what you can see
there's no modifier there there's no
guard protecting it from malicious
things happening and so if the wallets
already been initialized well you can
initialize it again okay that's not a
good thing so that was mistake number
one is that it had no guard mistake
number two is that there's no scope so
you can see yes solidity it has three
different scopes you've got
public which means that any contracts
sir anybody can call any of these things
so like as an attacker you can just send
make a transaction to in it wallet or
kill and then it will run those things
right that's public you get private
which means only within that contracts
can you call it and then you get
something called internal which means
that itself as well as any derived
contracts so example for example like
the wallets calling the wallet library
so this should have been internal so
that only the wallets could talk to each
other so coming back to this function
here this operated pretty much as a
catch-all statement this delegate call
so that so basically as an attacker you
have an attack vector that goes straight
in to delegate call by just making sure
that you don't specify a function that's
in here and by not sending any value to
it's by sending no ether and so now
you've got the entire attack path to
basically initialize the wallet as your
own during that initialization process
you become the owning of the contract
and then you have access to all that
ether and so here's the here's the patch
that was pushed shortly thereafter you
can see internal at the top their
internal there and this is the guard
here any uninitialized and so the
takeaway from this the three people who
were affected by this eternity editors
casino in swarm city the takeaway don't
put an infinity sign in your logo yeah
so okay a couple of weeks ago the second
hack happens well it's not really a hack
but again it was a multi-sig
functionality so again this the reason
this is so scary is that this is us
right we use multi six ordinary people
that like they don't really care but
just because you're using the multisig
you're affected by this 514 care ether
that's that's a lot of money right there
right and the bugs in votes so I mean
this size contract and kill
functionality sir look who we have again
so basically all that happened was they
didn't initialize
the library itself and so an attacker
this guy on github basically said that
he was trying to deploy a wallet and
that was buggy and he wasn't sure he was
doing so he tried to enter the wallet
which was a library
he gained ownership of the library
itself and remember it's a single point
of failure so when he was stupid enough
to call kill it broke it for everyone
yeah
everyone okay so sorry that everyone who
deployed the new contract since the
previous hack yeah so that that wasn't
good either yeah moving on to the dollar
hack this was actually literally what
happened with the popcorn and everything
so the Dow is basically a decentralized
autonomous organization which means it's
a company that's all of its
functionality has been or is intended to
be programmed right so it doesn't
actually require any individuals to do
anything within the organization it's
just all it happens at the programmatic
level and at the time that was hacked it
held about 14% of all ether which is a
scary amount 3.6 million yeah I gave you
the numbers earlier and it used a
reentrant sea bug which is kind of
difficult to understand at first if you
haven't seen it before but if you think
about a typical transaction let's say
you've got an individual who wants to
transact with the wallet contract the
first step is they'll indicate the day
when I will draw their balance their
balance is 100 tokens and the wallet
itself actually holds a thousand tokens
because there's 10 other users say or 9
other users so it's going to send the
credits ups and there's gonna update the
balance and then at the top of that
you'll have ok the users balance is zero
it's 900 ok cool but the thing is that
you can send make these transactions as
another contract right so you can do
something quite sneaky when you withdraw
it's gonna transfer the credits
but because you actually have this
wallet attention at this stage or no
attention what's the right word for this
you you've basically got it's going to
pause execution waiting on you to
respond to it basically okay so you can
call withdrawal again before it has
updated its own balance and you can
cause a recursive instance that will
basically keep withdrawing until the
wallet runs out of money okay and then
it will update the balance so in this
instance there are just two withdrawals
setup there's 800 so that's that's
basically what's reentrant see is now
this was the dark heard you can see is
specifically these few lines of
withdrawal a reward for a message to
sender and this balances when you set it
equal to zero right now had they just
reverse these two lines it would have
actually been fixed because when you
call back into the contract the balance
would already be zero right but because
it's a program like this is gonna keep
hitting withdrawal reward for each time
that you call into it so here you can it
just goes in so here's of a stroll for
payout and then if you go into that
function you'll see this code here so
you can see its recipient I call that
value so what that is it's basically a
low-level call into a solidity transfer
function transfer tokens currently there
are better ways to make transfers like
if you use dot transfer or dot send it
limits the amount of gas that the
transfer has so if you think about it if
you're making a recursive call you're
gonna run out of gas it's actually it's
a very small amount of gas just not to
log an error message so when you try to
make that recursive call is just gonna
fail so this bug isn't really that
common anymore because you need to
specifically call that value to exploit
it
so yeah just coming back to this one if
they had reversed those two it would
have fixed it fortunately a lot of
static and analysis tools actually
detect this type of behavior because
it's quite easy to pick up automatically
yeah so I guess the takeaway from this
is it's a very very young technology I
didn't realize how early on it is for
these types of technologies if you look
at like the scaling questions and our
interoperability like all these major
questions around how how is this
actually gonna work they haven't been
answered yet people see the massive like
50 billion dollar market cap and they
say ok well this must be awesome
no it's still very young so it's a great
time to be getting into this type of
technology and just the last point is
under s Antonopoulos he's an awesome guy
to follow he has this great point about
Bitcoin which is sewer rats versus
bubble boys so if you think about sewer
rats they live in the streets of New
York it's the in the in the drains and
the sewers in the most disgusting places
ever right and they're exposed to all of
these terrible diseases and just like if
they can survive they're gonna be the
most badass like yeah like this strong
and like animals around right so sewer
rats are like block chains right very in
the public anybody can attack them you
can do anything that you want to them
there's currently over 100 billion
dollar bounty on Bitcoin if you can hack
it right so that creates a very strong
technology whereas if you look at the
banks that have all of their technology
hidden from the outside world and
they're kind of like padded by these
bubble suits you don't know what's gonna
happen when somebody gets in so that's
why you have to ask yourself like okay
there's been some major hacks here but
is that such a bad thing actually like
those hacks have happened out of the way
they're not gonna happen again so that's
the core distinction you need to make
and like I said sorry guys the demo it
actually broke it's not going so uh so
that's actually the end of the talk
[Applause]
yeah yeah so there's quite a few
different solutions to this right now
like if you're interested in specific
technologies like Oracle eyes is one of
the major ones right now and now you
pretty much have to rely on the fact
that these people are going to be
they'll has like 7sl is in place around
what they can deliver to you and you
have to rely on the fact that they're
monitoring on a regular basis so like
you'll have an Oracle specifically for
like the Deeds office or for like nasdaq
prices for example but yeah I don't know
if I answered your question like the
hola
exactly yeah which brings in the massive
like as I said earlier like it's a big I
wouldn't say loophole but like it's a
massive question right now about how do
you actually verify that data and not
introduce to security risks into the
system yeah yeah and so I mean there are
some interesting technology all like
solutions to this I mean if you look at
art lies or if you look at Nia for
example they basically rely on the fact
that your reputation is very important
and if you can tell who submitted the
incorrect data so if you look at I don't
know say now Nasdaq screws up and you
can pinpoint it on NASDAQ and you lost
50 million dollars due to this don't use
Nasdaq anymore right it's kind of the
free market speaking so there's that
transparency about who's responsible for
things happening yeah sorry there's a
question
[Music]
yeah sure so on your solidity points
absolutely like solidity is the core
issue behind everything or all the bugs
that have happened it's people are
really struggling to coordinates kill
you because it's a different paradigm
there's quite a few things that you need
to understand behind it that's why near
as well they have their bit more
familiar languages for people to code in
it's a massive advantage for those
people so solidity is not I mean it is
Java Script esque but it's not
javascript so yeah noted that one and
then your second point on IRC 20 so for
those of you people who don't know years
C 20 is basically a token standard in
the if that was developed by the
ethereum community so if you want to
launch a new token like on an ICO for
example you can make it have this
standard and then you can plug it into
things like exchanges or other wallets
so that displays nicely and that you put
integration across the board now I'm not
sure I would say that that really
introduces additional complexity because
if you look at the alternative case you
basically require people to either come
up with their own block chains or to
like folk another one you know yeah well
okay I mean look you also get scaling
solutions to this I mean if you look at
some of the stuff being proposed at the
moment with charting for instance or if
you've got
what's the thing called sorry my mind
skipping it right now but you basically
got technologies are basically trying to
have your main blockchain and then
you'll have child block chains yeah
exactly but there's sorry this is one
specific youth boy there and that's just
skipping my mind and those technologies
can be settled or chained and then
committed onto the chain later and you
could use something like that to solve
this ICU issue because you'll you'll
actually able to detect if you use
ethereum on a like an hourly basis
you'll be able to see when an ICU is
going on because there's such an effect
on the network but I don't think that's
necessarily a security issue right I
mean that's that's more of a scaling
issue that will be addressed over time I
think if people do use your C 20 tokens
they're a lot better off than any other
eco system currently yeah yeah okay cool
sir we're second under Murphy so okay
you get remix which is a super easy
browser like you can just you can
actually put your all that you go to and
then you can deploy contracts onto the
blockchain in your browser right and
that that's really straightforward
there's also really nice framework
truffle which basically packages
everything you need into a single plant
or framework where you can write your
solidity code you can write unit tests
and everything like actual migration so
like if you've got multiple contracts
that depend on each other you can set up
the order that they gets deployed to the
network and like any configuration
things so to answer your question I
check out remix it's really not that
difficult to get into it's like just
it's as easy as any picking up any other
type of coding practice yeah sorry I
don't have a better if anybody is
interested in getting in writing small
contracts just come speak to me
afterwards and I'll show you how easy it
is you know cool any other questions
yeah so the question is just it was
basically how how do we stabilize the
value of Bitcoin and oh yeah
okay so there's some cryptocurrencies
were necessarily fascist I mean like if
you look at tether for example tethers
intention isn't to go to the moon but
they're probably gonna go other
direction yeah look there is a
philosophical question here and
ultimately most people who need to
answer this question on they don't
actually want the value to be pegged to
a dollar value right like for myself I'm
happy to take payments in Bitcoin in
fact for clients of ours we give them a
discount for paying us in Bitcoin and we
don't change it based off of the US
dollar price right because if you buy
into the actual ecosystem of it and like
the philosophy behind it you don't need
you don't care about what the price is I
mean like if you think about South
Africa okay the the ran race
against the dollar and sure like that
can affect like import rates whatever
but I mean that doesn't change like the
amount of money that you are charging
your clients on that daily basis right
as the dollar is fluctuating so you kind
of need to buy into the actual asset
that you purchase all those sort of the
currency that you are purchasing to
answer your question yeah this is I
don't really think this is going to be a
way to ever stabilized against other
currencies
if you're serious about that come speak
to me afterwards because I happen to
know someone yeah okay so basically the
typical like best practice here hardware
wallets trestles and whatever that's you
use cold storage or like deep free
storage like stuff you never gonna
access you keep on a hardware wallet in
a safe that's never gonna be touched
then you put the next step up from that
so that's more your actual cold wallets
so that's again a hard wallet
sorry hardware wallet then you've got
your hot wallet which is basically daily
transactions which again it can be
either a separate Hardware wallet or the
same one and that's generally I mean
like some people as only you're not
putting it on an exchange like it's not
that bad yeah well to be honest with you
like a small contract side of things the
only small contracts I operate with our
ICS or like to invest with I don't I
haven't found any daps I actually like
well like decentralized applications
which we normally use ethereum for so I
don't actually most of my funds are in a
cold wallets to be honest with you yeah
I mean like the yeah that's
[Music]
yeah and it's on the dock yeah no I I
haven't really looked at that too much
the security aspect of it I think it's a
very interesting space to be to be
looking at but honestly I haven't even
found quality gaps at the moment so like
it's not it's too premature I think well
okay so basically this is it's not
really a race condition because you if
it's more about the context of the call
right it jumps between contracts so
you're not really racing anything you
just if the one contract had finished
its own process while the other one was
finishing I mean like that would make it
a race condition but in this sense it
was jumping between them and because the
let me just go back to slide sorry yes
exactly exactly because your actual
context is like you're going from here
and then when this guy should be
updating its act the context is over
there so I don't think to answer your
actual question sorry was race
conditions in this space I can't really
think of I mean like a better example of
a race condition would be where if you
see some of these like lotteries for
example or if you look
like being able to get your transaction
process before something else so like if
you're a mine on the network and you're
able to like push your transaction ahead
or if you're able to clog the network
and slow down to everyone those are
bigger concern yeah I guess that would
be the type of race conditions you're
talking about yeah that's that's common
there's a few vulnerabilities like if
you look at yeah there are a few don't
see a question it's not just reentrant
see yeah
any other questions
so who's participated in ICA anyone not
fast enough yeah yeah exactly
if anybody wants to go to the moon or
drive Lander like investigate it that's
it's kind of cool it's it's nice to
participate in innocency the actual and
as I said at the at the beginning like
if anybody here doesn't own Bitcoin
download a wallet and even I will
personally give you some Bitcoin if it
if it has to come to that but it's just
it's so easy
famous last words yeah yeah but once you
bite into and you just see how
straightforward it is and how cheap it
is and how practical it is like I guess
most people they don't need to deal with
international payments on a daily basis
currently but in the future we're gonna
see that it's just it you can't compete
against it so I hope you guys take a
look at it and see how cool it is yeah
[Applause]