thank you for being here and it's not
gonna be dead thank you organizer is
Tony's not gonna be one of those people
piece next time don't just take another
thing another thing mr. Chetan observant
of well one off sir it's a white penis
okay there's a lot of so cheating in
facade if you start out you don't have
to be white so he so together of two
dead tops don't have half chap yet you
say I don't have to wear pink one good
you don't have to make so if you're a
female
don't don't tie team cheap ass too much
just be yourself you could metal fit I
don't even know school so the name of
tongue is art exhibition remove thread
because I think I'm Ella cares about me
of my name is nightie
that's my to the hender I'm having a I'm
less I'm a new and Xia
I've been fearful wedding
I do static English so if I don't forget
I don't remember something I'm just
gonna say you know on our zoo so almost
a good feeling that but I'm going to
think I'm you gotta have a tattoo you
don't need a TV for 200 sir
epic good America might sign up my HTML
for sense post before my dreams I love I
didn't know about fhc - I was talking to
George
one day and he said tomorrow we're gonna
be like Mary just fantastic stuff okay
so that's what I did
so why websites it getting a new job it
meant that I'm gonna have time now more
time to you some research in Japan it
wasn't fun anymore so because now I'm
working for years of organization I get
to get up get to receive those fantastic
phones so they saying
put that I was giving before now quickly
received it be now um also the many
politically for yesterday when I say
that suppose I have my period for shot
she find me this book I feel healthy so
I knew I had some defensive line police
also is a defend some hat so after
watching this fall this is actually a
talk that made it very easy for me to
spiders skates
it was cool I think so widely dead news
huh maybe one of Shakespeare's names in
the hopefully good house you guessed
that it
I'm reading expert at all so this is
Justice Party PT stuff so if you think
if you have any comment or I guess if
I'm you know just a few some parameter
paper
David Bianco is expecting a search on
you only say that organizations normally
for customers this you need to focus on
this distant in policy to check yourself
so if you focus so especially if you go
up you make a check on life atever life
ha so you make it hotter fun activity so
we know most people detect on the lower
levels - Vince is gonna be first mix
this is specific cash for a farm just
upload that so it can be checked it
[Music]
and mostly you just focus on that but
what do you wanna do with so come on in
okay so we want to focus on those two at
events so well not gonna take it to
let's say who this to leave this
happiness so now we were to check on
cutting back and alttp stealth tactics
technical you wanna say kokoomus
this is how an attempt happens so
what I need to learn a pattern so
essentially detecting
so now the more you go with this the
more unique your that's a lot harder
because now I tell them it needs to
change the tools and changing the tools
it's very hard they need to change their
procedures which which is very hard for
not a good way to Malaysia
she's Nicholson on the top on that top
layer on top that was she says just like
a situation did you wash area
investigation or visitation
you know when they try to figure out how
they how they happen dissing this is why
it is and I'm so obvious I watch it here
of course this is microbeads obvious are
so for me I said and it's solutions - in
my chest so the idea there is that with
this projects are you understand baby
the idea is just to included defense
just that's the easy way to put it and
same lady says simulation should be
dungeon and how that it's unlikely to
actually pose so when I really did a
solution you ask yourself this question
so you sit somewhere with your buddies
those detainees are checked if the
answer is yes okay cool that's simulate
this if you can have each other so that
if it out sighs no okay let's simulate
that and see really we kind of because
idea is just use of defense and also we
have some components so we assume that
we can be compromised
no matter heart any carpet can be
compromised pretty much is volleyball is
not a technology
simple is collective incident response
so the idea is that it
the idea is that instead of just waiting
for my lats and stuff or for some whoops
you call me and say you have leaked HIV
or something just go and see if you know
you don't have an opportunity personal
cell is dead I'll be hacked by this
particular tip so you could kind of
think about it I'll tell you say are we
hacked by this person that you if the
answer is yes or no you still good see
you - poop - do you have evidence of how
we had let me go ahead also he has been
compromised
we are doing that okay we might be
component you know it is good let's go
hunt
hi there process of this thing
I didn't come up with his name I just
thought about it and googled it and so
this is the process are take or you take
firstly one of choose a technique
interested in once you tell you that you
wanna check out the things if contrast
when I see how you doing ladies you see
you didn't attend too badly the
simulation now you wanna see if you not
being attack whatever I read there
you're gonna measure how you doing over
time authentic needs so did you go you
take me down you wanna focus on you can
basically check the internet if there's
a fire fire I spotted not check in a
while you listen a lot going on in the
wall so you can kind of do research and
then feed it up the technique you see
it's not about me same thing with
classic perfect they are rather people
first because you can go and take it
just the common see what it means of
technique fall if you are Kenny I'm
going to find a pattern eg you can see
if you don't have a patina
something about empowerment and 1000 in
purple closely can check out the vendor
secretary Burton see if softer you used
it's not so much any security eg if he
is doing take that technique we can pick
an epic oops
if you know we won't know about maybe
cats so again check mimic its
or you can take pen testing reports
technique and idea CD to my top so my
top the very cool organizations that he
collected this framework business led to
all on a techniques that that has been
used and sort of collected them together
for you just to go and pick a technique
and of course the minute you know about
this pretty cool we have techniques for
Windows Mac and Linux
so I think it's very true full stuff I'm
Jack Jack is a Jake is a sort of a Sun
hunting expect so basically he said he
became develop detection for even half
of what is in my top you'll be able to
teach Eckart a set of heavy so they'll
cool good idea media then scissor so we
honor if if something happens your see
so come down to you hey that's did you
eat this you get some effective - so you
have to say yes but you have to prove
that yes we'd be Hardy so you can clear
technology you see something come to you
and say okay then you take a technique
our man is CDC then capture this this
atactic so also can get technique from
tools of is that so there guy forms back
to us so they get in a talk yeah
um and they show you how kids if he can
didn't get he can get techniques for me
to said it needs me me can't visit the
example so it shows you how they've done
what he does in the KHL axis we can dump
killing Charles I'm gonna plate that
house in security support provider and
it must be done move men to go into
panic boxes then once you have those
technique we can pick the one you want
to focus on and use that for your
simulation of who I want to see where
they just pass the ticket to pass the
hash so keep that one your simulation
significantly check the stuff okay so
the first phases that we identified a
technique we wanna focus on so now
you're gonna do defense laptops when I
see how we're doing on the defensive so
my to look heat okay look it much just
looking more yeah
so essentially what I did the cheek so
they show you will take in order to
compromise your organization and which
did with this there is a defender you
only need to eat at once because an
attempt to be such non those steps need
to be to be a sexy success so you need
to just have one of those steps then we
can be able to stop so this is on your
left will hear our tech tech chains
service kill chain and what do you want
to end up hitting is something like it
so you're gonna have a tool or something
to detect or deny or yourself you see
the container tip so what are those
stages at one point once you have you
want to detect something honestly so if
you can have different people on staff
one now even if you can detect at
installation top you're good because we
still just
we should love to check it out son
so you want to detect at one point in
future cool so the phase two is done so
we understand now kind of defensive so
if we have a technique when I focus on
so we've mapped it today today's have a
Pucci and we know that we can detect
someone said well it's thing with it but
we have it to me
we know how we do it let's see if we can
do nothing leave this to me
so this is the process that you're gonna
take hey yourself
so basically assimilation as we know
it's not a test it test like heck and go
so why do you wanna you want to test
your detection tools we have a deep you
have a you have a technique and you know
so you want simulate that your tools
that we've done so you want to test the
truth so one of the Americas I see if
that is digital and how do you do that
you wanna use maybe see a digital
machine that's the same test machine I
need to have power so you want to have
the latest your security to lose more
than there so what I have this
devastating machine so that again kinda
became a little bit say that and the
idea was that the tools that one
opponent
indicators of components because the
ideas as we serve see machines about
improving the defense you wanna connect
person the kids are so that you can
eventually later on so it here security
software when you want to connect at
events you want to connect your network
motif it
so when inducing an issue you have to
does a network connection move it mops
and when I did this which is what about
like Firefox goes are
unique enemy PMS visits
most of tablet s used directly in ersity
to explain data to use it as a toner you
keep them touch me good man chat though
also on your host picks you are now you
wanna take you wanna you wanna and most
important thing 5 their plans on leaving
sir if you do hunting so if you if you
do feel at my table you wanna sub I
believe so no money that's how you when
I do for 5,000 people connect on this
was to make legit to be educated so
basically this is a test that you can
done that me expect you to to my top
flavor we talk a lot so we've made it
very nice and clear so you can just copy
any patience this testing test laptop
then quick news was collected in dogs
and stuff the idea also you want to
improve our details what I collect those
is so cool now when I done with testing
about our tools now when I test their
processes so you want to test how your
your defenders will response you to you
are tip so you wanna send that fishing
mail and see what how how your defenders
guys with the activator
when I see how they and he's following
direct cause seizures if I did you mean
that I things that I think what I do I
do
any gaps in the process that we take the
idea also is improve their capsule to
prove that processes a third procedure
so here you just just just checking your
once you turn your attempt for a
basically should add sodium
so this is an example of maybe linkage
ataxia to change so this is the playbook
got to follow teammate stuff so this is
a phishing phishing attempt see where
are basically so I'm gonna go through
each Creek so the first step in what I
did was take capital in so who is the
first day so what do you have what so I
said I said that's you and I defendants
and you talk what do we have so no
control of you have some kind of in
control - you don't have a cool we
accept that cinema is officially
medicines received by the company SMTP
server so what do we do about there what
control can you put in this so you can
reject email subject lines and IP liquor
some thirdly email goes to the companies
in those go but we do about there you
can flag bad humors to let the fish move
to the end users mailbox what we do with
that I occur whatever is probably a soft
would take a lot of moving
so you have put it there five user
notifies that new demand in the mailbox
the user opportunities for camellia
above it we can one use us on the
imaging efficient campaign so sir pizza
in college steps you have you are you
controlling it these are ticks on a
leaky nemesis million doses in the world
are not good users for meet up with the
DNS so there's a DNS involved what do we
do with them Nicole yes DNS requests and
it's kind of just taking that guinness
name and just giving it a not happy I'm
happy that doesn't put you outside
whatever just his office so nothing was
out of your organization so you can see
simple stuff after you time you attend
sit with depend on seppuku uses steps
are to this is the contours that we seen
are grateful now then
so nice well above hey I can help
yes wrong good so once you've done that
you said we fill the defender dies you
wanna because you didn't want to be
distinguish it if it's have for one
thing
come on up what to maternity check the
stuff so you wanna update your software
so your ideas FPS so maybe nobody you
know so you will not be just up so that
the next time she gets get detected if
there was an issue with the process that
was happening like where they they're
reaching that didn't further the process
what about the gap in the process anyone
updated if there was no control at all
for some for some reason now you have to
define the control you have to figure
out how to me if they were left simple
done if there was no ad when the box
there that means well now you have to
get and the issue will controls
especially for big companies that most
people just
this guy's my god hovering say for such
Eddie he felt she didn't the next night
we should be level she'd be a sense of
x2 so it should be something that became
if you can collect some software so she
didn't shouldn't be expensive encompass
good now that you deployed your controls
and you update your software securities
oh yeah now we can be too cool but let's
see if you really can't it so now you
want to validate whatever control is you
just stated I'm gonna buy didn't you
defense on top how many how many people
can essentially para dangerous how many
people in here knows that knows what
what what is going on with Eddie is they
be picking something hot how many people
have essentially we're doing a soft
wanna see if maybe words probably yeah
so what am i doing this stuff don't want
us Justin I'm gonna say hey I'm secure
but you know so you when I did you
respond hot and mostly when I take a
strict and yeah and you shouldn't we
don't need to get far with commands that
normally a heckuva carcinoma a hedonist
commands to get to get information from
your domain so you can just change its
character it's a good team this
basically does that will not near each
other so if this do if you don't get if
you don't if you don't attend to just
laugh now when it lands there's
something so so the not part of your
simulation used to track your activity
so we all know money management or
whatever business of that she type stuff
are just so you can change this circuit
any spreadsheet basically you can onion
African can have a to that
a simulated one technique that you used
technically used in depositor in use
then you have their results like
Inception do you detect the attack so
you see no detection authorization cool
Peter buggy detector which is never one
that POS prevented more than that you
know
did I just say so you wanna have this
also you wanna you wanna you wanna see
how to get looking yes when I see if
they wear note so the web management at
our tip so you wanna go and see exactly
they're not supportive you have to be
sending no dogs no no no no no don't do
you wanna ain't neva so you wanna see if
you need some time no no so basically
once you have your blocks whatever step
so cool so so we banded that destination
face so we test that test at the
technique that we talked about you have
dated my defense
and the good part is we Louis de
Chasseur to use for hearts we know
mister notes of our texture right which
is going to be helpful when you do your
hunt so now you wanna do your hunting so
you've done your simulation you wanna
you said poop we we tell you this we
cannot detect it but now we updated our
our software our security software so we
pretty sure that the net attacks will
Detailers
but now when I see if we have not
already hacked so we go hunting for us
they sent it the first step will be to
correctly or not
if on your attack you had you sir
HTTP HTTP a request going hot so you
want to take your poxy mugs so basically
you wanna you want to map your I text so
you can use your antivirus and up see
some more nuts so when you do your
simulation
you're gonna party need to system or
tools and when you do your networking
simulation values or IDs
not everything from your formative
machine again any chains like dividends
for stuff easily so now that you have
your notes so they were techniques that
used to process the preferred technique
that we use mostly good searching
because we know we've got your comity
cuts for our simulation simulation you
can search for a specific one of us so
if you if there was a file called nav
nav data doc we can take the popular web
set for that form but so that session
that's easy way to do I can use the
counting basically this is the console
so you can you can search for spit
specific user agent string and if you
find the one with the least occurrence
so basically the one that is what you
need then you can focus on that one and
see why is this again hope you can take
groups of steps if I'm life and wonders
so basically that's the deal
so yeah you said she might even learn it
on the network page so you wanna side
remember
you wanna start an in-depth level stuff
so living being sudden everyone in their
transition stuff for example here
telenovelas another user agent either
so you want to follow that boy network
then you'll find some host cities is
basically act event then you find some
post so when we find some species then
you can go to those do specific post and
that's how I realized and so what's your
time if you if you feel like there are
some suspicious activity that item to
the forensics guys something wrong here
p7 and then you get it execute your
incidences also we need we need to do
taking apart you need to have the
results in easy reach and get me hearty
did you say at the pool I didn't find
anything it's still good if you didn't
find any you prove that there's probably
nothing
also you can have something malicious or
something not mention somebody for me
see I'm deleted so they who have found
something that's not much education but
if all right so now we confirm if you
under a table of using hunting so we
basically have an idea how we go know me
used this technique we know we can
detect this technique we know that we
are not an attic but active and if we're
not able now we need to measure
effectiveness so we won't know as I said
of course it's or money just need me to
measure measure to measure stuff so the
guy committed what for better about he
guess change energy and shows you how to
email yourself atop okay
changes on a quarterly basis and show
you okay this is how we're doing with
the hands-on stuff this is where we need
to focus on so we can go there was a
very good
top and a blog post about stuff yeah so
please take aways here said I tell you
get to paid parking defense which is
cool get you find bad guys and
pentesters on a network you get to doing
stuff like get your light poles you get
to do cool helps that actually makes it
a blind an organization so get to see
them at that measure stiffness you get
to see that you actually help in your
company to move instead of saying hey I
had you this is this is this is nah you
got to say they're cool look ahead and I
made the company better good maybe
getting that we can get upon us to and
you get to teach and then from the blue
team to serve the idea is that you use a
bartender as a red team I need to be
able to to talk or to I told her what is
talk so this is big
last month they did and I thought the
same conversation just updated from the
same so we've been talking my rough
stuff now people are essentially these
people have these tools so you can use
color theorem which is ejected by might
are the same people who talked about
later
anyone there you really actually they
released a tool yesterday but it hope
would be this weekend
so there's also dumpster fire for
assimilations dev squad vm if you wanna
if you do thread haunt you do you have a
video Medicare dunno what I guess you
yeah they can motoring stuff just make
things easier for you the cesium VM for
incident yeah so this will do that post
hunting stuff when I is this V able to
connect that loss at effects which is so
we talk about poor ideas if you want to
do network monitoring this one for
system itself
hello is your free
combination - lets see Spencer Barnes
come on yeah so you're gonna use that
and this poor son back to skate this
case is oscillating
what a simulation to see I'm key to
develop thank you so these guys you
probably want to avoid them if you
enough and some resources and training
and also some training special thanks to
these guys venom Smith is Marconi - I'm
glad Kevin Kyne is happen my boss yeah
and George mallet so these guys are for
something so do the common thing they
have with them is that they're very
humble key um this is the code that
alive I use it both offense defense do
you whatever you want
Costigan mainly fit is very limited
knowledge
this is festival as dusty he questions
[Applause]