alright so next up we have veronika
who's talking to us about instead of
things the key to routing the human
being anyone hear me okay so should I
stand normally or my toes okay so my
talk is not a presentation it's more of
an interactive conversation so I'm going
to ask some questions and I'm hoping
you're going to talk back otherwise I'm
going to put people on the spot I'm very
good at it so I'm going to speak about
the Internet of Things
it's the buzzword it's a sexy word it's
it's what's new and enticing but has
anyone heard about a smart hospital it's
a horror show in my opinion they are
planning to connect to all medical
devices to a single card service so that
anyone a physician or a nurse pharmacist
radiologist can have access to your
information so let's start Who am I I'm
the VP's I call me Veronica that's
reserved to my parents or my husband's
an undershirt but generally be nice and
for maybe I am a Jane one cyborg with a
passion for breaking things to make them
work it in so I have a pacemaker this is
why I'm passionate about the medical
security not to say someone's gonna hack
me because I'm I'm really not a target
but it's something that can affect the
future of someone out there because you
can tell me if the first medical device
is hacked any human being do you think
someone else has got a heart problem is
gonna have one implanted No
so what happens the life expectancy is
lower and we die younger with curable
diseases or something that can help you
live longer so now my question to the
audience should medical devices be put
on the internet of things
No
okay so you buy a TV no no we not but
the thing is we need to identify what is
convenient versus what is not just safe
but secure so it's not to say this is
doom and gloom this is to say we're
gonna talk about what's wrong and how
are we gonna fix it but now I'm going to
ask you this well I'm not gonna put my
heart on the internet and I'll explain
to you later and then you wouldn't want
to do it either so you buy a flat-screen
TV
so you buy flat screen okay so that
might be right for someone that's not in
my shoes or someone that doesn't have a
neural transmitter you're sitting on the
outside thinking oh it's never gonna
happen
well dick dick chaney
replaced his pacemaker with an older
model due to him having wireless
controllers but it's a theoretical
thread that is what the vendors are
claiming and that is what they're
sticking with so as I'm seeing it's
gonna be interesting I'm enjoying it
carry on so I'm not gonna go and
everyone can read the internet of things
what is it we all know what it is do I
need to clarify that okay so medical
devices medical devices is basically
most of the devices in a hospital and
those are the devices the doctors used
to remote monitor you so he's sure that
they can identify problems before they
happen that's what he's used to do
chased suits and so forth okay so now
I'm most hospitals and and this was done
on a questionaire basis we actually
discussed this with hospitals decide you
what's on your wireless LAN the MRI
machines are on because for therm we
needs to be
David and I can promise you someone's
not gonna sit and physically do it they
gonna remote push it that is our the
vendor laughing your insulin pumps who
knows how our insulin pump works so it
remotely monitors you and then can
adjust your dosage according to the
parameters that your doctor has set to
give your router's of insulin but this
is then connected to a home device that
is connected to your Wi-Fi that
communicates back to the doctor but
that's the insulin pump and it's a good
thing because it ensures people are
getting adequate medical care as they
need it was I for example I know a
diabetic that doesn't look after himself
he doesn't shake his sugar so he easily
goes into a coma it's just not
responsible enough to do it on his own
so insulin pumps in that case would be
very good then robotic surgery arms who
knows what that is that is what they
used to do precision surgical work and
that is done by setting specific
parameters like these also need firmware
updates which is also pushed across a
network and the same of your CT scan
scanners and your heart pumps for media
is a very important one those things are
in put in your water and it's one pump
your heart those things are all in the
wireless LAN in hospital dialysis
machines infusion pumps pacemakers and
then the worst of them all the latest
trend and medical devices called remote
home monitoring system it's a little
device that sits next to your bed that
communicates with your implantable
device communicates back to your doctor
so they can do telemedicine the my
doctor effectively can access my face
making a thing to guide with it for the
universal token and see what's happening
if he then sees something needs to be
adjusted he can do it while I sleep but
it's also connected to my Wi-Fi and we
all know phone wi-fi's I'm not
yeah you all might be but the general
public not in security or not as
conscious as we are now I watched a
video on YouTube where they explained
the concept of a smart hospital
meaning that you would be given a single
card that contains all your medical data
that you would scan at reception
it would identify which way you would go
to what treatment you opted for and that
would communicate what sensors placed
like a Fitbit or a medical device that
you wear to tell the doctors with your
state of health is for example if you
have high blood pressure it would
identify where you've got spikes or
where medicines not working and it goes
so far as to say that it will be
integrated with the pharmacy
so you'd unlock your medicine as you're
supposed to take it it will then give
you a certain amount and everything is
integrated to your physician never has
to see you face to face it is all done
electronically which is not a bad idea
it's convenient but I don't think that
convenience should trump security and
safety and that is the stand that I'm
taking it's it's fine to have convenient
medicine but it should be conveniently
safe and secure medicine and you
shouldn't give up that up just because
we don't want to go into a doctor's
office so this is what they are planning
on doing having everything integrated
into a single system but we all know the
healthcare system is not known for
having the best updates or firmware or
security we've seen it with the events
we wanna crime was an example that hit
the inner chai hard due to something
that was easily fixable long ago legacy
systems and that is a reason that
medical security is lacking
this is legacy systems that are running
and being forgotten about this is the
mid fusion 4000 wireless syringe
infusion pump that is useful the
injection in terminal patients patients
now this was a study done by uk-based
company that have identified the
following vulnerabilities in these
devices now it's your buffer overflow
attacks there's no justification on the
devices hard-coded credentials on the
device itself hard-coded passwords
passwords which are stored in the
configuration field to make convenience
ease of easier for people to log in and
proper access control now if you have a
device that is responsible for giving
morphine these are not the
vulnerabilities that you would want to
see now I know it's terrifying but it's
fixable and this is what the vendor
could art in public remedial steps that
hospitals can take instead of redoing
their firmware in spending the time and
researching and actually having the code
tasted they said that the hospital
should just assign a static IP address I
don't really see how that's gonna help
and I wanted to follow DNA's in the HTTP
DHCP server traffic well this is one
community working so well in the forest
we gonna think of things after they've
happens after a patient and got and will
see in their system and let me tell you
two did some too much morphine you stop
breathing so that's in of these delays
ensure network segmentation and this is
the most shocking part in hospital these
devices on the wireless LAN but they not
segregated from the rest of the network
containing patient details so you get
into a device you get into the network
using VLANs for segmentation
available applying proper password
hiking because you all know that we are
so all we're dealing with people we
choose the passes the easiest remember
or we drafted on a sticky note
I spend considerable time in laughs
audiences with a family member
walking around watching workstations
with user name and password on sticky
notes I have pictures of it
ask me and I'll show you but to make
matters worse was the network share pass
on there was their usernames enforcers
but the submission does not want to walk
at this time ladies
even in a sauce with the easiest most
convenient way they are there to save
lives they are not feasible this is your
network
that's not their problem but we does
have fear invest their money they can
see us healthcare not say to see our
security and that is the problem we're
facing with healthcare as a whole it's
moving with technology but it's not
focusing equally on before to pop I mean
do not be impossible and generally most
of these things you can only use six
characters and no special characters as
well so this is my real passion is a
hacking pacemakers and it's not to kill
someone I've been like human beings but
I want to fix it so my concept is I've
always been I want to fix the security
without taking away the veil ability
Nexus ability of our services
professionals those imagine this now I
have an episode I'll fall down I'm not
going to tell the paramedics I wait
before I darling
baby give you your flight isn't any
password you all know that's not gonna
work
so we can't make it too strict or
encrypt data if you in a strange country
and they have to access your device it's
quite the conundrum on fixing the
problems without cutting the
opposition's hands so I think
so basically my device is an ICD
implantable cardiac defibrillator so
meaning my heart stops it shocks me so
if I do if anything is just no probably
good shot so let's some of the work on
the pacemakers name you would think is
it a good idea to have hard-coded
credentials on a pacemaker no they do
9 out of 10 device manufacturers
hard-coded their credentials on the
device itself and then you would think
okay but this is not going to be in
clear text or ASCII code well I'm gonna
tell you wrong because it is so the firm
we is not signed which is generally a
bad idea so meaning if I write something
that looks like firmly that matches
we've supposed to go this device is
going to open up and accept it and it
gets better if you know how to do the
handshake there's no specific memory
that I've stretching it into a ward
protective storage it will just accept
it so this is my theory which the vendor
that I discussed it with did not enjoy I
right firm when I go into a
cardiologists my cardiologist has got
five hundred face maker patients it's in
bloom for the small town can you imagine
driving okay time these machines
infected it then infects my machine to
beacon art on the correct handshake with
all medical devices and Ansel in the
hospital I reinfect other ones and a
beacons home now you've gotta solve the
army of human beings irritable you know
or hypothetical is what professor would
say would be the correct term to use the
file system is not encrypted on these
devices and these are both the doctors
programmer the base make itself and the
home devices
who can tell me what file system we're
looking at this is one does XP which
most of the program is run on and guess
how you put it on just press the button
and it'll just come on that's what the
cardiologists told me I want you must
I'm a cardiologist thinks there's
something wrong with me because I wanna
had come our own device not kill myself
but I'd rather kill myself and kill
someone else see I am ethical now this
one's a big one for me so any Dave herbs
or anyone it does programming would say
you need to tell the device what I can't
accept in context it well that is the
good idea however medical devices most
of them don't have command whitelisting
so if it looks like it smells like an X
like it it will do it
now this grates me
so in asking the vendors why they said
but we want power over security meaning
our patients don't want to come in once
every five years to have the device has
changed you know so we kind of have big
computing power that's gonna drain a
battery we want the batteries to last 20
years
well I'd rather go in every 10 years or
five years and have the device changed
suffer for three months but know it's
safe and secure we can't just give up
for convenience safety because we're not
talking about someone hacking a computer
rendering the services unusable if you
hack my device which I will explain some
of their text later all physically fall
down and die you don't come back from
that kind of thing
there is no reboot restart your ok
resuscitation it's not gonna happen
it'll call maybe it's not all doom and
gloom
no one finds a face see I told your
mother comedian okay that's a little bit
scary it's called a crash attack
basically means that your pacemakers
going to start doing some funny funky
retro stuff it's gonna start pacing and
unknown speeds but once you have access
to the device which is fairly easy after
the fact I'll explain them to anyone
that wants to know that was in a
previous book it basically if you know
the pattern of the RF packet that it's
expecting to see and it's facing the
universal the same across all devices
you with a serial number you could
effectively gain access it will say okay
no that looks right what do you want me
to do so how it works is when you access
a pacemaker
it goes into debug mode which allows a
physician to the in programmer
so it goes from debug mode to
programming mode now the very
interesting factor that stays open for
two hours effectively broadcasting and
waiting for signals once it's been
programmed I don't know why no one can
answer me but effectively that's maybe a
doctor changes his mind
two hours phoned you back he doesn't
have to go through the whole process
again so when you incorrectly
preservation you can go from having a
baseline beat of 60 to 120 to 170 and
effectively that's how it's going to
carry on because it controls your top
and your lower part of your heart then
this is probably the most likely one to
happen anyway they drain the battery but
basically overwhelming system so in
regards to pacemakers it comes 1 packet
2 packets free packet and it stops at 9
now this is the interesting effect you'd
think if you overflow it if it's ok now
often I take it something's not right
cut communication it restarts at 1 so
effectively keeping it on the whole time
by sending immense amounts of packets
you could drain the battery low if I was
doing this I would have communication
off the nine and you'd have to go into
the physician's office to see what's
going on with the device these devices
are made to go into sleep mode to
conserve battery power and this is
really easy did you
okay so that's the protocol that most
medical devices use how did I find this
on the internet because you can download
the pod specification for every device
so this is either ethical Google who's
your friend you go to the vendor website
you download read manual for the doctor
which you don't need to user name of
course but what's freely available you
then get your pot specification and you
go to that vendor and download how it
works and voila now you know entire tech
dot for the heck is in the room these
look very familiar as we see it every
day we use it every day I wonder if
there's a Metasploit packet for me you
know there's a business model for
someone so who knows what black boxing
is most people but that's how easy it is
most of the hackers that have worked on
this is youth back black box techniques
they reverse the protocols because they
know how that imagination worked so they
know what they see they know how to put
it back to what it was Oh
you basically have got the keys to the
kingdom you've got the keys to someone's
heart or neurostimulator or gastric chip
the each so many medical devices arts is
even a pull now that you swallow it was
an amount of medicine that wirelessly
controlled in a justified position yep
no one said these things was
I might be gone in yet but like I said
something should not be on the Internet
I know we want everything on the
internet but there are some things that
should not be okay so basically the
replay attack is reverse engineering the
protocol okay that's what I explained
there's no remedial steps you ask them
well how do you know if something
happens on a pacemaker what's your
incident response plan they can't answer
you so here's a hypothetical question
for someone someone dies with a
pacemaker or neurochip something happens
there's supposed to be trace evidence
there's supposed to be a trace of an EKG
saying oh no he had a heart attack but
there's no electrical stimulation then
you ask the vendor you say so what have
you got in place identify these no we
don't have anything cause the doctors
will rule that you're natural causes but
he's got our odd problem where we should
actually be putting these devices
interrogating them and actually seeing
why they're failing so the whole
statement of no one to our best
knowledge has been hacked is a statement
made by legal you sure no one gets sued
because I've got no insurance response
plan so they don't know if they've been
hacked it's not you should never feel
what you know you should feel what you
don't know and we don't know of devices
or medical devices that have been hacked
why because they are thinking it's
natural causes because someone's got a
disease anyone I'll see a problem with
us well they just mean hey this is my
favorite the little in the now of life
attack come on I've got some excellent
names you God cannot complain
it's you like I'm not doing a horror
show yeah it's a deathbed
no one is bad you know so then we know I
you know I pathetically so the other
thing is winner device is in debug mode
so I'm sorry day and I'm gonna make an
example of you again I spoke at a
conference I tried to murder me I'm
still yeah thankfully magnets or a big
problem for me to go devices that
interfere with communication so I'm an
ex-con
they give me a badge or wear it because
you know proud I'm a speaker I still
pretty I'm thinking I'm not nervous and
you know the thing starts pulling and I
think it open like how the boss that's
like with magnets on and it was a strong
enough mega to put my device into debug
mode so meaning the signal got blocked
and this thing decided nots gonna have
an easy-fit gonna throw a tantrum and
paste me at a faster speed but what
happens when your heart beats boss took
that pressure goes up sweetie
yes and then we realize that if that is
our sensitive the communication protocol
on those devices are even helped me when
I go through a magnetic scanner but
that's also why UConn goes through MRIs
except for the obvious at all food that
out of you and it will look like a
horror show it will effectively switch
at all okay so once you start
interrogating of the lines it's pretty
much like a right they're not gonna say
no it's going to be there for the
picking it's like the lowest of low
hanging fruit so the message is
identical as I said with most devices
because a doctor doesn't want to have
six or seven devices for each vendor the
single one for Medtronic's and Judes
phillips
all work on the same protocol they can
all the thing to get on the same devices
so it would be pretty much like having
all devices open with a single password
not a good idea
and you don't need to be closed because
it one since you're but it's nice make a
hack I need to be close to you to do it
no I think the furthest away was 50
meters but if you've got Mike as Mike in
the room with these antennas you know
I'm saying care of him excuse me
it's possible now who would have a
medical device only like 19 and I mean
it's murder it's murder made easy you
don't have to stab someone then I have
to be close to them it's machine killing
and if you keep it alive for long enough
unless if they they they estimate 48
hours over the night of Logitech and
your battery would just die and there's
no warning
there's no beacon that pops out and says
oh I'm gonna die soon I won't know not
that I want it don't get me wrong I
don't want to be walking in the street
and having a longer walk because my
pacemakers about died because I probably
would have a heart attack not related to
my health issues so basically what this
means and the specific thing is that you
can extend the window for the denial of
life attack instead of being on for two
hours you can specify up to 72 hours
that's the couple never in my life have
I seen a doctor that works even two
hours straight next to one single
patient again logic with security and
development it's just not there but why
would we use third-party libraries its
proprietary but its proprietary that we
bought from different libraries nothing
is written specifically for that vendor
okay so these are some of the changes
that a doctor can make to my device or
any device
you can let the device beacons identify
itself who's seen homelands broken heart
I tried to get the episode for you guys
we're they actually hacked the base
making killed president that only
happens in America but it was pretty
accurate the research showed that that
was probably one of the most accurate
hacking scenes that Hollywood got right
you can be compassion doctor was again
nothing's encrypted all my daughters on
this little device in my chest that says
Veronica Schmidt has got this disease
this is how we pacing her this is what
happens and this is where doctors hmm
what information you want our thing like
I said it discusses your cardiac
daughter
it can change the patient's thoughts so
when they check your pacemaker the
doctor would say hey I said this is
what's wrong with you but most doctors
as we all know don't know each patient
it may be in bloom was it small not a
lot of people but imagine if you change
someone's disease or you shock them at a
higher level now if you shock someone
and double their they like you know
electricity that's needed you're gonna
fry the heart muscle no one really comes
back from that kind of thing it's not
something like in capital for the place
and you can reno if the firm wait that's
probably the biggest thing for me that
you can actually make us run whatever
you wanted to run and this is not just
enough i haven't scared you enough this
is really the world's moving to an
integrated City versus then eventually
integrated internationally into one
system yeah I know this it sounds like
something no that's gonna be wonderful
this is gonna be done by 2020
I think it's fallen over jeans already
started with Olympics and look what
Tilly's presentation really showed that
looks like I want to live there until
you just take a step back and just think
about some of the smaller elements Oh
we put our they the Internet is great
but the Internet does not make for
everything there are just some things
that should stay offline okay so this is
one of the fictional found of a hospital
room this was very accurate because
sitting in emergency room for like eight
hours waiting to the health and you
start like scanning and listening for
devices I know it's not legal
I did not do it it's hypothetical these
I cannot go to jail this face I'm not
going to work most of the devices or
even Wi-Fi Bluetooth integrated with a
pair but that the physician or the nurse
has a Percy TV I know this but often why
I just know all it a gut feeling into a
woman's intuition is the correct word
are thing so I know James thought
together Angelou is boring and stupid
and I kind of love it because I've
actually taken micro machine I know you
guys any feel sorry for this and like
abused it on a live system on a large
network to see what it does now you can
think that devices for me can be changed
without it throwing too much trouble
your way along until we have the likes
of Lockean server locked up just my
jigsaw closet suck on a medical device
so I don't know if anyone has studied at
Rhodes University okay so some
interesting conversations happen around
the dinner table there we discussed and
did our own plan of ransomware
I imagine the scenario you ran some way
the physicians machine he infects his
patients you charge him a higher amount
of Bitcoin versus the patient then pays
you monthly or use of their organs
because if they date they don't need
them it's a profitable market it's not a
good one if not ethical it's not nice we
don't kill human beings I just want to
emphasize it please don't go killing
someone I'm not gonna take
responsibility for that
so there's on Cheney saying you know you
might not have our goal before this
pacemaker maybe we'll have a heart of
Bitcoin it's possible these devices are
powerful those lithium batteries and the
processing capabilities are fairly good
for a little computer with an antenna
was that effectively what's placed
inside your body so someone said to me
why would someone try good healthcare I
don't know because his bad people on the
internet that's what they do know
they've never been very secure
it's unfortunate truth that's a sad
truth but we know it they haven't made
catchable to all okay it's a high-value
target because they're gonna want to fix
things sooner rather than later cause
people are gonna die
health your daughter's lucrative what is
the biggest committed commodity on the
door with information something that you
can constantly sell the healthy daughter
is very important it's an application
here the environment everything runs on
a backing you've got oncology radiology
pathology histology and a lot of other
apologies that I'm not even gonna
mention there's just too many and it
uses out-of-date system with most
vendors have got specific chips that
only run X be lucky not older than that
much like the days before actually but
this is because at all to those and
access is placed above security we want
to make it easy
the last thing you as an archivist needs
is a notice phoning it's at you know
this workstation I cannot remember my
password but I need to give a patient's
medicine that's that's why I keep faces
the sticky notes on
I thought the nurses it's because we
want to make it easy to access
information so these are some of the
vulnerabilities that have been found in
healthcare it's not all hospitals or bed
there are some that are really doing
some good work
some of a questionable look we won't
name names and disgrace people is it you
know I'm working in a health care no one
so I'm not offending anyone in tomatoes
anyone have any more toes that's all so
hey they're not really a way of network
safety if you ask a doctor so is my
pacemaker hackable
he rolls his eyes and say no but what
kind of person would hack a pacemaker
and these I'm not making this up this is
what I've been told you know monitoring
and logging it's time to monitor and log
in sometime when you're half time you're
gonna look at these things but then the
incident has happened
so we actively looking for things that
have happened you should be looking now
I don't even think hospitals do pain
case or medical devices
maybe there's a business model someone
that should be done these devices should
be pain tasted collaboration is the
biggest key in security we collaborate
on code and we test these devices we
know what the weaknesses are it's it's
the same you know your enemy at the
stage we don't know what the enemy is we
waiting for it to happen
and obviously we all know I'm not I
don't even want to go into all of it
little things that everyone knows but it
is just in healthcare the main thing is
I want access immediately again if you
employ security you take away immediate
access but that's not the best thing you
know everyone said configure was they'd
okay hmm Hospital go ahead for the last
year again why because I still didn't
catch the vulnerabilities and I still
run a legacy system as I had Kenna paint
is that what's the first thing you look
for all vulnerabilities and we know most
of Isis on segmented in hospitals so if
you get to when you get to another
thing is your biggest to health
game okay
another pretty graphic to show how they
hope to integrate everything okay
another fun stuff oh I would do it I'm
not saying it's the only way or the
right way you know I kind of not did all
from thinking how am I gonna hack the
hospitals and then going to them and
killing them and then watching like that
drop you know when a bomb drops schwa
and it happens so you so convinced the
parameter which is you know doing this
is stuff that you guys teach every day
okay so most of these things I've got
patient websites that you log into so
how has your experience been those
things are all on the wireless
and it's not like someone's gonna peep
of your shoulder and say what are you
doing
- once you circumvent that you can
perfect and you scan for internal
connections and yeah this is not the
medical devices and then you can just
effective eise can you see what devices
are out there and you already know
there's no username a password we
already know there's nothing it's gonna
stop you it's not like there's a
firewall on a morphine system or AV not
that I think that would help but those
are one possibility that might happen
and you compromise the device by for
example your different bernetta machines
in the ER on the wireless LAN why
because they connect in statistics they
want to know that this machine as a
vendor is optimally functioning now you
have patient a I've got an into your
network
I have compromised the device and I've
switched it off so you can actually take
it and go gonna happen and effectively a
lot is lost the waiting room attack
but this worked in the cardiologists
office as well by just sniffing the RF
signals between the program and the
devices you could actually intercept
them I mean that's done with a backpack
on your back reading a book now if you
in a waiting room and all these wireless
devices are open and they connected to
the land on the hospital side you can
imagine one bad guy sitting there and
effectively pivot around in your network
and this is probably the biggest problem
is that most websites are not very
secure or most internal systems used by
hospitals I still open to old legacy
hacks effectively tricking the website
to think your physician and physicians
have got high level access they can do
anything and you can effectively
download data so they can so while I'm
at in Lourdes in hospital I am if people
said was a keen USB I just want to make
that decision
it's a workstation and you would think I
get locked it's not it's open and you
would think I go so it's only gonna have
trusted devices that's what makes it so
who would like to guess what happened
without that maybes being exactly so
nothing you imagine if I had one of my
dodgy ones very like that in I didn't
think I would have liked very much and
these are the problems that are faced
facing but I think if they start taking
these singles the Internet of Things
perhaps taking a step back and saying
okay fundamentals in security you know
let's apply those principles that we
were all taught not that odd but the
problem is they're facing legacy
legacies the nitramene security that
everyone faces
now I feel like I'm walking on it but it
is the problem we're facing you know
somewhat a company is not going to go in
and say okay I'm gonna replace all my
servers because it doesn't make sense
and Finance doesn't want to spend money
on IT and security because it's not
really a cost seeing tour doesn't bring
in money but then I must say there are
companies that are spending the time on
research for example my device thank
goodness for there has got a fail-safe
in so it's got protective memory that's
firmwares in their memory section so for
you to change it you effectively have to
know where to write to a first-strike
soft B Bob for two hours then counter
ticks second time hard webrick that
makes me feel a little bit better
doesn't make me feel better that the
schneid me by saying it doesn't have a
wireless controller when technically it
does it's just software switch tool but
they need to fix the fundamentals it
comes back to that the whole thing that
we've been taught not everything needs
to be on the internet you know it's not
like you undress yourself and face
yourself and what I don't some people do
but it's the same thing your life is
your most secure thing okay so for me to
kill you now I need to do something
physically to you
so why God's right knots way do you want
to put your body on the Internet if
someone can reach you because you have a
medical device it's the same with the
foot but there's been cases where that
has been forensic ly used to put someone
in jail
someone's pacemaker data has been used
to convict him because they said if you
were running away your heart with a
speed up you were calm while you were
killing your wife no it's a real case
generally I don't think we know where to
draw the line anymore it's a new thing
the Internet of Things are are they like
a new toy
everyone wants it but common sense has
to say yeah where do we draw the line
you know everyone's in that uproar about
AI seen ten beings coming to kill us no
a hacker is going to come and kill you
with your own medical device because
you've put it on the internet so for me
the conversation needs to be we now know
what's wrong
how do we fix it and that's
collaboration between industries it
should not be a secret how my devices
programmed what the software is Myriam
oh that's a PhD professor the does the
same research says you cannot have
security and obscurity and it is right
we need to be able to be open about it
USB attack what would happen if someone
in office lock drops a USB and walks
away nine out of ten people would put it
in their machines and this has happened
in a hospital in bloom not funny I'm
innocent when you maintain it but
someone spread malware in that manner
and these are things that every day from
little views okay some interesting
statistics is that 6.4 billion devices
will be connected by the Wi-Fi by the
end of this year which is now but all so
that's six point four billion potential
targets it's getting interesting this
landscape is you know it's no longer and
in the previous days before my time I
suppose you'd have like minimum
landscape you know a lot a lot of
devices when the internet that was a
commodity that was expensive unless your
dad work for telecom then you had it
from a young age it's becoming quite
worrisome to me by the end of 2020
that's 21 billion devices and this
includes medical devices so most
hospitals will effectively have gone
wireless 85 percent of the enterprises
bang they ready only 10% already
confidence but are you gonna visit a
hospital so are you confident that you
are safe and secure what do you think
they're gonna say we unhackable cuz
that's the trend it's never gonna happen
to us hey we're forward it comes down to
the vendors it comes down to taking the
vulnerable medical devices and actually
fixing the problems they need to figure
out hard to detect in real time we need
to be proactive not reactive they need
to be able to quickly respond and
recover from attacks but see it's a
double-edged sword the remote monitoring
would enable us to know something's gone
wrong but it's also getting able an
attacker to make things go wrong it's
generally alive you know what is
wonderful technologically can be used to
your detriment you know I suppose in the
ever design Stuxnet food it was going to
be very beneficial for them and some got
out of control it is always a
double-edged sword and firmly needs to
be updated regularly when lost you think
generally most hospitals update medical
equipment firmware every 36 months
that's when the vendors come in to do
maintenance I can tell you though
firmware updates on face makers are fun
I had to have one I had some software
bugs it's not due to being with magnets
they decided that machine learning was a
good thing to have in a pacemaker I
don't quite know yet why so it learns
from my heart what's wrong with my heart
to fix it no the physician knows what's
wrong with my heart it should tell the
face maker what it's supposed to do and
it should just do it
so the
since yeah you can just hear from the
name is a smart pacemaker that does not
work and these things on cheap
I think it's a handful in eighty
thousand for my one thank goodness I've
got medical aid otherwise I would have
to take out a bond on my house next
basically is the horror shows over
[Applause]