my name is Gary Disney liners I went to
Air Force Institute technology and
Defense Acquisition University
by study I T in project management from
that pretty much I
started Linux development for secure
systems
and that's where mantra comes to players
I develop mantra pretty much
to ensure that we and user could have a
secure virtualized platform to past
and be able to pretty much at the end as
their test case
shutdown flush it and then to redeploy
no bf the Camry 2.0 therefore you can
restart your session pretty much exactly
that was the idea via sandboxing through
artsy
I'm so pretty much about
me a little bit more as I am apart from
security engineer
at high trust had trust builds cloud
security
and compliance testing a promote
compliance
and what I do is I use mantra to break
it
ago and I punch in the face every day
that is my job so when I have to do is
pretty much
figure out what a black hat would do to
the system
and that is in theory seems like it
would be more
difficult than it
there's but in reality I'm for being a
black hat is
I want controls I want to be able to
take over everything
that's all black I really want is the
data from not so
what we do is we pretty much guarantee
the security of different appliances
inside your the cloud so I had to make
sure that
three dollars they cannot attack our
appliance so
what is meant to us men traverses
advertise attack platform
designed around the mantra security
token head and I'll austerity repository
on the I am security okay it was about
by
get mantra which is on I'm and busty
beauty even posit re: is Matt resource
and and the Commission does to me
pretty much created a independent OS
Metro us was the vote for Scott testing
professional pen testing environment
and has been really optimize over the
last yr year-and-a-half
far promotes virtual environments a one
from
pretty much a distribution to a virtual
appliance and over a year
driven we said joan anybody that wants
to because also
on our user base 75 percent men
transistors are virtualized so it seemed
to me as
the best route to goal was to virtualize
said
even further Tim guarantee integration
between desktops and
that VMware ecosystem um
it is about one I so noob a.m. which is
an ass and I
standard so that fits compliance not
sounds
I am how I implemented
mantra lesson to hide trust was pretty
much through
they hired me and and they said we want
security
cue track so I said okay I'm
some very much I am
decide mantra would be my best course
because I knew it inside out because I
was the developer on that
and from there have I had implements cap
and other testing protocols so have a
compliance PCI compliance
different components housing and
security so
one we send out to a customer and they
say
we help them keep combines our product
itself is compliant
Tom pretty much we Aussies are from $1
billion verification testing through its
mess
pollen and other back and spat pretty
much exploit
a I did put a previous owner and
it's pretty much you will see on the
demo how its integrated with the desktop
environment I love
VMware so
I redo I designed for McConnell up
the first thing I did was give the GR
security kernel patch what's the kernel
patch
actually gives a pretty much like I am
the model insight com gives an extra
security so
you can't do bad things to the server
itself
I also game open VZ chrome which axe for
dispatch
as a virtualization and job task handler
and I use a generally crappy cluster
with KVM to ensure that
if you wanted builders of into a team
server you could be easily do that
and have model partial answers Bay stop
the gas filesystem
a mantra us so that would make it easier
for
an enterprise situation for testers to
user
and then show us has
currently running three containers and
two sandboxes on every desktop
and since then is running so I use open
VZ
as they contain a controller for ok seem
and then rushers pretty much the
1.00 match OS had a sandbox
but then I said we can go further with
us so
when I did as I took that pretty much
that D Bus hug and I'm
many into wanna go still IDM
the pretty much goes the whole desktop a
sandbox
and penitent pretty much controlled
delivered for Joomla
GMC insurers that any and the see
pile compiled programs are sandboxed and
are pretty much starting Tampa and
flushed
at shutdown so this is
virtual core its quite large for
virgil cooper um basically
below if I and biases bare metal 'em
that doesn't particularly matter in this
case
so there's enough I BIOS I use grub2
big ramps and the been busy Khanom
been the Jan 19 and the music control
talks
via the genetic cluster 2 Kb I'm Tim
and then liberal ensures that the lupine
is constant
and the dust out is pretty much the PBS
and a vet for the Alex ease so
when the task is called a bike such a
shutdown when you have this many Birch
Run
processes running shutting down is
actually quite a task because as Intel
each of those virtual and scissors it
has to shut down
so pretty much live dispatch goes
through all those layers and Sons
initial 0r mission 11 every maybe
to give it the task I'm shutting down
so I was shown a demo how the IPS is
working but a
I gave IDS and IPS solution the IDS
answer Cana
which is like smart but a open see also
gives you a lot larger dynamic have
workspace
monitoring your ideas I also use are
totally in honey from my ideas
and watch that does is actually enables
the honeyed is set to make it look like
an eye as summer
and artillery gives that they can a
Sharpie seaports and all that stuff to
make a little look like it is. armor
I also it has contain a base and boxing
which are covered
then I also a minute Obama an ass Yonex
so
in something was to go around like a say
I Palmer will protect Firefox
because if you're running a social
engineering you don't wanna get your
browser per se hoped
at Parmer will try to protect that Tom
so this is the security audit talk had
bad I'm
pretty much worked out the with WT with
Matt ends at Bourbon
multi ego metal spoon armitage
which I'm intense slashed MSF gimme and
ends on map which is an maps Q me
also I asked the last week matter add
access our which is legs in a tax
project but for
1x I we have for packet capture
either cap and Wireshark your cap
is pretty much the burpee capetown
dollars
brentwood also there's also helps those
benefit us by showing us what happens
the ideas ideas one it is
properly running we have
for web applications Gunners we have
Skype session cutone Priory
single injection we have sequel brew
segal map and sickle map integration
entire collection multi ego now the fun
part we actually get to
pack some stuff on
welcome
as you can see on this one that ire de
set up a scam this is a website hosted
by Tom Lehrer so
you might know when you stumble after
seeing this but that it has cross-eyed
scripting
massive amount possible sequel gentle
points
after testing I can tell you fact shale
uses Oracle database even though its own
post-crescent hypersonic
and pretty much lemme
with Mercy Corps injection and the cross
site scripting
this site is one more formal ones I
could find so I thought it was ideal for
demo and
com
so much that I use as my primary a
scanner to see when I'm can do to this
any application I'm scanning so what I
did as
pretty much now I'm going to do is a
sequel map injection
the Oracle Preminger and said the
database management software to Oracle
so that
hopefully in theory we can get some date
out a lot
yeah
love
and
so pretty much this is telling yet I am
using the database
my dad indeed that but I database to
Oracle and hamper
I mean is the timbre between to ensure
that I can I get an
tampering
pretty much receive amount I film
Tom that's not good
well I'm gonna sit out this time
on
lemme okay so pretty much is gonna try
to inject into this
them photo
why this photo is particularly
vulnerable is
they are all reflect the values inside
their database
someone I inject the photo itself I'm
actually
doing reflective injection into their
mark a database
on um pretty much
but you can see their springs detected
and all that which means
its pretty bad Tom
when in Jackson that would be we'll be
able to get
cheese and a couple other things but I
don't think it's gonna
work man I'm Tom there is make it home
them
which is gonna try to do the scan on
and as you can see it's are defining
final tumbler stuff
inside the contents now West
that s pretty much we can take some
today have
that we found from Sat and other things
like such an icky dome
a blended as we have to generate some
report because people are gonna have to
mention the on and I just on this
information and they re and at that
point
we have to figure out how to me can take
all other than information and
information poss
other tools I use and how we can make
them to a collective
information for rent to share so how
I'm personal and it was everything here
is
inside the virtual appliance because big
June between the dust-up so I can
actually take the information I found
pretty much moved to it my Mac
on its desktop and write a report so
that
its no bounce between no emails no not
trying to get
two devices work at the same time
mom those of us on the other half on
when you're trying to such as on
on see what's going on I'm
stood
who
when you're running attack I lidija keep
your browser up to see
I'm knocking it down like Simmons action
if it's heading the wrong point and can
cause and now serves because this is a
lotta traffic going on
you can be making thousands a request
and so usually
a monitor the website
this nation and its not down
cousins down and Benny thing I clocked
elements gonna be pretty much
lost because it's gonna be bad advancing
was in Jackson's down it's going to mean
bad data
suppose that's so on I wasn't sure that
I'm some other things that user should
be where I am
is pretty much on
mantra originally came with tar but
because of the large security risk
poor sense it's been used as a CNC
another bad
things have been going for it it became
a decision on
when I mean from was being implemented
into a.m. prices you Asian
do you really want war right now towards
back door to a lot about things so
it came as a decision now were not been
implemented I'm
and mr. because that does bad things so
well
at the end result is your IP does not
changes does not have proxy anymore but
your actual
identity as a service has been modified
this memorable very rarely show up as a
proper London Cyrus
so the idea that is it was to be
fingerprinted
by some I can I D S IPS they would
pretty much
not be able to figure out what you are
services what it looks like be four it
actually has
the IPS running it only few services GD
oh man I'm
pretty much a squid proxy servers
and a couple other things running around
on
you know we will we brown not last stand
years
something I am a lot more ports open
the there is no way after a Tory is
running night
bukan positively fingerprint the service
because when it runs its going to
give such a large trainings a from the
finger printing service on the other end
it won't be able to the tact some
on
how's that me sir colors
as you can see on the other end on
pretty much a the gym setting the
connections every time there and map
servers running through
so one we attack be pretty much
fingerprinting and
by parts can I can actually do that and
also at
added parts can attack defender so if
there's an
active parts can eventually if you keep
on running have never never never never
again I'm
it becomes not available the houses down
to that user
they cannot see it so the theory is if
you were able to bridge into and network
and they were trying to figure out what
you are doing
while you're running now's you could
they would never be able to produce a
figure out crew are where you are your
Geo
your goip location because on
beneath the my guess would be a fun goip
but everything else
the pretty much be looking for Windows
box and I S server
which is not the case at all and the
idea is
tried to be communion Joan way to pretty
much
send out flyers and try to protect
yourself when you bring to not work
because
there's one thing they want to do is
kick you off the network when you're not
supposed to be there
and as you can see this is now
injectable by twenty columns
and pretty much it has
wanna buy technique serve the database
the very bottom want to see
injection as you can see simple map is
great for nerd
enterprise solution because it automated
out to a point that
if you have a single a database was
called session that Siebel I
you seceded in the test and if you do
not you founded
spree simplistic and then you can see my
daily ashtec's or trade an
bomb
see more there's also
other tools included such as burp
Tom bamut engine
on that too but
I'm some
at this point does anybody have any
questions
on
ok I'm on
slowed stop translate script and I'm now
on
okay snow on this one
bomb much out of things to say
hey so dozens mantra sure the seat here
offend but downey I highly recommend the
stalls at
I've used it for my mommy's model times
um it I have been able to breach willem
Twitter once and pretty much
everything you need to do
bugged down is now everything else that
you would wanna do
you could do with this operating system
and
be complete virtualize sandbox and
secure while you're running these
attacks
and that's the whole idea mantra is to
sum up as
a tool that is virtualized for
attacking and then collecting data and
being able to disseminate it down
because majority unless you're going for
by have wench
by all means and just use backtrack
that pretty much means be used this
before
the information that you need to give to
premature higher-ups be like that so I
breach our site this is how I did it
and that's when I use manager for I
think that's about all I how
so and impressions
and pretty much Island things The site
sour on
how does it differ from backtracked
pretty much a
the browser itself as an A grade and as
them
the buzz itself is an interview with the
mansion token
and then on top of that no tools are
parted wget repository which
aren't and to be more stable band
per se backtrack which is when and where
people are submitting each year
and that the idea is to give you a
stable
an automated palm operating system
mom
on ok a lost art mantra laos
that's where the virtual pines and
there's also the ice is on SourceForge
you
K yet they made at the remote
attended when he once more new owners
that
abductee made at the most so bean
IPS small my question these this
and then any of their mode so or any
other
where you can switch around the if you
don't deny a summer
you could be an Apache one reason I
chose
something that was not was because if
you can spoof being a Windows service is
being spiffing an Apache server
they're gonna be looking for something
completely different and the Beast at
hand
they're going to be looking for this is.
server that's attacking but in reality
its elements
engine access when Sir attacking on
well looks looks really cool me said
like it last year you're happy worked on
it
mean how often you updates what's a
long-term plan
if there is any barriers arms we have an
annual release planned
technically each one is underway very
long term support
I am every year under revision because
things do change
and the Linux kernel is a member
expensive project that is always growing
so every summer I pretty much go through
a release cycle
and them a release is about October
every year
on
movie questions
home
well