alright thanks I'm so your banker
condone
Mirko CEO in CT 0 NT objectives
I we do web app scanning our product are
key product Ventura spider mom
we focus mostly on webapps but we begin
and branching out into
ideal mobile solana stock is really
gonna be about dealing with the love the
mobile app's
I my blog remembers his web app
dot com podcast I often there as well
so feel free to check that out
brightness talk
is the you know titled The
backing fancy sportsman's really much
more now it's really just kinda
about away I'm starting to attack a lot
in the the new wraps and I'm seeing
and so we're not gonna go a little bit
over some more hacking what 101
mccumber the seven deadly sins %ah
and all get into that the a and then
we'll do some examples a some hacks that
I've actually done
I against various mobile app's and
and will wrap it up so the
first part of it is just understanding
how to do mobile hacking
I'm wearing a really start want to come
out how your set up for this
job one other things that I really
encourage is to look beyond the device
in your hand
a lot of people are focused on the
mobile binaries and
and other some you know privacy
information there some
now local storage issues that they have
I by
by and large I don't think it's as
interesting as what's going on behind
the scenes usually these abs are talking
to a server
and that's really what I want to look at
so that's already breakdown is Lou
look at how to start looking at that
traffic now what it looks like
understanding the session session
management issues and then
start you know doing hacks so
the first didn't just get in there and
start looking at the traffic I
one of the best ways that I've found is
the wifi pineapple
this is a very portable little device
under the older version the mark for
mark five is the
only the two antennas but this little
guy in the very portable
wifi hotspot that's run on Linux
platform you set this up so they've got
to
will do is take this this setup where my
my little
wifi hotspot you know from my mobile
network provider
think that with my laptop remember proxy
got the wifi pineapple and now I can
start broadcasting as like ATT wifi
right Sr offering real internet access
from my device saw sit down and also
heard all set this up in the mall
and turn it on an all the sudden
time the device to start connecting to
me right because
you know I know any in the one other
nice features
love media my pineapple is common mode
where you actually set it up to listen
for any other connection so if
a device is looking for an SSID doing
the probes
now looking for a home network or ever
it'll actually respond and say sure
that's me
right to get all kinds of devices
connecting to you
with the pineapple I so
that's a fantastic way to do it very
portable a set this all up
and few little lax now commands the
setup
by a transparent proxy so you can force
all other traffic through
and my way my slides will be posted
their online so baby wants those
Bob but pretty easy to run all the
traffic
to my box where my neighbor proxy so all
the port 80 traffic all the 443 traffic
is going through me
saucenao the mall with this K and I
get all these devices connecting in just
her written there watching
answer saving everything I'm saying I
and I'll go home later Inc
and use this data to analyze what's
going on see what sessions I can take
over all kinda stuff we'll get into that
so I'm really giving away a few lee's
wife by pineapples I think
two or three among so if anybody brings
me their card
I have been on a card write down your
name email address
just drop it up of appear in our after
the talk
and the are given wake up a little
dropper hack anything
I'm so
we start looking at the Trafford you
have to figure out what you're looking
at
a lot of these formats are different we
know a lot of the a lot of us are used
to
webapps and the standard me me perform
made me bawl value format that we see in
the webapps
that's kinda what we're used to doing
now looking at used to taking that in
doing some serious attack payloads
and you know trying to do standard web
security attacks
yet that's what we're used to and we'll
still see someone that
somehow format but mobile app switched
are having a lot of new
traffic that's out there on a new
formats
I was still see the name equal value but
also seen large a song traffic
on rest in our family getting a somebody
is here
but you start to see new format and you
have to start understanding what they
are
and how to deal with them the really not
that complicated by
you have to get comfortable with them
what you come from what time it easier
to start attacking
so Jaison is probably the most popular
Main St I'm Jays on his kinda like X
amount that it can be
you can vary nested structures I know we
refer to it as the fat free alternative
text for now
its it's a very mean way and sending the
traffic
by far the most popular for mobile labs
you see this when Ajax tabs and when
they talk they're back ends
I you see Jason a lotta places ritual
newspaper jobs ribbon outs
just used as a as a good format
normally I will see is like on the
bottom here is usually one long strain
bed me look
you know scary but it's really easy to
understand
up on top I format and it's a missionary
easy to see how it's built a nest in
data structure
and there's lotsa be there can be passed
along in their very conveniently
so you get sparse did say you know in a
nice little I am
you know syria im no multidimensional
array or structure something that's is
nice to deal with
Jason can be sent in different places
you can see it being sent as the
you know I'm parameter to like the
standard meaningful value in it can
pass and merge a song you CNN post data
you see id indifferent in different area
people plugin ever anywhere
but what you can look added you start
getting comfortable with that
it's easy enough to deal with because
ultimately you're still
they're still parameters are being
passed the back n
so %um rest I we hear about rust a lot
and restful
a URL's RESTful web services
on rest is not a specific standard it's
just kinda style
love doing things them making things
gonna easy to look at it from a human
viewing and deal with
I and ham programmable usable data in
many cases
you can see in a restful your else my
cup on top
where the pram it to you the directories
are actually just parameters
I miss economists serve it with classic
format you'll see it's sending back XML
sometimes it'll be sending back you next
to no response again be sending a CSV
response
the responses can vary I'm
you know someday you'll see mix real
send a classic mean equal value pair
as you're dead and you can receive a
chase on coming back
restful Baggins can do any number of
things are you know Google Web Toolkit
Scott its own structure words
actually just Mike value pipe value pipe
and then it usually respond to the chase
on I
coming back so all these formats the are
gonna look a little funky its looks a
little different than we used to
and no standard web security I am you
know when pen testing but
idea here just a comparable with that
it's not too big a deal one other one of
the ones that there is a little
lawn is AM out as the adobe master
messaging formatter actions were messing
format the Flash Flex aP's
I need of our PC format is
I but the thing that's nice is there's
decoders in just about any programming
language gonna need
so you normally would have on a web page
is loading up a sweat file
and then miss wood piles gonna be
sending a MF packets in the liberry
binary
a still seems kinda binary objects being
pastor these
you know serialized objects I but
they're decodable
you member proxy support said so you can
to decode those requests
see the values modify am you know do a
single injection
and repack an EMF request up and hit the
back end
so it's easy enough to deal with these
things T
I'm so quick question anybody know what
format this 1s
T
now OJ's on from the lot and AM
register Jason no rock request
there's actually a banner in the banner
ad request from words with friends
I'm and its gonna time information in
there
my life and work but it's got like what
carrier I'm on what type of phone I'm
using somewhere in there is the word
that I summit on the board of my
playing with words with friends it sends
all kinds information so you can
actually have banner ads that would be
context sensitive to what you just put
on the board
I'm but jason is very convenient
for mobile developers because it allows
them to spend a lotta data very
compactly
and compact format the so
when I started looking at the a fantasy
football app
I want to look at him you know I played
basketball yesterday with passive a
bonus
no one comes up so now
we like and fancy fur ball to D&D for
sports geeks
right I really not that much different
yeah I am and
what you basically do for those that
don't know how this works is usually the
beginning the season you pick your
caster characters
I each other teams gonna take time take
turns picking
players from where we were in the wing
they want I'm trying to get the best
players
and then during the season you can to
set your lineup you figure out what you
guys are the best
on any given week no one small players
gonna get injured or they're gonna have
a bye week unkindly the vacation week
job so %um manager roster every week to
figure out your best guys
and then them they start playing and
usually in a head-to-head matchup
against another team
and whichever teams players get the most
points
whens might for that week I'm as me
planning into the denim group
I happily go in I'm so I meet them that
week I was nice
I'm what each player going to get points
based on how they contribute
enough for wide receiver Damian passing
yards they get on sort of thing
so it's important for basketball players
were preventable
managers are fancy baseball is always
different fancy
games I to kinda said their lineup in
get it right
hand usually we get it wrong had to make
a whole lot of excuses as to why our
team sucked a given week
Brighton I you know and we also spent
time trash-talking
when we do well right so
I'm in Enderby very key so I started
looking this and I was living in a no
wonder how
securities things are and ice are
looking at the traffic alert to the web
app itself
and it was pretty secure million you
know I was doing while the Standard
attacks I wasn't really finding anything
interesting
an idea what's been a long time I'm lazy
so as I don't take a look at them all
out
so i'm good the mobile app it gives you
a lot of the same capabilities I can go
in there and see what's happening I can
modify my lineup
my for mobile app so I wanna look at how
it's doing that how is it talking to the
server
so I got my wifi pana I am all set up
but everything going on
so looking at the traffic and when I
start seeing
is that it's making these requests
and looks like sq equals
about the fantasy sports internal right
it's got some big long string
where path was Ella bike principals name
and rank
some I okay that's cool I'm
someone start playing with this and I
start doing some attacks I didn't find
any easy way to
do sequin Jackson apparently they're
using something called why sequel
as the %ah who's back and I'm and so was
was needed doing real good sequel
attacks
but are looking at what's that was
actually sending what's the data that's
being sent
and then then brain strain I spread it
out it's just an XML document
I it's got the player ID is number and
their position
I'm so it shows there's their starters
up there and they got some guys on the
bench in asthma red
I'm some time to look at an Aug in this
is all it's doing every time I'm change
my
roster missus what's happening so
do not use myself isn't as fun so I
wanna start understanding more about
what's going on I started doing an
investigation on drilling white
I know how can i mess with other teams
kinda knowing this
misinformation what will I do so kinda
let me down a path to understanding how
mobile app's communicate
and how they manage their sessions and
this is really where the seven deadly
sins ver no lab session management comes
into play
I one understand how do they
authenticate users and do this right
you know where they do this right when I
do is wrong suburb is down
and I'm basically what you have is
one is that your you're trusting the
client K
so that's usually the first step the
wrong they'd always right requiring
cribs in time to go through each in
these here
allowing lifetime sessions not keeping
secrets
along repeat request no curfew on these
requests
and then failing to prevent altered
request just aren't looking kind where
were the mistakes they make
first one always is trusting the client
K it always starts here
now people learn they build a mobile app
and they also build the
the bag and the kinda trust the traffic
would only ever come from that mobile
app
and I that's where the mistakes always
start games that's number one
number two is I'm not require incursion
I see AV vast majority in the abs
are not doing any kind about her cell
they're just running over straight port
I you know when you're using a mobile
app you have no idea it's not like a
browser where
and the lock icon the tell you that
you're on a secure site or not
there's no analogous feature in mobile
app's night you just left
unaware unless you start looking at the
traffic yourself no clue
I I also see that a lot of the ones that
are using SSL
do it wrong and the don't require a
valid certificate
so if I'm using burpee know if you
remember proxim for has its own SSL cert
right most absolute take me SSL cert
from barb just fine
matter not doing any kind a check I'm
I've seen them they do check and you
wanna balancer cuz a little bit they
said in the you know when they're doing
dev
Bob and what times I'll turned off
because they wanted you their self
signed cert
but the if your man in the middle
I most I'm not arm will check in a
certain do wanna balancer
they don't do the a they don't check
the assert authority they're just going
to accept that certain on its word
and I'm so they don't check the cert
already and if you man in the middle in
Canada cheat on them that unless they're
doing
SSL penning which most are not doing so
simple as Ulster paper stuff works
really well
so and the register actually did their
own they had the stands pretty similar
results
I think they actually think it's worse
than I do but and you look at that
article if you want
sewing now number two number three is
allowing lifetime sessions
mobile app's tend to allow a session
lasting very very long time
and there's reason for this you know
what I'm you know users
just want to click on a button have the
app launch and do what it's supposed to
do
they don't like entering the password
every time I'm
and the form factor mobile device is
terrible for entering a password
so people don't like to do it and when
they do when they are forced to do so
they have really weak passwords
so mobile app passwords are pretty bad I
also see some abs
buttered using the wrong type remain
firm Asian to authenticate the user
I've seen some that I use the and the
IMEI
and the device might have it so scary as
it's all security number its
you know it's a I little card number
to identify that user and nothing
terrible mechanism because those are so
easily stolen
that you know once I know that it's open
season and all get to my hacks later
they can depend on that
and then I found some interesting stuff
there so
miss this not timing out the session is
a problem
they also don't keep secrets I'm
you know in the web security world we've
had been stuck with the fact that
now we detain you can really storfer
really managing a session is
like a session cookie I you can't really
store any secret date on a browser
I and so if somebody's man in the middle
magazine the traffic they can still the
session ID
we're just kinda like stuck with it
right mission of 5 stars to answer some
that we can actually have some local
data store stuff
that won't get sent in every request I
the mobile app's have an inherently they
can store data
on the client that can be used to test
sign requests or do things
they're not taking advantage in this so
want your man in the middle you can see
everything
it's open season right you can still add
a session very easily
I the only thing that we see that they
do wrong as they allow weepy request
they allow the same request to be sent
over and over I
and there's not a lot good reason for
this I'll but what they're not doing is
like kinda tracking
the request me sign in with the nonce by
a number used one so that
when they send it the server would have
a list them all the nonsense used
and if it's one that you use to ready it
would reject the request now that I've
really got that
because again if I can man if I can
become an the middle
I can capture your request and I can
resend it
might be something I can do if it's they
actually founders work with Twitter
on the recently updated API but in all
the PI
that was just barely shut down in May
K metal the PI allowed you they don't
track non says
and once I captured a request I can
resend it later soffits Twitter
that's annoying if I'm just reset in the
same tweet either the banking transfer
that's really cool for Haiti that could
be a real problem
I'm thinking rescinded I
and it's pretty easy to solve my just
tracking the not just keep track
and storm on the server gang now when I
talk to the guy with Twitter and
actually with Twitter
adonis at Derby side or essay I was
doing light hacking de Mon 13 Twitter
traffic
and I'm and they will be able to see
their direct messages so
you know they're they're the checker
direct messages after that I can monitor
their direct messages from
good long time so that's you know that's
not so good for them
but to the pics that they've been chains
where structure works
but to anyway nonce is a good solution
most are using them
new Infiniti don't do in many cases is
time out a request
so given request I'm recorded I've maybe
stop it from being sent to them and the
Middle
I prevented not from going forward on to
keep it for myself
on I go and do that and actually see
that I can send that request hours or
days later and it's still going to work
I again it was a was a bank transfer and
I held it and then hurry scented
I you know and if they created a new one
and sent in
and got them being transferred go I
still have this 1i can send the later it
would still work
that's problematic right I'm there's
reason that they do this a lot of it is
around connectivity
no lapse have to accept that they're
gonna lose connection
from time to time I'm you know you gonna
be in an elevator 1 I'm gonna lose
connection for a reason
I and so what most do the whole didn't
bopper
until it gets you not able to go out I
and they should really come I'm these
out
and and all can explain a little bit
wyman 10 things is
if you tie this to the non to see you
say that request is only a lil
valid for an hour day and it doesn't get
sent in an hour
the app should just regenerate a new
request that one should expire
and it should regenerate a new one if
you do this then you're not is on the
server only have to be stored for that
lifetime as well if you know the creek
was only for now a valid for an hour
and we have to keep an hour's worth the
nonce is on the server but gonna save
you some
some space there I'm so
temple time stamping on the request an
expiring at very useful to do
I and then the final thing is on
preventing altered requests
most aP's made it once a kinda thurber
session
you know move its Twitter & Wales and
Twitter example I
if I could change the content between
that's kinda fun
right and how messed around people that
way ever the banking transfer
I a change the account is transferring
to that's a lotta fun
right I am and it's easy enough to tie
some these things together to prevent
all love this
right if I were to have the that secret
token
ella se y set up my y la gana Ramer
I do some kinda PK I am exchange or even
just her randomly generated
I'm shared secret between the client and
server
that never gets transmitted after that
initial setup
I can then sign everything's I could
take my request and take the User
Content
anything the nonce the timestamp kinda
hasya love that
and encrypt did are you know with my
secret key
now I have a secret hash that only I
could have generated cuz I would be
going with the secret key
right when you take all this toss in my
requests all
you know same at the session cookie
about the timestamp a nonce
got my secret key years the content the
server could invalidate that
very easily and make sure that nobody
else could a generator that request or
alter that request in any way
twitter is doing some others content
hashing that's why couldn't actually
change the tweet text
by Tom if you do this you do all seven
steps are you doing this also bring
Christian so it's
you know the encryption is solid and of
course you wanna make sure doing
you know standard bike sequence action
protection in with a very good profile
K so these are the kind of things I
recommend for
I'm form how and should be built and how
they should verify sessions and verify
the user making the request
K how why and change the formatting all
this weird
Bob went to so those those seven things
going to the never trust in the client
now using encryption limit the site no
less the session my time itself
using cheaper keys you know use a nonce
times Mb request
put all these together you have a pretty
good secure mobile app
so then I guess minutes around right
let's go back to
iraqi fancy football what are the seven
are they doing or not doing
okay I start looking at it for looking
at the back in the session last a very
long time
I never was asked to relog and for an
entire season
I they were not use the FSL
they had no nonce typeof activity you
know secret key hashing are signing
so all I really needed was a session
token
so again seek one direction wasn't
working but
I knew all I know needed at this point
was the session token from another user
and then once I did that what I had that
I can actually do a lot as them right
I could change their mind up so I want
to get session token so what i did.
awaited knows patient and I'm dropsy
draft
time was coming up and so I'm who do you
think provided WiFi access on draft day
drank I
so I collected all the session tokens
and I had everybody is well one guy he
was doing often
is a device near his own connection
combine
every also I was able to grab their
session tokens want to hand their
session tokens
I could do a lot I was them as far as a
written in the backend system 5
simple session times I needed to go in
there take their lineup
right right before game starts swap the
other starters with the bench
way sended and then they're screaming
and crying and having a bed
and they have no idea that happened
right
Bob images because the the the back and
was not doing this right in. report
missed ya them a new app
so it wasn't really does the new app
actually worth a new API is much better
I use SSL it to them
does timeout the things but the only PI
still work so anyway using that old apt
is still
exposing themselves I but it's harder
now to steal session tokens for that
most people updated
but going through this process and
looking at No seven
my those seven then we send in breaking
down as in what I've been spending time
with
looking at lots and if wraps and I found
want to stop Patna
offensive all one's a lot of fun but
there's a lot
I'm interesting stuff that I end up
seeing
as they go through this process and they
go through looking at
what's available what can I do with
these abs I
a lotta maps are not use the encryption
and then they're using
Mike I basic of for the authentication
I hate and the enemy No busy got this is
just like them
b64 cash train I you now see just
a 60-40 code written me out credentials
I'm they will steal some traffic
IRS some data so my Backup Pro
an address book pro they actually ask
you
I with my back abroad as it would ask
you for a password when you open the app
my and CN to plug in your password and
an apple actually load
our show your data I
looking at the traffic behind the scenes
a password is not used
for the communication with the server is
just used on the client
just to make you think you doing
something then there's some kinda
security involved
behind-the-scenes it's actually using
static passwords for everybody was like
my backup Colin pro when I'm did the
basically for decoding
I for every request and it was using the
and the IMEI as the identification for
that device
nightclub the amount to any I and yeah I
am i is whenever
the I could have a bunch of those you
know I've come when I do my ma set up
and I was 12 my Backup Pro and just
cycled through the list them
that I had in front all kinda people
data there's so many people you that app
is ridiculous
I and there's really no security
involved I'm
out play words with friends in this in
the earlier this girl you're my process
was doing it
I we're good friends not viable to this
anymore I
but I was able to do word bypass word
verification bypass
because man a request when you submit
the word on the board
bit of a nerd words with friends my
scramble I am
when you put your words on the board it
was making a request to do a dictionary
lookup
theme is a valid word so I look to the
response
you know why put a dollar word and I did
another nm dollar nad different
responses I fame in the good response
right and then I'd right to call seven
letters
drop them on the board row intercepted
the response put in the good one
accepted it actually sent did and put on
the board
but and I would play my cousin he's
freaking out phrase like
called me up immediately would you
and i won a game do so
but you know its ongoing internal look
in this traffic
look at how are they verifying this what
are they doing I
and we're just friends now they did what
they did the combined the request so
that's one request to submit it but
which actually nice
is in the response if you put a word in
Balan
in response have a list a MacBook um
words in a close to that
that you could use so likes think I'm
real suggestion box right there like
part of time usually use that one
so it's a good cheap that way I am
I was looking into other out and you you
lose some standard sequence action time
attacks to missus
Associated Press in the mobile app so
you can monitor to lose
right and it's a little rest fullback
and
that would send aid up to international
Jaison responsibility that's gonna
showing the app
I'm telling that will count equals Penn
think well middle a single injection
attack in sure enough
you know again she wears right love this
is because the
people developing his back and they're
not thinking I'm as
even as you know I mean web developer
make this mistake all the time but
even more so when it's it's done
something to an API that
really people on directly interact with
I'm so I see some interesting stuff
there
I am how much time ago left a mensch
we happen our genes early I'm going fast
I'm bomb was an interesting one and
we've seen this hack
ING keepers wanna found this I'm
Yes No a bump its common older apt now
bite to eat no's popular for a while
I'm but would bump would do is you know
%um
it basically transfer contacted us you
have two phones and 10 Conference like
this need somebody
an israeli what's the bomb so i bum
phones
an begin each other's contact
information right
the county where transferring a you know
I'm I V card I'm
so what was interesting about this is
it's not sending from the phone
K it's ending to a server and the
servers
what happens in the two devices they
bomb ma'am the event
and so they'll go and send to the bomb
survivors say hey I just got bumped
and this is my location and this is the
time stamp
right and so the bum Surber I will then
pair you up
based on proximity and time I've the
bomb I'm
so a matchup many did each other's
information and you're good to go
well location
is sometimes fuzzy right we don't
necessarily GPS isn't always on
and it's not always accurate sometimes
using our unique
you know the you know your towers
location
solar some fuzziness so were we noticed
in my in the
request from each other devices it had
an accuracy space
like 10 the values was how accurate
those the GPS coordinates were
and I'm more than a lot about under
conditions there
I'm so he would you what we did that
point is I we're looking at the Mosconi
that's the
where the copper to know the Dr say
conference at so that the GPS cord is
there
and a certain settings request myself a
little a prescription
that word on my high speed connection at
home with a cycle through and say
I just got bumped and I would make my
accuracy rating like within three miles
above the Mosconi right which is a good
space okay
and butter 1 and Western seeing
is that I would get bombs and I get
matched up with people
and so I'm you have that now it's like
okay
what would happen if I respond and would
like among German
you know a rare so I i creamy car there
was a small junk
lawyer air Morris we do they would
respond with that I would get their
information I would have that
had some back a rare now I'd see is the
number again
when I'm assuming is there be something
like what the hell I tried again
write a so now let's see these two guys
bombed
right I worry took their information I
gave them a ride back to do it again
now I can go and send back each other
data but I've got the stuff here
and I can modify anything I want you
change your phone number
I can add a malicious link in the
company's URL you do whatever I want
their
right there was nothing in bomb system
that I didn't that actually
they weren't storing your contact
information on their server they were
getting it sent on the moment
and I any word verifying clients in a
way they were heavy request signing was
nothing
but and Mg key measure to this further
he had found a
a safari bug an old Safari bug from the
desktop Safari
that still work on the I owe us
Safari and with them to get remote shell
the link that wouldn't you know exploit
Safari actually give him a remote shell
on my OS device
fantastic I but he just
first exploiting the PI's because this
is our gateway to the mobile client
this our gate we'd all kinds a valuable
data and what a fun stuff
so know the main process here is to kick
start looking
right I look at these means absentee
mobile market is really the emerging
market I don't think it's necessarily on
the client side either
Bob look me on that device in your hand
it is really the key
start watching the traffic how many have
you have been kinda
looking at this mobile traffic how many
human started attested
I'm going confused few hands it's very
easy to do
it's actually a lot of fun distrust are
looking to look at your own device
bird looking at you know connected to a
local hotspot
at your local my files are monitoring
traffic
there's lots to do for you that happen
again traffic in the body started
hacking absence in this paper thing yet
tens and ones that very cool
I so again the seven are going to be the
key
I'm if you want to when a
our wifi pineapple will ship it to you
and I have one with money but
we're getting shipped to you pretty
quickly next couple days I'm
to bring your car to appear and I'm
that's pretty much it if you want to
copy my slides and got 'em posted on a
have been posted here I'll give it your
all up any questions so I guess we got a
question answer time
people on
I with regards to authentication know
what mechanism would you recommend
you know properly using I am you need
when you're building a nap
my passion Ryan so using MDN
IMEI
I I CCID whatever well let me use a
password type a solution
is still fine for that I thank you
should be some pressure on over SSL
I and when I recommend is after that you
should
can also have some kind of key exchange
so that the request could be signed in
the future
but no center namely and name and
password is
is fine I'll see any issue with that by
and large
it's just what you do after that when
you mean once you've established a
session how are you going to maintain it
I'm and I do see that most small laps
and very very weak password
strength policies and again I understand
them form factor mobile device
is terrible for entering a password but
yell
we've gone too lax they think mobile
app's so why you're testing the zaps
a new you do anything to avoid getting
into trouble AQ store
for all your requests and stuff or just
I'm
you know most amid so okay I did talk
with legal about my setup you know I
know the mall with
you know an open heart by and I'm
I'm really happy you lie already kinda
meh
User Agreement on though wifi hotspot
and people connecting to me and I'm
giving him real internet access
and their I there the default policy on
privacy really doesn't exist
so you know it's not like I'm joining
somebody else's hot spot in stealing
data
IMing I'm offering that and people are
just making the
but and going in attacking nigga
individual app something is
I'm that is a little little risk in
times
I but I do soft touches I'm in tunis
long time and we have
clients that are that have elapsed time
in testing I am
none of these are from our clients
either ones I just found the wild or
I've been testing and I got some guys on
my research team that have
for better in different countries and
they don't really care
this
so how exactly do you pull that Jason
blurb
from the beginning Burgess on traffic
yes
I was so just me about being man in the
middle once a man in the middle I can
sit there
now go back on the ice lives quite a bit
I'm
back up here
for Mac and I thought
so kinda sending this up here
I so what all do is all I can either use
a
like that the middle and one on the
corner there is my
T Mobile Hotspot by chem wipe my laptop
but that have been a mile and
and then have the wifi pineapple hooked
up to my computer
so now my number by my computer lets you
know it's running on port 8080 right
I so the pineapple will be a hot spots
you just take your phone you connected
to the hotspot
the wifi turn off your mobile data
network right
South enforce all traffic build-up to
the hotspot and
I'm what you'll just are seeing the
traffic a member and so you just go to
bourbon looking here
your proxy you on and you have it all
their use fiddler whatever proxy widest
I am pennies per I like it I button
it's easy enough to start getting a new
day on bikes in although a lot of stuff
with my own device installing aP's
said you know using it watching the
traffic and I
you know there's few aP's that are not
using
our web server back and I'm into you
have to look at the traffic in Wireshark
in optimism will
I'm by you know if you're not adverse to
hang out March Arctic can look at
rapping there too
but most traffic is web two things one
because you have the site up
so somebody's wifi services you know
once you but then a kid
you also get all the users emails and
things like that I guess
in good reminder people shouldn't other
e-mail
and their wifi account be the same
account but his yes
yeah the shared password thing all the
standard security stuff does come into
play
I'm and I do see that like when I'm when
I'm
seen credential being passed I focused
mostly on the web stuff is it just kinda
my own personal interest
wi-fi margin where certain I see them
connecting Europe observer
now got a password there now that you
know what your man million do just about
anything you want at that point right
I'm and in mind when your laptop on the
laptop I actually have
I'm doing Internet connection sharing
any can you do a Windows or Linux pretty
easily
I'm so its you know it's an actual
router giving real internet access
and I'm just forcing the port 80 and 443
traffic through my burr
and I noticed in the fantasy football
SQL know is a date code you could pick
could you retroactively
after the game changed the date to
before the game in so do very well on
that one
I have been tryin I'm going to now I
that's good idea I'm
yours
lines you know what time does storage
group when would you suggest so
I'm he is so we ask it on the local
device you're gonna have like the secret
key there in a store on us
on the client out how would you protect
that
division world its authentication token
tokens
a time like the SSL pinning type stuff
good reason to learn
okay so just call home
homeland
lines right
so what I've seen then there's lots of
ways you can solve some other so if you
I am so you know and we'll see what you
get in your session ID and lithium your
secret key
I'm you can still hear even a simple
thing I'm just cycling the session token
everyone smaller want only connects
I'm me no man can I guess I could be
event begins a new session token so that
all traffic is no longer valid
I and then thats the day to the rest or
on the client
I'll really message that too much like
how united stored there
I'm then that's really not wear plain I
there's and I i was looking at was no
talk earlier name in all kinds of
solutions on how to store data
securely on the device that other app
can get to it make sure it's in that
your sandbox Basin Authority thing
I'm and there are hacks in turn allow
you know you to bust out in the Sam
boxes and stuff so
I know how you do it but beyond and that
and by Ed
that's the individual client you know i
think thats I'm
it's harder for an app to steal that and
you're only targeting
you know an individual client but people
bone losing their phones yeah and that's
another reason why you are a timeout
will will light you know and ask for the
password again everyone smile
I'm yeah loss to my sorry hun problem
and there's nothing as link Facebook has
a feature where you go in and see a list
in your active sessions and you can kill
'em
I most times don't do that in Ohio you
should be should be like
crap you know what it's like to use your
credit card in college credit card
company think get relevant
break kill that account I menu card
but most capstone give you that
capability so
good point so unless the same you
said I'm a broke ass as pawns and in a
separate traffic worth
but sweet if it is as is no connection
are more than the palm chill
for the certificates like a the mobile
app that you are connecting to a site
with the
so calm sumo stabs don't actually I love
you haven't built the interface are
using the
the library properly and so that's why
we're saying Islam will accept
any certain I you know they just want to
connect to an SSL connection and they
nor the cert errors
I'm and usually because during death
have you know they don't like a self
signed cert again for local box or
whatever and they didn't install that
certain onto their devices can I
turn off the air and on place alarm just
went off the air handling
I'm very few have the dialogue on a
popup
very very few so long your neck as you
can as you pick the SSL connection and
then
want an MP for you for more than a game
to the destination wrap here
exactly bumblebee man in the middle and
its it's the SSL server and enhances our
client in
in the middle as pure in a plain text so
last question how do for us that the
mobile app to talk to your proxy so in
this chair I'll just
when I do here is like that up the
device to force all the port 80 traffic
through my box which is the
172 1642 for into port 8080 that's why
I'm broke running
saw for traffic to their knowledge than
other line for destination port 443
and the Nelson I got the traffic going
into birmingham
on
well alone can go because labor
be sure to bomb bomb
on stormy and some random
I just the miss
the that the government I'm so I was
really confused here
so I will be manning the middle with me
doom contact the tsunami are I man on
this one
this one all I didn't was I had my idol
proscribe running
hmm on a high-speed connection it's
going into thinking I'm pumping a month
ago month ago month
and then I'm if somebody actually don't
bomb
often win both races and I'll get
matched up
snow was commissioned yeah but have the
recognition problem
and in on the night may end up getting
in there on
any other questions that
really find any any parameter
vulnerability that could possibly allow
the 49ers to overtake the CA ARCserve
said go ahead seems impossible this
it does seem impossible this point man
on we're hoping it'll playoffs but to
you know I was down here on the new york
I may go grab a
you know Miller Giants or jets shirt but
I just couldn't bring myself to love
those on
so
from California am unjust stick with it
I
on anything else
I will thank you all then
thank you