but I really actually do money people I
think they're for the most part
very smart
and actually know what the right thing
to do ask them what to do
take care easy almost always a good
answer assays
instinctively get the right they
understand up
what to do so I think alike God and that
it's David Ross
I Katie these people as if you happen to
see him around
run into him whatever I by a beer Yamaha
since there are some people actually
really like these people I i'm
I mean I'm actually no disrespect even
though I am constantly bugging them
I so but I will argue that they cannot
be successful at doing their job I'm
givin
with the type to companies that they're
on and ecosystem that we currently work
with them
so I have to ask the question and I
think you should ask them yourselves
like why are you here and I don't mean
like at this particular convention
necessarily I mean
in this industry like how did you get
here why are you here I
are you doing it for fame or money you
know what what what's the reason you're
doing how you doing it to protect people
I so Germany Grossman our city our
company is
my best friends and I am he and I can
always just wanted to help
I've specs on the stuff that's we see
broken and I think that sort of drives
us to do certain things and take certain
up as in life but if you wanna make the
biggest impact on security you really
have to focus on the biggest hits right
there's nothing the most important
places you can fix the
that choke points on the Internet for
things like browsers
I'll languages operating systems
networks I
you know mobile devices that those are
the big choke points we got on the
internet we can fix those things you
literally and then browsers case
you can actually impact 2.4 billion
people on the planet so I'm not talking
about small decisions here this is
actually affects every single person
you've ever met
I so here's the scope of the problem so
we have around 2.4 billion people on the
internet right now
that's that's not the entire population
world not by a long shot but its a lot
have their earth
I'm we have about 40
as I 84 to 90 percent now a shame these
numbers and how I got them later but I
love the Internet
say that they want privacy so that sa if
you ask missus all selected so this
number is a little
those cute or whatever but but you can
you can get my get my draft right
oz let's 2.16 billion people
I are so above the 2.4 billion people
who want privacy
I am within that group there's probably
millions of people that we can directly
impact in our daily lives that we can
I reach out to through the press or
whenever we can somehow impact and
change their lives in some ways so
a smaller percentage you don't know that
number cuz its its
it changes all the time really but but
you get my point and then
if you look at people who actively go no
script is a good example of a technology
a lot of people use to protect
themselves
I as 1.9 million users have no script
so the actual Scopus changes that we've
been able to affect with the given
technologies is very very small compared
to the size the ecosystem
I'm so we know things like no script do
not work for the ecosystem they were
great for me
agree for the people as audience but
they do not work for our
parents or grandparents I kinda stuff so
others what was really great
I like I said I'd actually like the
people at work these companies are
I somebody's got to actually I nice
different people want different
experiences are going to choose a
browser based on that preference missus
comes from is a lot I think that's
really accurate
and this is sorta a diagram I wrote not
too kinda try to explain to people what
the differences between browsers could
be
so the blue third the dark blue triangle
in the middle
is sort of what your browser as it comes
out in a box this is what it's for a
pre-configured to do it right
on day one you get this the darker blue
birds at librivox:
are trying a rather is around it is sort
of what you can extend your browser to
be able to do with plugins out on
extensions
job configuration changes network all
this other stuff
in line devices and so on these are all
the other things you can make your
browser do
the yellow train on the bottom is
possibly when a consumer might want
I they don't really care as much about
the security aspects
and terms and actually actively doing
anything about it but they
really don't go either way to get extra
features they want more
functionality and they want more
usability as only the same or as deep
a functionality is a guy like me are
people in this room I want you might
want to be able to do all kinda crazy
things bill the chain CSS on the flyer
always kinda crazy extract functionality
I'm sorry usability and does make
easy to use it makes it more functional
and a guy like me obviously was a lot
more security on to my browser far
beyond its normal reach
II wanna certainly turn everything off
that I could turn off but I'll turn off
almost everything I could turn off how
can I do still want to do some stuff
I am Palace like I messed up as weapons
you convert from
a Mac to to Windows button so Google all
and their I this is a
this a diagram I love what they're for
the different actors
in the space or want out a the browser
ecosystem
so Google primarily wants higher ad
spend that's the
fundamental thing that they want out I
love the
ecosystem they want increase the amount
it adds and increase the value of those
ads
I advertisers they primarily what high
conversion rates lower cost per click
a higher click-through ratios and
ultimately a return on investment
they wanna make money I have no selling
t-shirts or whatever right
so the thing that they share in common
and the thing that they both have in
common is monetizing users
that is that is something that they have
in common it's not something that users
why it's something that those two
those two groups want users if you just
look in his cell slacks
primarily they want privacy and security
in the fundamental lowest thing on the
I would think that they have its
distinctive I have new look at what they
share with advertisers they want quality
products they want better t-shirts they
wants a better clones and whatever right
the things they consume
the things that they share with Google
they they primarily want better search
results
they want to see I you know when the
searching for teachers they won high
polish church officials on top in 10
scam store right
and the only thing that all three groups
have in common is performance
the all want faster performance they
want speed on a browser
that allows you to spend more allows you
to transact more
allows you to see more on the Internet
short amount time and it's less
exhorted of a user experience so so
different actors
different needs different things they're
trying to get out of this ecosystem mmm
so this is a good example of where I
like people to understand advertisers
and Google are not in lockstep
they actually do have different needs on
this so
this is somebody's web sites and as ads
on there and I wanted ads is an ad for
Google
not have signed up and get ads and put
it on your website so
affectively by showing this ad they're
more last telling
a user on the site you should get in the
business I love putting up web sites and
putting ads on the internet I which is
through doesn't really help this person
right this person
doesn't necessarily get any benefit in
fact they might actually get less
benefit because you might be interested
the same thing they are
you mike in a competing business and
actually rehearsed their market more
last
so they're definitely not in lockstep
from
from a incentive perspective
so my goal I yours have to start with a
goal I
is to have a more private browser but
basically
I want to protect the sensitive
information that on my computer I have a
lot of people
other people secrets about my own
secrets I am and if you say you don't
have secrets
I'm not gonna trust your secrets I so my
personal
path that goal as a little bit different
to most people's I
I everything that I do you have to have
at least
to I answered have been methods are
protecting ourselves because
anyone could theoretically break right
we can define explain want it much
harder to change on abilities together
I makes it almost almost impossible not
impossible but nearly impossible
I so lately I ASM just this past snowed
in thing
I've been getting the question why
should you just don't tell people to go
visit or browser
I am and the the problem is the grandpa
problem
I am so a while back a couple years ago
um there is this problem where I
anonymous effectively I told I the world
that they had uncovered a hundred and
the sea passwords
by I'm having hacks at or accidents
I'm and what's interesting is because
it's exactly 100
it's a hundred mines not ninety-six or
something it's exactly 100 I which means
we know they have a lot more than that
which means that we know that's
there obviously looking a lot more
traffic than that we know that
people our house packed exit nodes in
section one another the best things
about running an exit known as Wasilla
traffic
I so so grandpa
I he might be interested in protecting
himself so dollars it or browser
I he send sensitive information over
HTTP and HTTPS because he's scrambling
doesn't know the difference between
those two things
and effectively there the exit node
steal that information
and hacks for grandpa and he no longer
has a retirement right so
there's a difference between an ammonium
privacy and it that's a very slight
distinction but I think it's important
to at least be aware at cognizant
up the difference and why you cannot
recommend for two people who don't know
security
do already very much understand that the
pubs best so what they want to submit a
loan application
you really don't need to be an honest I
can really can't be anonymous you're
trying to say
give me money iight know who once was to
give you money to write Sep by Mert nem
virtual what you're doing you cannot be
anonymous so there's no point in using
tor browser
but you may want to be pried it you
don't want anyone else to know that you
want this money you maybe you don't want
people to know that you don't have the
money you know i mean
I with your serving for legal
as opposed to illegal up porn for
instance maybe that's something you
up maybe you want a non-entity for that
maybe you do
I let's say you're work in the process
something you don't people knowing
you're not gonna person or whatever
waiter a a political person or something
whatever you know you get my
my draft but you probably still want
privacy you don't want your mom to know
what your surfin
in your spare time I if your political
dissident on the other hand you want
both
I you don't want anyone to know what
you're doing you don't want anyone to
know your name
you don't be in your family cannot be
trusted because you're putting them a
arms
in harm's way if they find out right so
that's another good example where it or
brother would actually be a good
a good idea I and then get things like
me research research in pressure cookers
because apparently that's not a bad
thing to do I so I may 1 anonymity I
don't want anyone to know that I'm
researching pressure cookers because
they were just ask too many questions
and I don't want to deal with the hassle
I really care about privacy is my wife
find other am searching for pressure
cookers
who gives a crap right she knows that I
just wanna crockpot i'ma
and I do my part but so this
this is what an average website looks
like today I
aligning a lotta people think other
web-site is very two-dimensional things
they are definitely not the browser the
DOM
and his very three dimensional town is
the access
absentia transparency steps you can
actually see through the DOM and
actually look at multiple layers
on one other thing that was actually my
health card I got actually bothered to
look for the source code
a huge mistake in Adana I but said I
but it has all these problems it's it's
a it's very three dimensional on there's
no way for you to actually know what's
going on any given time without actually
looking at what the DOM is doing in that
moment
and sourcing too much JavaScript there's
no way for you to know exactly what's
happening
in a time to check how to use issue it's
it's just a total tear down
but every site is like that it's not
health care not comment every site
I every Mon site has this exact same
sort of way out
so what am i willing to give up I
if I'm gonna make a secure browser what
I have to do to get there and I i have
done this
know it's is a major pain the butt I so
firstly I don't need anything to be fast
%ah so unlike the normal consumer who is
focused on spin performance
idoney that I don't care about it said
in fact I think speak can actually kill
you in a lot of cases has lot of things
that
in writing JavaScript fast they can
generate yeah the best to get hacked
I idoney bookmarks autofill prefetching
web slice gallery
whatever the hell that is and a bunch of
other stuff prime going to get rid of
all that stuff it's all pointless from
my perspective
I don't need any whiz-bang web sites no
fly and their whatever transitions and
stuff ammonia and all that stuff I'm I'm
really not extend that doesn't action
him help me on the internet do what my I
need to do and I'd really don't care
about pop ups are warnings
unless they're actually help for nothing
actually a warm me up impending
you reversible danger and they don't
warn me about that they're pointless and
they're just get my way
I so in Explorer has amazingly stupid
pop up if you're trying to dinner
make scripts run optionally it's like
scripts are usually and save you one
allow scripts
which script what you talking about ISO
usual stuff like that
so there's a lot of enemies if your
gonna bill that you gotta focus on what
the problem space are so here's the
props right
first thing crossed into anything cross
domain is a potential way you can get
hacked
I don't massaging IMO JavaScript appoint
an iframe or
or making a across from an request they
can do our house arrest forty percent
scraping by tracking and so on right
I so there's a much different ways it's
all that our request policies problem my
favorite bob ricks all across the main
requests
I'm there are some caveats that are some
ways to hack it but for the most part
it's very good
I if you've never used it it's sort of
like 10 i no script on crack
it's just way way worse than 30 minute
breaks is pretty amazing
i no script hi is good for iframes it
doesn't really help with that much
crossed man stuck with exceptional aid
application on reinforcement which is
very very good
and stopped all local arts 1918 request
leaving behind a probar y will be
protected
you can actually be configured as a I
don't want to be able to source in my
bank
from any other website other than when I
just type it and I mean
I poor blocking this is something you
typically do the firewall level you can
do it local
has base firewalls we can do and
network-based this can actually prevent
a lot of the
attacks with you can say I only in a
tunnel at the internet don't allow my
browser instance
are from when this VM for instance the
contact anything outlook Larson 1918 or
or whenever he is happy sex web
I living credentials upon logged out is
actually very helpful because it
it limits what cross a request for you
can do because you're you're not logged
in overtime right and so it that if i'm
wrong. out very frequently it's very
less likely option is the drive my stuff
is going to be able to impact aside time
are going to
since I don't have my cookies anymore so
that's nice Facebook rise in DNS where
applicable there someplace that doesn't
make sense
but typically you should not allow the
internet to see what your
your DNS looks like internally and vice
versa this them almost everybody gets a
strong
almost everyone host DNS on the same
service do so a
that's bad for all countries and by the
way had so pac-man execution
I am it's pretty obvious I don't want
people running stuff on my computer
right this typically we think I was an
hour I so
no script and put Java others are both
great plugins
day limit what you can do in JavaScript
space I that's great you are actually
turn on when you want it
that's right that's right really helpful
are moving protocol handlers
on the whole mess liberal handlers that
do all kinds a random things
that actually one of the main factors
that one hour gets and
I so you just need to train them to
always ask have do you sure you want to
run like it. mass protocol from your
website like
I probably don't need to watch iTunes
from my website
I released it let me know and I'll make
the decision
output to play is actually probably one
of the most useful features
if used properly I it basically will say
you don't run Java
or you don't run ActiveX controls are
you don't try and whatever we're talking
about
flash whatever unless you click this
button say yes I do want to allow it
I so that limits optimistic drive-by
pretty substantially
I Sandboxie I don't a few has a minor
Sam Barclay
as prequel to I have heard urged upon
checking out on Windows it's similar in
30 ish dear
sandbox and ash exact were joking after
someone if you're familiar with those
things
a Windows seven is great thing is:
learned that as so it actually prevent
prevent a lot of that sort memnoch
russian issues figuring out where stuff
is in 20 pointers of along with haitians
Alonso
go on Microsoft that was great they
really improve up their game in 107 her
for over a previous versions
I went to his crop don't even I be if
the
archery jails if you're not familiar
with this it's very similar Sandboxie
except the much lower level
there's only been one explain it in the
history of the product and it's been out
there for by 10 years or something so
very very solid
I a similar again to say market exactly
and Joe can't
for from over those things anti-virus I
a lot of people laugh about anti-virus
actually think ambers does have a time
and place if you have an extra CPU and
you don't really care about wasting your
own power
I by their is certain circumstances were
anti virus has car buyers is so you will
get some incremental gain from doing
that
ideally are some or something it hit a
half times are familiar with that or
are trip wires commercial product i
anybody is modifying binaries that would
be a good thing to know
obviously from our finger binaries
without you knowing it that's probably
something bad
I application whitelisting content agree
monitoring as a whole bunch products out
there to do this kinda stuff
Court races wanna bigger ones I actually
think we just got bob
time to mention I think about them up in
a way that kinda thing figuring out
I only one run the certain binaries are
from the browser process
so this is what that ends up looking
like I so
on the outside you have PF packet filter
inside that mean for the st. thats
routing the st. Jude retreats jails
inside that your you're launching
VirtualBox inside that you have multiple
and different affectively jails I
those I can be remember your male
friends 10c outlook access our
whenever hi and you have your browser
have those are windows 7 images
insiders 127 images yet Sandboxie inside
Sandboxie you
you have a stripped down version of
Firefox and there you go
right no memory corruption you have to
jump in so many hopes to get out into
the pan operating system
or into even even into one and the
subsequent a nearby jails
makes it nearly impossible so data
exfiltration in the next one
idea frustrations really gnarly I could
he'd take stuff out of my computer still
suffer me that would be bad
so I one thing that everyone gets wrong
as the same wing Aaron transparency
taking screenshots and you can still see
what's going on behind their
this transparency going on as his all
the time I remain credentials upon
lockouts
disabling an efficient at an hour
support which sounds like a bad thing
from a prick from the previous slide but
the there's reasons et phone home
I every couple hours if on time
depending on which browser using Firefox
an Internet and I and chrome from also
sent a machine ID and he's riding the
internet every five hours
I request policy i think is much better
than our block
for the purpose of protecting your
privacy and and really improving when is
actual traded out to third parties
I but I think both eg provide some value
I
settings require planning permission so
this is similar to us talking about with
operable handlers
I just make sure that everything's
always click to I to lurch you
I rip burp suite I pas Wireshark in
Process Explorer alt
show what's going on is a subset making
up our connections
I am I there's a there's a tool
I I what they called I Little Snitch and
Mac it for free without
for someone that not Firefox as a great
bill to enact
a our lack access to raise corn and
Falco answer SMB protocol is removed
which is great I they do you have things
like
chrome calling in about home one not
gonna stop which is not as good and I
wish they didn't but
they do so I so it the more you can read
that better
bold images upon reboot make sure that
nothing process so cookies and a Flash
cookies and all the other I
persistence items Aldous get removed
upon reboot
and in Firefox also just recently fest
affects the CSS history how can I think
they also affect that pixel perfect
timing tak
I just like last month so man the middle
I as a pretty common what I think we're
all familiar with this one I
and Charles CA and cities in Verisign
gold images to remove temporary allowed
certs
I it be if you have reimburse we can you
have to a temporally allow certain
you don't obviously want to keep that up
for ever I stand alone proxy support for
Firefox with this can actually hurt you
and help you depending on how you use it
if used properly it can help you to use
improperly and a surf the internet
wildly from a computer and don't
willy-nilly and just use proxies
this will get you killed because at all
phone home through
and they had smashed for calls outside
the proxy and so that's
not I butts but he's a properly and you
limit your computer only making calls
out throughout or friends since he's
been ghastly amor something like that
I you you can actually become very
secure as a staging bpm tunnels
preferably like I said everything has a
backup C is both at once
there have been many issues an SSL over
the years allow
I'll information leakage but there has
been no issues in both at once
I perspectives are as a cell all this I
like the concept that these tools and
practice their action a very good
I i'm not going to all wrist watch my
talk about later meant I meant
as a weird number proxy for proxy I
actually creates more problems in some
ways minute and helps
are you get a chain Firefox with per
proxy through local SSH tunnel actually
reduce
about the bad things a per box but he
could theoretically be doing
I'm not war and I use a VPN
and and like I said rap against p.m. and
make sure that everything's going out
out the same I the same tunnel directly
so if you're not familiar they're
actually are tools right now to doom
animal attacks are using as a cell which
is why should not be using a soldier
primary means a protection
I it's just doesn't work very well and
you have to like this
from packet forensics where you upload
the SSL certs for
you know their sin or whatever the route
certain that this thing and
I basically they they command a middle
any connection I does matter when using
a saw not
and they wouldn't know this if they
weren't using about what's up there
they're doing well I so texting in
pre-filled and protecting and fishing
are are
a common oddball but people care about
this a lot so it's we're talking about
the really are no good solutions new
stuff like Open DNS if you trust them
I kinda don't but had a lot of people
really like them
and newspapers a puzzle quest: policy
into the name on the
to disable javascript I because there
are some situations were superb a
scenarios where points are singing
JavaScript
on the target so on eBay for instance a
source in JavaScript remote page
it'll look like sign in page but won't
be as so
that's that's not really a not really
great solution but it does fixer
prohibits naras
and then my case education I these I'm
observe a lifetime member a BBW GIs were
for eBay and I fishing team
I just looked at literally thousands
efficient its I
I really don't actually need to worry
about phishing sites
personally this is as offers alright I
and I don't use patterns res conference
so it's not really helpful for people to
get my past her cousin they can't use it
anywhere else so
I so I I haven't totally solve this
problem but it's mostly solved because
I'm hymie
I'm some I as a good on the eyeglass
that so this is sort of what it looks
like I'm no scripts
for a cross-site scripting a quick
jacking application by reports much as
great party proxy
for the stand on fire RI party support
which is great
request policy as a super awesome for us
to request forgery issues
has the there some issues there but not
a bad
attacking some process scripting is as
the pics as well
with Java for redundancy with I with no
script
I actually really like that to a lot I
and II an actual don't download it
nearly as often as I should amish
machine and I don't think you really
shouldn't special attention to
perspectives
because like I said it doesn't work for
the reasons I haven't told you
I butts so that that's the score church
approach to browser security if you want
to be really secure
that your browser would look like out
what does it look like to actually surf
the internet
that is with CNN looks like my brother
a
I am so
an awesome people like molasses is lax
right I
and they are the problem with links and
as a buffer overflow in mind so
I ever be even if there was I could
happen and put inside say when put on
site in a sandbox Ian nah nah nah right
I could be on the same things but
I but the problem is I still want to be
able to enable things when I need to
enable them and I can't do that Mike
Swenson have
all the functionality so I need greater
functionality than
alikes could possibly perform a number
that triangle fact on
so let's shift focus a little bit
towards outside I
I know that that doesn't sound like it's
related but but it's very very very
related to this problem
so I ve ever seen an yeah
this is apparently what what it's like
to stay I don't I'll never see these
them but I
their parents what people have to deal
with it they go to Baltimore Sun I'm
so this is the first ad that ever
existed
this is from AT&T I'm in the early
eighties this is what started all
I'm I thought the square was really
interesting this come from cancer found
on the internet I am NOT al gore
I he now wants a new lawyer said we
couldn't runner systems and everything
in it were per-
at 150 because then we wouldn't know
which has to show you so this is a
system that was designed around a
particular business model
so I with the should has a dot dot dot
because we want to track your
right and that's that's what that's the
punchline to that quote
anecdotal tacky to quote someone you
work with but I thought there's a really
great the juror said
you get the smartest people in the world
together the best people this industry
has to offer for the sole purpose and
serving up ads
right and so we're we we have this out
his mom with Google which
hi is driven by a very different motive
then then you a consumer might be
motivated by
I this crap is a little tricky to read
but basically and I can write got this i
think is a Gallup poll but
I but it turns out that people only
slightly
distress hackers a little bit more and
they distrust
and actively will protect themselves
from advertisers advertisers are nearly
as bad and the public perception and get
mine is also like to the subs like a
survey so there is some bias
but its its almost the same people
visualize
advertisers and hackers and criminals as
almost the same right that is
well above government spying on them
well above anything else happening
and I was really interesting so why are
they so that wire had sold out what do I
care about at some
first of all they have viruses right now
they was very rarely if I am threat post
I am talking you're there
I propose Paul all these great post on
on our being I spun out by various
different ad networks
viruses in our ties and I people will
say hey
go down on this awesome thing you go
down the sauce us moving on to something
not awesome I am they waste a lot of
time on some pages that can be
eighty percent or more on the page wat
so if you care about performance
I'll Naz not helpful I
definitely get a much higher performance
on removing ads how the Psalms a
tracking which is
I think are the core what I'm gonna be
talking about here some people
kinda happen to stand by that bad but
and if you believe in all the people
shouldn't track what you're doing is
you're go from page page
you probably wouldn't my dad's the often
very offensive
I know this is a little small hard to
see but I but this is a
your meet Canadian singles whatever and
this picture is actually a shove
cleaning woman who committed suicide
which is why she's a newspaper so is
extraordinarily offense and add
I and and this is the most PG-rated non
a new offense that I could find aa
happened isn't the kind of stuff you see
on in a very regularly so the fence and
women and children are
people who have your sensibilities I do
not but I you can
I'm sure some people and i also really
obnoxious
I really terrible I am and China like
pay attention to something and do
something else
and the right move around strain my
contention I am in
the trying to be as offensive as he
possibly can to try and in your face for
trying to YouTube look at them
I so this is something that they are
aware I love I the more they do the more
you click on it
accidentally clicking on ads are
purposely clicking on it whenever they
don't care
on the signs that the industry is not
as small as I think a lot of people
think it is this is he many many many
times over multi-billion dollar industry
so in 2013 we're looking at around
forty billion dollars in the US alone I
industry-wide will be closer to 100
billion dollars a year
right and this is an interesting graph
comes from the IADB
sources sup selected have been absurd in
a bad way sauce liked it so this is
actually really good data
I from the advertising industry that
that belong to the idea that they can
track
so we actually know the numbers probably
higher than that I am
to put that in perspective a lot of
people talking about the b-2 stealth
bomber programming a very expensive
program
they can buy a B-two's tell program two
times every year
from now and told the attack right this
is it at every year
that's how much money we're talking
about I'm in fact
I lockheed I is the eighth largest
government
a lobbyist in the world followed by
Google as our Google is before them
there
their summer so let's change topics a
little bit to do not track and the sound
like it's not related
is all related topics I promise I get
back to the %uh explain why in a bit
I so the number one complaint I hear
about do not track the number one thing
I hear everyone say is that
I E 10 doesn't fall this back they say
it's useless because I didn't aspect
identify the suspect then we can trust
and therefore we have to turn off all
this kind of crazy non-threatening
and what you may not believe is crazy
but I'll tell you what I and so the
number one thing everyone says
they don't call us back practices in 10
do not track is before I go any further
his gun porn
now yes how much my as a do not track
base within the signal to web sites that
you do not want to be tracked that's the
simplest most the
you know I pg-rated version I could
possibly come up with but
its and thats affectively what they're
trying to do how many states do you
think do not track ass
anyone States
break
note and other comments do
hazard Brett addictive I joined other
three
there's three states I am butts and not
a lot of people know that
there's actually one state this says do
not track
one as one state the set which means do
not track me
there's one status as do not track 0
sets like a double negative like do not
track me not
I guess and stuff like that negative
that's great and has one status says
nothing it just doesn't send the signal
at all
I'm and so it turns out if you actually
look at
how browsers implement this almost no
one falls back properly
not just in an explorer they all do
something random so
this is when an export as I its it's
turned on by default
I and it just one but now it says do not
track have used once liked it wants an
HP Hatter
so they're not gonna spektr everyone
agrees right this is what's
crime does they do not have turned on I
have a turn off and then turn on the
side a screenshot but
I it's turned off by default and they
have to Settings one
don't say send a do not track signal or
two to nothing they have no concept the
Do Not Track not
I I this is Safari which I never use
which is why it's a
on selected here I but this is I
this again to states I asked whether not
to track me
or don't send a signal at all and then
Firefox they don't want to do it right
I are technically to the spec anyway and
and they have three states wanna says
and tell
tells me to do not want to track which
do not track one tells I thought I want
to be tracked
Do Not Track 0 Do Not Track not and
lastly do not tell
site anything about my tracking
preferences and the irony is actually
talk to the security expert now like
admit returned on is lightweight which
one is
do not track hot I don't like because
the phrasing is so bad here says do not
tell site anything and say that's the
party red is like okay I don't want to
cite
anything by stoned on track meet all
right and that's what he's thinking so
that even the phrasing here is actually
very bad so
I one would argue this is that doesn't a
hot mess right this whole thing is
terrible I'm
so a lot of people say no one supports
it well that's not really true
I Yahoo Pinterest whether they all sort
of support it I with a mixed bag when it
comes in and explore because they
believe their spores in doing it right
skills they're not by spec everyone else
is doing it right apparently
I but and %um and but keep in mind
so this is against my thoughts like to
study but 84 to 90 percent of people
want
more privacy I am be awesome
I into shadow puppet to do one school I
am
so true factors many of them them in the
news what I thought was really a really
great actually
I but because it kinda shows ecosystem
in one small snippet basically they said
that because Internet Explorer's has
this on because Hannah
as for tennis so prevalent they're just
gonna say when I can support it
at all for anybody for anything any
circumstance
and said I'm just not sneezing I it and
saying we which don't trust them there's
like screw when I can do for anybody now
I so that's kinda great that that solves
the problem right now the trucking
industry can
keep going doing what they're doing it
idea track doesn't have any me to it
this is awesome so let's talk about how
far away it is turn this on right how
many clicks does it take to get
do not track turned on this is an
indicator of how much work someone has
to go through to enable their privacy
right
so harris-moore is technically seven
they have a turn on by default those who
don't have to do any work so it's been
actually 0 I'm but it would be seven
online
Firefox yep there do with five clicks is
fun and an argument with a guy
privacy guys like now it's three clicks
might now it's five I
that's too bad they don't know I'm
neglect their own suffered experts com
chrome
is six I'll take six Plex to turn on I
so that's even you would imagine that's
chrome would have
last people's liking it because it's one
more step away as I can expense will
drop off every time you can add an extra
click
safaris 5 I don't actually have been
stopped in Safari apologize
I have the staff and got meds so smart
takes 5 seed imagine to be someone the
same neighborhood as Firefox
although I in practice actually think in
the last just because it the default
browser and people tended to use default
browser to not make change the bouncers
I'm so do not track
is kinda interesting I'm because it's
not how the spec works at how people
actually buy the company's you can use
it
that's what's interesting so there
actually using is do not track not
and nosing all are effectively the same
thing they're treating those things as
identical
I'm which is kinda instincts after all
kinds reasons but
hear numbers I was able to get from the
advertising industry themselves
I don't think they know who I am iris be
awesome but has so this is true fax
numbers
straight from them the game to me so I'm
didn't change anything about it
I E 10 is any 6.46 percent
I would seem offer low I Firefox
is 19.27 percent what seems about right
now actually right in the right ballpark
chrome as a 2.5 percent again I think
that's right and the reason why I think
I D ten is probably totally incorrect
it is not because I think they're lying
about the numbers I think me and at the
onset no reason to lie to me that in no
way I was going to use this for
I'm butts I but the problem he is
I think there's a there are so many
robots clicking on ads
and looking ads from an impression basis
to intentionally to defraud
chocolate frog clip agencies are been
advertisers
have for the purpose a decreasing the
fraud ratios
that I think that this is probably just
how much fraud they say actually are
seeing which is around 15 percent
I but anyway had as you can imagine
let's just pretend you're absolutely
accurate right I'm not gonna my god
double-double think this let's just use
these numbers as they are
this is what it actually looks like some
consumer preferences somewhere around
eighty six as such like that again
80s an even nicer 87 percent if you
average it out
I'll and I he is in almost a
exactly in parity with whites we would
expect to see if users had
the ability to change your browser I in
it in a way that made sense when their
brain
I really I have five minutes left band
times bring the same
and so that means the IEEE it is the
only one that is actually in parity with
what customers actually what what people
actually want
I am and so we see ad blocking I
basically across-the-board that makes
sense
mean Firefox is always going to be the
largest because how to make it the
easiest
a chrome is gonna as destroyed a newer
browser so they're kinda coming out with
a lot of the same software
so this or dad were coming anyway first
we had then we had
I want plus nah 14.99 use active users
I then add agency start paying off
adblock plus:
they're paying them are quite a bit of
money we don't know the actual amounts
I had to allow ads to go through our
price which means you can try savoir
plus anymore
then congress get involved and submit a
letter to say
now we don't know what's Firefox to you
a block third-party cookies because the
children
and am they don't they think Amber
Alerts are somehow going to get blocked
because
could be somehow turn on JavaScript or
something and it's this bizarre
saying anyway it's totally pimped
factually tolling cracked but whatever
and and because they're going payoffs
from the IB I
I thought this would be a lot more but
their outgoing paid I'm several thousand
dollars this doesn't however Google's
paying them directly
I so that's why we should have this
surprising ecosystem
I'm so remember google has forty million
dollars forty billion dollars Rep I
alone I'm not forget forget the
Maddon's going to go all their goonj I
I but a lot of people think why is
Firefox I'm not worried about this right
on ninety percent of firefighters
revenue comes from search deals
I've which of our on Google makes up
eighty to ninety percent run things run
eighty-eight percent
have those deals so the BOC Firefox
revenue comes from has
I this is last year's numbers I think
Google now has switched the numbers a
little bit now they got the ability
pancer also control slash mobile
providers not
I am NOT so Google is paying and Firefox
a billion dollars every three years
for this pleasure of I love being the
primary search bar when you for Wii
for that land operation corner whenever
I so we're ads
heading they're heading towards this the
serve not a great future where
I you're going to have a very slight
small set of tools like disconnect that
will win against most third-party
JavaScript as but not all
I sans some subset bass what stuff i
mean
as are basically turning into my rices
and they're gonna have there have all
the same to serve
filtered Asian wok was division had
stuff the C virus is just because they
need make money
I'm so advertisers will create local
source adlai true fact that's exactly
what they do
I because I'm it's much harder for a guy
like me to block because it's on the
same page if these heuristics for
something terrible
I so then companies will increase but
not tactics and say you have to enable
JavaScript sorry I've been able add see
my website we've already seen this kinda
stuff
there was a regulation that would be a
that the sea because consumers are get
past me like a we really do not want to
track anymore well we're tired of this
stuff
which is sorta bad and serve good
because you really don't want the FTC
writing regulation cuz I've Amber Alerts
and children in congress and whatever
I'm so we will probably start suing pass
in the not-too-distant future they're
they're always started attacking and
walkers directly
this is an example the prohibited
actions things won't engage in sex tv
now you're gonna take you down and then
they did they actually start removing ad
block from her a block
I like things from the from the crime
store
so so what's the so what so yes
do not track is a good example love
assertive one interesting fact it wasn't
wasn't good
in itself it about technology for kinda
reasons there was good for tracking and
basically gave us the insights we need
to know
the of in security is a bad idea of out
security is a good idea
I'm so we need to build technical
controls the best wing mirror that and
I'm and that means that we have to
support can on track as opposed to do
not track
I do not track doesn't work we have to
say that we
we basically prohibit our browser from
doing those bad things
and once advertisers learn how to play
nice then we can start
revisit this thing allowing this year
haven't done that so do you should
recommend my setup the Asian remember
recommend this horrible CNN world you
can see the anything but like syntax
right now and that the links world
I read something better we need
something that's more substantial than
actually works
I we need I something I
that doesn't actually impinge on
people's privacy and we need something
that isn't
I'll served a match we posed with what
consumers actually want
and at I was told that I use that
concern about lawsuits for instance
on that the perfectly with good reason
to be concerned about it so
we probably shouldn't use IE because
they're worried about lawsuits I am NOT
we want higher security
hi and privacy a tools as a percentage
of the things that come down as opposed
to
I other no perceive I tracking sorted
thanks
30 built-in browser and then alternately
gotta find a consumer because
I mean those are our family members
right those are the people that you know
we have the side West there that they're
the most important people to protect
I'm and they're always gonna win this
battle anyway so what's my had doing so
we're in a unique position where is your
conflict of interest we don't actually
make money off a bad no interest in
tracking people
I its survey unique position I we don't
believe in this do not track concept
I'm we believe in cannot track by miss
lee of thing everybody
out have security as opposing optimum
into security I you have to do stuff to
try offer security as opposed to do
stuff to turn on security
I'm so we got this thing called aviator
on the you may have heard about its Mac
only I were eventually gonna make making
its
available on Windows platform as well
I'll but this is a sort of our first
salvo at trying to do work round or
chrome made the internet faster we're
gonna try to make it a lot more secure
and private
so I'm outta time but thank you so much
everybody appreciates