so first things first why did I pick
gone in 60 seconds so those who may not
know me
I'm a bit of a car nerd this was at the
DEF CON Harbor hack car hacking village
and they had like a challenge to
basically take apart a car and find the
input ports and at this point I was
under the bumper of the car like seeing
if I could access the some of the
sensors there for the airbag and they're
like no no no we didn't mean take it
apart for real so yeah so the reason I
picked gone 60 seconds is because
there's a lot of parallels between this
topic and the movie Gone in 60 seconds
is about speed and so can hacking and I
want to mention that sometimes it takes
longer than 60 seconds in the movie the
in the original movie the last car to
get to get to to get stolen I was gonna
I was gonna say jacked but I didn't know
if that was right um that one it takes
like 60 seconds for the guy to get in
and then the car chase is for 45 minutes
so so the first thing the first example
we're going to go over is a wireless
assessment that I had to do I had a
really limited a scope pen test where
instead of you know instead of 60
seconds I had it 24 hours it was still
really short in retrospect it was also
pretty limited in that uh there were
there were just corporate users
connected to Wi-Fi hotspots
so my attack surface was just the
hotspot so those of you who may be
familiar with those know that the only
real attack surface is the password the
pre sure key so we're gonna go over a
little bit about attacking WPA preacher
keys the authentication for WPA PSK
happens using a four way handshake that
happens either periodically or in the
first authentication the
the session encryption key is calculated
using info including the SSID the pre
share key and a one-time number a nonce
from the client and the access point and
this is to prevent replay attacks an
attacker can who can observe the full
handshake is able to take that session
and then and then perform a brute-force
attack against it one thing I do want to
mention is you may be asking well how
can you make this faster and one way is
to force a Rihanna keishon by sending ad
authentication frame as the access point
and that'll cause the client to
disconnect and then Rihanna Cate
so now that we have the background down
let's do this let's start looking at
attacking it so yeah okay yeah let's
write okay a few more times are you good
okay so so maybe maybe asking like Eric
are you a script kiddie why are you
using Wi-Fi to and I'm using it because
it's a really good tool for learning and
for trying to attack out first if I was
teaching it using just aircrack-ng it
would it gets a bit complicated also
it's been rewritten just show what's
happening during each step of the attack
and finally there's a there's oh I just
mentioned it the debug options let you
see each step so using Wi-Fi - I started
it in it starts in scanning mode and no
I'm not gonna walk over there I'm not
using my pointer because I'll just like
shake like like you know you guys trust
me trust me it'll just be like a laser
point like going all over the screen but
anyways this is the first step with
Wi-Fi - it shows the the the SS IDs of
all the networks that are available I
picked the first one which is the ver
in my fight that I'm targeting and it
starts ad authentication attack well it
starts observing the the network on that
channel and looks for authentication
handshakes when it doesn't see the
handshake
it goes through and it actually sends a
D authentication if it finds a client
it'll send it to one of the clients if
it doesn't find a client it'll send it
to broadcast and try and do authenticate
all clients I really want to mention
this because that's one downside with
Wi-Fi too you can like denial a service
a whole network with it so in this case
it dedicated the client and then it went
and successfully captured the handshake
and save the handshake so now that I
have the handshake let's try to crack it
well let's try to recover the password
most hotspots have a default random PSK
and I started wondering if I could find
the format so I looked for the model
number the model number was in the SSID
it was public info it was clear text so
I did recon on the model number and
started looking I looked for looked for
documentation I didn't find it I started
googling and I came across josh josh
writes twenty ten posts on kind of the
same thing it was attacking Verizon MiFi
hot spots this is eight years ago and he
was able to find a flaw in the format of
the pre share key and and exploit that
to use technology from all the way back
then to recover the hash in a short
amount of time so that that got me
motivated I kept looking until finally I
started looking at YouTube I was like
well people do unboxing videos what if
like in the unboxing video the pre share
key is in there because it's on a screen
that's like hidden so I started looking
through and sure enough there was some
YouTube video from from Russia where a
guy was giving a review I couldn't
understand him but a little a little
more than halfway through he shows the
screen of of the setup page I'm just
gonna
so she shows the screen on the setup
page and it has the yeah to loud okay
how's this good so he shows the screen
on the setup page and I was able to get
the format of the preacher key what
format does this look like hex yeah it's
8 hexadecimal characters so using math
combinatorics in particular we can
figure out how long it'll take and this
is where I kind of dive a little bit
into storytime because it reminded me of
of something that happened with roommate
in college my roommate and I we were
kind of paranoid well I was paranoid
honestly he was a film major and I ended
up buying one of those security locks
for my laptop it was a Kensington cable
lock with like a lock and a key and he
was like oh that looks really cool
you're pretty paranoid but that's cool
why don't I get a combination one and he
said that uh he set it up he he created
a code and I don't know if he didn't
trust me or something but he never wrote
the code down so later on a week goes by
he never he goes to unlock his laptop
because he wants to go work in the
library and he can't remember the code
and he's like do I have to break my
laptop my new laptop how do I get into
this thing so he calls Kensington
support and they say well just try all
possible codes he's like no that can't
be that easy
and there's like trust us if you go
through all of it it's like less than an
hour it's like oh okay
so he goes through and you gotta try
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero one
and so on
and then sure enough within like 30
minutes he had the thing a lot it's like
oh that's not so secure is it so in this
case it's kind of the same thing but
instead of the four digits we have the
eight hexadecimal characters so we
looked through hexadecimal characters of
zero through nine and A through F that's
16 possible combinations and it comes
out to a little over 4
know the number of the key space or the
amount of the key space using hash cap
we can we can research or I researched
how fast my GPU can crack wpa2 and I
looked it was a GTX 970 which was
released all the way back in 2014 so
it's a little old and I was able to find
benchmarks published by the hash cat
team and it came out too for that that
key space and it came out to a hundred
and seventy three thousand hashes per
second so taking the key space of will
over four billion dividing it by the
hashes per second gave me about seven
hours and that's the worst case scenario
that's if I have to get to the end of
the key space to actually recover the
key so now that we have like the math
down and I at this point I had the
confidence to actually go for it because
I only have 24 hours am I going to
actually finish this assessment before I
have to fly out I I went through and I
started running the hash cat attack and
in this case it's gonna be a mask attack
these are the options for a mask attack
I want to go over a little bit you don't
need to focus on actually on fully
understanding this I just wanted to show
that you know option a is the mask the
mask itaú the attack method then we're
doing wpa2
that's the hash file the 4 Way handshake
capture and then finally a the important
part is the format of the mask so you're
doing - one to say that you want to
define a custom mask and you're saying
question mark digits and then ABCDEF so
that's all the hex character sets and
then finally we're saying it's eight
characters so using hash cat it started
and it was really close to my estimate
it was at seven hours so I was feeling
pretty confident at this point I woke up
the next morning and it was it was
recovered it was cracked in less than
four hours so it was less than
half the time this is how hash CAD
displays the plaintext so at this point
I was able to connect the hotspot and do
the configuration of the flying I was
able to compromise the host server
server message block so at this point I
basically made it through the assessment
and provide a lot of value to the client
but one thing later on after I realized
it left me with quite a few questions
the first one was how how overlooked is
this so I had a Verizon hotspot in the
fast or not a Verizon but a generic
mobile hotspot in the past and I left
the default key there because I looked
at it I was like oh that should be
secure enough and I didn't at the time I
didn't really understand the math behind
the attacking passwords like that so I'm
wondering how many other people have
done that and then I also want to know
is this widespread is this systemic
is it happening across a lot of devices
and is it happening across to newer
devices because this one's pretty old
and then finally is it being actively
exploited our people are our attackers
truck malicious people actually using
these flaws to connect to networks and
compromised systems so what I did is
while I was traveling as a consultant
and and going to conferences going to
airports I started casually scanning
using Weigel and/or wiggle and and using
just the default Wi-Fi apps and I kept
seeing that same hotspot this one in the
example which is from 2014 there were
plenty of examples this one was actually
at my tiny airport of like four gates
there were two of them nearby and then
this one was at a conference there were
about four or five that I noticed so
it's still in use today so the next
thing is is it being exploited and I
start googling a lot more as you do and
I found
- killer co uk which is a a forum and a
hash recovery service and one of the
services they offer is recovering wpa
hashes it's used to primarily used for
testing the security of your network but
anyone can go on here and pay to get on
a network that they want to that that
they want to access and they listed a
large number of routers and then they
listed them by by duration and how
difficult it would take so I was like oh
that's probably because some of these
routers are more secure than others like
some of them have more complex keys and
then I looked and they they actually had
a list of all the default routers they
could find in all the formats and going
back from - 2015 I believe and then I
also saw that on the hash Gap forums
they were targeting weaker algorithms
and working together to reverse the
routers to see if they could drop that
entropy and drop the recovery time and
in some cases it looks like they were
able to make it so it only took them
take some minutes or seconds to recover
a key and then I also looked they had a
form recovery service on their public
side where people can post the four-way
handshake and ask members on the forum
to recover it and pardon me and members
will come on and they'll they'll kind of
race each other to see to be the first
one to crack it and provide it and then
ask for a donation in this case it's I
wanted to point it out because well
actually I'll cover it later so but
first I wanted to go into another
example I had so at this point I my
interest was really piqued so I started
buying random hot spots one of them I
came across was the Alcatel link zone
and it's one of the most affordable hot
spots to get it's used actively by two
networks in the US and the documentation
actually contained the pre share peep
format I started searching and I looked
on t-mobile's website and it talks about
the SSID and the SSID contains the last
four digits of the IMEI number
oh that's useful the password contains
the last eight digits of the IMEI number
oh okay that should help a lot and it's
your through nine characters so it's
even easier than the Wi-Fi hotspot we
were looking at so I look at it and I
look at the IMEI format and the first
digit looks like it's almost always
static so it's almost always zero
because it's used to indicate like the
type of IMEI number it is the next three
digits are just zero through nine and
then the last four digits are just in
the SSID so you already have them
available so all we're doing is we're
trying to crack in this particular case
we're trying to crack or three ten digit
numbers which comes down to just a
thousand possibilities so it's really
fast so one thing you might want to
might be asking is what about other
devices these the pre shared key
generation methods are pretty systemic
across all devices that I looked at you
can just look at the list from hash
killer and you can look on your own and
one of the ones I came across was in
that previous example in the forum post
you'll see that the format is Bell and
then three digits and that's the SSID
format so it's one of the routers that's
used for Bell Canada the home hub fast
fast routers and there there's people on
the hash pillar forum who are actively
recovering handshakes for the routers
that are that are deployed for home you
know
in in ISPs like like Bell and Rogers so
how many on-time who's actually keeping
different oh you are okay thanks Ron
okay so the main takeaway I wanted to
talk about was that uh that the default
randomly generated passwords are not
secured forever
if you go back to when my five hotspots
were first released over in 2000 in 2008
they were using these formats and
they're still using them today
and at that point in 2008 one really
interesting thing happened the password
cracking kind of had a huge breakthrough
because GPUs were starting to be used
and that dropped the key recovery time
and that's one of the reasons that this
is so easy now the big question I have
is why don't they move on to better
longer passwords in some cases I've seen
that they have they moved to 12
characters which is significantly harder
but in most they haven't the
recommendations that I have for for
basically the practitioners the
corporations is to adopt a zero trust
model so your users connecting to walk
by now untrusted Wi-Fi networks
shouldn't be trusted
shouldn't sure they should be protected
against any network they connect to
whether it be a public access point or a
hotspot that they're using and then
these hotspots really should should you
should change the default password and
the SSID for the hotspots disable
unnecessary services on the endpoints
decreased or further further limit the
attacks surface by blocking any unused
services or white listing them and then
finally when you're using VPN or
deploying VPN disable split tunnel VPN
connections so with that thank you thank
you long con this is great
this is a great opportunity and if how
much time do I have
three minutes yeah I could do that all
right let's see if we can do a demo in
three minutes
Oh two minutes oh yeah you got me you
got me in the talked to sixty seconds so
I should be able to do this in 60
seconds
Oh oh no I have to my hands too sweaty
okay there we go
cool yeah it was a really secure all
right so first we're gonna run Wi-Fi and
we're gonna run the kill option to kill
the the network interface manager the
network manager and we're only going to
look at hot spots that have clients
connected so these are all the hot spots
here that uh that currently have it one
or two clients you're cutting into my 60
seconds come on I can do this okay in
interest of time I'm gonna stop this and
scroll up because I did this like before
I got here so here's the hot spot it
went through and it recovered the
handshake pretty quickly
by using a DI authentication attack and
then it tried to crack it using the weak
passwords that are built in and didn't
work it saved the handshake so I went
through and now that we have the
handshake let's create a word list for
the possible pass phrases so it's a
thousand combinations like we looked at
before and now that we have the word
list I'm going to copy it off to windows
because that's even faster than trying
to run this in a VM and then I'm gonna
use air crack in this case instead of
hash because this thing does not have a
GPU so I'm using air crack and I gave it
the word list the handshake
and and that's it so that was a demo
fail so we're gonna go to the screenshot
I saved oh I found the key thank you so
when I ran this before oh I have it here
so I'm gonna leave it on for as long as
I can if you want to try recovering it
and throughout the weekend and I just
wanted to let you know it took like less
than a second it just showed it
instantly when I want to practice this
but thanks everybody I'm at a time right
[Applause]