[Applause]
hi everyone good morning who here has
heard about that sack ops before your
hands who here actually understand what
it means okay
yeah to that so yeah
my name is Megan oh also known as magna
Logan I'm not from here
right I'm from Brazil so a few
disclaimers
sorry for my English if you don't
understand something that I say you can
ask me later no problem so yeah I focus
a lot of application security I have a
developer background I'm currently
working for skip delicious security
analyst right we have a few positions
available I've spoken at a few
conferences in Brazil I found it was
chapter there and organize a security
confess there as well so yeah that's my
main focus right now I'm originally from
City College on pessoa so if you visit
there just talk to me okay so software
development for me I believe it's like
MMO RPG game so it never ends so you're
always trying to create new features fix
bugs and improve your software so it's
the same thing like the game your try
always trying to improve your character
and doing quests and stuff so I think
that's a good analogy but the problem is
that security usually becomes a
bottleneck when we try to ship code and
create software faster right so if in
the current state and like the agile
methodology that we're using we can't be
doing that anymore
otherwise the company won't make money
right if we take like two weeks three
weeks to do a pen testing and provide
some results that's not feasible for a
company that's deploying software every
day in production right so yeah that was
first it was a waterfall methodology for
create writing code and developing
software and that was a slower process
so that was a scepter before acceptable
before but now everything became a gyro
and it's like we also need to adapt
ourselves to follow the pace of the
developers and the development lifecycle
so we can ship code faster but in a
secure manner right so if you ever took
a like a programming course or developer
course in college or somewhere you
always try to make yourself to work you
don't sometimes you don't know how it
works and it's like you don't care a lot
of about security so if it was it's
working ship it right but that's not
acceptable anymore right
and we tend to think that developers are
not worried about security and usually
they are they just don't have the proper
training they never learn about security
coding right they learn about
programming so usually that's a problem
that happens in companies before where
the developer wrote their code and it
works in in their machine or in the
developer environment and then they ship
it to production and it doesn't work
there maybe because it's consuming a lot
of memory it's breaking somewhere it's
it's missing a dependency or something
so that why the DevOps
culture or methodology was created too
tight try to integrate integrate those
teams so they can better work together
and cheap software faster right and
create value to the company
so yeah just a few things about DevOps
right focus a lot on automation right
and the integration of those teams and
one of the things that I think it's
important it's increasing the feedback
so everything that you do you receive a
feedback if it's okay or not from the
tools that you're using so you can keep
going otherwise if you see a problem you
can fix right away so break something
something like okay break the build if
there is a vulnerability or something
right but a lot of companies that are
doing the evokes they are not focusing
on security although some authors Rd
that security is already included in the
develops culture and it's part of it
they are not really focused on it so
what about security not working okay
good sorry so it has been proven that if
you find vulnerabilities on the early
stages of the software lifecycle right
it's easier and also cheaper to fix
those bugs so why we're not doing that
yet on every code that we write right so
I think that that's why was the the new
name the apps I copped was created to
emphasize the need for security in this
new culture change and methodology
called DevOps right there are many
different names I think that they mean
basically the same thing so there are
some discussions about it I won't get
into that in this talk but I think it's
important to to know about them but I
think yeah basically the main goal here
is try to integrate security in the
development lifecycle
so yeah the main goal of the black ops
is making sure that this automation and
this integration with the developments
and the operations are done in a secure
way and one way that we can do that it's
using the shifting security left
approach where we perform testing since
the early stages of the lifecycle right
most of the companies test for
vulnerabilities after the application is
deployed like a dynamic testing a good
way to start shifting security left
explaining security from the beginning
and creating security requirements for
the software that you are creating and
even you can also like participate on a
spring planning meetings from your
development team and suggest some
security features that should be added
there as well so yeah I think that
creating and testing for security at
each stage it's an important thing to do
and will help you to find issues faster
and earlier and it's gonna cost you less
to fix those so two weeks ago very code
released the state of software security
report it has a lot of interesting
information if you from app sack but I
think the main the main thing would be
this graphic here proving that
applications that scan their code more
frequent they fit their the they're
fixed rates are higher so you can if you
were if the developer seen that issue
over and over again he wants to get rid
of that issue and he's gonna fix that
right away so it relates the screen free
frequency with DevOps right so if you
usually if you're scanning your cone
like 300 times
you're probably doing that automatic
automatically I hope so yeah this just
proved that deaths a cops can increase
the fixed rate right because I think
that just finding the vulnerabilities or
not interesting not enough sorry so you
have to understand how to fix the code
on the custom application or to prove
not just like send your developers a
link of the vulnerability and here is a
generic way to fix it right if they
don't understand security very well they
won't be able to fix it by themselves so
yeah I think it's there are a lot of
discussions and different architectures
that what you should be doing to say to
be able to say that you are doing the a
cops from my upset perspective I'm gonna
talk about three things that I think
it's important so yeah automation using
a lot of tools available for you to
automate some of those security checks
right now and implementing them into
your development pipeline first thing
that would say is make sure that you
understand and know what are the tools
that your developers are using like the
code repository the ticketing system the
CI - so that you can use that and
integrate that directly in there - so
that it doesn't there is an overhead of
new tools that they need to learn and
use to do the apps AQAP's so there is
this company that releases a periodic
table of DevOps tools that I think it's
really nice and there are some security
tools here on the bottom right that you
can use these are not the only ones but
there is more so yeah I think this is
interesting
so from an application security
perspective I think that three main
techniques or tools that you should have
on your pipeline
are these free software composition
analysis that it's basically a to that
it scans your libraries or your
third-party code and checks for outdated
versions or vulnerabilities so usually
most most of the the code that we have
now in our software are third-party our
dependencies right so that's a good
thing the other one is static analysis
or static abstract testing sassed it
scans the custom code that your
developers are writing and the other one
is - dynamic abstract testing that
that's the running application right
usually people only do the last one and
it's either start doing with the last
one and I think the order here is it's
wrong you should start first with the
software composition analysis and I'm
gonna tell you a little bit about it so
some guys from os did arisia research a
few years ago and they they verify that
almost 95% of the applications include
any some kind of open source rights
either a library or import or something
that you use in your code and almost is
almost 70 percent of those applications
contain some kind of vulnerabilities
right and that's why I see a - is
important that's gonna check for the
components that you're using if they're
outdated right you don't want to be the
next Equifax so one thing to be - to
note here it's that a tool like that
will check not just for the penances
that you have but also for the indirect
dependencies it means that the penances
of the dependencies that you're using so
that's something that's hard to do
manually so you probably need a tool for
that there are a few tools that you can
use the pennies checks from a space free
you can use mostly on
like Java and.net applications but there
is another one called Nick if the dog
there that checks for open source code
so you can directly integrate that on
your github and check your github
repositories for vulnerabilities there
on the dependencies that he'll have the
link below there it's about a talk made
by another Brazilian it's in English as
well so he analyzes those tools and
compares them with like a few features
and which one would be better for each
scenario so I think if you wanna use one
of those check that presentation as well
so about the pinnace check from oh it's
a project by a wasp everyone here knows
about wasp can you okay yeah so yeah it
checks for the penises and basically
checks for the any VD database if the
library is out there or if it has a non
vulnerability right
it has plug-ins for maven Jenkins and
everything so you can try using that on
your own your code to check for those
libraries another thing that you should
have on your pipeline it's a static
analysis and it scans the custom code
that you have in your applications
it checks for vulnerabilities there some
vulnerabilities are easier to find when
you have access to the source code right
it provides specific information about
what the problem is what it's located
and how to fix it sometimes it gives you
like a data flow and provides you the
best place to fix to apply the fix and
it's gonna replicate that fiction all
over your code so that's nice there are
a lot of tools out there that do that
already like very code white hat so but
I think a good
that's also free but it might not be
considered a static analysis but it's
good it's a good start
it's a sonic qube it checks for the code
quality of the quality of your code and
it does some security checks
mostly for Java applications but it's a
good way to start introducing secure
coding for your labs so you won't create
a lot of friction so when you start when
you implement another specifics as to
write it integrate with a lot of CI ICD
tools each each also checks for like
code coverage and it has something
called code smells so it tells you like
this code doesn't look really well
implemented it might cause some problems
it's not a security issue right now but
you should take a look so I think that's
that's interesting and there is the
dynamic dynamic app socket testing right
that the the one that you run when your
application is deployed most companies
you only do this right and there are a
lot of tools available on the market but
be careful with false positives right
you don't want to run one tool like this
and just generate a PDF report and give
you to your developers right you should
also check if the vulnerabilities are
not false positives and make sure that
focus on the critical ones first and
also I think that if you have to choose
between SAST and DAST I think sass would
be a better approach because since you
have access to the source code you have
a way to find more vulnerabilities and
you can check use us earlier in the life
cycle so the bugs that you found are
probably gonna be cheaper to fix so one
of the tools that I like to talk about
is OS app it's a it's a proxy to do
mostly Maino testing on web applications
but it has some automation as well
automated features as well so you can do
automated scanning and you can integrate
that in your CI too since it has an API
and everything and also plug-ins for
Jenkins so you can run it before
after a Beauty generated and you can
already check for a few security issues
there so this is like desired depths a
cop's pipeline with a few tools on each
each phase I think it's interesting to
show here that it's not like something
that fits on every company you should
adapt for your your company as well and
for my last remarks or like dads are not
security as experts we need to train
them and make sure that they understand
the impact and the vulnerabilities that
you found try to make security as much
part of the development process as
writing code it has to be transparent
right so if you can't be asking the
developers to run a bunch of security
tools for you so that's why automation
is important another thing is that
nobody likes bugs right maybe ours
security experts were not developers it
makes them look bad right when you bring
the a lot like a PDF report with a lot
of vulnerabilities especially in a PDF
format right I think another thing
that's really important it's try to
become the developers best friend and
they will help you without even knowing
that's something that we call the
security champions so usually there is
like 1 to 100 ratio between security
analysts and developers in most
companies right so you have to recruit
more people for your team to help you
with the security
shoes so I think that's a good way to
implement security over all your
organization and also remembers remember
what matters to the business and try to
balance security with features right we
we can't implement all the security
features we want because sometimes it's
gonna make the business stop working
I think that's it that I have for today
here the reference and links and if you
have any questions we have two five
minutes
no questions okay thank you
[Applause]