hi folks I'm Matt Winnipeg is awesome
but it's freezing up here and notable
because three layers down I have a
b-sides New York City sort on if you've
never been to b-sides in New York you
should come sometime it is fantastic mmm
I have a New York centric Twitter handle
because that's where I lived when
Twitter started and you could still get
the five character handles that doesn't
work anymore either I'm on the security
team at a company where the local office
called Priceline and I'm neither a pen
tester nor developer I just know enough
to cause some trouble this is a
discussion of what are called online
skimmers you may have heard of the mage
cart attacks earlier this year that hit
companies like a new egg British Airways
and Ticketmaster in the UK these are
pretty advanced attacks the adversaries
also target the Magento shopping cart
system I'm gonna talk a little bit about
where the attacks come from how they get
into your system and some potential
protections so everyone knows what the
old-school credit card skimmer is right
a piece of hardware that you put on an
old card reader like in the states where
they still have the mag stripes and it
either copies the stripe data off of the
card and stores it locally or sends it
back home with a cell modem in either
case the results the same someone is
buying a lot of flat-screen TVs with
your credit card number because of chip
and pin chip and sign these attacks have
gotten less effective so the same actors
have taken their attacks online this is
some example JavaScript that was found
in the wild on one of those companies I
mentioned slightly modified for our
presentation and this what twelve lines
or something
we'll grab credit card data and send it
off to a malicious third party so this
the code somehow gets injected into the
side we'll talk about how that happens
sits in wait until the customer its
submit or does something that involves
sensitive data then it fires off and
sends a copy of all of your data to a
third-party website for the purposes of
our demonstration we're using this cloud
CDN ddns net skimming pre-tin that's a
malicious website it's actually running
on my buddy's wife raspberry pi right
now so please don't crash it so this is
a black skimmer it's native to I don't
know the southeastern coast in the US
it's got this weird under bright bill
and it can fly through the water and
scoop up fish and that is my
transitional slide it's the griddle okay
and my hands will shake so I'm just
going to play the video and talk you
through it this is set up without a CSP
don't worry I'll explain to you what
that is later you can see it's the
riddle we are buying jokes here and down
here will scroll up this is the same
malicious code I showed you earlier it's
running in the background on this
website it's loaded somehow in the
browser and you can see again the
malicious domain cloud CDN slash
skimming customer comes in here gives
his name he's found the jokes he wants
puts in his very valid credit card
number it passes a lung check puts in
the submits it this is our post checkout
page right action page PHP that Paul so
Mike the last speaker before dinner had
a lot of great tips in burp and burp is
my comfort zone I love working with the
intercepting proxy so my challenge for
myself for this talk was to do
everything in the chrome inspector pane
so I'm not flipping back and forth and
it's amazing what you can get out there
so in the inspector pane you see we
posted to action page with the check out
data as you would expect
got a 200 back this is our legitimate
domain where we're selling jokes and you
can see we posted
all the data just like you'd expect with
a very basic online shopping cart all
that data gets posted home to the
website but you can see that the browser
also made a connection to cloud CDN our
malicious site posted up more data to
that endpoint and when we roll down
you'll see it took all of the form data
made a nice serialize a JSON object here
and sent it on as well all the credit
card data on the site was stolen this is
the exact attack that hit one of those
companies I mentioned before you don't
need to see it again please skip skip
okay so these attacks rely on very
little code that's super simple right
typically they fire only on the checkout
page you don't need it everywhere and
they siphon the data off to a malicious
domain that I don't know passes a smell
test here are some of the examples from
past attacks and I know if I was looking
at the connections my browser what's
making or if I was reading through the
code in the web site and I saw a new re
llc.com
people are dropping vowels these days
all of these domains were set up with CA
certs
so you didn't get any mixed content
warnings and it's these attacks are
completely transparent to the user the
user is not going to know this is
happening unless you're doing a lot more
inspection than any of my customers do
you all of these domains are taking
advantage of a nature of attack called
typosquatting
and that's relevant both here and later
on right it's where you take a domain
name or a package name that people are
going to trust and look for a variation
on it a lot of sites these days right
you don't want to handle credit card
data you don't to pay the compliance
costs so you bring in a third party to
send the credit card data to and then
you just work with a token however due
to the nature of these attacks if
someone can inject code into your
website they can inject a fake check out
form and gather all of this data
send it to your legitimate third-party
processor as well as sending it off to
themselves one of the most recent
attacks by this group match card did
just that so how is the code getting
into websites some of these examples are
known from the public disclosures about
those attacks and some of this is
speculation obviously if you're serving
your web content with mutable servers
and an adversary can get on there they
can change what's served if they can't
get on to your servers or if that's not
the past of least resistance they could
get access to your code repository if
you've got a developer who reuses her
password for more than one place that
would be a very good address Avenue of
attack or if you can just you know slip
a developer a couple thousand bucks even
one of the flat screens you know you're
going to get later on all those are
viable ways of getting similar to the
domain type of squatting there is more
and more type of squatting in the
third-party library space for web code
so right so so these are all third-party
libraries that were found in the Python
public repos and they are squatting on
the name of Jango which is you know the
web framework slight misspellings these
packages all provide the same
functionality same code as Jango but
they also include some extra
maliciousness to siphon off sensitive
data and send it away
we know that for one of the companies
that fell victim to these attacks the
malicious code was injected to their
site through cross-site scripting we
know that one of the companies who fell
victim to this attack actually their
servers and everything else were
pristine but they were bringing in some
third party code on their checkout page
if you've ever seen the little chat
window that pops up hey do you need help
with this purchase instead of
compromising the first party
the attackers compromised that chat
provider because that JavaScript was
running on the checkout page the
adversary was able to copy off all
of the assistive content malicious
browser plugins and not using the
attacks we've seen so far but it's the
same idea either through typosquatting
or finding an abandoned plugin and
buying it up from the developer that's
two more ways to observe traffic in the
web browser and steal it off so what can
we do about this first there are some
really good IOC s out there for these
attacks go see the dog has a few
thousand host names IP addresses and who
is details for domains that were
registered in the most recent attacks
you can scan your code repos for these
you can look at your DNS logs you can
look at your network telemetry
to see if you see anything related to
these when you get in there your heart
sinks a little bit because you see all
of these domain names that are very
similar to something you may be familiar
with and something that you realize if
you saw it listed in a website you'd
think you'd not think twice about it
there are several other great write-ups
about this links are at the end
commercial company risk IQ has done a
ton of research there's this Dutch guy
willem who has a great blog covering all
of this beyond that beyond the network
Paloma tree and looking into repos for
IO C's of previous compromised you need
to have great integrity controls to
prevent this let's just go from getting
into your site first you want strong off
to your code repos stolen password from
a developer should not be enough to
bring down your site turn on to FA for
all of that you need to have some degree
of peer review before the code gets out
so that if a developer subverted it
would be detected when you're bringing
in third-party libraries to your code
you should check them for
vulnerabilities as well as maliciousness
and type of spotting retired is a wasp's
dependency check are a couple open
source tools to help you with some
if your repo is clean you need to detect
an alert on changes to the servers if
they're beautiful servers right so some
sort of file integrity monitoring over
the objects that get loaded onto there
and get served out to your customers
ideally what's in the repo what's on the
server and what runs in the browser can
all be hashed and compares and there are
ways to assert the hash of the third
party or first party resource to the
browser so that the browser will only
run the script if it matches the hash
finally you need to look at your site
from an outside perspective so sandbox
it somehow I would expect evasive
techniques here meaning don't only load
your network don't only load your site
from selenium or phantom jeaious and
expect that to detect all these changes
you need to have real emulation real
people looking at the site from
anonymous networks you need to inventory
all the third-party scripts pixels etc
that you're loading you need to do a
spell check against those and that will
help you in the next step and the
policies you can develop to assert
positively what the browser is allowed
to connect to so the best protection
against getting these online skimmers
injected to your site is to use a header
called a content security policy this
gives you really fine grained control
over what you allow the browser to
connect to when it's on your site CSP is
a header that you set in the web server
so Apache nginx whatever it's a
whitelist or a blacklist of what you
allow people to connect to there are a
lot of directives within the header you
can set anything that ends in SRC takes
what's called a source list it's a list
of domains that you allowed it the
browser to connect to for those
particular types of objects so style SRC
is the list of domains that you want the
browser to connect to
to get a spell see two important ones at
the end the report your eye that's an
end point that the browser is going to
post any CSP violations to so if you're
implementing a CSP and break something
you have a method to know that limitary
from the browser sha-256 is another
directive you can put in the header to
specify the exact hash of the attribute
you want it to load so there's a very
well named website called content
security policy comm has a bunch of
examples stolen by Lee from there the
most simplest CSP you can assert through
a header is defaults here the default
SRC self that just tells the browser
load any assets that are from the same
origin right from the same URL same
domain name you can be a little more
advanced a lot of people run GA right
this is a basic policy that lets you
load Google Analytics to get a little
more complicated if you do default FFC
none ya know there's a laser pointer but
I like to stretch if you view the
default SRC none that's a default deny
and then you say you only allow scripts
connect that's nature acts call images
and style sheets from the same origin
this looks great every site many sites
load dozens or scores of third-party
assets pixels scripts etc how do you get
to somewhere where you can implement
this sanely so got an example from the
same joke store before now it's
expressing this content security policy
so this is the additional header that
the web server is sending everything
else is the same
I'll show you how this works
so again it's the same checkout form all
the same information is gathered same
malicious JavaScript running posting to
the same cloud CDN ddns dotnet endpoint
same customer buying the same jokes give
it the customer name hey does anyone
know what 14 North Moore Street in
Tribeca is it's a famous eighties movie
firehouse I couldn't know okay finally
so we checked out here we posted to our
checkout page and you can see again the
same information was sent out of 200
submitted all the same payment data this
is fine this is coming back to me
however the connection to the skimming
endpoint was blocked the browser said no
it violates the CSP I'm not going to do
it this is the message the browser will
send back if you specify a reporting
endpoint so you can see something has
changed on the site chances are a
developer dissipated something but maybe
we have some malicious code running
that's trying to siphon data outside
this is a durable method meaning as we
reload several times you'll continue to
see it being blocked and this is the
magic of the inspector I would have had
to do all had to show you all of this in
burp it would have been a lot of
flipping back and forth you would not
liked it again feeling old but these
tools are
so how do you get started implementing
one of these on your site first develop
an inventory of the sensitive pages and
the third-party resources you're
bringing in on those pages so are you
firing Linux you have marketing pixels
etc you don't need to run this
everywhere focus on the pages that
collect sensitive data there is a
separate header you can set that is
called content security policy report
only takes all the same syntax but it
won't block anything it will simply send
data back to your reporting endpoint
saying hey my policy said I shouldn't
have connected this place I'm connecting
to it anyway but I thought you should
know you don't need to run a CSP on all
of your traffic either for initial
implementation or you can argue at all
right if you are getting a relatively
good subset and you know you've got good
coverage maybe you don't need it
everywhere Google has a great syntax
validator for the CSP when you implement
it to tell you've got any syntax bugs
so in summary first you need strong
source code control you need you need to
be able to connect what's in your repo
what's on the server what's running in
the browser if you hash all of those you
can compare in the browser with the SSRI
directive or with the hash directive in
the header to make sure that what your
browser is running is what you expect it
to be you need great integrity
monitoring on the servers make them
immutable maybe you don't care about
this but if you're running actual web
servers and something changes and it's
outside of your expectations you should
know about that right away the process
you need a process with any repo to
notice third-party libraries libraries
with vulnerabilities um what's good
today may not be so good tomorrow
you need to inventory what you've got
today I know in my case it's hundreds of
tracking pixels but none on the checkout
page once you've got
baseline then you work to build the CSB
you started with report only you move it
on into blocking when you're ready and
when you know what effect it's going to
have you use hashing or SSRIs to do that
full integrity check across the chain
and you look at your site from an
external perspective run it from a phone
off the network run it from our browser
off the network make sure that there's
not an evasive technique to prevent you
from seeing malicious code running there
real quick commercial I work for a great
company we're hiring here dev managers
developers coops and any security people
who want to live in an exciting place
work with me in New York work in Bangkok
work and Amsterdam work in the UK
booking comm Priceline open table kayak
we all have openings we all work
together it's a fun team here are a
bunch of references that will be posted
online very soon
any questions Oh questions yeah browser
plugin probably not right let's see
I don't think whatever operations there
if the and the CSP won't help if someone
contains a CSP right if you're that
screwed and you can't detect a change at
the CSP you've got no luck the way a
browser plugin would work if it could I
don't know save it to local storage and
then send it up later
that wouldn't be observed by the CSP
cool thanks
you