so I'm going to talk about BGP again
this year I think it's the fourth year
in a row maybe the fifth this year I'm
going to talk about how BGP has kind of
gone mainstream and it's gotten into the
news quite a lot this year and there's a
lot of emojis in my presentation because
they were quite easy to do so Who am I
I'm starting a new job tomorrow as
network operations manager at broadband
communications North I'm super involved
in the internet scene community but not
in Manitoba I'm involved behind the
scenes and a number of ISPs and service
providers I have a blog called BGP guru
I used to be Cisco do dotnet but I
changed it to BGP guru because if you
get a three-letter domain you better use
it right so mmm-hmm I I'm involved with
the internet exchange both on the board
level and the operations team I'm also
involved in called hack which is a local
not-for-profit that attempts to further
privacy in Canada and I'm also a
co-founder of the Manitoba Network
Operations Group and I've recently
discovered that I absolutely love curry
and so I even started the food blog
about that so I could publish one or two
recipes per year so the first event I
want to talk about is this 2017 Russian
leak slash hijack so if you alright so
next year I'm gonna use latex for my
slides so if you do a google for russian
google bgp hijack there was a lot of
news items from December of 2017 about
this one here so the networks that were
affected for this one here included
Google and YouTube Facebook Microsoft
twitch Riot Games and Apple plus a bunch
of Russian networks
the Russian networks were fully
propagated by almost all of the up
streams the the rest were only
propagated by Hurricane electric so I've
bolded hurricane electric here because
there's a couple pieces along the way
that all sort of fit into the end on
this one here so this one here there was
a lot of speculation about whether it
was malicious or not there were more
specific networks it seems like maybe it
was a traffic optimization escaped but
it's really really hard to actually say
for sure in this case a lot of people
noticed because upstream links were
getting congested and things weren't
working so some of the outcomes of this
one here so this guy I know named job
started putting a lot of pressure on
Hurricane electric to better filter
their internet exchange connections they
they appear extensively I don't know if
you guys get maybe the same Google ads
that I do but the Google ads I see for
American Electric say they have like
8,000 or 10,000 peering sessions so that
is a lot of different peering sessions
to manage filter etc it's not exactly an
easy job if you slack off on it
eventually it's gonna bite you and it's
gonna bite you and maybe kind of a
public way which is what started to
happen earlier on well this is about
january or so this year i'll publish
these slides later so there's a bunch of
links and whatnot that if you're more
interested you can follow them and read
some additional information so the
second event that involves BGP hijacking
this year was the Amazon DNS hijack so
if you google this one here there's tons
and tons and tons and everybody noticed
it was a very very visible of hijack
because stuff wasn't working so this
happened on April 24th of this year five
networks from Amazon Amazon's
route 53 DNS were hijacked more specific
networks they were all slashed twenty
fours they came from an isp in columbus
ohio it's not hasn't really been
determined it was malicious or not but
given the other stuff it seems like they
were probably hacked because they were
slash twenty fours they they were
accepted but they they weren't seen by a
huge number of peers only about fifteen
percent so not the whole internet saw
this but unfortunately because a lot of
people just plonk 8.8.8.8 into their
devices for dns and don't bother to run
their own DNS or don't have the ability
to run it or whatever anymore Google saw
these hijacks and so Google was
returning DNS results for my ether
wallet comm that actually had an IP with
a very long TTL that resolved to an IP
in the eastern Ukraine so some of the
outcomes of this particular hijack job
again proposed that major DNS
authoritative service providers offer
rpki for origin validation so I'd spoke
about rpki
previous years here and I said that it's
a solution but really nobody's using it
yet and so now there's been some
pressure to actually use our PKI
on networks where it actually matters so
Amazon serves a lot of DNS for a lot of
the world if someone else hijacks those
routes some different ASN and you have
an easy thing that you can do to stop
that you know it's no longer you can't
overlook it anymore so if major
authoritative dns providers offer rpki
validations for their routes it also
allowed ISPs and IXP route servers to
drop the invalid routes and so I've
bolded IXP here because I'm going to
come back to that later on and there's a
there's a long Twitter thread in between
job and
Matthieu prints of CloudFlare and
basically he compared them some people
don't want to use our PGI because
there's there's the invalid data and
whatnot in it and he compared it to the
clean up that the cloud filler did for
one dot one dot one dot one where a ton
of networks we're using it internally as
a ping sync or whatever right and so
later on this year there was also a blog
on a medium called towards cleaning up
invalid rpki invalids by a person named
nuisance they haven't really identified
who they are however they've been pretty
active on the Nanog list and they've had
a definite effect on the the number of
rpki invalid certificates that are out
there the post has a nice little graph
but as it turns out I wasn't able to
include graphics very well this year so
the third event I want to talk about is
the BGP hijack Factory so this started
as a series of posts on the the North
American network operator group list by
a guy named Ronald Gill Matt and as it
turns out you know there had been some
BGP hijack activity that was local to
Winnipeg and so he talked to someone who
talked to someone who said well you need
to talk to this deal guy and so I've
actually talked to this guy on the phone
about and I explained how a BGP
hijacking works so in June and July of
this is this is when this all kind of
came to a head so Ronald Guilmette sends
really long emails kind of like myself
and maybe some other people like mark
and and so basically he laid out this
this long history that this bit canal
company out of Portugal had you know
they're involved in spam
hijacking for spam all the a s ends that
they're connected with we're actually
all listed on the spam house drop list
and even their ipv6 slash twenty nine
was listed on the spam Hass drop list as
well and bit canal had extensive peering
at internet exchange points in Europe
but they had been dropped from D six for
bad behavior
BGP hijacking specifically so some of
the outcomes of this particular long
message thread bit canal was booted from
a bunch of transit providers and
internet exchanges and they basically
were booted off the internet with a
coordinated effort from a bunch of
people who cared about not having stuff
hijacked so forth hijack I want to talk
about is when that involves a bunch of
payment systems
this one here happened in July of 2018
of this year
so the first hijack that was attempted
there was a bunch of twenty fours from
various payment processing DNS server
authoritative blocks that were announced
so one of the most from sabbath's
another going the most one was van t'v
which is formerly world pay and then
another one there was actually two more
from a network called q9 networks which
was a data center in Calgary
hence the Canadian connection on this
one here so the first attempted hijack
was by out of a company called digital
wireless Indonesia and that was on July
6 and it didn't last very long and I had
really really limited visibility almost
no one saw it
it wasn't very effective couple days
later Malaysian ISP tries the same thing
the exact same thing
this one here is called extreme
broadband this one here also had limited
visibility and then later on that day
they tried the same thing but they used
a different bgp community that actually
let the route propagate quite a bit more
so instead of only three peers seeing it
like 45 peer saw it which if those are
large peers that can be a significant
portion of the internet additional
payment processing dns authoritative
networks were also hijacked the next day
on July 11 and a couple hours later
which is into the next day again
networks the the first networks that
were mentioned on this slide here are
hijacked yet again by this this
Malaysian ISP and their hijack for a
pretty long time like three hours as
compared to minutes or 15 minutes and q9
noticed this time and to combat you know
this this more specific route they
brought up their own more specific route
for these 2/24 and so in this particular
case as in the Amazon one the IP that
was being returned by these DNS servers
was an IP based out of the eastern
Ukraine again wasn't the same IP but it
was based out of the same city so some
of the outcomes from this particular
hijack there was a lot more push for
validating ebgp routes using rpki
again so job who who works at NTT as
basically an instigator is what you told
me went out and pushed for people to
start you know if you offer a Thorat
ativ dns and you're a big part of the
internet like amazon or dying or one of
these guys you should be making your
routes signed so that other people can
validate them and invalidate the the non
valid ones to one of the ones that came
up more recently actually this actually
only came up about five days
years ago so I haven't had a huge amount
of time to research this one yet is
apparently China Telecom has been
hijacking traffic and so the way that
this one here is actually a little bit
different is that instead of things not
working it was a an interception hijack
so instead of hijacking traffic and
sending it to a different location to
say oh yeah this DNS server is gonna
respond over here instead with this fake
DNS response they just intercepted stuff
and this is actually so this came from a
paper that was just published in the the
military of cyber affairs and then
someone posted this on to the the Nanog
list that I'm on on October 26 so it's
really fresh there's a lot of news about
it if you type in China Telecom BGP
hijack into your search engine you'll
find a lot of stuff about this actually
so I did a little bit of research not a
huge amount but in 2010 they did the
same thing and you might recall that 15
percent of the internet won at the China
for 18 minutes I was a headline that I
recall from about 2010 or so and the
reason that they were able to do this is
they had the backbone capacity that
intentional or not
when BGP things went crazy they were
able to take that traffic and still
deliver it so this particular paper says
that these hijacks were enabled because
China Telecom has an extensive presence
in the US and so essentially they are
able to insert themselves in without too
much latency and because of the way the
BGP works the IAS pass weren't any
longer and so these things actually
worked so some of the traffic that they
they claimed was high
was between Canada and Korea in 2016
between US and Italy in 2016
between Scandinavia and Japan in April
and May of 2017 and Italy to Thailand
between April and July of 2017 so
because these were interception hijacks
you can gain a lot of information by
seeing what sort of traffic is flowing
through your network if you're able to
to get this this stuff flowing through
your network so for instance they be
able to see oh yeah there's an IPSec VPN
between this IP and this IP maybe that's
interesting maybe I need to do a little
more reconnaissance on that
unfortunately the research for this
particular paper was not based on open
data and so I don't know if I'm gonna
get any actual data from the researchers
to validate this or not makes it a
little bit hard when it's a closed
system so some of the solutions so not
everything is all bad
so the BGP hijacks becoming mainstream
this year has increased our PKI adoption
especially with authoritative dns
servers so amazon signed their routes
after the roads were hijacked booked two
weeks later it's a good step also ixps
have been automating their filtering
based on IRR so I was a little bit
horrified to find out that there is
internet exchanges out there that have a
route server that basically this a/s is
allowed to peer in and this lis is
allowed to peer in and there's no
filtering lists so anyone could say 'oh
yeah google's over here 88's over here
and people would accept it because the
route server would send it through
that's crazy
locally at M bik's we've also enabled
automation to do two routes over
filtering we did that over Thanksgiving
weekend this year we're using a piece of
software called a rote server which is
some Python with a bunch of other stuff
all glued in nailed on whatever it uses
irr row projects which is the standard
it also uses Aaron who is origin a s so
if you have IP space that you have
control over one of the things you can
set is that this particular a s might
originate this or this other and you can
list a whole bunch of them in there
it's kind of a new field I don't think
it's been around forever because it's
not populated for a ton of IP space but
in terms of getting a route accepted and
having a local traffic go local it works
for this it doesn't work globally like
you know AT&T and Shaw where they appear
they don't use that they use IR only but
it at least helps with local and it can
kind of band-aid a thing for a day or
two the other thing that we filter based
on is also the rpki certificates that
the robos so if you publish a route that
says this slash 24 can come from this is
or this a s then we look at that the
same as a route object and if it fails
then we actually mark it as invalid too
so when we enable this route filtering
most of the irr objects existed already
and that's due to a lot of the up
streams having already created proxy
entries so sha does this for a lot of
there's not all the time
mts also does this for their customers
again maybe not all the time but less is
pretty good about this mostly because I
make him and then myself because I'm
involved in my own ISP and a couple
others yeah
so can we have any questions if time
what's wait wait we're gonna go with the
front row here first Jared sorry so the
questions about if if if it would work
with HTTP or not I guess is is basically
what I'm boiling it down to and so in
the case of the hijack of my ether
wallet calm there was a self-signed
certificate and so people just click
past that logged into a fake site and
gave out the credentials in the case of
like there's this China Telecom hijack
their stuff is still flowing through
them it's not flowing to a different end
point and so if there was weaknesses or
something in the HTTPS then maybe they
might be able to see something yeah
Jared
yeah basically that's the the best
solution ask for the regional ISPs and
the the tier ones and the i-x bees to
stock less because as a small guy you
know like there's there's people out
there that I only have a default route
you can't do anything with that you
can't do any sort of rpki filtering when
you only have one route and when you
expand that up to you know the people
like myself that are mostly single home
again there's it's not really a lot you
can do because you're just you know but
the the tier ones they definitely need
to be doing this and I know that that
job is putting pressure on them because
he works for for one of the tier ones
for an TT and also you know like the
tier twos and the aggregators and
whatnot
that's where is really really really
helpful and and that stuff has become
since I talked about this you know two
three four years ago it's become a lot
more accessible in in the routers and
stuff that people are actually using
yeah
these are all ipv4 hijacks but I mean
the same thing can happen on ipv6 too
and if you follow the BGP stream Twitter
account you'll see the occasional v6
hijack I don't know if there sometimes
it's just people changing providers or
things like that to you right so it's
hard to investigate them all really
seriously in the back yeah I think
that's you well maybe mid ways
so in the case of a lot of these hijacks
it was used to put up authoritative DNS
servers to respond with different
results
most of the hijacks were like that the
the China Telecom hijacks though were
like that's that's looking at traffic
that's not that's not hosting a
different end point for something that's
let's make this go through us and see
what we can see yeah yeah yeah exactly
I think times up the master questions
like super super super short I haven't
seen anything where people have gotten
certificates like through let's encrypt
or something as a result of this yet but
I think it could have been done in like
the example public the Amazon I think
they could have done that through let's
encrypt and it would have been more
effective
thanks for listening
[Applause]