hello everyone thank you for having me
back at besides our society the
conference formerly known as besides
this is my second time presenting here
and those with good memories and sharp
eyes will notice a few things are
different about my talk this year
compared to last year first and foremost
my version of Windows is now activated
so I consider that yeah progress right
there the the tone of my talk has also
changed somewhat compared to last year
so last year being my first time
presenting at a security conference my
tone was kind of you know go easy on me
please don't hurt me be gentle and I'll
try to entertain you so one year has
passed and now I'm brimming with
confidence maybe a little bit too much
and now my tone is one more of you know
come get some right because if you don't
agree with me by the time this talk is
over haven't helped me I will fight you
and I when I say that I mean it
metaphorically okay let's be clear so
anyway um bit about me so typically BIOS
suck and I would tell you to just you
know read the handout or whatever but
Dylan you know accidentally left me off
the official pamphlet and the reality is
it doesn't behoove me to engage in an
opportunity of shameless self-promotion
so I'm actually here in two capacities
first and foremost I am the IT security
guy at Merlin so for those who aren't
familiar with Merlin we are the primary
provider of internet and Internet
services for education in Manitoba it's
great off a great job and in this role I
get to wear every single InfoSec hat
imaginable I do forensics I do incident
response pen testing policy the whole
shebang
but I'm also here as the co-founder of a
small IT firm called Flying Fortress IT
which I co-founded with that that Amazon
guy Mike himbo and together we try to
offer a cloud in security expertise to
small and medium businesses in Manitoba
so if you or someone you love is a small
or medium sized business in Manitoba and
needs to need some help kind of bridging
that skill gap you know you're not quite
big enough to justify having a full-time
IT security
come on give us a call we'll see what we
can do to help you okay so I'm here to
talk about passwords now I love
passwords wait no I hate passwords but I
love talking about passwords I love
studying passwords I find passwords
absolutely fascinating now when I say
that that sounds really really weird to
most you know normal people now just
probably not too many normal people here
but just in case nobody is on board
I love the study of passwords if you
will password ology so why is this so
fascinating well I got a little example
here so if we take a typical
traditionally good password like Steve
Ballmer's old password developers it's
traditionally good right it's 11
characters long upper case lower case
and it even has a special character
right according to password meter com
it's 65% or strong and and it'll take 97
years to crack right yeah that's we all
know that's right any any
pentester worth his or her salt will
tell you you know it's a it's a really
crappy passer right it's a common ish
dictionary word even in the the raw Q
password of the database right and it
follows a lot of common patterns right
so sure it has an uppercase but it's the
first letter right and and sure it has a
special character but it's an
exclamation mark and it's at the end of
the word right whereas whenever somebody
adds a special character to their
password it's almost always an
exclamation mark and it's almost always
at the end right so the upshot is that
if a hacker is trying to break this
password they're probably going to try
the word developers and they're probably
gonna try capital D developers with an
exclamation mark what do I find super
interesting is if I take that password
and I make one tiny little change to it
I move the the exclamation mark over a
couple of characters suddenly I've taken
a really crappy password and made it
substantially stronger and I'm still not
claiming it's a great password but it is
a lot better than the one before and
that's mostly because it's just no
longer following that those common
patterns of putting an exclamation mark
at the end right it's kind of breaking
the mold in that sense now I do believe
there are modules in hash cat that'll
that'll still get that there's one
little like move characters around and
like that
so it's still crackable
but it's still substantially better than
it was before so this is why I find
passwords or password ology super
interesting right it's this this
confluence of you know human psychology
and computer science and mathematics all
coming together for this really
interesting field password ology the nd
mspaint skills are on full display here
today alright so Peters talk about
passwords what about passwords am i here
to say I'm not here to tell you how to
choose a good password heaven help me
we've beaten that correct horse to death
many many times I'm also not here to
tell you that passwords are dead usually
if somebody tells you or tries to tell
you that passwords are dead they're
probably a sales engineer and as we all
know sales engineers are the scum of the
earth so not making that claim in fact
reports of the death of passwords have
been grossly overstated quite quite
famously in 2011 IBM claimed that by
2016 five years later we'd never be
using a password again right but the
last time when I tried logging into IBM
calm slash support what do you need oh
it's a password right so good call on
that one IBM what's that
wishful that they're going for there's
also some noise about password lists
solutions but when you kind of dig into
them you realize they're not actually
password list who they are typically
doing is using another Authenticator
like say an email account as your
Authenticator so they're kind of almost
more more password outsourcing than
password lists and the advantage here is
convenience rather than actually
improving the security of passwords all
right yeah specifically I'm here to talk
a little passive rotation or more
specifically by passive rotation is back
or most specifically why mandatory
frequent pasión rotation which is to say
the passive rotation that exists in
pretty much every corporate environment
I've ever had to deal with not only
doesn't improve an organization's
security it actually actively inhibits
it it makes it substantially worse now I
hope you know these are this is a sample
of the InfoSec community in Winnipeg you
know probably a lot of you are already
on board this train but maybe some of
you aren't and even if you are this is a
sort of thing that that bears repeating
or something you can go and take back to
your IT admins and sysadmin and say hey
we should stop doing this because ABC
Sarah so a little bit of background
password rotation has been around
basically forever or at least since 1985
which is basically forever in terms of
internet time the Department of Defense
published a guide advocating password
rotation and the kind of you kind of
took off from there nobody's really sure
why it exploded the way it did but it
just kind of became standard practice
from there and it stayed that way for
more than 20 years until some fellow by
the name of Jean Spafford at serious
published a really great article
questioning hey why are we doing this
this doesn't actually help us when we
stop and think about it and as anybody
going against the you know common
orthodoxy of the day he was met with
Swift vitriolic and extremely ignorant
pushback the really good example is lob
saw the League of professional system
administrators we have an extremely
pretentious title published an article
in defense of password expiration that
really really demonstrated this pushback
so why is Pastor rotation not actually
helpful so the main rationale behind why
we do mandatory frequent pastor rotation
is is to limit the amount of time that
an attacker can use stolen credentials
to access your network now this sounds
like a great idea right like if you're
if you're constantly rotating your
password or your passwords you know an
attacker can only use a stolen password
to access your network for you know 30
days 60 days 90 days whatever right and
that makes a lot of sense in 1985 when
attackers techniques were you know very
very slow very manual and it took a lot
of time to do things right and I tended
to just kind of stick around the network
and not really miss things about but in
the modern day in 22 18 hear that that
doesn't make so much sense anymore right
like how long are you really comfortable
leaving an attacker have access to your
network are you comfortable with your to
an attacker being on your network for 30
days I'm sure not I'm not comfortable
having an attacker on my network for one
minute right how long does it take to
establish persistence or leave the
backdoor right or deploy cryptolocker
sure as hell doesn't take 30 days to do
that anymore and in fact a couple of
former NSA ta operatives have come out
and said yeah you know in our experience
hacking other nation-states passive
rotation is never inhibited us even once
and the idea being that if you've
changed your password you now safe
doesn't really help too much when the
people are doing it all the time right
and because when somebody changes their
password if I still have their old
password I have this huge insight into
what they're typically what they
typically choose for a password you know
I know what their new password looks
like or I have a good idea so a very
simple example right if a user's old
password was red Honda 11 how much do
you want to bet their next password is
red Honda
12 or red Honda 1 1 1 or or whatever
right and then you might say well we
could put rules in place this is often
the the approach to fixing these sorts
of problems is well we can put password
generation rules in place so that you
know a certain number of characters have
to be different well ok then the user
will just choose a password that's like
orange Toyota 11 right or still follow
some sort of predictable pattern and
then ultimately just in a larger sense
making you just change passwords
frequently just makes it harder for them
to remember passwords right users hate
changing the passwords frequency I don't
know if you guys have spoken to a user
recently it's it's a terrible thing and
I don't blame them I hate doing it
myself and ultimately yeah they choose
proper passwords that are shorter and
easier to remember and are therefore
easier to guess and crack for an
adversary this has been known for a long
time Adams and SAS back in 1999
published a paper about this but it was
largely ignored and we just kind of
tribes gone with it and it'll also lead
to more frequent occurrences of other
problems like writing down passwords or
storing them in securely you know text
files or spreadsheets and that sort of
thing it also puts a drain on your your
helpdesk right because people will be
more likely to phone in say hey I forgot
my password because I had to change it
to days they're going over what I
changed it to so ultimately it's it's
much better to have longer more secure
passwords that never or rarely expire
right and it also
you an opportunity to sell that right if
if you disable pastor rotation but up
your complexity requirements right
people are less likely to complain
because they only have to remember a
password once now and the reality is
past rotation is just it's
computationally expensive for users now
users aren't stupid welcome
some users are stupid but most users
aren't stupid right alright I kind of
resist that narrative however I do think
users are a little bit lazy and when I
say that I don't mean that disparagingly
I actually kind of you know respect that
right because if you're a little bit
lazy you're less likely to waste time
doing something pointless or worthless
so it actually has it has value to our
organization if your users are just just
a little bit lazy and because they're
lazy and they have to deal with all
these requirements and and advice they
take shortcuts right this is this is the
reality but it's not just that it
doesn't help my argument is stronger
than that I'm saying pastor rotation
actually makes things worse right so if
your if your users are changing their
passwords every 30 days well what else
changes every 30 days I don't know maybe
maybe the month changes every 30 days or
90 days maybe the seasons change every
90 days and so I've seen this time and
again you see a lot of common repeated
patterns right you'll see a lot of users
who use passwords like November 2018 or
fall 2018 or other passwords following a
very very similar similar pattern and
these again these are traditionally good
passwords they're long they have capital
letters some of them have special
characters even right most password you
know requirements are met with these
really crappy passwords so in my
experience in admittedly somewhat
limited experience I found that about
two to three percent of users in an
environment with their forcing password
rotation on a regular basis will have
passwords that fall into a pattern
somewhat like this you know fall or
November 2018 now two to three percent
doesn't sound like a lot but in an
organization of just one hundred users
you're almost guaranteed that at least
one of them will have a password that
fits this pattern right and if that user
has VPN access well you know there's a
organization from the outside in fact
this is such a common problem that I've
run into time and again I made my maid a
tool for generating passwords that that
fit this pattern depending on what time
of year it is that I'm doing the
engagement be welcome to check it out I
called it password vortex because I have
a flair for the dramatic and you can
download it check it out please don't
make fun with my terrible coding skills
no I've just ragging on pasture rotation
for the past five ten minutes I will be
grudgingly admit that it has a little
bit of an upside and that is if you're
using if you're forcing passive rotation
it does cause users if they're if
they're reusing their password from
their social accounts for their
professional accounts it does kind of
cause that to eventually kind of diverge
and and sort of lose sync and that's
good I mean users aren't supposed to
reuse passwords but they do and so this
does help with that but we still have
the same problem as before right if
they're if their social media password
is red Toyota 11 then you know what's a
good chance that their corporate
password is something like red Toyota 12
so if as an adversary I gain their
social media passwords through leak or
social engineering or whatever again I
have a huge hint into what that users
corporate password probably looks like I
also think there's maybe a better way of
dealing with this problem
but I'll come back to that so this kind
of persisted after 2006 until about 2009
2010 that's when we really started to
see some some pushback from experts in
the community and it kind of started
with the the first academic research was
published in 2010 by by a bunch of
researchers actually I forgot where they
were from well the security of modern
password expiration and the fact that we
finally had quantifiable academic or
research really went a long way into
allowing you know allowing the experts
to push back against this you know
perceived wisdom so Bruce Schneier
started weighing in other experts sans
waiting on it and said hey we should
stop doing this
Lori Craner who was pretty awesome
although I think I got her name wrong
former professor of computer science and
chief technologists of
the FTC has been quite vocal about this
as well and in fact shortly after she
started her role as the chief
technologist of the FTC somebody in
charge of the Twitter account posted a
tweet saying hey remember to change your
passwords frequently and she had to you
know step in and kind of lay the
smackdown on that one the GCHQ um they
changed their tune back in January of
2016 and NIST followed suit about a year
later in in 2017 so even though these
these big names like Bruce Schneier and
sands and NIST and GCHQ are all saying
hey don't do this anymore there are a
lot of examples of organizations who've
know better who ostensibly deal in
security who are still recommending that
we do this place is like like managed
engine the pide evolutions networks all
of these are our firms that deal with
security and some of them quite
humorously evolutions deals and password
management and privileged access
management still doesn't know better
right these guys are supposed to be
experts and you're still recommending
this I got to the second page of Google
results and I got tired of doing this so
the reality is you can just you can find
no shortage of firms that are still
recommending this practice Microsoft
seems to be of two minds about this
maybe not quite a typically they see
they officially say not to use mandatory
password rotation in fact it was some
Microsoft researchers where some of the
early ones leading the charge against it
but even though they officially say that
the default value for maximum password
age on a domain controller is four to
two days right that's still the default
and if you dig into the Microsoft
documents it flat-out says best
practices set maximum password age to
between 30 and 90 days so maybe it's a
symptom of being a large organization
like Microsoft but the right hand seems
to not know what the left hand is doing
so I consider this the most egregious
example of the Center for Internet
Security publishes a lot of great
documents benchmarks and security
controls they're still on board the
mandatory pastor rotation is a good idea
train and they don't seem to want to get
off not sure why but hopefully that'll
change soon and of course you can't look
to your governments as examples of what
to do with
a certain federal government whom I will
not name but we're all very familiar
with it still recommends or requires a
minimum of eight character password that
needs to be changed every few months
within a certain provincial government
seven characters 90 days same with a
certain municipal government is also
seven characters and in 90 days I
singled out the government of BC here
for also having a bad policy but I
wanted to mention them because they'll
all right publish this information they
have a great set of documents if you're
looking to create a security standard
for organization there have great
documents good for modeling after except
for the fact that they have really poor
passer requirements alright time for a
quick story so I was working with this
one organization great organization they
really got their head on straight
they're trying to improve their their
security so they brought me in to kind
of do a pen test and assessment and help
them out and as part of the pen test I
was able to leverage the fact that they
were using mandatory password rotation
to crack their perimeter and get onto
the network so afterwards you know we're
doing the after-action the debriefing of
how did I breaking this up and I did
explain to them why this is a bad thing
and how I was able to leverage it and
they said okay Travis we hear what
you're saying we understand the problem
we'll change it from 30 days to 60 a
mass maximum password rotation that's
just like no no that's you didn't
understand it at all
eventually they came around but this
just kind of goes to illustrate just how
ingrained this idea that passive
rotation is a necessary thing rather
even when faced directly with the
evidence the idea was just let's just
make it long fair right that doesn't
really solve the problem so the National
question is well if 30 days or 60 days
of 90 days is far too short well when
how long should it be should I do it at
all should I never change my passwords
well and the obvious answer is you know
if you sue if you suspect you've been
compromised change your passwords I mean
that kind of goes without saying some
people say you know do one year do two
years and this helps it avoids some of
the problems of having those common
patterns or where users are choosing
really really weak passwords pardon me
but it's kind of like what's the
then because remember that the main
reason is that we want to limit the
amount of time an attacker can use
stolen credentials on a network right
and and one year as a hell of a long
time to let an attacker muck about on
your network if you pressure me and say
how long should it be Travis I kind of
go I don't really know because even
though I just talked about how posture
rotation is terrible if you came up to
me and told me that you were using a
password the same password for you know
10 15 years I'd probably go you might
want to change that right it's even I
have a hard time letting go of that idea
so can we do better than pass the
rotation yes absolutely
it's called account monitoring user
based analytics and all that sort of
thing what that actually looks like
we're side of the scope of this talk
multi-factor authentication also would
go a long way to improving this problem
you don't really need to rotate
passwords if we have multi factors yeah
that kind of likes that problem of
course is that multi-factor
authentication doesn't really work in
Windows Active Directory environments
again that's another issue way outside
the scope of this talk so one idea that
I like I'm kind of kicking around
tentatively is the idea of password
audits and that is you you have a
professional come in or you do this
yourself and take your password database
securely of course and you try to crack
the passwords contained therein and
basically you're doing the same thing to
your password database that in modern
adversary what you're using the same
tools and techniques and identifying
which passwords are likely to fall in
the event of a compromised and the idea
is to kind of try to pick off the the
lowest hanging fruit
you know Bureau which passwords are
actually weak according to you know
objective metrics instead of just
guessing now the idea it's very
important that we want to use this as a
teaching moment we don't want to shame
users for having a strong password but
it does give us the ability to
concretely say hey you have a weak
password because you did you know you're
using a dictionary word you know please
don't do that here's how a better way of
choosing a password right and the idea
is is make sure that you're
communicating with your users when doing
this now this is a lot of organizations
may not be familiar with you know what's
how to crack passwords or they don't
have the resources to build their own
password cracking rig which
a lot of money but you know we can do
this with AWS and you know maybe
somebody can give you a hand with that
if you if you need so I do have some
bonus slides but I don't think I have
time for bonus slides no I do not have
time for mones slides so we'll go into
the questions you were first yes I think
you may have missed the the point of my
talk but yeah I can see some value in
that because you you avoid the pitfalls
of having them choosing weak passwords
or fall or following common patterns but
how much would that really help well
dubious I mean if the password gets
outright stolen through a keylogger I
guess and and with an automated service
I guess you can set it up to rotate the
passwords daily or whatever right so I
would see that house as having some
value and because it's basically free
with an automated service I guess yeah
turn it on why not okay
yes
yes rainbow tables also good times I'm
even kicked off the stage sorry Moz
[Applause]