I'm an eagle I'm gonna do a talk about
something I haven't just written this
late honestly they've been written for
about ten minutes so we'll get there
I'll be fine
so if you read the brief you might have
thought about pen testing and learning
about shit and winging it and stuff of
that and you might be sort of rightness
stop the boat okay pen tasting but
anyway so a blanket tree Who am I I'm a
fresh or an eagle you might know me for
several reasons I would sharp I put a
rope and some people seem to enjoy it
if you've not read it called fucking by
it's great and you also might know me
because I got a lot of spirit
conferences and they talk at people but
not ask me who talks so this is the
first time in about three years I've
done a talk a security conference so it
may be okay oh okay
FC and Jessica Barker will shine about
at the start what's the worst that could
happen on stage now white will probably
shake yourself hopefully that doesn't
happen so we'll go for it and the other
reason you might know me and I phoned a
couple years ago Frank quite a few bugs
and quite well-known public services
website some you might have heard of it
it's to have videos for people and if
you don't know going people my name
you'll find out this is a safe for work
top guys and I also work so my day job I
worked for a pet I work for a company
called paint as partners as a security
consultant so I break shit for a living
and and I get paid for it it's creative
fun and and my evenings I spend them
kicking things breaking things hacking
things good films and driving places
some things in that order
because it's quite good fun now seat
guys come on I've only just started
I've I even got into the interesting
stuff yet just talk about yourself so
that's me they are not dead although
some of you might have been led to
believe last night on Twitter I was dead
that's red wine I saw an opportunity and
I took it so you should doing pen
testing always so apart from being a
tech in a lot shit I'm also a black dog
right so I'm not only a keyboard warrior
I can break your legs if I want to so
there's that so thanks for today yes
we're going to understand pen testing
we're gonna give you a few tips and
tricks so and what I've learned through
my time in pen testing which is about
four years some lessons that I would
wear should be
before I got to pen testing and the
different traits that a tester can have
so it's not all about acting that are
other aspects of things and I saw a
better person see stuff as a pen tester
slash hacker because it's not all poppin
shelves it's not all sunshine and
rainbows as they wait to see it it's
good fun so okay giggle penetration
testing if you've not heard it before
it's the art of finding holes on certain
websites or in the real world that's
it's hacking things but it's a good
conversation star certainly when you're
chatting to a bunch of muggles who have
no idea what you're talking about they
ask you what you're doing you go what a
penetration tester like right
what's that well that's not what you
think
find homes and computers and break
things and food bits and pieces but it's
also good to laugh when you follow up
with I faint holes in pornhub and they
go there's hot holes in that website
don't you know it so so really what is
pen testing the expectation is have
already said is popping shells all day
hacking all the things and yes there is
quite a lot of that but the reality is
you're working zarkan so and for our
clients your your there's a massive
human aspect of things once you break
something you need to explain to the
client
well yes I broke your thing but this is
how you fix it and this is why it's a
problem recently on site with a client
and they had MS o 8 which is quite
annoyed everyone bow if you don't know
it it's probably one of the most famous
execution if underbellies and it was
like yep this is a problem no no no it's
fine they're not interactive machines in
like yes but your staff gets the waste
point these things are still sensitive
bigger they're like nah that'll never
happen and like a month later somebody
run off with our customer database
alright just tell you this like and once
the goods it's fine so that's that's
what happens in pen test and you tell
people that their stuffs broken and you
tried to help them a little lesson -
yeah so what are you gonna do anyway if
you also need to be the king or queen of
analogies when you're explaining things
to business because you can't just go
well if I found Exeter CSRF srf and all
that stuff and the business guy goes
what yeah so anyway I'm rattling through
this top industry for two minutes anyway
so it clicks the trees the good the bad
downright ugly - so these are the dues
of pen testing when you're Europe
away about read the fucking manual
always if you have if you have time
because sometimes if you can pull in the
framework the Apple fall it's always
worth doing so if you've got something
like Oracle Business Week you look at it
and you go are well some guy called Dave
watch field phone a bunch of one about
if you go to use them straight away
you've got actually or you've got
exercise with it sequel injection or
something else so they're quick ones are
looking at a little bits and pieces that
might fall under stress in certain
environments you've also got to be not
afraid of googling things like a ninja
you just if in pain testing is
inevitable you're going to come across
something on site you're going to find
something an application you've never
seen before you may have seen something
like it but you know how to well maybe
you don't know how to good be asking
Google how they do this no a lot of
people will say I don't do that say you
do you do if you think about it you go
well I've seen XSS before but I've lost
you in this environment exercise for
those who don't always cross they scrape
things and we've executing JavaScript in
our victims browser so you might see
that one tag is filled out you might try
something else and googling it finds you
find out what stopped you it's good so
as well as that on an application
actually use it before you go to start
hacking stuff because some things
function out it can also be a bunny you
have the current phrase that it's not a
bug it's a feature but a lot of time
that stuff can lead to more serious
issues so as to use it before you go
breaking it the other aspect of that is
if you start hacking things before you
actually use it and you break it to an
extent that it's no longer usable how
are you gonna like work out what the
rest goes the business do you buy oh
yeah go exercise the app doesn't work
anymore and like well yeah that's great
but like can you elaborate on wife's
problem or or what users are impact if
you wanna break it out can't use it you
don't fight the internship on day one
you're screwed basically and the other
tips I have are if you can't use Google
if you're on site always have to
colleague you'll be surprised how much
people know more than you and the little
things you forget you can use them and
it's really really useful also being on
site your dog can be quite lonely so
maybe don't ask the client how this
works or maybe do is it just depends if
your wife always gauge your situation
and what you're doing and so Google like
a ninja and when it comes to em fuck
try HTTP HTTPS on kind of random port
she be surprised was run on HTTP iPhone
things running on like port
10,000 or 11,000 the one that is an
admin interface for like a back-end
database or the internet people what
they wouldn't ever find that it's on a
high port no one scans high port it's
true some people don't but the people
who do you find the golden treasure
troves so it's worth doing there are
there other random things where you find
really high for so always go for scan if
you can because you can find things
running you can run that cat connector
finding that minute fish use FTP use
telnet things that are very old but are
still run the bellies and people still
run telnet on for 10,000 because it'll
be fine it's safe so people like there's
and admins they do weird things so
that's the dues of pen testing the
don'ts don't do these things bad things
happen okay so when you're when you're
testing away about and this I know
someone who's done this don't run spy
though just don't just flex by leg
around going for lunch it's really bad
things happen I had a million in the
previous company who ran spider on a
wordpress site and it came across he had
automatically submit forms on so when it
finds a function which is done' and it
had a function that was delete table no
that's fine i'm so drop tables so what's
in the picture of drop tables that's
fine if you catch it but he wiped the
entire client production database they
have database and pre prod database in
the space of a one show I was like how
you doing is that yeah it's a great test
having phone and the apps don't and what
okay why is the app don't so you can try
it was so the apps down and yeah
everything's don't say okay care to
elaborate there's no data where's the
data going
so there goes for the logs and say oh
yeah we found the function that's
dropped tables and you can do on offend
the kid who thought that was a good idea
so anyway don't spider things round away
also if you're using Bob sweet door just
right-click on the root of the web web
ruin quite active scan because that can
also cause problems that was on site
recently and there was a web interface
for a virtual desktop environments at a
shutdown function which is fine for
admins because you obviously need to
shut down maybe boxes on this they you
think maybe there's education or
something but but no who needs a
authentication grown in Tehran network
so if you
if you were to act out that we scan that
we didn't do it but we asked the quite
houses we could just shut them run them
boxes it just pack a box and go
gonna shut that one down that one down
and that one doe because because why not
there was disaster recovery but I don't
know who thought I was a good idea but
alas always make sure as well see when
you're given a target range by a client
to scan check is the right range because
if you're if you're entirely or
externally the worst thing that can
happen is crank goes yeah so Mike's
Terry is 192.168.1 you like is it is it
really and we're am I going to be
located to you they gave me a VPN oh no
you don't have VPN we can access it fine
in our systems it's like yeah the other
problem is as a human you will make you
will sometimes mistake like so always be
careful we could type into the web
browser if you missed taper the main by
a single character stuff can go wrong
hasn't happen to you personally but one
of my colleagues not program vehicle to
companies go enter the URL wrong who's
hacking it for five days so no problem
lovers of flight goes yeah that's not
all right don't who's that that is best
Nora so don't be that guy so as well the
other doors is always be careful what
kind of bandwidth you've got and not
work twice but in my personal and I do
like researcher to pass research and I
have a 10 gauge and dedicated service
it's got Lane and normally yeah as finds
great for taunting and everything else
but see when you go to test applications
just be careful you're not bossing
someone with 10 gigs that they only
therefore Scott it happens I've seen it
I was doing research and at the site
when donors are shit the site stone what
I do and when did it from my lesser VPS
and nothing massive oh it's the
bandwidth you need be careful how much
daily attendance so I was worth looking
into and being careful so they're
they're the the do's and don'ts of
testing so the lessons I thought let me
want to teach you as a potential pain
tester one site 101 always pack
everything be prepared for anything if
you're rockin a dataset
pack warm clothes it what Canada itself
pack cold foods have along an Ethernet
cable have a switch have an extension
lead basically going like you're ready
for war have a camping chair because the
floor is come through for a day but if
you don't say for five days it's not fun
believe they have done it have a USB
Ethernet adapter model pulls off them
because one can feel you can be
convinced the night before was working
rock up on the client say it's like yep
but the quite definitely your fault your
infrastructure is broken find out your
Ethernet adapter it's diet always have
multiples always have a USB stick on you
if you need to transfer things they're
quite the make sure it's encrypted
the only pacified there about don't be
silly I also be prepared for things not
to work anyone who's been on site as a
pen test or as an eye Arkansan or
anything they one normally as a right
off normally sometimes it's fine wrong
something goes so yeah and we knew you
were coming
we've known this for three months but
we're not ready it's like okay cool
that's fine we'll just wait for you you
get for once Dana Andrews yep now we're
still waiting for dangerous reads better
change order and get all that stuff so I
know which it happens anyone whose
apparent half the room will have
experienced at some point if you haven't
you've got fantastic clients and I feel
really bad for you that you're messing
today on site alas anyway so let's talk
winging it Moo spokes are waiting here
and if they tell you they're not they're
lying or they're probably old enough
being in the business for a while and do
everything up here but not way in the
sense I have no idea what I'm doing it's
more that every opportunities a learning
opportunity at a colleague of mine
described it as experimenting so you're
not necessarily learning a new
technology and then going I'm just gonna
hack it you're you're learning new
technology experimenting it and then
trying on find site and and usually ends
up being you find technology one week
that you've never dealt with before but
you've found something someone to and
you can apply the same methodology the
same motions to that to go and hatch
this somewhere no answers it's really
good for that perspective and it works
fifty percent of time obviously the time
so there's that the other hats of a
tester so intense that can have many
hats not in this case of black hat white
hat and green hats not heard about the
good guys are bad guys and the guys are
not quite sure if the good
but alas you have the the range of
trades I deal with the text around day
to day basis you know hacker yes you're
finding home you find problems your
consultants you're helping the business
fix things you're also helping the blue
team in some aspects of things so if you
break something you're working with the
recovery the response the forensics
everything you're you're learning on the
go and this is this is a quote it's not
really related to this late but I found
it quite funny anyway one of my
colleagues this this is mattre for
testing something something root so you
rock up you go
unless this this route they would have
no bother
so it's usually working from so yeah
you've got you've got the different
trades the the trees that being a hacker
you don't really get talking universe
you don't make that toilet of course is
the business aspect of things so so
being a bear of business hacker you get
all these amazing acronyms and you've
got you've got a she exs FCS RFS is
sorry beast who do robot SSL you could
possible angle everywhere cop use of use
of colleague sons very good there if
anyone notices and being being in a
boardroom and seeing this or if you're
in a boardroom you end up seeing this
and they said if you've got a lot of
people that were just cook with white
just not understand you see she need to
be king at what you're going to king or
queen uh what you're going to say you
need to be able to articulate both the
technical Wizards and the c-level
executives and my old boss used to say
imagine you're teaching your granny
imagine and your executive some are you
explaining it's an old person know what
the fries used to be is amazing you're
teaching a toddler but a lot of toddlers
these days were smarter than sea level
use X so you've got that I'm thankful
you guys laughed I was like shit is that
gonna make you laugh or not but yes
you've got that you imagine you're
teaching your granite any anytime so any
any paint tester anything with a
business rust summary executive summary
they might have teaching of grounding
imagine you explaining it but but so
you're a guy doesn't know exercise says
you know SSRS they don't know what SSL
or they might know SSL is you've seen it
to be padlock some people describe the
handbag in my browser not so fresh often
yes it's fair so you need to be you need
to articulate were these things asked to
try and break them down to if you're
looking at something like SSL you're
like well those encryption and it's
keeping your data safe and it's making
sure that bad guys can't see that you're
an Amazon buying your shopping
or bad guys can't see what you're
browsing on YouTube and stuff with that
or you've got things like XSS so a bad
guy or a good guy or in it or bad Garrow
it doesn't know gender exclusive all
that stuff and you can execute malicious
code in your browser and therefore steal
your session and steal your shopping
potentially so think it's thinking about
it
as well as being a business hacker you
also need to be a people person so being
a hacker you quite well a lot of hackers
are in Traverse I'm quite a social guy
so I find myself a people person but you
need to not be able to manage your
situation so it's a case of knives in
the clients when things go wrong you
need to be able to communicate that the
client you need to be able to articulate
things in a way that you then become a
consultant more than a hacker so you're
able to admires when things are
happening so if you report something to
clients so I had all my thoughts with me
yesterday they call it anyway or yes
something's gone wrong and that they
didn't follow up with an email so the
client at the end of it they went oh no
that wasn't report that's been here and
that's it but back to the phone's no no
no but there's nothing on paper so I
always always keep a note of everything
always always trying try and keep notes
it's the same as anyone who's looked at
the forensic protest you keep everything
in a repeatable state your report is
going to be readable by someone so
anything that goes into your report
should be like communicated with you the
client and also anything you say should
be report and vice versa so those that I
have rattle through that's talking about
15 units at the apologize but you can
find me on the internet that's my
twitter my blog my book which is
currently free so anyone who's
interested in getting into pen testing
and security check out Lucas just pretty
good and also from their work for
apprentice panelists we did blogs about
hacking I've do things in swaps bits
pieces my head of us pretty good stuff
so they'll forgive me a minute to take a
few pictures of that or to come and fade
me offers and finally they don't get any
questions you've got questions right
around is it ten minutes in we get any
questions so don't want to be the guy
waiting about afterwards that yeah
so the question was is pentesting going
to more towards camp ice yes and no you
get clients who do one technology
exercise but a lot of clients that I
work with and the enters partners work
with a warden actual pen testers so
their what their apps tested for to be
secure or to be an acceptable risk
standard you've got the same things with
hardware your wanting your hardware to
be find holes before the bad guys do
there are there isn't a certain degree
of things like cyber centers which are
check box exercises but it means that
you get a badge that you can go and work
with mystery defense which is fair
enough if you're if you're Jamie's
corner shop or Jimmy's IP that wants to
go in what with um LD you lose on the
EDB cyber essentials certified so
therefore as a tech bhakta so I would
say the majority of pen testing is
probably 70/30 between 70% being actual
pen testing throat sentient exercise
they'll probably have this things like
gdpr which people want entice things
like bullshit GPRS common and we need
pen tested we've defined our homes and
all this stuff but I'd say it's probably
70/30 there are some farms out there
that are they're described as point
penton's popping though so they would
just do check what it says over and over
and over again just an easy ground they
easy easy easy
which is fine like because you're making
a lot of money but if you're a pen
tester in that environment you'd be
expected you'd be extending your spell
to move ones and 12 months to find
something interesting so does that
answer your question yeah enough
yep so trends wise certainly pen test
partners we've weeded quite a lot of
work with hardware so we've got quite a
lot of internet has an evil things test
the car we've got a lot of like youthful
hacking in bits and pieces
hey the trend is more towards hardcore
nowadays there's a lot of people
interesting like fishing in different
fishing has always been interested it's
now becoming more and more interesting
because people are going or GDP are
going to do everything which is just a
bunch of layers really bit
that the trend is more towards hard work
refrain it which was Hardware night but
the stowaway anyway other other places
will probably find that a lot of stuff
is moving towards web because everyone
everyone in the dog can write they've up
and go off I'm your GS to be that's a
good-ass that tends to be the train in
the ass better things but I'd say
probably hardware so if you're wanting
to get into paintings and hardware the
proceeds that we forward who listen to
poly and routine he's talking to me talk
about that sort of stuff too so when I
said transfer method is not like by the
book I found excess here so I'm going to
try it here it's more looking at the
technology so if you find if you come
across an application freeze up uses
WebSockets so I came across one reason
is WebSockets is using everything that's
transparent so you look at similar
techniques you use napkins previously so
I found previously that there's
application has object referencing so
references by one two three every three
a3 through them using they were document
so the same things up that way it's not
just gonna going yes from this this is
directly transferable places it's
ticking being more fluid with it
so no not not wait for like bit knowing
when to Google things is more like
you've heard of it you sort of
understand that go and read about the
kind of documents that sort of thing
that's that's what I'm say it be a typo
also
Google's really helpful for when the
random flags and tool so if you're using
like really all the articles he pull
you've not used it in ages so remember
you've never used it you like shipped
another fight for us it can be really
useful to go with other man page my page
is really useful I hope air else
it depends on their job
it depends it's a knowledge as well so
some applications will be brand new
technology that you've never seen before
and you end up failing boats by accident
that end up going well our phone sequel
injection here and it's blind but very
it's not like its tendency you'd only
get in the app sleeping for like 1 2 3
seconds that type you want to dig into
it and find more so it really depends on
the length of the job if you've got to
post once or two days test 1d reporting
you're not gonna have enough time to
write an order or if you if you do you
know you you know we but it just varies
sometimes you'll get like a 20 day text
which is fantastic you've got enough
time to look at like a whole free mark
or something and go in Dec really deep
but it just depends but also the the
kind of person that spent things I do
like bug bounties and stuff my free time
and I find myself doing a lot of
research with that which helps with a
day job so I'll find something about
Bernie which earns a bit of cash
whatever but then I see our customer job
couple weeks later and go I've seen that
before I can go and apply that it is
it's so Imperial it's pays the Spencer
that's left the job depends on how
interesting it is
friends the technology if you've seen it
before there's lots of factors but the
rest is really vague answer yeah I don't
think that to be honest I don't think
that'll ever happen I think the human
aspect things is always going to be
valuable
you'll get clients you mean that there
are already automated solutions out
there there's army avv that is maybe
next generation amazing but it's still
we bypassed the computer is only as
smart as they treated it they mean you
have artificial intelligence business in
their name you know what other non sirs
but you still have you still need our
human aspect things because you make
mistakes as the humans but if you take
everything by the book from AI and go
are this said that we're vulnerable to
this ends up being a false positive it
might be able to correct itself but if
you want a human to step and go that's
apps they're false positive you take
that as gospel and it'll be where is but
that's you Kris Pilon the think it'll be
I don't think it will ever be a time for
to be released I think painters will
evolve of time and maybe in corporately
I think it will be well that that's that
is a problem I mean that falls into the
check box no sighs that is a plant over
there a lot of check box test people
will just click and run net is there are
some consultancies out there I'm not
going to name them but it will send a
graduate and they'll drop neces and an
internal network just run it
Oh export the NASA's report and go
there's your report there's no value
there the test there isn't learning
science not getting anything they can
they can tell would be for NASA's it's
no problem using this as an example
there are many tools like that do it but
necess is one of the most popular so
there's no value for that I spent things
but the clients like I've got my check
box I'm happy so it's just it's it's up
to confessional and I'd see Frontera
class but things nobody's nobody's
getting any value or that you're getting
on you get a gold star with a little
star me to fuck off I said I wasn't
gonna swear anyone else
thanks for come along as my first
talking three years our security
competence I'll speak speaking at
b-sides Glasgow where the Internet of
death so they don't fancy seeing that
come off the Glasgow it's not far the
train is live for us from here and I'll
be a great conference being run by
that's fun
so yeah
[Applause]