if you like you can all move to the
front as well just like in church you
know come on down
Oh looks like we've got who we're going
to have I'm Sam Denard one of the
volunteers it helps make in a is G and
Hugh set can go and just by way of
advertisement you can also share in that
joy we can use the help ok but at the
moment I'd like to introduce our next
speaker Jason breathnach he is an expert
in snort he is a source fire security
fellow he is a part of the Sourcefire
vulnerability research team and he used
to work for what is now two of the big 8
now that they've merged that exactly
okay he's well qualified to give us his
presentation today please welcome Jason
can you hear me the mic okay I have to
use the mic so snort how many people
here know it's nor it is and you used it
show hands actively use it all right so
we're here to talk about dynamic
security evolving world's kind of the
difference between how it used to be
done and how it's done today so you know
snort from days of old 1998 couple
signatures and that was life life was
good right he had little small networks
and we're about 30 attacks total you had
to worry about yeah maybe 10 years ago
was that today it's a far different
landscape how many vulnerabilities that
Microsoft patch in the last Tuesday
anyone wanted
30 ish and that's just one company Adobe
Oracle Mozilla everybody else says you
know 30 30 a month is about a norm for
any given product these days here's the
problem your network moves so fast and
the threats of all so quickly that you
can't use the old school fire-and-forget
ids IPS so a dynamic world that's what
we're living in if you were to look at
your network take a snapshot how many
people here scan their networks with a
Volm scanner or a you know and map or
something like that now if I can ask you
when you scan your network you do it
daily weekly monthly weekly how
different is it every week about the
same number of computers same number of
services same number of alms or does it
change constantly and then what do you
do so you found a new machine it's
windows XP hasn't been patched to you
call the helpdesk right and say hey you
got to fix this machine and then they
work on finding it and next week it's
probably still there and it probably
stays for two or three scan cycles and
then it disappears do you do anything
with your protection infrastructure in
that three-week window before they find
the Machine and and remediate it no you
can't here's the problem your network
changes too fast and exists in too many
places for you to actually physically
manually make adjustments and so that's
led us to these systems where first you
know just trust me I'll tell you what
you need to run all right set your
policies and leave them be we don't
believe that's appropriate we don't
believe it's effective either so that
you know machine that XP machine has
been in the network for three weeks
turns out it was a virtual machine on
some developers desktop and they were
testing something and you know they just
they were done and so they turned it off
and that's how finally disappeared right
cloud virtual endpoint challenges are so
dynamic that we can't as practitioners
hope to keep up with the change in our
networks you have a 2,000 person network
there's no way you couldn't staff 20
people to keep up with everything that
changes in their everyday right so you
need dynamic security we look at the
impact of kind of a static security
posture and a system that doesn't allow
you to adapt with the network you know
you might come up with some of these
words take a new person plug them into
your network and ask them to secure it
this is their first three months trying
to figure out what's happening wondering
why it's even happening if I could ask
another question how many people work at
companies that had networks established
for greater than 10 years and on those
networks how many people have been able
to totally refresh them come out with
brand new builds of things secure right
secure builds of operating systems and
software packages and everything else
you can't the company's just don't work
that way but bewilderment for the new
people that show up they why isn't this
set up so we face these powerful threats
hackers they're scary people aren't they
they're just like you and me by the way
right there just like you and me they
just have different motivations the
problem is they have lots of things that
they can work from and they come in many
forms let's look at hackers script
kiddies advanced persistent threats how
many people love apt in a great term apt
do you think it's a real problem for
commercial entities yes no do you lose
sleep over it there's a hacker in my
network how many people think their
networks are currently compromised how
many people think their networks will
always be compromised yeah what's our
job in doing security and a network that
we accept is constantly compromised hmm
well
it'sit's to minimize the amount of risk
and what they're able to get away with
right you're never going to get them out
of your network why because they're
focused organized innovative they're not
encumbered by process and change control
they're not encumbered by up time
they're not uncover encumbered by PL
they need something they do something
they want to change the way they
approach a target they change the way
they approach to target they don't have
to go change Control Board to release a
new attack drop new code on you they're
also relentless they get bonuses just
like we do right you achieve your goal
you need to compromise our essay i'll
give you an extra fifty thousand dollars
this quarter go do it take it 50k with
and compromise our essay right it's
pretty motivating form i don't know if
that's a real number or not but it's
still pretty motivating when you think
about it they have a salary and so we
deploy these technologies AV and IPS and
firewall and proxies and all this other
stuff and what happens i love the quote
right the better we get more deviant and
creative thicket and this is essentially
what we're dealing with we're trying to
protect our networks with walls it
doesn't really work but this is in
essence modern-day defense for networks
we build it we put it in believe it be
doesn't work well and it's driven by
black box solutions systems you set them
up you plug them in you click a couple
default settings you say go and then you
wait for events and you call the help
desk and they fix things and you know
you might have an incident or two you
deal with you have to deploy patches and
everything else right but that's a
losing game the system itself needs to
know what to protect and the threats you
face in order to have a hope of winning
can anybody tell me in the last
Microsoft Tuesday how quickly that got
deployed the network the patches on
average a week a day sorry seven days
how long does it take an attacker to
turn that patch into exploitable
conditions for hours yes binary code for
hours what what just happened did we win
oh no we absolutely lost this game so it
takes us seven days to get the patch
deployed and we had to test it make sure
it didn't break anything even though it
still breaks things when you deploy it
and it took the attacker four hours to
turn it into usable exploitation so
let's just say six days of delta what
are you doing those six days JV help you
Fire will help you do you increase
monitoring but what do you do okay well
in our ideal world we've got coverage in
well the moment the patch is released in
products whether it be a firewall or the
next-gen firewall says they call them or
the IPS but here's the next problem if a
vulnerability effects windows XP and
Windows 2000 but not you know windows 7
what do you do you turn it on for
everything how many people have
experienced a false positive come on I
know I have how many experienced the
false positives took out a business
critical application I have all right so
having the system know where the
vulnerabilities are and automatically
enable protections are what we believe
the ideal situation is it can recommend
to you what should be done it could act
upon it on its own and do it most people
aren't quite comfortable with that yet
it takes them a couple months before
they accept that right
and in the absence of that we have to
assume our people are what well we
already disprove this there's no way
that you even having the tools can be as
vigilant responsive as your adversaries
seven days to get a patch on your
network four hours for him to turn it
into something useful for him right it
leads us to the fundamental question
right is it a fair fight it's building
walls good in an age where we have Jets
the attackers are flying jets right over
our walls shooting into our castle
courtyards all right it since no longer
land-based attack they're no longer
coming in the door and taking pieces of
paper off the printer although i think
printers are the greatest things to
compromise in the network by the way
what's the last time you patched a
printer anybody know what is a printer
typically run what's its operating
system usually some form of linux does
it have a web browser or a web server
i'm sorry ftp telnet big hard drive and
where do all the important documents in
a company end up going to the fancy
printer all right every contract goes
through that fancy printer to when they
put it down they scan it so they can
electronically file it and we never
patch them in your security technologies
whether it be knack or a fee or IPS or
firewall is there some selection for HP
printers I want to protect my printers
no would you put in IPS in front of your
printer and just turn on all the rules
anybody know
a smart enough system modern defenses
that you could bring to the table we
refer to them as next-generation IPS
would know that printer is running
Apache and what version of apache it is
it would know that it's linux based it
would know that it offers ftp it would
know that it offers telnet it would know
what the associated vulnerabilities for
those versions are in that operating
system and would turn on just protection
for those things and it would do that it
would minimize your business risk of
having an IPS in the network where
things get printed what happens when a
printer breaks in a network by the way
anybody here work I helped us it has to
deal with that any time in their life
when the printer isn't working you get
lots of calls and the problem to the
business is they feel like business
can't be done because they can't print
stuff it's you know high priority
everybody knows your problems the
highest priority there is so if you put
a system in place that isn't aware of
this and it starts doing things like
blocking windows-based attacks for a
linux-based target that is your printer
then you run into that mix of
false-positive right because it's not
really a false positive it couldn't be
any vulnerability exploited it's a Linux
machine so a system that knows it it
knows the users in those two behaviors
and those the operating systems allows
you to overlay a policy on that so they
can adapt on its own would be ideal a
sequel slammer everybody remember sequel
slammer anybody how about what's Code
Red I bet today you still have Code Red
offense on your border anybody have an
IDs out there that kind of alerts you to
it how many do you get it day a lot this
is a decade old threat only affects
windows only affects mt and I is was it
50 I think 40 50 still out there that
tells us how vigilant responses people
are by the way 10 year old vulnerability
existing and still haunting the internet
if you were to deploy a machine that
were vulnerable today you would be
compromised within minutes problem is
they're all valid events they're all
valid attacks they really did happen
they just weren't successful right so in
your classic incident response cycle
you've got a hundred thousand of these
things a day that you would have to go
investigate if you were really looking
at all of the real attacks that happen
on the network if you didn't have the
context of a windows machine or the XP
or and t4 running iis as the target or
it was a Linux target or an Apache
target you would in essence be forced to
do what we do today which is ignore
those events because well I don't know
if anything was wrong about nothing else
changed right until the developer starts
that vm to try something on so we think
next-gen IPS by the way how many people
have heard of RNA real-time network
awareness it kind of dries our IPS Tech
in that it observes the network it
notices all these things services users
ports protocols applications operating
systems and creates these vulnerability
maps right and empowers the system to
make these changes but that's not good
enough yeah you have to be able to do it
fast all right you have to these are NSS
data points i believe from the last
group test if the system ends up slowing
the network what happens to it it's
turned off just like a fee on the
desktop right if you can't catch a job
done you end up turning it off and then
everybody loses you got to have strong
performance while you do it and it needs
to be accurate it needs to cut out your
hundred thousand events needs to make
them the one event that matters the two
events that matter right that's what we
believe is appropriate it needs to have
the best detection possible now we think
we have that it's been verified through
consistent testing with independent labs
however that's not enough just knowing
about the attacks and stopping the
attacks not enough especially in today's
world I think the last presenter talked
about
Facebook and the threats it represents
how many people have a corporate policy
against social networking for the
average employee 1234 yeah are you able
to enforce it yeah kind of maybe you can
enforce it you get fired well that's one
way to enforce it do you even know if
they're doing it yeah what about
web-based email no no policy guess what
based email I love this by the way can't
send an attachment because my email
system says it's too big can't send an
attachment because my email system says
it's in a disallowed file type what
employees do what they do they log into
their yahoo mail or their Gmail and they
send it that way or the contract and and
your system rejects it how many people
have witnessed this in the security
space witnessed this happen persons
trying to do business with another
organization a few contracts back and
forth the other organization maybe they
were compromised maybe they the word
document does have a virus in it right
and your gateway blocks it that virus we
got protections can't help you deadlines
quarters coming to an end got to get
this contract signs for the business can
move forward what does your employee do
I don't care send it's my personal email
send it over to gmail I'll download it
from there all right and they execute
the contract and they get infected just
like everything else you need to be able
to cover the application specifically
that you think are appropriate for your
business and while it's a policy
enforcement point it reduces your threat
posture so instead of saying Facebook's
not allowed but I really can't do
anything about it gmail is not allowed
but I can't do anything about it we only
run windows on our network we only run
Linux we only run mac whatever our data
center doesn't run anything older than
you know windows 2000 and having no way
to enforce that or even be aware that
it's different the system should let you
know it should also bring us to the next
point which is next-gen firewall allow
you to in
forsett it should allow you to know that
a person in accounting will be working
with the outsourced oracle instances and
person sales only be working with
salesforce or whatever your CRM is right
we should allow you to know that
Facebook is allowed for the marketing
department because they have to do their
social media campaigns but it's not
allowed for your sales team and it
should allow you to make those decisions
so I'm not so sure oh did display fine
okay all right we're coming to market
with it I think it releases in a month
next-gen firewall now it's based on IPS
technologies right the best IPS
available in the market is kind of the
core threat prevention engine
firewalling itself like another slide
that illustrates as well we believe that
the to work very well together now we
don't believe that one will replace the
other how many people here if the
perfect firewall existed today that
could do IPS application control
standard firewalling at the border in
VPN and all those things would replace
their existing firewalls for it oh and
we're free I gave it to you would you
replace all your firewalls know so you
need a transition path so right now
people start think but you guys are the
snort people you two IPS firewalls I
think this is a great graphic for
representing it next to in firewall
defined as classic firewall stateful
firewall I guess is the way to refer to
it no do you guys think stateful
firewalls work anybody our firewalls a
security device yeah I don't think they
are I really don't especially in today's
world firewalls are more of a access
control device not so much security
they're more of a you must be this tall
to ride this ride bar HTTP is the new
tcp if you
missed the memo right everything runs
over port 80 and 443 today VPN security
device NAT security device access
control operational what are they right
they're filtering devices for very basic
stuff app control IPS however are
different and this graphic attempts to
illustrate the level of difficulty in
doing stateful firewall pretty easy
green app control you could probably do
app control if you wanted to think about
the level of effort data inspected in as
the first hundred and twenty eight bytes
of every packet would probably tell you
all you needed to do for application
control IPS not so much you have to
inspect every bite of every packet of
every day right there there's no
singular good packet you don't have to
look at we'd like to think there is but
there isn't and so in level of
difficulty we've got already the vast
majority of a handle we need to add some
staple firewalling features an overlay a
policy that makes sense to firewall
groups operational groups that maintain
policy enforcement not security groups
that do incident response and threat
mitigation and then we have another
piece that fits into our overall
strategy which is immunity has anyone
heard of any net how about clam AV
anybody yeah one to claim of ease our
open source AV product two runs on the
vast majority of male gateways out there
Emmy net is an endpoint protection
product we call it malware control I
guess their mission reinvent endpoint
defense how many people run AV in our
company I do how many people think it's
effective
AV deployment stopped something say why
daily how many times do you still have
to respond to new viruses daily some
stats I'll share with you 48 to 50
percent effectiveness for any given AV
and if you think about the process you
can understand why let's say you are
patient zero for some new threat
suddenly worm what do you do you upload
it to your AV vendor yeah virustotal
maybe all comes back negative negative
negative negative maybe somebody comes
back with heuristic detect on it then
what happens maybe vendor sits on it
they wait for other people to come up
with it but another stat for you
seventy-eight percent of malware that is
observed today is unique to its target
so they never see additional infections
you're only ever going to see it once in
one place at one time so the traditional
method of bubbling up the quote
high-risk threats doesn't work why is it
different how can it be done differently
that's what I mean I wanted to look at
we picked them up in January because I
think well clearly we thought they were
doing it right cloud-based real-time
updates 300ma 100 Meg gigabit how big
are your virus definitions on average
okay I'd say an average is 100 mega
updated day for AV if you're staying on
top of it it's a lot of data to push
around on your network and if we take
patch management as an example there's
going to be a 30-percent failure rate
and deploying them and this is an update
that happened after things got bubbled
up remember seventy-eight percent of it
never going to be seen in your network
there's a way we think to do this
without having to push out updates to be
real time what we call collective
immunity we should exist with existing
AV because really nobody wants to pull
out their 80 anymore and they want to
pull out a firewall we should make it
customizable personalized protections
kind of core to our being and we should
make it so that communities of people
share protections if you will so think
about think about how the apt threat I
hate to use apt but think about how that
thread propagates through network if if
you're an attacker and you have to
compromise the network and all your
tricks have failed and you need to bring
out a new owed a never-before-seen
never-before-released but you need to do
it to win you want to get into our essay
and win you're going to burn it if
you're going to burn it in our say or
you're going to burn it elsewhere
probably all right if I burn it once I
lines will get my value out of it and if
you have a campaign against I don't know
government contractors you think maybe
you'll burn the same o day at all of
them at the same time right if I got a
compromise Lockheed and Grumman and all
these guys almost I'm gonna use the same
one over and over until it's it's
patched because I've really only have 14
days from the time I start to the time
it gets discovered communities of like
organizations tend to see similar
infection vectors is kind of the
fundamentals so I think this is an
animated graphic of how ultimately how
it's different you're classy Gabey agent
right 32 32 350 makes in size with a gig
of definitions on your desktop new file
gets scanned right perhaps we'll do it
DNS requests to the internet right and
it's a one-to-one match a one-to-one
match meaning i took a sha or an md5 I
did dns query I got an answer back or I
like maybe not found means it's good and
well I found it so it's not good right
classic AV model not going to work so
well when we overlay the way we do it
it's a little bit different I'll have to
explain this to you one to one we have
Shaw matching prevalence so if we know
seventy eight percent of all malware is
unique then if we only ever see one
binary one nobody else has it it's a
good or bad I just flip a coin what are
my chances of being correct alright if I
just say all new things are bad I have a
seventy percent chance of being right
that's thirty percent better than my
existing technologies all I did was say
it's bad if I see it in three hundred
places three thousand three million then
I know it's probably good I didn't do
anything other than look at how many
people have this binary right temporal
how fast is it moving generics cuz i
recall i think is another key element
though but before i get the cloud recall
let's talk about how a typical response
would work you are on your computer you
go to a web page dropper happens things
happen my agent sees it it sees do stuff
get installed but nothing changes so we
say okay allow it to run we're going to
let it be you're going to be patient
zero and we're just going to observe and
then all of a sudden your machines start
sending emails to all your friends all
your friends start having the same
binary downloaded well we know that it's
moving fast and that it's doing things
automatically downloading for you we can
now take cloud recall and say even
though I allowed it to run on your
machine and these 50 other people had no
knowledge
of you know badness I'm now determining
it's bad I'm reversing my decision is
saying no good remove it right so things
like dancing baby everybody remember the
dancing baby video I think was awesome
wasn't it how fast did that move among
your family and friends and everything
else I got I think it was an hour before
the whole company was looking at the
same video back in the day if that were
a virus today a worm a drop or a Trojan
whatever you would have an entire
company in probably an hour and a half
classic a ve wouldn't know about it
because nobody uploaded it yet now you
got a week before you get a real
definition that says it's bad and the
attacker has been on your network for a
week cloud recall allows us to see that
change in the behavior and immediately
determine that we're going to block it
and uninstall it so instead of a week
from the time somebody uploads it to you
get your definitions and it gets removed
we can in minutes right we see that this
instance here turned into a hundred
thousand instances we decide it's bad
everybody's throwing the agent can now
be informed that this is no longer good
we uninstall it for you kind of kind of
neat I think comparisons I think this is
the obligatory chart of feature function
right one day to a month for sample
collection a data two weeks has anybody
ever uploaded a sample to a Navy vendor
and gotten a response of the day I
haven't but I don't have those big fancy
contracts with them either it's possible
an hour to a day to publish once it's
out and up to 350 makes and footprint we
like to keep things real light real
simple 200 millisecond response time by
the way from the cloud so that the
common question is will if all your
queries are go into the cloud and you do
this recall stuff and everything else
isn't going to slow down my machine and
my response to that is the machines
already slow for maybe scanning a
gigabit definition for every execution
document opened is slow I give you a
response to 200 milliseconds
and it is relevant relevant to the
entire user base whether it be your
organization or the world as a whole and
make decisions pretty quickly we're
bringing it to the enterprise web based
management group policies all that stuff
right but if you break down all of this
what we believe is that this is the
right solution that the cloud if you
will the network will bring a collective
immunity to people that you can
ultimately share relevant information so
that everybody becomes protected at once
instead of everybody having to take
action to get protection does that make
sense I shouldn't have to give you that
updates I shouldn't have to give you
signature updates the system should be
able to subscribe to these things and
know that they're happening and based on
some real simple observations we should
be able to make appropriate decisions
for your network that's what we call
next generation we refer to it as you
know cloud two core protection I really
its cloud to endpoint protection but
right so are there any questions about
what I said is everybody falling asleep
yet lost or Hungary yes
starting at one
great we're able to track update agents
and see the binaries are drops through
updaters you know like boom SMS we're
able to allow organizations to create
custom so you might find your binary you
might say this is whitelisted there's a
number of actions you can take on that
through the console to handle it we
would see that it's localized to you
that it was built by one of our people
through a compiler and all kinds of
different stuff right when you get to
the edge cases like that there's
certainly situations right that you
might want to see however how many
people run custom applications right and
how many people install them in random
locations not many you know what your
application is you know that it should
be whitelisted you know there should be
allowed to run you put your whitelist up
you go deploy and it's only local to you
if that application shows up somewhere
else they don't get the white listing
for it makes sense other questions
anybody nobody yes
sure so the decisions are cached there
is a climb AV engine in the background
if you want to have classic AV
definitions that you can use you can
download those I'm simply going to say
though that I don't believe that there's
any system that's truly offline and what
I mean by that is it wouldn't be a
threat if we're offline you could block
it out on otherwise right if you have to
deploy local highly constrained black
lists and white list right that's where
the customization comes in a SCADA
systems fairly static it all should be
fairly static right it should have very
well-known environmental that you can
whitelist and then creeped out right
policy nothing new is allowed until I
change it and allow those decisions to
be cached the problem is let's say I
don't know the the more common question
around that is you know laptops they're
at work they're plugged in we're doing
our work and then we leave and we're on
the road we're doing presentations like
this right here somebody hands you a USB
stick and you check it out you plug in
your machine became infected and you
weren't connected to a network so you
were unable to check for new definitions
right well it can't connect to anything
and steal data from you at the moment
when you do connect to the network
you'll immediately be query on it right
so you have a couple seconds while
you're on the network that it could do
something before the cloud becomes aware
of it and can make a decision on so you
know there's definitely edge cases where
it's not the perfect solution but I'll
argue there is no perfect solution
especially in the static war that we
deal with today makes sense any other
questions
alright well thanks for listening we're
letting me listen by letting me ramble