okay let me introduce myself my name is
William charnock I'm the director of
data network engineering for allegiance
telecom presenting with me is Dave
Israel he's the senior manager backbone
engineering for our company and we're
presenting about a network consolidation
project we went through in the past year
basically working what we're going to
talk about is the history behind the EAS
merger what some of our business drivers
were for doing this the approach we took
why we chose to do what we did dave is
going to discuss the preparation in the
actual cut and then we'll tie it all up
with some lessons learned allegiance
telecom acquired the IBI network assets
in december of 2001 from worldcom as
part of the SEC mandate when worldcom
bought intermedia they were required to
sell the old digits ibi backbone
allegiance telecom was will refer to it
as a tier 2 network we had a nationwide
network with some peering but we were
still purchasing transit whereas I bi
was a nationwide tier 1 backbone they
did not purchase transit so why would we
do what we did basically we wanted to
gain some efficiencies in network
expense by consolidation of our
facilities consolidate our operations
and support have uniform routing
policies across all the networks and
have the ability to sell either legacies
Network either networks products at any
site we had a pretty diverse set of
products between the between the two
companies the approach we took because
we were migrating we made a decision to
go to the 2548 AAS because we felt that
it had some value we had to tailor the
migration to fit within the limitations
of our of the legacy allegiance network
and by that I mean that the IBI network
was well aggregated being that it was a
little older than our network and it
would have been easier to migrate their
network popped by pop whereas we were
not so well aggregated because having
started in the last five years or so we
weren't able to get large allocations
and so we had our net blocks scattered
all over the place it posed some issues
as far as consolidation
what we had traditionally seen in some
network consolidation was the
integration consisted of moving the
smaller a s behind the larger ass
basically making the smaller a as a
transit customer of the larger ass we
view that as a less risky proposition if
it didn't it didn't pose any real
significant customer downtime but by
merging the two networks we could
accomplish all of our goals and do it in
a relatively short period of time who's
obviously more risky and required a
significant amount of downtime but if it
suited our knees so some considerations
if you ever consider doing something
like this the network's sighs we had
approximately 500 routers pre-merger the
protocols that you use on your network
have to scale
and we'll get into that a little bit but
we encountered some scalability issues
along the way in a multi-vendor
environment you're going to encounter
some interesting things especially if
you're using mpls we unconfortable ab we
uncovered it once we had done the
conversion but we we found some
interoperability issues that were nasty
and the routing policy can be a little
tricky to adapt from one platform to
another especially if you're still on a
learning curve with the with a new
router and you have to ask yourself if
network consolidation makes sense given
your specific situation it may not we we
were in a unique situation in that we
had a brand-new nationwide network that
we had just built for allegiance prior
to the IBI acquisition and we felt that
that gave us a little bit of an
advantage in the consolidation phase
so I'm gonna let Dave take over at this
point
so the first thing we had to look at it
was how we were going to do it we had to
come up with an overall strategy
obviously what was important was to make
sure that technical people understood
what the business people wanted at in
the end otherwise you end up with an
integrated network that wasn't what
people wanted the first place eight
hours of downtime that didn't accomplish
anything the second thing was is that
that animal milestones and goals we we
truly tried to push it too fast at first
and fortunately we realized we're
pushing it too fast before it got too
out of hand yet scientists say we can do
this in a month I swear to God I won't
sleep how come in weekends I'll eat
while I'm typing but it's much better to
actually keep your sanity then we had to
put together the team a team building
was interesting allegiances stations in
or home office in Dallas and we're all
up in Greenville that's a good several
thousand mile distance there and keeping
everybody on the same page was and
making sure everybody give you about was
involved was interesting process but we
got through it through
and we put together our plan the new
basically besides that neither of the
old policy is going to work for us so we
have put together a new policy between
you to prove the new policy worked lab
time lots and lots and lots of lifetime
lap time isn't always what you need I
mean you have to see what does in the
real world the lab can find a lot of
your mistakes early we'll talk a bit
more about that later ki dependencies
identify risks couple buzzwords tice
personnel based on core competencies
yeah that's actually a little bit harder
than it sounds because sometimes you
think somebody's best in one place and
you find out that's not where they
belong click laying out the code of a
process everybody here is you know
things I know what I'm doing yeah we
thought we know we're doing having
keystroke documentation even if you know
exactly what you're doing is a wonderful
thing because when you're running a low
on time you start to panic you start
cutting corners things start going wrong
keystroke documentation you exactly if
you're supposed to do you don't have to
think and McDonald's will tell you the
less your employees things the better
they do
um
small company owner of the station it is
set hard backup point that was a big
thing we had to say if it's not working
if this isn't working by this point
we're never going to get this done
instead of rushing forward and blowing
everything up just put everything back
the way it was sigh have some coffee and
try again next week and practice
practice practice practice it doesn't
matter if you're not actually doing any
real work just going through the motions
over and over again we'll get you the
feeling of okay this is exactly my do
that night and hey would be really nice
here is we had somebody doing this you
catch again you catch a lot of mistakes
by practicing a first time you tried it
we try to do it one night big mistake it
was there was way too much because if
500 routers have to be touched one of
them goes wrong and you know you spend
ten minutes on fixing it and now you're
really behind so we back that out and
went back and tried it in two nights
first we do the legacy ivi network which
had more routers but was closer to the
policy that we were going to so it was
less work and then the second piece we
would reconfigure the allegiance one
there's really three networks involved
but the third network didn't carry
traffic it was a backbone be wrong
everything on two and
so that was actually a boon if you can
do that if you have ref to merge is is
you can have a third network that's not
doing anything that's wonderful because
you can play on it of course not
everybody can afford to build another
cozy 48 number so the week before we did
allegiance we did I VI we shut down all
of our external peers so you know we
wouldn't get death threats and car bombs
basically do not pay attention was
happening behind the curtain we'll come
out when we're done that again was a
really good idea I strongly recommend
not letting anybody see what's happening
the energy or network sure customers
have salt late down time instead of
spotty downtime but custom have more
downtime is Wrigley decides not going to
listen to your routes anymore we found a
couple small policy bugs things that
didn't behave exactly we expected
nothing that caused huge trauma but good
things to fix before we integrated the
rest of the network noon day before we
told everybody no more configuration
changes if you ever have to do this do
that last thing you need is to find out
that somebody could figure something 20
minutes ago that you have no idea how
you're going to handle during the merger
you configuration to generate a sandy
checked put together a perl script
actually that downloaded the config
figured out what it should look like
after it was done and sped it back out
shared that with people people point out
things that were vastly wrong with it
things that had missed things that I've
gotten right we did again perl script
was poorly written and still do router
every two seconds if you have somebody
can script like this and you need to
make a lot of configuration changes
again i strongly recommend it it's also
less prone to typos and human beings or
if the negatives come at the same type
of yeah and we backed up the router
configurations because really the easy
way to back out from a massive change is
about the whole configuration back and
reboot which is actually how we put the
configurations in the first place just
to make sure we had a clean committal we
then may I can mention before shut off
the ball appears on both sides for the
for the complete merger and loaded all
the configurations out in a single
market rebooted that market made sure it
worked it's not the slide that it didn't
so we had to go back and say what did we
do wrong and do it again because we had
this group that could Gentry janitors
configs in a couple minutes it took that
in three tries to get involved working
but then we put the variations on all
the routers
yeah after those are I was working the
patient's out on the rest of the routers
and you know took the big switch Network
off network on market by market the five
minutes it takes for the worst case
router to reload and everything's
working a couple cases it wasn't working
but again for the most part it worked
very cleanly surprisingly well expected
to lose a large number of routers to
various stupidity and it didn't happen
there was a couple of routers that were
running the wrong rep of code they did
some unexpected things but for the most
part everything just worked a couple
customers are issues getting the
different routers we've heard policies
talking to each other it is bad when one
thing uses this community to say don't
export that the other one uses a
different community or the actual no
bucksport tag they will leak routes
that's not surprising in different
version of the software can do
completely different same thing
completely different ways or completely
different not completely different but
slightly different things with the same
command and you don't expect it so again
how much entity is really
leave the key here a different software
version something you didn't expect in
the lab so you try it there can really
ruin your whole night scalability
not many people have 500 router test
labs a couple people do and if you do
i'd like to go work for you but with 500
routers you will find that you are
testing the limits of routing protocols
and transports other people haven't
tested just pure number of nodes can
knock over or really stress test a
number of protocols and you relate to
make sure a your policy scaled in the
first list and be your code is is solid
yeah I'm not going to mention vendor
names but I guess you can guess
sometimes they don't do things the same
way they read the same RFC they don't
look each other but on the other one
doesn't exist they put together exactly
the same words completely differently
and assume that's the other ones fault
what doesn't work when they talk to each
other when you actually sit them down
and say hey this is broken they worked
with us and we'll attention that later
they were really good at bringing our
stuff up but
yeah it was a surprise how many things
didn't work exactly same last thing I
want to mention real quick is I think my
lesson is a policy gap I don't know if
anybody was peering with this one we did
the merger I'm sure there's some people
here who were solace announced the
entire Internet the summit success it
wasn't actually a policy gap that's kind
of misleading as much as a customer gap
we had a customer that lost their policy
when we redid the network and got stuck
on the default policy which was hey this
is a peer announcer stuff so they were
appearing with another writer there a
multi-homed did announce the entire
Internet to us because they were poorly
configured and poorly configured plus
poorly configured equals really really
bad so we had to turn that off and deal
with a customer
I'll give it back to will for some
clothes yeah we learned a lot during
this obviously nobody's perfect we
didn't go into this thinking we were but
you know typos happen you move on with
your life we expected some equipment to
fail and sure enough it did every time
you reload a router I think you're
taking a big risk we also learned that
you can't plan enough we spent several
months planning this cut and for all the
testing we did we still uncover things
that we didn't account for and Dave
specifically wanted to mention from a
scalability point that some of these
problems obviously don't manifest in a
lab where you have you know half a dozen
or a dozen routers however on a large
network they will manifest and
unfortunately they manifest in bad ways
some of the company type lessons learned
communication is extremely key during a
process like this we probably didn't do
a good enough job of notifying our peers
and customers exactly what kind of work
we were doing
but I think it's key going forward that
if you ever attempt something like this
that you make sure you notify your
customers give them a really good idea
of what you're attempting to do and as
well as your peers and peers are a
valuable resource and a valuable asset
and valuable partners I feel like we
probably should have given a little
better notice to our peers there and
also set and manage realistic
expectations both to your customers and
your executive management and we also
learned that an out-of-band management
network is a priceless asset hopefully
we all learned a lot of especially about
that also we also some of the things
that you should think about if you're
ever planning something like this is you
know don't be afraid to speak up we had
a lot of meetings and a lot of meetings
leading up to this and if somebody comes
up with an obscure way that this could
break don't don't knock it down and as
you know that's too obscure I'll never
you keep it clean we just discovered a
lot of things along the way it was it
was a hellish two weeks I'll just put it
that way what we started with these were
the networks that we had going into this
we had the allegiance network the old
ibi network and are what we call our
next two networks which was this virgin
network that we had and this is the
finished product or an approximation of
it this is approximately what our
network looks like today we officially
I'd say we're about what 95% we've
accomplished about ninety-five percent
of our consolidation at this point
there's still some optimization
occurring some links going up and down
being disconnected and links coming up
but this is what we're done
and I have a little personal slide at
the end I'm a long-suffering tampa bay
buccaneers fan oh I'm sorry I'll get to
that first and I just want to say go
bucks i also want to send some thanks
out to the teams that worked on this
with us this was not a two-person effort
a lot of people worked on this I want to
thank the greenbelt team primarily the
xib I did X people the Dallas team and I
don't usually thank vendors but the
cisco and juniper tax were very helpful
during this actually they were available
during the call they were on the call
while we were doing the work and they
helped us resolve some of the critical
issues in a relatively short time yes
any questions
I've always been taught that for a large
operation you just never ever ever do a
cut over find some way to do incremental
change and and one could argue that's
what you came to although going from one
switch 22 doesn't seem like much of a
step so my question is whether you think
now that you've gone through this there
would have been a way to engineer this
more incrementally and therefore less
dramatically I think that if we'd had
more time and yeah we probably could
have come up with some ways to be a
little more clever about it something we
didn't mention was that we were under a
timeline of about a year to have this
consolidation done so it required us to
take steps that were maybe more drastic
than we would have liked to have taken
but in the end we accomplish the goal
you know with some with some heartache
and headaches so yeah I would say
there's probably some ways we could have
thought of to do this maybe using
Confederations or something like that
again it the way that we chose suited
our needs and you know we just yeah go
just add something real quick here from
a customer service point of view I would
have loved to do an incremental change
as an engineer the first thing I thought
was my god if we do an integrand
incremental change will get halfway done
and gets stuck we'll have a policy that
nobody wants it doesn't do anything and
we're not allowed to change for whatever
reason so I was very split on that
but the timeline let the engineer win
which I usually prefer I was wondering
if you could speak to the tools
environment a little more you mentioned
having a perl script to munch
configurations in the larger picture
were you changing dns at the same time
did you have like a rent a big rancid
router DB that you needed to change at
the same time what was going on you know
one step away from the routers sure i'll
take part of that and all i handsome off
today we did a lot of post-merger can
clean up and we're still doing some of
that here and they're weary numbered our
entire backbone or some of the links
that we kept from the allegiance network
we're on different space than what we
decided we wanted all of our backbone
links number loopback addresses were
changed things like that Dave you want
to talk about the tools that were used
well yeah the perl script because they
get completely hungreh we changing dns
was more than on aux said experiment
more than anything else monitoring one
reasons why we remembered is some of our
modern tools discover based on network
and so and based on DNS but also by
network and so by putting everything on
the same network everything
automatically discovered we did have a
huge rancid database of configurations
that was where I pulled the
configurations well half rancid half
homegrown tool because there was two
different networks before we got started
but I had pulled from those one was
Pauling liver routers four times a day
the other one was blowing it more often
that's par the reason for the huge
config freeze time period those make
sure the monitoring tools that play him
time to get the exact current config
make sure we weren't modifying a
customer out of existence
I guess
some more questions
yeah I think that's all I had one
question but that was the one that
Steven just as well okay so thanks again
very much guys for that talk