oh I've worked on a couple of
conferences in the immediate past and
one of the interesting things that
happens is not a lot of people are
familiar with building wireless networks
that support extremely large numbers of
users and very small spaces the subject
of high-density wireless networks seems
to be a lot more relevant and
interesting these days given the amount
of interest in capital that seems to be
going into building wireless ISPs and
hot squat deployments and you know if
this technology becomes truly vik
witness the way cell phones are then you
all sudden have a problem supporting
several hundred to several thousand
radios in an extremely small space
interestingly enough I ATF and nanog are
actually extremely good test beds for
doing that it's not that often that you
can go someplace and fly in 500 to 2,000
active wireless users in one room how do
you keep them happy when you have them
institutional knowledge on the subject
of building networks that actually
support this is extremely limited when
we started talking to vendors about
products that might be able to do this
you get two sorts of responses on some
vendors don't even know how to test
their equipment in an environment like
this and some of them say things like
well cool tell us how it goes when
you're done and that's not really a
whole lot of support especially when
you're talking about buying a
hundred-thousand-dollar sorts of
equipment or something like that
one of the things that we can observe
from having worked on previous events
before the two that we started planning
for last fall was various enterprise
access point products get into serious
trouble and they have more than two
hundred users and that's a combination
of properties one of them is the cart is
some of the cards that meanders
manufacture only support 255 max on one
side so clearly if you get to that
number the whole access point blows up
some of them simply the performance
begins to degrade around seventy to a
hundred users and by the time you get to
200 the access point is just in the
state that it's not going to work radio
interference which is caused by other
radios transmitting on the same
frequency either X points our clients
causes drops Ethernet frames and because
the access points are designed to
ameliorate that by caching the ethernet
frames and resending them results in
queuing on access points since they only
have 16 megs of ram you can only queue
for so long the most obvious impact of
this is you start seeing greater than
one second ping times or round trip
times for your package to places that
are immediately on the other side of the
wireless network when you get into when
one access point gets into trouble other
access points tend to get into trouble
because the clients that are on that
access point roam over to another one
either because it's finally given up and
crashed or because the users move so
that they can get better connectivity
the largest source of radio interference
in any deployment seems to be the access
points themselves and not the users when
you have them close together because the
users are actually sucking down more
traffic than they're sourcing unless
they're running file sharing
applications or something from from
their wireless network if they're mostly
brett web browsing or pulling down their
email we're watching streaming media
it's the access points that spend most
the time transmitting on and so it's the
access points opinions end up stomping
on each other site surveys and testing
can't entirely eliminate any problems
that you have you don't know things like
where all the users are going to sit
when the meetings are out you don't know
what or what the performance
characteristics of a room are going to
be when it has an extra 200 tons of meat
and water in it versus not having that
what do people want when they sit down
and use a wireless network well I mean
the basic thing is they want to get
their work done but they want to be able
to roam again between access points
because when you move around you don't
want your connections to drop you don't
want to get a new IP address you
basically want to be on the same subnet
there are vendors who are moving into
this space who do things like tunnel
between access points on different
networks some of them do extremely
strange things a lot of them look like
gnats I think probably the ultimate
solution to the roaming problem is
probably the ultimate solution to all
roaming problems which is some kind of
IP mobility stack we're probably still a
long way from there they want low
latency and loss but just to say that
when they do something they wanted to
work just like an Ethernet network or
any network with desirable
characteristics they want it to work
just like it does at home because most
people who go out and buy wireless
equipment and deploy it at their house
just plug it in and it works and they
have a reasonable expectation that they
should be able to do the same thing here
so a couple of Givens about that you can
just assume when you're building one of
these networks in the US you have 11
available channels three of them are not
overlapping on the total amount of
spectrum you have 83 megahertz
and each each of these candles is 20 20
megahertz wide so you know that's how
many you can stuff in there wireless
cards with thirty mil alive TX basically
like the wave land have about have a
free space range of about a hundred
meters so if you have to wave land cards
basically you could hit this entire room
with one access point course it wouldn't
work very well from the perspective of
the users but as far as coverage goes
they work approximately that difference
the antennas on wireless cards are
actually pretty poor in most cases
they're about minus 2 DB gain but one of
the observations you can make about that
is they only perform incrementally more
poorly in the vertical space as they do
in the horizontal space and that's
something you can use to your advantage
for nanog 26 which is the first of these
events that we did last year we deployed
13 access points 7 in the main room by
itself so in a relatively small hotel
bar smaller than this one we had 13
access point we used a mix of two
antenna types in order to get the
density in the one room and I have a
good picture that here in a moment but
half the antennas are horizontally
polarized and what that did is the the
antennas on the access points which in
this case are dipoles are far less
sensitive to each other in the
horizontal and vertical plane than the
antennas on the wireless cards so even
in places where we have a map coloring
problem and things are adjacent channels
the likelihood of the access points
interfering with each other is
significantly lower in this case we were
also able to reduce the output power on
the access points themselves which has
the property that the wireless cards and
the clients will associate with the
access point they see with a strongest
signal if you have 6 access points in a
room like this all transmitting at 30
milliwatts it's going to see at least
three or four of them at approximately
the same city
we'll strength and so it will probably
stay associated with it regard with one
access point regardless of where you
move in the room if you can reduce the
power to the point where not all the
users will end up associated with the
access the same access point say the one
by the door where everybody powered up
their laptops or came into the room then
you're in a situation where the load can
actually be distributed reasonably
across all the access points so there's
a horizontal access point very high-tech
it's rotated 90 degrees from being a
vertical access point the practical
result of that actually if you look at
it is it has the same radiative pattern
as a dipole would ordinarily have it's
just that the doughnut goes forward and
back instead of all the way around the
thing so in this case in lieu of using
an external antenna we can use the
internal antennas in the access point
and we get patterns that look like that
so all the horizontally polarized access
points basically have a footprint that
is rectangular and they're far less
sensitive on the edges then the
vertically polarized access points which
have a traditional dipole pattern I ETF
design much bigger problem instead of
550 people we plan for 2,000 people in
Yokohama we saw more than 1,400 people
in one room associated with the wireless
X points so the IETF problem is much
larger and you know you could apply it
to other large venues like sporting
events where potentially you could
deploy wireless access for you know
order of 10,000 people using similar
method gets us into the address space
problem the address space for that
wireless subnet was a slab
20 the total address space that we had
was a / 19 not all of those users were
on at the same time but we handed out
about three quarters of that address
space which is a big number it's hard to
do things like crank your dhcp least Im
down and have any kind of reasonable
person systems so you really need the
amount of IP address space that you need
in order to do this in this case the
least time is set around eight hours
which would get some be associated with
the thing for basically the whole day
even if their machine got turned off
again reduce the output power to 15
milliwatts not all of our equipment with
Cisco in this case so the gear stuff
which has a fixed radio output of 30
milliwatts we used a density setting of
high and I'll explain what that actually
does here a moment where possible so the
ITF 55 layout is a much worse map
coloring problem given given only three
channels and one rogue Japanese access
point which is down in the corner there
you know you don't have a whole lot of
choices but you can see there's there's
27 access points on the one floor with
all the users and in fact during an
especially boring ipv6 meeting there
were more than 700 people and the
wireless in one working group during
during the plenary it actually peed did
around 1100 which was significantly
smaller than Yokohama that there were
fewer people there as well logical
layout for that network ends up looking
something like this we have a couple of
small backbone switches and the
interesting problem with this hotel is
that there were a number of Ethernet
runs that were in the range of 150
meters which is you know significantly
out of spec but
that actually worked pretty well some
complaints about enterprise access
points that we've experienced in the
process of attempting to deploy this
some access points allow you to set
output power that would be like the
Cisco's and some use density or
sensitivity settings and that would be
most of the OEM Avaya equipment that's
available from all sorts of vendors and
what density settings do is on the
access point they limit the quality of
the connection that the access point is
willing to tolerate from a user so the
access point will disconnect a client
that reaches a certain threshold and
what happens is in situations where you
have marginal antennas or marginal
quality and all of your access points
are marginal from the perspective of a
client the client will associate with an
access point and then get disconnected
and whereas if you have the opportunity
to use power settings the access point
or the client simply won't hear the
access points in the same situation so
clients tend to flip-flop on because in
many cases they can hear the access
point just fine but the access point
can't hear them one vendor provided us
with access points for which it was
impossible to determine how many
stations were actually associated with
the access point and that was kind of
interesting because we know that the
access points get in trouble when they
have a really large number of users on
them and in this case this access point
would send an SNMP trap when it crashed
that said that the max table and the
card had filled up so we knew that the
access points had too many users
associated with them we just didn't know
how many immediately beforehand so there
was nothing we could do about it so it
had an ethernet bridge move the wouldn't
age which is
an interesting idea it's like how many
people are actually on this thing and it
had no enterprise nib from which you
could tell what associated stations were
ia PP which is the inner inner access
point protocol which has been in IA
Tripoli standardization process since
1997 is not in fact standardized between
vendor platforms at this point so for
example Cisco's can see I a PP messages
from a via access points but not the
other way around which has the
interesting property that some of your
access point can tell how many users are
on some of your other access points but
not vice versa crashes but tend to leave
the cascading failures so when you don't
know how many people were associated
with it when that access point blows up
all those users move over to the next
available access point in the same space
so that access point then blows up
because it becomes overloaded so you can
watch the crash go around the room and
in fact you can watch the frustration
level among the users go around the room
as well one vendors access points would
give up attempting to dhcp after four
attempts and then they would one assign
themselves in a RFC 1918 address and two
removes random bits of their
configuration so by the time you found
the access point let's say you powered
it on without plugging in the ethernet
and was unable to dhcp by the time you
found that access point it would be in
some unusable state so if you were
having network connectivity problems
with various portions of your network
your your access points might go into a
host state and never come back
interoperability issues with some older
cards and this when you have people who
have a broad variety of hardware and you
know we now have 802 11 cards and old
intersil prisms and others
that are now more than four years old
and they don't support all of the
features of 802 11 be so things like
short preambles at very low bit rates
they don't support so you have to do
some tweaking your hardware in order to
actually like get all varieties of cards
to working and there's some question as
to how obsolete you want to choose to
support but when you have users
complaining and you know why it's pretty
hard to not justify tweaking it you need
real management tools for all access
points at this point they'll provide you
with in most cases an SNMP management
interface which is snmpv1 they will
provide you with a web-based management
interface they may provide you with the
CLI which would be via telnet and in all
of these cases you have to pass the
management password in clear text so I
mean an SSH or SSL rapid management in
your face would be really nice I mean we
have those on switches now it can't be
that hard to implement on an access
point one access point model would
actually provide management passwords to
anyone who asked by sending a magic
broadcast packet to the network that was
kind of cute and as far as client issues
in terms of tuning the network not all
wireless cards are created equal by the
standards of wireless cards the OEM
levaya and lucent technologies cards are
actually pretty good when you get into
the ones that are built into laptops
particularly laptops that are made of
metal the actual performance of the
wireless cards is quite poor when they
say that the distance on they recommend
on the on the appletv for titanium
laptop the original one is 100 feet they
aren't kidding so what happens is when
you use those in places where you have
sensitivity settings some of your
clients may work well
others don't simply because their
antenna is too poor and so at that point
the only real solutions are increasing
the number of access points which you
may have trouble doing because of your
map coloring problem or cranking the
dent the sensitivity setting down which
has its own issues because one of the
things you're using the sensitivity
setting to do young easel is allow you
to set the broadcast and multicast rate
higher to say 2 megabits or 5 megabits
so that you can actually support on the
amount of broadcast or multicast traffic
that you have on the network so you have
trouble supporting marginal clients in
extremely high density situations
misconfigured clients things that are in
ad-hoc mode have it which you know
clearly if they're in ad-hoc mode
they're not associated with any of the
base stations in your network so they're
non working well clients that are
configured by default will probably
associate with the ad-hoc network just
as easily if they do with the other
network so you can suck half the people
in the room down into the non-working
pit of despair because of one ad hoc
user and then of course those users
remain ad hoc mode and wander around and
cause more users to go into ad hoc mode
so I mean that can become a support
nightmare and part of the problem there
is simply the post implementations of
802 11 B controls for various drivers
are either lacking or hiding critical
control functionality from the user and
Microsoft is certainly an offender there
although the Apple stack has its own
problems which have mostly been
rectified by now what does the future
hold the map coloring problem will get a
lot easier with 802 11 a
you have somewhere between eight and ten
non-overlapping channels depending on
the equipment you're using those are
available with various powers up to 800
milliwatts I believe is the acceptable
maximum that's a orthogonal
frequency-division multiplexing scheme
as opposed to the cck one that 802 dot11
uses and as a result it ought to be
plenty more resistant to interference
the problem with it though is that the
power requirements the chipsets that are
operating in the five figure Hertz range
and the size of the antennas that are
required to perform decently it's
probably going to keep those out of any
devices smaller than laptops for the
foreseeable future which means that 802
dot 11 b is probably going to be around
for quite a while 802 11 a and b access
points are kind of a no-brainer all of
the enterprise vendors are pushing
products that do both some of them have
better implementations in other the
range on 802 dot 11a is going to be
significantly more restricted on any
device it doesn't have the largest
external antenna so the density you're
going to need to support that is even
larger 802 11 g same rate but we have
the same three channels we have now one
of the issues that's being hashed out by
vendors is that if you transmit at what
would be considered full power like 100
milliwatts or so on channels 1 or 11
with an ordinary antenna you're actually
going to leak outside of the 2.4
gigahertz is M band into the adjacent
bands and kind of unacceptable levels as
far as the FCC is concerned so you may
end up having only two non-overlapping
channels if you use say three and nine
or you might have to significantly
reduce the power you use on
1 or 11 in any event you're sharing that
spectrum with all the 802 11 B devices
your access points may be backward
compatible but I think ultimately what
that's going to do is sort of hinder the
adoption of the ng dual stack devices
people may end up just paying for the
chipset and using it one way or the
other performance may not be
significantly better than one expects
now except in your home environment
where the nearest access point might be
several hundred meters away on laptops
we basically solved the problem of power
consumption on laptops as far as
wireless chipsets go I mean when you
have a monster like this that has 120
watt hours of batteries the actual
impact of a wireless card and the thing
is negligible on pdas and cell phones
and other devices were probably in to
stick with B and G until the power size
requirements for a go down and given the
need for high performance antennas
they're the size requirements may never
go down to some level that's acceptable
for things like PDAs and cell phones I'd
like to thank all the people that helped
me with this Merritt University of
Oregon and Nokia and the IETF
Secretariat who allowing me to mess up
their networks bill Fenner and Carlos
content they who did the tool
development for the monitoring stuff
that we used at nanigen ITF David Quezon
from Nokia who bottled the access points
jennifer adams from cisco who actually
provided a large number of access points
and everyone who worked on nanog 26 and
ITF networks thanks
thanks Joe um we have we have time to
take some questions if you can um if you
can direct it to the speaker who you'd
like to have answer it just a quick
comment from the guys from Tennessee on
finding rogue access points I posted to
the list it hasn't made it there yet uh
no it's just the list of slower if i fat
fingered something but there's some
other ways that you can track a tease
one cool trick we found is few aps
actually do multicast so on your edge
interfaces you could look at the igmp
groups and see which what access points
are doing multicast that way
so you check it on your internet you can
check it on all your interfaces where
you have multicast you can just do a
show igmp groups all union routers have
a database of all yours and then convert
it to I posted something to the list so
as soon as it shows up there you take a
look at it and appreciating feedback if
anyone has any additional groups here
information that i missed actually hello
Joel are the tools and stuff that's you
guys or the UFO folks center at all
developer those going to be made
available out through the community I
think we'd like to they're not packaged
in any sensible format right now but the
person to ask on that would probably be
bill since he has most of the effort
that went into doing those on there are
actually quite cool for something that's
you know a relatively minimal scripted
interface they actually work a lot
better than the enterprise tools that
we've paid a lot of money for isn't that
usually the case so a lot of the scripts
were just things that I came up with on
the fly to solve a given problem or
something so they're not like nice
polished things but yeah I mean I don't
see a problem with making them available
I might keep the one that steals
fantastic from the base station but
other than that yeah closure oh yeah I
mean in the interest of full disclosure
we've given that vendor a fair amount of
time so I think it's time to revisit
with them whether or not they've
actually solved that and if I can since
there's nobody else I had one of those
watching for the u.s. to Tennessee folks
um have you found issues with people
other than your frat and sorority groups
pushing yeah geez towards you um have
you found any widespread bad things
happening with people using the network
sort of open mode I guess my question is
coming from the sense that I get
homeland security and folks like that
are out saying we need to really lock
down our wireless networks because they
could cause evildoers do bad things and
stuff like that so have you noticed or
do you have any preparatory ability to
notice a bad things happening on that
network now we haven't noticed anything
so far and if the homeland security
people want to come and help me they're
welcome whether that we dare you the
edges not only three about convene so
I'm i would love to secure that thing
and but please this convenient because
then you lose everything that you
devious so at miss people just learn how
to protect themselves it could be better
this is primarily for joel's every year
i work a show that does very large wide
area coverage with wireless 802 dot11 be
this year the people from ncsa to set up
that network ran everything on a single
channel and we had extremely good
results i'm not an RF person by any
means my last hour class was mumble
mumble years ago so i don't claim any
expertise but i was wondering if you'd
ever looked at such a solution where you
covered large areas with large numbers
of access points all operating on a
single channel
well I've had relatively negative
experiences doing that in small areas
one of the vendor suggested solutions to
to the crashing access point problem was
simply to put two cards in the access
point on the same channel but what
happens at that point is you have the
same collision domain and all these
things are operating in ibss mode on so
the access point assumes that it
actually has control of who transmits on
that channel to some extent and as a
result you have I think more issues with
people stomping on each other then you
would otherwise have I mean a large
portion of it has to do with the size of
the packets you are sending and how many
people are sending them at once because
I could see situations where you have
large amounts of relatively small
packets UDP for example that you could
push out in one direction or the other
on the same channel and not smash each
other whereas when you have extremely
large packets on the other hand I mean
right up around 1,500 the probability of
one of them getting smashed and having
more queuing as a result is much higher
but a lot of whether or not it performs
accepted lee has to do with the
utilization on each access point and in
the IETF situation you see things where
the access point to get very close to
four megabits and at that point
everybody starts to suffer and if
there's more noise on the same channel
then people start to suffer more than
they would otherwise if you
one second let's take these last these
last few questions and we'll take the
other ones offline one other request um
can maybe people give us a clue about
how to bring up the mics on that on the
table subject can we had nice accessible
we need a portable but I had a question
for Joel have you given any thought to
what happens if you roll into a venue
where there is already a wireless
network deployed when we gave when we
did the site survey for the hotel in
Atlanta we discovered I mean it's
basically surrounded by 40 story high
buildings so I mean in the process of
doing the site survey we discovered
about 15 wireless networks that you
could actually hear in hotels it
actually turns out not to be much
problem because these buildings are so
large and they use so much concrete that
the actual amount of interference is
small at the point where people start
deploying wireless networks that cover
hotels it's going to get more
interesting when you look at something
like the STS n network deployments that
people are doing in hotels they're not
providing nearly enough address space or
network infrastructure that an event
like the IETF could just pay whatever it
costs to use their services for the
course of the event so I think in many
cases it's going to end up being a
negotiation between whatever wireless
isp is already deployed there and the
whatever Network you have to deploy in
order to actually get reasonable service
because I mean if you look at it the
remaining address space available in v4
would amount
about 200,000 / 19 which might cover
every venue that you could conceivably
like deploy that kind of wireless in but
it wouldn't leave much left over for
anything else so it doesn't look to me
like venues are going to come up with
things like large amounts of address
space and wireless networks in order to
just to support flash crowds so I think
the biggest issue is negotiating with
whoever's there first yeah thank you i
was taking more of an interference issue
rather than a no debating that they'd be
able to handle this a lot of traffic
yeah i mean that goes along with it as
long as it as long as there's relatively
few people i mean if the if the existing
network is there for the convenience of
the hotel staff then it's going to have
relatively low traffic on it and it's
mostly just then an issue of ensuring
that you don't stomp all over it
completely but that's about all i can
think of an in that environment say hey
Louie you're gonna hate me you're going
to hate me we're going to have to take
your question offline I'm sorry so thank
you Joe and sleep