I wrote an abstract that caused this
work to happen and so they give me
credit unlike the third one down but the
guys who actually did the work I can't
pronounce their names but there they are
and they're really great and the really
neat thing about writing an abstract and
having some grad students think about
and try to write some code around what
the idea is is that they think of things
that you wouldn't necessarily have
thought of and some of them are kind of
interesting so I'm pretty excited about
that this work came from some work we
did it Aaron I'm on the Advisory Council
of errands so when the public policy
meetings happen and there's consensus in
the community we try to help formalize
policy changes and make sure that it
represents the consensus of the
community so when we started changing
things like from a plush 19 minimum
allocation to a slash twenty we started
thinking well gee what happens to the
global routing table and is there some
way to look at it and so I went around
for a lot of time because I have limited
programming skills and has limited
amounts of time and said to people gee
wouldn't it be great if we knew axor
wouldn't it be great if and so people
like Phillips Matthew does the weekly
routing table report thing has
breakdowns by regional registry now and
some of those quotes that some of those
things answer some of my questions but
my main questions were things like how
to actual allocations affect the routing
table so when a registry hands out a
block of address space how does that
affect the table and so this is more
focused on the routing table while
looking at address allocations and
assignments as opposed to you know how
much could we aggregate the routing
table based on you know a s path lengths
or whatever that everybody else talks
about so it has more of a registry focus
and I don't have any idea what my first
slide is oh okay so a little overview I
think you guys are all familiar with
most of this stuff that internet
registry design address blocks and I
want it I want to take a minute to
explain the difference between a sign
and allocate
in this talk will use them
interchangeably but there really is a
distinction when an address registry
assigns a block it's to an end user and
it's not a block to be subdivided and
handed out to customers if its allocated
its allocated to an ISP and then it said
assigned to customers and this talk will
use them interchangeably but they're
always assignments and allocations from
a registry so they're not said
allocations and an ISP would do to its
customers and we look at the also a
little bit at the routing table
evolution but again with an allocation
and assignment slant and some
conclusions and I came up with some more
in my sleep last night so again this is
what I just talked about some of the
policy changes again are the the change
to cider and I have some slides on that
that that are no big surprise and the
change from a 19 to 20 what we really
wanted to see if it had any effect at
all so how have the address assignments
been performed what are the block sizes
over time those sorts of things what are
the distribution of prefix went the
length and again these are of
allocations and assignments so let's
look at some of these charts so in 1993
but before we had you know cider was
deployed it's no big surprise that you
know that the allocations were 16 or 24
hurts because that's all we had we had
the three bears you know the /a it was
too big and the / 24 was she small in
the / 16 was just right only it wasn't
it was huge so and then after cider a
lot of different sized prefixes started
being assigned so there's no big
surprise there again when we change from
a 19 to 20 again there's no really huge
surprise it used to be that there were a
lot of 20s allocated now there I mean
19th now there are a lot of 20 so no big
surprise there now if you look at
allocated blocks over time these were
going to I was thinking about removing
these from the slides because they're a
little bit deceptive but nonetheless are
a little bit interesting at the same
time so if we look at the different
years you see the allocation of blocks
over time just how men
and the yellow is what the grad students
called non-aligned blocks which is the
part that's a little bit deceptive one
of the registries does a assignment and
allocation in the database slightly
different than the others so if if a
block gets assigned say a company can
only justify like a 19 and a 20 but not
a whole 18 in the database it'll show up
as one contiguous non bid a line block
even though it's really two bit of line
blocks and it's assigned as two-bit
aligned blocks and then there's usually
a reserved space for the rest of the 18
and then if they go back in the right
amount of time they fill up that space
and then they have 118 so it's a way of
trying to promote aggravate aggregation
aggravation and but in the database they
didn't know that because they're not you
know they don't got a registry meetings
they don't get address space from the
registry so it wasn't something that
they thought of there are however a few
really interesting non-aligned blocks
and I have an example later on also
notice that there are blocks that are a
sign that are longer than the minimum
allocation and most of these are because
of the micro allocation policies and
again the scales a little bit different
so there aren't really a huge number of
these non-aligned ones so this is an
example there's a couple examples and
this has nothing to do with this address
block like it's not their fault I don't
know whose fault it is but anyway it's
not a bit a line block and actually it's
broken into a bunch of smaller bin
allein blocks and if you look in the
database that's how its represented
there's another one we found I was
talking to Richard last night from Aaron
and he knows all these intimately so
we're going to work with him to to help
identify what some of them are just
assigned a long time ago but there's a /
16 where they have the hall / 15 except
for the last / 24 which makes for a
really nice non aggregate able block and
again like I said some of them are not
been aligned just because of the way
they show up in the database but they
really are and so we're going to tease
those out and include them appropriately
in the datasets but it's just so small
that it didn't really affect the
analysis any
so how do how do these allocated and
assign blocks appear in the routing
table how do they do they appear as
they're allocated are they aggregated
are they fragmented I'm going to talk
about that some more how long after
their allocated do they show up in the
routing table are there some that don't
appear at all we all know there are but
we've quantified that we've looked at we
use the right data we use the route
views data and compared some of that to
the links data and as you know we don't
there's nowhere that you can look on the
internet and get a full picture of what
the routing table looks like from every
vantage point but we feel like we've got
a pretty good handle on it the total
prefix is allocated in our studies here
in 190 554 so if you all to prefixes
appear this is a month-by-month graph of
the number of allocations and the green
are the ones that have never been
advertised so as you can see over time
there are certainly blocks that don't
get advertised and it seems like in 2002
there a lot of them compared to the
number that are allocated um this is one
of the interesting things that I don't
know if I would have thought of looking
at necessarily but they did and I think
it's kind of cool so they looked at the
difference between the amount of time
between when a block gets allocated and
it shows up in the database and when it
shows up in the routing table and as you
can see there's a hundred and eight
allocations and have a delay that are
greater than 400 so there's you know for
any timeframe there's that they pick
there's still a lot of outliers but the
really interesting thing that I think is
interesting is this graph I mean this
chart I i removed the blocks because
well I kind of looked old I probably
should so because I didn't want this to
be an exposé or whatever but they're a
bunch of blocks and their allocation
date and notice that there are some from
each of the regional registries and lack
Nick was too new to really to really
tell but this actually shows that
there's a negative delay so it's showing
up in the routing table significant
amounts of time before it shows up in
the database is being assigned
so we're trying to figure out and I
talked to Richard quite a bit last night
about what some of these could be he
said that some of them might be trans
transfers that in Aaron's case when they
transfer from one organization to
another it shows up in the database as a
new allocation with a new start
allocation date so some of these might
be that some of them look like they were
they were assignments back before there
was an errand or raipur ap Nick so maybe
they weren't actually in the database
but they needed to change their and
adder or something and then they ended
up showing up in the database so we're
in the process of looking at them but
it's pretty significant time in fifteen
hundred days that a prefix get to get to
advertised before before it gets
assigned by the registry that's pretty
pretty big so how exactly do the
allocations show up in the routing table
are they show up just as they're
allocated are they fragmented are they
aggregated I have some examples and then
the last four or combination so if it's
in the graphs if it shows up as
identical then then the only
advertisement for that block is
identical to the allocation links and
then there are combinations at the
bottom and this is an example I don't
really think I need to go through it but
if it's a 16 then it's advertised as a
16 and if it's fragmented then the 16
isn't there but some of the fragments
are so anyway so we look at some of
these graphs this is for all of the
allocated prefixes in our study period
and some interesting things to take note
is that are that forty-eight percent are
advertised as identical to how they're
allocated but there's a whole bunch that
a bed aren't so another forty percent
are some variation of fragmented which
means means a lot of things but to me if
you're looking at changing the policy it
might mean that maybe you don't want to
start defining little assignments to
each person who comes because for forty
percent of the prefixes an ISP was
trying to save the routers from killing
over could filter out those more
specifics and and turn down the routing
table and still be able to get to those
prefixes I mean there's lots of other
things you could say about that but
that's the thing that strikes me today
so if we look at these more individually
for / 16 they change a little bit more
over time than just the the whole
picture they have a higher fragmentation
rate than than any other size block we
looked at they also seem to get it
replaced instead of just being identical
they gets replaced with mostly with
identical plus a fragment to somebody's
injecting a hole for one reason or
another out of these 16 so that's why
the identical line that the blue line is
going down well the little I don't know
if how well these are to see the little
turquoise bubbly things are going up it
might be good actually if you pull up
these slides on the web if you're
interested in and looking at them
because some of them later on or a
little bit more difficult so 19 I
actually didn't find this overly
surprising they tend to be advertised as
19th and I think that's because of the
filtering policies that we had for so
long and some of the people that
wholeheartedly enforce those policies 19
seem to be you know really highly
identical to how they're advertised
three twenties are also interesting
because the 20s can tend mostly to be
aggregated into 19 so if you get a Gris
if you get allocated 20s from the
registry over time you're more likely to
aggregate them and you're more likely to
aggregate them into 19th and again I
think this was an artifact as the
policies the filtering policies that
were beaten into our heads for so long
okay this graph shows the average number
of prefixes of fragments of allocated
prefixes which kind of hovers around 14
the little blips that are way up near
the top around mar 30 are because of
addi aggregation event of net 63 / 10
and the rest of them so over x it grows
a little bit but it averages around 14
so one of the things that I wanted to
know was everybody talks about how / 24
is there a big component of the routing
table and I kind of wanted to figure out
are those allocated is less 24 so how
many / 24 is in the routing table are
actually allocated as / 24 s and how
many of them are d aggregations and we
could have done this for any length
prefix but since / 24 is the largest
component right now we decided we'd look
at those first so of the length of the
allocated blocks is the x-axis and the
little little towers are how many are
advertised in an aggregate so like out
of a thousand and eight / 18 140 42 or
advertised as part of an aggregate so
this kind of gives you an idea of the
amount of aggregation that's going on
let's see this shows that ten percent of
the allocated blocks contribute to
seventy percent of the routing prefixes
and ninety percent of the allocation
allocated blocks contribute less than
thirty percent of the routing table
prefixes so you know I think that the
stuff that was talked about earlier of
going out and trying to get people to
aggregate you know it's a pretty small
target and probably could do a lot of
good if you can get to those ten percent
so here's some more on the / 24 so
before 1993 you know a lot of / 24 s
were allocated a big no big surprise it
was that it was that model where sunday
will be able to aggregate them so let's
give somebody you know 30 of them
instead of the / 16 so and over time
fewer and fewer of them are allocated so
this is just a number allocated per year
and then if we look at / 24 s as
fragments of larger allocations so year
by year you can see that a lot of these
are fragments of larger allocations
especially like in 99 and 94 but some of
the early ones I think are probably
because people just never aggregated a
master they could aggregate them
and this is a breakdown of flash
twenty-fours fragments heard the size of
the block that they're at their d
aggregated from so like for a / 16 there
are fourteen thousand and 307 / 24
fragments out of fourteen hundred and
six / 16 so 58,000 329 are fragmented
from larger allocation blocks and most
of all of these came from most of them
came from / aids through / 23 so if we
look at this per country I guess they
decided that maybe it would be cool to
see if somebody is worse than somebody
else country wise at aggregating or D
aggregating and you can see that they're
pretty much the same so the u.s. is
about six point eight percent so the
average number of routing entries from a
from a Negra from our that are
fragmented from an allocation block or
six point eight in the u.s. 6.7 in china
6.2 in japan so they're pretty pretty
much the same it seems like Canada does
a really good job of aggregation yay go
team so let's see changes in the global
routing table so let's look at how how
the allocations some more about how they
show up in the routing table how many
prefixes get added how many prefixes go
away and where do they go things like
that and also when they talked when we
talked about IP address is being
consumed it's basically they aren't
necessarily reachable but they're
represented by the routes in the routing
table so if / 24 is in the routing table
then then that address space represented
by that / 24 is is consumed even if you
know three of the addresses or whatever
all of them aren't reachable the routes
there
so this is a standard graph of the
growth of the routing table size and if
you look on the graph on the right the
dashed line is the the amount of
allocated address space and the blue
line I hope you guys have colors the
blue line is the amount of address space
that's actually represented by the
routes in the routing table so it's
consumed as we call it in the paper so
the routing table size in our study
period changed from 53,000 some routes
214,000 routes and depending on your
view of the world that could have can
change so the growth has been really
huge and again the growth and address
based consumptions of the amount of
address space represented by the routes
in the routing table has only grown 26.3
percent and let's see pretty good so
where do their new advertisements in the
routing table come from the total number
in our study period was eighty seven
thousand nine hundred and forty-one and
we wanted to look at the rate of the
relationship between those and
allocations so eighty eight point four
percent of them are fragments of larger
allocations ten percent of them are
allocations of equal size and a little
smaller ones are aggregations of
multiple smaller allocations so let's
look at this so this is where the new
advertisements come from as far as a
year so these are allocated blocks from
these years and which ones how many
showed up in the routing table and then
by country so the US had the most and
the other ones are smaller so I guess
it's no surprise we have more d
aggregation I guess we're more prefixes
so if we look at the pie chart of the
pie chart say the fragmented ones so
when advertisements leave the routing
table some of them get discarded so
they're just not represented by anything
some of them get aggregated a lot of
them get aggregated like seventy-seven
percent of them get aggregated into
other prefixes so one prefix may go away
but it gets replaced by another one and
then some of them get further fragmented
so the prefix itself went away but then
there are more fragments sitting there
that's see this is going faster than I
thought okay so this is a breakdown of
the newly announced prefixes by length
prefix length and they're like we said
before there are a lot of slush
twenty-fours but there are a lot of
other ones too and if they're all
fragments of larger allocated blocks
then a lot of these little guys get
filtered out and you are still reachable
the one of the ones that went away so
there's you know there's 30,000 that
went away and 80,000 that showed up
twenty-two thousand of them were / 24 so
they're still they go away and they come
you know they cut there are new ones and
then they're ones that go away and the
impact on address consumption so when
prefixes go away there's there's still
the discarded prefix let's see here
sorry so the total number of address is
covered by the prefixes was 2,400,000
and the total number of addresses that
drop off was only 131,000 so there's a
bunch of them that become unreachable
but there are a lot of them that just
get re re represented by other prefixes
so what are our observations no big
surprise allocations play a dominant
role in the routing table size because
you know you have to advertise your
address space to get it reachable so
when we hand out blocks it's no big
surprise that the running cables going
to grow on some level hopefully people
aggregate better than than they you know
they do it well the 19 to 20 change it
had an impact but I'm not really sure
that it had an impact that would be any
different than if we'd stayed at a 19
now that's not to say that we should go
I still don't believe that we should go
and give everybody a portable prefix
that isn't part of a provider block even
if they punch a hole in that provider
book because it takes away your ability
as an ISP to filter it out but that's my
opinion also remember that there's no
requirement that an allocation get
advertised in a particular way so you
know if you go and you get a block from
an NRI are there's no requirement that
you advertise it aggregated or
fragmented and maybe some guidelines
would be good but I don't think that
that's the role of the registries to do
that so what we would like to know is
whether this is interesting what other
things you think would be useful if you
have questions or comments that would be
great
nobody okay we really want feedback
hi it's that nice stuff it's and yoga
system reneges i think that the
protection is actually much larger than
you see I mean we have seen from about
what few dozen tears that we have
something like 350,000 distinct legal
practices this year many of them appear
for a short time or appear only for
certain tears totally endearing crowds
so people are rearranged and keep
rearranging practices or legal ethics is
at a much higher rate than the semi
static picture of the routing table
gross shows that's just a comment okay
where where where are you like is there
is there a way that we could connect to
something near you and look at that yeah
we can talk offline now okay to talk to
you because it all depends on your view
of the world we are appearing without
this in South Africa Asia Europe in the
United States okay it's avi
I'll just say that we see the same thing
but in many case depends on looking at
ISPs that you might not think of that
don't appear that you don't find you
know major exchange points but to do
some caring especially sub caring
amongst themselves you know and
internationally where people who do peer
you don't have their bgp sessions log so
i'd say that you're looking at edge and
looking international and i don't know
exactly what the number is but it's in
the hundreds of thousands of distinct
things that we've seen pop up for some
period of time looking at bgp from
Malcolm I ok everybody else thanks