well good morning everybody good morning
as him you made it finally
so we are happy to be here today to talk
about the work we have done with Pierre
related to GPS tracker technologies and
during this talk we will try to share
with you the fun we had when we analyzed
the security of such technologies so as
introduced by VIN we are a security
researcher at the mobile and telecom lab
Zenoss lab test validation labs of dark
matter and we had the third friend
walking with us in Menasha he/she wanted
to be here but she had some exams so big
up Eman and we are all with you today
let's start with the topic of today's so
GPS tracker technologies so there are
cheap devices that we can buy online and
basically they provide you specific
devices that you can put on specific for
space for specific applications
especially for expensive good tracking
people tracking if you need for example
when you have to manage cars at a lower
scale they are available everywhere they
provide you also mobile apps for iOS and
Android we have been buying a few of
them so they are here if you want to
have a look at one of them is in the
Faraday cage we have built yesterday
because we will do some live demos
during this talk basically when we
started working on GPS trackers it was
early 2018 we have been looking at the
infrastructure of GPS trackers devices
but we had no information about the
device we were testing so basically it
was a black box type of analysis and we
started with gathering information so
the first thing we have been looking at
is basically if
see reports were available online and we
had a look on the website and we found
basically that the tracker have been
evaluated from a standard as a test a
point of view and here for example we
have one of the model we have been
looking at in the report you have
everything you need to know about the
hardware the wireless interfaces the
network what type of sensor they enclose
what type of specific technologies they
may be using how they work and a lot of
information about the way you can
manipulate the tracker there is a lot of
interesting information related to
network network interfaces wired and
wireless so we will see that some of
them have interesting features and we
had also to work on the reverse
engineering of the hardware with the
support of the Asus FCC report the same
way when we were able to extract it and
web app data data put online to manage
the tracker remotely and also mobile
apps and for the web app we also had a
lot of fans and we will show you what
kind of veneer ability they have so the
general architecture is as follows so
basically the GPS tracker is supposed to
get the signal from the GPS satellites
then they collect the data and through
the mobile network they will send the
location periodically or on demand if
the user would like to request
especially at a specific time the
location of the tracker with the mobile
apps it's just based on sending an SMS
to the to the to the tracker and the
tracker automatically send back the
location of the tracker so the user can
use the web application on the
smartphone you can also directly connect
on the web app online and get access to
the tracker and the management interface
so as we can see here there are a lot of
point of interaction so base
we can use that as attack vectors
depending on what is the purpose of the
specific attacks we try to launch
against the attackers technology we were
not the only one working on that at the
same time we have seen very interesting
paper studies released online track
McCadden is one of them and it's
basically focusing on web app security
so finding vulnerabilities in management
web application provided by
manufacturers a second study which is
basically sending fake time and GPS
location to again the web web app and
also videos which was the study of the
most most important GPS tracker use in
UK where the researcher was able to
compromise more than ten ten thousand
devices a last interesting publication
published by Zak Whittaker was a study
from a security researcher where he was
exposing one of the interesting new
features they tend to introduce in GPS
trackers which are a microphone to
provide the user the access to the audio
environment where the location we have
the tracker is located most of these
studies were have in common that they
were focusing on the web app and how to
compromise the tracker
location from the web interface in our
case we wanted to have a look at a more
attack vectors and we decided to work on
finding new vulnerabilities having fun
of you of course by trying all the
attack vectors we had in mind so the
first one was how to reverse the
management protocol by using a fake base
station then becoming active manipulate
minimal
the data by bypassing security features
if they exist accessing the remote
management server and custom protocol so
we had a look at what what kind of
vulnerabilities exists in the management
interface and how we would be able to
access over trackers location we also
had a look at the hardware security we
opened all the GPS tracker we have we
have been processing at least the one we
have been able to get because many of
those stay blocked at the custom
reversing the fem we're finding
vulnerabilities and also having a look
at the mobile apps and the web interface
again because they are interesting
features that we will talk about so we
just went online we went to Aliexpress
we took the ten most ten most popular
GPS trackers we finally were able to get
three seven where Ava sent back or block
at the custom even by sending them to
friends it was a little bit complex so
we were not able to get them but what we
have seen from a infrastructure point of
view all the tracker have a lot of
similarities at the infrastructure level
so even if there are a lot of resellers
the there is a specific art were sold by
OEM and they are used by different
resellers what they just put their own
label on them most of them are Chinese
and you will see that for privacy
purpose there is some question to to ask
yourself before using such technologies
so for starting we study at the AF
interface level we want it first to
hijack sessions to and break the a51 but
we found found it easier to just set up
our own base station and collect all the
data we need to stop we publish one
paper in misc
where we focus on the methodology we
applied during the research and one
scientific paper where we focus on the
privacy issues
introduced by GPS trackers so those
studies are online or in the misc Jonah
so regarding the first attack scenario
which was not written attack scenario we
just put our sim card in the GPS tracker
set up a base station as we did here and
we just started to get data order the
different messages sent between the
tracker and the infrastructure what we
have seen basically that they have very
old baseband so they don't support use
him and we spent one day just to figure
out that they don't are not able to
handle them here for example we will
just go on the website and register the
tracker we are we are we have on in the
Faraday cage and basically that's what
the user will have so he will have the
location it's low specific location soon
because we are also doing another demo
same time I think so we can create the
account basically the login and password
are either the ami of the of the of the
tracker or the serial number and the
password is basically the same
information and no one asked you to
change the password so basically if you
have one serial number you are able to
brute-force them because they are just
incremented when they are produced so
from that specific part we are already
able to get access to the data of a lot
of stalkers we also have seen that
basically the full configuration is
managed for SMS that we can see in clear
text and the first fail that we have
seen is for any SMS we sent to the
tracker the content of the SMS is sent
back to another to the server and and
basically to the manufacturer or the
tracker so he is aware of any action you
are doing on the tracker action that can
be changing the password to log the
tracker changing the
getting access to the location of the
tracker and over they tie we will see so
these are proprietary protocols of have
text messages in clear text and you will
see that the protocol is really easy so
as we said set up the BTS everyone every
security researcher now has at least one
ser we have here the blade RF with that
we have been able to get a lot of
information quickly especially about the
often authentication of Education
protocol which is really unsecure all
cut curves and coordinates to IPS in
China which is also something
interesting the traffic is not encrypted
and is easily detectable the password is
sent in clear text the serial number is
used as a token and it's also sent in
clear text the SMS configuration is
generic in the sense that all the
tracker we have been looking at use the
same management SMS commands so as soon
as you have been able to look at the
configuration mechanism it is common to
all tracker you will be you have you
will have a look at later
the only firewall the only security
feature that we called firewall is that
the tracker is locked against master
phone number which can be easily
bypassed if you are able to spoof the
caller ID when you send an SMS to the
tracker and the phone number Locker is
supposed to be secret but we saw that
the phone number for Sun tracker as soon
as you put the SIM card is sent to the
manufacturer so he is already able to
get critical information that is
supposed to be only in your hand it's
cool okay so we wanted to mainly do live
demo so currently we have a blade RF
this laptop is running yeah to BTS so
inside the Faraday cage
so we have a super nice setup as you can
see with two antennas and one GPS
tracker unfortunately we are not able to
get a GPS signal within the Faraday cage
so what we can do is just we can sniff
the light traffic on the GPRS interface
everything is sent to the Internet as
you can see the tracker is sending a
specific request to IP in China so cname
0-6 is the data center dot-com so we
wanted to do a live demo about that but
unfortunately we can do well so what we
can do is we can analyze other pickup
files so for example this kind of pickup
as you can see when we sniff the traffic
you send at first SMS to the tracker so
you Sandra status then we sniff the
traffic on the GPS in their face of the
blade RF and what is what we see is that
everything is sent to China so inside
the packet you have the serial number of
the GPS tracker the phone number of the
sender and the statues the content of
the SMS at first we were thinking we did
miss configuration and it appears that
it was not a Miss configuration
okay so this is live for this is the
capture of the packet
this one okay next one okay so basically
we wanted to replace the content of the
SMS and we saw that everything was being
sent to China so we were a bit curious
and basically it means that when you
want to configure a specific option like
a geofence of very basic option of GPS
tracker everything is sent to to China
even your passphrase your pin code so we
reverse the protocol in order to fan so
we wrote our own GPS client so basically
we don't need a GPS tracker anymore we
can send the fake information what is
very strange is that this IP is located
in China but in fact currently we are
look we are working in Abu Dhabi so when
we are trying to ping this IP we have
like nine or ten minutes gone between
this IP and our workplace which was very
suspicious so in fact this IP is a zero
located in China but everything is
Australian dubia we were a bit
suspicious about that in fact all the IP
range is announced by 80s a lot which is
the largest United Arab Emirates
Internet service provider that's very
strange so everything is sent and also
nothing is written about that in the
manual or in the privacy policy of GPS
tracker so we are currently expert so we
found a very good way to get SMS from
banking services and stuff like that so
currently we have this at home in France
and we reconfigure the management server
so basically it's and everything to our
server and we can use online banking
service also we want it to analyze this
IP because this IP is a bit stranger
so first things you do when you are
doing something like that is another
analyzing all the bottom so we were a
bit suspicious because basically you
have a lot of TCP services running on
this IP and when you want to reach this
IP over HTTPS so we will accept the risk
and you have this kind of website so
apparently it's the website for a
Chinese bank and if you try if you read
Chinese it ask you to this activate ipv6
and to disable your antivirus why not a
lot of suspicious services are running
and his IP so we changed because we
found other interesting stuff but this
is highly suspicious and so everything
is sent to to this IP so we also analyze
another kind of tracker so when this
source of tracker is booting so
basically it will reach you blocks
server so you can find a lot on shodhan
and the first thing is that so we hide
some information it will use a specific
gmail account with a password account
and it will send latitude longitude and
altitude directly to this server very
strangers and then the client running on
the GPS tracker will reach another TCP
server and it will send information so
as you can see it's very straightforward
to understand everything so basically
you have in read the latitude and the
longitude in red also so now the
question is how does the authentication
work in both cases as you previously so
we didn't see password or encryption and
that's true so you don't have
authentication so what we can do we can
write a small client in term and what we
did is we send fake coordinates
specifying is that our GPS tracker is
currently located in Pyongyang so we
were never went to Pyongyang so we can
suppose that it's not legit coordinate
also what is very interesting
thing is that it's very easy to guess
cycle number of GPS trackers so
basically if you are a bad guy you can
send fake information to like hundred of
thousand or million of GPS trackers
seeing that everyone is doing a part in
conn-young maybe you like the move just
like the mode let's go okay so no I have
a small pant
I'm sending information so this is this
is your GPS tracker I hope it will work
because as we will see some things are
broken in the back end is all chinese'
infrastructure so this is the
information about this tracker so
currently it's in green it means that
it's getting all my information so we
are here let's refresh can you see it
we will refresh the webpage and well we
travel incredible super fast so now I
don't know where is a tracker traveling
having fun I hope I am yeah so you can
see we can create a fake information for
a lot of GPS tracker it was not very
complicated to do because you don't have
a consultation and we can analyze the
protocol very very easily now more
active radio attack you can do GPS
spoofing the fact is you can get a lot
of program on github and do it very
easily we were more interested in the
detection of GPS tracker so basically as
I explained before you can send specific
SMS to tracker and you will get
information back what is very
interesting is that a lot of commands
they don't require authentication
basically if you want to detect GPS
tracker using sfa sync Yana you send a
specific keyword to also SFF a number
and
you will get a lot of answer from angry
people but also from a valid GPS tracker
and also what is very interesting is
that you can really find the management
server why is it super interesting so
basically you can redefine this server
in order to do man-in-the-middle over
the Internet which means that from the
tracker you are unable to verify how to
check that the management server
webchange and using a balanced program
you just do a TCP forwarding and then it
will send all the information back to
China which means that you are doing a
manís amid all over the Internet and you
are getting all the information but also
if you are using better cap or mhm proxy
you are able to change on the fly a GPS
coordinate which can be a very funny to
do but if you want to do that use a
Faraday cage as you can see we have a
very very a fancy Faraday cage here and
don't do this at home because it can be
a bit illegal just regarding the devices
we have been looking at and the trends
in GPS tracker
technologies we have seen that they tend
to introduce a new additional sensors
the one on the mic with the Micra have
seen that they are a lot now sold with
the feet you have to eavesdrop the audio
environment movement and noise detectors
also that will trigger the transmission
of a specific location when they detect
a specific noise level we also have seen
that a few devices now have cameras and
closed in the during the device so you
are able to request a picture anytime
from do your phone and you will get it
back we also have seen additional
wireless interfaces the first thing will
be to think that they add wireless
interfaces to increase the connectivity
of the trackers which is completely
wrong because what they do they added a
Wi-Fi module with in a monitor mode to
collect all ap
AP parameters and they sent that that
back also in China so we can think about
cars having GPS trackers equivalent to
the Google car that collect all
information and sent them back to China
so it increased the attack so fast but
it also increased the capabilities of
the tracker which is a scanning for
access point in the vicinity of the GPS
tracker so again what we have seen on
with the devices we have tested so free
GPS trackers three different backends
but a lot of similarities on the
advocacy level the Chinese IPS that are
exposed by the devices are located in
China we found her in also some of them
in Germany and the one we saw in the UAE
with this crazy banking website
presented to a user
we have reverse-engineered all the
protocols so that this is down we are
able to analyze and detect at the
network level any GPS tracker traffic at
the ISP level we think that it's super
easy to detect the presence of GPS
trackers as it's really easy to detect
specific messages from the network side
so and they also got can get the
coordinates and modify them if needed to
protect the information the the critical
infrastructure that these companies are
able to map today in the same time we
have seen that they are interesting
api's and now we will switch to
interesting vulnerabilities we have
found in the in the web apps so
basically this is a website as you can
see we have a lot of functionalities
what is very interesting is that you
have access to a lot of different API is
allowing you to get history of the
tracker to define geofence and to get
funny thing but before showing
this kind of information let's speak
about adware
so oh we also analyzed the hardware of
the GPS tracker so mainly you have two
different GPS chips you blocks a very
common and sim come from a Chinese
company so you support GPS GLONASS
Galileo we found a lot of flash memory
of four megabytes mainly with a erm CPU
on the motherboard so we didn't find
protection against physical attack you
have uart port everywhere you have jitta
so why we are doing that we were mainly
interesting to found hidden commands and
potential backdoors so basically we dump
everything and then we analyze so it's
very straightforward we load the binary
with in Ryder Pro we found nucleus F to
us which is a real-time operating system
and we were interesting in finding
backdoor SMS commands so that was not a
big success basically we found different
commands for different a network
protocol but a lot of SMS commands are
not enabled so it was not a very big
success but also what we found is that
when you pass stuff normally you can do
a lot of error so we were interested in
sending bad information over SMS and
also you have a client running on the
GPS tracker in order to contact to reach
the management protocol so it means that
you have a passing of information also
some trackers supporting HTTP protocol
so they were in which very specific HTTP
server and do passing of text file this
one is very interesting because but it
clean no one try to analyze this kind of
security and if you can do a
man-in-the-middle you can send specific
HTTP packet and crashes GPS tracker or
so when during the reverse engineering
we didn't found anything about a few my
holidays which means that if you found a
remote code execution or something like
that basically you can't patch so you
put everything to the trash and you buy
a new GPS tracker then we also spoke a
bit about different clients so we also
have ios and android client at first we
used static analysis using jeddaks for
the android client so we add
authentication first time yes in order
to get access to API access so this one
we were very surprised to see that you
have authentication but the fact is when
you are authenticated then you have a
session the problem is that the session
is not linked to your GPS tracker which
means that you can fetch information
about all the GPS tracker so if an
attacker about GPS tracker you will get
validation and xeni can type information
about all the other GPS tracker also
everything is done over HTTP so we try
to found a vulnerability so if I want to
insecurity wrecked object references so
you can dump also database but it was
already found by another team a pair up
in the same time and they already are
each different from those and nothing
was done also we have access to specific
API website so this one as you can see
this is a super API web page explaining
explaining you everything so you can
craft your request and by default
activate hit debug so here you have the
definition or all the API
Viper's everything you can do which is
super cool so you can try to find good
stuff but the fact is that it was
already public so we didn't continue in
this way also you have access to the
website so basically the website it
allows you to
define a lot of functionalities so you
have live information about speed
location you can replay so if you have
access to also history of people it's
very interesting and also you have
geofence definition so geofence is
something you defined around gps tracker
and if the gps tracker is going outside
this area you will get alert so you will
get a left using SMS or push on
application this is a very good idea but
the problem is this functionality
basically can be linked with the online
so if the car is going outside the
geofence area you will come a shutdown
so it's not a good idea
we also found vulnerabilities allowing
anyone to different geo things around
your GPS tracker so it's not very good
implementation and also it blindly trust
GPS information which means that if you
are going out to the periphery and you
send a fake GPS information you may have
fun but you can do it because it's
illegal let's do a demo about your fans
so for example this one we have a
webpage so you can define geofence
around this test
test test at success yes so I defined a
very small geofence so we also have
another device hop this is also ours so
as you can see I was logged with my
account and I got access to another
account which is corresponding to our to
a GPS we are so we can define a new
geofence HIV HIV and giant I want to be
free yes and it works so basically we
define the geofence for another GPS
tracker this is a very good idea the
problem is the implementation is very
bad also authentication in fact in the
web on the website is a very bad
basically if you have the same number
the password will be also the serial
number or one two three four five six
and basically no one is changing as this
kind of password finally I didn't speak
about it but you also have access to a
history so it's very interesting this
vulnerability was existing two or three
months ago and you have access to a lot
of very interesting information you want
to speak about it yeah we can just for
example here we have found a GPS tracker
that was used in Netherland and tracker
was going to a specific ambassy every
morning and going back home every
evening so it shows that the device is
really is used also a lot in Europe we
found also some of them in France but as
it's started to be more offensive
research we decided to stop we try to
inform the vendor but it was really
difficult to get in touch with them we
don't know what they were doing but when
we released the paper three months ago
we have seen that what a part of the
infrastructure and this specific part is
not working anymore
so we don't see them patching things we
just see that it's broken so every
someone is playing with it or they just
don't have good software developers
and the question about DGP are we leave
that for experts but we have the feeling
that it's not really a compliant so just
to conclude this talk we had a lot of
fun we hope that you also had a lot
others we did the blackbox analysis of
devices the device are used everywhere
and they are still available accessible
so it seems that anyone using the device
should just remove it from his car the
cell IDs are also collected with the GPS
coordinate so all the manufacturer are
half today
the map of telecom infrastructure in all
over the world because we found the
tracker everywhere it's a very
interesting topic because for us it
becomes like a CTF style research where
we did reverse engineering network
analysis radio analysis and there is a
lot of work to be done and we hope that
people will also work on it and we thank
you very much for your attention and if
you have any question please let us know
[Applause]