[Applause]
thank you for coming welcome for Hawking
parents
my name is the gore Latino friend I
would like told you how EMS may destroy
it by a smart button a few words about
me I work at a dress lab company
I searched different security issues in
our product before that I spent time to
program industrial control system
program pill see also look security
questions for industrial control system
and took part for smart home project so
in my presentation I told her what is it
bemis introduction sir Kennex
EJ award it means what the organization
connects suggest to protect foci
cybersecurity attack and what happened
in reality before my talk I would love I
would like to ask some questions
maybe somebody recent the news when
hiker locks the door in the hotel in
Austria and nobody can enter or exit
from the hotel and his room or as in use
was a hiker shut down heater system in
the building in the winter
so let's what is it be my as Bemis its
building management system it is very
huge season to realize a to realize
function for automation usually it is
possible divided for several level on
the bottom wealth is a sensor and
actuators for and usually it's usually
some smart button or some move detector
or climatic station or something else
next level is automation level this
level get information from sensors and
send common to exchangers for example
when you set up the heating system
when I can't perform at six o'clock I
will work to 25 degree for because it
needs comfortably and the top level of
building management system its
management well for example big boss who
look like well his employer come to the
work or how big boss will pay for
electricity because power strategic are
collected and like a mix cover bottom -
well and I will talk about this
technology and his weakness and inner
abilities so what is the main objective
of building manual systems first ladies
reduce power consumption comfort
operation of different systems and we
don't forget that it's comfort for us
for visitors and usually to build
beautiful management system use a lot of
different technology the main
technologies botnet as a technology
useful field level sometimes may be
exceptions because we can buy a lot of
different sensors actuators a program
logical controller for clinics for
example and realize all system use
single technology but sometimes it may
be very very expensive clinics we can
omit for some few buildings like ISO
square
I'll mark Town International Airport or
wealth museum as I said for ant user
more clear understanding kids may be a
transplanted reader in your hotel when
we come after the conference or room
chair massage indoor presence the same
presence detection lot of other
different notes notes I mean sensors
actuators and something curls for
example ABB company provides interest in
solution for clinics hotel Hotel
automation
interesting because we can see that
transponder directly connect to clinics
network and this transponder may walk or
unlock the door for hotel room so now I
would like to talk more deeply about
clinics technology to reverse this
technology used the two main physical
media I can express the pair or connects
the peep or clinics net IPM also you my
friend
clinics RF and can expire line but this
to technology not so popular the speed
limited presented on this slide common
questions when the owner will make
automation it's the quantity of lot
which may present it for connects
network or CB network or other network
so connects at rest up to 15 areas in
each area maybe up to 15 lines and in
each line up to 2255 notes it's mean one
smart button it's one not one act water
it's another node and up to 255 knots
now I will like say a few words about
house not communicate in clinics network
you can see that the logical 0 presented
by changing voltage on the wine and
logical one is no changing on the line
and this is a common structure of
connects frame which sent for from one
node to another node so the first byte
is control but it's described as a
priority of the frame and shows this
telegram repeat or not the next two byte
is source address and next byte is
receiver address and the structure of
receiving address it depends from the
integrated solution
and intelligent moment there are a lot
of documentation it's good but sometimes
this documentation conflict itself
because you can see for one sentence
says if you won't use group address use
defeat one and a few sentence later you
can see that for group address valve it
should be set to 0 the next 8-bit is
describes range of connects connects the
P frame roads encounter and how to
detect this message group or in general
address but I spent a few cup of coffee
because when I use canis connection at
IP and clinics GP frame and communicate
where I pick it way there are some
interest and moment about this moment I
will take a little bit later
finally there are TP shy and ATC I field
which describes common commands in
connects frame and how to the text is a
frame is this frame comment or is this
call oh is this framed up datum and he
presented common a PCI comment and you
can see from and for me and for us I
hope it's very interesting that there
are some comment like read memory write
memory user message comment and as I
said usually also use connection at IP
to do that connects TP frame packet to
send message and sent via UDP Datagram
and he'll present at second control byte
this bite take me a lot of cup of coffee
coffee because in the documentation you
can see that this control by describe
the roach encounter and Blue Point you
doll address but when we use IP router
the second country
but added and we should select and parts
this bite not first bite now I will talk
about few words how to in eg award by
clinics few years ago my recommendation
of clinics organization was rise our
communication and don't worry because
the war is hidden and nobody can hug
your building but it's not good
recommendation and now the white paper
for security position became better and
there are some mechanism through which
provide security communication also a
good user guides how to security can it
not use private key and make protect
your systems and yet a software also
provides some security fusion like her
security IP communication however it's
ETL world and we live in reality and not
so good because when I try to add modern
IP Rooter to a test software I receive
this message that sorry you use IP
security communication but this device
don't support this future it's new
device which not support this device
which not support the security fusion
there are other pictures I hope you'll
recognize I hope you recognize this
print screen because it's shown on
senses and as a global search and we can
see that there are a lot of device which
connected to the to internet it's a lot
of different clinics device and we can
sometimes manipulate manage this device
so before look the attacks of face we
showed this
two questions first how to connect to
can exist where it is possible you
standalone device or dissing some
transceiver use smart like smart
transceiver or in my case I disagree on
serial based on analog elements the next
question is how to work with skin except
for how to configure so if you have
approximately $1,000 or less you can buy
a test software then you need press
button to switch in to program mode any
node and sometimes to do that you need
go to the attic of as a Boojum for press
button and after that you you can commit
configure lot and enjoy but I don't like
easy way and I try rights small tools
might rules allowed to connect to
connects network we are as a net usually
I pick a tree or also I use ESP 32
microcontrollers to connect via Ethernet
or Wi-Fi or connect directly to connects
twisted pair the mind future of this
tool is sniffing traffic scan not read
write and set key authorization well we
get answer for two common questions how
to connect and how to manage
so if attacker connect to clinics
twisted pair anywhere anywhere between
smart button in hotel room or climatic
station in outside secure perimeter he
can get basic information about lot he
can listen the traffic and also
understand what happens in the network
and no problem to realize the play
attack because just takes a telegram the
play and you have success so
we discovers the area or segment where
and intruders connected and after that
he can just manage any not because
protocol is simply and there are no any
security feature to send the Datagram
between the node and we hope that
integrators was good guys and make the
segmentation for for example for
different flow and the attacker finds
the IP route of each log it means that
this routers don't transfer the telegram
for as a network and we have
segmentation but we can use a common
treatment and we get all network
settings and look how the Schlueter lock
or unlock after that after that we use
comment right moment to change the
configuration we can change network
settings we can change his status and we
can unlock the rotor and discover other
signals after that we discover and may
manipulate change config and destroy
something or broke connections between
from example press button to switch
right and broke this connection models
are some nice fuchsia
during my research it is a DJ commands
user message as you remember the still
that says at the range of clinics the P
frame may up to 15 bars
however some routers allow transfer up
to 69 bytes
the next thing is that for some router
we need use pad part or patent because
when you send connects net IP frame to
clinics network and is this frame less
than 16 bytes the IP router don't
for this frame also you remember that I
see if you use a taste software you need
press button to change the configuration
in fact this action no need because just
use comment read memory of right memory
and you have success and interest in
future key authorizations the connect
standards says that this key used for
memory access protection however you can
set new key they're not confirmed that
yes I receive new key it's okay
but after reboot no no lawful happens
you can use all the key now let's look
how the attacker made prepares a
springboard to penetrate the corporate
network or operation technology Network
as you remember he connects anywhere for
clinics TP line broke the segmentation
and finds the router which may abrasion
way from field site I mean from smart
button or other and devices after that
intruder my updation well for other
router so I hope you have a questions
how it is possible to update field well
from field side just use a PC I comment
usual message with additional comment to
read filter and right from where
additional code presented on the slide
and how to get control the other device
to do that there are some difficult
steps like connector Ethernet run the
under update tool and just this way and
no check present northen checks northen
integrity check just updated inside say
pewter you may find there are a lot of
different chemical controller units from
atmega 128
some different arm microcontrollers this
IP router work under Linux also custom
server or not O's or some real-time OS
for embedded device and usually IP route
are you smart transceiver now I will
talk about a texture phase for
automation level for example the links
115 it is a program automation station
and this station will connect for a lot
of different protocols and technologies
which used to which use in VMs systems
on this right you can see that this
automation station a low manual control
micro SD card USB and Ethernet there are
free way to connect for this device set
of communication manual connect a manual
communication and as a net via HTTP FTP
Asajj and some other protocols so when
you connect in manual you can do
anything
operation we're done great silver change
stations to enable some future and to
this to do that you need also no
password know any other security
mechanism to changing but I think you
agree that more interest in remote
attack so the least 155 web interface
and when we open the browser and come to
this web interface we see the basic
information and for quest for quest user
we detect the number of film violations
what film where maybe downgrade also
which technology is used when we use
default credentials he presented on the
slide there are a lot of information
you can draw also anything update silver
change settings or do something curls
and don't forget that all this
communication across HTTP or FTP
protocol it is not secure and you can
see that all web interface have a lot of
different attraction phase like SQL
injection cross-site scripting and
something else so you can see that the
range of password may be from one single
to fifteen singles I hope you agree that
fifteen singles it's more good password
but I look for formal rules and I don't
find that iptables my blog brute-force
there are no fail to bound search words
so if you miss you may prefer brute
force password and you also have success
of this realization little bit step
aside I spent a few minutes and finds
this inter sent note which use a default
credential password and it's not only
this device there are a lot of device
which use default password and only
small information message that when you
use the full password the web interface
face
hey you use default password and
continue so more interesting is a field
where for this automation server this
server you might download from official
website it's at the first point of you
have magic extension like the dot DL but
inside this magic extensions there are a
lot of Debian package with some package
from high tech and
unfortunately there are a lot old old
package trees now ability for for this
device more oh I look for links a 1091
file it's one of general binary file and
we can see that this file not stupid and
there are a lot of information and stack
may be executed
also if you forget oh not forget if you
lose the documentation don't worry
because the silver can't contain
hard-coded credentials like admin and
only tech for use this default password
and you never lose this information
because it's hard-coded in the film
we're also interest and function call it
Phil we're update from file it's good
because this function a lotto operation
we're fix some bug but inside these
functions there are no any check just
check that there are additional spaced
update and update system well I think
you look the slide and get smile because
also in firmware was discovered some
private key and as I see the same
private key used for different versions
of film and for intellect ceiling I
suppose it's the same private key used
for different devices also I look for
more modern automation station call it
links 153 but but but the situation is
yes of course some new specific package
for links 153 and a lot of old package
from the preview generation of this
automation station in conclusions for
additional information for
okay next security you can read and look
for this presentation from for example
for Jose Molina he describes that when
he reaches the luxury hotel he can
manage his lash in Nate ball truth
because connects network and public
Wi-Fi it's the same network the next
paper describers extended security for
clinics but main idea of the security at
some additional field for security enter
the other presentation which describes
some security issue for ZigBee and
clinics as a conclusion unfortunately
connects network weakness and
vulnerability because it is possible
dos attack operation where from field
site manage any node and if we look for
automation station for from low-tech its
use old package and use non secure
communication protocols however not so
bad because the white paper
security become more body better by step
by step by step and now it's more better
than few years ago and some vendors try
realize this security fuschia try spend
some time for security issue in clinics
finally I would like to say the great
rate for Dmitry Victor of Santa Monica
and my friends of keys thank you for
that for your attention and I am ready
for questions
you