so yeah we've got interns 45 minutes
welcome on my presentation as you can
see poor village a quite a complex last
name and I'm from Poland just a couple
of words to mentioned do you want
something you might come over no it's
good okay great great perfect thank you
yeah so as you can see I'm the CEO of
secure and the company that I started
almost 11 years ago right now just to
give you a couple of words we are
editing between four locations Poland
Dubai New York and Switzerland and we
are a group of like 40 people out there
and we do basically all the geeky stuff
that I guess you guys do the same which
is cyber security that's why we're
meeting up over here
I do have 15 years of experience in the
field are playing with cyber security
this is my hope being my life my passion
and together with my team we are doing a
cyber security research into various
fields we've written over 200 hacking
tools that we share for free that we use
normally for the pen tests but why not
sharing that's why you're also here so
this is pretty much our background now
just a couple of words yes so today's
presentation it's gonna be fun one of
the most difficult subjects in
cybersecurity I would say which is a
data protection API and data protection
API ng so different ways how operating
system protects our information and let
me tell you something that I personally
believe in and I think so is that this
is a subject that I really think each of
us working in cyber security should know
at least well because this is how our
data is protected in the operating
system so that's what we're going to be
talking about yeah
so difficult subject but absolutely
important now why do we have DP API and
dpi apap ing we're going to learn the
prison
but ng stands for new generation and
that's something that basically allows
us to encrypt data in a little bit
different way we could think new
generation means kind of better but not
necessarily really because DP API
classic so the regular one it's
something that operating system uses
anyway so this is basically what we're
going to be talking about today
now few words basically about myself if
we haven't met before I
you probably notice that I really like
to talk so I talk about different things
all the time including cybersecurity and
I also have a chance to speak at other
conferences quite recently I was rated
number one speaker at blackhat in Asia
which I mean it's okay I'm happy but it
doesn't really matter at the end as long
as there is something useful for you
guys yeah so as simple as this so also
things like ignite things like Reber say
in San Francisco so our team and myself
we really like to share knowledge about
what we do so let me tell you a little
bit about the research regarding data
protection API because as far as we know
we are the first team out there that
fully reverse engineered data protection
API it took us over two years to do it
but research in general around data
protection API it's a hell so basically
in Windows putting this in a very
shortened version you don't have that
many standards if it's about how do you
actually approach data to encrypt it so
if you go if you have to go through a
bunch of levels and it's like 20 levels
to go through you're wondering what kind
of algorithm was used over there yes so
this one is this this moment is that
this is that this is this so you have to
figure out things all the time
by all means and that's why it's a
little bit painful this is something by
the way that reminds me my vacation when
I was in Siberia and I was just
traveling around you know this is one of
these places that you want to go to
because there's like sometimes no mobile
arrange so for IT people that sometimes
perfect because we are all the time
connected so there's this moment when
you're gonna get disconnected and that's
the place and I was having breakfast in
a
in places yes so there's like let the
restaurant here someone's house over
there this place here and I speak a
little Russian too but unfortunately
every single time when I was like asking
for something during the breakfast can i
police have scrambled eggs I was just
getting a sausage and I was asking for
example for whatever our dumplings and I
was getting scrambled eggs so I
literally could not and that started to
become funny I literally could not get
for the breakfast what I wanted so there
was his restaurant when I get in or like
the place little place and in a menu
there was a cheese sandwich now
how wrong can you go about the cheese
sandwich you can't right it's a slice of
bread and the cheese I was like score
I'm gonna order the simplest position in
a menu to make sure that I'm gonna be
successful finally in ordering my
breakfast so when I asked for the cheese
sandwich I got that and like they they
kept the promise yeah this is the cheese
sandwich but sometimes it's really
disappointing and what I'm saying is
that data protection API it's a dad kind
of a subject so there's always a
solution there's always a hope that
you're gonna get a good thing but the RO
through it it's very very painful yeah
so forgive me for the presentation but
we're gonna focus on the hard core stuff
so no jokes anymore and we are just
purely learning what DP API is about
when you leave this room
I really hope and I hope that this is
your goal too that you will know more
about the DP API that's my goal okay so
just a few words Windows uses the
following algorithms of course it uses
more but when you do the research around
cryptography that's more or less what
you are seeing so when you kind of
define that scope you can predict that
people who are writing the code on the
other side they can pretty much use one
of these algorithms out there so that's
kind of nice because that narrows in a
certain sense what you were actually
dealing with and whenever we are
thinking about the data protection API
what we will need to discuss is what is
it in it for real in Windows yeah so the
day the prediction API it's a API in
Windows that allows you to protect your
data in place when I
you are saving it through various
applications or by using the operating
system yeah so basically whenever you
are thinking about for example saving
your password in Outlook or saving
password through the browser generically
saying or you are thinking about how
your private keys are protected this is
exactly where the data protection API
comes to place and of course question is
is this a safe mechanism and beta
protection API in general is delivered
in three places three things one system
DP API second local user dpi PI and
third domain user DP API because for the
domain users they PAPR is done in a
little bit different way so whenever we
are thinking of course about that
question is how do we protect these
secrets so we already know what are the
secrets it could be an Outlook password
password stored in a browser do you guys
by the way we cool software from new to
soft yeah ok some of you who does please
put your hands up I need to know okay
like seriously ten percent or you didn't
have a breakfast or something okay
yourself please check it out yeah so
near soft is a software that allows you
to basically extract the password from
the browser and if or Outlook etc Wi-Fi
please check it out
and when you run it as you then they
give you your password let me start with
this so that we are basically at the
same page so we're learning let's do it
so this is basically Windows 10 and
eventually when we get into different
tools that I have over here
I got a software called Chrome pass and
this is near soft so this is what I
wanted to show you if you want to
recover your password for example
because you stored it somewhere in the
operating system this is the software
that will allow you to learn that
particular password yeah so Krampus
allows me to extract information from
the Google Chrome yeah so we've got
Freddy Krueger password for LinkedIn
password password yam so basically what
it says is that Freddy stored password
in Chrome and every single time Freddy
enters LinkedIn for the East logged on
yet so this is the setup now whenever
we are thinking about the protection for
that what is absolutely important is the
differentiation in between as we
mentioned local user and the domain user
and this is something that we're going
to be talking about one principle here
is very straightforward is that this is
a secret no doubt and that's secret it's
gonna be yours it's gonna be someone
else this is something that allows you
this secret allows you of course to log
on to LinkedIn but at the same time what
are the preconditions to reach this
secret answer is you need to be you so
when you log on and you are logged on in
Windows and you open Chrome as you
that's the precondition to reach your
secret even though it sounds very
obvious right now that's what we have to
talk about let me give you an example
from two weeks ago I was in us during
the penetration test for one of our
customers and I managed to become a guy
not a domain admin yet but to add to be
a guy who is in person a domain admin so
I had access to his account regular
account not being a domain admin yet and
I was wondering maybe he's connecting
the roles somehow so when I was him I
started to run different types of for
example news of tools on his account and
one of the funny facts is that I was
able to extract different passwords that
he actually saved in Chrome including a
password to the Victoria's Secret
account of his girlfriend yeah so almost
like I mean I mean no we could be
thinking that it's maybe not very
ethical but yeah ok we can leave this
discussion for later yeah so anyway and
there were also some different passwords
of whatever services he was using in the
infrastructures I'm like score I don't
have to be a domain admin I'm just gonna
use these passwords to jump fodder so
let me explain you guys different things
that are related with the data
protection API and basically how does it
work so what we're gonna do right now
I'm gonna actually explain one simple
thing which is related with the data
protection API and how do we actually
reach our secrets and that's gonna be
quite interesting because I'm not very
good at painting things but
we're gonna actually leverage it this
way so let me whiten it at and we're
gonna do a little bit of a picture about
how the domain user reaches its secrets
so the domain user does it in a
following way
domain user logs on this one is going to
be easy of course yes so user logs on of
the username and the password what we've
got in a simple words is that password
is converted to the md4 because use
windows uses md4 so the password hajj
eventually we're verifying if we can log
on to the domain yeah okay user logged
on fine what's happening next is that if
the user has a password stored in a
browser let's call it a secret over here
then what's happening is that that
passwords hash it's and that's crucial
protecting master key that is stored in
the master key container and that master
key is protecting a secret so simple
conclusion is that our secrets are
dependent on the strength of our
password and the security of our account
so whoever's gonna be you will have
access to any of the secrets that you
guys possess including by the way and
that's so important to say all the
applications that you run and the
question is do you trust all your apps
that you run on your account whatever
that will be 7-zip WinRAR whatever that
is yet do you trust the people that
wrote these ups because you run them on
the account that means that these apps
are able to get access to all of you the
other passwords that you have ever
stored in your profile okay now another
part is and this is interesting there's
another master key in the same master
key container so let's call it 1 and K
let's call it two master key 1 is
exactly the same as master key too but
master key too it's encrypted with the
public key of the domain now this is
where the fun begins by the way
we work in a hundred thousand people's
organizations everybody of course is
like a domain user we all have account
in a domain we kind of sometimes store
our secrets we have old look at each of
us as old look we've got Facebook
account accounts LinkedIn and so on and
we save all these secrets in our local
browser yeah we may be like oh I don't
do it I use keep us okay then you will
not be the one but then the rests are
gonna be and this is really the point
over here so here is the question every
single secret that we have its encrypted
with the public key of the domain which
is by the way the same four hundred
thousand people I'll prove it to you in
a second what's the threat over here
what's the question to be asked come on
guys question is where's the private key
right who has access to the private key
if you're gonna have access to the
private key then basically you have
passwords of every single employee in
this organization let's talk about it
and let's demonstrate it so how does it
work we're gonna leverage over here a
certain scenario that I would like to
show you and that scenario is gonna
touch based on the various aspects of DP
API so let's let me explain that it's
gonna be super clear but let's make sure
that we are on the same page so let me
show you one thing first I'm gonna lock
the desktop you can see that I am a
domain user here yeah so I'm gonna log
on Freddie and let me show you the
password password is password yeah and
I'm logging on and that's done yeah so
I'm basically logging on to the domain
not a big deal
now I can see the password everything is
fine
question is where this password is
actually stored where this password is
stored but we're gonna talk about it in
a moment but this password is stored
somewhere in a browser data and so on
and in the hackers mind we will need to
get there and get this data this data
will be encrypted with our master key
eventually and then master key is
encrypted with our password harsh or the
public key of the domain so what I would
like
so today is how to get this private key
of the domain and how you are able to
decrypt every single secret of everybody
that moves within your organization yeah
so let's do it with this positive accent
we're gonna reboot this machine with a
one simple reason because I would like
to show you indeed in this scenario that
our secrets depend on our hash let me
explain that so first of all what we're
gonna do we're gonna reboot this machine
we could be thinking well BitLocker
could help it yes we can do this
demonstration online and offline so for
this BitLocker could help but for the
other scenario with a dpi API it
couldn't yeah so let's let's don't don't
look at this from this perspective now
whenever we've got our Windows box over
here what I would like to do I would
like to change here cache logon data and
cache logon data we're gonna do command
prompt let me just increase the font
quickly here we go
font Bank we got it cache logon data is
something that we're gonna use to log on
when the domain controller is not
available what do I do I want to show
you this because if we're gonna log on
to the system by leveraging cache logon
data we can play with the password so
we're gonna eventually log on with a
different password because I will
overwrite cache logon data so that when
originally user logs on user enters a
password that I have pre generated here
and the cache logon data it's a value in
the registry sometimes we call it crash
credentials but these are not
credentials at all we cannot look gone
with them we can only compare with them
yeah so here we go let's dig in
so in order to be able to override cache
to logon data what I'm gonna use and the
tool that how to present you know this
is a mimic us but this is our secure
edition here we go
where are we going to be overriding the
cache logon data by setting the default
password that is hard-coded in a tool
which is called mimikatz so let's do it
and let's say dump cache and we're going
to overwrite cache logon data based on
windows
system32 config and then system and let
me explain why system in a second system
32 config security and we're gonna do
slash kiwi to override cache logon data
now why am i recalling over here system
and security because when we look at the
cache logon data before we press enter
small explanation is needed within the
cache logon data it looks like this so
cache Logan data is stored in the
registry in the security hive by default
it's 10 values and that hive in general
or any type of something that we call
system secrets they are encrypted
indirectly with the boot key and boot
key is stored with that system hive so
this is why we are actually referring to
the system and security in one command
over here so we've got a LSA dump cache
the windows system for the two convicts
system and security slash key we enter
yeah so we are done fantastic so we have
just over eaten cache logon data for
every single user that is in this box
now just to log on with a different
password which has been generated with
the cache logon data I'm gonna
disconnect this machine from the network
because I will need to log on with the
cache logon data yes so I'm gonna
introduce the password that I already
know in order to compare with the cache
logon data of in the registry bring it
on so we can just cancel this continue
and reboot in the meantime while we are
rebooting let me show you how cache
logon data looks like first of all in
the registry when we do analyze it it
looks like this cache local data has a
name that name is called ms DCC - and
msec - is generated out of the function
that you guys about know because if you
use key pass last pass key volt etc you
are actually using this function for
your data protection this is called
pbkdf2 while keep us for example uses
schwa 512 though for example in Windows
for the cache logon data the
schwa one we could criticize on that but
to be absolutely sincere with you I'm
not working for Microsoft so hopefully
you know that this is not that bad yes
so eventually the complexity of this is
good enough for us to be trusting the
solution today yeah
so cache logon data it's comfort comfort
for us and don't be afraid to use it now
whenever we are thinking about our box
over here so let me just simply
reconnect because we supposed to boot
this machine already and this is this
one now what I'm gonna do I'm gonna log
on Freddy Krueger once again with the
password password so if you remember
this is what we've been using over here
and this password is incorrect because
right now we are comparing with the
cache log on data pre-dinner ated value
in the registry so we're gonna do Mima
cards like this here we go
and this is basically what we are
comparing with so what's happening over
here over here right now when we log on
we're taking this value we are
calculating md4 on the top of that we
are joining it with the username on the
top of that we are calculating md4 back
again and we take this value which we
called ECC one by the way we compare we
take it together with the H Maxwell one
we take a user name we do 10240
iterations on 16 blocks and that's how
you look on easy right anyway so we
logged on and eventually what is next is
do I have access to my secrets and if I
do have then that will be really sad but
data protection API as we already
explained relies on our passwords harsh
that's mk1 master key 1 and because our
password hash is different right now I'm
not able to get access to my secrets
second part oh so password is empty
right second part is don't forget we've
got a master key to that is encrypted
with the public key of the domain this
one we're gonna focus on in a moment now
please have a look because this is
really cool this we don't have a
password so we're like man
as the hacker what am I supposed to do
my job right now is to find all these
different secrets that are stored in
your windows and eventually figure out
how to decrypt those so let's focus on
this now question is where do we have
secrets where do we have secrets so
let's do it like this as a regular user
I'm gonna start a common prompt you
don't need to be privileged for that and
what are we gonna do over here let's get
into the secret tools let's go to the DP
API and we've got a very simple tool
that I really like and this one is
called CQ DP API blob searcher and CQ DP
API blob searcher it's a tool that
allows you to search through workstation
server and so on for every possible
secret that you might ever store so
question is do I have any secrets in my
laptop sometimes we may be thinking oh
I'm not serving passwords in a browser
I'm every single time I open outlook i
log on etc I don't save any passwords
any secrets well figure it out you can
do it with this tool so this tool allows
us to specify a directory to be searched
so slash D and we're gonna refer to I'm
gonna shorten it a little bit users
Freddy Krueger updater loco Google
because we are searching for secrets in
Chrome yes so let's just give it a
direct path more or less Mullis it
doesn't have to be direct but we're
gonna do it - air slash error which is
recursively and my and - or / o to give
it a folder where we're going to be
doing the output of the secrets now the
next part I'm gonna do to make it a
little bit more convenient DP API dot
txt we're gonna stream the whole output
to the file so that you guys can see
what we are actually dealing with right
that was quite quick because we don't
have that many secrets ah yeah that's we
can ignore this it's not important now
anyway so we've got this one I haven't
disconnected from the network so here
you can see that we've got one simple
thing we've got a secret stored in
cookies of Google so Google Chrome user
data devote cookies now this
masterkey guiit is p55 let's mind that
p55
it starts with it and that is most
probably the master key that is
protecting our secrets it's a good
knowledge to have now what I don't like
and this is just my personal comment
here is that chrome use chuan and Triple
DES to encrypt my secret
that's not very convenient I mean I
don't know how you feel about it but I
feel bad
yeah but anyway yeah you will do what
you want with this knowledge moving
forward b55 it's something that we will
need to focus on okay so let's see let's
see what I'm gonna do I'm gonna do start
dot let's just open up the windows when
we're gonna dig in into that % up data
percent in the following path guys we're
gonna go to that percent update the
percent which is Freddie up data roaming
we're gonna go to Microsoft protect Sid
and this it's a set of your master keys
that you all use let me put it this way
each of you sitting here
if you're using Windows 100% you've got
a key over there at least one yeah so
check it out if you want to do someone a
bad joke you go there and delete them
all and then it means that's the other
person will not be able to use the
secret storage every single place this
person will we need to reload on yeah I
consider it as a good joke bad way but
anyway let's move forward so if we move
forward we've got this so be 55 be 55 I
mark this key over here like this
so that I don't have to search for it
for a long time but this is this guy
that we will have to get access to
because this master key encrypts our
Google Chrome stored in the Google
Chrome password and I'm like come on I
don't know the users passwords users
hash I want to get access to this key so
how do we do it and this is where the
party begins because we will need to get
into a domain controller and search for
the key now we could be again thinking
well no this isn't
where we have to engage a domain
controller really think about it
differently if someone is a domain admin
in your organization that's what this
person can do so hackers it's like a
second problem over here yeah that's a B
what always makes me think is that if
someone if you do the pen test or if
someone does the pentas for you and this
person becomes a domain admin this is a
big trust relationship that means that
this person can potentially extract the
private key like this and get access to
all of the secrets of your
organization's let's have a look this
this one's gonna be super easy because
we've written it this tall it took a
while again but this tool it's at the
end so simple to be used so with that CQ
else's secrets dumper we do file and we
do export it pfx let me just put the dot
here pfx enter and this exported pfx
this is nothing but a private key of
your whole domain it's really something
that if you're on a bad site you would
like to have so if we do import it we
don't have to by the way but I just want
to show you how it looks like next next
next next next xx password is secure our
company name next next next ok and then
cert MGR dot MSC enter we go to the
personal and then certificates and then
we can see this not available cute name
certificate which represents us the
certificate that has been issued to
nobody by nobody
by the way it's valid only for one year
can we renew it no can we fix this no
can we no okay so this is not something
that you can fix but you can monitor
domain controller and make sure that
none of the code that you don't know is
executed only domain controller
let's summarize it in a moment yes
because it's not only that protection
method which we can apply and it's not
the only problem that we are having over
here so this has been only issued for a
year so if your domain is like whatever
from 2000 and
eight this is the how old is your
certificate over here okay
and having this allows you to get access
to the secrets of everybody else let's
have a look into this scenario we're
going to start a common prompt as a user
back again on Windows 10 I'm back on
Windows 10 right now so we have we've
got this exported pfx I already copied
this to this machine so that we don't
have to do it now let me show you we're
gonna get into the C key tools we're
gonna get to the DP API now just to keep
it super clear in order to be able to
get access to our secrets now we have to
take this particular master key this b55
decrypt it with the private key that we
grabbed from the domain and encrypted
back with our current password hash yeah
so this is the procedure quite
straightforward because when I'm logged
on and I want to on-the-fly being able
to get access to my secrets I have to
have this master keys encrypted with my
current users password hash let's have a
look so let's do it we're gonna do it
like this first of all seek your harsh
calc and our current password is
mimikatz and let's just do one and mimi
cuts over here this is basically the md4
of our images over here yeah I'm so of
our string so I'm gonna copy this now
what we're gonna do we're gonna use over
here seek your master key ID this is our
signature tool from our team and seek
your master key ID allows us to do the
following first of all we're gonna
specify we're gonna and we're gonna
decrypt the master keys with the P
effects that we already have from the DC
now new hash we're gonna encrypt it back
again with our current password hush and
file I don't know yet but let's have a
look over here we're gonna be
technically getting access to it by
giving a puff so shift right click copy
as puff in the command so here we just
do it like this file Bank now what
happens when I press enter
please have a look yeah there is
basically this new key created ad
modified so what we will need to do is
to replace this so we do rename and
underscore good like this and we take
this ad modified and we replace it and
basically our goal is going to be to
give one more thing over here so this is
good
you can change it yep okay fine and our
goal is gonna be to one build one more
thing which is giving an attribute of a
system and hidden because otherwise data
prediction API will not treat it
properly this is a generic statement but
it's better to do it okay now what we're
gonna do now well basically what I'm
looking for it's a Krampus because we
have just replaced our master key we've
decrypted it and re-encrypted it back
again have a look
f5 I get a password right what's the
conclusion here there are many actually
and not over all of them are positive
this represents the situation when
someone has access to the domain
controller so if this person has access
to domain controller and has been
intentions this person can decrypt every
single passwords every single person's
password now I really like to give my
favorite scenario we were also
discussing this scenario of the guys on
a training that we were running before
the conference this is basically the
scenario with imagine one thing if you
would be a bad admin it might be not to
you about someone else yeah if someone's
gonna be a bad admin your infrastructure
this person will pick this private key
and grab it copy profiles from the file
server or whatever of the users or
basically copy profiles of several users
loot log on to Facebook or LinkedIn or
whatever you want with these people's
password and accuse you of a sexual
harassment that sounds bad right
so there is employee this says that says
the other one says that you are not
honest the other one says that they are
working in a hostile environment and
it's your company and you didn't do
anything that's bad so this is how you
can put the company down by just having
an access like this now okay let's put
it aside how can we protect ourselves we
can protect ourselves in a various ways
way number one is privileged access
management so making sure that domain
admins they don't there they're not
humans yeah so basically that these are
the accounts that are logging on only
don't the domain controllers we should
we even call them domain controller
admins yeah because that's where they
should be that's a B you need to make
sure that whoever has access to backup
in general in your organisation doesn't
have access maybe to the backup of the d
c-- so any members of the backup
operators group it could be a service
that you are using in the organisation
and someone let me show you something in
a moment so let's keep it assigned it
could be a backup service another one is
whoever has access to the privilege of
replicating directory changes all this
is something guys that you hundred
percent need to check and what we are
talking about is the following yes so
when we've got a domain let's have a
look yeah we're gonna do it like this
we've got Active Directory users and
computers and this is basically what we
are over here referring to yeah so
replicating directory changes all yeah
and another part number two number four
is if you've got a read only domain
controller you need to make sure who is
looking on over there because if there
is a domain admin logging on for example
this person can also pull out on the
read-only DC the private key that is
stored within the domain so read only
the domain original domain controller
requires additional additional
protection over here so these are the
four things to have a look at now data
protection API system also comes to
place let me close the circle of the
problem over here so
when we do have a backup software
question is what kind of privileges this
software has because what I would like
to show you is the following yeah we're
gonna get over here to the services.msc
and assuming that you've got some kind
of a backup software it could be
anything I'm just gonna take this
service whatever so we could do it this
way and I'm gonna just type here a
username here we go let's do it let's do
it this is a simple thing yeah so we've
got a pj service running on some kind of
a user so that could be a backup
software your backup running on the
service account which is a backup
software so long story short what we're
gonna do over here is what we can do is
let's get into the tools folder I'm
gonna use PS exec we have also our own
tool for that it's called CQ impersonate
whatever works
not this one know that but exe so we are
starting the console as a local system
because system secrets that are also
related with a DP API are managed by the
local system therefore we have to get
into tools and run CQ Secrets dumper
this is a free tool available also in
our blog you can guys download it this
is one of our favorite tools we just
specify the service here and then we
specify pj service and then of course
password comes out yeah now also to
connect the problem we've got this
service account do we make sure that the
service account can only log on as a
service in our systems
if yes awesome but in most organizations
that we do pen test that's not the case
so if I do steal this password I can log
on with this account somewhere else
interactively and then jump jump to the
lateral movement maybe at the vent at
the end manage to do the backup of the
private keys from the DC that we were
mentioning yes so that's another another
scenario that it's a little longer but
not impossible
yeah so this is something that basically
we wanted to discuss now the next
question of the universe is okay that's
data protection API classic what about
data protection API and
isn't it better well let me put it this
way it's different it's completely
different because it relies on a
different mechanisms and different ways
of communication with the domain
controller leveraging the KDS root key
so completely different concept of that
were in comparison to the classic DP API
but at the end it's not that often lis
used in the operating system so where do
you use it use in use it in asp net core
you use it in BitLocker for example sit
protected the drives you use it for
example within the GM SAS use it as well
for example with the seat protected pfx
files and this is something that I would
like to show you at the end today
because this is a very good method as
well to protect a pfx files which how do
we manage passwords to pfx it's such an
old-school type of file yeah we just
specify the password and that's it
but since Windows Server 2012 r2 you are
able to rely protection of the pfx file
on your own account on your SID
through DP API and G let me show you how
we can do it this is actually quite easy
so what we're gonna do right now is I'm
gonna pull out a box like this and this
is who is logged on over here yeah we so
we can check we can see we are Freddie
yeah so what can we do we can do cert
MGR dot MSC and we can do export our pfx
so I got some kind of a certificate I
can do all tasks export and then we can
go next and then we have a possibility
to export the private key by the way
even if you don't have a possibility to
export a private key
that's not true because you can always
grab it from the operating systems
memory so this is quite easy me me cut
in PowerShell can do it so this is this
is funny block over here but anyway yes
export the private key next and then the
next and here is the thing you've got
over here group or users so we can
specify if ready or we can specify the
password in a classic way we always
specify password but
what we can do we can export that
certificate that pfx to be imported by
these people here so you specify these
guys sit next next and you save it in a
file yeah so I already have a file like
this this is this one Blizzard so if I
open it as I as myself I can go next and
this is really funny by the way this
file has been protected this way there
is kind of a password because this is a
very old-school way oh this is a very
old-school file and old-school way of
protecting it and we can always display
this password and this one is called IX
fgt and so on this is the automatically
generated password which is protected by
the state protection by the DP API and G
so at the end file it's still the same
type of an old-school file but it's a
really better way of managing it now
question of the universe is how can I
steal this password so if I see these P
effects because someone protected it in
this way I want to get access to this P
of X is there a way to do it an answer
is of course because if there is
something that relies on a domain from
that security perspective then since we
have access to the domain we will be
able to get access to this pfx password
now let me show you how can we do it so
I'm gonna leave this for the moment open
like this so that you can compare that
this is actually at the ends the same
file what do we need to have in order to
get access to this pfx password and
answer is KD is root key so the
passwords that the KD has a Kerberos key
the Kerberos data that is extracted from
entity as Det and in order to be able to
extract it we need as well a boot key
because entities do this both like some
for example realize it's security on the
boot key so how do we extract the boot
key and what's the concept behind it
answer is very straightforward we do it
like this I already have a copy of
entities that did made within the domain
yeah so let me get into my tools so
I'm able to at the end extract that
particular data what do I need to
extract data from entities that did a
boot key so let me show you how to grab
the boot Kieffer's we grabbed the boot
key in the following way this is easy
yeah so we take this to main controller
or entities that did or or system on
that domain controller and we do it like
this
CQ secrets dumper so I guess you already
know the tools from the service accounts
password but this time we're gonna use
it with a different functionality that's
the boot key like this and this is
basically the string that I'm gonna be
using over here that's simple by the way
this is the boot key yeah sure so we got
it now over here we're gonna be working
on ant ideas with it so let's do it
so we're gonna get so let me get into
the tools and we're gonna get into the C
key tools C Q underscore tools here we
go fantastic and then we're gonna get
into the extraction of the data from
entities to date so for that I'm gonna
use the tool CQ NTDs DT decrypter by the
way you need to admit that our names of
the tool are awful it's so hard to
remember them we'd we also have problems
with this but we have so many of them
that we decided to put them in a
descriptive way so that everybody knows
when you look at the name even though
it's long what does it do yeah so here
we go this one is to decrypt the content
of aunt Edie's door did so we're gonna
do it like this boot key bang and then
file and then I got aunt IDs dude it
over here and then we can export hashes
if you want out file hashes dot txt from
that aunt idea so did but what is
important for us is one more thing over
here which is related with the KDS
root key and KD s dot bin where we're
gonna be extracting the kerberos root
key so we have extracted this already
and in the big organization you can
expect like two three four keys like
this and from one of these keys for
example there is a password generated
for the group managed service account so
100%
you have it yeah so we're gonna take
this one even though I know I have three
of them because I know that this is the
one that I will need to use for the
decryption I just tested all of them
literally and then this one works yeah
here we go so enter and then we're gonna
get into the tools no not this this
let's just get there here we go
and we're gonna do CQ d PAP RI ng pfx
decrypter easy to remember name pfx and
we're gonna use this file that we were
producing over there so there is this
Blizzard pfx and one more thing we're
gonna specify is the master which is
actually our cadiz root key done now
enter simple thing you've got the
password IX f GT IX f GT and if we do
have a look at what we got underneath
over here it's basically IX f GT so this
is how you can access the P effects file
which were sit protected yeah now what's
the conclusion same conclusion as we
discussed sometimes comfort it's more
important yeah so this is very
convenient way of managing pfx files
yeah it's just like you don't even have
to remember these passwords because you
are who you are you double click you
could access to the P of X but if you
have a domain admin or domain that is in
protected that is not protected well
then this can violate so many different
things so that logically more things to
rely on it the more than can be affected
that's why yet another obvious
conclusion here we have to protect our
domain domain controller we all know
that but yet this is a very important
reason for doing it so this is basically
data protected data prediction API and
data protection API and G that we have
discussed now one more last thing if you
don't mind to show you a little bit of a
cherry on everything yes so I really
like to finish with
think cool at least I think so so let's
have a look so what do we have over here
so this is basically keep us now I am
not knowing the password for the key
pass of the user that is out there I
will try to type in secure so that we're
gonna be using it and if I do click OK
it says the password is wrong so I'm
like hmmm how am I supposed to get
access to the users keep us so either
you're gonna brute-force the password if
the user is protecting the keep us with
the password or if the user is relying
keep us on a data protection API this
time we can always learn that by getting
into the key pass architecture let me
just cancel it no and checking out
protected user key this is what is in
the users profile and that's for real
the key that protects the keep us and
what you protect it's not the key pass
database but it's this key right so you
encrypt this key with whatever method
you provide I can tell by the way how it
looks how it starts over here but this
is a data protection API blob so I'm
like perfect by having access to the
domain of the user what can we do we can
technically decrypt s keep us by getting
access to the users data let's do it you
have you can be anybody who wants to I'm
actually logged on over here as
admission but it doesn't matter because
we have access to the users data so let
me show you something what we're gonna
do over here let me copy this I got over
here access to the master key of the
user we already discussed this so master
key of the user has been decrypted with
the private key from the domain this is
this stage I will not do this demo once
again cuz I'm gonna be repeating myself
yes so we have decrypted the private key
the master key with the private key of
the domain done that's where we start
now what do we do next we go to the
tools tools those tools and over here
we've got two tools one
CQG pap I keep as DVD decrypter and with
this tool we are learning what's the
entropy of keep us keep us users entropy
it's all the same but it's there so it's
kind of easy but the second thing we're
gonna need is the c q DP api blob the
krypter and this guy takes two
parameters master entropy and blob three
parameters so we're gonna do it like
this master and i have the master of the
user here we're gonna do our blob blah
blah blah blah and I have the blob of
the user to which is him see analysis
and this one is the protected user key
Ben
yep and another one is in this case
entropy which we're gonna get to so I'm
gonna go a little bit up because the
previous tool displayed it so we're
gonna just copy that very in details we
got it
we go next and entropy bank enter good
so this gives us a decrypted data
decrypted protected user kibun which is
a directly a key protecting our key path
database we're almost there so we're
gonna do it like this see Q and then all
these names DPA PRI key pass DVD
decrypter and this takes two parameters
K and F so we're gonna do okay which is
the key that we have decrypted bang and
F which is simply simply the C Q base
that we are using over here for the key
pass so now what's happening we are
getting access to this particular key
pass database and decrypting it route to
the C Q base file and this file by the
way it's the one that we can enter and
if you put here a secure password so
again our team's name you're getting
access to someone's keep us right so I'm
always like confuse a little bit that in
a corporation's the big organizations
advanced there's some advice use keep us
use keep us great but people don't know
if they're not working IT how to use
keep us the most pleasant thing for them
and how to use keep us would be too to
rely keep us actually on the windows
logon so this even the worse because all
of the passwords will be in one place
you don't have to use all these tools
together passwords and secrets from all
the locations you can be like okay I'm
gonna just go keep us and go to keep us
because this is how IT advise them yeah
so if you want to do or implement the
password management in organizations
that is also something that has to be
taken into consideration
I'm not saying keep us it's bad keep us
it's very good it's just the way how
sometimes we see that it's used it's not
very secure because it relies on um
factors that are not dependent on us but
dependent on someone else out there and
insecurity there's a one in popular
world and that word is trust the less we
have opportunities to trust in cyber
security the better however said that
sounds so with this positive accent guys
just to give you the summary this is our
DP API toolkit if you want to basically
have access to the toolkit you just need
to get into our blog this is where we
share our tools summarizing your
computer your DP API system is a safe as
of an axis or the privileged account
your personal data is as safe as your
password is or domain security is
anything else requires additional
monitoring additional management and by
knowing how data protection works we are
able to pick a good way of protecting
our data and organization and this is
what I hope that you will tell you at
the end
maybe after listening to this
presentation maybe reading more about it
it's a very difficult subject by the way
you will not find that many information
in the internet so if you guys have any
questions absolutely let us know
you can also take a challenge
participate in a quiz you don't need to
register we like to have fun in
cybersecurity
we always think with our team that
sharing is caring so we share our tools
you can always like learn more we have
some videos over there so check it out
and at the end if you have any questions
then of course please ask them in the
applications that you guys have access
to so thanks a lot from my side thank
you for being here thank you for
listening and I'm waiting for the
questions to appear on the board thank
you so much
[Applause]