okay so I'm delighted and very excited
to be here today for two reasons firstly
this is the first time speaking of hack
in Paris so I'd like to thank the
hacking paris team for the opportunity
today and secondly I'm going to be
discussing a for the opportunity he's
demonstrated and also share with you for
the first time here today I knew when
does the defence evasion technique which
has been discovered by McAfee ATR and
who here is familiar with process
manipulations such as process injection
yeah I got a few hands process Halloween
yeah process doppelganger few more so we
got a few volunteers for a demo later
yeah only joking okay so what if we had
a technique that was much simpler to
execute require no code injection didn't
require any complicated ap is most
likely affects every endpoint security
solution impacted all versions of
Windows what we do and we call a process
reimaging and that's what we're going to
demonstrate here today and we're also
going to talk about some of the
mitigations and how you can protect
yourself so if you cast your minds back
to April May 2018 does that resonate
would anybody from a ransomware
perspective so it was roughly five
months after process topic gang was
disclosed at blackhat it became
weaponized with cynic ransomware and at
the time myself and an ATR teammate a
man Ryan were analyzing cynic ransomware
in the lab and what we discovered was it
was using processed doppelganger but if
you blocked doppelganger it would fall
back to process Halloween okay so at
this point you may be asking well what
is the relevance and what is the
importance here today and why does it
matter process reimaging well if process
DARPA ganging was weaponized only five
months out have been disclosed there's a
high likelihood this is going to be
weaponized also um and I think it really
all gonna be amazed how simple this is
to execute I'll be pretty complicated
under the hood and we go through some of
the kernel drivers are the kernel api is
and how it works
but it is relatively simple to execute
um
so later on we're going to do a live
demo and we're going to show how we can
bypass Windows Defender with process
reimaging the reason we use Windows
Defender is because process reimaging
impacts all versions of Windows and
Windows Defender is a default security
solution on Windows now I just want to
clarify before we get into the
presentation when we speak about Windows
Defender it's explicitly in relation to
processor imaging we're making no
reference to Windows defenders ability
to detect or protect against process
Halloween a process stop again
so before we kind of get into the detail
I'd like to get some attribution done so
myself I did all the reverse engineering
understand what was actually happening
under the hood root cause and also the
impact and detect and analysis and then
Steve Hernan who's one of our kernel
developers he did some of the proof
concept code and he also designed a fix
for this and Cedric Cotchin who maybe a
lot of people here today know he's a
Parisien living in Hillsborough in
Portland
Cedric actually discovered the technique
and how to execute it and then Steve of
Olney who's the head of vulnerability
research for McAfee ATR or advanced her
research Steve handle all the
communications and the disclosure
process so just a little bit about
myself and who I am so I go by the name
EE tree night on Twitter probably
connected with a few people here I've
been working in technology for about
twenty years or so at first ten years I
worked as an electronic engineer across
the semiconductor and also cause the
medical device industry and during that
time I worked across hardware and
software and then I moved about ten
years ago I moved into security and and
since then I've worked across product
security IT security as an individual
contributor team lead and manager and
that's given me kind of really good
perspective before moving into a
security research role within McAfee ITR
so over the next 40 minutes or so we're
going to discuss an overview what
process reimaging is then we talk about
the AV scanners and how they relate to
process room
we'll talk about the major attack
framework and defense evasion and then
hypothetically what would process
reimaging look like if it was weaponized
by syn/ack ransomware and then we get
into a bit more detail under the hood
what's happening with the kernel api's
they're exposed by ntdll and why this is
actually happening and why we can do
this technique and then we will finish
off with a live demo demo God's
permitting but hopefully all goes well
and I'm sure it will and I think you'll
really see how simple this technique is
but very impactful and then we'll finish
up with some impact and protection
mitigations so Microsoft did give an
update for this in the June cumulative
update but it only resolves a small
piece of this bypass and it only
mitigates a Windows Defender it doesn't
fix that the operating system level so
we'll talk about that later on so to
give an over your what process reimaging
is exactly it's exactly what the name
says it takes a process and it reaches
it and associates the process with a
different file on disk and if you take
about an employee security solution why
does that matter
well there's generally two use cases
where an operating system will depend
our sorry an endpoint security solution
will depend on an operating system it
will depend on her to verify what an
executing process has any malicious
files associate with it on disk but it
may also look to verify whether that
process can be trusted if it's signed by
it's by for example Microsoft or
wherever the case may be and it's
trusted to call in to its infrastructure
so they're generally due to use cases
now I do want to highlight here as well
that process reimaging targets non EDR
type as security solutions so with EDR
type solutions if they're configured
correctly they can trace processes and
can detect this so this would target
specifically consumers and people who do
not have a deal ADR such as small medium
enterprises as I mentioned it's
equivalent an impact to process
following a process stop again and it's
highly likely that every endpoint
security solution is vulnerable to this
because they're going to be dependent on
these api's ok one last thing I wanted
to say on this is that what's really
important here is that once this process
gets
securing and weary image it then until
there's a signature update or even after
a signature update you need to do a full
scan or a reboot to detect this so we
talked about AV scanners so on the
left-hand side here you can see this is
the general flow for process getting
created on Windows and when when an AV
engine is active it will scan a file for
malicious code at file create at section
create an image load once it has a
signature it will detect malicious a
malicious file now if it doesn't if it
doesn't have a signature and it will not
detect at those points and at that stage
the process will execute and then the
endpoint security solution becomes
dependent on the operating system API is
to verify the attributes of that process
and what I mean by the attributes is
that whether that process has malicious
files and discs associated with it sorry
so just to define process reimaging
exactly what it is so the windows
currently API is returned stale and
inconsistent file object Pat's which
enable aniversary to bypass Windows
operating system process attribute Farra
fication
and right now it is actually no
documented way to securely identify the
files associated with a process and disk
in Windows so when we talk we talk about
the mitre attack framework and and the
different domains within it the mitre
attack framework is a post exploitation
enumeration techniques which are used by
real world adversary's on windows linux
and mac and what's an adversary gets
code execution on the box that obviously
want to evade detection using defense
evasion techniques such as process
hollowing and DARPA ganging and our
process reimaging do we have any Game of
Thrones fans here today yeah everybody
happy with the last season all right
maybe I shouldn't ask that question but
everybody trust this guy here yeah
so he's Irish but I still don't trust
him so Sansa depended on this guy and
she trusted him but she wasn't
completely blind to him right and any
Game of Thrones fans know how would I
tended up in the finish the reason I
show this is because I've meant heard a
lot of product engineers and security
engineers and one of the first things I
always say when you're looking at a
system you got to understand the
security model how does it work what are
the main dependencies how can you break
that system what does it really depend
on that may be in or out of your control
and if you think about endpoints sorry
if you think about the endpoint security
solutions
sorry it's around blunder
if you think about the endpoint security
solutions they place inherent trust in
the operating system for capabilities
such as digital signature verification
and also for process attribute
verification so some time back the team
at Spectre ops and subverted the Windows
operating system for digital signature
verification and similarly what we've
done in ATR is we no subvert the
operating system for process attribute
certification with process reimaging so
just to cast our minds back again I'm
going to go back to May 2018 and talk
about use cynic ransomware as a case
study and a reason going to do that is
because we're going to compare and
contrast to set ourselves off for
understanding the demo of what Halloween
and doppelganger look like compared to
process reimaging so when we look at a
typical ransomware generally you know it
needs some initial or I suppose an
attack but in particular for cynic
ransomware it generally needs some kind
of an infection vector our initial
access such as a drive-by compromise or
a phishing attack and then it needs to
get a code execution
once it gets code execution then it's
going to try and evade itself from the
operating system from our from the
endpoint security solution from
detection now if you look at how
processed DARPA ganging worked it had a
dropper for argument's sake we call it's
enacted exe and then it had a trusted
binary called MSI exec now for process
hollowing as I'm sure a lot of people
know here today it starts off by
creating the process in suspended mode
so
uses the trusted process MSI execu and
then it uses numerous API is where by a
hollow Celtic Ohio's out the memory and
then replace it malicious code now what
if the endpoint security solution fails
to detect this dropper then the process
is allowed to execute signatures get
updated but once the process is
executing then it's reliant on the up
its operating system to tell it
information or attributes about that
process and so this is where process
reimaging comes in and why these aps are
important because you now have four
api's which we look at in a moment which
are required which the endpoint security
solution depends on to give the
information about the running process
and so the operating system now gets msi
exact back which we expect right process
Halloween we know how that technique
works and now the adversary is free to
act in their objectives because that's a
trusted process now if we talk about
process doppelganger same approach here
exactly the same binaries being used
albeit a little different a technique it
also starts with a trusted process MSI
exec and then we have it uses the
Windows transaction file ap is a little
bit different process following about
the same end goal and impact where can
get malicious code executing in a
trusted process and once again once the
endpoint security solution fails to
detect that wrapper then the operating
system will return back and say it's MSI
executing and is trusted and once again
the adversary's free to act in their
objectives so let's compare and contrast
what they look like with process
reimaging so process reimaging has the
exact same prerequisites as process
Halloween or doppelganger
you need to have code execution on the
box first and then it's about evading
detection so they've already gained
access to machine and the GAR code
execution now the tree attack vectors
are variants to process reimaging and
we'll see this later
when we look under the hood and also
when we look at when we see the demo
alive but there's a file path
where we sit it's as simple as rename
the file part of the process that's
executing or you simply the second one
you rename the file name and then the
third one can use either the father file
name or file path but it just uses Lord
library to reuse the same object in
memory it's not as impactful but we will
just highlight it here today it is a
variant of it but it still requires the
change to file name or fall apart okay
so what would Cenac ransomware look like
if it had weaponized process reimaging
you know and the reason this is so
important if you if you think about
defense evasion techniques right there's
many techniques in the miter attack
framework and with sin act we saw
process topic gang and hollowing being
used together right not just using one
technique anymore they're using many
techniques so this is another both of
our arrow in a way and we need to make
sure we're protected against this so
we'll just go through how did the
mechanics of this attack would work or
this technique so it's a little bit
different so instead of starting with a
trusted process it starts with a
malicious exe so if you think about what
would happen here is same as before
you've the same two files here we have
an additional undetected file here at
disrupt the disk now instead of having
numerous API is here noisy API is that
can potentially be detected by yarra
what we have are very very simple API is
which would be very hard to detect yara
because they would be very noisy we'll
be seeing typically in a binary and
they're used to copy and move a file
around on the file system and then
what's the dropper once the endpoint
security solution fails to take the
dropper we get that malicious process
executing they update their signatures
and then they query the operating
operating system API is for the
executing process name and you can see
here right there's a malicious process
executing we just don't we don't detect
it right the the operating system gives
the wrong information back what we
actually see from an operating system
perspective this MSI exactly and we
actually see that in the demo we'll see
the malicious process executing and then
we reimage it you actually see the
operating system it gets a different
view of it so we get the exact same
impact this process Halloween on top
again
and once again they're free to act on
their objectives so we go a little bit
deeper now on the colonel AP is and
what's actually happening under the hood
and a reason for this so there's
numerous api's involved here we see
summary table in a moment but there's
four particular ap is the forestry API
is here we have get module file name we
have process image file name and we have
query full process image file name and
ultimately they all call in to the
Windows kernel query information process
which is exposed by NC dll and
ultimately that goes into the Windows
kernel which is like a switch table a
large switch table and gives you back
depending on the API you call it will
give you back information from the e
process structure okay now the reason
process reimaging can actually happen
this technique is because windows is
inconsistent right what's we imagery mr.
process these fields hold different
values for the file name and file path
once you rename them on a disk you get
into consistent values back here and
depending on the API you called you will
get the wrong file name or file path so
the very high level that's what's
happening so we have these three api's
calling in the query information process
and then they get information back from
the e process structure from different
fields depending on the API you called
and a fort API is get mapped file name
and this API calls into another ntdll
api which is called NT query virtual
memory and I get this information from
the a process a process structure to vad
our virtual address descriptor ok so
there the for api is and at a high level
10,000 foot level that's kind of what
we're seeing in Ida and what's actually
happening underneath okay so to
summarize that on the left hand side
here we have for AP is the specific API
I get module filename get map file name
get process image file name and query
full process image file name and
depending on which API you call
once you reimage a process every version
of Windows will give you back the wrong
file path if you rename the file part
but any version less than Windows 10 and
depending on which one you use will give
it a round file name okay and one thing
to note here is sorry for just go back
one slide on Windows 10 a new field was
added to the process structure and it's
the image file pointer field so in
Windows 10 if you call the write API
this field here will always give you the
right file name when you really rename
it but for some win the reason Windows
Defender does not use it so even though
they have the capability in Windows 10
they don't use it and they get the wrong
file name back so we'll see more on that
later
so as I said this is a summary table and
you can see here what we summarizes the
API is the anti DLL a PID call and then
the offset fields within the process
structure where do we get the file name
or fall apart and you can see here on
Windows 10 depending on if you use these
three api's you always get the right
file name but you'll always get the
wrong file path so we said it was three
kind of variants or attack vectors
there's a file path the file name and
you have the load library version so I'm
going to show now what's happening at
the kernel level and then we'll see in
parallel what's happening at the process
and filesystem level so as you can see
here what we said before we have for AP
is and then depending on the AP ID is
called
they will call into anti query
information process our NT query virtual
memory now these two top API is here
when you put a curly bugger on these you
will see they pass these values in to be
hex which executes switch-case 43 in the
kernel once you call query information
process and then they get the file path
and file name from the SC ordered I'm
sorry from the section object now if you
call get process image filename which
we'll see later that Windows Defender is
doing and it does execute a different
switch statement within the kernel and
it gets the information from the section
object here
and then the guy get my full name that
actually gets it from the VAD here so
all these fields are wood in the process
structure and but depending whatever
process been reimaged or not which we
see later these will actually giving
inconsistent results so these are this
is the data structure side and this is a
logic flow here and how did the user
mode API is connect to the kernel api's
and then today actually process
structure so if we want to talk through
the sequence of actually what happens
from creating a process what happens in
disk and then what's happening at the
kernel level so we were seeing a demo
later on that ultimately what we do is
we just create a process called running
phase one at a you see a fit so the
directory running you could make that
any directory you want and we just cause
a phase one early exceed that can be any
AC you want but that exe is made me cats
we just renamed it so from the talk
earlier today I'm sure everybody
remembers what mini cats is it's a post
exploitation tool and most employee
security solutions should detect that
and that's the reason we're using it and
we will see defender detected and then
once the image has been a process has
been reimaged it will fail to detect it
so what we do then is we just simply
rename the execution directory so we
launch the process as running phase one
which is ultimately mainly cats and then
we renamed a path to hide running so now
what we have is and then we copy the
Kodiaks eve which is msi exec which you
saw with the cynic ransom ever been
dropped to disk and we copied that to
face will not exe so ultimately what we
have now is we created a process with a
malicious file we rename the directory
and then we copied a good files where
that malicious file was so now when you
scan that with Windows Defender
what happens is when does the fender
cause the API get process image filename
and it actually returns running phase
one and running phase one is now MSI
exactly that exe and we will see that in
process explorer with the demo later on
so the alternate view of mini cats
running as fair as well nadiak see
you've renamed a location and I Windows
Defender tinks MSI exactly SEC security
and you can see here has been absolutely
no changes here in I needa fields in II
process structure so the Windows kernel
has failed to reflect the file system
changes through the fire control block
to the II processor fields so that
impacts all version of Windows so you
simply rename the directory and you can
completely bypass the process attribute
verification so for Windows 10 sorry the
second variant is called with the file
name changes so instead of renaming the
file directory we just simply rename the
file so you can see here again apologies
you see here again we launched our
process running phase one which is mini
cats
and then instead of rename the directory
we just rename the file name so we
renamed the father hidden Daddy XE and
then we copied it MSI exact which is
good exe the phase one a XE and then
when Windows Defender runs once again it
calls the same API and it takes phase
one not hidden exe so once again it gets
the wrong file on disk once you rename
the file but you can actually see as I
mentioned before Windows did put an
update into Windows 10 for a new field
called image file pointer which actually
does get the right funds you can see
here it reflects the change so you
changed name a disk and it was reflected
but depends on the API you call to give
it a write value back but the API that
Windows Defender is using does not
reference this field it actually
references section object and so it gets
the wrong file on disk so that's four
versions greater than Windows 10 and the
reason I was that's happening with the
file image pointer if you look in the
kernel the file image pointer is located
at four four eight hex offset in the
process structure and and now I'm not
sure that field was added for Windows 10
I'm not sure not void or not using it it
obviously does reflect the file name
changes and you can see the changes
clearly in the kernel but it's not being
used now for Windows versions less than
ten what we have is
it's a little bit different so and what
I mean by the different is that it makes
different changes here and in the a
process structure it doesn't have the
image file pointer because that's only
for Windows versions 10 so once again
you rename the file name you copy the
MSI exactly good file to phase one at
exe and Mme cats are sorry
when is offender fails to detect the
memory cats process executing and you
can see why right I mean you only feel
it's all updated here is the the VAD
right so the only API that would give
you the correct file name is get map for
them which Windows Defender is not using
to verify the backing file at disk
associate with a process everybody with
me so far
yeah I know there's a lot in that but
when we when we do the demo I solidify
and you really see what's happening so
once again here like we don't have that
for 48 offset here we have the P
reference process file pointer which
points to this section object and
obviously we're getting the wrong
information back I'm not going to go
into these ones in too much detail and
they're a slight variant or not as
impactful the only impact they get my
full name and ultimately what's
happening here is when you do a lord
library in a free library it seems to
cache the object and the file pad
associate with our file object so then
when you reload it a second time it uses
the incorrect path so I'm not going to
go into it in too much detail because it
still depends on the file name and file
path but it is a variant of it and it
impacts all versions of Windows so I
think I want to spend a bit of time in
this demo and really kind of solidified
us here today and put it all this into
action so you can see what's happening
so in the demo we're gonna focus
completely on the file path we're not
going to do the file name because even
with the latest windows update for the
June cumulative update this still works
if you if we did a file named bypass it
wouldn't work as Windows protected
against it specifically for a defender
not at the OS level okay so we're gonna
fire up this demo and show exactly what
how this works
second okay everybody see that okay just
duplicate my laptop so we've Windows
Defender turned off here and the reason
we have this turned off is we're
simulating a undetected piece of not
ever being dropped to disk right we're
not in the habit of releasing zero days
here so we're just simulating what would
happen in a real-world scenario where
for example with cynic you got a binary
which was dropped to disk a malicious
binary and wasn't detected so let me
just show you what's happening here so
what we have in this excluded folder is
bad Exe which is mini cats you can see
here it's me me cats and then we have
good exe which is MSI exec so we're just
going to talk through exactly the floor
we saw earlier and then we're going to
execute it so you can see MSI now on
this run here we're not going to reimage
the process we're all we're simply going
to do here is create a folder called
running copy mini cats to phase one at a
UC and executed so basically we have
made me cats running as a process called
phase one at a XE and offender should
detect it okay so we're just going to
show what it looks like when you don't
reuse the process and if you look at the
filter here for a process monitor and we
have we have a filter on running phase
one that exe so what we see is when
Windows Defender scan runs it will
actually look at this location correctly
for the file on disk and then when we
show the image process later you'll see
it looks in the wrong wrong location so
let's just run this to see what happens
sorry just as a couple of events in
process monitor so our
there is on Windows Defender exe and on
the path where we're running phase 1 ATC
which is ultimately memory cards so
process reimaging on the score file path
that exe is busy just simulating a
dropper which would be used for example
with cynic and no itself just means that
we're not actually going to reimage the
process so you can see here we've
Windows Defender turned off because we
want to simulate an undetected binary
let the process run then weary in able
defender and it should catch it ok so
you can see me cat is running there
right now if we pick up process Explorer
second now okay you can see our own sign
dropper has launched phase one dot exe
which you can see as many cats can
everybody see that clearly yeah okay so
let's run renders offender
see already winners offenders pick
something up here they may be tress in
your device and you can see the alert
here and and that's what we'd expect
right we have a malicious process
running it's phase one dot exe you can
see here we just copied we just copied
mini cats in here and called phase will
not exceed that's all we did
and that's exactly what you'd expect
right so there's no reimaging going on
there and you can see here it detected
mini cats okay so let's just pause that
and we go and do the process reimaging
so now we're process reimaging exactly
the same setup we have Windows Defender
disabled similar to zero undetected
binary on disk we have our dropper and
then we have Mimi Katz and we have MSI
exec just called good exe as I said
before so what's going to happen this
time and I'll leave this window open so
you can see it happening real time we're
going to create a directory called
running which will have phase 1 exe as
before and that Lots baby mini cats but
then we have a second folder we'll
rename that folder called hide running
and then we'll make another folder
called running which will have to go DXE
and we completely subvert the operating
system so what I have here is I have a
filter on the windows defender process I
have a filter on running phase 1 and
have a filter also on hide running phase
1 now the reason I put two filters is
because you'd be able to see the binary
I used to launch the process will be
located at hide running but Windows
Defender never even goes that location
and our good exe is going to be at
running phase 1 dot exe so completely
looks in the wrong direction or wrong
location and it trusts the file on disk
so we'll just hit OK there
okay so you'll see the changes happening
here real-time so we just we started
it's just running there it's phase one
dot exe that's me me cats and now we
rename the directory you'll see it
happening now so now we just renamed
running to hide running and then we
create a new directory called running I
put two good exe in there so the process
the process patch you started with now
has a good file as opposed to the memory
Katz file so now let's have a look in
process explorer to see what's happening
before and after we run Windows Defender
so now you can see here that's exactly
the same we started with mini cats we've
reimaged the process and now we can
clearly see that's a trusted Microsoft
Windows installer that's a messiah
exactly so now we have mini cats running
and from an operating system perspective
it's msi exec and that-that's-that's
process reimaging and what we'll do here
now is we just run Windows Defender and
you see it failed to detect it
since one second so now you can see
Windows has it looked in the same
location running phase 1 at Exe but
we've renamed a TAC team is slightly
exactly and our malicious file is
running in hide running location so you
can see there's no alert stare and I'll
leave that running we can check at the
end of the presentation you'll see it
doesn't detect anything so you can see
it's already looked in that location
it's looked at this executing process
it's looked for the Associated file on
disk and a file on disk you get is MSI
exec as opposed to many cats it's
completely bypassed the operating system
API so I leave that running and we'll
see at the end that it comes back with a
clean scan anybody any questions on that
ok so I'll just continue on with the
presentation and we come back to that in
a moment to see a clean scan ok ok so
that's the demo just to give a summary
down of the process and the epilation
techniques a recap so we have processor
e imaging and a lot easier to execute
very very simple you can see there all
we're doing is rename it a directory or
a file file name that's it there's no
complex API is a code injection involved
excuse me
process hollowing across the stop again
the difference is to start with atrocity
XE we start with a malicious exe but
ultimately the end and impact is the
same they both bought up here as trusted
processes and are allowed to evade
detection and execute interval on the
endpoint so just to kind of there are
some pros and cons right to all the
different techniques from processor
imaging perspective and as I said it's a
lot easier to execute it doesn't require
code injection impacts all versions of
Windows there's no real API signature
there from a yarra perspective and
there's no protection out there right
now and now I suppose on a disadvantage
side is you
use it as a fireless attack and you
can't delete the file on disk once you
have the process running like process
hollowing it up again you still need the
malicious file on disk because it's
still associate with the process you
can't delete it now we'll talk about a
fix that we put in our selves which was
designed by Steve Herndon but ultimately
if you're using EDR or memory scanning
obviously you would detect this but for
non EDRs the systems you're not going to
detect this so from an impact
perspective as I said before there's two
use cases and we scored this the same as
we did process doppelganger we gave it a
CVS s of 5.0 where the integrity was
very high because you cannot no longer
trust the process
so the to use case we spoke about
earlier is where you're trying to verify
a remote process whether you can trust
the file associate with that on disk and
obviously you can't in this case and in
the second one is where you're trying to
verify the actual trust of the process
whether that can call into your trusted
infrastructure or not now that depending
on your endpoint security solution and
the architecture how it works that CBS s
could be a lot higher I can't quantify
that because it depends on the endpoint
security architecture so if you have an
endpoint security solution and you're
using any of those API is mentioned
today it's highly likely you're
vulnerable to process reimaging so from
a protection recommendations to the
endpoint security vendors and what we
say is that you need to track the file
object so if you remember back to the
process creation steps of file create
you can get an idea at that step when
the file objects created before it's
cleaned up and it's closed by the
operating system I need to track that ID
the whole way true keep that cached and
then when you want to verify a process
you take the trust away from the
operating system and you use that ID
yourself to verify if the process had
been reimaged or not so the endpoint
security vendor actually needs to track
this unless windows go on update the
operating system I mean I think that's
the right thing to do
Windows haven't done that and and
Microsoft I hope they do do it but right
now they haven't
so we did give a number of protection
recommendations to Microsoft as well so
for example one of the things was that
if you change something in a file system
that the file control dock were to
reflect that in the process structure in
the kernel and also one of the big
things is to consolidate the API is
right we have for API is effectively
doing the same thing and getting
information from different areas in the
kernel they're inconsistent right it
needs to be more consistent so Microsoft
did make an update in the June
cumulative update as I said but it's
only a partial fix for the file name
bypass and it only mitigates Windows
Defender
there was no change at the operating
system level ok so if you're an endpoint
security solution you know I'm hoping
Microsoft will update an operating
system level but if not you're going to
have to do
I think the recommendation that we
propose is the right way to do that so
Windows Defender as a show today that's
the latest updated operating system
version it's still vulnerable to the
file path renaming so even with our past
are still vulnerable and that's it right
SHINee Dena which is Irish sure that's
all folks and we have a blog which will
be released after this which goes
through this in detail and I'm sure you
can all decode that piece at the end
I'll leave that for a challenge for
everybody which I'm sure won't be much
of a challenge but you can decode that
nonetheless so thank you for your time
today and if there's any questions and I
think we have another three minutes or
so
[Applause]