so good afternoon thank you for coming
here to this introduction to IOT reverse
engineering with an example on a home
router I know that the time after lunch
is the most easily be time of the day so
I hope you will find this presentation
interesting enough to keep you awake
my name is Valerio Dijon Pietro I am an
Italian I am passionate about
electronics and technology since when I
was a child for this reason I studied
electronic engineering at University and
started working as a digital hardware
designer but soon I moved to a unique
system at the ministration position and
later to an IT infrastructure manager
position managing servers but on the
cloud and on-premise managing storage
networking databases and so on I am also
a Linux enthusiast since 1993 my
personal home page is Valerio written as
valor dot IO you will find a copy of
this presentation and more important
links to everything I will talk about
today my email address is Valerio
written is v8 lair dot io and my twitter
handle is Valerio being a nerd I am
quite proud of these addresses what we
will talk about today I will start with
the short introduction about reverse
engineering and then describe the
reverse engineering process based on
informational gatoring
building an emulation environment using
came where to run interesting IOT
binaries then analyzing out the device
work and then at the end modify the
firmware that is our target what is to
define reverse engineering we have to
first define what engineering is we can
say that engineering is the science of
making things that starts with the
product requirements continue the
designing the product and finish
building or manufacturing the product
the reverse engineering process is
exactly the same process but done in
reverse order and
usually with the limited scope so we
start from the product manufactured by
someone else we analyze the product we
take measurements and we reconstruct the
design and the requirements in our home
router example the limited scope is to
understand how to modify the router
firmer to add features and additional
programs will start with informational
catering the first information we need
is who makes the device in this example
it is the d-link that makes the device
and but we also want to know if there is
an original design manufacturer because
sometimes a company makes the device but
another company is designed and
developed the firmware of the device we
start opening the case trying to
identify the main device components and
we are especially interested and it is
very important to the word and the JTAG
interfaces at at the end we want to get
the firmware and the root filesystem of
the device we increase case in this
example we open the case I start to
looking at the mainboard top you can see
that it's not easy to identify each
electronic device because some devices
are hidden below that black it's ink and
also below that metal sheet used to
shield radio frequencies anyway we are
able to identify some devices and in
this case we are able to identify the
the word that is clearly market on the
PCB I wasn't able to confirm the
position of the JTAG interface in this
case looking at the bottom of the board
that we can identify some additional
devices like for example the NAND flash
device in the Y file module but I wasn't
able to identify the system on a chip
maybe it is even below that metal sheet
used to shield the radio frequencies
locating the what interface is very very
important on the right you can see the
word position on some machine and all
sports we the first step we start the
searching on internet to see if someone
else is
the job before us identifying the word
interface on our device otherwise we
have to identify potential serial
headers candidates sometimes these are
market on the PC basic screen so it easy
to identify but otherwise we have to
identify four pins that are power ground
TX and rx we can use a multimeter to
find potential candidates it is easy
with the multimeter to identify power a
ground TX usually is a pull-up resistor
and rx usually is an AI impedance input
we can also if we know the system on a
chip and if we have its datasheet we can
identify the word interface on the chip
on the ship itself and try to follow the
PCB traces this this is not easy to the
multi-layer board we can also use tools
like jtagulator a calculator is a
fantastic piece of tool it is it has a
lot of headers that we can attach to
potential headers candidates but for the
earth and for JTAG interface it can run
some automatic scanning logic and it is
able to identify the pin out of the word
or over the JTAG interface we can also
use an oscilloscope or a logic analyzer
to locate the TX pin because for sure
during a boot something will be written
on the seller console and this pin will
go up and down but maybe it is a bit
overkill we also want to locate the JTAG
interface the JTAG interface is an
intern into standard for testing printed
circuit boards after manufacture and
allows access to many internal signals
of complex integrated circuits it also
allows access to read the right to flash
memory content and can be used as a
primary means for any in-circuit
emulator multiple devices are daisy
chained together and each one of them
can be accessed using the geotag
interface it is four or five signal pins
that are test clock this that I mean
they started out this mode select and
resid test resset is optional because we
can reset the interface also using the
other pins to locate the position of the
JTAG interface is not easy because there
is a non-standard pin out but anyway
there are a few popular pin outs that
are available on the oral shown on the
slide on the right side you can see some
examples of popular pin outs so the
first step is always to search on
Internet to see if someone else has
already identified the position of the
track interface in our device otherwise
we start looking for adders labeled t ck
t di t do and TMS but if no label has
been found we have to look for potential
pin headers candidates arranged in a row
of five or six pin or in a double row of
ten 14 or 20 pins we can use a
multimeter to identify power ground this
is easy we know that TMS and TDI usually
they have a pull-up resistor the test
receipt can be pulled up or pull it down
tto should be.i impedance so with the
multimeter we can try to identify
someone as a mortise pin then match what
we found with popular pin outs and this
way try to identify the pin out of the
JTAG interface otherwise we can if we
know the system ownership in this
datasheet as before we can identify the
position of the JTAG interface of the
system on a chip and try to follow the
PCB traces or we can use tools like Jada
kool-aid or as seen before after we have
identified these interfaces we have to
repopulate them this means to attach
adders to these interfaces using a
disordering pump and a soldering iron
and then use a connector in this case it
is it a USB TTLs serial adapter to
connect the IOT device to the PC with a
terminal emulator running running putti
but why you want to repopulate interface
say why we are so interested in the in
TC 2 interfaces the word is really
really important because it allows us to
watch what is printed on the serial
console during the boot and T's allows
us to identify
the bootloader and operating system
version because I want to modify the
firmware I can also watch what is it is
printed on the serial console during the
upgrade cycle and maybe get some
information on how the upgrade is done
we have to use a neo submitted TTL
cellular doctor and the terminal
terminal emulator on a PC like for
example booty we also are interested in
the JTAG interface because it allows us
to read the farmer from the flash EEPROM
allows us also to break into the boot
cycle and use the JTAG interface as a
means to do in circuit debugging to do
so we able to attach a board like bus
pilot to the JTAG interface and we have
to use an open source software like open
OCD to damper the flash EEPROM and to do
insecurity debugging any way to do this
kind of things is really really hard the
last step of information gathering is to
get the firmware file we always follow
the easiest part first
this means that if the supplier is a
website with the firmware updates we go
and download the firmware file from
there if the firmware update can be
downloaded directly only by the device
we can sniff the communication with the
Wireshark and get to the firmware file
if the above steps are not available we
have to download their from image
through the JTAG interface using a bus
pilot and open on CD once we have the
firmware file in this case I downloaded
the firmware file from the supplier
website we want to have some information
from this firmware file on Linux we can
use the file command but this tells us
that we have just a data file but there
is a very good piece of software that is
been walk bin work is able to scan
inside a data file
searching a lot of different signatures
of many file system images or image
pictures of digital certificates or
compressed data and so on in this case
bill bin walked tells us that we have j
FF s 2 file system image and exhibit
compressor the data segment jmf through
stands for journaling flash file system
version to ant is quite popular in
embedded device with named flash flash
file system we are also interested to
extract the content from the flat from
the file system image because we want to
see the root file system to extract the
content we need the Jefferson program to
install on our Linux machine because the
jmf to file system runs on top of the
empty driver that operates differently
from the block device driver and cannot
be loop mounted but once we have
installed Jefferson we can use beam wall
to recursively extract the content of
the thermal file in this case with the -
II option we can see that beam walk
extract the first file that it extracted
is the good zip at the data segment that
is at our archive containing some
packages on board specific packages the
second file 200 . j FF s2 is the file
system image and the third folder GFS 2
- root is the filesystem image that has
been regularly extracted into the file
system looking at what was extracted it
seems that we have a tree file system in
reality we haven't only - this is a
glitch of the Jefferson program the
first file system is the boot file
system we have we seek it that we have
two files one is CF Irama dot 0 0 that
it is the boot order image based on the
Broadcom common firmer environment the
second file is the Linux kernel in an
unusual cfv compressed format if we
start looking at other files and start
doing some file system analysis we can
see that the system is based on busybox
using the strings command we can also
identify the busybox version busybox is
quite popular in embedded devices
because in a single binary it it
implements a lot of different
functionalities like the init process
the bash interpreter LS grep and in many
many other device using the cross to
Train read F command we can also
understand that the system is based on
moosie
you see mu syllabus e is also quite
popular in embedded devices because it
implements a lot of functionality of the
Liberty library almost everything the
the the newly BC implements but which
are much much smaller footprint we can
also look at our other libraries for
example the Lib decrypt library and
other libraries in their version so now
we that we have done some preliminary
analysis we can attach the cellar
console to the PC running putti and we
power power up the board they start
looking at what is printed on the serial
console during boot we can confirm that
the bootloader is is a CF v we can also
identify its version we can have the
chip ID in this case it is a Broadcom
chip it is there are no so many
information about the chip on the
internet probably is a custom-made chip
because the Brautigan allows is a
customer to build chips putting together
a processor core and some other devices
but anyway we know that it is it is a
processor core that it is an ARM Cortex
a9 dual-core cpu running at 1 gigahertz
we also can identify that it is 256
megabytes of RAM in 256 megabytes of
flesh a prom we can also identify the
Linux kernel version that it is 3.4
point 11 with real-time pages 19 the
instruction set is the arm v7
instruction set and the jmf through file
system among other things supports the
non-standard feature that is the lzma
compression we can also identify how the
named flesh is a partition and we can
also confirm that busybox
is the init process and that the first
script started is the LCS script this is
according to the init tab configuration
file during boot we can also identify
the string epicentro software version if
we search on the internet for this
string we can identify the original
design
so this router was made by the link but
the firmer was developed by a swiss
company called ADB so summarizing what
we has found till now we found that our
router is based on an arm ab7 cortex and
multi-core processor that is 256
megabytes of anand flesh that use a
linux kernel that was released on in
2012 this router started shipping in
so it is a 6 years old Linux kernel we
can also identify the version of other
components like new syllabus II was
released in 2012 busybox
in 2010 Liberty crypt was released in
2009 and we also identified that the
original design manufacturer was ADB as
you can see we have all the software or
a new device we can ask why this happens
probably because the the maker tried to
save some money reusing something that
it already is or maybe reusing some
software development development kit
that was released by the chip
manufacturer anyway from a security
point of view this is quite bad because
we have a new device with all the
software potentially with all the
software with some unpatch with the
vulnerabilities now that we have done we
finished the information gathering
process we can start to build an
emulation environment we won't want to
build an emulation environment where to
run IOT binaries which we have to choose
an emulation system to emulate first of
all to emulate our processor and we use
K mu K mu is a fantastic tool that
emulates a lot of different type of CPU
and a lot of different boards in this
case we choose the we express a 9 board
with the cortex a9 processor that it's
the same CPU is the one in our IOT
device but we not only need to emulate
the processor we also need a kernel and
a root filesystem
to emulate our environment we could
think of building everything by
ourselves
cross-compiling everything but it is an
almost impossible task because of a lot
of interdependencies among packages
libraries device drivers and so on so we
able to choose a build system there are
open source very popular build system
the most popular one is the Yocto
project it is very powerful it not only
builds a root filesystem and a kernel
but it is also able to build a custom
Linux distribution with an included
package manager but its main drawback is
that it is a steep learning curve
another popular build system is build
root it builds only the root filesystem
and kernel but it is easy and fast to
learn and there is a very good user
manual
another popular build system is open wrt
later renamed it leader it is tailored
to build a replacement or outer firmer
but the documentation is cut red in the
website and it requires more time to
learn compared to build the root for
this reason in my home project I choose
the Builder root choosing builder root
is not enough we want to have a root
filesystem that is computed compatible
with what we have on IOT device because
we were want to run IOT device binaries
so we are also able to choose a builder
root version because we want to have a
root filesystem and it is based on same
components that we have on the IOT
device aw it has to be based on the same
syllabus aversion it must have a
compatible Liberty crypt carpet crypto
library he must have the same kernel and
also other libraries should have
compatible version on on on what we have
on the our IOT device so the Builder
root aversion to use is build the root
that was released on February 12 2014
unfortunately due to the dependency hell
this version doesn't run on a recent
Linux distribution so it doesn't run on
Ubuntu 1604 or Ubuntu 1804 so we have to
use an older Linux distribution that is
more or less the same age as the other
components that was released so we can
use they been with Z that was released
in 2000
13 and we will run teas in a docker
container using docker as a light a
virtualization environment so we have to
build a docker file for docker container
this is a minimal they've done with the
container with just the packages needed
to run build the root docker file is
available on my github repository the
important thing when we run docker is
three important choices we map the
temporary x11 folder in the author of
the Oz machine inside the same position
in the docker machine this is to be able
to run graphical programs in the docker
machine as for example the make X config
command we also map at the home
directory in the host machine inside the
same position in the local machine and
we map user name and user read in the
auto machine to the same user name user
read in the docker machine in this way
we can have a system with for example
two windows one it is the host window
running a boon to 18:04 and the other
one is the docker machine running debian
with z but the two windows share exactly
the same home directory and exactly the
same username and userid using the the
shredding of information files build
route must also be configured B because
we want to build this root filesystem as
we want so the configuration starts with
the ship at the configuration file
sheephead with the build route that is
based on our emulated bore that is the
be expressed board but we able to do
some modification the most important
modifications that we want to build
packages a ladder is with debugging
symbols and other debugging information
because we want to be able to run IOT
binaries in our environment they want to
be able to use the new debugger and at
least we can put breakpoints on library
functions entry and we can understand
what the bynars do looking at what
library function function calls and what
are the parameters use the in this
function calls we also want to build
debugging tools like GDB GDB server and
so on and we as be able to include
for the men to flesh in the jmf stew
file system we also able to include
other libraries use it in the entirety
device we also have to do some minor
kernel configuration basically we select
the same board with the vestry support
we select the preemptable kernel as in
our IET device we have to include the
name the device the support and support
for Linda Fletcher simulator and
obviously we have to included support
for the jf2 file system with lzma
compression we also have to do some
minor or configuration for the MU
syllabus II this is the result of trial
there for example we were able to
include a native POSIX trading and so on
and we also able to include some debug
to include the back knee symbols also in
the mo syllabus C configuration you do
some quirks in this configuration we
able to do in it some more complicated
way I go fast because I have to be short
shorter than originally anticipated
sorry because we want to replace the
firmer the original idea is to modify
the firmware file to load the firmer
using the normal upgrade process so we
want to analyze the upgrade process on
the IOT device we start the upgrade
process using the web interface and
start looking at what is printed on the
serial console during the upgrade in
this case we can see that is printed and
Sarah consult at the script that the
start is upgrade prepare dot SH but then
the script upgraded SH is started it
prints signature okay so this means that
the firmware file is assigned then a
flesh aerosol command is a command is
executed to erase the third partition
T's is the partition dedicated to the
firmware upgrade and then the DD command
is used to extract the root and boot
file system from the firmware file and
the nan the write command is used to
write this booter root filesystem to the
nand flash device after T is some kernel
module does a partition split on the fly
and create two new partitions that are
both FS 2 and the root FS June
looking at parameters in the DD command
we can identify where in the former file
the boot a root filesystem
are located we can see that some
packages are added in the new root
filesystem these packages were included
in the zip at the compressor data inside
the firmware file and then the boot
order is written again in the in the
flesh Abram and then the router is
rebooted so summarizing very shortly the
most important script to analyze to be
able to understand how the per grade
farmer works and how we can modify the
firmware is upgraded SH the firmware
file is assigned at the signature is
checkered with the sig and the score
verify binary that is included in the
root filesystem
of the router the booty root filesystem
are written a single and the write
operation some kernel module is used to
split the partition on-the-fly some
other kernel module is used to delimit
the end of the root file system
partition some additional packages are
added at the end based on on bore type
and the bootloader at the end is written
on the nand flash and the system is
rebooted so if we want to modify the
firmware we have seen that the firmware
file is a signature so we want to
understand if we can fake the signature
to be able to load our own of famer file
because the signature is checkered with
the second score verify binary we want
to we want to execute this command in
our emulated environment to understand
what it does and to understand if we can
fake the signature second score verify
is all other binaries in the router is a
stupid binary it is no debugging
information but it calls library
functions so the idea is to run it is
acceptable in our emulation environment
and putting a breakpoint on each library
function entry we can have a list of all
library functions called by the sig
verify binary with the cross store chain
read elf command
the shown parameters in this case we
have a list of all the library function
calls we can run a ciggy verify you know
the bugger using the DB DB server in the
emulated environment and the cross to
change DB in the author system these two
will talk together and on those the
system the gdb will do the hard work of
showing the breakpoint variable contents
source code and so on doing this kind of
analysis it is possible to clearly
understand what sig underscore verified
us just looking at the library function
calls that it does basically it reads
the last 256 bytes from the ephemeral
file this is the signature then it
calculates the sherwin checksum of the
firmware file using the Liberty crypt
library functions then it calls other
Liberty crypt library functions to check
the C to verify the signature passing as
parameter the sherwin message digests
calculated passing the signature and the
public key the signature is the original
ish a one message digest encrypted with
the private key and the public key is
used to decrypt the signature and to see
if it matches with the calculated a
sha-1 message digest if it does it
returns okay otherwise it returns an
error the public key is based on two big
integers or multi version integers that
are called models and exponent using the
new debugger we can this we can dump
these two big integers from memory
and we reconstruct the public key in the
standard dot pam format but
unfortunately the private key remains
unknown so it's not positive and it's
not included in Reuters certificate
files as expected so this means
basically that we it's not possible to
modify the firmware using the standard
Firma upgrade process because we don't
know the private key and we cannot fake
the signature so we able to find another
way
so we start finding another way we can
see that the in this case the router
allows an telnet SSH connection but
present a Cisco like restricted shell
Cisco like means that if we type help we
have a list of all available comments
the comments are also out of completed
and if you type a question mark all the
options are shown but that's all annal I
don't doing some file system analysis we
can understand that it is restricted the
shell is based on an open source project
that is called clash analyzing the
startup script we can understand that
the configuration file files are located
inside a select MP / Krish directory and
this is a link that points to a folder
in normal mode and to another folder in
factory mode so we can start analyzing
the startup script for example in normal
mode to see if we can find something
interesting inside in this case we find
interesting command inside that is
factory mode this is an even command it
then means that if you type L it's not
shown and it is not also how to
completed the pressing tab because of
this this means that it is an
interesting command so we execute this
command and the Reuters enters the
factory mode and reboots factory mode is
a special mode do we have a non-normal
Wi-Fi no internet connection or the DHCP
server and so on but it is an
interesting comment it is a privilege
with a non privileged reddish relogin so
it is the system shell command that
gives us a normal linux shell this is a
normal user linux shell so we cannot
modify the system but we can explore the
system so our target is to become a root
so we start looking for process for
processes running with the root
privileges trying to find some something
to act to become rope to become root so
with we start identifying each process
and exec tables we can use the strengths
command to see the strings inside the in
this case identify
what this product is a process does and
is a version we can also try to run at
these executables in the target itself
or in dominated the environment with -
v4 version or mine - h4 ALP command to
identify the program in this version in
this case in this way we can identify
all open-source executables and their
version and we can search the internet
for known vulnerabilities for the
specific executable version if some
vulnerability is found we have to check
that this vulnerabilities is exploitable
in the specific IOT device configuration
because often we have vulnerabilities
that are exploitable only under certain
circumstances if no exploitable
vulnerability has been found as in this
case we able to select a process
candidate to reverse engineer in our
emulated environment to find
vulnerabilities operating system
binaries with non owner abilities are
hard to crack because if nobody else
have already found the vulnerability it
will be difficult for us to find one
lower level stuff like stuff related to
DNS or VoIP or other special devices
usually are more difficult to crack
because they do one specific thing and
they have a smaller
attack surface higher level executables
like with the bigger configuration files
usually are less difficult to crack
because they have a larger attack
surface analyzing the process the most
interesting one is the configuration
management process it runs as route in
background 8 it does all the root
configuration changes like adding new
users configuring the DHCP server
changing router address and so on
analyzing startup scripts and executing
a cm in the emulation environment we can
discover that this process use shell
scripts to carry out its duties on the
router there is also the CM client
command that is executed by as a normal
user by the web interface and by the
restricted shell that talks to the
background CM pro
to do the change in this way
it seems the the router seems
well-designed because in this way only
permitted the configuration trains are
allowed but cm are doing filesystem
analysis we can see that cm client is
used in startup scripts to configure the
CM process so in a startup script there
is for example that command that tells
through the same process flawed all the
same ml configuration files I will label
in that folder in that folder one of
this configuration file is management
dot XML but others are similar that is
inside it is interesting snippet when
basically to tells to the same process
to use the users dot SH script to change
users properties or to add new user so
the idea is we can copy the management
dot XML in our own folder modify it
reconfigure the CM process using the
same Claude client the trans is a normal
user we can modify inside the fake
management XML just to execute not the
standard user dot SH but our own version
that we call fake users dot SH that does
same thing as the original but just with
the few instruction to modify the H
password file to remove the root
password we can then trigger the
execution of accusers dot SH it will be
executed by the same process as rune as
a root and we'll be able to modify the
edge password file we can put together
all these steps in a in a script and
then we can copy this script on the as a
normal user on the device we can make in
the device is a script executable we can
run this script and having removed the
password for the root user we can do n
su and become root so now we can find
everything we want but our target is to
modify the firmware
so basically Ana based on a firmer and
our own analysis of the firmer upper
grade script we can understand that the
the firmware file is the following
structure we have an immediate Wrexham
we have the boot file system a partition
splitter the root filesystem an endo
partition marker at at the end the
signature so our idea is to modify just
only the root file system so we can
extract the root file system from the
firmware file modify it create the new
root file system image modified pad pad
the file system image to the same size
as the original root file system image
because in the firmware file there are
many fields that we don't know their
purpose and we don't know how they are
recalculated changing the root file
system sides if we need additional
software to be installed on the router
we can use an USB key that is additional
storage at the end we can reassemble
everything putting everything together
using the DD command and in this way we
have an unsigned firmware file the
problem is that we cannot load this
unsigned firmware file with the standard
upgrade procedure but we are also we
have some we we can do something in the
original upgrade script the the firmer
is check it with these two lines of code
so the Sigma verify does the track and
the red code variables returns the
output of the the return value of the
Sigma verify command so we can copy this
script in a temporary folder modify it
to always return 0 this means always
returns ok also if the the signature
check fails and then we can temporary
replace the original script with our own
version using the mount with the - -
bind option the bind option in the mount
command is usually used to mount a
folder over another but can also be used
to mount the file over another an
interesting thing is that it can also be
used to mount a file over another in a
read-only file system in this case we
can temporary replace the
Grado TCH script doing so we can do now
the upgrade with our unsigned framer
file and the upgrade will succeed so we
have reached our target that was to
modify the firma so conclusion summary
we can say that reverse engineering can
be really really challenging it is
important to clearly define the limited
scope of the in the reverse engineering
project to remain focused on the target
it is important to start gathering
information always following the easiest
part first so if something is available
internet we can search this otherwise if
some information is missing or difficult
to get we try to move forward and we go
back only if absolutely needed we can
search on internet for everything
including known vulnerabilities this is
always the easiest part to do and if we
have talked to
Aksum process we able to select process
running his route and with a large
attack surface on this at the end of
this presentation I have included a lot
of useful links to some github Miami
github repository one with all the tools
and a firmer modification kit for this
router another one to build the
emulation environment add other link to
everything I talked about today so I
unfortunately I even have time for
question because time is quite short and
so thank you very much for your time and
your patience
[Applause]