okay
bonsoir twosome my name is Andrea peony
and first of all I want to apologize for
my bad english I'm much more comfortable
for this French so I hope that you will
understand what I'm talking I will talk
very slow and I have only I know only
few words of English but are these are
technical that word so I I guess
everyone is able to understand me first
a little bit about me very short
introduction yes that's me
among the other things I am an IT
architect and security manager I have a
very long time experience I I think I'm
one of the oldest here and IT security
it has always been a very special
interest for me to be honest
offensive security it's much more an
hobby for me and during my spare time I
like to understand better the
vulnerabilities of Windows and Linux
systems these are my contacts and to
demonstrate that I'm old I don't know
how many of you attended this chat
system this was a French chat system on
x.25 networks so it was in the
pre-internet area and this was a very
very funny place where you could meet
heckles worldwide and i learned very
very many things in this period ok so
back to us why this talk because I
forgot to say you that I'm talking about
Windows privileges
I guess that everyone here knows what
Windows privileges are ok and why did I
choose this talk because I'm during the
time I noticed that often these
privileges are misunderstood or they are
not taken in consideration when you have
to do privilege escalation so I decided
to learn them better and to make some
practice with the privileges in order to
understand how to make privilege
escalation
abusing from these privileges sorry I am
Italian
so I speak also is my hand don't pay too
much attention to my hands okay one day
I ran in this great article which was a
perfect summary of what you can do with
some privileges especially the god
privileges the maximum privileges that
the user can have and I got in contact
with the outers and we exchanged also
very useful informations so this is the
agenda agenda short introduction about
privileges and how to get them and then
we will dig deeper in some very
interesting privileges like the debug
privilege the rest or back up take
ownership and so on and finally a
special attention due to the last two
months because in conjunction with an
exploit has been demonstrated to be very
powerful privileges because Microsoft
was not able to fix them
ok and then finally prevention and some
final thought is my English ok great I
don't want to bore you with Windows
privileges so it's it will be a very
very short introduction what is a
Windows privilege is a special right
that you can grant to a user or a group
in order to perform a special operation
on the operating system like shutting
down the system changing the system time
doing a backup and so on
some built-in users or groups have
already built-in privileges and you can
assign privileges via the the GUI
interface but you can also play the
wisdom by launching by invoking the the
the right API stew so you don't need
graphic and interface to assign them
another interesting things is that some
privileges bypass totally the sick
purity settings so for example backup
and restore privileges also debug
privileges don't take in consideration
the security which has been put on this
object another interesting thing that
you have to pay attention is that some
privileges are only available in a high
integrity level process typically an
elevated shell because if you have a
standard shell you won't see the
privileges you have to elevate to a high
integrity process and okay Who am i /
breve will list your privileges another
concept is that windows access token
because it's bind with the privileges
what is an windows access token again I
don't want to bore you it's an object
which is create which is created when
you log on and this object is used when
you need to access a securable object in
order to verify if your rights are
appropriate to access the object or when
you want to perform to user privileges
because in the access token D all these
informations are stored so you can see
among the other things a Windows access
token contains the list of the
privileges the type of the token and the
type of impersonation level what does
this mean very very quickly a token can
be primary or impersonation if it is a
primary token you can launch processes
with it if it is an impersonation token
you can impersonate it red very simple
the impersonation levels there are four
impersonation levels but only useful for
us for privilege escalation are the last
two ones
another thing that one your token is
created you cannot add new privileges
obviously no but you can enable or
disable privileges you can also
duplicate tokens
so from a primary token you can
duplicate it and get an impersonation
token and vice versa which are the
counts that have special privileges I
said it before
obviously administrators local system
has maybe not not all privileges but
most of them then some built-in groups
backup operator printer operators sever
operators okay local service and virtual
accounts managed service account usually
they have very very interesting
privileges they have impersonation and
assign primary token privileges we will
see this more later then third third
party application users and sometimes it
can happen misconfigured use it because
a lazy admin playing with the GP GP edit
console clicked on the wrong button and
assigned a privilege to a user who
didn't who doesn't need to have this
privilege for example this is the backup
exec utility and in the specification of
this utility three privileges are
required backup and restore obviously
because it is a backup utility and also
the TCB privilege actors parting also
act as part of operating system this
means that we have granted to this user
the right to access everywhere to have
full control on our machine okay how can
we count these privileged accounts so
the techniques I think you know better
than me because I'm not a pen tester all
these techniques but basically weak
service configuration remote code
execution everything that I everything
that gives me the possibility to gain
access like a user who has special
privileges so stealing credentials
man-in-the-middle via and LM and so on
Kerberos ting etc
etc there is also another possibility to
get privileges and manipulate tokens by
using exploits
the most interesting one are the last
two partial rights and arbitrary words
this has successfully been demonstrated
that with partial rights I can activate
or betray rights I can activate
additional privileges on my token so if
I am a simple user but I can exploit a
binary who has some weakness I came from
the userland interact interact with the
kernel in the a process structure and
activate some privileges so this is
another very very interesting so my talk
is not about how to get them and so on
my talk the goal of my talk and I hope
we'll meet this goal is to show you with
some practical examples
once you have one god privilege how you
can abuse from them from this privilege
okay and so let's start with the first
one I think that the back privilege all
of you know the debug privilege this is
the simplest and the most powerful
privilege because what and it's not me
that that I'm saying this but a guy from
Microsoft more than ten years ago said
if you grant somebody the debug
privilege you gave it away the farm
because why is this possible because the
debug privilege was given to be able to
debug a process but not only my process
a process of every user or system
administrator does not import so once I
can debug a process obviously I can
inject code in this process inject
malicious code in this project execute
the code in order to get a shell or
whatever else so these are the
well-known api's for interacting with
remote threads writing to the memory and
so on
one other interesting way to abuse from
this privilege is to set the parent
process a privileged process because
starting from Windows Vista it is
possible to modify the parent process of
a other other process and to set the
process to another user
so if with the debug privilege I can
spawn my process and tell to my process
that the parent process is a process for
example belong to system and with this
simple powershell script i'll published
it on github but you can do it in many
other ways as you can see it's getting
system with debug privilege is as easy
as drinking a bottle of water it's very
very easy so it's a very powerful
privilege with which needs special very
special attention don't grant debug
privilege ok the restor privilege ok
what what what means this privilege this
privilege grants you to perform restore
of files but not only fights also
registry keys what does this mean that
with with this restored privilege i can
access files which normally i could not
access and this is you can imagine very
very powerful to api's and millions of
possibility create file and ragga create
the important thing is to have the
restored privilege enable the restore
privilege and to use this simple flag in
minor api so I'm telling to the
operating system and I am performing a
store and he permits me to do everything
I want
ok I can even overwrite in the system 32
directory where you know all files are
owned by trusted installer so it's very
difficult to overwrite them all checks
are bypassed so I can overwrite this
file so how can I do privilege
escalation with this privilege I
there are millions of possibility I will
show you one very simple example I will
modify the configuration of a service
which runs under the system account and
is startled by all users and then get
back a red shell the service in question
is the yum-yum a WAP Push service I hope
that my spelling is correct because I
don't never know how to spell in English
some words as you can see this service
in red is startled by all users this is
very good so we have a service that
transfers like the system is startled by
each user we have rest or privileges so
obviously what are we going to do we
create our service DLL which doesn't do
what windows expect but will simply
launch by a batch file which contains my
reverse shell once my shell a once my
DLL is compiled I simply put this DLL in
the system32 directory and I will change
the parameters of the Reg of the service
configured in the registry I will
overwrite the the service DLL parameter
not more pointing to the original DLL
Mott but to my DLL and once I'm done I
will copy it in system32 but I could
also launch it from another one
allocation just to show you that it's
possible or if I'm very bad guy I could
overwrite the original DLL because I can
do it even it is protected by Trustees
dollar I have also a short video about
this and this is it it's very simple I'm
not a good video maker I have an
elevated shell so I have the restore
privilege all I do is putting this piece
of code in my XA and do it
I have overwritten the service DLL and
now I start the service because I can do
it ok and now let's verify I had back
connection and I'm system very easy do
you agree
Becca privilege this is the opposite one
okay
again with this privilege I can backup
file so I can access file which normally
could not access because I'm performing
a backup operation again I will use the
same api's because backup software used
is api's and i could can do many of
nasty things with it for example I can
backup the Sun database of the local
registry because with the Reg you till
'ti if I am bad if I have the backup
operators it permits me to save the
system hive and the Sam hive and then
with one of the tools in this example
example I'm using mimikatz but you can
use other tools I can dump the hashes of
the NA TLM database and so get the
hashes of a local administrator and so
on
I can also access files which I not
could not access again create with the
create file API just specifying the flag
backup semantics and I'm able in this
case to read the file of local
administrator members of backup
operators on domain controller can
backup also the NTDs dot did file so the
entire active database directory and
they can do it because this is this file
as you know you cannot access this file
bit is blocked because it is in use but
using backup software you can backup the
database in this case I'm using VB admin
as a normal user only with Becca
privilege I saved and I make a backup
copy of the NTDs dot did file and then
with one of the values tools I get the
boot key and then I dumped all the
hashes in this case the hashes of the
domain admin of the data of this
database so is the backup operators I
can get domain admin without problem
I can also use another utility I don't
know how many of you know of this
utility
it's the disk shadow utility which is
very useful because unlike versus admin
you don't need to be admin to launch
them but you can backup also with
disability the NTDs dot deep database in
this case i make a backup then i copy
the database because i cannot access the
database but i copy all a swiss create
file and backup option on an other
directory and then again I get the boot
key and I can dump all the users ok
there is also which I call special bonus
because if you have backup if you have
if you are a member of backup operators
you automatically have two privileges
back up and restore privileges and with
these two privileges combined you can
also change the access control list of
each file and event registry or
directory and this is also very very
powerful in this example I changed via
PowerShell script this file is only it's
owned and only the administrator has
full control on it I can change the
access lead and try and grant to myself
the right to access to the file
the take ownership
is not a god privilege huai because as
microsoft says says this privilege
allows you to take ownership of a
security leak security real object in
the system 280 eyes set security info or
set name security info in the first one
I have to pass the handle in the second
one he acted the name of the resource of
the object I want to take ownership
there exist many types of many object
types file printer shares registry keys
and so on and once again the ownership
of the file here what I can change the
permission and then the same rules apply
like for example the restored privilege
so in this example I will show you I
will change the parameters of the MSI
server service which is a service which
normal users can always start so first
of all I will take the ownership of the
registry key one I took the ownership of
the registry key referring to this
service I will create an access list
which permits for keeping it simple to
everyone to access completely this
registry key in read and write and once
I have said the permission I alter the
service and I say and I will launch
instead of the original access for
example a command which will add myself
to local domain local administrator
groups these are the privilege
is very very powerful too because it's a
god privilege - what does this privilege
says Microsoft says this privilege is
act like as an operating system what
does this mean that with privilege I can
impersonate I can obtain a token for
every user without specifying
credentials and the other cool thing is
that I can add supplementary accesses to
my token for example I can add to my
token other groups so if I have a normal
user I can add to my token the
membership to local administrator this
is very very powerful but we have a
problem because I can get this powerful
token but I'm not able to impersonate it
because in order to impersonate the
token I need special privilege which is
impersonation privilege I have only this
one privilege so how can I do it we know
that it is possible to impersonate a
thread as long as the token is mine and
integrity level of the token is less or
equal to the process who launches the
who's lounge to the originating process
and Microsoft added other constraints
starting from Windows 10 but there is a
good news we can impersonate the trade
in these conditions we can impersonate a
thread without any privileges and
bypassing inuring completely all this
constraint and why is this possible
because of this as long as the resulting
token origin ID equals the arm the
authentication ID of the original thing
process and this is always the case all
other checks are bypassed because the
kernel the first thing checks is ok with
what is the token origin ID and what is
the authentication again are they the
same ok go you can impersonate the
thread
so and you don't have any limitations
that's cool now I have some examples
prepared some example to show you how to
abuse from these privileges in the first
two I will the MS v1 as for you logon
extension this is the extension that we
need to call in order to impersonate the
user calling the LSA logon user function
and in the other case I will use the
Kerberos extension so I will can
impersonate the domain admin in the
first example I will impersonate myself
so I will get back a token from with my
user by but I will add as an extra group
the administrator group to my token and
once I have this token I will
impersonate a thread with this token and
grant to myself the debug privilege
because I love the debug privilege or I
can in your completely what matters of
says because the to originate and
occasionally are the same I will
impersonate administrator and I will add
myself to the local domain at a local
administrator group the last example
using Kerberos domain authentication I
will impersonate a domain admin as a
domain user with TCP privilege
I will person to domain admin and right
in the system 32 directory as you can
see the last one is very very easy if
you do it in c-sharp two lines of code
very very easy to abuse from so I don't
think I need other explanation this is
the other example where I used the MSP
one extension and @ln authentication
okay so I can impersonate TCP user
administrator I will can add an extra
seat typically this is the seed of the
local administrator group call my
function Alessi my API call
Alessia logon user okay and passing the
groups and well and I will get I will
get back this wonderful token
which I called H token as for you which
I can then impersonate in a thread and
do all - nasty things for example in the
first one I will add a privilege at the
debug privilege to my token and in the
second one to my user and in the second
one I will grant myself I will put
myself in the local administrator group
because I have a video about this I have
two videos you trust in what I'm saying
yes okay I will show you another video
this is more a joke I made with my sis
admin colleagues because I told them we
make a bet as a local administrator I
will impersonate a guest account and act
like a domain admin they told me now you
are crazy it's not possible okay if I'm
able to do it you will pay me a bottle
of Italian red wine okay and this is
what I did local admin guest user
account enabled I launched my
silly program the a please okay so I am
user guest let's show my groups and
that's you can see I'm member of domain
admins is it true okay so because they
didn't trust me okay let me show you
this one I go in the administrator
directory of the domain admin as guest
user it should be impossible to get to
get in No and then only the main admin
can access this file and this was it and
evening after I drank a fantastic Red
Vines a grantee know it comes from
Umbria where I live this is clearly more
a joke because as you can imagine with
TCP privilege I can alter can put groups
everything I want so I could do it in
many other ways but just to get them
they were really really scared after
this demo create token privilege is an
as the word says the privilege which is
granted to create a token so I can
create a token with the specific API and
adhered that I will create a token and I
can create a custom token putting
everything inside
I want privileges groups and so on so
also this one is very very powerful it's
the god privilege I can use this token
without impersonation privileges if the
token is mine and so on okay and this is
great but we have a problem starting and
this is something I discovered two weeks
ago starting from the windows 1809 or
Windows
nineteen server this doesn't work
anymore
even if I have the create token
privilege I'm not able to impersonate it
and this is the error I get back as you
can see I created a fantastic token
because I put administrator and trusted
installer in my token so I could go
everywhere in the file system but it
didn't work
because if I tried to write a file in
the system32 directory I got an access
denied and the problem was that the
impersonation level is invalid what does
this mean that probably the kernel
demoted my token to an identification
token which is a real beautiful token
but I cannot impersonate it so this is
what this was very really sad for me
because I thought but there should be a
possibility it's not possible that it
doesn't work after some tests
I discovered this one that if I said the
outset the authentication ID and we
create token I can set the
authentication ID to the anonymous login
ID this one with 7 is the system ID so
it's the system login ID if I set it to
out anonymous authentication ID again
like the other trick Windows doesn't
make other check because it's an
anonymous authentication so it's it's
not the dangerous token because it's a
noun anonymous you can do and you can
normally you can do you can do anything
with this token but no because in this
token I put special groups you cannot
use everything but some a subset of API
calls works and especially these two one
create file and drag create key so again
you have the key of the kingdom spec but
you can alter a service do everything
with it so some sometimes Microsoft
fixes but they don't care about what
they
and thought it would it could not be
break broken okay 15 minutes okay this
is the API call as you can see I can
pass the authentication ID so if I pass
down on you most authentication ID I
have create Oken privilege it's okay I
can go on the load drive a privilege
what does this privilege mean that you
can load kernel drivers okay
how can you abuse from in first of all
load driver privilege is granted to the
div by default to the printer operators
of the domain controller this is very
cool to abuse from this driver obviously
I need to load the driver which has some
vulnerabilities that I that I have to
exploit otherwise it wouldn't be
possible and you have also to trick the
antelope driver function to load the
parameters of this driver not from the
classical system32 system hive but from
another hive because I cannot write in a
system hive and this example I will show
you how you can abuse using known
vulnerability of a recent one ability of
the driver of an anti-malware software
stopzilla this driver is known to be
vulnerable it's a sign driver it cut it
gets not caught by antivirus so you can
abuse from it I create a special
registry under my local profile and then
tell to until Oh driver to load the
parameters of this driver from this hive
which is under my control and we send it
a load driver I load the driver and if
everything works
I get the driver load it okay and then I
will use an exploit for this driver
which I modified a little bit and this
is interesting because in this exploit
you have to change to privileges the
load driver privilege and the create
token because it's an arbitrary right
right which activates you the create
token privilege so I can obtain the
token I obtained this privilege and then
I add my
self to the local administrator group so
this is an example of how abusing from
this driver okay finally the last two
ones the in percent assigned primary
token these are also very powerful
privileges because they permits you to
impersonate an access token so if we are
able to get an access token from a
period user you can impersonate them
with these two privileges assign primary
we can impersonate a process or
privilege you can impersonate the
process or a thread in personal
privilege cause the create process with
token API which permits you to launch a
process but it relies on the secondary
logon server service so if the secondary
learn several is not running you cannot
use this run the assignment token is
also interesting because it's available
in a medium integrity level process you
can see what sort of nasty things you
could do with these privileges how can
we get this privilege token because we
have impersonation or sign primary we
need to get the token of a privileged
user well there are so many ways to do
it the classic ways is the unnamed pipe
if you force a privileged process to
write a name pipe which is each each is
under your control
once the privileged process rights in
your pipe you intercept it impersonate
the thread get the token and then you
can do everything with this one or via
and local and ELN authentication which
is very very interesting or the adikam
RPC callbacks the killer expla exploit
for these two privileges is the rotten
potatoes know how many of you knows
about these previous robot is exploit
you will already know it okay this is a
fantastic
exploit and basically it's this one if
you request the initialization of the
atacama object using a fake storage
object you can reflect the RPC
communication to a local and
point which is under your control and
TWEN and tln local authentication of
cure you modified the until and message
in order to establish the secret in
context once you have established the
security context you are able to get the
token and with the privilege we
impersonated if I impersonate a local
system authentication I have the token
of the system users and I am I have the
maximum of privileges there has been
also an exploit published three years
ago and it's still working and this
original exploit relied on a meteor
patter incognito there were other
standalone variants me too I wrote two
variants which didn't rely on this one
but or standalone but there was a
problem first of all the decom server
was fixed it was the bits at the
background intelligent transfer service
and the second one was that also the
local listing port was fixed on 666 okay
and during a Windows desktop padding
review my friends at pay found a week
service configuration gained access with
these privileges but the rotten potato
didn't not work because the mid server
was unavailable and the local port was
firewalled so we decided together to
produce this one the juicy potato how
many of you could knows about this great
we discovered that other than bits there
were other out of possums come servers
which could been abused important thing
is that they run as local system they
can be instantiated by a service user
and then they expose the I Marshall
interface because all the magic occurs
during the unmarshal of the object there
we discover also that were interesting
clsid which impersonates the user
connected to first session so if i have
a domain administrator connected i can
using the clsid impersonate directly the
domain administrator is cool
you can see the typical setup of a
perfect deacon server what does our tool
do it's what published last year you can
choose a clsid you can define a
listening port because in order to do
that we had to change the string binding
of the marshal interface pointer
structure you can define also an
external air PC port and IP address and
in this do if you have a machine under
your control the authentication will be
totally silent because in the lock and
even viewer there will be no trace of
your authentication system your abuse of
this exploit the program to launch with
optional argument then if you want to
use the one or two process modes you
want to use and also you produce the
list of clsid for every Windows version
you can find it here on them on the
github and recently it was or it is also
available at as Metasploit module ok ok
this is an example of some of this and I
will show you a short video also about
this I have gained and chairman D speaks
shell ok my user is the Iast typical
default approval user who has these
privileges so I will launch my juicy
potato is in the clsid the interesting
one
I'm lab I'm domain administrator very
easy so this is because it's very mmm
how can you say disrupting is privileged
and also I asked Microsoft Hema what can
I do in order to prevent this one the
first thing is that like reading The
Lancet they were not aware of this kind
of exploit it seemed strange to me but
it was and after some exchange of email
they told you why we are working hard on
it but probably as Microsoft says the
behavior is by design so we cannot
change this ok and the last email in the
current model we can know we can give no
hardening if recommendation because you
cannot fix this one maybe in a next
version disease was the last male and
then Microsoft closed the chasm so is it
possible to prevent it yes and no
obviously protect sensitive accounts
this seems obvious now or end your
application disable unnecessary service
in Windows 2 2016 the Xbox game service
which runs a system was enabled so you
have to tell me what the hell does I
that does do I need the Xbox service on
a Windows Server it's crazy and then
restrict the permissions it could be an
option but it could be very dangerous or
disabled they come at all but here again
you could run into several several
problems so the good news for the
defenders is if you upgrade to Windows
1809 or Windows 2019 the exploit does no
more work
because they fix it it's no more
possible to do oxyde resolving using a
port different than 135 and so they
finally fix it so but there are several
windows 26 2016 servers there are
several windows 10 desktop with version
smaller than this one so the problem
remains final thoughts from the attacker
perspective
never underestimate obviously these
privileges especially in elevated shell
and in Windows pre versions if you have
to these two systems these two
privileges you are automatically system
this is what we call the golden
privilege and service user are more
safeties and security features maybe
there are other interesting privilege to
abuse from probably yes
there are some new privileges which no
one knows exactly and what they do so
it's another there are an atom you can
explore other privileges so we have four
minutes that's all I hope that you
enjoyed my talk that it was heard and
special thanks to this person yes