[Music]
hi
everyone welcome to our talk autosphere
i'm delighted to tell you something
interesting about the worst bypassing in
this talk i will show how long draw-offs
are allowing attackers to cause splendid
damage
okay i'm jinxing a graduated student at
georgian university and xiaomi is a
research associated at iscs
and tremen wu
my supervisor is a professor at georgian
university
and this is the agenda of our talk
firstly i will introduce the background
of our talk including web attacks and
raf
and secondly i will introduce the
traditional methods and existing tools
that are commonly employed to bypass
graphs
however i will show the shortcomings of
these tools
and thirdly i will introduce our attack
framework autosphere it can be used to
generate sql injection pairs to bypass
the target off efficiently and
effectively
then i will proven to
present some results of autosphere
against the silent commercial wi-fi
service from mainstream vendors
and as a responsible researcher i will
detail our vulnerability discussion
progress
and finally i will conclude this talk
ok let's begin in this part i will
introduce some background
as we all know web services are being
exposed to worldwide threats with rest
methods here are the top 10 web security
risks amongst them injection is one of
the most dangerous attack measures
with injection attacks
hackers can send untrusted payloads to
the web storage
and
they can steal information or take
control of the underlying system
example for sql injection and cross-site
scripting
the gndi injection is also crucial
attack method which is the
exploit method of log for shell in this
talk i will use injection text to
present this talk
and to mitigate a malicious request like
sql injection the web application fellow
akwaf is one of the most widely used and
effective defensive systems
normally one is default deployed in the
front of the rg server
that any requests
from clients must be detected and
filtered by this graph
already requested that the detect data
as benign will be forwarded to the
oriented server for further processing
and generally buff can be categoried
into
two types that is a signature based off
and the machining results
the formal one is the traditional but
effective it takes advantage of rest
rules predefined by domain experts
to detect and block
emergency requests
recently motivated by the greater
success of machining
a variety of machining baseballs has
been proposed and implemented
moreover with the development of cloud
computing wi-fi the service under one as
one kind of security as a service
has been proposed to
facilitate the deployment configuration
and update of the traditional ones
the administrator who manages who
manages web services only needed to
redirect their
requests from clients to the interface
interfaces or wi-fi the service
provided by windows so that admissions
request can be detected and filtered
before sending to the origin server
and here i will employ a funny example
to illustrate how frequently vaf is used
in the cloud
when i submitted my content my session
content i was blocked by the cloud flyer
used by blackheads.com so i had to
change my content to order being blocked
by this wife
okay
so both are the
here i will introduce some by wifi
passing methods including
manual and automatically ways
and they're shortcomings
as of needed to trade off between the
false positive rate and the false
negative rate buffer cannot rudely
intercept all suspected emissions
requests
this condition give attackers an
opportunity to perform
attacks
and the attackers can bypass a waffle
in many ways such as
his architecture level
he can just access the original server
or he can send his payrolls in chunks
today we focus on the most common and
universal way that is we can mutate the
original payload
as shown in this example we can generate
the original payload
and test the generated periods by
changing the case of letters
or just adding some comments
a neutral question is
how can we automated this progress of
generating and testing
are the existing tools or methods
usable firstly i will introduce some
semi-auto tools of ninja provides a
single point of function test for sql
injection and process scripting
with it we can further test
we can
perform a function test with the sql
induction payload
which continuously replace fast with the
values in the database
however even if we find a valid keyword
what will still block the entire payload
after being inserted to the entire
payload
unless the most suffocated attackers may
consider a modifier multiple defaulting
tests after constructing
its original payload
it may effective sometimes
finder attackers need to manually
specify the keywords and the
replacements before each attack it
requires stomach expertise and is
deliberate
besides this method is similar to brutal
search it is inefficient
and sql sqlmap as an excellent sql
injection testing tool comes with many
of bypassing template scripts when using
sql map
an attacker can specify some scripts
such as equal to like random comments or
upper case
however
attackers need to choose temperature
manually just like i said
and
sqlmap cannot select them intelligently
besides multiple temples can also work
well together the templars can only
mutate all locations within the payload
so above worker present valuable
concepts are semi-auto off bypassing
next i will introduce some latest
research on fully auto developed
bypassing firstly
dimitrov proposed the wi-fi mode it has
a tool that can avoid the machine and
visible valve
the frozen predefined seven stream-based
sql ejection
payload mutation operators like a key
swapping committee injection and
operating swapping
afterwards the employer priority cube is
the opportunity method to gather the
mutation progress
specifically of a mole repeatedly
mutates the initial payload
multiple times to generate several pills
so it selects the payload with the
lowest mercury score as the initial one
for the next round
until it bypasses the target above all
which is the termination condition
and inspire the work of our iridium
mobile detectors with reinforcement
range
while it all proposed the wi-fi vision
framework with the reinforcement ring
approach
after training
the reinforcement the new agent can
select an optimal mutator operator
according to the current data of the sql
injection payload
and the in fact they have followed the
mutant operators in
rafael
besides hematite atop improved the work
from one
in several aspects including expanding
their
the mutation operator space and
they have defined some
some data based on the faster text
embedding model and so on
i was about worker has some shortcomings
uh according to the chrome sig
hierarchical the stream-based mutation
method in your ball works
cannot fully cover the attack pillows
that is it it may make some key parts of
the payload when generating adversary
payrolls
specifically
here is a
code snippet of a mutation operator in
of ammo
it can search for technology in the in
the payload and replace data with other
steps out authority such as mutator one
equals one to
one dash one does not equal two
however if we add a space next to the
next to the equal sign in the payload
offering more wound to not will not
recognize it
besides of emo may then evaluate the
entire payload for example it may mutate
the alex into r equal
and at the same time the priority cube
is the
optimization method and the
reinforcement based methods are not
suitable for attacking real world ones
as their output is binary besides the
gradient based optimization in adversary
machining
is also
not suitable for our problem special tag
to sum up it's imperative to do as a
generously semantic preserving mutation
method we should preserve the original
functionality and the measurements of
the initial one
besides we should
design some auto operation method
suitable for blackbox attack it should
be trimming free and it can generate it
to different walls
okay in this section i will introduce
our proposal framework autosphere it can
automatically bypass and inspecting
the target valve
normally http consists of four elements
that is the
scheme the domain name and the password
file and the parameters with multiple
pairs
of k and value
as the process of sql injection attack
is limited to the parameter values
and keep other parts unchanged
because that we should generate secure
injection pairs based on the original
one that therefore autosphere should are
not only
to be limited to be limited to the
payload of the original sql injection
but it also ensures that the generated
circuit ejection has the same
functionality and maliciousness as the
original one
to handle it according to the different
rows of different parts in the original
sql injection we divided the original
sql injection pillow into three modules
that has the left boundary of the query
as the red boundary
and we thought we further emitted the
attack surface of auto sphere to the
query part
both the boundaries the left boundary
and the right boundary are restricted to
unchanged so that the functionality of
the original and secure injection is
preserved
the query is a call module and it's
needed to be further processed
i'm sorry
small
instead of simply treating the query as
a string as a sequence of strings we
first represented it with a hierarchical
tree
we argue that on the basically of the
heritage representation we can perform
one fundraiser and customer processing
for each node
according to their unique
characteristics and constraints
i think it called fascinated the
generation of adversarial sql ejection
payrolls
besides
we propose a weighted mutation strategy
based on the context of free gram
we can use it to generate a set of
candidates as a result rascal ejection
payroll
and the generated payroll keeps the same
functionality as malicious nurse as our
original one
we formulated the cft grammars for each
semantic type
of the sql ejection hybrid tree
for example as shown in this figure the
tutorial of
y equals y in order to
can be transformed by context of grammar
into
uh into a broad expression that in order
to be true
or to charge in other formats
and we can mutate the escrow injection
payload at the atomic level without
breaking the original semantics that is
we can keep the same functionality and
the merchants
and there was about representation under
the context-free grammar in addition to
carrying the mutation operators in
existing methods and tools we proposed
several novel and practical mutation
operators according to the latest tech
blocks
and we employ some color research
algorithm together our searching process
that is combining the mutation
replacements of each node the monocular
research is to continuously build a sub
tree where each node represents a state
of the ethical reduction hierarchy and
the ages correspond to transformations
okay here is an example
after a few rounds of the game we select
the current best child of level 2 which
passes 3b under 5a specifically
through b is to mutate the white space
in row 3
to command 4.
and the first way is to mutate the equal
in node file to inline comment afterward
we perform an expression progress that
is randomly selecting
4 8 and generating the number three at
the child of number two
so we finished the surrounding of the
mirror again by simulation that is
randomly mutating multiple times by
reaching the limit
at this time we interact with the target
wave to obtain the current
classification result of the malicious
confidence score and the update all
parent nodes based on the number of
visits
as a result from the off
and in the end we output the payload
corresponding to the final state of the
multi-car circuitry here is the final
generated payload
okay now i will present the results our
autosphere against
selling commercial wi-fi the service
from mainstream vendors besides by
performing our
several case studies i will analyze and
inspect some general deficiencies on
wi-fi the service amongst its wonders
we first manually constructed about 100
escrow injection payload
of common methods including universal
injection aerobic injection and blending
injection
and these petals are used to verify the
semantics of the generated appearance
and then we find the two commonly used
datasets from kegel and github
these pills are used to evaluate our
otakus success rate
okay firstly to compare the semantics of
the payload before and after mutating we
first deploy multiple runtime
environments as shown in this page such
as
disk space in multiple versions and
background scripts in person and php
and by observing the execution results
of the payloads we can
prove that our autosphere will not
invade the generated appearance that is
all pairs generated can maintain their
original semantics
okay then we deploy seven months from
these windows that is the nws49 i5
server security cloud volume cloudflare
and motor security and we send our
pillows to them with four commonly user
request method
specifically as our modified backend
available service supporter for commonly
http request method that is a guidepost
under their
json types
we find two and the mutation process in
autosphere to prevent semantics
across different request methods
that is
for example the slash n should be
encoded either percentage0a in for
non-json requests
and the hash sign cannot be presented in
comments
when we're sending the payloading web
get
okay here are the
other results firstly is the force
negative region the fnr
fmr directly reflects the protection
effectiveness of our waves
laminate both its obliqus and call flyer
have fans of over 60 percent
on the calgary design
that is more than 60 percent of
mauritius requests will be directly
forwarded to the backend service
further we can divide the last thing
into four categories based on their
responses to different request methods
for example the cloud flyer replace
repair implies means different
strategies
based on so whether the request is where
get or post
and itambas processes the payloads
separately uh according wisest request
parameter is
in json type it's a motor security
processes requests will get changing
separately
and here are the attackers success rate
the asr the sra l-stress reporting is
our award for organ but the warsaw
attacks our attacks
against wi-fi the service in the car is
successful
the aisles against the aws
on the cargo data side you can reach the
99 percent
besides we can find that when requesting
weber service injection type of
parameters esrs are much higher than
non-json it's a greater security risk
given the current deployment trend of
web services
that has more and more web services are
designed based on the decal powder
architecture
which most always use the json to
transform the data
and if a waffle shows higher
efficiency it always enters that the
protective effect is entered
unsatisfactory
if the fms or water is low but the esrs
are relatively high it means that the
wife cannot defend against the world
structured adversarial tax
the asrsr our e-12 has a similar
distribution to fmrs which led to the
foreign conclusion for example
the forwards hosted on aws are less
capable of
providing sql ejection the volume is
effective because it has low iphone and
asr both and photonics has
as many times higher than ethanol which
means that it cannot defend against
adversarial attacks very well
however we must stress that
so both results and the results and the
rankings are obtained with our limited
settings and
samples
it cannot fully represent the actual
different effects against all samples in
the world all these vendors
and here i will play a short video
to show the autobots attacking effect of
auto spear
okay uh here we first deploy
web source on dvw
on aws ec2
and then we create a load balancer to
access the web service
here we can access the web service
that's a normal request
and now with the texas web service by
sql injection
y equals one it is
as then we can steal some information
from the website such as the
database name
and the column name
sorry it's the table name
here is a column name
and even we can steal the data in the
in the database
the encrypted
password we can decrypt it
and the above attacks are against the
unprotected website
now we enable and configure the
item sr
first i will create a access control
list
and either our load balancer
then we add some rules provided by aws
for example the
call center the knowing body inputs
under the sql database
all of them are used to prevent escrow
injections
okay we have opened and configured the
aws one
now we already attack the pillows
okay the wife is on
here is the original payload it is
blocked by the aws one
all pillows are blocked
and the normal request still works
and now we use autosphere to attack the
hws one with three simple steps
firstly copy the url of the target off
that is the target web service
and secondly writes a
desired pillow to the configuration file
and finally just around the script
we can find that within several seconds
all the pillows are
attackers are successful
okay here are the generated apparels
let's test them one by one
here is the original one it is blocked
by the aws lab
and here is the generated one
okay we can now we can bypass 8.
okay what can be bypassed successfully
and we have found that all the generated
payrolls that kind bypass the awf alpha
are being added to some control symbols
we can manually add some control symbols
to bypass the aws one
there's a
session can
let me
go to the file from the password holder
system
and we can even write a website to the
target web service
okay
here is a php info
and we can execute the system
terminations
and the
directory is double a
okay
let's continue
here are more examples we select three
representative pillars which can
still table name column name and the
sensitive information from the protected
website
just selecting the video we can
replace replace white space with control
symbols like the
slash cheat session we can bypass aw as
well and further first of all just the
idea of
a commenter
or turn
dml into inline comments we can bypass
the i5 on the call flyer
and as a ball commercial off a black box
we further investigate the exact reason
of bypassing by monitoring the audit
drugs or motor security
the multi-security is built and deployed
by us
take a
ticket to the escrow injection panel as
an example
we need to buy the two engines at the
same time
that is a semantic
analyzer engine under the regular
mentioned laser engine you can find that
adjuster id or selector zero or you can
bypass the label injection
under idle comment
we can bypass motor security completely
in summary this case studies froze away
from our conjunction whether the
detection signatures are non-robust
causing thorough vulnerabilities
and based on the hierarchical traits
during
attacking we present the effective
mutation method for wi-fi the source in
the cloud
uh you can see that i mean this table
for example the
uh just adding some comments we can
bypass forwards
under specific pills
and the lucky attackers come manually
using this conclusion to bypass some
wealth however the effective mutations
for specific graphs under different
pairs are unique that is
only a combination of multiple mutations
for specific locations takes efforts
uh that is auto sphere is much more
effective in bypassing the mainstream
offer as a storage solution
because
this wi-fi as a service has a vulnerable
detection signatures for both
symmetrical matching and the regular
expression machine
and then now here are the feedback from
mainstream windows
we reported our findings with the
affected vendors by submitting
vulnerability reports and contacting
their technical support staff and the
security researchers up until now f5
called the flyer and volume have
mitigated the frozen and the other
four a still working with us
as the flow of the way we found cannot
be easily packed
and for example the security incident
response team or i5
have mitigated
to fraud the reported bias within yms
nazi how added our names to their
official website
okay
to sum up we have proved that wifi is
the source from mixed frames
mainstream windows can be bypassed in a
fully automatic and intelligent manner
and specifically we propose autosphere
which utilizes a semantic-based mutation
strategy and a heuristic switching
strategy suitable for black box attacks
and we have to summarize the worst
underlying message of waves in the wider
and there are actual different effects
based on our limited
samples and
settings in addition we disclose some
general bypass patterns
that
defenders can use them to employ you can
use them to improve their products
okay thank you for your attention i will
now take some questions from the
audience
thank you very much
um the first question is from tian
yuitang
he's asking if how do you configure this
waf in your evaluation
and are they all in default settings
okay
thanks for your valuable question
in fact we have
we have deployed
uh sorry uh
we have deployed our own websites and
databases on the google cloud platform
and protecting them utilizing the data
service in turn
the waves are
following their default configuration
specifically
for the aws 49er i500 cyber security
cloud these four they require manual
rules configuration and we have enabled
call reciter that is suitable for
protection against the owasp top 10
attacks and there are advanced rule
setters for sql injection
[Music]
you