[Music]
hello hi welcome um
sorry it's probably got it was the worst
time for my internet to get stuck uh
it's a very good start this presentation
welcome everyone to our talk um my name
is michals magnetakos
i'm associate professor with new york
university in abu dhabi i do work in
industrial social security as you see
from this talk and joining me is uh
santa rasput
uh who's a currently phd candidate with
nyu uh working actually the masters of
this project and i'm just here doing
introduction taking credit but uh
prasant is the main
person who has done all this work
so uh coming back to the the talk today
the title is non-intrusive localization
and hot passing in the control systems
so the first thing we need to do is to
to properly define what is interesting
control system and i do assume that many
of you already know what it is so i'll
be very brief in discussing that so the
name says industrial control systems are
systems that typically control
industrial processes so you can think of
them as computers regular computers that
are pretty that are hard and not as
regular as what we have in front of us
um and they're employed in in conditions
with harsh environments right uh like
increased temperatures electromagnetic
interference
uh so
you may have heard the 10 plc
programming velocity controller we see a
few of this today scada and so on and so
forth so these systems appear
a lot in critical infrastructure you may
have heard the term smart grid
that's the smart part implies that we
have those small computers
that can be used in order to
improve performance improve automation
um
many many things that you can do with
that right so what in the past was uh
pulitz electromechanical now we have
smart devices uh doing that
so uh in terms of
smartness what i'm trying to say is that
we have more and more digitization we
have what we have seen as industry 4.0
uh integrating automation and data many
of the decision or the control systems
are being taken by the system themselves
and the human is the human factor uh has
limited input in the process so it's
much more automated
but this smartness comes from having
smart computers and smart computers or
computers right imply
something like a regular operating
system for example so nowadays we see a
lot of modern ics with regular general
purpose operating systems so when you
have an operating system uh that's
regular like linux right with a
real-time patch
then you have um
functionality that is amazing for a user
such as ftp as a state access and so on
and so forth but at the same time
anything that is a problem in the ap
world like out of bounds in the rights
um
buffer overflows now can be used in the
in the ot world in the person technology
world or ics so and this is why we're
here right that's why we're trying to to
see and do
uh trying to protect the
plcs the systems against um
regular attacks
and the problem is is exaggerated
because those systems are not typically
updated right we don't really upgrade
the firmware it's hard to have a proper
patching mechanism uh so many of these
devices have outdated firmware so any id
threat from the past like even block for
day that we saw the availability right i
mean they will take years for many of
these devices to get past
uh so many of them can be exploited but
of course what saves the systems
currently is the fact that there's
limited access to that but once you're
in the it side you try to jump to the ot
and then you have you can get access to
that at the same time we don't design ss
for security so vulnerabilities can
affect the runtime and we cannot just
install an antivirus to that right uh
the device have limited computational
power so we're trying to see
better ways to defense and defend
against our stretch
so
what we're trying to do here is that you
know we say we cannot patch right well
um
there are reasons you cannot pass but
you cannot just avoid uh not i mean
avoid passing so what you're trying to
say here is yes you just have pets
and passing may mean restarting that's
something we don't like either so in
this talk we focus on hot patching so
how do you actually fix vulnerabilities
without restarting uh and prasan will
give you a few more details about that
but let me also briefly
before we dive into the details of
um
of hot patching that we'll do in this
talk a little bit information about the
runtime itself and what we'll be
focusing on so we'll talk about plcs
modern plc is typically regular
computers with a runtime on top like a
virtual machine you can think of it as a
virtual machine
that it's like a process that reads
from the sensor computes does some
actuation and then does the scan cycle
again and again in this scan cycle you
can think of it again as another process
in the operating system in this iec
application
uh and this application shares the
process memory with a runtime so on the
right side you see
our hardware layer cpu and then the
linux operating system with the
real-time patch and then the contest
runtime but you know enough with the
boring stuff i think this is now time
for prasant to take over and show you a
demo of what we're trying to say here
prasan the floor is yours
thanks mahalis so before we go into the
details of the batching let us try to
motivate the problem with uh an example
so we have
an experiment set up here where we have
a msf designation plant model working in
simulink which is regularly sending
inputs sensor inputs to the plc which in
our case is fargo pfc100 so as you can
see here the inputs and outputs are
being updated regularly
so for simulating an attack we uh
we create a function here which we can
enable with a single bit
uh now upon enabling it at the hundredth
operation cycle the attack will actually
send a signal which in this case is just
the temporary size to the plc and the
plc will then execute a specific if loop
let us not focus on the attack but look
at the impact of the attack because
that's the main point that we want to
make here so
the iec application or the control
application will write a non-zero value
at a specific offset on the stack in our
case it's four six four nine so let's
see what
exactly happens when when when that
that occurs
so when we fast forward
we see that as soon as the attack hits
the
okay as soon as the attack hits the ic
application stops updating the input and
output
so why does this exactly happen
so uh we uh did an attack where we
overwrote some important information on
the correspondent time stack how did we
do that we use pointers in structure
text the static checks on the propriety
compiler are not the best so you can
easily do stuff like that in structure
text and the impact is that we
completely skipped the execution of the
control application and that's why the
inputs and outputs were not being
updated so why does this happen
this is the disassembly of
assembly of a function that is executed
before plc prg you can imagine plc prg
to be a function just similar to the
main function in c so it's executed
first this function is executed before
that so it is somewhere between the
runtime and
the control application so you can see
the stack pointer is passed to r10
register you get some address from the
stack store it in r6 then you get some
value from
the r6 registers with an offset and you
store it in r4 and compare it with zero
so if this value is indeed zero then the
execution will go to plc prg however if
it is not zero
then it branches to another location and
it just returns
so why is this attack possible because
the currency run time passes the control
to the control application or the ic
application in this case
so any vulnerability in the ic
application can be utilized to
manipulate the stack of code assist
control and
any vulnerability in the ic application
can then have an impact on the runtime
itself and that is exactly what we did
so there is a need to batch the
vulnerabilities in the ic application
itself which hasn't been done in
literature because most of the work has
been focused on hot patching the runtime
itself
so for hot patching we assume that there
is a test plc which has the same uh
variant of code as runtime running on it
with the same
iec project with an exploit input loaded
to it then we extract application state
from it to a path server application
state in our case consists of hex terms
of courses runtime ise application
shared libraries such as libsy libm and
certain register estimates most
important
are the program counter and stack
pointer
then we reused everything in anger
execute it try to locate vulnerabilities
then we calculate offsets in anger get
the live base address from deployed plc
generate a patch
this patch is then sent to local path
server which communicates with the lcm
patcher which is the part that actually
does patching of uh the iec application
running in the codesys runtime
so the two import there are two
important questions that we need to ask
for hot patching the first one is where
exactly do we need to patch so most of
the vulnerabilities in iec applications
manifest themselves in the imported
shared functions
so patching at that specific location
means that we are essentially patching
the runtime however those functions
might also be used uh somewhere else in
uh in the program so there is no way to
guarantee correctness so that is why uh
what we want to do is patch closest uh
to the ic application itself somewhere
in the boundary between
the ic application and the
the runtime part
so
for that for localizing the
vulnerability we create a data
dependence graph
when we execute it in angle so as the
execution happens we create certain
nodes for instance instruction nodes for
instructions which can be stored which
writes to certain memory location
represented by memory nodes these memory
nodes might be read by other instruction
load instructions again represented by
instruction nodes so this is a very
common structure in codices because
functions and choruses pass parameters
to each other using memory locations
the loaded memory locations in registers
might be manipulated which are
represented by transition nodes and once
we locate the vulnerability in uh
during execution in anger then we can
traverse back on this graph and figure
out exactly where we need to patch and
in this case
it is this memory location
which is at the boundary of the ise
application and the runtime library
the second important question that we
need to ask is how we patch it because
we have to insert our path somewhere and
change the execution flow but before
talking about that let us look at how
a normal branching happens in in case of
these iec applications for
currencies control working on vargo pfc
so after every function there is a base
address to the jump table or more aptly
the address table
then it loads the address of the
function where it needs to
where it needs to jump to from that
address table using this second load
instruction and then it changes the
program counter so that it can
change the execution and go to the next
function
so we
[Music]
so for us there are three important
parts in the patch first one is the
patch itself next is the address of the
patch and the third one is the hook
that changes the execution flow so our
hook is actually
changing this second load instruction
and adding our own offset to it so we
find an empty location in the jump table
we write the address of our patch to
that location
we change the offset here related to the
base address of the jump table
such that instead of getting the address
of the next function we get the address
of the patch in the second load
instruction then we can uh jump to the
patch the patch will manipulate and
change the memory uh
memory value at that location fix it
and then we can uh restore the execution
flow and then we can go to the actual
function that we need to execute but
this is how we patch um in case of the
ise application input this v3
so next let us look at some demos of
patching certain vulnerabilities we
consider top four out of five
vulnerabilities from common
weakness enumeration index
we won't be discussing improper
input validation because improper input
validation in our data set eventually
leads to auto bombs right so this covers
both of them
these kind of vulnerabilities manifest
themselves because
no like most commonly because of missing
bomb checks in the imported functions
an adversary can override smaller
buffers so
essentially overwriting certain return
addresses on the shared stack which
might mess with the control flow leading
to denial of service and most of the
times
this scan the effects of this can spill
over to the runtime itself and the
runtime need might need to be rebooted
so
now let us look at the experiment setup
for this
again we have a hardware in the loop
setup where we have the msf desalination
plant model working in matlab simulink
which is talking continuously to our plc
avo pfc100 it is sending two uh it
descending four inputs uh first one is
the distillate flow rate which is the
output
of the desalination plant and the
initial brine temperature tb0 and the
corresponding sizes to the uh plc in
in question
so
in this case we again have the same
function for simulating the attack
which
when enabled uh at the 100th operation
cycle it will send a malicious
size
uh to the plc
and what exactly happens on the plc side
is that once it gets an input it scales
it
it adds the sizes together in this case
it's the array size variable
uh this is sent to the second function
which is first pid this is a cascaded
pid setup in the same
plc so you can see uh here we use mem
cpy uh which is vulnerable to autobahn's
right
for copying the variables the parameters
sent from
plc prg to the second function
[Music]
if the array size is more than what is
expected by the program then it will
override
the stack itself the contents of the
stack
however uh there can be two types of
effect of outer bounce right
for instance the effects of this
vulnerability can be limited to the ic
application itself what i mean by that
it might only crash the control
application but it might not impact the
running of the runtime
however the effects of this
vulnerability can also spill over to the
runtime as well where it might crash the
runtime and there might be a need to
reboot the complete plc
so these two cases are handled
differently
for detecting the first case which is
the ic application we
run the clean uh
we run the instance of the
of the
of this ic application with clean inputs
we gathered the information then we come
when then we gather the right offsets on
the uh stack frames and compare it with
the example of uh
of when the same program is run with
exploit input any deviations in this can
tell you about the vulnerability the
second instance is when it impacts the
codex's runtime in that scenario what we
can do is we can directly use uh the
breakpoint functionality provided by
anger execution engine to detect if that
specific rule is being violated or not
if the mem if the stack part of the code
is runtime is being overwritten or not
so in this case uh we
are going to
look at the second
uh setup which is uh impacting the code
resist runtime so when we start
executing uh the msf designation plant
model
in a normal scenario the distillate
output will remain somewhere close to
19.18 ton per minute
however when
when the attack is enabled and the
execution hits the 100th operation cycle
the malicious size of 200 will be sent
which
will lead to an out of bound
vulnerability crashing the runtime so in
this scenario the ic application stops
responding it stops regulating the steam
flow rate into the uh brian heater such
that the distillate output decreases and
it keeps on decreasing
so for patching this
we first gather execution state of clean
sample
which essentially means that the
running of the ic application with
normal inputs
so
we have a local path server working on
the test plc
the script the framework talks
with this local path server gets some
important information and then as
explained in step one start getting the
hex dumps
after getting the hex dump it
starts uh rehosting everything in anger
and then starts executing everything
so in this case there won't be any
vulnerability because this is a clean
sample however if
it retrieves all the intra stack frames
right which can be compared later on
with the execution state off and
of the ic application with an exploit
input so next we feed the exploit input
which you can get using frameworks such
as iss first
so
we do the same thing we again gather all
the execution state however in this case
and now
the
outer bounds right rule will be
triggered
it's executing it in anger okay as you
can see it detected the vulnerability
then using data dependence graph it it
started from a node in the graph
traverse backward and figure out exactly
where it needed to patch again as you
can see this is a stored instruction so
it is patching a memory location which
is being altered by this store
instruction
so in our case we are patching between
the mem cpy and
the call to the mem cpy right so the mem
cpy actually
expects an input of size
now
let us look at this so it is expecting
an input of array size into the size of
l real which in our case is comes out to
be 24 so unlike
just the array size we have to actually
specify 24 as the new new size which is
to be written in the patch
so after that the patch is written and
as you can see once we start executing
it again
at the 100th operation cycle we will see
the 200
size being sent to
the plc however it won't cause a crash
in this scenario it just keeps executing
because the patch is already installed
okay
next vulnerability is out of bound speed
uh it manifests in the same way as uh
auto bombs right using uh because of
missing bound checks can leak secrets
but it does not crash the runtime
unlike the outer bombs right
in this case we don't have a hardware in
the loop setup we directly put the
inputs that the plc receives in the
program itself
uh
the important thing to note here is that
we are using pcpy as a function to copy
the parameters send from plc prg to the
second function
two important parameters with this
function are the
bit offset which
which essentially means
the bit from which you have to start
reading
and how much you have to read is the
fourth parameter which is the size so in
this example the adversary is
manipulating the bit offset for causing
outer bound speed
so it
executes the
the
patching works in the same way first we
gathered the execution state of clean
samples
and
which is which is the same which is not
interesting uh let us move to the second
part
okay now it's gathering execution state
uh of the ic application when the
exploit input is fed to it
after
after getting all the input it is
so it is now uh
rehosting everything in anger it should
be noted that for patching as as i
mentioned before we need two things we
have an lcm patcher so i inserted that
lq module first and then i
i have the local patch server in the
deploy mode so that it can talk with the
lkm patcher here
so it's it's executing the ic
application in anger now the output here
is a little different from the previous
ones we have two possible places where
it can patch this is because uh fit cpi
function in this scenario takes two
important inputs which can cause this
issue first one is the bit offset and
the second one is the size in this case
clearly the index 0 which is p 3 v 0
value which corresponds to 46 000 that
is the exploit input in this scenario is
the issue so we figure out where exactly
we need to patch in memory we calculate
the offset
the user can specify uh which specific
index in this scenario it will be zero
the value should be zero as well
and then it can be patched
however uh before going to the next one
i want to talk about something so as i
mentioned there are three important
things with the patch first one is the
hook in this case the hook is the load
instruction
the original load instruction was
without any offset but we added an
offset of hex 28 so that it points to
our own patch code and then we then the
execution goes to our patch we actually
found an empty location in the jump
table and that is where we wrote the
address of our patch so that is how we
change the execution flow
okay finally the last one which is os
command injection
in this this is a little different from
other vulnerabilities because
uh we need to change the execution flow
so that it goes to the payload that is
being sent by the adversary it can be
done in two ways you can either
overwrite return address on the stack
itself but that is a little finicky so
in our text examples we override the
next function address in the address
table
so that the execution flow actually goes
to the malicious payload instead of
going to the next function itself
so in this scenario uh so in all the
previous examples we were actually
patching the
cause of the
of the attack rather than the effect but
in this case we'll be catching the
effect what i mean by that is
we won't be patching the malicious
offset which has been sent by the
adversary which leads to overwriting and
addressing the jump table or the address
table but instead we'll be fixing the
malicious payload address that has
already been addressed that has already
been inserted into the jump table
so
again
let us look at the example again in this
scenario we don't have a hardware in the
loop setup but the inputs are directly
provided
in the program itself we have a payload
which is just executing a simple syscall
for creating directory
we have an offset of zero this is a
clean example but this offset can be
manipulated by the adversary if
this is received over the sensor
and an adversary can then use that
manipulated value to overwrite an
address overwrite the address of the
code
function in the address table so once
the execution reaches this point instead
of executing this code it will actually
execute the it will actually execute the
uh payload itself
for this uh we
okay uh i should mention that
codesys runtime actually runs in the
user space and on linux it actually
utilizes uh some functions from the
shared libraries such as lipsc and libm
so the framework also provides
functionality to
get the
to get the hex dumps of these uh
these files
of these uh
okay
so next we run the
ic application we
gathered the clean inputs because
as i mentioned before the adversary can
also override the return addresses on
the stack which can be detected by
comparing the clean and the unsafe input
stack
right the offsets that are written on
the stack but again this is not
important yes the next step is patching
with the
exploit input in which we again capture
the state of execution
then we start executing it in anger we
do host hpas start executing it and
anger unlike previous examples in this
case uh there is no input required by
the user
this is because
what we'll be fixing is the address on
on the jump table and the user won't
know this address so everything is
calculated by
from the angular instance so we
calculate all the offsets then get the
live base address from the
the local path server working on the
deployed plc and then we figure out the
final address that needs to be
uh overwritten and what has to be
written there
directly so
everything in this specific example is
done automatically
forward
so in this case uh it detected the
the exploit input which was the offset
so you can see uh the
the framework talks with the uh for
talks with the local patch server in bit
string and then the local patch server
talks with the lca apache also in
bitstream so every all the communication
is done in bitstring the local patch
server
is implemented both in we have
implementation both in python and nc as
well
for patching we have an lk apache but
also we have implemented a similar
patching strategy with jtag
so
it can be used anything can be
configured and used together
finally we also have a debug mode where
an user can patch the
the test plc and then extract all the
execution state and check if the rules
are being triggered again in in the
framework itself so it is
something like a debug mode
so
that's it for the demos uh back to you
mihalys
thank you prasant
so in order to quickly conclude and have
a few say a few minutes for questions uh
some limitations uh we tested mostly on
on wagon the bigger born black
but adding hot passing to other devices
requires some modification manual
modification and some slide changes the
parts itself based on the platform that
is being targeted so because of the
offset sayings on different devices so
for this to be adapted to some more uh
plc's we need to do some more
modification but it should be easy just
a manual tweaking here and there
uh so to conclude uh what we showed is
that you know having a sharp stack
allows control over runtimes if so you
have a vulnerability application then
you can get full access to the system
and that can have devastating effects so
in order to avoid that without
restarting your plc what we saw in this
talk is a way to hot patch those ic
those variable ic applications running
in potassius using alkane patches so
without you don't need to restart
so this concludes our talk thank you
very much for attending and we have a
minute or so for questions
[Music]