[Music]
hi everyone
thank you for
attending our session
so
today we are going to discuss about
mobile botnet and
you know how we uncovered it and how
these cyber criminals are taking
advantage of it by monetizing
and we are also going to present
how the mobile supply chain attacks you
know takes role in propelling the
manifestation of the cyber crime
business model so we have been
researching this for the past months we
are still continue
monitoring it and um
it's because of my fellow core
researchers namely
zhangyu dong our mobile threat analyst
from mobile china and then
forward looking threat researchers
namely theodore
ryan and vladimir
also thanks for our editors headed by
abigail and so yeah our session for
today is about
this firmware supply chain if you
attended yesterday um
it's about how they
uh you know um the complexity and how
they solve the issue and the
vulnerabilities but on our side it's
about the cyber criminals are you know
embedding this or deliberately embedding
this um
malicious loaders so
our agenda briefly discuss the history
of mobile supply chain attacks um some
of the notable incidents with
pre-installed malware purchased that
were reported we then delve into the
lemon group
so these are responsible for the mobile
botnet
we say that they are chinese speaking
individuals
then how they monetize the services
using the sms service and proxy service
of course implications um impact
conclusion
and some recommendations how to stay
protected
right so terms which i will be using
interchangeably during the presentation
so as cited online in mobile industry
oem stands for
um original equipment manufacturer so
these are the companies who have their
own factories who manufacture phones
but
as for example the lg and samsung and
then odm our original design
manufacturer also they have the
factories
and they
manufacture phones usually in bulk
manner when oem
started to manufacture phone they will
embed the android
basic android os then they will
head over the system image the
third-party vendors
and so
they will provide additional features in
the software after doing so they will
revert it back to the oem
and so oem can prepare to sell it in
market through the retailers
and then when it lands to consumer it
needs an update in the firmware so
farewell is basically the lowest level
of software that has direct interaction
with the hardware
so firmware is actually um
firmware over the air or
you know ever since the android was
created ota was required and so there's
also coined the word um
software ota
phone verified accounts services
this is a security mechanism that is
employed by platforms and service
providers
in order to prevent fake and bot
accounts
which can be used for like spam fake
news and
as a means to perpetuate online harm
you can see here the guerrilla malware
we will discuss it later and this image
flow chart originated from
the researcher named lucas i hope i
pronounced it correctly so they are from
google they reported about the triad of
malware involved in mobile supply chain
attacks and so
we can say that gorilla and triad are
both prevalent malware in terms of
mobile supply chain attacks
and that um they were able to help the
oem to disinfect the votes
so the rise of the or the growth of the
android market is also the rise in the
demand of
reflashing services in in china the
rampant customization of rome
became rampant
because we know android os is an open
source software and sorry
the malware is activated when you
purchase the phone when you boot it
but of course the antiviruses can detect
it but over and over again so the only
way is to disinfect is to re-flash the
firmware
now the low-cost mobile device company
manufacturers they often mass produce
and so they can also negotiate to some
third-party vendors for a cheaper price
and i think that's where the compromise
can occur and so
um
not to say that the quality assurance
may be possibly
overlooked because maybe issue in budget
resource and time
now
this is
the
timeline of some notable mobile supply
chain incidents first we take a look at
the silent plug-in
here you can see that
it was in 2011 to 2012.
the good news is they got arrested it
was in this
news article in china saying mobile
phone trojan stole 20 million of
contacts so that's a lot
so in here they developed silent plug-in
matter of fact in fact the device is 400
involved by 10 persons and three
companies and the crime is illegally
obtaining data
and making money out of it
so in 2011 to 2012 they developed this
plug in because
reflashing is not attractive anymore and
that
in mid 2012 they start sending the
personal information
to the server
and they got discovered and in 2013 they
got arrested
one actor put behind bars for about
three and a half years um
seven eight
hundred us dollars for fine
well the thing is there are there were
three companies colluded one company
promoting the app store the app store
and thing is the developer and then the
last company is the one thing providing
rom packages promote software for
developers with a fee and so they
generated a lot of revenue
out of the private data so we also
emphasize here law enforcement and the
police investigation is possible when
crime is committed um
domestically and we found the samples
it's not triata it's not gorilla but
likely a photo update
tampered update
all right triad emerged in 2016 as
described by kaspersky modularized
mobile trojan
first case of triada with oem is with
which i mentioned earlier
from researcher lucas they helped the
oem manufacturers to disinfect the
phones
and in 2019 brian krebs reported about
vendor called yahoo
or blaze fire they were able
to i think
um
say that triada was involved in embedded
in the oem image and
the trojanized version of whatsapp and
apk pure or compromised sdk
software
now these are examples of thousands of
low-cost mobile phones
in africa and with embedded of triada
the german smartphone
manufacturer their photo opta update
server got compromised and there were
malicious loaders while actually
downloading a malware
so a sudden installation without
notifying the
user
and so even you delete the app it keeps
on spawning because of the
updated servers so the best way is to
um
what they call this disable the update
so we found a company named redstone ota
supplier of gigaset we found in
virustotal that
some packages detected
the what we call this
com.redstone.ota.ui
detected as i think guerrilla and then
here is an example of news in 2018
pre-infected malware on white labeled
phone the idea of from switching 3g to
4g is
attracting attracted a lot of consumers
to buy this phone you can think of white
labeled phone as um
being manufactured or sell sold by
retailers with their own branding and
logos but the manufacturer is from third
party so what happened here they able to
retrieve uh personal information mobile
numbers
and created lots of gaming accounts
gaming here refers to gambling account
well actually um
for gambling companies they would
normally give you bonus money so they
were able to monetize on this one and
also to emphasize that
the
what they call this
they have to check the manufacturer and
telecoms in that country
and also to
find the national information security
standards is being met
this lastly is the case of
non-smartphone
um pre-installed with malware so just
the basic functionality sms
the police found the main board is
sending and receiving sms and send
uploading it to the server
and so they estimated 5 million infected
devices 50 million stolen pii 14
individuals who actually sold
uh bought the p a stolen pai
they actually arrested the developer
they arrested the manufacturer
in of the main board in shenzhen china
and
yeah pulling the wool means um something
like the sms selling fraud
um
out of the sign in bonuses
right so sms verification according to
freebuff a community of security
security enthusiasts in china um
they they were saying that the birth of
sms verification was in 2004 when people
wanted to solve the issue on identifying
real identity and real names
and so the binding of sms verification
to human is made use of phone sim card
and the human operating it
and in 2010 the banks were the first one
to operate you know the verification
code although it's costly like 5 cents
to 10 sets of sms still it's very
effective in protecting the accounts and
secure
system and so the internet companies can
complete their kyc or know your customer
and also monitor the behavior of the
device
now the sim banks or simbox is a device
to aggregate or read sim cards
so connecting by a gsm gateway through
ib address to allow communication so
this is heavily used by the sms pva
companies so some operators because this
is costly and you know maintenance is
difficult
so some operators found a clever way to
generate more numbers and it's out of
the bot that they're operating
here they boasted about like thousands
of mobile numbers
high availability and i think
all numbers in almost all countries
so we have encountered this in facebook
page named receive code free sms
verification goals so if you are looking
for free virtual numbers you would be
enticed to try it but there is a hidden
magic behind it and
so um yeah like it offers like a
thousands of numbers in a single day in
a single country you would think that
they have this big sim box but for free
really
so
in that facebook page is also the lemon
sms pva but this time with a fee you can
top up your credit to use the service so
it was advertised in 2018 in youtube and
in that facebook page is in 2020.
um yeah that's topping up the credits
in terms of
api
it's actually
indicating that you can automate
creating bulk accounts that's perfect
for cyber criminals right so whether api
or ui the feature is you can request
number you can rent it for about five
minutes then you have to release it so
others can use it
actually you can
select country
then
these are the platforms well you can
also block place the number in case you
don't receive otp or probably the owner
of the device already found a compromise
these are the platforms almost all
platforms are available you name it the
whatsapp twitter that uses the sms
you can actually
include another project if there's a new
sms but overall the goal is to get the
otp code
let's say
lemon
customers they would use proxy because
some platforms they use geographical
location the phone number country should
be matching before you can create an
account
and we believe
they have operating this dove proxy and
we believe that the ib plug-in
linked to this
is connecting to the cnc server and we
believe that the residential proxy
originates from devices coming from
connecting to wi-fi and the mobile proxy
originates from devices connecting to
mobile data so this is a security
implication in authentication of sms and
it enables cyber criminals to create
bulk accounts without worrying the
location
while um
you know exploring their official
website
we found a replica website under the dot
c and domain
and so
um this is an important pivoting point
because we were able it led us to
several guerrilla malware and
did that
we think it's staging because it has
lesser traffic
well the dex file
main functionality is to intercept sms
okay this is the plugable app designs of
lemon sorry design
in fact device um activating
pre-installed loader connecting to cnc
server and then that scene server will
request for some commands from the back
end and then the back end will um digest
all this uh the data from the fields to
wrap it up and then create a plugin and
then send it to the device well the
zygote is an android process being
exploited here zygote will request for
this um
data fields to the back end and then the
back end will wrap it up to create an
encrypted plugin that encrypted plugin
will be hosted in the url of the lemon
will be pushed to the device to install
it
and an example of it is let's say sms
plugin hooking to the device for
intercepting the sms and so we found the
main plug-in
responsible for the main execution flow
proxy plug-in um
used to open proxy server
service rather in sucks 5
like retrieving ib address port token
and let's say the time out because
that's the time when they want to set a
connection to the infected device they
get this they call the cnc server to
open proxy connection
now the sms plugin has three main
functions
it intercepts the sms using start hook
or using the ams or activity manager
service
they can also retrieve regular
expression rules from the cnc server
which they can use to filter out sms
content and lastly is they can send the
sms to the back end using that regular
expression
rule and so that's the sms plugin
the lemon sms pva and the dove proxy we
know they're being advertised both in
that facebook page and it led us a
company in heinen province in china and
the lemon sms pva will offer numbers in
different countries and different
platforms and then the proxy will offer
different ip addresses available for
example bangladesh has around 122
thousands of ib addresses
okay sms pva and sms interception how
does it work hand in hand let's say a
customer will register in lemon
register the number of course you need
to top up to use the service and then
let's say uh select for a project named
carousel
carson is you know
popular marketplace in southeast asia
so
in that in carsol app he would register
and when it comes to phone number he
will switch back to lemon to get the
number
actually they can also request for the
specific country let's say singapore and
then they could put it here and then
click verify it will send sms code
verification code to the infected device
and that device will
be called by the lemon using the
guerrilla malware and then the the lemon
will
return the otp code to the customer of
lemon
and it's successfully created when i
um the castle account because of the odp
in the background the sms plugin
actually intercept the sms
calls the css server for regular
expression rule let's say the condition
here is carousel text with four digit
and so it will be sent to the server
it's also not being visible to customer
because the guerrilla has capability of
preventing the broadcasting of the sms
and it happens in an infected phone
right so we emphasize the different
persistence mechanism of mobile supply
chain
before bad apps they can download root
exploits and rooted phone can be
installed back door for persistence but
here first roam image
being compromised or tampered as i
mentioned earlier guerrilla or triada
embedding without notifying the oem
second is photo auto update server
either photo auto update has malicious
loader or photo auto has
pre-infected rome image example are
redstone adopts they are ota supplier in
china and they
manufacturing are also based in china
actually and
last is a software sdk example is an apk
pure
it's an alternative to google play and
they were
kaspersky mentioned that
triad is embedded and so
it
exploited the zygote um let's say
what i call this
yeah um the triada was able to modify
the zygote
now this is a
what he called a sample of forum let's
say a user reported about his rom image
version 11
and he found out that the sms in his
phone is being intercepted to this
domain name
and the rom image actually came from a
yandex sharing service and they found
out
or they are also reporting or
complaining about the infection
putting it together to show you the
cyber crime business model
we know the angle in mobile supply chain
attacks you know became effective and
efficient for cyber criminals
um they exploited the zygote because of
they created the main plug-in that
zygote will
install loader connectors in the server
retrieve information like imei and then
the back end will
revert back
the plug-in based from the strategy
the zygote also
able to modify live android which is one
of the components of android os
um basically it created a routine
to write the dot text file to the dalvik
cache directory
and so these are the plugins the ip
proxy plugin for residential and mobile
proxy and then sms plugin for sms
interception both are in the infected
device and this operation our business
was around 2018 the dove proxy and the
lam one sms pva service
they
attracted more customers to create bulk
accounts
and that facilitated or end to some scam
or fraud
right
we now go for implications uh sms
default verification but because they
bypass it the search of sms pva service
there are some implications like
anonymity it's one of the obstacles
cyber criminals they would create
account
that account
because of the smsp based service
it's
an added arsenal to them coordinated
inauthentic behavior
it can use to distribute and amplify
information often misinformation in
social media
abusing sign in bonuses and app
gamification bonuses
they would create a lot of accounts
based from the phone numbers
and so that let's say coupon codes
promotional codes they can convert it to
the hard cache
and it can also
lead to some other scams and fraud like
roman scam investment scam
i know you can all relate even me i
receive those kind of sms
um consumer privacy the infected devices
the owner of it is highly impacted their
phone numbers may be possibly used by
cyber criminal cyber crime and can also
be as a monitoring tool now
circumvent regional restriction there
are some countries like for example
banning cryptocurrency exchange
platforms so sms pva isn't
an option to bypass it
this is an ideal example of abusing
signing bonus the starbucks in china in
they launched a promotion of like
if you create an account using their app
you will receive a free drink for about
five dollars to six dollars and so in
the first day of their promotion the
cyber criminals were able to create 400
thousands of accounts
and so the starbucks would um
notice those ghost accounts and they
immediately halted their promotion
and on the other side you can see the
phone numbers
generated from the lemon group those
numbers using social links we were able
to get the
social media linkages on a real-time
basis
two telegram accounts with same photo
actually the photo is from an online
shopping site so it's a model and one is
in chinese name one is in russian name
definitely this is a fake account we
also found numbers linked to
let's say the country code matches the
social media the nationality but then
there's another account with different
nationalities so that's also a red flag
this is a project list of lemon sms.net
we can you can find it in their url
parameters so we could estimate about
thousands of regular expression rule
or the number of target platforms there
are some platforms that are recurring
like wechat but i think it's because the
sms if it changed a bit then they will
add
line head highest
i would say maybe
line is not widely used but any phone
numbers can be used to register in line
and this is from trend micro telemetry
data from october 2010 to 1 to march of
it's another example of fraud the tingle
it's an e-commerce site
they offered
gift package and shipping coupons when
you register or for the newcomers
here using same telemetry data from
trend micro thailand had the highest
well ting dong is also based in that
country perfect for cyber criminals and
it could also indicate that
there are maybe possibly
more infected devices surprisingly the
second one is mexico
we know single is not being used in that
country and the user of
in that country would not notice the
fraud because they don't know this app
and that's how the cyber criminals take
advantage of it
these are the phone numbers generated by
lemon for otp requests still from trial
micro data
the southeast asia
countries and india had
highly impacted
we could say that these countries are
possibly
impacted with the mobile supply chain
attacks or that some countries are
lenient in provisioning sim cards
this is an example of um
examination from police
in shouting um internet police
discovered that
the fraudsters are exploiting the
loophole in online e-commerce platforms
like
taobao jingdong and to-in so an example
is the tingdom
they bypass their real name verification
in that case
uh they were able to buy phone numbers
and real names from what we called card
holders so that is someone who owns a
lot of sim cards
and that's from the examination and why
a lot of devices here
of course for creating bulk accounts i
think for example in whatsapp you can
create account without phone number
like using the api but it has a high
tendency to be disabled because of that
so that's why there's a lot of phone
right um as i mentioned earlier you can
top up service credit using their
cryptocurrency wallets so we were able
to trace it tron wallet uh had like
thirteen thousands of detections
sorry
transactions
and
from that
we could estimate like let's say once a
month you have to top up your credit so
we could estimate about 2 000 of
customer but they also have other
wallet like bitcoin
so we could sum it up to around 660
thousands of u.s dollars but there's
also like the alipay and others
country statistics-wise lemon
provides daily numbers available phone
numbers like in their free received code
and the lemon official
you can see the commonalities right
mostly southeast asian countries and it
also matches with telemetry data like we
found indonesia and thailand with highly
or most attempts of let's say mobile
supply chain or gorilla in that in those
devices
we also
found the affected devices
in our research paper we
put some of the phone brands and models
but this is only to say that they're
mostly
attempts of mobile supply chain attack
and guerrilla malware and we found that
of course the main
targets are the low-cost mobile
phones
right so we come up with the conclusion
so we have seen the evolution of mobile
supply chain attacks and
it still happens to some of the oem
companies
we emphasize the different persistence
mechanism
compromising or tampering the rom image
photo of the update server and the
software sdk
here
we can given the recommendation for the
oem let's say
to know their vendors
to establish assurance by performing
strong evaluation on the apps
especially
sorry on the image especially on the
loaders embedded
anonymity is the main what they call
this opsec of cyber criminals they could
create because of the this sms pva
service it spices up their arsenal
and the implication on security
uh authentication of sms
is also
saying that
this is uh let's say
the
what he calls a million of devices could
be possibly impacted because of this
and this
evolving cyber crime business model
from click fraud to pre-installed
malware or the silent loader
is becoming uh
what i call this
uh let the cyber criminals to
thrive to survive because of their
persistence mechanism and it can also
lead to data exploration
uh to identity theft when they um let's
say hijack authentication cookies
um
so they can impersonate and hide their
identity and that's silent loader
i skip on the security model i would say
i was trying to say that
[Music]
okay they are trying to exploit the
behavior-based security model for
example
there's a social media has been active
for several years and that
suddenly a new account is linked because
of same number
so that new account is preferred over
anonymous or random account
and if that new account is used by cyber
criminals it can baffle police
investigation
identity uh challenge in identifying the
real identities
and adding confidence to cyber criminals
because they can minimize their online
footprints they're abusing it so
with that
phone is becoming our real identity
however there are still some caveats and
it continues to reshape the threat
landscape and security model
and so
we have here some counter measures
that we mentioned for online platform
services
use of one-time sms is not enough
anymore
be cautious when launching sign in
and for smartphone vendors
ensure provenance
trust to the third party vendors for
consumers always consider cons security
when purchasing
phones so i don't have to delve
or mention one by one this is available
in our research paper published in
february
so you can visit trendmicro.com
for that and i think that's all for my
presentation for today and
yeah we are now open for question and
answer and my co-speakers zhangyu and
vladimir is on the line can also answer
your questions
so yeah
any question guys
all right um there's a question from the
virtual audience
how could a consumer protect ourselves
with these evolving cyber crimes related
to sms
how this cyber can you repeat again
sorry how could a consumer protect
ourselves with this evolving cyber
crimes related to sms
right first of all is of course you need
to install
security software in your mobile phone
and second is to
[Music]
well it's a challenge but they have to
carefully check their phone number is
connected to
uh only to those social media social
medias that they have and
and to say that the phone
that is usually infected from mobile
supply chain attacks are low cost mobile
i'm not saying that don't use low cost
mobile phones but there are some
well as reported
from the news they are highly targeted
because of the i think maybe poor
um
implementation of security mechanisms so
um yeah um always secure your device be
wary also of
i'm not sure if chrome images is
available now but
always check
the account
is linked to your account in social
media that phone number
and so yeah i hope i answered it
correctly
[Music]