[Music]
foreign
sorry for some techno technical issue
here and we are presenting the hidden RC
services that control the joys
and due to the Quality lockdown
situation in Shanghai we are presenting
this remotely and sorry for
inconvenience cost
and here I will introduce ourselves and
uh I'm China researcher Chief researcher
of Charity security lab I'm the winner
of multiple pontoon championships and
spoken and conferences
Mosaic hrtb power community and so on
uh
hello everyone
most of my time focusing on mobile
security and program analyze finding its
vulnerabilities and keep tracks the
state of art of exploration
okay so now today's agenda is as follows
we will give an overview of the RC
services in Android and a second layer
will introduce a different remote code
activation box in Android ecosystem that
we found including the leap pack bug in
the Android AOSP the image format box in
the Samsung Android Chrome libraries and
the SPI image barge in Samsung Notes
which have like billions of downloads in
the Google Play
uh Sunday we will dive into the dynamic
binary funding
how to find this box uh especially
without source code access
and the final part is a conclusion part
so uh to give a brief overview the
remote connection service Android can be
categorized as five types the Wi-Fi
attack surfaces including bugs in the
Wi-Fi protocol stack the Wi-Fi
implementations and the Wi-Fi chip
drivers and there are some previous
external research on this
like in the broadcom chips the NFC is
also uh called execution surface in
Android including marketing the NFC
photo stock and NFC software handling
and some like intent handling uh in NFC
uh the fire format bugs are somehow
old-fashioned but they but are still
live even after so many years previously
they are very famous fire format bugs in
Android the stage fraud box and I think
most of you have heard about it however
after those years the box in the median
server has like vanished but we are
still seeing other file from my box that
we will introduce later
also there are Bluetooth and baseband
bugs including the protocol
implementation faults and others and we
will not elaborate on it today
so uh as I have mentioned about uh in
this talk we will focus on the fire
format box that we have found
so uh the fire RC Box still exists in
Android since the like the introduction
of 4G and the 5G and the improvements of
cameras like the the phone today's
phones may ship with cameras like which
have the ability to process like
millions or billions of pixels and with
the with the developments of like of a
tick tock uh insert Instagram and people
would like to share high definition
images and videos so the Android and
Windows they develop a high a new high
definition image formats and complex
video and audio and image file formats
and also as the BYOD is very popular
these days the the corporate and
Enterprise networks they also have some
special specific configuration file that
is introduced in Android to support the
company's needs or the ice here that
means knees we will go into the details
later on
so for our first Target is the lead pack
deep pack surface in the USP so what is
what is packed or what is Leap pack the
OS provides a way for users to configure
a process Auto configuration script a
personal configuration script defines
how web browsers and other user agents
can automatically choose the appropriate
process server refreshing a given URL
and you can see that it's defined in
JavaScript the whole process
configuration file is actually an
implementation for the function find
process for URL that are given a URL and
the host the function need to return how
this uh specific URL should be reached
whether it should be accessed directly
or it should go through a process
so a different platforms a different
operating systems support the pack and
they have the different implementations
for handling the pack the windows use
the gscript to pass the pack file and
preface previously a Google project Zero
have an excellent research on the pack
handling that Windows attacker can
obtain remote code accusation by uh
hijacking the dark pack domain to host
the manager's pacifier to exploit the
memory corruption box in the g-script
so our questions arise that what's the
situation for Android
in Android we know the most famous
JavaScript engine or most widely used
JavaScript engine is a V8 engine the
width is a complex and Powerful attack
surface in Android so it's heavily
sandboxed since it has like it's a huge
attack surface the browser weight engine
runs in the isolate application contest
before 2017 we have a good old times
when application web views are not
isolated
we utilize this feature in mobile.1 2017
and quickly excluding Android o that all
application web use is isolated like the
like the Chrome ones
so can you imagine there's still a
remaining un isolated V8 in the platform
application context
uh it's so good to be true but it just
exists
so and now let's see how the pack file
is processed in Android there are
different implementations in Android
including Android 10 Android 11 and
Android 12. and the Box we found here is
is including including cve 2020 zero two
four zero a CV
2020-0224 and CV
2021.0393 and you can see it got like
high or critical ratings from Google
foreign
Service Pack service is exported in the
packages a service pack processor in
AOSP and we can see that for the for the
network request from for the network
request it with the parameters host and
the URL it actually calls into pack
native make process request
and the cognitive Mac proceed request
actually is backed by a pack native and
it will cost to Native implementation
which are in the Deep GI pack processor
dot ISO
and this also implemented in Surplus
Mass actually was various costs to the
V8
so uh where is the proceed resolver V8
handle implemented in the screenshot of
the source of the snippet I posted here
so let's dig deeper here and we can see
the answer is the external chromium Leaf
pack and external V8
the final implementation that is called
by wiper actually creates a weight
contest uh in the process space our pack
processor and evaluates the packet
script file and you can see in the left
side of the uh of the snippet code the
for the incoming UI on the host uh
contest is created and the function the
final process for URL function is
retrieved and evaluated in the innovate
context
and the other problem here that quickly
arises that uh where is the
corresponding weight source code is it
in webview or is it in a separate Branch
or separate Ripple
uh the answer is very uh uh interesting
or very promising to attack her at uh
before the Android 11 a separate branch
of V8 is maintained in the external
weight report in the AOSP and from the
commit log here that we we have several
I think very interesting conclusion
the separate way the Ripple has patch
Gap that which means that end days also
work the resolver itself is a native
code and might contain box uh actually
it is also the case that uh
there is some somebody found some bugs
here in the is over rather than the
weight code
the weight itself does not run the
isolated process
Ary previously uh some people reported
uh some and some end days here and it
lead to a minor change in weight options
and we can see uh no optimized uh option
is introduced
it accused a jetty box which means that
since there's a it is because that if
there is no optimization you can the jit
feature is turned off and you can not uh
export the the git box but only turning
off GRT is far from enough because we
still have other zero days and then days
for example
a CV
2020-0240 is an integer overflow in the
new fixed double array the originally a
chromium issue is
938251 and the root cause of this bar is
that the new fixed double array does not
expand at negative length integer for
the lens and it leads to a natural flow
and it does not require git to exploit
this part and the root cause is also not
in jit
we can see on the right side of the
screen there's a POC called snapping for
this part
that uh so to craft an exploit in the
pack processor we can create an array
with with auto band lens that uh
so that we can use it to get an
arbitrary read write and finally to
overwrite the webassembly code page to
to write our Shell Code in the code page
and finally jump to the Shell code to
get a code execution
the detail of the bug is not going to be
elaborate here and if you are interested
you can consult originally issue
so the consequence of this is exploit is
that we got good accusation in the
platform application contest
which is a
somehow promised in context rather than
the untrusted application contest or
isolate application contest
uh fortunately for the user but
unfortunately for the attacker is that
the permission the application
permission or pack processor is limited
by saying it's limited I mean that it
does not have like a read or write
external storage permission so it cannot
access your photos it does not have SMS
permission they cannot access your
contacts but still it opens the way for
attacker to like exploit a further box
because the platform map contest is good
for the attacker to try to exploit the
drivers or other services box to
actually privilege
so uh here is a quick demo here to show
the bar
so we can see that as soon as the
malicious pack URL is entered
the the shell quickly picks up hooks up
and the attacker gets a reverse shell on
the uh currently and use the word under
on the newest version at that time
and of course the bank has been reported
the patched by Google it's Embark in the
Android 10.
foreign
so we quickly saw some changes in the
Android open source project that were
introduced to medic automatically the
Sparks a new flag has used webview pack
processor is introduced and it switches
it controls the switch between the pack
value and pack native
apartment will now redirect the pack uh
processing to system by wheel which
means that it will directly use the
weight bundle in the system by view
instead of a separate with branch
under the flag is by default true which
means that in Android 11 hacknet
cognitive is never used in the
screenshot here and you can see that now
the pack processors process process Maps
now contains a webview code instead of
the originally with code
so in Android 12 Google goes one step
further and the switch is removed and
only pack by wheel is used
but the question Still Remains that the
passing still runs in the non-isolated
context uh here the screenshot
demonstrates that we use a a zero day or
a newest lead bar to test and we can see
that the crash is still in the pack
processor itself rather than rather than
a isolated application contest
so here's all for the for our first
Target the pack serve service attack
service in a USP now I will go to the
second text service the dng and other
image formats in the Samsung Chrome
Library
and the first bug of the current library
is found by Natalia project zero in 2015
and I believe some of you have heard
about this research in the Quran because
in 2020 the project zero and I both
contact conduct funding again in the
Quran library and we find we did some
research in the from different code
passes and different formats and we
found different bugs the project Zero's
blog mentioned part in the qmg code qmg
image key image format and I found other
box in the jpeg shift dng passing
the Chrome is a quite complex binary
with lot of codecs and in the Samsung
system partition which means that it
exists in in billions of signs and
phones by default
the API reversing of the Samsung Chrome
library is the first step for for us to
find the box here a natural entries in
the stock Gallery applications and you
can see that the Chrome codec interface
is a Java wrapper for the Chrome codec
and the code the puzzle will be called
by image decoder decoded file and when
will Chrome codec be used and we will
use the Android scab used there are
three preconditions uh the codec need to
be presented the flag injustical bonds
need to be true and in if preferred qm
codec flag needs to be true
so when will this flux be true so that
the current codec will be will be used
uh the rounds are different for
different image types but for all image
types for some image types uh the the
flags are defer to true for some Samsung
perpetually format but other major
formats like a pack GIF BMP and others
it is set to true in some threads for
example in the thumbnail thread the
phase detection stress and is
automatically triggered when the fire is
is added to inventory by media scan
interns for example if you download the
image
from browser from e-farm emails from a
receiving a receiving or send or saving
the message from a saving the image from
MMS
and for other situations the scaled
using instead current we are not
interested in scale here so we will only
considered about the aforementioned
situations
so to draw a conclusion receiving the
image triggers the library and the code
is actually in background suddenly
to take further away go from the Java
code to the native code the Java code
called in the GI function then the GI
function accepts a far path and the byte
array and returns a bitmap with pixel
filled the metadata had retrieved by
Chrome get image info from file under
the create speed map
based on the metadata
the metadata will tell the color the it
will try to decide the image type the
words the hit another meta message for
the image the Android bitmap log pixels
function increase buffer depends on RGB
types and the file the image size image
Wireless orders other informations other
parsing now will dispatch it to QR
decode image for different types and for
example in the right side of the of the
presentation you can see the code the
compare code snipping and for different
types they have a decode jpactic called
EMP and other functions code on the code
passes
and there's a passing result is written
to the buffer provided by bitmap.pixels
and the final is Android feedback analog
pixels finish decoding and handles the
bitmap but upwards to the Java world
you can see from the other screenshot
that this code is a rather complexity
which means it's a very interesting
Target for fuzzing
uh to if we want to fire this codec we
need to draw a curve flow of this
Library under so to for summer for
summarize you can see that from because
from ji entry to Chrome get image input
from File 2 and decrease Android paymap
and locks buffer and accurate economics
right for buffer and finalize the
bitmaps returns
the other interesting uh
a situation interesting exception here
is that for the dng format you can see
that dng is a specially handled here by
a specific code parts
and uh I I would like to say I like to
say that TNG is the first class citizen
of the Chrome image code
it has a more complex called flow here
and there is never delegated to scale
for some Custom Custom formats uh for
example in the right side of this
presentation we can see the The Parting
flow of the dng images for incoming
image file if the extension is dng uh it
will call into QR pass metadata and
there is a metadata about it and there
is the make field uh it's also the
window field is Samsung and it will cost
into Quran bit manufacturer decode TNG
preview I mean if the metadata is not
valid it will call into current bit from
in my factory decode file
and if the extension is not TNG the
current build manifest radical fire will
be called again to decide if the current
gas emerge image info from fires think
the fire is a job format the Azure
format is is a separate name for the TNG
format and this answer is true the
qrtical dng file will be called
so uh to create to create a filing
harness uh is similar to the previous
program example we have a new dng
harness for the dng passing and
we will conduct funding on these harness
and we will elaborate about it uh more
later
so we found several bugs or actually
tensor bars in the Chrome our Chrome
Library including cve 2021 a
24346 and there is a typical integer
flow here and you can see a size field
is retrieved from the image under it and
it have uh it is passed to the
Constructor of the new of the array by a
multiplied by eight and then the side
used as a loop to the array and they're
the obvious interior flow here and found
by flooding
and also other bugs like hippo flow will
be right by free others in the hpback
parsing others
so this is uh the the story for the
Target 2 including the box or font and
now I will handle to change out to talk
about the target 3 here
okay
thanks cheetah
now after we drag into two no file
formats it's time to deep tie in can we
find the most similar availabilities
beside Q Mage gpack dng and the exaggery
no more information on the web about
primate media files for searching phones
so where we are essentially use its
unique format
for application point of view media
files are commonly found in preview
instilled applications
and at the same time from another point
of view system or some other privilege
in the process can also handles media
files
so let's find something interesting when
we look for new attack surveys based on
the idea of meaning qmage format
vulnerabilities
we review the past availability mini
methods we found something interesting
in some dictionaries for example system
Media or the dictionaries of building
application on the phone
in attention to Q Majors there are files
which is in SPI service format
in fact security researchers from Google
project zero had discovered this file
formats before which you can see it on
their blog in the mm series but this
audio has no attack service and the
ignored it
however that doesn't proclude us taking
a great interest in this matters
you can see that these files are named
all about system studies like battery
USB charging and some others
for a common scenes of system designs
the system developers usually put files
of the same type of some similar types
together
therefore we found that after we have
found the relative vulnerabilities of
qmage we believe the SPI it may be also
another sensing special image for file
format and it may have such a problem
foreign
next we need to determine our attack
service
unlike Q major we had a no more
information about SPF format so we
decided to choose the old version Away
we have done a lot of reverse
engineering the Java application Level
and the nature level of the system
and we found some interesting strings
and the sound related functions about
SPI
in system binaries and function
libraries we found LPN and label made
Shadow Library
to help him it is actually responsible
for some logical processing when the
Android device is plugged in and the
label Mage is a library which provides
creative processing functions
in fact when we reversed here we can
already understand the name of the SPI
file we talked before a correspondence
to the operation to this processing like
charging batteries or remote it is
actually the picture which is displayed
when searching phone is plugged in the
exactly but unfortunately we can't do
anything about this startup process the
file path is used is a hardcoded in the
code
and all we can do is change the picture
which is displayed in the charging model
therefore we continue to reverse the
relative applications of the media files
and we found the different applications
have the same some same native libraries
which names counting span
it is actually the underlying support of
the S Pen SDK or we can say that is the
SPM framework expand is the highlight of
Jesse mobile phone and it can support
you to do something like hand write text
pictures
that's why so many preview instilled
applications about it
and after we classify the functions of
each applications we choose testing
nodes as our Target because it has a
very clear way of passing attacked
vectors
it is processing special Note 5 formats
and stocks and stocks
so we did the detail reverse engineering
of searching nodes on the right of right
side of the screen you can see the stock
for Mid file opening xxg hackstamp model
it is a compost compressed file counting
information about other media files like
SPI spp and some others you can see
exactly the string of spi is already
including the Xbox file
and on the left side of the screen is
the passing logic in Java and the native
labor
when you open or save a stock format
document it will first performance
operation similarity simulator to the
compressed and secondly if there is a
image information in hand drive format
which is actually the SPI in the
document it will call its unique puzzles
FPS green coder decoder to cover the
speed map and passing it like a spr
so the logic in Java layer will finally
called native function to code SPI to
puzzles the bitmap of the head driver
picture
then at the nature layer
it's passing logic is similar to the
usual media file pausing
so Vanishing checkout file will call
region metal RGB and the performance
series of processing
so the logic is clear here
the SPI is a built-in file formats for
stocks and this message is retrieved by
read the message argb
it will increase speed map based on
these metadata and the j9 function also
accepts fire pass or better area and the
returns and attribute map with pixel
field
and Andrew bitmap pixels Chris buffers
depend on RGB type passing this patch to
metadata code for different types and
your bitmap on block pixels finish the
decoding compared with the pattern logic
of the queue measure you can find that
something has some similarity in the
processing logic of file policy
so similar similar to many ordinary file
puzzles the point of passing basically
lies in some boundary values like white
height and or the number of materials
the index of material or the size in the
material
understanding likes to use logs which
help us to convert its logic quickly
therefore we focus on the reverse
analyze of the analytic Logic for the
boundary key bound values and the change
some key bias to see as if the code is
running correctly to our surprise we
easily found out about the right
availability this leader has to believe
the statistics piece of code is on test
and we found the Downs of
vulnerabilities based on positive
and the filing work is similarly to the
previous operation in community part we
also wrote a harness to load the
function Library which is responsible
for passing the pspi logic and the
litigator running our folding tool so
space every detail will be discussed in
the following pages and now let's take a
look at the sum of vulnerabilities here
the first case is cve
2021-25496 it happens in the code snap
about segment passing logic and it is
actually a function table hijacking
vulnerabilities caused by an area index
out of bounds
variable V4 is the user to calculated
the index of the area offset
b4138 so obviously it's Point actually
points to an area of functions which is
on the right side of the screen and the
opposite will pass the edges of a
function to v11 and finally in the next
passing logic it will call different
point functions according to different
fragments and you can see v11 is used as
a function point we will just need to
make it point to the position of the
target function and the menu is the
opposite and constructs the parameter
Methods at the same time then you will
give it a primary of excision of the
function
and the next case is CBE 2021
25498 this venabilities is actually a
hijacking of Striker internal function
points you can see it happens in that
code snap 2. the argument of history of
major corporate CB model is actually a
structure that stores the contents of
the object file for for convenience you
can consider it as basically
controllable content so V3 will pass
through the read function and there is a
struggle internal function point will
finally be executed in conditional
statement
but the struggle here is the parents
executive by this function are defined
it and if you want to use this you need
to find a better way
well that's what's the SPI spots
researchers next the chidin will
continue to give you the spreadsheet of
the following contents
since the time is ticking and I will go
a bit further a bit faster here so to
find the previous Mission box we need
some sort of fasting to to do the bug
hunting and the central filing is the
courage guided funding and you know that
her funding needs some sort of feedback
and the coverage information is a key
for source code focusing with source
code access we have compiler
instrumentation support like the ones in
GCC and rvm and therefore if you do not
have the com sort code access or or
compiler support you can use
hardware-based like processor Trace like
Intel pts however they are not very
stable and not very mature to use
and in our situation we use binary based
static rewrite and dynamic tracing a
fighting approach
for funding with resource code access
you have a compiler instrumentations
like the very typical AFL implementation
that it insert code at Edge transfers
and record coverage Edge transfers in
the sharp memory current location is
generally have a random generated and
the share memory records the control the
control flow transfers and the inputs
that triggers new local states which
means it touches new code is added to
the queue and the inputs that have no
use are dropped
uh so we have a very we are very
familiar familiar with open source
software fuzzing and there are tons of
use cases started here and tools to use
however for closed Source uh binary
funding like the previous box we we
discussed there are few real work cases
that we can refer to and especially for
mobile boundaries so in today's talk we
like to fill the gap between the theory
and actions
so first thing first is that so which
one do we need to choose for binary
funding static rewrite or dynamic
tracing
uh our conclusion here is that factory
rewrite is an option for Android
boundaries but it has many disadvantages
for example the arm ct4 support for
Android boundaries is immature at least
for a publicly accessible tools that
they have runtime crashes income
coverages especially for complex
boundaries
and also funding on phones is uh you you
have many issues that on if your father
and phones you have overheating issues
low for privacy issues or even physical
bricks issues it is so it is of course
more convenient and more affordable and
cheaper 2000 servers especially on X x86
servers rather than arm servers so a
conclusion here is that uh rewriting arm
binaries and fathom and armed phones is
not very acceptable solution not enough
scale and of course you can try it on
servers but we do not we did not test
here and I think is it is somehow a bit
expensive on AWS so it's an open
question here that we can discuss later
if you choose a dynamic tracing approach
you still have some decisions that need
to make uh you do do you want to use the
Trap or debugger approach it is great in
Macos format advising as demonstrated by
project zero and it's also good for
doing quick dirty tasks and fasting in
the service apis but have the same
problem that it does not scale
so finally we choose the cumul approach
for the dynamic treating fasting a cumul
you know that cumul provides a dynamic
binary translation where transistor
block the TCG time no tiny code
generator has Ops isir and for Target
machine code it translates the target
machine code to uh where front end to
open to Ops ir and the Ops IR is
translated by backend to actual host
machine code and and executed the whole
flow is Illustrated here that for each
Target PC a translated block counter is
looked up and if the block is already
translated and is catch the transit code
is directly executed
and therefore
uh for untransit blocks the
the code the block is will be will go
through the TB generator code and it
will translate it into a new block and
change it to explain existing block and
the transit code is executed and for a
synchronized interrupts process iOS and
there's no more a translated block
exceptions uh the excitement handling
routine is called
so a procurement approach we can insert
the coverage collection of our TB
hooking and they there are some
implementations some patches in the AFL
plus plus and AFL Unicom into the cumul
code and so that the coverage is is
recorded when the TV is executed and
translated
uh so for human approach we still have
some options here that uh Kuma Unicom
provides a raw interface to run machine
code that it can run some code at a
given memory address of given content it
also uh Pro it provides callback and
memory interfaces for end users and
developers which means that it does not
have support for this course or AFL in
the erf initialization or loading and
the user need to implement them himself
the QV user on the other hand reduced
uses the host operating system
environment to support different
instruction set and there is a
translation for this course to host
kernel with the same Cisco interfaces or
ebi so that you can use Google user to
execute Android arm ex64 harness on x84
Linux server
uh so to draw uh to to give a more uh uh
clear illustration here you can see that
uh for cumul a system that uh when when
it executes the binary it actually have
the CPU immigration part their interface
part the peripheral model part and flow
control part A cubic user approach
actually delegates the io interfaces and
a periform models to its translate and
forward it to host operating systems
however for human user approach you need
to implement the assist calls yourself
like implementing a provided kernel and
even managing the memory and and
implementing the peripheral models
yourself
so uh
okay so uh to draw conclusion here that
Community come is a faster than human
user if you implement the ciscoes
yourself with the cost of engineering
effort but the QB user is very fairly
enough to conduct funding with a proper
harness
foreign
unicorn approach and Community approach
for conduct funding on the about
mentioned harness
so the first input is actually a very
common image case image seat in the AFL
images and we prepare the relevant
screen partition in the environment for
the camera user to run the Android
boundaries the funding it runs at 200
200 seconds at 200 per second per core
and the 66
000 per server.com is like a 7 000
crashes here under the box is all
Dimension above
uh so for crowd charging that there's a
problem that cumul does not reflect
reflect crashes to host and you will
need a custom arminer and Bug Tracer we
hear you some memory sanitizers like
this locator and curation the Quran is
especially useful
so uh here's uh the power for the
dynamic dynamic fuzzing and for other
cases we also found a large part of
critical High celebrity box in the
Samsung symbol library and show Miss
Library another vulnerabilities but due
to the disclosure process we will not
discuss it more here
uh finally we have some references on
the tools and the codes and you can read
them more if you are interested
so here's our first slide and do you
have any questions under the relevant
POC and the fasting harness and funding
script will be available at the at my
GitHub after the talk
thank you
[Music]