[Applause]
hello to all
thank you for being present it's nice
before just starting the talk there is
something that I had to do for a
long time once again that's why we
attended an idea has only a small
moment I had given something to
someone and it turns out that suddenly this
someone has something for me and he
wanted to give me today so
we are going to make the changes quickly
it happens that this someone  and I
don't know how we manage to
find
a cash register that's
a cash register
and more or less old and which in my
opinion it will be the subject of a
proper dismantling is certainly
a myth  analysis beating suddenly I have
something for you I'll be back
after the rabbit skin of microphones
[Applause]
it takes up space as a jeweler
also goes to the
and hey you are for who you know at
second minitel yeah you don't care
thank you in time when
I see them later wait  tion
over it's packing up
ok good
thank you and again thank you for the cash register
so we're going to talk about two wifi routers
we no cash register
today mainly to
simply beat so it's a wifi router
as an example and  I think we
can extrapolate to other equipment
the idea is above all to say to ourselves well
here there are lots of things in the
bubble bath that come out on on-
board equipment, roads in wi
fi or other it  is very good but
what happens after a little introduction
for those who don't know what does
n't know me sorry I'm
a security engineer to coire slam my hobby
is all that's left too much
software engineering materia
incidentally it  it may happen
that I want to stream on twitch briefly
incidentally
if you have followed the news a little bit
in terms of vulnerability you must have
seen a lot of news appear in the
news on invited cities falling
on 20 which conceives  there were wifi routers
for example we will take one
because it is quite nice it is the
moon that touches cisco small business
or cdd router here not necessarily wifi
and there is an execution of commands which
is possible on it like c  is the case
of a lot of equipment as well as
denial of service it is marked critical
nevertheless relatively relatively
critical is roughly speaking what we can
do to suck execute arbitrary commands
as a route so like
the  very critical level of vulnerability
so the truth is due to
poor validation of the parameters
sent on http bins
again something fairly standard and
we have encountered many times it allows
to execute commands with a
route level  the part that's a bit more
annoying in this story is that
the manufacturer of those on this gear
said that actually down that it was over
there was no more support on this
gear is so they don't go  not
correct vulnerabilities
so that means what does it mean that
if you have this equipment there at your
disposal
you will not be able to fix you will not
be able to update everything is
all you can do is
to remove it  of your of your system of
your story and no longer use
it it's a bit of a shame in the story
because it would be nice if we could still
correct the vulnerability there
is a reflection made behind who is
to say is this  that we could not by
chance knowing that we have root access on
this type of original equipment or even
this vulnerability by making the patch
which is then it is not the case study
that I will take  concept for this
time but really the weight of the
first tic that we have is that we have
cookie equipment on which we can
have road chains and we can do
a bit of everything and anything finally or
not  it depends on the configurations and here
what will interest us in this tau  x
is in particular to see what we can
do what we cannot do what are
the limitations and I let you
imagine after what you could
consider facing this kind of
problem others in the news on
find other vulnerabilities and
zyxel routers here which are again
vulnerable to command injection
so i haven't been digging
code level but generally speaking
about command injection of routers
etc it's d  'call to system which is
not globally protected so
a nice injection of commands via a
system call which this time
allows you to execute commands with
the nobody utility it's a little less
cool that a tool is in  road but it's
already a first step to
compromise on this sense
and equipment in
short all that to say that ok you have
a road shell but having a road oak
on equipment does not mean that
you have totally  vs  compromise
the equipment to be able to install a
backdoor to be able to take control
there is still such a margin
if you have a wheeled shell on
an equipment not necessarily mean that
you will be able to pivot thing
power you will be able to attack other
equipment behind it  will give up its
problems afterwards and of course
that does not mean that you rang the
system because suddenly you did not have
full control over the fath system on
these configuration files on the
services which fall on it in short you
cannot  do what you want with
with equipment so before digging
into more detail the really post-
exploitation part that this talk typically deals with,
we're going to do a little
summary for those of you
who won't necessarily know how
a running linux works  on a
wifi router my little pepper with
embedded linux and we're really going to leave from the
bar, that is to say from bern metal everything
that is close to the ha  rdware and we are going to
go up gently towards the systems
and applications so that you have
a little idea of how it works and i
will be useful to understand what
ill happen next good
et's take a platform here an arrie
a g25 world arrieta g25  it's a
small board on which we find
ram you have in particular here on the
left of the slide an arm cpu so an
atmel I don't know how much the head 91 knows
something about expansion ports
like on races checks for example
and then of course a place to put
a flash card an sd card sorry a
flash memory which will contain the
operating system it is generally in
time to embark it is generally
what we need i.e. a
processor  a system on chip for the
vast majority with ram to be
able to execute code and a
storage medium on which we will bring in
particular the firmware it is also
common in these architectures to have
a score at p  eine a mud drome that is to
say that the system of a system on a
chip whose chip here is more than
you see it has passed not just a
chip there is a small part of rome
inside we who will say we are said well  sure
memory henry denis so it's going to
slam once and for all in the
chip and it's she who will be in charge
of doing all the mud
strapping process which will trigger the execution
of the application code which is installed on
the memory  there already there are already a lot of
funny things depending on the
architectures it is for this contract to
test with all winners at one or 7
there are little
weird things they provide you with
binary codes to put in
special places for it to run
normally you don't know what's in
it is that this volume and there are bits of
rome where you can have control which
is very practical especially when you
want to do secure boot  late
radio it's all the same later but in
in any case this sulking but there for
charge to go launched the bootloader so
ok bulldozers it's a piece
of code which will be loaded from the
flash memory which will have the objective
of loading the operating system of
him what  he will do is that will
detect all the
storage devices that are present and it is in
particular the sulky that will allow you
to start from a usb key
for example from the network we move
the author  the vast majority of the time
it's to make breaks and purpose
because people don't take the
lead but we also have other bootloaders
there is ycc up and it's that we can
find on some  systems in
short, this bulldozer will then
load the kernel and the kernel will have the
objective of going, in particular, to launch the
whole system and that's so that's
really the boot chain, we'll
say standard that there isn't  has no
protection necessarily put in place and
this is what will allow in particular  t
launch the embedded system
I talked about secure boot secure boot
is a process that consists of a
security mechanism that consists of
ensuring that each piece of software
that will be run on the system is
legitimate and authentic  that is to say that
we have a good rome no
boot code that is installed in the chip
that cannot be changed and I
insist on that because that has some
implications in terms of security this
code that cannot  changing it will go to
check that the bootloader has a
valid signature which is valid and
therefore by the idh the supplier of this code
which is supposed to be an official supplier
if the signature is valid in this
case he will execute will
transfer control  on the end of the
authors the bulldozers him at the time of
loading the system will similarly ensure
that the system is indeed authentic with
a signature verification and it will only
start the kernel when the
signature this match ser  to the one expected
or that it will simply be valid
and its mechanisms there of course obvious
that clever little ones tweaking
memories to go and put codes that are
going well to do things that are
not planned in
short keep that in mind chapter
d  after that will be useful
at the memory level let's talk about the
flash memory on which we store in
particular the notebook the fal system etc
and well its flash memories experience
form more generally so when
you're lucky that it's
old enough you  have the format that you
find on the left what is called
the shard 48.48 big h 24 on each side
usually nand alain flash memories
typically and when you are a
little less lucky I say that because
technology has evolved  you have the
chips which are therefore located on the right which
are in the format of ibg to bald grid of re
with contacts which are made between
the chip and the circuit to say
that once it is welded you can  You can't
access the component pins
unless you go underneath in some
cases, but hey, it's still a bit more
annoying to do. Is it that these
flash systems
still use the same architecture to
store the data and we
typically find  other storage
remembers pages which stores a
certain amount of information
certainly knew for fans
system systems define
hard drives sorry to pass these
systems hard drives which
also stores data and we have a moment
made of typically the  size of this
sector what is the size of the
smallest given that we can write or read
from a hard disk on flash moments
it is the same at the level of the
controllers which are integrated we can
read and write only one  certain number
of bytes here in the present case these
flash memories which have a page size
of 2112 bytes and there is a small end at
64 bytes which we find later
q  we generally call the spe rare
and house of band arias, that is to say
data that will be surplus and
which will allow in particular to
store information,
that is to say that when you have a
2 gigabyte flash you do not  you don't have 2 gigs
you have two gigs +64 times the number
of pages oct is available, that is to say
that in fact the flash is more than 2
gigs and this space is generally
used for what are called codes
error correctors but not that we
will have the opportunity to talk about it again after the
error correcting codes of the error correcting codes
this is what is
called the oc c which uses in particular
without using pardon to detect
flows  flip because the
nand technology is not 100% reliable when you
do writes in the pages
sometimes because the storage cell
is a little worn out in some places
etc. there are beats that will go from 0
to 1  or 2 to 0 and it's quite common and
that's a bit pro  problematic
because suddenly when we extract
firmware sometimes we have beats that
don't match and that will complicate the
task of analyzing the firmware
dance dance block of 64 bytes that we
saw previously so we have codes
error correctors whose
objective is to be able to recover
errors on 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 bits
according to the size of the code
generally these
correcting error correction codes are based on a
system and an algo that we  calls ch
which is the most common in flashes
it's not just that the south has insisted on that
you often have bch but not only
because there are certain vendors
certain manufacturers who develop
their own algorithms to make
leaving its  especially those who
integrate demand controllers into
systems on chips I'm thinking of broadcom I
'm thinking of others other and other
equipment and who have their own
mechanism in fact they have their own
way of coming to write the  s data
from code detection code
error corrections and when we come
across that again we have to
adapt
in addition to that the storage memory and
being quite limited and above all based
on portland and suse systems
as the use or its view
of the usb keys they are given for
a million writes have a million
rewrites the same for the sd cards
because in fact the
storage cells wear out regularly and therefore
to avoid having dead cells
too close finally death of a mother too
quickly what the
hour control systems do is they will
try to distribute the wear and tear the even
use of storage deaths over the set
cells available in order to
increase the life of the memory
so that is typically present and
that is also why for those who
do forensic that you are told that these
are usb memories, in particular usb flash memories
usb keys or other ca  it is
very difficult to completely erase
the content because in fact each
time you are writing you are
not rewriting on a blog that already
exists but savvy and allocate a block
elsewhere and therefore you have to do this
many times to  be sure to have
rewritten all the blocks at least once
and it depends a lot on the algae
oddo raises ling
wear distribution system and so keep without
also in mind if you do forensic
that's why  the standards of
waiting that we find on flashes
finally flash memories or usb key
it is always a little more
complicated and longer than what we have
on the usual hard disks at the level
of the bone we typically find
the name mtd port memory
technology device is generally a
type of device which is represented on
the excitation or linux genre stages and
which needs a particular driver
between often the mtd point k o driver
which is often used and which  allows in
particular to manage the Zionist party of the
party on partitions in for
anglicisms and therefore in its partitions
will find different tricks such as for
example a cutting in size of the
memory of the dead flash say that from a
point of view of the bone the  flash memory
is like a hard disk in which we
will be able to write and there will be certain
partitions which will be accessible that
means that pigments that this
data there generally it is inserted
directly at the carnal level lordat
compilation we can also the sphere
dynamically thereafter with certain
limited tools of 8 x or linux but
roughly what we can do is to
already have an idea where the
bootloader is where the kernel is
where the fs routes are found you have
root access  you have access to that so
already with a scale axis you can
retrieve all this information
is stored the data and what types
of data are stored where in
da  ns my flash memory
and of course to accompany all to
dance mtd in ltd partitions we will
find specialized file systems
or not moreover which will
allow access to the files which
are used by the system in particular
the root partition and that  is in these
file systems we have
file systems that are said to be specialized
in nand game flash memory but I
put an asterisk on the first one
because it is not typically
specialized in flash memory storage
but we find  a lot in
the embedded because it's a
compressed file system so very useful
especially when you don't have a lot of
space it's the son it's the sheed
also to display squash and fes everything
you need  does little hardware rivers or
as for the npd of flash memories or who
are interested in
router forms or other it is necessarily finally
it is obligatory you have at least had
to do once this type of
file format o  n there are others of course the ffs
two for example very used on
android gfs2 than another
journaling file system and the version
in version 2 which has improved support in
particular for nand storage systems
and we have one of the most  common in any
case nowadays that they have undergone effect
which is based on the system u country an
output of blocks imagine I
spoke to you about it later in a little more
detail but roughly speaking this
btrfs file system is  perhaps a start
of the most efficient in any case at
the present time and that is why it
is very useful very used
glued buttocks as I said
compressed file system not at all optimized
for storage moors in other words  it will
cause a lot of writing which will
consume a lot of cells and not just
one or two and suddenly it will use up
your storage system much faster,
especially the flash memory the
file system decompress in ram
thank you the file system  iers to
decompress in ram and we find it
very used on flashes and this country
but that means that here typically
when we make a modification of a
file system or make
modification
inram
necessarily on the
ffs disk of it  is optimized for
nantes storage why because in fact which I
pass it goes very well in the slides
here but roughly speaking we have a storage
which matches the size of the page
used in the flash so basically it will
use in a way  we will say
intelligent the two missions you
choose for example range and the 64
bytes of this father to nothing and it uses
this father area to store
metadata and in particular the error
correcting codes but it is not only
that it puts the oc  c including error
detection and correction codes
but in addition a side of that it will also
store metadata on the system
I did fes 2-1 to the file system
same size of blogs that match the
size of the  page by  against it a little
longer because suddenly for
this one you have to pass all the blogs
which are used to find the
file system it is therefore very slow
to mount when you make a world for
example of this kind of partitions that
takes time on the other hand we heard
read / write access it remains really
good and unlike in particular what
I did just like the 7 case also for
ja ffs two there are com effects of the ffs
two have read write access on  the
fath system is only used if you
write to a file on this site and
the files it is automatically finally a
few delays it is
automatically replicated in
flash memories because it is flash companion of
its small
and ubs which is therefore  the
file system that we find the most so it
's quite a complex estac we
go from the ltd device through what
they call the smes and the physical
eras block we know what a physical at
the risks we are  on on  ubs this
time it's a page in fact it
represents a block of storage which makes
the size of a page the size of an ace
block and the system u pays it's a
system that will use that will use me  calling
logical blogs on physical blocks
avoids giving it away
, that is to say that if you ever have
data that moves or files
that are a little split or on
which they have rewritten imagine that we
would see writing the end here of this file
we are just going to change the location of the
last of the last b we are just
going to update and if this structure
and add a little but here it
avoids doing too much writing it  is
a file system which is fast
which showed quickly who is
journaling which also supports
compression which is very used and which has
read-write access except in the case of
a particular configuration and therefore under
linux we have a lot of tools to create
all these systems  files have created at
the fo  is the binaries that are fine
kernels and system dfas generally
you have file system creation suites
like byd route or yoke rates which
are used quite often the vast
majority of them use busybox
busybox a shell implementation
plus utilities  linux but in live mode
it really weighs nothing and it's
totally configurable you can
allow the presence of a binary or
whatever it's a sort of configurable command line toolset
and it's very very very often  present
and that's where it's quite funny is that
in fact buzz ebook to work
it only works with symbolic goods
that is to say that if you want to have the
ls command you will point
the  command and leaves with a
symbolic air on bbox and he will
detect that it has been called with ls he
will execute the command and the ess and for
the record in fact you
often have buzz boxes which allow you to do
much more  more commands than the
simple binary that you find in the
wise big mustache us has been especially
on embedded systems
all that to get to the third
part of this presentation the
problems that post
exploitation encounters so here we get to the
interesting heart of the problem  so
I try to also propose some
solutions but we'll see what it's worth
so remember we're on the road is the
big question that's to say but that's
good we're tough what are we
what-  what we can do afterwards and
there are plenty of possibilities I don't want to
talk about all these possibilities during
toc but the first is to
play them mirail style I'm going to play the
mirail style in fact we're going to drop a
binary in  ram is the binary will be
executed and will create a botnet
for example of two peripherals
or compromised equipment and from there
we will be able to do denial served on the
entire planet we know that we experienced a
small  little l  'era mirail see what
i'm talking about we can play it watchdoc style
you know the game ubisoft intends to return
by hacking systems we intend here
to bounce back anyway getting
worse from a compromised system
could hackers and others
systems and then bounce back
then pivot to arrive at
compromising all the systems or we
could really do it hacker style,
that is to say well you are a bit of that nasty
and you absolutely want to
take complete control of the system
and not  only being able to
execute commands and well that's kind of what
I'm suggesting you do here so it's
not necessarily the ski will be adapted
adopted as in terms of approach by
real attackers who will more
certainly go  on the side of the mirail,
that is to say after we will execute a
binary and we will do we will use
the platform to make a rebound for
example but it is also more put
chalandon is more interesting to go
dig into what we can do so I
'm going to base this part of the toc on a
case study of a router of which I will scrupulously keep silent about
the no don't look
it's just to illustrate the point
but it's valid for any type
of equipment again and I will
remind them during the conclusion there are
certainly other
security mechanisms that exist that are not mentioned
in this in this talk I will
quickly remind them towards the end but if you
want to discuss this mechanism has not
then don't hesitate until you're ready after
the con so what do we have we have a
vulnerability let's take the most
classic with a sky escape I can
issue commands on the
command system ideally on the way  well, I could
n't get there this morning, you can
imagine that if we have
commands executed on the system, there are
also risks that we will harm systems
and when we study this kind of
vulnerability when we are a  researcher
in s  security we perform we provide ourselves with
the same equipment here imagine I
bought equipment a wifi router which
is similar to the one that interests me
and suddenly I can look for a generality
in it and to make my life easier
because I know that  in the process
the device will inevitably be lighter the abandoned device
I will unsolder the flash is soldered a
small socket and the small photo
you have here in the slide it is a
kind of socket there is exactly the same
imprint as a flash mob 48 that  you may
wish in place and a hassle to
weld if you are if you are trying to
do this take your time but
once you have the south east of the
sock in place after of
course bunkers and the influx of downforce  this
flash you can insert it back in and
with appendix programmers
first make a theme of the flash and then
restore the contents of the flash if you
can do trial and error sig ii
to facilitate compromise
or facilitate  té in any case the
third possible tests third example
also if we really do
hardware hac in some cases we have access to
a debug console which can facilitate
the search for vulnerabilities as
a fine operator when
we exploit  remote device suddenly
we will only have the shell script
to work but we will use these
two axes and tricks there,
namely access to the flash or the fact of
making bricks and equipment and that the
console  syria to facilitate the
exploitation phase and that your there we want for
example to modify the system look at an
access on this system we want to be able for
example to deactivate updates the
updates it is not our friends when we
do the  compromise when we
do access matters in particular but because
imagining that the router on
the update overnight any
system is going to be stuck in the trash
and all your pretty modifications are going to
be changed not  terrible or you
're really nice you say to yourself
it would be really cool to put a
double green open and on a
rotten road which is all vulnerable well yes
why not it could be
interesting so we will talk
about all that the first pitfall  which you
can face are the
henri-dominique file systems in other words
you arrive on the system you want to
file a backdoor or a tool to
do bio thing you are going to put
in sage tmp when the great us the
vast majority of the gains on the other hand
when you want to maintain
maintain your access forgiveness put a
ring on time or other it becomes more
problematic because there are
file systems on which we
cannot write on which we have a
curtain partition the dip for
example tape  fs squash is made on
some systems so mounted in
ram and it's henri denis you can't
modify the content you have the slash
hockey you want  it put a thing in his
ankle or whatever there is
no access to lie and orrit mint comma
r w as we usually do with the
internship of course after on android when
you can get write access
it doesn't work no  more so it's
problematic only we have
workarounds there are solutions
the solution is a bit risky but
consists in saying ok the system eye
prevents me from rewriting on the other hand I know
that the data is stored in such a place
in the  flash remember with the mtd
we have forgiveness the partitioning we
know exactly where to go so if i want to
rewrite the fact system roots because
what to do is extract the
fascist and even root closed
modifications get a new
scotch image and  fez for example and re-
file it directly in the flash
via the system commands a
simple cpf the case for this kind of
manipulation so before you must of course
take care of 2 mp of sys file  tem
and then we go to the patch and I'll
pass on the details on the patch agen de
squash fs we used facts are
modified files reminds to tape
buttocks etc you must have no
home your isp system to
install your super backdoor from
death you have to put it back in the flash
and so to put it back in the flash
we will copy the backup the fire image of the
fal system that we modified and we will
re-file it with root access that's
all  quite doable with root access
little trick which I have bitten
my fingers quite a few times do
not use the stage of the mtx stages we could
be tempted to do it with x number of
the partition of a problem c  is if you
do that you will make a write
that will not be synchronized and that will
not be with a device of the type
blocks device blocks therefore on linux and
prefer to use this age of mtd block
xx I lost a lot of time with this
with  that because every time I
repeat  was writing the flash I had errors
of these it is precisely
error correcting codes because
the writing was not done as it
should while with the use
of dave mtd bloc it was much
better the same mtd  block xx that you
have here managed by a driver is
called were blocks that must
also be loaded to be able to
access them but in the large add
targets in any case only one that I could
test it was present it is necessary  do not
hesitate we name the file system
scotch fs through usb ports
accessible external storage or
directly from the network we can make a 4
for example davd event and blocks 1 and
sent saint vianney of 4.6 our case
very present and busybox  if it is not
present on the fal'cie this theme in a
symbolic link check that it is not fooled
books directly by typing the command
busybox hillis all the
commands supported on your side and on
your pc you put  one and four in
eco  ute and you redirect the fire
directly to a binary file we
phase analysis i stem have made the
modification and we will try to do
something the problem here is
also wish to have the right
questions that's what I'm going to put a
day we file system ok but
what will happen next
I change the route file system well that's
good but remember the secure boot
secure boot there was a problem
anyway because secure boot you have to look at
that anyway  in a corner of the head
good here in this case there was a
unitary medium iron bankruptcy update utility of
firmware update it is practical it avoids having
to type all their winters ce2 how
the updates work and therefore we
will use the firmware degree of file
system to make systems to create
a system image for example modify
and deploy the update so that we do
not have to type directly on the
partition and this since  simple  well let's take
a look at this great utility that we saw
we write very small this post
happens to him to read but I will
detail you a little bit what is happening
so here typically there is from the
first part which is located here  yes
here yes my pointer at worst if the
first part which is located here I
see that he is kidding in short the first
part here with the if it is to choose
a question the partitions which will be
targeted then he will decipher the
content of the  'image to extract the
last 400 bytes and there is a question
of signature and if we zoom in a little bit
on a part of the code in fact it does
an integrity check on the
fs route with a signature with a
file dot p m that  starting to smell
bad it means that here
potentially an authentication
is done on the fath system and if I
rewrite the fhal system suddenly it's
finished it will be detected at the next
system reboot will not start if
there it is  a big indicator in  any case
of secure boot or pseudo secure boot
we will see later so quite
interesting if we look a little
more in detail we see in particular and
although we have copies of files which
will be made in partitions
stored directly  system the ps
is from carnel dst this is what we
found here at the very beginning whose
partition there is a partition
apparently that stores
information so do we know
we know that the file system
degree of condat provide is  he also
signed canton deza seems well the binary
we know that the new signatures
of this file system of this gred file
are stored in a
specific partition the big question is ok
it stores all in the partitions it is
certainly to be able  use it in
the boot world so with a secure boot
well let's take a look at it so there
is suspicion of secure boot so we'll
try to see how it works
then secure boot is bi  in
secure boot it works well the only
problem is that as I said if
you modify
duroux fs files it does not put you off except that at the bottom
when you find a bubble
in secure boot the secure boot actually does
it  there are different ways to do
secure end there is the right way and the
wrong way guess what
was put in place here otherwise I wouldn't be
here to talk about it if he had done it
correctly here it was the wrong one
way so we managed to have kept
a little how it works the level
of security but here we are then the sulk
roms in some cases do not check
the integrity of the hour job that is to
say that they do not have  the possibility of
generating a boudouaou so it's the
bulldozers that does all the
secure boot part but once again the
hourly job is what is in the
flash we can modify perhaps only in a
way of  patch the bootloader
to modify the operation is
deactivated the verification of signatures
why not but first we have to
look at how it works so what do
we do we look with bulldozers
small precision before entering the
code of the sellers bund so I have already
saved the  bowsprit of the boss of the bazaar and
the bootloader used to a system of
stand alone applications based on a
road so in fact it's something I
discovered for the occasion there was an
August hub which had stands of olonne
application what are they going
to do hot pic it's a kind of plugins
for a drop that allows you to add
features are pretty cool there is
an api that exposed by a drop and
its sphere the compilation on  compiles
both the taste the smell and the
stand alone application and from there the
sulky can hand over to the application which
will manage a whole bunch of stuff but a whole
word custom and that's what  they were
using here so this
stand alone app it is loaded and if  we
look a little bit at the code we see in
particular who is going to read at a
particular place he dares a data which is
located at the address 40000 in the flash
in the 13th fair 81 000 of water
so it is good and a little more  far in
the code he will copy we are not too
readable because here will finally guide
little crap on the part of the
compilations but in fact he will make the
same copy of what is at
the address 81 00 and  20 doctors
at address 81 1000 and then a little
further in the code it will call the
code that is here good that's
how the application to load in fact
it gives little islands of the flash an
application  third party he loaded memory
and then they transfer the execution of
the application it is quite simple we have
an email with different parameters that
are passed and it turns out that the mind
looks something like this so it's
undrinkable code and  it doesn't matter
first step we load the signatures
we decrypt qua signatures  nd we do
n't describe we decrypt
yeah not said we don't say encrypt an
ipad name it in short
we decrypt the signatures
from an rsa key we get h at 256 he is
already calculating the redemption of 156
compared the h and  if it's good we execute
or not well yeah but here I have a if and
then a second if it can be
interesting to go digging so to
synthesize we have a score which
contains signatures the sulky
notes Czech signatures of carnel  the
pomp does it road system if any
match it executes yeah but seïf the
key happens to me if I change if
I force them if I say but in fact everything
is good don't worry no problem
for the little story just
modify  two therefore opt instead of
paper the root f s if we patch the
bootloader at the same time and we manage
to deactivate the signature verification
it is to save life balloon
let's do a small patch of bulldozers
thank you will guide in passing a small
editing mode d  instruction that follows  to
practice so i did a job of
modifying that i then copied from the
one route i had on the
mt bootloader partition of blocks 0
and then i rewrote the
ntfs partition with a route and facebook  says proud
and of course if ever his magnifying glass because that
's always the case when you do this
kind of manipulation isn't sure that
the Drôme mud checks well and well if
ever his magnifying glass it doesn't matter
because I  like a little flash that I can
remove and reprogram there it's
perfect the suspender belt
let's go we modify all that and well guess
what happened it worked so
from there we can consider lots of
things for example  to maintain
the action can put a boot script
that will launch as backdoors enough
lab poor actors based on bbox and
elne and such designs some
help you can ask from the old
a particular script or binary
when  the tcp connection and not
typically create ic  i you have an open skies remote
has always without authentication
was thought 1500 its 777 which is not the
best idea as we say
you can install a golden pack version
of bbox or to add accounts
for example and also the possibility of
do porto king 60 on some
systems if you can put me a
binary note for example sending
a series of packs and particulars
with rules that are put in place little bit
this pony a shell on demand so it's
pretty handy that c  is more stealthy in
terms of recovery is just as
interesting good in what they
suit me in the case that interested me
ok do the maintenance of the racks and the
bins of the system etc
I could have also modified the binary
which  made updates to
disable updates from
you can do a complete write
of a complete rewrite of the system
it's won but it's not always
the case that we could see the cij had modified
ie the spinning wheel did this from the get go i
would have had issues
my aim was a bit more a bit
lower glorious i would say the most
interesting and that was to arrive for
the equipment that was vulnerable
modified its system of  exploitation
put an openwrt so think that they do
n't know open open and it's a
dedicated firmware for routers its
son in particular which is completely open
and which uses the latest versions of
the up-to-date linux kernel island and the
latest versions of  up-to-date services we
know very practical and it supports a
phenomenal number of chips
and good equipment except mine because
it's a bit weird that this
man who was made to order it
didn't exactly work for me that  it was
necessary to modify all that a little bit so
before I embarked on this super
stadium at this super
bread installation wrt bah suddenly I checked that
all the chips that were present on my
board were well supported, in particular who
gè  re wifi bluetooth etc and we
had to make the heavy decision to
go from squash suffered effect and fez as
I said forget fesf a longer
life in terms of the use
of nand flash it's better and the
sealant  I also realized
that the open wrt toolkit is really
well done to say that I did not know
finally I knew openwrt before
I had never gotten my hands
dirty with this thing and when I
dug a little on search  low tool kit
it was really super practical I was able to
adapt scripts to install
openwrt on my super wifi router I
also modified the partitions for me to
have more storage space because
there were two versions of firmware
c  is quite common I will not talk about
when we saw the first part two
first partitioning but there are two
routes is done there are two kernels which
are there to do what are called
ab installations i.e. you have
one  image of farmer  s to and a
b firmware image if ever they can't
get rid of the format it launches
bs firmwares which allows on
updates to avoid bricks and equipment
so me here I excuse is purely and
simply these  parts there because the
open wrt system already has this kind of
function of built-in mechanisms and it
is able to roll back and
here I have an open open and on my
equipment without with a little
trouble thanks to a vulnerability  which
allowed me to have a route shell so
as I said in the introduction it is a
particular use that we ensure on this
kind of thing but I could very well
have lefa the system etc
now when you  think back to skis
to the images that were swung a
few years ago from what is called
theory for those who know the
taylor dax operation only to a team in
particular
if I got a link that made
particular installations or
particular modifications  by village  of
cisco routers at the time there is a
good chance that this evening of the kind of
hack worried that they have done we do
not have more details of the plan pure
speculation on my part so we will
necessarily end up nicely with the
conclusion  so in conclusion of all
this what can we say we can say
that when we have a route shell on an
equipment we can manage to
compromise the entire system
but in some cases it can be more
difficult than  others when we
deal in particular with mechanisms such as
secure boot such as the
signature signal such as file systems
which are accessible only in read only
secure boot low on paper it
works but there is a lot of
literature in all  case of
leading in the world to cyber security
on urban sites which was which
was broken either because sulking
rome had a vulnerability or because
as is the case here we do not have a
real secure boot we have  a good smell that  i
did a firmware authenticity check
and we can rewrite the
bootloader we can't touch the
bulldozers still is it that if you
try to reprogram
the flash memory live remotely with a
modified file system it's
still s  to risk it you have you
risk bricks and equipment and
father your access we may not
necessarily have the best move to make
clearly you understand better
now why the sites and the
people who have exploited
of ip cameras connected or other there are a
hundred are mainly due to I
launch an executable in memory and then
that's all it's the best way
anyway to be able to maintain
access but to be able to really operate
at 100% without risking  of bricks
and equipment now if you
are looking to modify the firmware
installed an open wrt for example it is
still the best way to do it
and it is the only solution in all
c  as to install an arctic open
than this volume so it's interesting in
any case on my side I remember that for
what I believe it's the first time
I installed an openwrt from scratch
on something was not  support as much
help some or a certain
wireless router I had succeeded with this little
thing is installed as many
perhaps of you have already done as
much added a device which is not
basic support in the
little opening  it's also super interesting to
dig into
so here is in any case this openwrt router to
turn and it's always a
good experience there are lots of things
that I talked about in this thing there lots of
things like containers
systems equipment that  we find at
the present time which are in fact
equipment which virtualizes a
whole set of functionalities from the back
on on the same equipment some
fairly sturdy stuff will talk about it for
example high school students
of linux meter systems there  also has
secure elements that they are totally
forgotten here in this talk simply
because in the case study that
I had chosen to illustrate the subject
was not present in it and then by
a matter of time if these are
systems that exist that are more
complicated to circumvent and on which
you can also come across at the
emulation level to make it really very
simple that it is not the point of going
into detail
when you have a route shell on this
kind of  equipment you have a
road shell in a vm running on
the team so there we fall back on the
same problem of skateboarding 2 v / m or
2 how to say lateral movement
that must be carried out to be able to
hit the real one  system which is below there
are methods there are ways to
do it but we are still on the
level of exploitation which is a little
more complex than the simple inscription
on a call to this system is
overall we have once again  just a
little  t being in quettehou can be
compromised with enough time and
the big question here is time
and either you have come across
equipment which adds adds to play
security mechanisms then it will be
complex in any case to carry out here I am
I was lucky enough to have a system
that was vulnerable quite
simply at the level of bulldozers but
in some cases we may have to
do boudreau rivers
or boudreau extraction when
possible and so on  and it's a
lot more work in terms
of exploitation
we're
going to take a few questions I think
it's high time also to
people who are interested
[Applause]
so we're going to do a clooney session
[Music]
hello
hello yeah  yeah good day just
to bounce back a bit on the last
sentence on time
a little question how
long did his whole life last here
ah yes there ok
yes that's the question was  so excuse
me the post him the question was
you ended up just addressing the time
it takes for precisely that
equipment that the more we are virtually
all hacker it's just a matter of
time tammy how long
to  for the understanding of this vote
how long ago I took his steps the
thing that really blocked me the most
in the story was when I was
flashing the job of the reds had
lots of errors and  there is the tunnel effect
which came a little bit from adam i
was sure it was a problem
due to what i was writing and it was
actually the method i use to
write the memory which was  good but
I'm not a few days to smash everything
after if I accumulate the time yes
for this compromise
but once again we are sure of the
compromise which is not too complicated
we are on hour work which can
be patched but in some  case it
may take more time
another question
good to u  do not question
your preference between a
physical extraction of the nand and use of let
's say a jtag directly for to
extract it depends mainly on
what you are looking to do what on the
nand as for an external request there
is no  gitaï which allows you to extract that
I can go in some cases by the
ploughshare to hit the moor but
in this case we prefer to
directly extract a world
from a dune parts apparently control
on the chip and on  the contents whatever
it contains and without having something
in jtag intermediaries we will use it
more for the bits of rome for example
to try to recover them that we feel
when we can access them and then
make withdrawals from  'a reverse engineering
I say well when you can access
it it's not all the time
thank you for the halo it's good you
hear me yes thank you for the
presentation a question is what
in cases where there are systems
of files with upside down aces e  u all of
that can be a problem with file systems
sorry in overlay in overlay it
can be a problem yes because
if you readjust the root partition you have to
generally in the default versions
of the files that are deposited
in it and that will be hidden by the
worley waters but in this case we can
manage to hide overlay challenge which
suggests before are located on
annexed partitions so it's just the
manna of the place we are going to write that it
will change
good our question yes no  we'll go otherwise
I think my colleague has already done it
but hey those who are interested in a
question so as a reminder afterwards
thank you for the press it was cool I have
a little question so there in your
case we have  modified its
bootloader to pass your conditions and
you said that suddenly it was a
bad way to do secure boot
typically put how you check
the integrity of your bootloader if you can
not read write and write your bootrom in
fa  it quite typically the boudreau
barque of the keys of the keys
of allowing the authentication of the
bulldozers so basically the mud of rome
makes
that we will say as to will
transfer executions to the bulldozers who
count themselves sounded flash the aude the
contents of the bulldozers calculates the h is
then authenticates 2 h at the base and on
the keys for the vast majority of the time
that means that your bootloader you can
never update it what yeah that
then if if if you can update
because  that generally you have two
methods either two lakes the ponds of
in the mud drome but generally the
signature goes with two bulldozers in
the flash memory that is to say you can
very well steal a new taste of
the hour water with  his new signature
and make it work it's
just that the key on the other hand it's
supposed to be secret and not power is
extracted for that i just now
that mud we are in some
cases we can  not forced  nt take them out and
generally we can't take them out you
have to use acts to succeed in
recovering the content and if you accept
the mud drôme generally that does not
mean that it can compromise the system
because it must be seen that you are  on a
system of asymmetric keys and with the key
generally here who is who and where he
declares I can and private publicly
but I believe that it is deprived of memory
which is used to verify as soon as those who are in
debt crypto suits me
well  sure if I say nonsense basically
you have a key which is used to verify
the authenticity a key which is used to
produce the signature and suddenly this
click is used to produce the signature so you
do not have basically even if you manage
to  getting your hands on the key is not
catastrophic from the point of view of the
security of the device that said it's
still not great to get your hands
on dabo must not what does that mean
that you have access to  codes that runs
and you can do the search
vulnerabilities typically buffer
overflow another function and we can
manage to present it with a condition
which means that suddenly we can divert
the use of the drome mud and
either execute code from the code
of the drome mud and bypass and
signature verification which is
generally what we are looking to do
but not only and that's it finally after there are
plenty of other serious things that can be
launched so that little can result from
but again it's not really
the same  level of research must be
done between judges I pass two
bulldozers and basta and I have to thank
everyone a good run find
vulgarities to exploit them
was arrested to be able to execute a code
which was not planned
so not  any other questions
ok thank you virtues of the look
[Applause]