[Applause]
thank you
so now
let's start so
good morning i think it's good morning
so my name is philippe peters again i'm
a brazilian but i live in portugal in
this moment with my big family
yeah i have four children maybe i'm
crazy probably
and today my idea is to
to talk more about the something that i
would like to think
because we saw in the last
presentations about debuggers and
debuggers more analysis and stuff like
that
it's pretty cool
but
we need understand how those bases works
and the idea behind of this talk is
explain about those bases and how
important
is to use those bases
for each
field when you talk about the cyber
security right
so this is my contact act twitter
i like to share
many open source tools there so if you'd
like follow me and send a message send
me tools i like to test as well
so
other contacts that i have a small
simple web page we can find some talks
there about the same topic in other
talks
and my github you can find some research
that i made in some security
vendors actually and of course i share
with those reports with the vendors and
i talk with them to improve the
solutions and stuff like that and my
linkedin
right so who am i i pass very fast i'm
security research at sapporo support is
a startup from swissland
i'm responsible for creating attack
modules from for this app so i need to
understand how the attack
how the attacker explore vulnerability
or using permissions in the cloud and
privacy environment
and i need to create those you know
scenarios and i sent to the developer
team and the team created to the
intelligence of the product it's very
nice
and i'm a founder of this organization
it's a small company for now it's a
black black watch technology it's my
company
and it's a kind of reseller company
actually and i'm developer advocate of
this uh open source projects cube shop
specifically looking for the testers
uh it's more when you talk about the
software development life cycle and
stuff like that
and i'm advocating of those projects
mainly
to the two of the oh this is
specifically it's a hacking it's not a
crime it's a very nice project starting
in us
the idea behind of this project is to
explain more about the haki concept
right
and how you can use in this in your life
because hacking is really not a crime
because when you talk about the crime
it's a cyber criminal is um you know the
people needs to pay for that not a
hacking hacking is a lifestyle lifestyle
and how you looking from the
software how to use your creative mind
let's suppose if you are a soccer player
and you do bad things like a cream you
you you and this moment you norma
you're no more
a soccer player you are a criminal right
so that's the point unfortunately the
newspapers on tv needs to pick up one
person and call this person has a hacker
the bad guy but it's not a hack is not a
it's not a crime another project it's a
defcon groups from my friend jason
i'm a leader of this project in sao
paulo one of those leads in sao paulo is
a community like this that we can share
the knowledge of security and others is
saying segura is specifically about the
solutions
for organizations in his nic is
assassin's solutions application
security for for the software action
analysis in code
and this last i mean right structure
writer and reviewer from those three
magazines this is light it's very
important for my mother because of that
i'd like to share with you okay
but anyway
so very fast what is a threat just to
put all those people in the same page
simple definition of definition from
flip from this iso is a kind of
potential incident maybe the software
attack tough intellectual property maybe
identity death sabotage and information
stores are example of information
threads the point is if you see here
all those things is related to a
software
maybe it's a code maybe software maybe
application or maybe a binary but if you
see all those things is about
the code right okay so when you
start your research or your analysis
when you talk about the
the mower analysis specifically or
hunting something
first you have an artifact or a sample
because you don't know if it's malicious
or not right so this is the first step
identification i will show after
semi-small comments and stuff like that
and you you need to understand if he's
malware it's a malicious software or
maldoc malicious document and after that
you can choose what the best methodology
you can apply okay statistic analysis
and dynamic analysis so two different
approach maybe you are think where is
reversion engineering reversion engineer
is a technique that you can use in both
of those methodologies right so when you
perform something like this
my recommendation is a suggestion
actually
when you do something like this it's
important to register all those steps
why because you can learn more about
those steps and mainly about the
technique used by the attacker what kind
of technique and after that you can
prepare an article you can prepare a
talks and you can present a report for
your manager it's good for manager right
or coordinator like this because you can
explain those
steps and how you discovery
what is the
way that the attacker used in your
organization not only that but you can
improve defense's mechanism because you
will understand what kind of technique
the attacker used
in your environment and what kind of
solution the attacker bypass your
environment because of that it's very
important and not only that but you can
create in this beautiful name called cti
or cyber threat intelligence it's a
beautiful name
right i know that is it's very difficult
to implement that but you can use in
some tools to automatize the process for
help you okay and of course other
beautiful word is straightening cyber
resilience because the
the threads are changing all the time
okay nice so what is the statistic
analysis simple definition basically is
the first step when you talk about the
mod analysis or threading hunting when
you're looking more about the binary not
about the tools because when you talk
about 3d hunting you need to hunting
using tools right but how you can
looking from the binary because in the
end of the day
our idea is to figure out how the
attacker using the binary to explore the
environment how the technique they're
using to inject something in the binary
and stuff like that because of that is
the first step when you talk about mri
studies not only that because this
the analysis the statistical analysis
analyze the process of the specifically
program code or if have some library
what kind of function is important by
this library if this library makes sense
or not makes sense with the the system
operation if using the the dll or
specifically library inside of the unix
platform for example
and this specific analysis doesn't run
at this time the file so you're using
some comments you see some results and
here's my the point of this talk
what is the result when you executing
the tool
because sometimes when we analyze
something we perform the tool
you see the results and you think
this tool doesn't work for me i don't
find anything for this binary but
actually we can find some results but we
don't
know how we can interpret that or in
understand actually the result of this
comment okay
so because of this is more safe and on
the other hand you have dynamic analysis
is a kind of analysis based on behavior
when you can put in this malware in
specific place and you can analyze the
behavior so i have a question for you
when you talk about the dynamic analysis
you can use in this this concept calling
sandbox right so you put in your binary
inside of this specif specifically
controlled environment
and you can run the binary inside of
that and you can see all those
behavior right so my question is so if i
create in the virtual machine in my
environment i have a sandbox yes or no
yes
ends up no
maybe
no
the people are shamed
i don't believe in the security events
that people are ashamed
i need to talk i need to talk bad words
like a you
yeah okay so actually here we have an
important information when you talk
about the sandbox we need to have
different engines inside of that so of
course it's a virtual machine that you
can execute the binary inside of that
but you need to have these engines
because those engines will be
responsible for
give you the result if this binary is
malicious or not based on those engines
based on those intelligence right like
you probably you already heard about the
uh virustotal right scanning so you put
in the binary there or url so they
they have many engines inside of this
platform like others like joey sandbox
or other hybrid cloud or other sandbox
so when you try
or you would you like to create your
sandbox you need to have those engines
inside of your environment right so just
a simple concept very nice okay let's
talk about the
binary all the first steps when you talk
about the binary as i mentioned it with
you so
first remember we we have the
[Music]
oops we have the identification step i
have here many files
let me put here i think it's more easy
to see
so we need to understand how those files
is exactly what kind of type so the
first step is to identify remember in
the flow so identification steps it's
pretty simple so first of all i would
like to see what kind of
file i have here so it's a simple amazon
i use file command right so
how many people heard about this comment
it's simple thank you god answers nice
and the second is malware.txt is
probably a text it's a text nice so
let's read what i have inside of this
text
nice what i have here
a simple python code right is that
correct or not
see yeah
no
i don't know
let's try
what happened now
cool
it's a mou it's a it's a python okay but
the extension is different
okay something works here so
i have a question again so
what is
what
how type works so what information the
type collects from the binary to
identify this specifically binary
do you know
what is for example let's check what
there is a
file sample here
simple
take a look this is a kind of different
when you see if you see here
i have a two text files but one of these
is a python script
executable
and this
is different you see
so what do you think about that why the
difference between the files
sorry man i can't hear you
maybe i don't understand my baby
okay
probably
i i really i sorry i don't probably they
have a microphone but sorry for that but
here is one specifically key
how the file works that's the point here
so
oh no philip i need to read the manual
yeah i don't like the read manual but
fio works
actually file looks for a specific
information is inside of the binary and
this information it's here
so if you read the book on the book the
manual
you see here the
magic
you see
the kind of tip here
actually this concept is called magic
number
how many people heard about that
think of god answers again so nice so
basically fio works in this way so they
try find this to find this information
in
so this file
here
this file here
have a magic number stored in particular
place
in the beginning of the file
you see so that's this is the
informations that the file use has a
base to find that
but philip how this works so actually of
course fios is compiling inside of the
uni unix platform they have a database
inside of that to check
those magic numbers not only
one specifically but
let's see here i think i download here
i don't remember but i think every yeah
file
magic
magic gear
yeah
and let's see take a look that this is
the
database i download this from the debian
to see how database works so let's check
for example
python
this is a kind this is a kind of
rules actually or magic number
that the file the
file used when they check the file
right so as you can see here some
informations like this take a look this
interesting they're using some
rules
and strings to define those files right
so if you see here three double quotes
and if i
if i return here for example
let's
um
change something here
so if i
change here for example and put those
three quotes and i will save this
let's see if the description change
you see
why
the question is simple why change
because i changed the reference of the
magical number in this specifically file
right
so if i change once again
um let's check here percent pdf the 1.8
save
and
now we have a what we have a pdf file
it's a simple magic number manipulation
of course it's a simple because it's a
text file i'm not talking about the pe
portable executable or alpha for unix or
other or macho for a mac os no it's a
software
for a text file right
and
if you are using for example pdf id is a
tool to check some strings in a pdf file
take a look this
the identification is
these tools
understand that this file is really a
pgf
but it's not a pdf
it's a python is that correct or not
right
so i am
manipulate something but the tool
because of that the tool is important to
give you the result but you need to
understand the result of those tools
malware analysis is a very nice topic to
understand about the reverse engineering
but we need to understand those bases
because when you perform something you
can understand if you attacker are using
some techniques
since the base
to advance it right so other things
interesting here is about that let me
show you
let me go to the windows
i think i have here yeah windows
and i have here
some files
okay and not here let me go to the
start with linux i think it's better
linux
so i have here some files okay
let me check if this is executable or
not
okay this is a elf binary okay it's
executable so let me check another
maybe it's a text okay
so take a look at this
another
super simple
tools to using in the first steps in the
first
when you talk about the more analysis is
strings right
dash o to see all those things now you
check for
the first errables
okay and i put the pipels here to start
the beginning
take a look at this what kind of the
first information you can find by
strings
this is the first string mentioned by
these tools right
but
when you using
uh
x
uh to to find some hexadecimal to to to
changing to convert actually the
the hexadecimal information for the
string
let's see what happened now in this for
the same
noise xt
this is the first string
so something happened here
put it here
not yet
not yet so where is the
the
the reference of the strings remember
not yet
okay
that's me changing
how many bytes 60 600
maybe
yeah here
this is the reference of the string the
first string remember
yes or no
yeah
but here
it's really the first string
and when you're looking from the
structure of the alfie
you can understand what those
reference years for example
um
meaning actually when you're looking
from the structure of the alpha i will
show you after
but here i have a one interesting point
so why
those ladders
doesn't appears when you executing the
string command
what do you think about that
to shorts
maybe it's a good answer
it's a good answer
and the explanation is simple it's here
in the beginning of this manual
um
no not this
yeah
what is the explanation
oh
what is is a key
strings yeah thank you
one letter
here
this is the answer it's a short
but
it's after
four letters
you see
simple
is basis
and we need to understand those basis so
how the binary works and all those
things but not only that but how the
tools for example
um let me go to the file here once again
i will talking about the
structure of the eu the linux right the
unix
where is the file here when they define
the structure it's here f dot elf dot
that
dash eight
um
locate
elf dot dash eight
is in the beginning here
here
cool
and
so here is the structure of the pdf the
elf
and here we can understand how this
works since the beginning for example we
have a specific array of the the
information specifically bytes in the
beginning how is uh
created those
words as words the words and so on and
so on
and and the header of the
the healthy that we have the health the
elf file that we have here
in the beginning we have the first array
of that we have 16 bytes right
the first array is called identity the
identity actually
and what kind of information we have
inside of this specifically 16 bytes we
have a magic number and others
information very nice what kind of
informations we have so if you go there
you can see
this words the letters elf take a look
this
so this is the first position right
zero
and this magic number the second is e
third l fourth f f
so this is the structure of the
the the the alpha file
not only that but if you go there you
can understand those positions for
example
let me
split other things here
and
um so let me compare
some files to show you here is xd
um any 32
[Music]
16 better
airbus
and another is xt
um
linux i think it's i have a thing 32
yeah
okay
so let's comp you can see there i think
you can see
okay so
if you see here in the beginning
is the same right the same information
that you can find here
so those reference about the structure
of the elf
and when you go there
let's
compare here
about those informations
let me
see here
so and the and this position
if is
0 2
is
what
16 bytes 64 bytes right
so and the second one
is not two is zero one why
because
is
32 bytes
see so let's check another
so about the structure it's the same
case the position seven so if you if you
see some
difference
we can check
how the tools works when you're looking
from the binary so that's the key so we
need to understand how
when you use some tools how these tools
can help you
but you need to understand deeply not
only the two but the concepts of the
binary
that's important is that the idea of
this conversation right
so cool
this is the when you talk about the
portables equitable i just mentioned i
had some instructor about that it's very
simple you have a sample here you have
it divided in two ways a habit in
session
and inside of the header we have many
informations like
uh um
mz signatures pe signatures and stuff
like that
and you have the sessions and this
specifically session is usually the
place that usually is the place that the
attacker using to inputting something
malicious like
in this um
text doc data
or something like this and this specific
session
doc or s or c usually is the
the session using for the icon or the
the binary
data piece to the users okay
nice and this is the elf as i mentioned
that it's almost almost it's not the
same but almost the same they have a
header session and stuff like that okay
so nice so let's talk about other
structure about the pd the pdf
okay so pdf has specifically four stroke
four uh parts actually the header the
body cross reference table or x table
and trailer right so basically is the v
in this way so this print but basically
is from the
dj students blog it's the person that
the researcher already know about our
analysis and other things like
this topic specifically and this is the
how the pdf organized those things right
so you can see the header and you see
the body when you see the
funny things like a color you know
page images and the cross reference
table you have a locations of the
objects ethan the file for access random
leica you have a specifically first
object like a root object okay and you
have others two child
and after that in object two or three
remember of this kind of three you have
another reference so object four and
five may connect it to the object two
others objects connect to
an object three
all those uh objects are reference
each one okay
nice i will explain more when you talk
about the virtual machine i think it's
easier to explain this and um
no
okay
let me return here my
pdf
files
okay here i have some pdfs and um
for example pdf id is a tool from dj
stevens did this even create these tools
basically so if you see here i have in
this case this pdf they have the header
small
but
okay
we have a header as i mentioned it
we have the body with many things like
pages and we have
objects in this case we have a 6 63
objects
and we have
22 streamings
usually these streams is apart important
inside of the pdf that the attacker
using to put in something malicious
thank you
they can use of course the url
you know in other parts but usually they
put in something obfuscated encoded
inside of this streaming okay so they
need to using something to uncompress
things and of course to check those
informations we need what uncompressed
right okay so let me share other
um
other pdf i have here for example no
photo file pdf
pdf id i have a thor
in this case nice pdf id
in this case it's almost different it's
is not to not too much object 18.
not
streaming
16 streaming
and they have here and specifically open
action
open action yeah open action so it means
one thing very interesting when you have
this flag and a pdf it means that the
user don't need to interact
more than once with this pdf the only
thing the user need to do is to open the
pdf and after that something happened
automatically this is the functions of
the open action
so that's interesting to see to
investigate more about that they haven't
specifically object streaming here
so another point to investigate
and
and as you can see and i show you about
the pdf we have a different things here
so
some pdf has more than
15 objects so it's a too big
and more than 20 streamings is too big
that we need to investigate as the same
case in this case it's not too big
it's not too much object it's just 18
but
maybe each one of this object has any
streaming so
becomes this more difficult to
investigate because we need to look in
for each streaming to see what kind of
thing we can find there okay
nice let me return it to the demo and i
will finish my presentation okay
and
so i have here one specifically fio in
pdf that i received
like a cv
something the people
receive if the people works in hr team
receive
every day the pdf okay
so first
i checked the version of course i
i
check other things if is if this r5 it's
really pdf or not the second tool that i
used here is a pdf id
right to check how many objects i have
here so i have here how many objects
15. in this case i have a look
just only two streams okay and but they
have here if you see
we have here
five maybe or two
js reference javascript and other
specifically javascript and in this case
is three and the same case they have an
open action here as you can see so
very interesting when i made this
investigation because
they have a specific object
and they have a specifically open action
and they have
maybe five javascript
so maybe those things are linked so i
need to investigate or i investigate
more to
to see about that other tool that i use
here in this case is pdf parser
is a is a part of the package of those
tools
and you can find the in the in cal linux
or parachute s and you can find there so
just to see some comments that i can
search inside of the the pdf
so first of all you
compare
this reference remember when i use pdf
id i found five javascript so this is
the first one the reference object one
object seven and object
12. so three javascript another is js
only two right if i'm correct only two
okay nice only two so okay i used two
different tools
to achieve the same action not the same
but the same result because just to
compare the results
but
now i need to looking more deeply about
those javascript because for me it's
totally suspicious right is suspicious
for you
our script with pdf
is very suspicious so it's malicious so
let's finish the presentation because
the idea is to yeah no okay
so the the next i using the
this this flag because they're these two
looking from the raw data
for filters to actually to open all
those informations inside of this
specifically pdf okay so if you see here
so let's
walk through for this specific pdx so we
have here the object one and take a look
at this three remember the structure of
the pdf
object one referring those six objects
remember those the three object one and
more than one the child files and take a
look this
one interesting information
so the open action is totally linked
with
a javascript so
i can suppose now
that
when the user opened the pdf what
happened
some javascript running right is that
correct
i'm supposing because
that's this is the information but here
it's interesting i heard something or
many things i heard actually from the
some guys
that ah this tool this doesn't works
why because
appears some efforts for us
actually is not er
i am not using in this moment the
correct tools to find this information
that of course some
sometimes we try to use in in problem
happen of course but in this case or in
many cases happen that you are not using
the correct tool
to find the information because of that
it's important to understand those bases
right
nice
so let's continue so we have this
reference and open action link it with
javascript cool so let's go to the next
object two nothing to to lead to c
object three take a look this object
four is another part of those this three
referring object eight and nine remember
how many objects we have here
fifteen
okay
in object 7 we have another reference
object 10 and not only that but one of
those reference is
remember of the link
about the javascript object 8 is more
you know
shiny things like a font image object
nine you're referring the four because
this object is connected with another
object
referring on others
in object 10 remember they have the
specific reference of javascript but
referring another 12 with javascript and
here take a look at this we find
this the first
streaming okay
and here
you see this is an i specifically flag
flat decode
it means
we need the code something
it's simple
but now we need to decode why what
exactly we need to decode this
streaming the content inside of this
stream but if you see here the left is
it's a kind of small
but maybe we can look in from this
specific object okay let's continue to
see all objects
objects whoever been fairing object 13
that we found in specifically javascript
but take a look this and this
specifically is the second one remember
we have two stream and here the left is
is too big when you compare with the
first right it's too big
so maybe this is
the focus that we to look in this is the
main object okay so let me go to
the next okay so
what i
thought here so
i have the
pdf
and they have an open action linked with
a specifically javascript and i have a
nice a cool information inside of this
specifically
object 13. so i need to go too deeply in
this object this specific object but i
need to using something
to
to show this information for me
because i using pdf parts it and i
didn't find anything with this so i use
in this case pdf techa is another tool
to manipulate pdf
it means that i can create pdf i can
merge pdf and
i can do other things i can encode i can
using
for different purpose not only that but
i can uncompress
recompress
so my idea is
it was uncompressed
this specific information in object 13.
okay so
basically i said here pdf pdf deca the
file output because i would like to
collect this output
not only this but the whole pdf
and i set the dump doc text to copy
those information from this file and
execute and compress to uncompress the
fire so now we have here the pdf
and the whole
uncompressed file okay nice so now i can
look in more deeply and take a look what
i found in this streaming
i found here the very interesting
information the javascript
it here it's here
but
if you know how this
javascript javascript works you know
that's not
looks like a javascript because yeah
because
this javascript
is obfuscated
because of that is this way so
the next step i need to copy this
and pass in creating another file
because i thought so i'm talking about
javascript javascript maybe i talk about
the web application so if i have
application i can try to interpret this
in a specific html file that's my idea
because i found a specific evo parameter
here and i can change in this file
my idea is to try to rewrite
this specifically javascript to
solfuscate
this file okay
and if you see specifically the other
thing interesting is a kind of standard
here letters percent numbers you see in
inside of the parenthesis you know
and the color is different so something
is interesting here but the first idea
here is to rewrite remember i
i set this specifically script here and
i put in document right to rewrite these
informations
because i'm using this specific
parameter to
describe this javascript so i save this
file and next step is to give the
permission to access this file
or to show this information for in the
browse for us okay
nice
cool so the next step is to as i could
this to see what is this
kind of behavior or what kind of
information you can find in this
specific javascript obfuscated so after
that open the firefox browser
and take a look what happened now
we have a payload
nice
you know what is a payload
we have an exploit and you have a
payload you know what you know what's
the difference basically
yeah
you know
okay let me clarify for something
because i don't see many hands okay so
exploit is a
maybe it's a a tool or a binary that you
can use it to explore and specifically
vulnerabilities
okay and a payload is a package
is a code
that you can download in specifically
victor machine
to gain specifically access or to
receive and specifically reverse or
reverse connection actually okay
basically those different so you're
using the exploit as a tool to explore
the vulnerability and if you would like
to
because of course depend on the
vulnerability that you are exploring but
if you like sometimes you can download
these exploits it's a pi a part of
package that you download in the victory
machine to receive
this connection reverse a kind of
reverse shell maybe okay so in this case
we had
the specifically code to explore a
specific vulnerability in this case
because after i don't have a time to
explain those details or using dynamic
analysis just a simple
statistic analysis but
the attacker using specifically exploit
to explore specific vulnerability inside
of the environment of the customer
or the client and after that you
download this
payload inside of the victor machine
as you can see here
it's a payload responsible for
starting the connection reverse with the
cnc so uh now i could finish my i could
because remember the idea when i
investigate that is to identify if this
pdf is malicious or not or not it's
malicious
point you know
um
but now we have a payload
so let's go
more let's see what happened now
cool and if you see here some remember
the behavior like a number of ladders
percent or something
are happening here i don't know
exactly so let's go to continue to do
so i copped this code
and i my idea here is it was
to
[Music]
clean actually to clean the file
uh
i copy this this file here and i using
sad
basically to cut the percent because of
course after some times to try other
things like this i found the information
that this payload basically the attacker
using another technique
the encoding technique okay the using
specifically technique here to encode
this payload
because remember for the attacker
perspective they need to using many
techniques like debugger like you know
encoding like
obfuscation many other techniques
to make more difficult our life
as a researcher as an analyst or
whatever okay so basically this is as
you can see here now we have here
the
the the
the informations that the the real
payload not in real but the payload
encoded and basically the attacker using
here the the different techniques
because they don't use in here the ascii
they use an unicode is a different
because it's based on two into binaries
not only in two bytes not one bytes has
x ascii
works so they're using specifically uh
unicode so remember they use it the
first they use a javascript
obfuscated
inside of this javascript they're using
the
the payload and inside of this payload
they haven't specifically code
using this technique in based on unicode
so i'll explain more any other thing
because maybe you are thinking flip just
using
unix i would like to see if it's
possible to using windows okay
so are you continue to doing the same
analysis but in windows platform
remember we have here i stopped here the
investigation when i found the the
encode right the code
encoded
it's a kind of
okay so i'm executing here the same i
mean copy this
the payload remember that the payload
here and i cop and paste here using
another platform mozilla
i don't know if you've already heard
about that this about these tools so i
pass here and if you see here this is
the
technique used by the attacker to inc
oh my goodness let me go to the end
again
this is that
i'm putting stop here okay this encoding
that the attacker using
is based on this specifically technique
ucs2
is a kind of old
because the evolution now it's called
etf16 if you have 32 that using this
and the idea here is to it's the same
that i use in the set
i cut the percent
and i created to to generate
this information in the axa file right
as you can see here i click
and now i have the exa file basically
this is the xfi when i cut the percent
using sad i had
the extra file but i used but using here
the mozilla i have the extra file i
generate and specifically binary
okay because my idea now is to to try
to find
the cnc
from the attacker
and after that
i try i use ensure
to find in specifically
information inside of this binary that i
generate for http and now
we have
the commanding controller from the
attacker remember the payload
so the attacker using those steps to
to go
for this
this
server right the
the command controller the idea from the
attacker for the attacker is when the
the attacker on the vitamin receive the
file and download the payload that this
ip address will receive a connection
right
and i finish here just to
show the
information here about the specific ip
address as you can see so they have all
these informations other url related to
the specific attack but
you see that this uh
this ip address is totally linked one
specifically attack as you can see here
so we go step by step into these
investigations and now i finish the
presentation this is some books if you'd
like to read understand more about the
the more analysis we have here
about the you know
specifically difference here but it's
more this
so since the beginning to the advanced
set here is more focusing in 3d hunting
even in trendy hunting looking from the
the tools
and yes thank you so much for this
time
once again it's a pleasure
[Applause]
thank you
okay
we'll have a short q a
session
so uh
questions
[Music]
i have
maybe it's good oh baby it's bad i don't
know
hello
go ahead go ahead
okay
hello
yes thank you for the presentation it
was
really really interesting i have
question here about the payload actually
that is
stored inside the pdf file
let's say that we have a victim for
example a target that will open the pdf
file
how the payload will be executed it is
no click
like the victim will be compromised uh
without uh just like by uh opening the
file or he need like to activate
something or no the the action is is for
if you understand your question because
i can hear you not so good but
it's the flow of the infection the user
perspective right
so when user received this this file
let's suppose that you work in an atr
team and you receive the cv the resume
and the only action the user need to do
is to open the pdf
to read to see one file one file after
that automatically you're running all
those steps
automatically because they have the
specifically open action functions
linked with javascript remember the
javascript this javascript is obfuscated
inside of the javascript you have the
payload this is this payload is
responsible for callback to then cnc
you see so the user don't need to click
it more than once just need to open once
again and that's it so may if of course
if user
should have the specific security sensor
like antivirus or other thing like this
in the the you know the laptop to
protect but
because it's a no mower actually the
vulnerabilities it's a non-vulnerability
and that's time when i investigate that
but it's the flow the only one click and
just and that's it
okay thank you
anyone more
here below
here over there
um
okay
is this exploit related uh to
um
to adobe
and
oh
um
did they say that
uh
can i tell it in french and someone
trust me yeah yeah yeah yeah thank you
yes
acrobatics
um
is that
vulnerability linked
either on pdf format
in itself or in acrobat reader
um i don't remember exactly if this
vulnerability was in a in a in a correct
reader
but
you know
when you create
if you are would you like to try for
example your security sensor let's
suppose that you are testing okay so you
can create in this pdf you can put in
specifically exploit inside of this pdf
using for example pdf deca to compress
something or use it in code
and you can explore the victim so
the the point is the exploit that you
can put in the pdf you can use
each one
desire you know and uh i don't remember
this exactly it was specifically
vulnerability from acrobat i don't i
really i don't remember
but you know you can using whatever
exploit you want of course remember when
you're using something to test like if
you see my in my my repository in on on
github i test in some security vendors
and
i like to using
when i test something i like to using
i i like to go to for specific steps so
the first i like to using no
threads like a normal hours no exploits
no
to test how the engines the engines
works like uh signatures
machine learning or other things based
on signatures after that i go to the
not a nazir day but you know it's a
other techniques but you can put in
whatever exploit you want inside of this
pdf
you you just need to on the or to know
what kind of tools you can use to put
this information inside of that
hi hello hi thanks for the talk is there
a way to mitigate or to disable the open
action
actually good question
for the open action
[Music]
actually i i don't know
yeah because it's for me open action i
don't know if that makes sense some pdf
open the other task like an open action
because it's another activity from pdf
maybe
for the security perspective
probably in security uh sensors like
antivirus as i mentioned or a binary
that you have inside of the machine
should have some specifically behavior
like or related and specific like
if you have a pdf binary
no a pdf it's a binary of course but you
have a pdf
so pdf
having a specific reaction just open
shared information because if you put in
the string in pdf you see like a text
because pdf is a really text file
but with image and phones
and shiny things but it's a it's a text
so why they need to using other
activities like
because you don't use macros in pdf
i think
using you know in word in excel in other
in microsoft office files but in pdf
usually not
so based on this behavior you can use it
specifically tagging in antivirus you
can put this for example
but for the specific pdf or in the
specific machine i don't know exactly
but i
if i
had if i you know if i have the
specifically security vendors i you go
for this way you know to looking from
the specific behavior from the pdf
or if some
block to javascript is not is
complicated because depends of the
application that you have inside of the
organization you see
and
it's based on behavior basically is how
the
the antivirus works
the new technology is based on behavior
and machine learning and many vendors it
doesn't work with the signatures only
from behavior
so the user need to click in the mower
and after that they you protect
i don't like this i like to use them
both you know so i don't need to check
if it's malicious when i
know that it's malicious for me that
makes sense
and i talk with some
i talked with some vendors about that
and i have some fights but anyway it's
another talk
okay
[Music]
anything more
there
i go i go there to hurry more too hello
so yeah it's working uh thank you first
of all for the presentation uh then i
think i have a question
about the very last command and it was
the one to get
the information about the attacker like
the search exure
that exo one i think
the question is about this script
whether it's a github
script
whether it's something that you've
downloaded we need to download it from
somewhere or something a tool that we
can just like get on linux
so yeah
uh i don't know if you understand the
question but it is based on the the file
or based on the
your question is about specifically
some tools to check
yeah i saw that you used a tool maybe a
file which was exercise i guess
and this is something that i'm like uh i
didn't see before and there wasn't like
uh the reference whether it's a github
file whether it's a tool oh okay so yeah
my question is about the file
itself okay yeah you can actually the
file is one is specifically command
right and you can use in
other commands that you can use
to check those informations
because
for each um
it's not investigation system operation
but you have for example the kala linux
if you read for example the kali linux
they have specifically suggestion to you
you
you should be using for example cal
linux has a desktop
only for and specifically purpose in the
same case apparel choice we have a
specific version inside of those tools
in this specific system operation we
have many tools to check so you can use
it for example file you can use in other
tools to check i don't remember other
uh
check types of file now
but one thing interesting about that i
don't know if i can i answer your
question but it's about
a specific vulnerability and
specifically tools because i remember in
if i don't uh if you know wrong
and specifically vulnerability in string
command
when you has a cute and string command
something happened you can using the
string command to explore the the
environment but i don't remember i don't
try and that time but
you can use in different tools you can
use in you know um
again you can use in
some comments like i don't use in here
but you can use in for example read read
pe it's a kind of tools to check the
structure and the informations about the
pd the portable executable the pe or you
can use read elf is the same for the
yield the linux and you can check the
structure of the binaries and how is the
sessions and all those reference
okay so this is
this wasn't something that you
structured like for your need or
something that's available online on
open sources like uh sources yeah yeah
just to need to download the the linux
the unix
you need to download the kali linux or
parachois and usually you have these
tools on those machines or even you you
can download the the ubuntu you can find
there you want to debian because it's a
it's like a file it's i think it's open
basically it's a kind of you don't you
you can using you know apt install and
that's it
okay thank you it's it's just that it's
a tool that is the very first time that
i see the exhort thing and i thought it
was a library that yeah those two that i
use this totally open source is is
embedded in the in the unix platform in
this case for example for the pdf
perspective are using
some many uh comments and tools from dj
stevens and inside of the blog of the
day steven they haven't specifically
packaged to using those tools in windows
so you can download the zip file and
compress this and after that you can
using so many tools he developed many
many many tools it's very nice of course
in linux it's more easier you know to
put in those open source tools
thank you and thank you for the talk it
was quite interesting thank you
thank you all
merciatus