hello
hello everyone how are you doing um i'm
already apologizing for running late uh
because uh some stuff came up and so i
will be running late uh
you got my slides right there it's like
okay there we go so we start with oh
whenever i do a talk where it's like
offensive and like i'm robbing people
and i'm doing bad things i always tell
people it's like i mean i'm not a lawyer
but i played one on the internet so it's
like just remember the kittens
when when i tell you about something bad
you're thinking what a horrible person
well i can't believe he would do that
just remember them because i'm adorable
i would not try to rob you steal you
steal from you or kill you unless you
pay me first so it's it's all good it's
like i i don't lie for a lit i live for
a living i don't do it for free so we're
good
uh so let's get right into everything
and i promise
after the first little hiccup and speed
bump it's gonna be all great we're gonna
have fun we're gonna laugh we're gonna
learn hopefully uh it's gonna be great
uh this is the title of the talk and it
gave me some uh feedback i got some
flack for it but i wanna explain it uh
when putin invaded uh ukraine
and you started seeing uh the blue
tractors
removing tanks and it's like it made me
think about
wow
you never thought a tractor would be so
good at an anti-tank weapon right
it's like i never understood that i
thought that was very cool that was neat
and so i decided to use that as my basis
of my talk because you see one thing and
you're thinking oh this is what this is
it's a farming equipment it's no big
deal and now all of a sudden you're like
oh now you got like the freaking army
going like oh i don't like this you know
it's like watch out there's a tank
coming right it's like and so
um but then also something happened i
got feedback and i got blowback
from a lot of my friends in russia i'm i
love
uh russia is a beautiful country it's
like i i've been to moscow i've been to
st petersburg twice
and there's an amazing community of
hackers there
uh that are all about community
and they were perceiving what i was
doing was against russia against them
that's once again a perception and worse
they thought i was speaking on behalf of
defcon groups or i was feeling that i
was being political and i was like no it
is not about politics
it's about being a
decent basic human being
it's like that's what it's about so i
wanted to drive that home a little bit
uh by showing some other examples that
uh i can get black for
uh one it's like when uh george w bush
and in the usa uh did a horrendous
invasion of iraq with no actual pretext
with no actual reason with actual no
justification i was one i was right out
there talking about how bad that was
it's like oil should not be costing
people's lives on either side
it's like so i was very upset about that
but then we get to this
and i did this before yesterday
but this is uh another symbol and then
that
example right there is the guy throwing
the shoe
a shoe
which is not big in western culture
but to throw a shoe in arabic culture to
throw to show the bottom of your foot
is one of the highest insults
and so that resonated with the people
there even though we didn't perceive why
the insult was so bad
the people that it was intended for
did
it was the perception of what occurred
even though we didn't figure it out we
didn't understand it fully uh it's like
i understood exactly what i saw what
happen but it's like but most people
didn't
but that's what that was that was the
significant of throwing a shoe that was
worse than throwing a rock
or a tomato
and then also you get to hear and you
see the bra
and it's like and we think that that's
what the the feminist movement was in
the 70s uh because in the 70s uh for
some reason uh women were upset that
they were treated like you know
you know less than people
and they thought that was bad
so they started protesting
they started
going out there and showing that they
mattered that their lives mattered that
that being a woman should not be a death
sentence
they should they should be equal just
like anybody else
and so a woman
through her this is the freedom trash
can it was never put on fire
that is a myth they didn't burn their
bras
they were throwing in mops and mop
handles they were throwing in lipstick
cases they were throwing in the things
that were saying that society told them
this is what a little girl good girl
does
this is what a little good girl has
and then a woman removed her bra and
that started a chain reaction
because you know boobies it's like oh
we're paying attention now what's going
on
it's like that's what happened
and now
so many years later
i find out yesterday thank goodness i
didn't find out before my talk trust me
it would have been a totally different
talk
i find out that the supreme court has
decided to turn women into breeding
equipment
and i'm thinking
we have i have to speak up
i have to say something about that
and not because i'm a father
not because i'm a husband that's trash
don't ever say oh well what my daughter
that happened to my daughter or that it
happened to a human being
period
that's all you need to know
that was another human that is happening
too
and that's what you should pay attention
to i promise i do get funny in a little
bit but i am telling you
if i don't have if i have a voice
and i don't use it to talk to the people
who don't have a voice
then i'm wasting my time here
because what's the use of having all
this male privilege
if i can't talk about that i shouldn't
have that privilege
it should be equal
we are all the same in this chamber
we're all hackers we're all belong here
we need more people to understand that
[Applause]
i am embarrassed
for my country right now
but i'm talking about this is after the
trump years i'm embarrassed for my
country right now
because you have all these religious
people talking about how they're
pro-life
well guess what
why is it when the baby is born
the fetus is out of the womb you don't
give up about it
you're not giving it health care you're
not giving at school lunches you're not
giving it a proper education you're not
taking care of the child when it's
actually alive but instead they go to
school and they get killed
why aren't we doing something about if
you're pro-life
show it
it's like as the bible says it's like i
i don't want any to know you by your
deeds or your actions i know you by your
actions not your words
i'm a christian but i'm not a very good
one because it's like i don't believe in
you know i'm just really tired
of people talking about all these faux
eras and using the bible to hide behind
it
i am telling you people are sick of you
trying to get christ in your christmas
if you can't if they can't see the
christ in the christian
and we need to remember that
okay i'm done now
okay
um
this is this is inconsequential i don't
care uh i i speak i i ride my motorcycle
uh i play no man's sky i rob banks and i
love to travel the world uh that's all
you need to know about me
so
i am so tired
of information security
talking about stupid user clicked on a
link
stupid user went to a website stupid
information security didn't properly
train their users
you think humans are the weakest link
mother you put a snort ids into a a
company
put the default rule on
and how useless is that
you're not fine-tuning the ids you're
not trying to get it to work you're not
doing anything with it so you got the
box there is it actually creating a
secure environment
no
humans your users are the biggest
intrusion or detection system you're
ever going to find
because they do the same job day in and
day out they will know when something is
unusual but do they know who to tell
do they feel comfortable approaching the
security people that could help them
probably not
it's like so that's one of our problems
they're not the weakest linked or the
least invested in
how many thousands and thousands of
dollars are you spending on blinky boxes
but you're not actually paying
a little bit of money to get your users
aware
you don't give the keys to a car to a
delivery driver on their first day the
job said oh yeah we know you could drive
take it
you tell them what is expected of them
with that equipment
why do you give a user a laptop and just
say oh yeah you're fine with it there
you go without telling them their
responsibilities
that's irresponsible of security not the
user
and this whole mythology
of apt
are you kidding me
you know apt advanced
persistent
threatening right
threat it's like that's scary right
that's oh my gosh stay apt apt is what
the ceos tell their shareholders in the
public when they get popped by an email
apt stands for adequate phishing
technique that is apt
i don't do apts i'm not good at apts i
do bad
basic adorable destruction
i come in there and i literally walk off
the street
and i start robbing you
not knowing where anything's at not
knowing anybody's name in the building
not doing any google searches i promise
a company that i will do less than two
hours of google
uh when i'm doing recon and ocean on
their company
one hour 45 minutes
kingston jamaica was the longest time it
took me to do research to find that
information and i had helped though i
did have help but it was still they were
a very good target it's like but it's
still less than two hours i was still
able to find enough information that led
to a successful compromise
it's like so i don't need all this
advanced stuff i don't go to lightning
i'm literally walking in
and talking about some of the olsen i do
let's start with google um i i was i
tried to get hired by ernst young like
20 years ago and they didn't want me
because i didn't have a high school uh i
was a high school dropout with a ged and
no college so uh i'm still petty and i
hold a grudge so we're going to target
them
sorry ernst and young employees nothing
personal um so i'm going to target them
it's like and so i'm going to go to eny
and i want to rob their building
i want to go inside and take over and
drop something inside their building not
any building
i want to go to the ny headquarters oh
first of all just going to google it
shows me
all their profile social media profiles
it shows me a lot of their information
i've gone over that that's fine but
check this out
i'm not after the company
i want the building
and this is one of the biggest problems
and misconceptions we have we think that
the company just because it's got its
fancy name on it
that is the one that that's like
that's running the the building
seriously do you think tony stark was
collecting the rent from the starbucks
at the stark tower and the avengers no
it's like there's a management company
that handles the security the
maintenance and more importantly the
retail space and the office space that
they're also selling
and what does an office space company
what are they interested in
they're interested in getting people to
rent from their their building
they need to occupy it
so how do they do that
well they give you information
because you want to see how attractive
it is to have your building your office
in this building
like they'll tell you
right off the bat without having to
google without having to try it they'll
tell you where the main restaurants are
in the area so you can do badge cloning
by employees that are going to lunch
because they're not going to go out of
the way to go to lunch they're good
employees they're going to go right by
the building
they're going to take their lunch nearby
and so now you know exactly which
restaurants they frequent you know what
hotels to put in wi-fi uh malicious
access points it's like because that's
usually their guest and their
consultants from out of town will be
staying
it's like and you see their office
neighbors uh which also gives you more
information of like say we're working on
this other uh building with this company
and we're we had a tie-in going into the
electrical closet somewhere i mean just
ridiculous it's just information
more information that you need
but they really
really want to sell you some office
space
do you know how fun it is when you find
bank blueprints online
have you ever seen bank book no they
protect that you don't want your
blueprints
of a bank
online you don't want anybody to find
them i know because i almost got you
know i had a very bad running with
police in a dumpster in houston at a
bank when i found their blueprints so i
can i can assure you it's not a laughing
matter it's a serious money to get some
of those but here
they give them for free
there we go
there's my blueprint this is the
entrance way do you know why the lobby
area is so important
not because of that blue stuff screw the
blue crap right because that's public
area security guards are out there and
they're mean and they're scary and
they're big and like there's cam that
you don't want to go that way
what you always look for in blueprints
like this
you look for the gray area
you look for this nothing to see here
folks
nothing to see here just look at look at
this highlighted blue area right here
this is where all the good stuff is look
at all the yellow stuff right here
that's where the good no i'm over here
looking where the freight elevator is
i'm looking to see where the corridors
are where they come out of what side of
the street that they come out of
and what to watch
i've not been to this location
theoretically yet
this is all based online
not only do they give you the public
area they give you the office layout
do you know why the law office layout is
so important
it's perception
you do not want to be walking in a
building that you're not familiar with
acting like you don't know where you are
i walk everywhere with purpose
i may not have no clue where i'm going
but mother i'm getting there and i know
it
and that's what counts
but now i get stopped at one of these
offices
and on one of these floors and someone
says excuse me
what are you doing here oh i'm going to
the electrical closet uh down there to
the right
they're like oh okay
because that's believable because
there's an electrical closet down to the
right
because it makes it the perception is
they must belong there they know which
way the mail room door is because you
can tell because look at what are we
looking at now what are we looking at
the dark area where it's like nothing to
see here
that's what we're looking at
this is what we need
but don't worry they were nice enough to
un-gray it out for me at some point in
one of the part of the pdf so now i know
exactly where the elevators lobby are i
know whether probably mail room is being
put i know all this information
just by going to the website of the
building management
that is like
less than 20 minutes
and i'm also going through social media
of course
i love this one it's like
i just went to instagram and i didn't go
after ian y
i just went after the building
so do you know how many employees that
you have that tag your location and
their instagram
post
too many
too
many
so it's like there you go i got not only
do i have information and have pictures
from inside the building and some some
of them i have board rooms and things
like that we'll show that in a little
bit but i also
have names of people to attack that i
know are socially active
that's awesome
and the best part is
i did it while having pizza and a diet
pepsi on that
the same thing i'm presenting on
it's got 16 gigs of ram an i7 processor
2 terabytes of hard drive space and
it'll take over a network pretty effing
quickly but it looks like a game boy it
looks like it's perceived to be just a
game
device
do you know how many people let me into
a server room that you're not allowed to
bring a computer into because i got a
three-hour update and i just want to use
uh my kids switch while i'm in there
too many
so and also imagine this wasn't up an
arab but this was actually like the
lobby of the building
because i love going to the starbucks or
the cafe inside the lobby of the
building because then i can like you
know sip my hot chocolate i don't want
coffee and it's like you know and have
my malicious access point up and watch
everybody watching the traffic patterns
when security changes what kind of dress
people are dressed like what are they
expecting who's more alert and security
than not so i can go back the next day
and rob them on that day during that
time period
i love that
and it's like so especially if they give
you free refills that's amazing um and
so there's just another little thing
showing that i'm actually doing it there
now let's go into more
because this is also another thing about
uh
how you can get all the other companies
involved it just shows you more
information of what's going on what the
area is and where it's located
and then
now we get to the reason why
security drinks
um
if you don't know why information
security people drink
just
search instagram search it for new badge
okay
search it for new job
it can be depressing i i warn you i've
literally used that
as a way to create a badge
within 15 minutes of being on instagram
to break into a company i was
attacking and you know how i did it
i did it with the badging 1000
no no it's a 100 badge 100 i'm sorry the
only way this would be cooler if it was
like the badgie 3000 but it's only the
badge 100.
less than a thousand dollars though
and
instantly print your id cards
but jason
they don't have the rfid tag
they don't have an nfc capability mother
i hope not
i've literally used a blank card and
gone
this is this is not working cause
someone let me in i don't know why this
isn't working
and they let me in
so thank you badger100
uh it's the gift that keeps on giving uh
to the bad guys not you uh the the
client um and then also some more
pictures from instagram
why do you need to do a network
footprint
uh when you do like that in that nmap
scans are noisy trying to figure out
discovery of devices i know they're
using window devices
i know they have iphones i know they are
using ibm lenovo's
so i know exactly what kind of equipment
i can need to start working on
now i want to prefix this
you know i asked this question do you
think where you work is more secure from
infra infiltration and compromise than a
bank which is understands and is aware
that people will try to rob it
that's my question to you
now the
other thing what i'm about to show you
could be anybody
anywhere
i hate showing examples and
demonstrations of me actually attacking
people
because then i have i don't want people
in the audience to go oh my gosh those
guys were idiots oh my gosh i couldn't
faul i can't believe they fell for that
that's bad information security
you learn from it
you don't mock or punch down to someone
else
it was a learning experience for them
and so i'm going to show you
how i gotta figure out which way the
mouse works
hello
come on
and oh
oh there we go okay here's a mouse
there's a mouse i got a mouse so i'm
going to show you live
a clip
of me
robbing a bank
this clip is less than
uh
eight minutes
a hundred percent compromise
and let's see how long it takes me
before i get in the front door before i
uh get the first machine
i love the look on her face she knows i
don't everything belong there
did you see the suspicion that's what
you should have for your employees
okay it's now 12 seconds 13 seconds 15
seconds before my first compromise from
walking in the first door
how was that advanced or persistent
within 20 seconds the payload loads
and less than 30 seconds i finished
but look what happens next she comes
over
and she stops me
and i act what do you do i act like
nothing's wrong i'm doing a usb audit of
course
i don't try to get questioned i'm
authority i'm an auditor she's like what
can i help you with i'm here to do the
usb audit and she's like i don't
didn't headquarters call you
uh i thought
your head off was supposed to contact
you that's not my fault
uh can you and she's like can you talk
to the uh head manager and i'm like sure
no problem that would be great
so she did everything right
except for this part
pardoned she says like and then i
dismiss her i say i'll stand by i assure
that i'm going to go talk to him
now
he thinks that she vetted me
that she thought i was legit and brother
and now
he's just going along with it
i call that a conversation in the middle
attack
because it's like i make one person say
one thing's going on and the other
person perceives something else happen
when they're right there talking to each
other
so now i'm compromised his machine
and now i ask him to escort me to the
rest of the bank
oh and i realized i want to attack the
data center first let's let's get the
data center right off the bat okay
because you know the teller line's fun
and everything but it's even better when
you get the data center that's my
trusted agent he's someone that's to
vouch for me if i get caught uh and be
there to help me out he's a little too
happy because he can't believe what's
going on either
so i have to tell him he's like get the
back dude he's like you're not supposed
to know me it's like and so now he uh he
walks up
slowly
i i didn't edit this at all this is
literally the whole thing that would
happen uh so
and we get to the data center and he
puts in a very secure key code i'm a
walking talking google street streetcar
when i'm in an engagement i've got a uh
watches i've got pens i've got all these
video recorders it's like so i could
have easily gotten what that date that
thing was but he was nice enough to open
the door for me uh and now here's the
part i'll be down there in a second uh
to go to the teller line so i'm like
he left me alone in the data center
and the problem is you can't hear
the sadness in my voice
as i sigh
like
why am i in here underscore this is not
good this was a bad thing uh so but then
i realized he's really too good to let
go
it's like hold on i'm coming
let's go to the teller line now
so he helps me he helps get me to the
teller line
and yes i apologize to the camera people
that have to like you know keep track of
me as i'm walking around the stage
oh they're good
okay
so i start compromising the teller line
the manager is right behind me how am i
not supposed to be there
now this one part was i'm not being
petty i'm i promise you okay
but
this rude
employee
locked his workstation when he went on a
break
who does that
it's like there's a lot i mean so i had
to go get the manager to go get the
employee to unlock the workstation for
me because i want to get 100
[Applause]
yes i i respect the french language too
much to speak it it's like but it was
very horrible it's like
and so there you go like this there's
good i got all those and now i want to
go to the vault
people don't realize once again
perception the vault's not that big
shiny metal thing you see in movies
we're about to go visit the vault
the vault
is where the wire transfers happen
it's where the money is moved
oh it's getting real up in here now
the managers right beside me
while they're in the middle of doing
wire transfers
my code executes
it's just notepad i'm not trying to be a
bad person it's like i'm not a criminal
i'm a hacker it's like i'm trying to
just uh do a notepad to show them that
the exploit could work
so i got in got out
now
i have to confess
i mentioned that i was petty
so
i had to make sure
that i got the girl that stopped me at
the very beginning and compromised her
machine too just out of principle
ah
so with the manager now beside me making
everything okay
i get her up out of her chair
and i compromise that machine as well
so i've compromised a hundred percent of
the machines
i'm just rambling i'm just talking i'm
smiling i'm being funny
being polite oh i unplugged that let me
plug it back in for you so you know i
didn't want to do that and i did
appreciate their help
and then this was my honest reaction
how did that just happen i was more
surprised anybody else
can you please explain to me
where
oh let's go to the next one oops there
we go so where
can you tell me
that i was advanced
where can you tell me i was being
persistent
we need to stop looking like these
attacks are well orchestrated or going
to be like they have you have to have
all these techniques and you all have
all these things if this is so easy i
can do it
that should scare you
i've got really bad adhd on the spectrum
it's like trust me i can barely organize
what my email folder looks like and i'm
robin banks
that's a problem with the people
not a compliment on how good my skills
are
we need to get better at protecting our
people
and here's where we go here's where i
talk about perception
because watch this video
i walk in
i'm coming from the public area but i
immediately turned left
to where the lady is sitting down but
she's on the phone but i don't go to her
i just stay hidden behind the column
i stay there for a few seconds
and then i walk around
like i had been talking to that lady and
now i'm coming from a trusted side
i'm coming from the private side
and so i walk in
if i would have come in
straight into the to the lot from the
lobby to behind the teller line
i would have had a bad day
they would have been like what's going
on that machine's not even plugged in
but i had to start the process
because then i could go to the next one
going i'm doing usb audit
i love usb audits i don't know what they
are but i love them
everybody passes my usb audits though by
the way so win-win for everyone
now this she wouldn't have me so i'm
just spinning around in the chair
because i'm just a go lucky you know guy
i'm not doing anything bad criminals
don't you know spin around in the chair
when they're waiting to rob someone
except for me
and i pop it up
and there we go so the key thing here
is all about
perception
they perceived me
as an internal person
because of the direction that i came and
after enough a time
it's like they perceived me as
okay
how many i and trust me it's not just
this location it's not just this country
or this industry or this people
it is literally
it's like every place i've been
i have robbed banks in jamaica i've
robbed banks of the u.s
in the u.s oh my gosh i had a great one
i robbed a bank there
by literally signing in
as a vendor
at the front desk
i used a fake name
that i did not have a license where i
had no
id i've got some fake ids didn't use any
of them
i
signed in with a fake company name
that if anybody would have checked
they'd be like i came in as an
electrical company
and then um because i had a pump plug
and i was doing storage protections and
making sure that all that because we're
having brownouts at headquarters so we
need to to have those monitoring
equipment and the voltage
and so
i got that and then i used a fake phone
number
that i don't even if it worked
they let me in
i got the manager to get out of their
desk off their uh behind their desk so i
could plug the device into their uh
underneath their desk
did i have to do it there
no but i thought it was funny at the
time it's like and so that's why i did
that one
but that was like they didn't they
didn't even check the names
it's like so and i mean and i look i
mean i was wearing it's like i'm in i'm
on the west coast of america right now
i'm wearing
a work shirt a blue work shirt that
literally says defcon on it
and i come with warning labels okay
always
so you got to understand
that you can't make excuses saying
oh but that was them
no that's going to be you
or it has been you
and you just don't know it
so we need to get better at treating our
people as allies and part of our team
than liabilities
so after this after seeing this you sure
hope so but you're probably not
because once again like i said we're
dealing with perception
what people see
or what they want to see because
sometimes humans don't like
seeing things
we don't like reality so we want to find
a perception or something that matches
our own
that is too topical right now it's like
so we go there and we find that
information and we get those sources
like the blue and black dress remember
that that whole thing hysteria that hit
the internet
if you don't
you're so lucky congratulations
um
so let's talk a little bit more about
make it more about us right more about
hacking more about breaking into places
this guy
this is me
uh robbing uh one location
it's like
going in as a what i call my a
assertive role and also going in as my
passive role
how long do you think
uh the time had passed between these two
pictures
the next day
i go in
as the passive role
with my little you know prox mark
scanner and and my usb recording glasses
and a couple other little gadgets and
goodies as your company's computer guy
and then after i do the recon after i do
everything or or compromise as much as i
can the next day
i clean up a little bit as much as i can
anyway and i show up as
the auditor
now the tricky thing about this
is people are going to sort of remember
me from the day before
but oh
he looks vaguely familiar
because they're not connecting because
i've changed my appearance
and the other can you tell what the
biggest
thing
in perception that gets me into a
location like this
look behind me
it's
winter it's nose on the ground
even when i'm in a short sleeve shirt do
you see me wearing a jacket
i had to walk three blocks in the snow
freezing my butt off
but why
why did i do that
basic perception
you can't act like you're trusted
like you're an inside employee
if you've got an outside jacket on
so you show up
without a jacket
and oh he must have put his jacket in
the conference room or he must belong
here or what kind of idiot would you
know go to work without a jacket on
right it's like that's how that works
it's just basic perception this is not
social engineering
this is basic human nature
i am not a great social engineer i'm
really good at masking and understanding
human behavior
that is what gets me it's like who knew
survival instincts from childhood would
pay off so well
these are some of the other roles that i
use i love i love my homeless person uh
role that's dear to me because i used to
live behind a dumpster uh it's like i
never begged for money though it's like
i just scavenged but still and then i
got the work guy and i got my other role
the assertive role
uh the one thing in common i'm all
trying i'm trying to rob you with all of
them
so so that is fun
it's like i love the cardboard because
who pays attention to homeless people
who actually looks one of them in the
face
it's like it's the perfect way to rob
people
it's like trust me i oh no i won't say
that it's like i'm gonna say i know but
it's like i don't know no but i've heard
i've never robbed people uh unless they
paid me first
um that did not sound convincing but i
actually was i was actually being honest
so
assertive roles do not mean aggressive
what mana original and pretext are
involved hardwood use can be limited but
the more discreet the better your
chances are of success
if you notice i came in a suit in the
bank and so i had just a usb drive
it's like usually i'll come in with just
a regular usb drive
bash bunny batch money 2 now
omg cable something like that to to just
come in uh when i'm doing the assertive
role i don't want it to be too flashy i
don't want to be too technical i don't
want to provoke that much notice
it's like and the other thing is
i'm going to be assertive i'm not going
to be rude
there's only one time and we'll just say
it was in a european country uh where
people were a lot more used to like you
know directness and uh and i'm not even
talking about france no
i didn't think that was funny at all
okay but so i go in there and i'm found
in going into the server room and i get
i get stopped
very assertively
well what happens when you're approached
assertively
by someone when you're not where you're
supposed to be
you respond
more assertively
yes i'm here doing the surprise
inspection they freaking pulled me out
of new york's office to come over here
to see what was going on and i have to
do some private section it's like
yeah i need it let me into the server
room that's what i've been waiting here
for trying to get in
uh well you know
what part of the prize inspector did you
not
do you think i want to be here right now
now let me in and i won't put your name
on the report
i lied i put the name on the report no
i'm joking i didn't i never put the
names of people who fail only the people
who succeed because that's how you teach
people to be better
this is what i usually look like
um i love that's my business suit of
doom
on the left i had it i had a tailor in
beijing
peter amazing guy did my shirts and did
my suit he thought i was a magician
when i asked him how i when i told him
how i wanted to build the suit i want
the suit made i was like no peter
i'm not a magician
it's like magicians always say
there's nothing up my sleeves
and i specifically told you to put
something up my sleeves
so yes those are my two bash bunnies and
my my little pocket sleeves
are they
are they really useful there
no
but is it cool
yes
and sometimes that's all it counts
[Applause]
now
can we see the three hacking devices in
this picture
i mean the first one is easy the usb
pin
video recorder
but then we've got the high def video
camera and the watch with the 16 gig
hard drive with an easy to attach cable
so i could download 16 gigs of your data
and walk out on my watch no one's i mean
who's going to notice that right
but it's not a rolex but and then my
favorite
my favorite because i told peter i said
peter
i want to have french cuffs
on all my shirts
and he's like oh you like cufflinks i
was like well i like to be fancy okay
that's why they call them french cuffs
they're fancy it's like
no i want them for this
one
usb is a wi-fi adapter
so i've just turned your server
into a wireless access point for me to
connect to
and download all your data from your
internal network and broadcast it out
into the parking lot
then the other one is oh don't worry
that's the usb drive that has all the
drivers for windows linux and mac
so i can
load the wireless adapter and plus maybe
some malware here and there it's like if
needed but don't worry i don't write
anything to that that cuff link it's
like i'm just writing to your drive
and writing to your network the the the
the the receiving part comes later
also i have pockets
i love pockets
women understand pockets
why is it with western society it's like
women can't have pockets men can't have
purses but i love my purse it's like
it's like it's got all my stuff in it
so it's like i've got pockets and i use
them very well i do not carry all that
crap with me
that is just to like be real cool
looking like oh look at what i could do
well i could do all these no i don't use
all those things i've used mostly every
one of those at least one point on an
engagement to prove a point
but i don't use all of them at the same
time and my favorite is the back pocket
the back pocket is huge it's the whole
length of it
and i will tell you this for a fact that
i know
it can carry out a laptop
without anybody noticing
guaranteed verified
so let's go to the next role the passive
role it doesn't mean that i'm being
wimpy or timid
it's like the manners i'm using is like
i'm here to help you
help me help you
it's like oh i'm just instead of saying
i'm doing a usb audit
i'm like oh i'm here doing a usb audit
we're trying to make the network faster
you tell someone you're trying to make
the network faster
carte blanche motherf it's done
you ask a user it's like have you
noticed a network running a little bit
slow they could be on a t1 fiber line to
their desktop and like yeah it has been
running a little slow lately
it's like i'm here to make that faster
whoa
you know
what can we do for you what do you need
i'm just just everything it's like so
yes
so you do that where you're trying to
help them but you need some help too to
do that and that's how you do the
passive thing and the hardware is
amazing because you can do way more
techy stuff you get a lot more unusual
things
it's like this is the way i usually
dress
and yes i have worn the shirt that said
hacker on it while i was robbing places
before it's pretty hilarious it's like
warning labels uh but yes this the black
shirt says a hacker and the uh the other
patch says your company's computer guy
and yes that is a microsoft badge copied
from the website from twitter where
someone posted their new microsoft badge
which i was very thankful for
microsoft by the way has updated their
badges which i appreciate the person who
then tweeted that one out so i could
update my badge and i have the newer one
do i use the newer one no
because who knows what a microsoft badge
looks like
and it's roughly the right one so that's
what i do
and now i have the
clipboard yes
it's the clipboard of doom
don't judge me on 12. okay it's like the
clipboard of doom
is very cool
because it has compartments
like the two batch bunnies right there
and i love the fact that yes i have used
the bash money where it says victim on
it
it's like that was a little weird to
explain but i figured i i was able to
manage it
here
is the most scariest
scariest
device in my arsenal
more people need to be afraid of this
i'm not talking about the omg cables
which are microcomputers that look like
charging cables that can compromise a
machine from five miles away i'm not
talking about those
the envelopes
with a marker
i walk into a secured area that i'm in i
see an unattended desk i see an
unattended office
but they have their name badge on there
they have their name tag
they show me who's supposed to be
sitting there
so what do i do
i take the marker i write their name
on the envelope
i put in a malicious usb drive
in the envelope
you know seal it up nice and tight
and i leave it on their desk and i walk
away
who's not opening that
you received an envelope in your secured
area
with your name on it
with the usb drive
who's not going to plug that in
it's got to be legit
it's never legit okay
but also i have more
i have my proxmart i can carry like my
proxmart a wi-fi pineapple full size i
got the land turtles uh but the favorite
one right there is the one that says
hacked that's my hdmi uh screen crab
have you seen these
what it does is you connect it to the
hdmi cable going to the monitor
and you know the executives have the
good monitors they're not stuck with
those vga crap things at the tellers or
or the other uh people in accounting are
stuck with
they got hdmi
you know it's lucky if they can get dvi
right
your executive's got hdmi
so you plug this device in
and it will record everything it sees on
the screen
while still going through to the screen
and
why is there an antenna there jason
because you can access it wirelessly
you can record take screen crabs grabs
it's like with that
that should be frightening how many
ids's and blinky boxes are picking that
one up
yeah exactly none it's like
so let's go to the next one uh these are
the omg rolls uh this should not be your
first choice
too many times it's my first choice okay
this is when you're just like
i don't know what i'm gonna just wing it
you know i call it the yolo uh plan
right you know yolo let's see what
happens
uh and so
um i can't tell you what certain
mannerisms are pretext also the hardware
is totally different i've robbed a place
um as a tv producer
uh i've robbed uh and actually will show
this picture
uh my favorite is robbing hotels
uh this was actually in the south of
france i'm sure y'all recognized the
area
it's not the hotel i was i was robbing
um
the hotel that i was robbing
was so high-end
and expensive
they could only afford to have me there
for one night
then they put me in this cheap hotel
for the rest of the engagement
which i love the view and i've literally
robbed them in those teenage mutant
ninja turtle pajama bottoms barefoot
and a t-shirt
it's like i walked out drunk actually
like i was like oh get some air it's
like walk around
go down go around the side find the
kitchen entrance door unlocked and i
start walking through the underground
everybody knows that uh most hotels have
underground sections right that's where
all the work happens
and that's where i go
because that's where the server rooms
are and the departments and the hr and
the executives and stuff that are
usually not the executives but they're
like the people that are doing the work
go then i was done
and so while i was done i was like well
i need to get out of here so i see
a person in the uh
the room service guy and i'm like
eleanor
hello there
holland elevator
i i'm not supposed to be here
where it always helps if you look like
you're upset with them because they're
like what the what's going on it's like
it's not my fault
it's like and i'm like oh
and it's like you know what he did
he let me into the employee elevator
push the first floor button you know
where that elevator lets me out of
the management office is behind the
front desk i picked up hotel master keys
and an unlocked workstation on my way
out
it was a five-star hotel they they gave
you everything i loved it
so
that's how simple it can be
but usually i do something like that
it's like i just i'm not trying to
exploit you i'm trying to educate you
so most of my payloads come with like a
payload of just notepad or i'm using
these usb drives showing them like in a
pin to show them that dangers come from
all different shapes and sizes we got to
stop thinking that this is how an attack
is going to be
because promise you i will get in
okay
and um and you got to remember if i do
find a way in and i usually do you need
to be worried about it right because
this is two people these are two
sections where someone told me i
couldn't get up or i couldn't do
something
and the one on the left is nekozia
cyprus i am seven stories above the
building and to get up there without
getting the camera to prove a point
because i was actually being petty at
this point it's like to prove the point
to the guy that i was auditing that he
told me i could not get
to the server rooms that had a plaster
wall behind a glass window on their roof
without being detected by their cameras
and i told them like well if you go out
the elevator lobby right there at the
corner and it's like and you climb over
around that column even though it's
seven stories up and get up to that vent
you can climb up and get to it and you
would not trip any cameras
but that's not you can't do that and i'm
like hold my jacket
and then i did it and then i told him
it's like there's a camera in my jacket
will you take a picture for me and he
was nice enough to do so um this one was
telling me that it's like this was a
secured building
because they have an anti-climbing
uh
thing around their ladder it's for
anti-climbing
and yes that's me taking a pallet from a
less than 10 feet away at a dumpster
using it as a prop and then using the
anti-climbing ladder as my ladder
so you never know
so what you need to do is then make sure
your employees know how to respond once
i'm there
this was from january 2020
the best engagement i have ever did
this is me using a paper printed
visitors badge
that i literally copied from online it's
like it's just a printout it's not even
the real badge
didn't matter
i got stopped
people did the right thing
every section i went to
i was uh caught
because they because i was there the
year before
and they learned the lessons
management took it seriously not the
employees at first it requires
management to take it seriously and then
security to take it seriously to educate
the users so they will take it seriously
and so i loved it that is the best job
i've ever done
because i was stopped in every section
so i don't know what time it is that's
one of the problems so i don't know how
much more time i have i probably don't i
don't care um but um wait i said that
part out loud i'm sorry um so um
remember perceptions don't just warn
your employees show them how these
attacks occurred not in theory but show
them real world examples
show them how these things happen
show them how easy it can be there's
plenty of videos on youtube there are
plenty news stories out there
show them how this happens
interact with employees when things
aren't on fire
when i worked in security and i was a
supplement officer for uh law
enforcement guess what
i met everybody on their worst possible
day
something horrible happened and then i
show up
i show up something horrible happens to
them
it's always a bad day with me
but when you're talking about your
employees
they can't just see you on the bad days
you need to reach out to your employees
show them when the newest apple update
is show them when the newest android
updates are shown when there's a new bad
thing going through the through the
internet that they have to watch out for
send them those kind of emails walk
around and talk to them try to get to
know them so they now understand that
you're not an enemy you're not someone
trying to trip them up and make sure
that that they're doing the right thing
but you're someone there to help them
keep the company secure
you're not the police you're not the
goodness like you're not those kind of
people
you're there to help them
you are there to actually
be there for them to be better defended
now also we need to start educating and
empowering and enforcing the rules
what what educating means start teaching
them on day one one of their job
responsibilities is security
how many of your employees know
that if they click on a link they could
be subject to termination
how many people know that it's their
responsibility to secure the equipment
that they're given
they know if they go to an inappropriate
website
they can be written up or fired
but why don't we equate that the same
thing with them doing something that's
not secure
we need to educate them to let them
realize they are part of the security
team that's part of their job
responsibility if they want to continue
to feed and clothe themselves or their
loved ones they have to follow the rules
and so then you empower them
you give them a cell an extension number
that they can call
if they see someone suspicious like me
usually it's like you give them an email
address
that they can send suspicious emails to
and when they make a mistake
and click a link
you've got to make it sure where they
feel comfortable enough being able to
forward that to you and tell you what
happened
because that means your compromise lasts
five minutes instead of five months
if your employee is afraid of responding
to you or admitting that they did
something wrong
that's when your company fails
that's when your security fails
but if they are comfortable letting you
know that they made a mistake
they do better
oops
one last one while you're out chasing oh
days there's
7 331 days that still haven't been
patched
ignore the low-hanging fruit start by
picking up the fruit on the ground
everybody's like all mesmerized like oh
i got an old day oh gotta watch out for
this new old day coming out
patch ms0867
get that done
who's got eternal blue running on their
network
i don't want to hear about your old days
okay i want to hear about what you're
doing to secure your people for the
things that they're actually facing
the attacks that are actually going on
and also i want to add one last thing
yeah i'm done sorry i'm done just like
so um
[Applause]
but i also want to take a moment
to talk about uh because just like the
beginning
just like the end we got to help one
another
i have a friend of mine who used to be
in hong kong
and they're an amazing hacker
who literally almost lost their life
to domestic abuse because they were not
seen as a human
and they are trying to rebuild their
life they're trying to re-get together
it's like and so that's the website
for them to go and uh for you to donate
because i've seen so many people donate
money to get a hacker to defcon
but this person is trying to rebuild
their life from what happened to them
it's like and they need help as well so
that's what that's for
and that
i'm done thank you is there any
questions do we have time for questions
okay we have a couple times for some
questions
does anybody have any questions
that's okay i'm sure the speaker that's
coming after me would appreciate if you
didn't have any questions
i know i would have
i see they're done okay very good thank
you very much guys
see y'all
you