hi good morning everybody let me know if
people can't hit me in the back anyway
so I'm bretzel Mahajan and I'm going to
talk about some work we've just started
doing with my advisors David and Tom at
the University of Washington and it's
about managing inter-domain routing in a
very cooperative manner so here's the
problem we are trying to tackle that
mainly inter-domain routing our bgp
policies inter-domain routing decisions
they are based on very little
information about other networks so what
I do as an operator while trying to
manage my own network is take decisions
that are based on the state of my
network without knowing what's happening
in the other networks and some of the
bad effects Randy talked about at a
global scale what happened when in this
situation in particular you can identify
three undesirable consequences of this
state of the world one is poor
performance that bad paths are chosen
even when they are better paths present
in the network the other being in
stability and oscillations something
when bgp does not converge or because
local decisions are being made without
any global view we get into some sort of
oscillatory behavior i'll get to the
examples of these two in the next couple
of slides but there's an even bigger
cost which is the cost of managing these
networks is high just because we have
taking local decisions without any sort
of global view operators have to be
manually involved at all times whenever
making inter-domain routing policy
changes are rerouting the traffic
towards some other direction so here is
a simple example of poor performance
just consider a simple case of two isps
those three links in the middle are
basically peering links between those
two isps and I'm going to talk about
just two floors 11 of the flow is going
from is PA in that dot to is PB and the
flow back so what happens when is PA
wants to send traffic to is PB it picks
what it calls the earliest exit since is
PA does not know where the traffic is
headed inside RSPB the best it can do is
to optimize
cost of carrying traffic within its own
network and hence pick the early exit or
hot basically what we call hot potato
routing purely in terms of the path
length this path would have been better
but is PA cannot do that because it
doesn't know where the traffic is headed
to within is PB and also the fact that
this path is much cheaper for eyes PA so
it's taking a locally optimal decision
but if you think about what happens on
the reverse flow is PB takes a similar
decision of early exit and we end up
with both high speeds taking early exit
and the net cost now for both high
speeds not just for is PA is much higher
compared to this particular what you
might call an optimal from a path length
perspective system that both high speeds
using the middle peering link and doing
that so the good thing about the
solution is it's cheaper for both
highest piece and also end-to-end path
length is shorter and the point is there
is no currently currently there is no
mechanism and bgp to let you do that you
could use meds but meds basically means
that instead of the upstream eyes we
choose is how the traffic goes the
downstream eyes we choose is what you go
so in this case so if both high speeds
were using meds we just get the reverse
of hot potato rodding where the traffic
flows in reverse with no reduction in
path length whatsoever so that was an
example of poor performance and also
said it can lead to instability or
oscillations in certain cases so here's
an interesting example of that again
considered to isps with three peering
links between each other and we're going
to talk about two floors going in that
direction the orange flow and the blue
flow and assume we're what happens when
the peering link between the two isp
fails now is PA is forced to read out
this traffic so what it does it looks at
the state of its own network and say
okay i'm going to choose the bottom
peering link for both of those flows so
what happens as a result of which is PA
is actually not aware of this causes an
overload inside is PB and what B does an
operator on the B side comes along one
of the links inside my network is
overloaded let me shift some traffic
from the bottom peering link to the top
pairing link using some bgp mechanism
either prepending
our local in our local prayers so it
does that but what this does now is PB
has taken a locally optimal decision and
moving the traffic upwards but this
cause is an overload inside is PA so
what it does a comes along and moves the
traffic right back or something similar
that goes to the same path well be
notices this stage moves it right back
and I'm not making any of this up this
was actually an incident that happened
between two big eyes peas I was told and
this went on for two days operators on
both sides were changing the routing
configuration every 30 minutes or so and
at the end of two days they realize that
what was actually going on that both
operators were undoing each other's work
and if they were actually talking to
each other you could imagine their
solutions in the system that do exist
where no oscillations happen and you can
come to rotting both flows in a manner
which is acceptable to both ISPs here so
what is the current methodology when it
comes to making inter-domain routing
changes so whenever I Spees want to make
any sort of entertainment ordering
changes either in response to addition
of peering links failures or changes in
traffic due to dos attacks of flash
crowds the first is what we call we can
pray so you want to make some routing
decision and you just change it and then
you pray that things would be okay and
you haven't adversely impacted anybody
now this I guess works only for those of
us who are religious and for rest of us
it just fails so what you can do next is
you can do something better the problem
which we can praise you might not
observe the problem in your own network
but there might be a problem in somebody
else's network and that other operator
is now racing against time and firing to
understand what went on so to remedy
that what you can do is call ahead if
you wanted to make some change in your
own network and if you know it would
adversely impact some particular
neighbor you call them okay i'm going to
make changes 12 o clock tonight so this
way at least even if it causes problems
inside their networks they know what the
cause of the problem is and they'll give
you a call so what now what you do is
you call ahead make changes and hope
that you don't get a call from your
neighboring RSP because if you do you
make another change and start hoping
again
so better way out of this dilemma of
making chain making changes basically
based on just local information is to
basically call the operator and manually
negotiate a set of mutually agreeable
solution you know you talk you talk to
the other guy on the phone and say okay
this is the situation these are the set
of flows I want to read out but these
are the changes I want to make is this
okay with you and the cost of this
solution while it works and it's
probably better than the other two
options the cost of this solution is
just the human coordination time which
makes it very expensive and it's
probably not practice often unless it's
unless the change is really major so
here's the challenge for us can we
automate this intro eyes p negotiation
can be instead of letting operators
negotiate manually on the phone when it
comes to can be automated the benefit of
course is that you can now negotiate
even for minor changes without any human
cost involved for automatic negotiation
to be successful it has to achieve these
three criteria first of all it has to
minimize manual firefighting because
that is a primary motivation behind it
if we can do that then our operators you
can imagine they would start using
automatic negotiation and we would rely
less on operators firefighting whenever
arcing changes have to be made the
second thing is the solution that
automated negotiation should produce
there should be as good or maybe even
better than manual negotiation because
if they are not you can still imagine
expecting operators to tweak their
traffic even after automated negotiation
has been done and which basically undoes
all the work we are trying to do here
with automatic stuff the third and the
most important thing is whatever
negotiation protocol of framework design
has to honor certain real-world
constraints constraints of the world we
lived in and we've identified three such
constraints that they should be
controlled information disclosure across
the ISPs we live in a world where ISPs
are competing entities and their
competitive concerns due to which is
peace would be reluctant to give away
all the information about the internal
state of the network to otherwise peace
so we do not want a negotiation protocol
in which you know one isp has to tell
the other everything about the state of
its network and minimize this
information that flows across the isp
boundary the second constraint is that
the negotiation protocol should be
independent of the optimization criteria
itself it should not be focused just on
optimizing latency or just an optimizing
resource utilization in a network and
the primary reason there is twofold one
maybe aspies don't want to reveal their
optimization criteria and the second
reason is that which is more important
in some sense the different isps you
could expect are optimizing the network
for different things one might be
optimizing for latency and the other one
is just optimizing resource utilization
increase inside its own network or
protecting certain links that tend to
overload so the negotiation protocol has
to be such that these eyes peas with
different optimization criteria can
still negotiate with each other to find
mutually acceptable routes and the third
is flexible outcomes different pairs of
ISPs have different relationships with
each other some might be peers with each
other other ISPs might be providers or
customers and you could imagine when
these two isps negotiate with each other
they would want different solutions so
what we are not looking for is a
mechanism that given some input produces
a fixed out but what we're looking for
something that's more like a negotiation
where the outcome of the negotiation
actually depends on the people who are
involved and the relationship between
the parties that are involved in there
so is the current status of her work
well we just looked at negotiation
between two neighboring ISPs as of now
and you could imagine this negotiation
happening at an Internet scale where all
the ISPs negotiate traffic negotiate all
the traffic across variable whichever
paths the truck whichever is PS the
traffic is using all of them no traffic
is flowing through them where and you
could imagine a global negotiation but
what so far what we've looked at is a
simpler but still challenging problem of
just negotiating between two isps it
basically boils down to picking a
pairing link between them when they're
multiple links between them and what
we've come up with is a very high-level
methodology so I have to warn you I'm
not going to talk about protocol details
because we haven't really focused on
details yet but we just wanted to come
up with the high-level methodology how
this should work and evaluate the
potential benefit of it and it and if it
turns out this is actually beneficial we
might just go down and come out with a
very detailed proposal on this issue
so here's a very simple here's a
simplified view of the negotiation
methodology we are talking about so
suppose two isps are negotiating with
each other and they have a bunch of
flows to route a readout between each
other so for starters we say well let
them assign a numeric preference just
like med and opaque number let them
assign a numeric preference to each of
the option for each flow so between two
isps an option is basically which
bearing length to pick for a particular
flow so good thing about using this
methodology is that first this numeric
now this number is completely opaque I
hand you a number 20 and as an ISP and
you have no idea what I'm talking about
how did I come up with that number so my
optimization criteria is hidden and you
don't know what like 20 even them even
the magnitude or what I'm using
basically is not clear to you so very
little information is revealed just like
and no more than what's revealed using
meds today second so both high speeds
have come up with the numeric preference
and the second they exchange this
preference list and the third step is
the most flexible part of the component
here that I Speece take turns to propose
options and while proposing options as
in appearing link for a flow or
something they find good compromises in
the preference list data I will come to
an example on the next slide and in the
middle of the negotiation you might want
to reassign the preferences after some
of the flows have been negotiated the
load in the network changes or the
potential load in the network changes so
you might think about reassigning the
preps and redoing the negotiation step
and you it's flexible and stop whenever
one of the SP wants to one of them k ok
I'm done I don't want to negotiate in
more and that's when the negotiation
would stop and you would implement then
go ahead and implement whatever you want
whatever you negotiated in your network
so so here's an example I I'm going to
talk about the simpler of the two
examples I talked about where they were
trying to reduce the latency of the past
between them again to isps a and B and
two flows one the blue flow going from A
to B an orange one going from B to a the
matrix on your right is basically the
preference list so what I am saying so
zeros base I put the numeric preference
for the default routing path shown here
in dark
in zeros just to evaluate how much
benefit they get otherwise so for a to
be was using the bottom peering link so
the preference for both high speeds here
is zeroes and B to a was using the top
reading link and the preference is 0 and
now for the A to B flow this is the
first entry in each of these pairs is
the preference for is PA and the second
problem in all of these is a preference
for is PB so let me just walk through
this one for a to b flow what is PA
saying it slightly worse for me to take
the traffic to the middle peering link
so it assigns a minus one but taking it
to that but taking it to the top reading
link is even worse for me so assign a
heavier minus for a negative preference
minus six similarly similarly be saying
for a to be traffic it's best for me if
you bring it from the top link that's
six and it's it's still good for me if
you bring it here and this is just the
default so let's say is PA gets to
propose an option first so what it does
it looks at this preference list okay
this is the default anyway can I do any
better than what i'm doing now it looks
here zero minus one minus six now so
this is my best option the default i'm
good with but then it looks in this case
out there is some place for optimizing
flow flows going from B to a so looks as
this is 00 default but looks here it's 6
and minus 6 you would think that is PA
is tempting at proposing this option but
it knows if it does that is PB is
unlikely to accept this option so
instead of proposing this which is
highly negative 4 is PB it tries to find
a good compromise here which is much
which is much better for a but only
slightly worse for be so what it does is
proposes this option and you can imagine
since this is just slightly worse for is
PB eyes to be be basically accepting
that so B does the same calculation and
proposes this so what we get is this
solution and if you add a preferences as
some rough measure of how much the ice
please have gained in during the course
of the negotiation you can just add you
can add okay this minus 4 & 4 here so
it's gained three and similarly for is
PB has gained three and end-to-end paths
are even better so this is basically the
insight behind why negotiation would
work that both highest peas are actually
trading small sacrifices
never the flow is routed not on the
default path for bigger gains and if you
put together such options or such trades
what you get is better performance for
both high speeds individually and for
the end-to-end path over there so we
evaluated the potential of this
negotiation using we had we had measured
data for pop level I Spit apologies and
these data set basically contains
measure topologies of all tier 1 ISPs
and a large number of tier two isps and
we play with all sorts of synthetic
traffic models to understand since we
don't have data available for traffic
like what's the nature of the traffic
that flows across these backbones we
came up with several synthetic traffic
models and evaluated our results for
each of them just to see if our results
are sensitive to traffic models as such
and what we did basically we compared 3
routing methodologies one is just the
default early exit selfish showering
each SP is looking at its own network
and routing traffic using that optimal
an optimal was basically what is a
globally best solution across both
highest piece and the definition of
optimal is dependent on the metric we
are trying to evaluate negotiated
routing on sand I am come to that in a
minute when I talk about specific
experiments but the difference between
optimal and default it just basically
gives us some sense of what is the how
much opportunity is there to negotiate
if the difference between optimal and
default what happens today is not much
then there's no point in negotiating
because we are living in a very
efficient world as is and the third
solution we third routing methodology we
evaluated well just negotiated routing
and what happens with it I'm going to
talk about two sets of experiments one
for latency reduction how much
negotiation helps with latency reduction
and the other is hotspot avoidance what
happens with short-term overloads in one
of the networks so his experiment for
latency reduction and inside behind
there or the motivation is just that
high latency basically implies poor
performance for your customers and
through the network but it's not just
that high latency has also impacts the
isp network itself if there are shorted
pads present in the network but longer
ads are being taken that basically means
more resources are being consumed within
the network which in turns could
translate to a costlier operation so
with this more with this motivation to
evaluate the reduction in latency using
negotiated routing what we did was
mention latency of traffic when rotted
using the three doubting mechanisms are
talked about default optimal and
negotiated an optimal in justins
basically means since we know the
latency of traffic in both highest peace
optimal basically is what is the best
across to ice p is not caring about how
much an individualized speed gains or
losses in the process so here are some
results are what this graph here is
plotting is total reduction in latency
across both eyes peas and reduction
compared to default the solid line is
for the solid line here is for optimal
traffic what reduction using the optimal
rotting strategy what is the minimum
across both high speeds and the dotted
line here is for negotiated traffic and
what this graph is for this point here
for instance is saying that for sixty
percent of the ISPs the reduction in
latency is five percent or more and
they're two things here one is the
negotiation is very close to optimal so
what this is saying is by negotiation
you can come very close to optimal by
itself so there's not much cost to just
negotiating instead of finding the true
or globally optimal but there's nothing
going on that there is a very small
aggregate latency reduction here that's
like five percent or the medians even
less but the when you dig deeper there
is some flows that really gain big and
these I suspect are the flows which
really suffer using early exit roaring
because traffic is routed in the
opposite direction altogether and at
this point it's not clear to me whether
the small aggregate production is
actually valuable in terms of the
benefits it brings but this is something
I'd like to get your feedback on or
whether it translates into any sort of
monetary advantage or not but there's a
more interesting thing happening here I
mean we saw that optimal can be computed
at least for latency the interesting
thing here is what the graph on the
right is plotting what is the reduction
in latency inside each individual
network as against across both of them
so what we see is if you if you just try
and get achieve the optimal
one of the ISPs actually suffers a
negative reduction it basically means by
moving from default to the optimal
scenario it just so happens that one of
the ISPs reduction or latency inside one
of the ice PS actually increases it
basically means that this is P maybe
would have no incentive to negotiate
because you know it's latency is
increasing as a result but the dotted
line here for negotiation basically
shows that I space either don't win or
both when it's basically a win-win
situation that you have nothing to lose
by negotiating you are not you're bound
to not lose at all you might just win
let me talk about a more interesting
experiment now which is this talks about
dealing with short-term overloads so
sudden changes inside even a
well-engineered network can cause
short-term overloads and the sudden
changes could result from failures dos
attacks maybe addition of link is not a
sudden change change but it still leads
to read outing or traffic and that can
cause overload in certain links and
finding these I understand is a major
time seeing for operators today so we
try to evaluate where the negotiation
can help with hotspot avoidance or not
this experiment is three steps assume
that appearing link between any peering
link between the two between two isps
fails and what we do is read out the
traffic traversing the failing and this
rerouting happens using those three
routing methodologies are talked about
the default selfish routing the second
is optimal an optimal here was computed
using this complex constraint solver
that bought sensitive load on the
individual links and negotiated routing
and negotiation the metrics used by both
high speeds and negotiation was again
since we're evaluating for lewd was
basically overloading the network and
authorities we measure the potential
using with each of these methodologies
and the metric for measuring hot spot
potential is the increase in the link
load before and after the failure and
the thing is the intuition there is if a
link carries 10 times as much traffic
after the failure as before the chances
are that link is loaded would be loaded
after those changes after rerouting so
here the experiment these graphs are a
little different from the ones I showed
so I'll just run
through them this is again experiment
for all the ISP pairs the graph on the
left is depicts what happens inside the
upstream is P and this graph depicts
what happens in the downstream is P and
the and the x-axis is basically the
multiplicative increase in load relative
to the optimal so there is some optimal
strategy which which basically focuses
on reducing overload inside both highest
piece and what do you what do we do when
we and compared to that optimal how to
negotiate it and default routing do so
what we see here and the dotted line is
again for for default and the solid line
is for negotiated so what this point
here is saying is that load ratio was
like twice the ratio basically means a
two hundred percent increase in link
load compared to the optimal over here
so what we seeing here just by the shape
of the curve here is that there are
certain links if you use default routing
there are certain links in the topology
that would carry you know two hundred
percent or more load so the tendency for
the links to get overloaded is much
higher with default routing and ideally
what you would want in any solution that
to come close as to the optimal is
something like the negotiation a line
that goes all the way up to one so
negotiation we see since it's like it
does go all the way up to bond but it
closes there so incensed it's close it's
very close to the optimal but not quite
there there's some cost to that but
nevertheless you can see the negotiation
reduces the possibilities of hotspots in
the network which once the possibility
of hotspot reduces then they are but
this basically means there are fewer
problems for operators to resolve
because no short-term overload happens
as a result of changes in the network so
I'm going to conclude my talk here and
basically just summarize what I just
told you that the motivation behind a
work basically here was intimate
interdomain routing or bgp policies are
based largely on local information and
which has cost in terms of the quality
of the paths we can achieve on the poor
performance of the paths in steady-state
instability in the face of changes that
come by and the network can lead to
oscillatory behavior with people making
changes independently without any sort
of
view but a bigger cost is in terms of
our playlist I'm the management is
tedious it's error-prone because of
humans are involved in the loop and what
we started investigating was can all of
this go away in terms of management
costs in the performance cost by just
automating the negotiation and our early
results basically point that automated
negotiation can help and none of the
ISPs actually loses by negotiating and
which is which is the way the whole
negotiation framework is set up that you
are guaranteed to not lose during
negotiation and I'd love your feedback
on it and basically just one cushion in
terms of from what ever since you've got
an hour it would you would you use it to
talk to your neighbors in the sense put
it in what scenarios automated
negotiation makes sense in what scenario
does not what kinds of problems it
solves why are why it's not possible to
do that in the network I while I focused
on latency reduction and hotspot
avoidance you can think of automated
negotiation as a load balancing tool
that you use with your providers or
customers when you're trying to balance
load across multiple providers or across
speeding links of the same provider
answer and there is a paper available on
that URL there that talks about the
experiments in detail which I didn't get
time to and explains the expense the
whole thing in more detail than I could
get you in my talk thanks
Nick now you're
yes there's time for questions here
please we just didn't see anybody
deep-fried up I'll stay here for a
moment please okay because I think this
was a very interesting next step in how
to do that so if there's questions
please rush right up to the mic right
now because we're a little tight on time
so yeah I'm manish from merritt network
i had a question regarding your approach
in addressing this problem now a lot of
words that you've used seem to be
indicative of using the min-max
principal and game theory and global
Optima so is that the approach that
you're taking in this work we did look
at we are still looking at this so we
are still looking at game theory but
from a different perspective we're
looking at game theory mainly what can
we say about the incentive compatibility
and things like that of the solution and
I mean and the prop and just
articulating the properties of the
solution in terms of Pareto optimality
are just social optimal and things like
what the impact would be of the
resulting solution when one of the ice
piece begins to cheat and things like
that we haven't made much headway in
terms of actually applying some solid
tools from game theory and in for
certain nice properties that you might
want out of it but if you have ideas I'm
happy to talk to you after that thanks
but but you're writing general game
theory does look like a tool that would
be it's meant for scenarios like this
Bruce Hana from park it's a little hard
to tell from just the cursory overview
presentation here it seems like the
assumption you're making is where you've
got provider a and provider be that if
they both play nice and decide to
cooperate with each other with this
automated protocol then there's mutual
benefit
the previous question are brought up the
issue of game theory it seems to me you
can end up in a prisoner's dilemma
situation where I as the bad provider
try to trick the other guy into being
nice to me but in the meantime I'm back
stabbing him by taking the low-cost
route all right so so I try to make him
take take a path that minimizes my cost
but the meantime I'm taking my low-cost
egress and making him pay to carry the
traffic so does your research address
the situation where one provider tries
to defect from the cooperative
arrangement and trick the other guy into
cooperating it it does so but in ave
trivial manner and the tribute manner is
the following if you know the default
routing then no matter what the other
isp says the other provide bad provider
says you cannot lose by negotiating so
now the point becomes that you have in
this default scenario which in which
both high speeds will I realize what the
cost is and as a provider I know what my
cost is and by negotiating with you what
my cost is what the cost of the
negotiated solution is so the trivial
answer I responding is basically that I
will not negotiate if I lose now it's in
the cheating I squeeze in trust to
actually give me incentive to negotiate
and you know because you gain a lot by
cheating you being a lot by negotiating
but you also have to give me basically
give me some carrot to play otherwise
I'm not going to play at all and so then
the issue becomes that yes there is some
margin for cheating and the result of
the cheating is that the gains from
negotiation may or may not be divided in
a fair manner whatever the definition of
fear might be and we are still looking
into this whole fairness issue but
beyond that we don't have a good answer
yet ok so I'm guaranteed not to lose but
yes my competitor might gain more than
me right that's true ok yeah thanks
maybe that included you okay this is on
right Tom vest no picks a dress actually
I wanted to address the game theory
issue as well you you start off with
mentioning that this assumes absence of
local information but in fact the model
you set up which is correctly identified
as a prisoner's dilemma in a way
implicitly assumes perfect information
on both sides the way you've set it up
is the incentives are or equivalent or
symmetrical and in most real-life
circumstances are considering that even
appearing between two peers generally
they won't receive each other is
absolutely identical and since most of
the interconnections are actually not
peering but what are some sort of
compensation based arrangement you'll
almost never get a situation where the
two parties actually do in reality
without knowing it have perfectly
symmetrical views of the relative merits
of coming to an agreement so you always
have somebody who sees the relative
gains issue in fact this is sort of the
ship replica shipwreck of game theory
outside of this for the network modeling
well yeah I think there's a difference
in the information aspect that there is
perfect information but the issue is
like how much information is being
revealed across the boundary which is a
prime concern I fail to understand
whether the ocean was that information
is the interest are always aligned is
the issue there or the fact is perfect
information is not available even
locally
apologies okay the way you're
calculating it in effect it embeds the
assumption that the payoffs are
symmetrical and for that to be
operationally realistic in some ways
they have to be that that's the way the
providers have to perceive it as well we
okay so you're saying you're coming into
the negotiation as equal partners I
think that can suddenly change based on
maybe that's the yes maybe that's where
that's where I would diverge because i
would say in most situations that
wouldn't be the case so okay I talk to
you after dog there's a simple um Randy
Bush iij I'm that strange minority here
I come from an ISP oh and I heard the
presentation I cheated i also read the
paper and my perception tom is that
whether we come as equals or not what
matters is in this negotiation I don't
over disclose and I don't lose I may not
gain as much but I don't lose and the
truth is that is an operator and an
operator does peering that's all I'm
interested in that meets my needs I
don't perceive myself as winning by you
losing and I don't
I'm here trying to make a better network
and I don't think the operators with
whom I peer are bad actors I like the
fact that this doesn't encourage bad
acting and that it doesn't introduce a
lot of complexity and yet I think a
difficult problem I smell that you're
actually doing something useful and
thank you it was good thank you