my friend Tim tells the first time he
spoke at Nana
he was told everything will go right
this some blankie blankie Randy Bush
gets up to try to ask questions
and
it was taught
audience and so on and so forth
oh oh it's not a portable mic because I
like to launder all
see how this works
here we go and he says it was absolutely
horrifying and that I was really mean
and nasty i don't remember thing he's
lying but so what he's done this time
has forced me to give his talk this is
an engineer solution to the problem I
wish I could be here it gives it brother
well but Tim is an Intel research in
Cambridge England which is associated
with the university until and they kind
of tread it in Iraq a bgp wedgie is done
is their portable mic
ok ok ok I'll stay here
they want to see me they're desperate um
okay and sorry about this multimedia
that this thing only works on one okay
bgp policies make sense locally you can
look at your router's you know what your
policies are so sore okay but the
interaction of local policies allows
global multiple solutions and that's
going to be the point of this it's a key
points will show to you okay in fact bgp
is multi stable in a global interpreter
situation some solutions are what you
meant okay some solutions are not what
you meant
manual intervention can be required to
get it from one of those you didn't mean
back to one of those who did meet and
when unintended solutions are installed
there can be situations where no single
provider a single provider has the
global knowledge sufficient to
understand what the heck zactly
this is not good by the way
this is the BGP problem talk like this
afternoon I'll give you a BGP ain't so
bad time
ok
this one's stuff we all know but I'm
just going to sneak up on it slowly okay
we want to shed inbound traffic we have
two links between two providers
providing customer and we want the
traffic to go this way so we prepend on
the a s path okay which is a disgusting
little hack but kind of works
so
traffic all flows down this path
yeah I have to run it to occasionally to
do this powerpoint crap the police thing
and it doesn't always work okay because
in this case as3 is going to send it
here because the provider always prefers
customer
so even though I'm prepending up the
yin-yang here this guy's traffic is
going to go here and that's because you
can see an argument between me and
embarrassed I forget
I think Vince fuller back in about
ninety six where essentially it became
clear that when you have multiple
peering points between two providers so
that provider a announces the same thing
at both peering points they have to
prefer their customers to their ears in
announcing prefixes
so that provider is can send that
traffic this way so it doesn't always
work so how do we get out of that it's
Oh communities to the rescue so what we
do is this provider says hey you can
send me a community or for the movement
call it normal which says the pref is a
hundred my normal customer preference or
you can send me a different community
which drops it lower and that's how i'll
send you
back up community
you say oh I'll put that before lower
than my peer so i'll take the pier route
it seems to do what we love
this a s has this policy
and it said it nice and low
but
everything's not going to be perfect now
this is a critical thing recognize this
elbow because you'll get it again later
okay this is a provider customer link
this is brighter customer link peers I
use the vertical thing to show this all
the time so about that okay customer see
wants a backup link customer wants to
put a backup link in to see just in case
things go bad right so they put in the
link and they send see a community that
says hey prefer your provider please i
want to be ranked this this route ranked
it lower than going this way so the
traffic properly goes that way just what
we wanted disaster strikes this leap
breaks perfect
the backup worked just what we want
it's repaired
but this provider prefers customers the
community that you're sending year is
not being sent there has no meaning
their community was low cleaning here we
are now in a bye in the other half of a
bistable situation by stable this is
stable that stable by what's actually
multi stable in this case they're only
two so it's by okay um and
this is going to stay
it's going to be that way
how does he get out of it or she
by the way this was not a Cisco bug
don't laugh most because what fixes it
is reset this session and it will flip
back
and so he said all the stinkin cisco
router here it wedged it didn't this was
protocol aspect this was your local BGP
policy and their local BGP policy in
their local BGP policy interacting in
ways we didn't expect okay
it was but you reset this and it flips
back so it must have been a cisco bug
right it wasn't okay this is only half a
wedgie and because this person can
actually figure it out if they've seen
this presentation and they can do
something simple to fix it okay what
they could do more is if this provider
when they got the preference that the
community from here that said hey down
press me they could have translated it
into this providers down pref community
and sent this provider the down breath
okay pretty kinky huh
I don't think we want to build that
level of complexity in but that's what
would actually work okay
now we're going to get a three-quarter
widget
by the way remember if you probably know
what wedgies were it had to be explained
to me my teenagers grew up a while ago
um
I want a load balance I've got two
prefixes I'm going to use this as the
primary for this prefix and this is the
primary for this prefix and reverse the
backups ok so I'm going to do the old
community hack and all that stuff and we
have this route we have that route so me
to this traffic goes this way p 1 is
traffic goes that way I'm load balanced
everything's cool both sides no my
community no my prefixes so if one of
these breaks I'm cruising okay so this
is a three-quarter wedging because it
has all the stuff of the last one I'm
not going to go into the detail show you
how it breaks because remember this
shape that's the same shape as last time
but what happens is the either of these
lame look breaks and this is actually
try stable okay because it can go either
way and it's broken and what I have to
do is reset both links and I have to be
smart enough to reset both legs now the
reason it only gets three quarters
credit is two reasons number one if I'm
smart enough and I guarantee or not I
could I did have the information to
understand it just here and secondly I
could fix it just here I can reset both
sessions
now theoretically I can reset those
sessions but anybody who's running a
provider you know that's of any scale
imagine calling your ops people and
telling them could you reset the BGP
sessions to both providers by the way
we're going to lose connectivity for
about five minutes right that's about as
likely as cash falling from the sky okay
so that's a three quarter wedgie because
I could know enough to do it and I could
fix it and I could run out of batteries
I saw one of those were
maybe that's what this is
this one's out of batteries to know
there we go
right in mind ok so that's why i'd only
gets three quarters credit i have to cut
two links but i could know it I could do
it
okay what's going on there is no
guarantee that a BGP configuration in
the global sense has a unique solution
there can be multiple solutions and the
order of updates will control which one
comes which of the multi stable
solutions wings
that's why there's no guarantee that a
BG piece configuration has any solution
by the way and checking them as an
np-complete problem okay and there are
situations in the lab but that goes back
the first one that have shown that their
bgp solutions that can oscillate
continually and lastly complex policies
and the more complex we make it you know
I'm a great fan of complexity um weights
community setting preference and so on
increase the chances of routing
anomalies the kink here you make it the
weirder the outcome
and now a full which is coming up
okay we insert into the last pretty
picture a peer of provider see provider
d the customer sends to see telling me
hey prefer your provider Doug but let me
start I send on this path for Fermi
under your provider and under your peer
only if both of these links break pardon
me this link in this link break should
you send traffic to me please and I send
to D a community that says hey prefer me
under above prefer me before your
provider but less than your peer so the
traffic goes this way
of course
the carrier's come through again and
break the link backhoe day get working
petzl going there this switched over
here whammy it's restored oops now we
understand why this is happening okay
but i am now looking at providers DS
traffic coming in here okay I don't know
why and I have a problem with d to fix
this I would have to reset
if I take this down it's going to switch
here so I can't just reset that session
I have no reason to think provider G is
involved ok I have to reset both these
links simultaneously and I don't no
longer have the information to know that
ok and that's a full widget I have to
reset both those links and I have to
tell my knock by the way you're going to
reset a perfectly good working session
and what do you think they're ready say
to me it's not going to be polite ok so
here's your full wedgie how'd we get
here again the PGP always make sense
locally but the interaction of local
policies has weird global solutions and
it's multi stable some are what you
wanted and some aren't what you wanted
you have to kick it to get back to what
you wanted and sometimes you don't have
the knowledge to kick it
okay what couldn't we do
be careful to find communities very
sparsely don't get carried away with
tons of definitions and maybe consider
translating them and transiting up the
words if you remember the first case was
I could have when I could have said when
this provider received the down pref
community they could have said oh he's
telling me to down breath I'm going to
have to take that retag it and use her
down pref community when I tell her
and that's all she wrote
rox questions now tim has to walk up and
ask a nasty question Tim where are you
how long
hmm ah here comes tli go for it go
please by the way state your name and
your affiliation who are you Tony Tony
Lee and i'm not speaking from my
employer which is currently variable the
problem that you recognized is not to
choose surprising we have local
mechanisms we're surprised because they
don't have global semantics
and your suggestion translating the
communities is simply one to give that
community global significance why not
just Li talk about the final
because when you start going up four
levels you're going to find that he
didn't really mean that right when you
start merging those will provide we've
got somebody else who's a customer
provider a and B they may not like that
result
while she's coming all season can you
how about transitive communities read
Sweeney in the Indians can you can you
pass a community to a through C or the
witches approaching clue i knows what
seems provider is do I know who sees
provider is and we'll see transit
communities I'm back in 96 we had a
presentation at nanog that did suggest
that providers should let in other words
see should let customers provider
through community through to a but see
doesn't always do that so seek an OC
often what C does is just strip off
every community it doesn't know that may
not be good
let's go
grace LBG
why did you start off by saying that BTW
be waiting
because I don't like because remember
what I wanted was this that's good
right and I had like it pardon why is it
good because i'm paying ten cents a
megabit for this and two dollars and
make a bit for that so I want my traffic
coming in this way and I'm paying for it
okay and since both of those are my
provider and I'm paying them I have the
right to tell them how to write to me
route to me so I tell them through the
communities or jective have money for
the routing to do that capability all
right but I'm paying them there might
providers so I have the right to tell
them technically here's how to do it
you're the customer I'm the customer see
us here on ER right so I have the right
to tell those two no pardon you don't
have a right to tell them how to
function you're the customer no no they
are giving me a kabillion because I pay
the money and if they don't I will
choose another provider and that is your
right right but I have now chosen to
providers who do what I ask because I'm
paying the money right and what I ask is
they accept communities that let me
preference their preferences and they
are being perfectly good providers
there's nothing wrong with what they are
doing they're doing the right thing
what's wrong as the technology we're
using isn't doing it the simple way
because it ends up this way on the more
expensive link and that's not what I
wanted
tended to be me here d technology isn't
the bad part here it's the person d is
the one that's circumventing everything
nobody is circumventing anything and
there's no D in this foil keep going
forward to the end of your presentation
keep going you meant you meant the full
wedgie configuration there this one
these not circumventing anything d is
going giving traffic to its provider who
is paying money to accept its traffic
but you said customer is blind see
pedra who are you
from I don't speak on my employer either
yes but it's still nice nobody speaks
through their employer but they should
tell people just in case without meaning
to they are slightly biased especially
when that employers a vendor so what
Fortuna cornetta's mom um and did the
question of a little bit on same plane
so we have profile array now you're not
a customer Pryderi and let's
the finer a finds it cheaper to send
traffic towards the provider ceiling
aren't we having to economical equations
that conflict with each other rather
than you know a diversions on the
protocol sign don't
on economical models
yes okay
we can back up for letters that aren't
here one of the problems is what
problems do we have way up at the top
that we haven't discussed one of them is
that bgp is all about policy and not at
all about metrics or as an igp is all
about metrics not about policy and
that's a dilemma we've been in for years
number two is the policy we have is all
about influence upwards the jewels we
have are all about influence upwards not
negotiation okay but
it's not that I disagree with you it's
we've got a whole new world about how to
discuss policy and I don't think we have
the tools to do that today and when we
do if we feel we want them when we start
to build them then I would suggest we'd
be very careful about the country just
saw something on the floor you did
um we'd be very careful not to introduce
the kinds of complexities that allowed
us to get into this is my real question
would be
we had different tools would be
acceptable to have
they're a policy
by customer doesn't
that's the transitive policy question
whether this person should be able to
put community on the trans goes to their
transitive communities and therefore
influences their policy to problems with
it is are the communities transitive and
the second one is I'm not being paid by
you why should you be able to dork with
my policy yep
currently by the way there's a subtle
thing in our model which is we subtly
believe that since I'm paying you and
you were paying you that there are some
rights which were transitive
right that I had the right to influence
your policy and that you had the right
to influence yours Susan is saying it's
time out Oh
no don't warm it it's almost comfortable
go for it you're another northerner then
AC then you're another northerner I'm a
northern oh but anyway there's more than
one cold spot right
don't sound like you're from terra del
Fuego you're close very close huh
actually Dan identify
No
annual
question is as I think two things
actually three things what is the basis
of the understanding of the system
money talks
now the other problem is Joker's and
wild cards
right
do you believe that everyone functions
according to
everyone actually tries to or most
people do and those that didn't work you
know Vinnie was ostracized back in 1998
he even he learned his lesson 1998 yeah
what happened then he's God was around
go to the nanog archive people were not
following the agreements and Ravis
routing traffic over multi-point
multi-access Nicias meshes like may east
and people just chop them off we all are
working very hard to act cooperatively
presume the people are not just like
it's not a cisco bug that providers not
meaning that i understand that providers
also not meaning to cheat everybody is
doing the best of their intentions here
to make the network working and
unfortunately the technology is too
gives us a multi stable situation that's
all it's a distance vector protocol when
do you believe in
black or gray
I think their colors they don't require
an act of faith mum martyred one more
question sir I Randy Louis loosely from
what I work for Equinix today in your
half wedgie scenario if you want to go
back to that world house half which is
this is the full one owns the first
right there yeah um if you employ the AS
prepending hack at the same time of your
communities when your failures the
aerial when your failure is a fixed well
provider a would hear both routes and it
swing back but of course that's the
thing that much more imagination to add
another provider and your ASP panic will
break again but at least employ more
than one tool
help someone yes it would solve this
problem but somehow adding complexity
doesn't feel intuitively like it's going
to solve things in the long run we can
at least try to use that yeah yeah taxi
oops sorry you said I let it go that
Susan okay do I have a live one wife
okay my question is how many of these
providers are does this also happen
inside of a pro fighter where they're
made up with several aliases sure yeah
by the way how many people suspect
they've seen this with these wedges yep
in life daily life
Arden
right team actually had to believe this
has occurred in their network has
actually happened