steve is that you back there I don't see
Steve the first thing I want to do oh
thank you yes to thank Steve Steve's
been known to many of us for almost 10
years since the mid-90s when he build
one of the first exchange points as I
mentioned yesterday he's been a pal to
us ever since and he got together a
wonderful team from cnet I'm only
mentioning a few names here these are
the people who I'd happen to interact
with and who were spectacularly helpful
ken Emery George Allen Steven gillett
Justine noggin Paul Auster host ted k
hall jim brown techie yuuki sakurai and
Ron Corrin thank you so much IP networks
just plain flat out donated the fiber
link to the hotel and it was robbed
Willis who particularly worked with
Steve on that 365 main is the colo
provider for IP networks and cnet and
donated a cross connect not only donated
it but got it in incredibly fast
providing connectivity for us we're
grateful to Jamie McGrath for his work
on that switch and data gave us a
wonderful party last night and we've had
other wonderful parties we've had three
Sunday night parties and they were all
brought to us by one individual who's
did with a couple of companies over the
past few years but it's chris casada I
don't know Chris are you here he's been
fabulously helpful and we're very
grateful for this as I said when a
company steps up to entertain all of us
it's it's fabulous cloud shield
entertained us with food yesterday
morning we want to thank you for that
Joel yay glee Hans Coon and Lizzie lynch
Evan coming to nanog for years in
various combinations they are from the
University of Oregon they're supported
by Cisco and pocket and they are a
delight they've been on the cutting edge
of multicast for 67 years
at least and they are keeping us there
and we're very grateful for it Duane
it's hard to know where to start to with
everything that he does particularly
this time with introducing us to IPSec
and for that we are very grateful
juniper donated our edge router this
time Aviva Garrett was really the person
who launched that but Tzeitel bana is
the one who well Aviva has been around
for the entire weekend as well but say
it has been a tremendous help from
cutting wires to just be encouraging and
helping us get them network setup we're
very grateful to you too and to Carol
who works back at home on all of your
behalf so hard David Gilbertson who is
on loan to us from Missha net one of our
lead engineers there Don conesus with
registration Teresa did a fabulous job
on the real media thank you so much
Teresa Larry Blanc and al fey set up our
authentication server which worked and
Betty is our infrastructure manager back
at home our beer and gear sponsors we
are very grateful for your support to a
plus you give us beer which is good your
wireless cards should be returned I
think at this point to Carolyn dawn out
at the registration desk we're going to
start to clean up soon so goodbye and
we'll look forward to seeing you this
fall thank you