i'll be presenting a talk titled how
developers don't think about gender
privacy before i get started i wanted to
acknowledge my co-author on this talk dr
yasmin akar who is at the george
washington university
so to get started with a quick overview
of the talk i'll start by sort of
describing the problem i may spend a
little longer on this point than other
research talks just because
i have a feeling it's something that
people aren't necessarily familiar with
i'll then move to talk about the study
we did
talking with developers about gender
privacy
particularly we looked at
data on reddit as well as we conducted
interviews with developers
finally i'll move to discuss some key
takeaways for the people in this room
so to get started what is gender
it's defined by the american
psychological association as one's
internal sense of being male female or
something else
sorry
sorry i have to reference this to be
able to see
so it's ubiquitous in society
at least
american society and users may be
required to provide it to service
providers before they can use software
so what's the problem with this well
there's a few issues that can arise
in asking about gender
first if you provide insufficient
options such as only male or female
people this presents an accessibility
issue where people may not be able to
access your service second gender
identity may change over time so this
can be someone who
for example
was identified at birth as male but then
transitions to identify as female
additionally for people who for example
maybe aren't out about their true gender
identity when you ask about their gender
it presents a privacy dilemma for them
if they can't opt out of that question
and finally gender data may be used in
unexpected or harmful ways often this
comes up with people being categorized
for advertising in ways they don't
expect or are inappropriate and i have a
further uh suggested reading if you want
to learn more about these issues when
you get the slides
so i want to give a sort of illustrative
example here from the real world uh from
a co-worker so when they uh accepted a
job at the company they were working at
they provided them with three gender
options they didn't really know what
this was going to be used for
they selected the option diverse which
is a third gender option
in germany
when they selected that option
they looked at their profile on the
employer's website and they got this
nice picture
on the right here which
sort of
did two things that they didn't really
like the first was
it provided with them with sort of this
gender uh representation this photo that
they didn't identify with but secondly
uh they weren't out about their gender
to others in the workplace so when they
saw this it sort of
inadvertently outed them because there
was no clear indication of how their
gender was going to be used
so i think this clearly illustrates two
of the points i talked about of the
previous slide
so in order to learn more about this
issue and where these sort of bad
examples come from we did a study
looking at how developers use gender
data and we started with these three
framing research questions here so the
first one is
how do developers use gen how do
developers ask about gen ask users for
gender data
second once they have the data how do
they use it
and then finally what advice if any do
developers receive about
asking about and using gender data
so we decided to use a mixed methodology
for this study first we went to just
practice on reddit
so this gave us insight into two things
first we could see discussions about
gender and this was really why we chose
reddit over other options such as other
data sources like stack overflow or
github because of its more discussion
oriented nature
but additionally we were also able to
see code snippets where people used or
asked for gender
second in order to get insight into some
issues that weren't covered in our
reddit data we conducted an interview
study with 15 developers
as i said this allowed us to probe
issues that were not uh you know present
in our reddit data set
so i'll start by discussing what we did
with reddit
so in order to collect data
we looked at we took search terms
related to gender and apply them to
and use the reddit api to look for them
on
programming related subreddits like
compute rsls computer science our slash
foreign programming
and other such subreddits so from this
we got over 900 posts with over 10 000
associated comments
um we couldn't stop there though because
of our broad search criteria
we had a lot of sort of unnecessary
posts
ones that were not really relevant they
just used one of the search terms
so that was the vast majority of the
posts we found
the next was a category where people
were using gender and from this we could
get sort of two data points that i
mentioned here which are
how they're using gender and also how
they encode or represent gender
and then finally we had a very small
number of posts where people were
actually discussing the use of gender or
sort of high level concepts about that
so first i'll start by discussing some
of the good aspects of what we found on
reddit
first while there was a small amount of
discussion about how to use gender the
advice that people generally received
when they asked about it was inclusive
yeah unfortunately uh the vast majority
of posts on reddit where we observe
gender being used in practice use
uninclusive options the most common uh
representation of gender overwhelmingly
in the post where we could identify a
representation of gender was a binary
representation
additionally
we observed
a variety of uses but the the most
common was for audience demographics
which
again most cases we could not identify
how they were using it just because
these are small code snippets but for
those that we could what we found was it
was most often being used for
advertising or other demographic
purposes
so now i'll move to discuss what we
found uh the interview study
so um there were a lot of things that
just were not covered on reddit because
people weren't talking about them
and so
we
had a broad inclusion criteria uh for
our interview study uh inc so basically
anybody with a year of work experience
in development or a computer science or
programming related degree
um recruitment was conducted on twitter
as well as on the freelancing platform
upwork
about two-thirds of our participants
came from upwork
um
and yeah data was analyzed using
qualitative coding after data collection
was complete
so what did we find in our interviews
perhaps somewhat surprisingly
the plurality of our interviewees
preferred more inclusive options so this
is sort of an example quote when we
asked about
what how they would ask for gender this
person stated that they would ask for it
using a text entry and sort of giving
people that free form option
as with reddit the most common use case
that people cited was audience
demographics again this sort of suggests
some sort of advertising purpose rather
than uh gender being used for some
centrally important task
moving forward um
another thing we noticed in our
interviews was that most developers as
you might expect we're not really
familiar with the topic area
so questions often had to be repeated or
reiterated or explained in more detail
one interviewee
and as i conclude discussing this study
i want to point out one interview e we
had
was specially recruited because they had
worked previously on a platform for
trans-identifying individuals
so this person
so the platform did not actually
represent gender directly rather they
allowed people to
represent their identity using tags on
posts and create community that way and
i think this is for social media
platforms and things like that probably
a better option than asking for gender
so to conclude i want to summarize some
key takeaways here first while we saw
positive signs especially in our
interviews um
i think that more direct
standards need to be set on how people
collect gender data in order to
make it uh make software more accessible
for everyone
additionally software should accommodate
people who
cannot provide their gender for privacy
reasons or
have genders which fall outside the
binary
and finally unnecessary collection of
genders should be eliminated as much as
possible
of course it's not always possible to
eliminate gender as something you're
collecting there may be valid reasons
why you need it so
for some quick advice on how to approach
that
keep in mind that gender is a social
construct that can't be
encapsulated into a single boolean
the purpose should be clear to people so
if there's a financial or legal reason
which you need to collect gender data
providing to that providing that to
people will give much more clarity on
how they should approach the form
and finally the software should
accommodate people who cannot provide
their gender
uh
oh excuse me the software should
accommodate people who need to change
their gender over time
either for
reasons
such as transitioning or because
their gender identity changes
and finally if you take nothing else
away from this talk
if your gender option is only male or
female you're doing it wrong