so welcome to this session on privacy
threat modeling i'm really excited to
kick us off
with this talk on the privacy threat
taxonomy that we've been developing
so let's start off with the privacy risk
equation because it's a great lens
through which we can conceptualize
privacy threat modeling privacy risks
are a function of privacy threats
vulnerabilities and consequences where
privacy vulnerabilities are flaws in a
system that can be exploited to cause
privacy harms or consequences privacy
threats are actions or inactions that
exploit privacy vulnerabilities and
privacy consequences are the harms to
individuals that come from the
exploitation of privacy vulnerabilities
and when you want to model and manage
your privacy risk there are a number of
privacy risk models to choose from
there are also models for privacy
consequences and for privacy
vulnerabilities many of them from the
national institute of standards and
technology nist but many of them also
academic solves taxonomy kayla's
objective subjective harms
but when it comes to privacy threats
there's only one model actually
advertised as a privacy threat model the
linden model was presented at pepper
last year actually
we would argue actually that linden is a
crossover model between a vulnerability
model and a threat model because it
focuses on system flaws rather than the
exploitation of those flaws i know
that's a very fine distinction between
the two and linden is also a very high
level model
so the motivation for this work is this
gap in privacy risk modeling around
privacy threat modeling we thought that
there was an opportunity for a more data
driven a more granular model that can be
used to describe privacy attacks the
actual steps that a threat actor goes
through to carry out
something that causes a privacy harm
so what is a privacy attack though
that's not a term that's often used
so we define a privacy attack as actions
or inactions that cause a perceived
privacy harm as defined by solids
taxonomy that do not solely involve
cyber security violations and let's dive
deeper into two of the components of
this definition solves taxonomy and the
cyber security violations
so i'm sure many of you are familiar
with saul's taxonomy it's an ontology
for privacy harms that was developed in
the mid-aughts
it's held up to scrutiny it's used in
many different research contexts and it
divides privacy harms into four
different categories information
collection harms information processing
harms information dissemination harms
and invasions or invasive harms
and what we say in our definition
is that most actions or inactions that
cause a privacy harm are actually
privacy attacks
except those that arrive exclusive that
arise exclusively from cyber security
violations so we're defining our scope
as the yellow bubble not intersected by
the blue bubble so
there are fantastic granular cyber
security threat models that cover the
entire blue bubble
which can be called cyber security
related privacy events or
confidentiality attacks involving
personal information
one example is the mitre attack
framework which is a cyber security
model that our privacy threat taxonomy
is actually based on
and we don't want to duplicate these
cyber security efforts or focus solely
on data breaches because when you start
talking about data breaches as privacy
attacks it just eats your whole threat
model so our focus is on privacy attacks
that do not arise from cyber security
violations but the question can be like
what actually exists in that yellow
scope bubble
we're going to ground ourselves with
three examples
so the first example of a privacy attack
we'll discuss involves re-identification
of health data
which is
very apt after the dp talks that we just
heard
so
the state of washington maintained a
database of patient-level health data
containing almost all hospitalizations
um the data set didn't include names or
addresses
but it included full demographics and
zip codes so a researcher purchased the
data set for 50 bucks and re-identified
it with a 43 success rate
so this attack clearly demonstrates the
solids harm
identification which represents harms
from reduced anonymity
so the next example we'll talk about is
lenovo's superfish and you might say oh
that was a cyber security attack uh wait
a second in this attack lenovo
pre-installed software onto its laptops
that man in the middle packets being
sent in and out of the computer so the
software intercepted all the information
coming in and out over the internet it
decrypted the packets with its key and
it read them so that it could
target ads at the user with invasive
pop-ups
so the two harms from solos taxonomy
demonstrated by this are insecurity and
intrusion
where insecurity because the attack
caused the user's web traffic to be
significantly less secure and intrusion
because the pop-ups intruded onto the
traditionally private domain of your
experience on your device
so the third and final example we'll
talk about today is cambridge analytica
a privacy attack not only on individuals
but on our democracy in the united
states
and it demonstrates the power of
non-cybersecurity attacks of privacy
attacks so in cambridge analytica
data was appropriated a saw of harm from
a personality quiz and used to target
political ads which amount to decisional
interference because they invade on the
political choices the citizens are
making such data were also used during
the election to cause chilling effects
and cause people to actually not vote in
the election which is another form of
decisional interference
where
decisional interference is an invasive
harm and appropriation is an information
dissemination harm
so we use solid taxonomy to classify
these individual privacy attacks based
on their privacy consequences or harms
because they don't arise solely from
cyber security violations so they fit
our definition so they're they cause all
of harms they're not just cyber security
therefore they fit our definition of a
privacy attack but solo's taxonomy is
inherently a privacy consequence model
what we want to do is describe the
components of the attack so that we can
better understand the privacy threats
themselves we're building a privacy
threat model we want to improve privacy
risk management by making it threat
informed targeting mitigation efforts at
the most consequential or likely threats
now unfortunately across
most of the industry right now
privacy risk management is still the
exception not the rule
this room obviously excluded
whereas compliance-oriented privacy
programs are pretty standard um so the
focus is on compliance with rules and
regulations or with policies not on
managing the risks to individuals
so privacy can also take a cyber
security perspective and focus on data
breaches which we discussed which misses
the potential threats like the three
that we just covered which are not data
breaches so we hope that by developing a
threat model that is granular and can be
used to describe privacy attacks that we
can actually change the narrative around
privacy threats the privacy community is
still without a descriptive threat model
or even a kill chain model cyber
security's had the lockheed martin's
cyber kill chain for ages now
we have the fips and privacy impact
assessments we don't have a granular
threat model
which takes me to our work on the
privacy threat taxonomy we're going to
transition now to talking about this
threat model that we are in the process
of developing
just know that you guys are seeing
prototype today you are not seeing a
final product
so what we did was we started with a
data set of known privacy attacks that
occurred in the wild we followed a
methodology from garfinkel and
theophanos paper 44 non-breach privacy
events which down selected from closed
ftc and fcc cases to those that
fulfilled their definition of a
non-breach privacy event which is what
our definition of a privacy attack is
actually based on
i want to note that neither definition
requires malicious intent
or any action whatsoever benign intent
and inaction can be a privacy attack if
it causes a privacy harm
so we looked at all the ftc and fcc
cases between 2000 and 2022 and we found
that 146 involved privacy attacks based
on our definition now we cataloged these
attacks with metadata such as how many
individuals were harmed and what data
were involved
and we used them to generate two
prototypes so the privacy threat
taxonomy
is a privacy threat model it is a
hierarchical ontology that describes the
components of a privacy attack
the privacy threat clusters are groups
of attacks from our data set that share
similar attack components
is a typology of privacy attacks
and each privacy threat cluster will
have an associated privacy threat
pattern so now we've got a taxonomy
clusters and patterns um the privacy
threat patterns are generic kill chains
that describe the type of attacks within
a cluster
so the pattern was developed the
patterns are developed by taking
a privacy threat cluster
mapping it to the privacy threat
taxonomy and then taking the results of
that mapping and assembling it into a
linear or semi-linear kill chain so
basically clusters can be mapped to the
taxonomy and that mapping creates a
privacy threat pattern
which are similar to design patterns
all this is going to make more sense in
a moment when we go through an example i
just wanted you to understand the
interoperability of the two
prototypes and how they relate to the
privacy threat patterns
so
structuring was our first research
effort to develop the privacy threat
taxonomy
so what we did first is we broke the
attacks into individual threat actions
taken by the potential threat actor or
the potentially threatening system
next we grouped the threat actions into
domains of similar activities
so that looks like this an activity is a
group of threat actions and here we see
the collection activity and the exposure
threat action which is under the sharing
activity
it's a hierarchy
so next we begin refining the threat
actions and activities so that there
would be few overlaps and gaps between
them in the model so this involved
taking individual attacks from our data
set and mapping them to the taxonomy
identifying where the taxonomy could not
and could capture the nuances of the
attack this is a process we're still
engaged in it's quite difficult
the taxonomy doesn't yet fit all attacks
easily
and identifying how to resolve gaps and
overlaps and what things actually belong
in the model for example does data bias
belong in a privacy model
we're also facing the challenge of how
to clearly and concisely name the threat
actions which is no small feat on its
own
so we will continue this process of
mapping individual attacks to the
taxonomy until it stabilizes
and few to no changes occur when we map
each new attack iteratively against the
taxonomy
so there are 13 activities currently in
the in the privacy threat taxonomy i am
going to read them i know they're small
um
these are the the different activities
that a system or an organization can
take in relation to personal information
and data subjects so from left to right
we've got notice and consent collection
of information insecurity specifically
related to privacy
identification of data quality assurance
not only of data but also data sources
of
different parts of your
cycle model
aggregation and processing oh
manageability of data by the data
subject
sharing use against the data subject
and retention and destruction and
deviations for example deviations from
stated policy
so here are some examples of threat
actions from the collection activity
these describe different potentially
threatening actions that an entity can
take in relation to data collection so
for example data collection can occur
via tracking or by externally
appropriating data collected for another
purpose
or intercepting it like in the lenovo
superfish attack
so our second research effort involved
the clusters and clustering the attacks
in our data set into a typology
so similar to the taxonomy the first
step is to break attacks into the threat
actions
but next instead of you know
categorizing them in a hierarchical
model we took attacks with similar
threat actions and grouped them into
threat clusters
to verify the clusters
sorry i woke up with a frog
we mapped the entire data set to our
cluster types um refining and renaming
our clusters along the way merging them
separating them killing some of them
and so a single attack may map to
multiple clusters based on its
components and its complexity
so once we actually stabilize the
taxonomy which is not yet
we will be able to map each of the
clusters onto the taxonomy identifying
which activities and threat actions
define its generic kill chain
this is going to be we already know a
finicky and tricky process it's not
going to be easily clear which threat
actions and activities are necessary or
optional because there can be many
different types of attacks even within a
cluster
so what we need to do is what we will
find exemplary attacks within the
cluster and we'll select activities and
threat actions that represent these
exemplary attacks trying as best as we
can to have the threat pattern represent
as many attacks and as many exemplary
attacks within a cluster as possible
so after this mapping we're going to
assemble
all of these mappings into threat
patterns the generic kill chains
and this will make more sense we're
going to go through an example
so the example we're going to use is
data de-identification
whoever put us after the dp group is uh
pretty good
so here's what it looks like mapped onto
the taxonomy so sometimes an activity is
selected and sometimes a threat action
within the activity is selected so when
an activity is selected it means that
it's essential
to the pattern or the kill chain of the
attack
but that any threat action within the
activity will do so for example in this
threat pattern there needs to be some
form of generation of a data set some
form of maybe data collection
but how the data are collected is not
important to the pattern what's
essential for this pattern is that the
data are not de-identified properly
so here's what the taxonomy activities
and threat actions look like as a threat
pattern
so the collection identification and
sharing activities do not have
individual threat actions specified so
they appear without any of the gray tile
threat actions
while the quality assurance and
processing activities appear with their
relevant threat actions data not
de-identified and insufficient
de-identification so these threat
actions are what differentiate this
pattern from other patterns
aggregation is a common feature in this
pattern but it's not actually essential
to the kill chain
the the data identification pattern can
actually exist without aggregation
for example one of the attacks in our
data set involves a local news station
which published a woman's full name and
her phone number and the rest of her
contact details on the local news
so here is a chance where
in in
where lack of de-identification
existed without aggregation actually so
it was just a single record that was not
properly de-identified
so you can also map individual attacks
from the data set onto both prototypes
so here are the three threat clusters or
threat patterns associated with the
lenovo superfish attack preemption of
privacy settings insecurity and
behavioral advertising and each of these
will eventually have a privacy threat
pattern
once we're done with the taxonomy
so here's what lenovo's superfish looks
like mapped onto the taxonomy itself so
to give you a better understanding of
the threat actions and how an attack can
be described with the taxonomy we're
going to go through this whole attack
mapping
so you can see here that lenovo provided
neither notice nor consent any consent
mechanism for users to understand and
agree with the monitoring and the
pop-ups
the collection occurred via intercepting
information
lenovo caused privacy related insecurity
through insufficient encryption and
digital certificates and undermining
authentication
they identified the users using
persistent identifiers there was no way
for users to manage their own data or
settings because the controls completely
bypassed the user
personally identifiable information was
aggregated with web browsing history
which is sensitive information
and finally the data collected were used
to actually intrude on the user's web
experience via invasive pop-ups
so
we hope that the categorization and the
naming of different threat actions
and activities allows for a better
understanding of privacy threats
and we hope that it facilitates
discussion about privacy attacks
that's the goal
so we want to create both a method for
talking about privacy and a way to model
privacy threats we've seen that similar
models for cyber security threats have
done both
and we see the dramatic benefits in
cyber security from each
they're already on to threat informed
cyber security defense we want to get to
threat informed privacy defense
so next i'm going to talk a little bit
about how the privacy threat taxonomy
and clusters can be used and our next
steps
so to use the taxonomy for threat
modeling you can do one of two things
you can assemble a data set of attacks
associated with similar technologies and
map those onto the taxonomy
or you can map the system itself to the
taxonomy asking could this action or be
a threat action or an action
for example are you de-identifying
information are you vetting your
information source
you know these could be threat actions
once you've mapped the taxonomy you
identify which threat patterns might be
relevant to the system and you disrupt
those patterns with privacy medications
now we plan on developing a web app tool
that will help with these final steps so
all a user will have to do is select the
individual threat actions on the
taxonomy and it will pre-populate with
the associated clusters and each cluster
will be will have associated mitigations
so we're going to populate the web app
with all of the different privacy
patterns and what they look like on the
taxonomy and how the taxonomy might get
you to the threat patterns as well as of
course
a whole wiki of all of the definitions
of everything in the taxonomy so you
just select your threat actions the tool
tells you which pattern your system
might be causing and you can disrupt
those patterns with mitigations that
lower the privacy threat could think of
this as a privacy threat assessment
and as an added bonus you'll have a
better understanding of privacy threats
and ways of discussing threats with
management and others using the taxonomy
and clusters terminology
so like other threat models we do hope
that the privacy threat taxonomy will
integrate with privacy risk models and
risk management and
so by analyzing systems and asking could
this action or an action
be a threat to the data subject system
owners and operators will better
understand how vulnerabilities and flaws
can be exploited
privacy threat assessments can become
part of privacy risk management
then system owners and operators can
tailor their mitigation efforts to only
to the vulnerabilities and flaws in
their system that are most likely to be
exploited those with the highest threat
risk and they can do this in a
data-driven way
so
like in cyber security we expect that
threatened foreign privacy defense will
be the next phase of privacy risk
management
so what's up um we're going to finish
the first iteration of the taxonomy
and the threat pattern generation we're
generating a new data set not fdc and
fcc cases but out of news publications
we are going to map that new data set to
our prototypes and we are going to
adjust and stabilize them with this new
data set of not just things that
actually violate the law in the united
states but things that cause privacy
harm outside of things that violate the
law
so
we're looking for people to get involved
we're looking for data sets or
information about privacy attacks we're
looking for partners to beta test and we
are looking for experts to give feedback
on the taxonomy and the clusters
and we're inviting everyone to join us
at the privacy threat modeling workshop
at soups this this august in boston
so please go to our
workshop website and register for soups
and register for our workshop where we
will be diving really deep into this
work and into linden the other privacy
threat model as well as hearing some
really interesting papers presented
so thank you guys all very much