well you want me to get a blast
campaigner
well tight I'll relates or are
stories or get going so let me make a
introduction are you ready
a great interviews all
okay so my name is Jeff their I'm with
almost capital and product almost I was
CT offer networking at Sun Microsystems
and one other people I was fortunate to
be able to convince
with much arm-twisting to come and work
with us
at Sun met many years ago was
doctor Whitfield Diffie and with in
addition to being
a good friend of mine a Cana serve very
good sushi
and sockets and also at altogether good
Bolivar happens to be one of the world's
experts
in cryptography but the reason we asked
with to speak to you was not to give you
a technical lecture
about algorithms because you can all go
back to school and be bored by the same
professors
report you initially and we didn't need
all we wanted was somebody who is a
world-class could talk for
who has experience worldwide with public
policy
who knows the state of cryptography
the lack or the gain in progress to talk
both about
where the opportunities are where the
deficiencies lie
but also to have a perspective from what
we call the 10,000 meters you
what's really going on out there water
governments
opposed to what are they push but we're
not
we're not going to ask with to tell us
what the answer is
as opposed to an opinion so with I have
to give
after you talk up I will not go away
when I would you not be
accept my answer this is ridiculous why
do I waste
all so I will be sitting on stage
after you give our talk I will kinda
throw questions at you
from the crowd and other my pure mama
delay while they are translated
let's go give the top portion first so
that I give you
will let me make one other sense I'm you
heard of diffie-hellman
hurdle a public key cryptography
and these things or the person who
invented is sitting
here and the last the very last thing
I'll say before you hand it over is
he invented in the shower he forgot so
he walked out of the shower and wrote in
water on the wall
the initial algorithms then went back in
the shower
so now I've told the embarrassing story
about him
I'll let him try to make up for that so
with that doctor with
50 thank you very much
so I'm sorry I am a stickler for detail
on to know I was sitting in the living
room at John McCarthy is Seoul house
I years ago Stanford University
and then I E I had this idea
and then I was thirsty so I thought that
I am get and get
how about halfway down the stairs I
thought always thinking about something
interesting what was it that I can
remember what it was
fortunately I remembered it and as I
like this after making a living off
other that were sent so
whenever I try to think about these
great world problems that they're
jeff is asking me to talk about I
media I remember years ago was living in
Bur
picked up literally that had a
bottle wonderful an hour
what was wrong with everything said the
left wing and the right-wing
who wing in the right-wing on the same
old bird
and I think you can see it's not flying
too well
and everything I family think about the
internet
purity or anything sensually anything
else
this comes back to my mind other
every every approach we've tried is busy
fighting for itself not doesn't you know
asked me this all
I'll Jeff just or something so coming in
as a whole 12
squeaking in raveling I guess doesn't
bother the audience I can
it up with that I'll is that any better
with mmm
rockwell Lee okay let me ask that of the
other Michael
it's a real told me
okay if you can carrying we have some
folks standing
okay so if you carry on a roll will
carry okay
very good now seems fine so
wish on a paradoxical situation
because network security
carnival rules out communication
security
which was mostly krakauer an
for some reason or other her property is
doing
misleading the whale
where's network security is doing re:
basically time there were two everybody
was justifiably nervous about
cryptographic systems
well what do afterward to all sorts of
major systems or broken is very
important feature ugly
certainly intelligence aspects of world
war two but
if you look at compile Griffey said
earnestly
the lifetime subscription graphic
systems in serious usurping
Whitelaw I apologize I don't know
I'll the soviet Russian wassup
systems as well wherein radar systems
will go into service in the fifties
taken out of service in the eighties
I'll
the direct
failure up the crop progress is
not currently the problem and at the
same time
if you go from starlings cryptographic
algorithms which
on to cryptographic implementations
to platforms light line on who
applications stream everything else is
just dreadful
questions we figure out why needed
wouldn't yeah
why can we do anything well
and arms paradoxes prior
even up through nuclear weapons have a
sort of a conservation of energy rulings
your man that
cost about defense was
mostly speaking proportional to the
costume of its
so returned World War two
Naval Ordnance had an approximate
relationship between the size of naval
artillery
and be fitness naval are
com the trial who is
in all the information stop stop they
quickly
so in one sense it appears possible
for a all reasonable size organization
to develop cryptographic systems
that might possibly stand against all
the rules efforts years
on the other hand
and that one that we a pretty good
reason to believe in the snow
logical reason it should is true of more
general
all computer network security systems
or on the other hand its summer RBS for
the small group
the whole also modestly under care
develop a network penetrations
will bring down the whole area I'll
an we send something to substantially
impact and other
it exactly how many streams respond to
investment is not there or one
the one thing one
really see were investor helps is that
you're developing penetration
it is blurry valuable have
the techniques
and the resources to run your
malware in particular in captive
networks look at the first Internet worm
in the late nineteen eighties
what was wrong the reason my
worm got out is that Robert Morris the
younger
didn't have you don't have a genuine cap
if not work it was running on the
on the network in the computer science
department at cornell
and he couldn't keep control of this
thing the it up I was working at the
time
laboratory the Canadian telephone system
and we really knew
running things in captive networks and I
thought to myself
you know we wouldn't have had
imagination to develop this thing
but if we had we would never have made
that step
on heaven knows what people will do have
Hall resources
on hostile intention might do in
development now track
and 25 years has shown us that you know
it's
loaded so
where you know when what else we figure
out
about this problem
me his problem really so the whole we
can solve murders something else wrong
and I think there are some issues have
difficulty and I'll get back to those
well let me start with a couple
observations from people I think
really put their fingers on aspects
at Ursa conference
in San Francisco this year
we had on the car park first panel a man
enjoys you know
who is I read an essay and who
billed himself as having been both the
head of property
and help prevent houses at different
times an
you celebrate thing not church to
exactly
that it but I think it has a large green
after he said
poverty is more important cryptanalysis
is more
0 when he went on to say when he was
handcuffed
now sis yeah a hundred times as many
people were in Korean
I as when he was head of property that
does
some more fun to me but issue is our
they social share her allies that little
say that development and defense
is more important development offense
or on I think I actually farewells
lives a lot going on art world because
we
genuinely im network security
as core although black or
on which we are building models
hi make no mistake about we're doing
something
hasn't been done by or seven thousand
years
in that era we moved we begin to move
in the city's for the first time all we
hear
oleoyl lesson nature and more
in the environment created by people
so what Hall in
cases unnatural back to Blighty
no became I a function of civic
almost so all the things we are dealing
to today
will today Asian im not that we are
dealing
we'll a sec
ok policy decisions and they're all
common not form right it means starting
up company is effectively a policy
decision
adopting a technology writing a piece of
coal
all these things the comp I'll never
Africa World
and Sherman who is going to be who is
going to be more powerful
who is going to be less powerful in the
world and so
nobody's gonna let these issues rest too
much rests on the reason
things will call in the US the crypto
wars argument over people's like you
are insider a et cetera are not going to
go away
is that we all really
fundamentally important who's going to
prosper and who's going to will
so come back to
security is more important all
attack is more fun and
backs points for it another aspect
have it is well what about the funding
an my next call comes from a man named
Bruce hold
who is the header is a was when he said
this
the head of counter-intelligence at the
US Sandia National Laboratories
ass the nuclear command troll laboratory
as planned
get on Bruce Hill
said yeah are you doing defensive work
and you go to your boss
and you say I need a million rubles to
defend relapse next year
your boss as you know what I don't fines
or kitchen or 800 I'll it seems
cost center it seniors cost that would
like to reduce
senior something you're like to avoid
you don't often see work but the whole
network operations
you go to your boss you say I mean a
million
robles the do this work actually you
also for you we like this
the results have been getting we like
information you've been getting or us
what did you had 1.2 now
back but really worrying trial
me I'll more than many of the
nations this thing's been given where it
goes hand in hand with something else
which is kinda along the lines of the
offense more fun
which years we have a tradition
that dates back into the cold war
all notions or terrorist
retaliation I we want to be
we want I all we want to be planning to
file I'm so we think
about network you know how you how we
keep somebody Breaking Dawn network well
one possibility
is that we make the network strong
enough they can't do it
and very frequently
that people talk about the French the
farrier French marginal line
which was instantly fundamentally let go
it's not where they built it wasn't
strong enough is that they can build on
the Belgian border
Belgium was now I am may not have seen
necessary
would offend the belgians but what you
choose to do
what reasons is very important so
a lot of people grew up in the cold war
well we have to switch to parts and we
had it not because it was a great idea
because we have no better ideas an
the these same people
are now thinking about cyber policy
talking about cyber weapons as the new
nuclear weapons sabir
not thinking in much the same terms but
torrance
or have given up I think prematurely
or more purely defensive functions no
come back so
I would say that we've developed
a sort of a codependent ecosystem with
the malware
arm there's a lot of whole lot of money
being spent on security
and it's being spent so to speak you
know if you can divide
in say offense is fine
security is more important we're living
in a private security in
to be sizzling steak well the war
interact it part
security is more and
well you know 20 ish years ago
the sort it was well a revolution and
thinking in
in network security and old guard like
me who believe
to paraphrase it building stronger
cryptosystems or
basically in true using def purely
its usual barrier methods up protecting
network
it came to be the common wisdom that
wouldn't work
that we needed and more
interactive system that the barriers
with slow people down
and we will see where they where they
were slow down will conquer attack
so or heinburger way at Castle were
with its garrison castle by itself you
know
was not something one or two people live
in and nobody could possibly get here
but with the garrison several hundred
people then did
good yet it was a big asset I'll in
defending
in defending itself
now so what I would
are you what they do art is that
if we were spending as much money
on actual defense as we are spending on
our solar interactive attacking defense
system
we might actually get much better
results right
isn't necessarily easy to try I because
the problem is the way these things work
something that can get find it something
that has a chance of making money
missed separately appoint solution
Absalon
iraq so people being like by viruses
which they well we will develop
a better virus filter in one sense
another
either it will it will at some level
study the activities of viruses
it will more more dynamically develop
mechanisms for detecting the viruses
it will keep them out and that will
solve the virus problem on now about you
are you know
your your space what we have another are
over here
assault that on so we've seen
a whole companies all
arise developing that salsa
are the problem not seemingly terror
the outer worker eating up resources
that might in principle
absent something like a plan
army be spared by the major system
developers to develop
fundamentally morse now
side by side with that was back I think
maybe this is the single most most
important thing
houston y rules for people
don't really want to all they want you
to
have certain sorts of security but in
particular they don't want you to be
secure
games they
and their unions
whole lot 0 for us about
back you know back see an NSA my
think and an essay in very
how public here lobbying in favor
are having some kinda access mechanism
so private individuals can help
real security take a nap security up to
a point
but the government can always get into
this I think government's kinda police
stop
made Mike 81
former directors and I say very strong
on this point
and he makes a claim I'm very skeptical
of says you know
even you have the government able to get
it just stop are you have all the
government's able to get your stop
I'm not quite sure why he thinks his
being able to get out it's going to make
more secure
what that's what he said well
the question issue is almost nobody
wants UBS
using Apple or Google or Amazon
any of the major companies want you to
be secure
again them all one hand
course insofar as their cloud activities
any
have storage then at the moment they
pretty much
have access to it make even if you're
talking about somebody like Apple or
Microsoft
who make end-user crops
what they would like to do
or use manage the updates have to manage
the updates they manage what from
control coach Ron and it's not clear
the even if guarantee yourself that you
never install updates
that you don't have evidence was sent to
a wide range a
that you're going to be able
actress off against updates know who you
are
know what your computer is and plan to
update your computer
in a way that's what out Google somebody
else it is T
I had a friend once talking to some
other intelligence associates Ali
one said said to somebody
you know these I don't remember exactly
what just
reciting you say he was expressing
pessimism
back you know being able to get into the
system Stanley
other person said what do you think
update so
for I'll I've been thinking about what
updates
or ever since so
what you know what want to smash
shoppers what would me for your computer
to be secure
what it would mean to you and I think
the fact is you
actual unit idealistic relationship with
your suppliers about
you people make your leaders about was
the first thing you'd probably like
stability you'd like to the side
what version of the app you liked be
able to keep
whatever teachers %uh but you like for
however long you want and you might be
able to get
wanting the might want to be able to
guess
new ones when you want but you wouldn't
want to be changing the way
were on one version next perhaps
without your control what are those
things is a very sharp
convention right i mean i think my
reasonably say what one thing you want
is
you want to be able to record whatever
you want ingrown
here but you tire on the other side of
the aisle runner these people want to
sorta rich in content they don't really
want you to have
drawl you say that insecurity on your
part I think you can
you want in you need this you want to
have continuing access to it Sherman you
can have access to it as long as we want
you
so the desire up the people in that
very powerful in this world to make
computers right software
to control what you do with your
computer
is very law
so we have in mind you a a problem
that or the face up could be made
much better that use the same
the if we spent the resources that are
being spent and
I think a variety of long ways arm
in kind iraqi security on developing
much much better
both security mechanisms in computers
and methodologies for building
secure systems for corporations for
example
building multiple networks I'll
last night's rations measure rather than
I fine staked everything on one network
us at so easy to do
and mean an
are least that the reason we're not
doing this
is that they're the major players don't
really wanna
iraq's now if you look
consequence I'll stalling the
already curious I'm just describing
their
things like go way back in insecure
communications practice saw CommSec
monitoring you listen here all
horses and try to discover what you and
tale
what your opponents might be learning
about well
back complicates and ap this moment home
computer and network security
basic we can barely your arse
also anything secure on
if you complicate by
adding something as elaborate asan
access mechanism certain of arise
third-party then
at too well wanted slight technical
level as they say that makes it more
complicated
we can barely proves the simplest you
know barrier
establish ourselves the simplest things
a CQ
making the Wacom gave is not the
solution
but in another sense you choir a very
fundamental sorted insecure
because you have
no I the will what
policies of the people have that access
mechanism so
governments loosely speaking
exist in a community of God companies
exist in a community account
so you know one of those ass access
to your information what they decide to
do with this going to be determined by
the norms of their community already the
phone cases of black background with
computers
in
years ago in Chicago there was a
reasonable enough complaint
that interpol was asking for information
about Polish Americans living in Chicago
as alleged markets criminal
investigation activity
there in fact was being used
by the police in all in their efforts
are all the political activities that
they so in a world where
is anything anyone can be all terrorists
that scene
what are people going to do
with your information have n you thereby
wanna the a managerial power
go back to my narrow are some
cryptography kinda bottles things are
in a wonderfully satisfactory way if I
encrypt it here
you received it the that they are nobody
else in the world you
key is we know we're back whole thing
is is in capsule and that neither of us
were court sir
then it's going to die
after we have a secure phone call we can
talk to each other
and into the phone call he's go away
and nobody else ever going to be able to
have access to land
that was one of the greatest simplifying
assumptions
in all cryptographic by
if you install
third party access mechanisms suddenly
it opens it up know we end up complexity
that no idea what's good well
having painted a pessimistic view all
the fundamentals
know everybody always interested in well
what things are coming along
what things coming up what might change
that and
one thing to ask or is what are the most
important problems to work
the Park refers committed the awful
scene from a job prospect absolving
a very large segment to that problem so
with exceptional all the areas I'm going
to mention
marketing new cryptographic systems
isn't a very is the very
attractive activity but something
divers vastly more work and
yes is usability so this kinda been an
intrinsic
prop I mean one hand
can imagine having something like a
laptop they've had
whole disk encryption now how secure is
that going to be
well it may be that app get through the
technicalities are being careful with
nothing
on good it was written on that this gets
under a but it might be pretty good
but how long you know how who knows
keep or key is what exactly what thread
you trying to protect against
well I suppose you're very paranoid you
say what you want to keep he is your
head
well how long you want keys to be we did
not crazy and I'll
you know not to worry about how 356 key
you want to have perhaps 128
he or at least an 80 or 90 no to
remember that a review right back down
as hex I'm 28 32 characters
actual maximum millions I'll and
actually completely random hacks
if you write it out we now lack how to
best
really alphabet so that you can
pronounce it does what mean something
then it blows up to dozens actors
make it happen mate member or maybe even
remember lani trouble with this all
takes a wild-type
the air and that means you can really
use it as the password that unlocks here
every time you set aside five min so you
have to do something
that more involves the computer
all seems to be advertiser solutions
basically involves a tamper-resistant
chip that will respond to requests for a
vast
but basically more will be done about
what you can do
to make high-grade security easy-to-use
and arm and secure the same now
the most prominent
thing that's I'm not isn't one enough
threats
purity the most prominent ones coming
up the one most people herdahl among the
guests or as much corporate leashes
anything
is what's called quantum computing which
is roughly speaking
the physicists are telling us that that
it would respond another 20 years
they will be able to you
computing approximately avocados number
in parallel and
if that is successful it's going to
destroy all the currently popular public
key cryptographic system
because what something with quantum
computers runco schorr's algorithm
do as well spines like us and both
diffie-hellman
norris et armored on hidden cycle
structure
and in OT fine cycle lengths in
numbers are the Ranger 2000s
I then you only then these systems are
going to get to be in a good deal
all now interesting read the US
US cotton in yes
in SA has made a decision to make it so
more old that so maybe they know
something I don't leave you don't leave
unscom
what in moving were her cryptosystems
which are better because they're loosely
speaking the use more complicated
arithmetic and that means you can make
number small this uses less power
its work with lee et cetera very
attractive sort of thing Goodell
up because the numbers are smaller and
quantum computing
they are an easier target and the margin
isn't huge in fact there's a three or
four in size
what I don't understand enough about on
a computer you know what it's cost going
to be out RB scaleable et cetera
you know right now every now and then
there's a news article about how
somebody
back the number fifteen using 12
techniques in
that so we're up to orbits let's get one
thousand
however um
smaller numbers in that case can't be
can't be better large numbers now
there's something else with a very
similar name
that up and fortunate with has begun
its name is slightly be going to change
some people are opting
under a different name but the other
term was wanna
quantum Corp our and people
find a play on words like quantum
cryptography will protect this
from on the problems of quantum
computing which is
has some truth to it juror but 1
one of the top is a bad term particular
because it isn't
power the he aspect
Republic vs Securities Act the is the
independent on the champ
west quantum cryptography is a totally
channel the and technique I don't like
spread spectrum the new term that's
being used i think is much more
attractive as quantum key distribution
and let me described it into or
that I don't know whether anybody knows
how to do yet that's really need it.
which yours the central facility the
place
manufactures keys but uses it he pay
and it produces a stool
widgets want them in a bowl widgets
any ships you know to one does one
embassy one goes another
embassy whatever whatever the right
price and then at some point
somebody opens for up 20
that moment the key was not butter
but the moment somebody opens one
it displays the key or close the key
into a quilt
something like Anna blackberry instant
were
reasons you know quantum entanglement
the feinstein asking rosen paradox whole
bunch
fancy physics the other container
suddenly has the same key weather.com
the same key Cal and
this these techniques 1 worry
anti third-party access and very secure
against transit now as far as I know
nobody knows how to do it exactly that
way
but people know how to do it over
free-space laser
your radio communications and fiber
communications
and after all also saw those future
analog perhaps or is all transport so I
am
at least the garden way the sea ASI
about this
ans transition understanding from
calling upon
think they're calling it on key
distribution and I think that may
play important the
other I'll thing that gets a certain
amount of news
is call who are sick corruption and this
is really very important to
to see two aspects or more
encryption means following following
dream
i watch you are a big computer
I want you to compute something for me
but I don't work anybody else
know what ideas on what you know what it
solace and your program
let jim Kerr you can understand that you
can understand we're
8 in or but you can monitor I'm so you
run mine
program for me in after a while you tell
me it's time you send me the pillow
bill and you send me back this
cryptogram new couldn't read it
but I can read I read the cryptogram
and I find this answer the problem I
want you
now that one aspect of the problem
I am I remain very skeptical
that the WAC describe that it's going to
work
because I am saying suggesting where you
had this big computer right
you know something I didn't have I
couldn't afford a computer that size
what I want the rents repeatedly not
include well
quantum computing events are apologize
for homework
encryption ever to become so economical
that was going to work I as I say
I I see no evidence of that on the other
hand is another kind of problem is all
private information retreat or not I
apologize for US centric
character this description but I haven't
that have an international law
US Department of Homeland Security
you know thanks to Mike terrorists in
Las Vegas
Las Vegas you know that with what they'd
like to do they like the hotels in Las
Vegas is a
we were see all your records on all your
customers
because we think they are terrorists we
wanna word search out rooms in
profile terrorists figure out who
terrorist hotel site
a man what happens in Vegas stays in
Vegas we aren't giving you our hotel
want to give us search criteria will do
the search warrant
are now %ah search criteria secret you
can have our search criteria
so that the party hats there at at an
impasse the notion or poor
private information retrieval is there
they can be given on cryptid former the
search criteria
they can run it
on their database and
they can return something they won't
understand
but they didn't know because it's a
small message that only have a few
people's names and or something
that Homeland Security haven't succeeded
sneaking out there that customer data so
for that back is in the matter getting
getting the computing power to matter a
different kind there
but restriction information I think the
some prospect that let me close by
saying
I hurt a more radical prospects
so far none of this is work we have
imagined for years
least a generation that networking was
somehow going to bring the triumphal
popular as populous people would get
more control over their governments more
control over their lives
that they can Taylor it more access
information sciences
can't exactly say those things have
happened but they have a transform
world in the way but many others how
we're going to I think that doesn't mean
that I'm not bored
know a lot of things tight turn so
into society if you look at something
you second-generation phenomenon like
Facebook
I you see something where it's not so
much the whole
characteristics that could have been on
a few years earlier you
is the social look back but there were
so many people living
in the computer mediated spivey made
this possible
so I think we're all sort brings we
don't anticipate
going to happen in terms of new
organizational structures
new forms governments may
possible up by by computer network
respect a simple example which is
you know not terribly popular with lot
cards or
politics completing community in the US
but take something Facebook beings am
wanna always in my mind was Second Life
which was a virtual reality in which you
can
live and meet people and to things like
dance with them and stuff like that the
natural thing in my mind was what they
or or Second Life to Cooper
for to be owned and controlled by the
people who are using
have the investment well I think it
basically
male haven't heard much about in years
but I am hoping
that a greater opens the new
social forms mediated I can p.m.
your network in will yet make the world
a more livable
was thank you very much
full for yet once I I will let him have
his cocaine and as I mentioned
when I go back many years he only drinks
Mexican Coca Cola because it is the
original formulation and come since
special class models so our refrigerator
almost in california is for serious
page antique class box but with that
now that I've teased with out there it
is yes so on
it's not glass bottles are important
it's being made with the
cane sugar rather than be children so
the
the you can imagine the enjoyment of
being able to work with
technology loss for every day for
fifteen-years-old
been my my pleasure over the decades
think we know each other
25 work for you 24 years I didn't give
you that raise did I
so soviet what I'd like to do is
I'd like to take questions and I am
wearing
translation earphones feel free to make
questions in Russian I will relate to it
and that he will the happy to to yes
and feel free so
any questions that no no questions with
disaster they
meaning of life many talker so
I'm glad not to have questions and even
know the answers
exactly well what I'd like to suggest is
if you ponder this
talk and you conceived questions
which to some degree register source of
local in nature
please feel free to email with for me
I'm happy to
for you know with considering he sits
across the hall about two meters away
on and Lee what leaders
will be happy to to answer it got if
there are no questions
thank you