group for
or tea door with whom she shared her
I near book was all in all so it was
good each
enabled it possible to go easy online
she did she is a small just the two name
the
ship her on speaker
will shop
good camp
ascent like to talk about terror
a certain thinks and identify some
thoughts and
to our asset let's start with a riddle
it's a magic number one of four
work what do you think what do you think
it means
what does it mean 401
yes issue sweep it over okay its get and
this is the number of days
that Google will allow to remove
vulnerabilities from from this
software identification over
their villages and this is the time line
and and the developer has a
timer to you or to do a patch to update
and search and the user can use it and
%uh so this number actually a
a speeds up to other concomitant
processes makers for example a couple
years ago we had to so than a
number of days that you are to removal
of the problems
some and no one is happy with this
number
so the users said
don't like it day
developers don't like it and because
it's so fast and there's not enough time
or something
the researchers don't like it the
developers don't like it
Sunday and Minnesota being am being a
researcher
also understand it or not for 104 days
is nothing
said very little time now so compared to
you
the time it takes to develop in you
software and the
to regulate doesn't like so then the
regulator
is and say that absolute security is
replaced by
risk security compare comparative
security
certain level of security so they day
day in order to secure will be hacked
but
when she just a matter of time and
they're so then the regulator
SOES is resigning to on to
to that instead the system will
eventually be
pack so down dear as I was saying so
dandy
developers I had acted the regulators
bite the bullet to the researchers are
unhappy
well about the timelines and ask him and
so then the situation is slowly changing
and
so even those who for up
so want who asked for services
so don't happy with the results because
a
usually so there is a around two pillar
so this number on their villages goes
down a
number to but if you study her
the software and an eventual the
situation is
levels of and then you get the
impression
that the number is no changing so what
what they're doing so you invest a lot
of money
it's very time consuming labor-intensive
the disfigure is not improving and this
is kind of this
rule that of hatred to so when the each
hates everyone else which one and
they're so they hate each other
so both the the regulator the user the
researcher the developer and
so then this hatred and hatred their own
turns around and this is what
and so then the new in the last five
years group trying to
figure it out and so than that working
from the company
as a that shit certifies
for its products on the basis of paper
requirements
and there we realize that we need to do
research
practical security and even just a
Assoc talk about the importance of
regulators
because there's paper a regulations that
are important to learn this
and and it and that's related to the
pressure for security
some say summer approach her
dry summer approaches going around so
that people in
wearing their caught some Thai
and so there are people wearing T-shirts
and
submit so wanna talk about on their
ability so why
way the algorithm so because there's the
idea that has been formalized towards
the mission systems
and then eventually and campaigns
a certain thing said that were part are
or something written on paper was in the
head to the person who developed
and I think that's so this could this
this components should not
that BP that against each other so the
need to complement each other
to pieces synergetic a for the sake and
for the sake of the developers and all
stakeholders and the regulators and the
user's
to and so that would comply
with the requirements home the regulator
show that mean
say a few words about myself and
what loved it was studying how it's been
going on
and what mistakes we have made and
some I go back her
long way concerning IT security
and so we hear are parked over in for
tax
group of companies and so we've been
that way over the last five years so we
we work long syringe attacks so this is
over complicate cryptosystems his other
components is so we
for example so we will protect so the
and the Russian Railways her her tickets
so than other things we write to the
Colts
with developing the software Anderson
works pretty well
and actually we performed pretty well
so about five years ago and we've got
the impression that their sizes
functional requirements
that would should be complying to the
crime so the regulator we should have
concerned also
Paso the functional characteristics of
the products or start it
with efficiency so then we're trying to
get to the Gigabyte
to speed and we're catching up for some
together because they were
market went far ahead at that time so we
have got caught up with them in to
develop new approaches
out to complement testing Mathis
functional tests
out like this
different tests user experience this is
and
car and %uh so we're we just increased
our efficiency now so then we calculated
the area since entering the next test
for
logical step so would be to concern
ourselves with security or solutions
it was very important and that was
elated
just and to the factor that to this
the publication about vulnerabilities
started to
seep into the pages the mass media and
Sun people were confused so what to do
with that nickel slots on their
abilities
securities none dares than and people
were confused
missus its certified but at the same
time is
it's around around the world or so under
abacha's
something to be used protection efforts
need to be
implement and a service Howard to mold
and %uh so the key points
that we and 2012 fun
sup 2012 so now just we had
in so where concerning ourselves with
the issue or
secure development so that took him bad
security
hinder development group so then the
Monitoring Centre so this what we are
will launch in 2014 monitoring centers
alarms
him on his door so when when it or the
development effort to are developers
software
to make it to congenitally secure
from Linda so what are we talking about
them
ham first so the first idea
I don't want to talk about how we war
packing sir SNR
two factions so some of them no matter
how to attack broader than me and some
others are not interested
how to hack broke so cuz have their own
people who know how to hack
so but we with the help of different
methods
famous means so we organized
sir efforts how to increase the security
of the products
this massive so I think it was found
very important point
which allows to give more value from
research
and justified for business purposes
for the developers and
in Prosser someplace got good results
sometimes negative positive experience
an experience
was welcome and her and then
so we're just or followed sustainable
fashion so that contribute to the cycle
of
security enhancement as and when it
understand where
so that the developers a big systems
within bad security so companies
Saunders IT systems business pros
lacking at the company's so than 90
security issues hard
very pertinent so the IT security
use 100 call product sample and
people's for are excited
and company has been participants of
different
important so how Asian friends
invited us and was the best Russian
conferences
written in the russian with lots of
criminalistics
Sanders they tried to to distribute
viruses to
get so to answer does my wrists and to
alright
system so this is the something
is high indigent him
so we have a lot of information %um
and the product that will develop hits
it's up and running yes it can get the
remote access to our programs
and that's all great interest because
it's a
knowledge the people a SOHO
attack two sisters now so that's
complex broad so with the life cycle
which consists of number components
so the product
needs to be certified came to the
conclusion was
the product acquires a
so certain the low-interest IT security
starting from
development requirements certification
design development testing the way so
when you
stop to reading this system when you
remove it
discontinued and
so all the way
to the and life cycle so when you
so when you destroy the system
should and there we decided to for
to learn to see what can experience
exists in the market
so what is the secure development or
product
stance to apply
what's written here to the extent
Wonderstone
so that they will look at different
domains so there's a
stages secure the room when it ordered
and responding responding I'm
the longer religious and life cycle
dan's then
everything that has has to do people
technology
business pros all this come for mister
put it together and make it go oldest
back so we realized that we need to do
it
im and to follow police points I
so it was thought with them
so we started with man you might call it
started with the following
as my colleagues were saying does
developing organizations developers
researchers India security issues so we
started with ourselves
so with the hearted security
Security Auditor all their systems
because we are all around our country
russia's rock what information are
stored
within our systems and if you streamline
did
then service to ridiculous so you can
can think past for a number of attacks
so that that could be launched against
us
against decline
viewers sewer system against us
shop via us Center used
and so we look at everything we're here
so this is quite interesting and juicy
or guys for the best guys and so this is
a
technological companies so developing
centers distributed
dick that's what we're here so many
things
and angolan change shuffled all the time
so all the resources are administered by
developers
up programming years
virtual machine settings he's the
ultimate authority
and the same gesture of
India as a supporter Department
so they can outsource thinks become more
vulnerable
but when we talk about this security
it's
protections it means that you have to
work with Health Sciences
software not in the house software
compatibility test so there's and
so then this product is so great
interest
and it now it can be
we have headed summer college
have been instances when when they tried
to attack him to hack
am Santos to still do materials to
develop materials
quite quite interesting so answered
means that the developer is an
interesting target averaged
issues what if you hear what the
regulator
says it's a good solution for
for hacking in a sauna attacker so very
much changed
specialized tarde attacks target
her attempts to hack to the information
systems that bespeaks
bespeaks the importance our system and
its
and its its wealth
and absolute example away
can get together with net and and
distributed so there was a similar story
character her risen there was a
publication
some companies Richard pastor Troy on
her viruses for three years to
was okay so they were so successful
although they were distributing
so story on him bandaged
software and so than results have been
monitoring and
the audit so we can so we decided to
pull the logical to set out for
our own monitoring center so
40 partners for I'll companies
report River companies and we do not
claim
that way courageous and you see him no
what you need when it
answer within our own functionality and
reliability said
sold in a pack as we go so we need to
develop more
more stuff by ourselves and and
and it's not only the analysis
collection and data collection
so we can work and get this more
information from the problems
sources but what's important is to
joint effort ticketing and
synchronization
with client client base as
in-house is would outside companies
following asks identification we've
services public a public software
is year to here's judy
incidents and a life-cycle incidence
node
Sona hai K I'm
finished with general statements
from now so what is this
monitoring center doing size the
standard procedures
analysis night systems monitoring the
orders
else
so than devote their abilities
identification so
we saw that there were a lot of
challenges
public price Crouch challenges at a very
important time
power for way and reliable development
so awesome in this would be the final
store success
to present very popular like
so so control control on the
publication's
homeowner religious in the third party
components
a certain very interesting thing Hazare
hundreds
outside components and OS
analysts and the song glamorous for
Association some third-party comparte
if you don't try two minutes or does
have on their futures which are inherent
after those things again all this
compromise the fraud
final product your product negotiated
and defied
on after the event after the
certification has taken place in there
is difficult to change anything so
and a vulnerability I'm explodes ernest
was too late to taking steps under
too expensive and then the so than
mentioning sir
a half day on the front exit
on the Internet what's good and what's
bad and someone with a mandatory
her notations a mention Inkster
so for example beep net coordinator sold
so what's was deposed most 2.0 selling
the
net a router through
Beatles so unless me know what that is
why should anyone want too much and this
isn't
some work to do so this time so you do
become very popular
people on beginning to buy although the
wounded
and then moving or chew the technology
that technological stack him nothing
just released on the instruments and
methodologies
procedures love you good cast said
because
is there's a long list yep
my mail
Pandora technicals I don't want to go
into it that we can just say that so
there are some static
static announces Monica now since the
phasing
with the old we do want to get
the final stage and for this will
develop
instruments and so what I on it too tell
specifically
his that was the final outcome most
outcome experience
goes to prove that had the best
Department works
and although it has not competence
testing for security
but they do it anyway he adapted the
outlook tests can do the reverse this
some mixer on its on you
versions Holt old mistakes
to to do about them and
so this is what we with take to take it
to the test
Department and then
has we progress so identified
very interesting points is a how what
what not to do
I'm not to research in should what needs
not to be done
or you should not do sewing product
so this software talk about
stand aside and analytical effort to
so when we say but white box truck
testing so you should make passionate
shinri documentation coercive
hacker was no information historic
untrue because the hikers always
read all the manuals hers young Dyson
technicians
this ultimately to face a knock
and it turns out today day
either use catch a problem in different
places or
no or or dip the problem is not the
problem
becomes element be used in general
system
by there is another extreme
and so they made million were mistakes
said Wendy
researchers decides to her expound
his vision on the brother their vision
pros and very the right to the technical
documentation
and it works out and they're not
analytics neither
they are programming engineers and no
one else was going to use the results
this effort should
and in other another dimensions
this problem this coordination those who
ordered
so Commission to that Anderson and
so that many participants many
stakeholders
to the process and so they are after
different test kits
Thursday development manager so the
responsible
1 so this product managers process
managers
there's lots of other things and
so than magnetic fields worship
to always so make sure did there are no
magnetic
storms anyway under so than the process
engineers
you don't discuss all stakeholders and
if you don't have the city team effort
not I'll stick with a severe into steam
so there will be a lot of people on the
head
customers and that to a certain this
that might kill the project
what's this you know was this some mmm
my house this I showed it on a Web
Developers Conference
no one knew what that was up
MCUs with orders that which
it's true that the developers day
they use different instruments and
so that the researchers know spoke about
and the use them in their own way
and a few go back a bit
a look at it. you would do I
are those who developed a compiler so s
so the issue differently completely
different good
child and so the whole for long memory
inserter
Anderson this is where this is this is
the hand of
information security so because they're
not done a
interested in anything else
the same with the programmers society
thing that
so what you are her mmm
what you do should not be done because
it somewhere
tested solution to use instruments and
they say that
everything's fine from the instrument
pointer you're so dont
certainly not concerned and the same
with the management
the same goals them strong diminishment
so the classical management or is it
supposed to do this to do
timely manner deadlines meeting the
budget at center ice and and then
there's a certain amount of
something within for them too much but
prefer
for example so that the the security
requirement is not dear so than any
any attempt orange is iron just to make
this gadget safe
so we'll will fall under the years
sander
on mom on deaf ears and
that's why no one will be concerned
about that if it's not part 2
day for the statement the work persona
resistant to this kind of work
awareness in the same problem there's a
big companies are riddled with this
problem as well
and me land and certainly it's
it exists in the developers community
although they understand at the issue
very well
I'm not again just to go into greater
detail
number to at every stage
and so we have also materials
can learn from it
and so we're a light on the attacking
methodologies public domain lists
everything only to I list them
but very important to blind them her
Hyundai purpose base and a needs basis
so then knowledge so when they're
I'll attach them best practices systems
that a good
for the systems broke in practice so
then the system consists of several
components
for example web applications server
mile platform and certain type occur
scattered around and there's enough for
this car broker configuration there is
no
a house or combine with a village in
there are some gadgets and devices that
are
outside programming efforts and so the
can be connected to a later stage
so there's this methodology to and
so than a good application dismissal
nonchalance to develop methodologies
is very interesting so the methodology
that
alas to guarantee the integrity of the
problem
St the holistic nature the problem
then the so then this so there are some
certain some trailblazers
in dairy farmer the source
secure software development so Microsoft
that so what offer them and Russia ever
tried to
for identify what is it work what
girl to have already covered this on a
small disclaimer so they admit that
because what did publish
Microsoft some kinda reverberation
so long so that they got about 5-10
years ago so managers are moving forward
and
so did publish certain things in there
are some instruments
that the hair about the practice and the
way they build it do an agent and what
mistakes that are made
a so then the something about something
a public domain so the
they played their cars close to be chess
and they're so they're not so developers
for some exotic cases holding out for
fashionable practices
project management they do it to and a
and this is all can be found to for your
which specific case term
can be available
on on this basis
them than concerning
had things two points this to phases
acid a customer requirements and design
Halford so because the requirements on
is to be a good basis
the development but security
requirements the are the
and not existent or ordered a
related to some kind of basic primitive
cases
and they did not see the big picture for
example than
answer is this maturity model logging
system maturities system I to data
management maturities
and a for actual for this seem to occur
passe as desirable for all the
architectural components updated system
is
so than to talk about themselves and do
it properly sold
this practice is exist and my
most favorite case to stand it so when
this
system I was absent in doing this to
is the application on and there was a
presentation conference I love that
sir southern Andes network sniffer
for a flight protocol the system that
developed themselves
so they made the system developed a
system but failed to login system
and to identify its conditions so they
had it and monitoring system
editor for the DPI so they would do the
protocol standard
members nasa research will check around
the condition of the system did they
develop themselves
same so very interesting trip
down or already absence
those who do and the latex so then the
tracing
requirements is very important because
they're interconnect source
requirement there was a server so the
server day
they strengthened it became unfold and a
balanced episode
Dave working servers and then all longus
got to %uh new address is so so so so
everything was balanced there so that
this information went to long's
somebody forgot to change the
requirements
so than
now tracing the requirements issue
it's there it's very important
and is not to you cannot to address it
with the help of research
and started the product and service
development it's truly
so what are the useful
mammoth its approaches as trials
am so that Microsoft to end this
back has details back retried
liked it and we're trying to stir client
possible where's awesome sound there's a
there's a poker planning
and disorder as a mother lost right
model of
threats this country eventuality
availability
spans this issue cancer and then that
too
to widen your conscience the developers
can always think are which components
you need in the workers
hounds happens and especially if your
model
francis your soon architecture how the
flow data that occurs in the system that
would be good to do that as well
if its scale damper in your company
this is great because your hand across
functional military
personnel I send any developer will help
you
to identifies for its and
business sides good business drivers
be Stoppers
Anderson to make sure this process is
useful may be used
so the first point I always come up
against it
so this is generalized experience
talking about suffer certain
return on investment so they're
certainly some tangible results
returns business wants to understand
so to what extent so if you invest
more sources in time and the return will
be bigger
that's on the and comments security West
is not only
money her return a although it's
important but they're talking about it
from the
under viewpoint carver
happened the so the developer and the
the calmness did for so his quite happy
time
and this is this is work day one to what
extent
so then the two respondent the
so to the challenges soon to what extent
they can generate
a serious crisis and for example so
that's my purse or whether through this
some time ago so the same happen here
with us so that security secure secure
development cannot be done from scratch
no one just alone realtor hiring new
people to start a new product lines
those will be the legacy products the
same people
and the need to jam to in into certain
into certain
a her
soapbox and certainly you cannot stop
from a
from time alas I it's impossible that
but you have to work in the index system
context against
existing background the conductor
than so then how to
implement her so security component into
a big company for example
so how how to introduce is how to embed
this security component to make the
entire system security measures
lots different products so we need to
streamline the products
Danny to to face them and
the first face most important
those that can't wait them put them on
the back burner et cetera Financial
chant and and then approach
and then then apply this approach in all
the decision-makers
a so ask them to come out with their
ideas for their viewpoints how it can be
how it should be so how to streamline
the production with projects
and that the first coercion my hand
when they just brought to India vision
how the situations
had us 3 respectable guys %ah
day has a cross-section so the way they
see their lives
and they're so they want and %uh this
the way
images see explains a lot so this is
number one number two number three
and that's how they view it
then you can juxtaposed compare and see
how it works
you would and den worked
options do we have here who could apply
min suffers with it
certain idea need to be developed a and
gold
salon from your pointer value marketer
and development talk about security
security because this
upscale security system the built to
independently some technological a and
to extend
here on the brought to attacks center
so when I just two to build this lineup
from scratch
Anderson and then to to predict it
worked
where it may aunt
and then the initial data initial data
needs to be obtained
they're all the date is wrong and it
turned
so this raw data her temper to him
will not be this not not enough to
sink your teeth into an A and and not
enough to make any conclusions
sound and a model mister B do the agent
separately in the specific case
and information that we have an initial
stage will not be sufficient on the
tentative
than or what blocks
the Diest introduction of
new research in the area of for
security suffering this
some some say some markets expensive for
some argue it's unpredictable some
argue it's impossible to meet the
deadlines for the locker room
take and so some
some argue that there's an absence of a
powerful the yep
Rd holistic nature on their search
who'll be properly done for me to see
and
and ending its own probe spur ability
that
that the research will not draft-day
deal
resemble Anderson and then there's
another challenge that didn't have to do
there they're better for I'd I to read
if
research so me love going back to square
one
and yes when the owners
assistance on this certainly want don't
want to do that onto fashion because
it's scary
and a so the response only once there
there's only one such down to do the
research showed initial stage
so when I saw not so much expense and
so2 good
so for example if they don't dust I'll
so the classical classical problem in
their search doesn't of tail
and Sun Anderson developer
case the user the user Hayes developer
sound and in your thinks
come up and eventually so the new
challenges generator and an
and which and then and then eventually
so this this
start hating each other sonya problems
pop-up older
their son and the people who are all
this is search
so many to to formulate their through
and what about what about
quality sorry cannot detain any good
quality so that the key
the keys demand is said the sustainable
Prosser's are continuous adapt adaptive
adoption
adaptive molter so with the and manage
control characteristics
something so this adaptation should be
on sustainable
all the time and to make sure that the
the
another research should be cheaper so
to design this process so that you can
hi to rate their search and every time
and every next iteration should be
cheaper than the previous one
and they're so that would not provide
for summer radical changes in the ass or
some other product and went on the
compliment
what has been done earlier and to
Assad's
just don't break it down don't smash the
system just a at tinker with it
tinker with it and then then then decide
duration: process won't be
1b session expensive will not be
catastrophe every time to nature
I do some fall off on that as I and then
eventually we came to the conclusion
that
having alliance to the ass and so the
cycle or security development secure
development
and then we need to have our by their
knowledge secure development
cryptography included yes this is true
I'm very challenging because this is
where we
we collect don't know how and
how work and what's the was the ass and
so on research
how it can be adapted offered to the
customer
sour technical guys so with the
development
and how just to put it all together
so this puzzle eventually work out
hatch the and another point
from as taking point my point
and because security is
is it to work and %uh so that was it
any product development so provides for
the
different roles so everyone is
responsible for
she's on her hair and the
or so it's a team effort today it
doesn't work out that way so
should be analysts a whole
analyzes search for with
and so there should be managers
understand and dear area so then
everything will certain to fall into
place and the last thing
so when it's just common ground common
language so looking for
common language and stop talk about
different cases
and they're so then them have on their
ability is
weaknesses and replacement of
imports mmm et cetera how this story
tells us that and it did simplifies
communication you don't have to
to discuss why this on their abilities
dangers
the software and there were so we can
you won't have to give this sir
examples of hacking attacks in center
and decide whether there's no need
because now they're on the same page
understand what they mean
and so we dont I don't have to do that
ABC
from year
the legacy systems developing project to
project
throat the product and shit on and the
customer
and in the course I will not get the
idea the feeling that
they started from scratch because in
your company's
they just you know design you think's
the open up new laws for themselves
discovering your principles
and a happy to share it in the market so
there are three doses good
and for this is all based on on some
a knowledge awareness of one's own
witnesses us logically delineated
them so we are
now involved in this this summer I have
grounds for
optimism and the business in a moment
and follow-up development and
and installation application in practice
and so I I am positive about their
quieter
optimistic what's good what's
what's in it for us and her
so it's a good initiative for
some cost which state standard for the
development of
have SeaTac yes yes it can motivate each
to the research
beforehand it so there were
so then are lower as if they were
starting over the phone their abilities
but it was all segregated
horse a random a but not through the
camera specific lever
and that could be used her to stop
competition
tenders Bates development now because
and for example some
a tender for the development is is a
good things down because it cost
a standard to us because everyone is an
altar and
development means us her
contributing to the security how the
system and
me talk to me dinner a person Hall
understand that
the cats and their products all have so
components of security badder here
depending on the importance of and the
information to the processes
Federal Security Service or dings Rd
for the health system and us about the
standard disgust standard state standard
one
it is released and citing did
this year beginning next year so
expected that will be good lever
to make sure that this works done
properly
logical streamline fashion testing
research study and that could guarantee
the integrity of the system
the as a development stage
and then identity certain
fax so the global monitoring system and
this system is important too you know
the just-completed
circle to make it integral and us how
this is done developed
about separating so the whole life cycle
something at the lab for
can see that we need to build
to destroy and so they're nicer
shit practical security so for
in the is developing at a rapid
Minnesota companies did
specialize in that Olympus no works in
the department's
big corporations but the next challenge
really I get to face these two
to make this effort to knows more
systemic more streamlined
more sustainable logical
saw them bringing and bringing Hamas the
the results searched for so2
so than and to stop talking who hates
home
about to stop talking harm so who can
use
who can help home and to do this synergy
canvas
rather than Anderson featured planes
Canada
hamp
and there are no option except for you
know starting doing something if you
have some questions
on here but here so this is a car
complicated process
that some great old activity but quite
the interesting I hope are you enjoy
my story so my view are
and a I would be ready to answer your
questions
privately I'm around under please
approach me
I'll be happy to talk to you thank you