leahy
to get himself orgy yet so
I'm happy to see you my dear colleagues
my name is Alfonso and today
I'll be speaking English me to speak
with you today
to start ole to or your
experience and you on is your day marked
if you feel inclined piece riser and an
organized your view
so all when you view at their stories
of people or organisation will go barn
tried me trading but I V information up
anyone don't miss I so %um you know he
did
and how many have you have ever
experienced the trial
defection or extortion in this secretive
mark
and I'll meet you expect to face
any of those obstacles in the future
well
is next door dismiss such situations
if four doesn't view never heard such
stories or
everyone it's too I have one sure
genitals fewer
as a pretext of family and he's in the
Phoenix suburb
future niece the causes a manicured
lawns backing
2013 after spending 10 sport this ride
Jonathan was poking around on so one
stumbling through it wouldn't be enough
I US$7 Jonathan
was security career is old enough to
remember where when his colleagues were
exhibits nothing all for it fine talking
for finding gonna be
is the rockies like damage
that's about discovered your friends
because Hill
you can make some extra cash from his
work any you read it
lost he tied days ago with a view to
broker
word about done it since Corey from the
night of chill alt
always in touch with some people inside
the plan is to take
John discovery that y'all likely just
like three
SL is as a package deal unit and yes
up meanwhile another group of us going
to be a nurse
good about to see her in a beauty and
got one million dollar bill
with a different route Chinese man it's
not a friend got in touch with that
window
they could all work together you know
what's after turning down
the biggest get it finished like this
theory out
sliding back door and we erase Jonathan
never thought that once friends tawny to
send him out
when you find out we no tools know what
steps
no court system to protect discovery
John
that use which is to say dat
trading gonna be information or Saturday
spice
is consider restoring your we're seeing
this secret market
0 days face faced some in your and
obstacles
related thanks to steven is trade
commodities tossed
price fairness impossibility to FactSet
ok to put it succinctly
is in the air is this to begin with
when I get information is is it time
sensitive commodities
you're wasting a Sat serious flies are
available on the
when they are not widely known added
value drops instantaneously 20
awesome I as a nasty brunette beauty's
disclose or mitigation
release therefore transactions compete
short time so we do require discretion
or
every day in the last day for is your
day sale
yet in this market reno centralized way
to look at it spares
finding buyers and sellers can be
time-consuming a minute apart market
participants
let business the is with individual are
not familiar with
was retention or are verified
fought him or you even if buyers and
sellers managed to find
each other we'd is legacy you fair price
is something challenging you to a lot
spines I got to level so
winnable component presence between
getting a tux
face level authentication like this by
given immunity
difficulty all independent risk obvious
foetal ABS United
of course all ebony but on on a price
still
these are difficult measure in the
position of the security researcher
starting bloggers by the tension that
exists between them out the information
you're required to disclose and the risk
losing
lacks a property %uh step is for other
information good
proving that the needy ok would it be
information without disclosing it
is up in silencing there are essentially
two approach revealed or demonstrate
and get ball undesirable if this to
reveal something about it reliability
the possibility exists for
the for to buy it to take it we don't
pay for it
embrace their site the buyer pays for
that when the deputy
sell your bike run away with the money
with up supply information goods
demonstrating the buggy all good
will have yet to be honest like is not
any better whether controls the
computing environment
as the Nets overdyed party on the one
ends if the seller spice the computer
environments then the possibility exists
for the same to tamper with it
leaving the buyer in the position to be
enable to verify
its integrity on ya trend the buyer will
be
the position to record to work and it's
like in to see the tax
property if the devastation has to be
clear out on the
buyer devices even worse
the a team will review it claim can be
sure up
learning about given immunity from the
center the other part may claim the same
wanna be.
us their own and sell it or slight
as many trades are internationally
are regulated you becomes are horse
potential conflicts
and finally service may be interested
rock exclusive rights
to their the
to divider in order to receive the
largest be all but
the seller males the facts any the same
intellectual property to multiple
party's stance this time are biased
black
me to protect himself of course
conscious me new
language it forced a security researcher
to
returned upon your return the funds for
the same note on her
the contractual obligation but busy
today markets
the difficulty to identify source to
execute more to
work with people transaction for the
same information good to the same
supplier
it with Force contract at bias
we need to be trade these are also
considered for additional businesses
service
do not at face in order to alleviate
somebody's Argos
it was suggests to use punishment for
escorts to buy from defecting
in the form of public disclosure yes
resort on the use of proper the party's
a special entities or anything operation
market but the stands
essentially charms service all
built a reputation system as an
instrument to establish
process relationship between distrust
years a simple which are
reputation score we find a black markets
today
we've talked about the first results
ongoing study honest or Sony Corporation
this year the market through to Sobe you
know duties for you my see
in process because it's boring I West 38
so you don't at
the questions motivating this research
are can is either the market chief
corporation
agency even not since the process the
party's even
you not since escrow service for
instance game punishment escorts
by from the fact in under which
condition
a player can distort opponents King
corporation be sustained
all sing cunanan citing and what about
seeing an on-site
the talk will address this is not a
question
by providing in tonight's 0 0 day
trading strategies
up the couple which season are you now
YM
interested in this 1
if why you may also be interest as well
I work at the intersection softer
security and security software
exploding inside a contagious is on is
based
the choice of my career was the take my
dream
I deemed it software manufacturers at
the incentive to be a
security to produce I it in the security
researcher
a efficient means to capitalize on the
Fort yesterday analysis
I dreamed it users at any instrument
stretch against information security
risks
US Postal especially dream that
information see mystery
is finally established between buyers
and sellers in the security market
but that's just me get ninety is it that
current economic
regulator you like a lease gives armies
online store
in a factual what we assist today what
we'll certain today
is what Dickens economists call Mr sale
any market peter is about being a
punitive Sat right
software manufacturers no formal shares
sumpter user with no formal features
which translating greater complexity in
greater exit face
and not doctors no forgot that you thano
municipal but system
out member his pocket army chains
I'm on director for funding be wise the
first information security protection
market
is was my contribution towards
establishing their party incentives
wide-eyed didn't success far they're
still immediate
we can improve our globus your foster in
order to understand
the market forces young 20 the market
and need
for our community are Charlie attention
today dynamics in this
economy honest and you did emergence
sustainability and breakdown of
cooperation in this hearing market is
increasingly
increasingly important as our society
goes more interconnected
it becomes more interdependent within
South and more
into vendors demo the greater than any
breach of clause
possible tornadoes as it comes as no
surprise
that with abuse information ski for both
offensive a defense bacchus 0 the
s price Rd NE a prominent role in it
more
modern-day Belgian
national security and law enforcement
operation nations's top
estate of course are buying with a BS
securities course proposed a
intelligence and law enforcement
communities
use 0 TR TD Azimi I've done it mean to
address the immediate talks
communication
and underground community as well as
well as
surveillance and defense industries act
you respond which is to say dat
is work going application the number or
of markets for
maybe information is your day exploits
during from
over-the-counter 0 dictating between
would you cast by providers or freeze
your neighbor wanna be's
for a subscription fee disservice modos
for
what have you resorts in order to
understand
extortion and cooperation in this year
the market we need to understand story
on the bus are
the marge schott macon any shade over
the future
is the store your data in the face by
zeroed a market participant
whites even these if was like each other
few preliminaries
and definitions argue the ultimatum game
is a game in economics there's the first
player to propose a receiver some money
a proposal to divide some between South
in it not appear a second pair the
responder just
either a Sat or reject a proposed if
responder a sec
the months recorded or he rejects
need it the roses any man the price I
that my
is the canonical game study game you
need to show out to you
purity iraq's individuals may not
cooperate
even if it appears thats David best
interest to do so
the president at MIT prize winner me to
cry
if they both did not confess they get
low punishment if the bus confess they
get
in more severe punishment if one
confesses the other does not
than the one they can fast get a very
low price mated 1-day
it got it got one gets a very see their
punishment
day I curated price that misery P
where the president that I'm a game is
stage I just paid a price in mind that
at my gate
any that
times now in order to model secret raids
I'm easy and UK michael is your day to
them
and the 0t that mike is a small there's
is your day so there in a buyer and I
spoke apache
yes probably espy t0 day and people to
see they both receive anymore
the of are if
the boat the fact respectively retaining
intellectual property and the money both
receive a
constantly of be if the buyer
base or did when I mean in the cellar
defects then the piracy a socket we all
as
and a satyr a temptation the of d
however
if the Center supplied is your day and
by Interfax than three options begins to
be able to get ready for
is the sir me either aw
up to a set the trial this is what they
call is some missus
not you or to push you to POF for Remax
retaliation
if first Avenue retaliation is to
close alternative the O's for desi
intellectual property
we'd other buyers is what I call in
adoptees
not a second every new recreation
resembling
the adultery on mutually assured
destruction is to publish this Saturday
indicates that you too despite
minimizing the weaker party unity
associate with the disc older when
interviewed
is what they called a mess night boxing
match
recognition approach work as long as the
we're gonna be
information express now
they all 43 the
scenarios r us all in this to me since
an audio
decide who receives this suck at the
office in the Bible impatient
healthy in the add up is an audio the
seller receives
they spy PLC and the buyer
reformist the of you in the
30 lasts an audio the receipts again
this socket the of s
by the buyer with receive air the
receipt the of
be the following conditionals forget the
of the temptation help streak
greater than what the of getting more of
three
greater than the constancy of they would
be of greater
also and their part parties the of you
receive a call
and aspire of finally did I'm sleepy all
is three
grader than that soccer I'll few remarks
in the some its not its leaders greatest
under president that I
their relationship are treated in P
price in which the corporation is
superior
to move to the faction however
relationship greater than our integrated
in S
implied it defection is the dominant
strategy for both odds
or defection is better the corporation
for one piano maker
no matter out your opponent make the in
that scenario
who need a buyer and the seller have
been it done in strategy
this despite the upbeat greater than the
soccer the of and the reforms the
offbeat smaller
and more the party without if it
reseller
is the ability to close alternative the
A's for the same splice any
one day weekend at that all or when they
privatized like for instance
the defection is not the dominant
strategy anymore
but didn't market needs a place a role
in this capacity
today disunity market is not in my
office in the AM this week
you regulate by starting from day
implementation give us another
arrangement pregnancy know me emergence
idea
in the ebony but on the market the
medicine audio is a body into the
process all the standard
uprising that know what to say to that
to negate the buyer
impatient fact any does so by making
sure the temptation y'all
approach that feinstein I'll asked if
action is not
not determine strategy on the four by
your
now if after such as market liquidity s
or
regulation me because it would prevent
that you recognition approach for being
undertaken
then this other ship the Cedars closing
pop
be destroyed or be by doing so she will
not make
make South warsaw because she was going
to get decide to pay off anyway
rich media other way around seller will
reinstate
the by reason if to differ defect in the
first place
duties and it's important for 0 decide
there's
lebanese shimmy for disclosure not for
the sake of bragging rights anymore
but for modern-day brinkmanship effect
us foster disclose a given immunity a
shorter
the window of opportunity despite her
and a smaller
the residual y'all now sister late 2002
before Discovery's this is CSU or legal
troubles
way and any market it
like to see more regulations in the hole
in the coming years
well CNN Middle East me personally trust
a
in and outside fate or if proper steps
are not taken
you notice your day ani its me which is
to say
that that would not be surprised to
learn about assistance always your days
goes right back
researcher to use it for me for the
score clear CZ City Market
use it great meeting is buyer with the
facts insider went on to beat this post
this secretive
trading inclusion a surveillance
technologies that
with the day o0 reeks like that was work
noted as long as the sender that doesn't
mean this missus
are you the buyer is not better off the
fact this means that
in the one shop sequential 0 daytime
operations
possibly this seller most there's
everything that you need
punish the buyer artifact if is not the
case
the russian economies section provides
them with all the faction
that evidence that was separation gets
the better of condoms
faction but he's not cross outcome
because the choice to cooperate
individual level is not cross
from South interest view before I want
to ask you
if no form of punishment can get if
taken by the seller
can cooperative comes to be sustained as
an
review now whenever speak about
PPI whenever we have your forty to
reason about
0 Saturday markets term sick leave yet
we are speaking about
mashek now a John S
in you know all motor times pass away
just two days ago
so I would like to ask you to join me
give you a warm round
laos John Nash they say
speaking about EB a day I to rate is
your day to that now
is every game what is your date and my
is this stage
be I display this unity that I'm a game
end in death number thanks whenever
Desai missus not applies
they i to rate is your day that I'm a
game reduced
today I curated price on it that I am
therefore it becomes possible to stop
being today
extensive theoretically and
experimentally Fisher devoted to start
your review games
and Joe some prediction on emergence
sustainability
a breakdown of cooperation in this unity
mock I ask you to consider
threesome not use the I'm setting where
previous
noted that you departed yet you can with
they are not inciting
were treats takes place most Rangers and
a senior nonce
site where either the buyer or seller is
an arms
it has been well known this
sisted overall memoir published 1959
that in the onset in to russian other
individuals
meet sustained a corporate com if they
face each other in the
that new number times fluorescently we
impressive Freeman Dyson
change the view point in this game by
mistreating the power rounded
to a sentence player or appear with your
mind now
if you remind is a quiet weights 8 the
player
realized it their behavior and having
impressed and ebony
out on the on instructors pressing
doesn't introduce
in Newcastle trading strategies cause
you to determine strategies
which for sale in your relationship
between 8
players course l0 determine strategists
ever far-reaching consequences or for
COD traders
if one trader is aware 0 determine
strategies
but your point is a balloons one than
former inches to extort lot
AP receipt to be evil lucidity it's a
process not the reminds
and is to simply see to adjust their
strategy to maximize their own story
response to
whatever dead nurseries doing now
extortion strategist run
disproportionate number like y'all
extortionist this s pass it to be is
that
but it's the beating best interest to
cooperate with distortion is
because sable to increase escort ladies
any so doing chin-ups secrecy just those
from the score even more dinero
depicting never the top to distortion is
she with a seat for extortionist because
Acer
so him yet any some following
distortions
relation writing three thanks to share
healthy but punishment P let's compare
does received by the 21 by out doesn't
work in practice
improper is that priest's abuse their
war
impatient punishment suck at the of to
be respectively
equal to 3 5 10 and if
we assume that I was an extortionist
player
you any pollution one def play into only
way
if we both operate less time then take a
break
we probably 11 over 13 if I cheat you
ice time then incorporate the game but
with probably 7-over
26 if you cheated me last time then
incorporate we provide you
on one of and if we both the fact I'd
fact
in this way on the long run my score -1
would be pressed score -1 I refer you to
or it States but present I Z
also show that if book both there's a
sentence but only one
is notable abouts you to determine
strike
is ben de I curated price that I'ma
released
they are maiden name I suppose both ears
a sentence but only one
only the buyer is knowledgeable about 20
different strategies
then the buyer me try to extort seller
but the seller will
eventually notice is something is amiss
whenever she pressed
to improve their score Shin that's
improving that by a score even more
now have you you remind she may
eventually decide to
supplicate discourse both in the
tentative
to change the buyer behavior they I to
rate at present that might then reduced
today ultimately
we did buy a prophecy and I'm Iran me
and the center responding make you
receding
or sup aging what both fierce course
finally pressing doesn't show it
if both players a sentence in weakening
or $0.10
strategist then what you can do is to
they
what they call it senators 0 the time
strategies if I T
tentative to a store on it result
locally the
helpful before Russia thing to do is to
agree only
fear operations strategy they can do
that
if they Union let the reset the other
score Negrete that
presumably months possible whenever
you do that media player improve escort
leavitt violating strategy
each's fines for any puree monies
violation see me senorita look to see
or distortions relation yet janitors
relations rent in today
the racks thanks that sure the of people
more compared with those received would
it be a while in practice
if we assume the same the y'all forget
war
temptation finds me suck at the office
before
to Pius X and X&Y could play
anyway you know about the returns if
both cooperate less time than X operates
if axed
she did why this time the next to press
a game we probably
a over if white attacks
like the last time then X cooperates
with probably
3-over and if they both the fact last
time the next
a brace but we probably the only two
over on average in the long run
escora facts -3 would be twice the score
a why
months 3 might order results
site is so far apply on the the market
participant at the ability to recognize
they tend to do.
appointed dealing with identification is
replied
described fast action DC market
participant
and to choose prodigies already the
outcome
Austin for option but now with this
there are a number of black markets
worked readers are a nice so
is this right last is cooperation
possible in a non-zero the office
you believe he's if yes which
institution for monitoring and
enforcement
promote cooperation he said unit
experimental study
on anonymous economies that the look on
the map
oxide fund up the corporation is i
increase the speeds
but you also notice a law degree of
separation when subjects EOG to get
there
can speed up survey i dont this a smear
result from discussing
treaties it is on anonymous for more
interestingly
the the notice that cost a costly
personal
feinstein significantly promotes
cooperation in particular re
in an experimental treatment subject
with even
the person to observe action enough time
gave me impeded
at a cost as all seemed earnings or the
fact
or and they did so by adding a second
stage game
there the produced on their price on it
that I'm with a one-shot a all their I
to read
now recognition stated the second stage
resemble some point the adoptive and
that's not just a busy road it
that I am i is fortunate because makes
they're workin yep people to our as you
City Market in this same treatment the
real
cool observed opponent the facts and
them simply personal constant
which is the same answer recreation
what's the
corporate bold into on me its and
eclectus testified against it yes
show preference for this kinda
recreation remix retaliation funny
they also find out the personal linesman
is a he said because
defectors with punished by operator were
more likely to Capri
in the following theaters which is to
say it person a punishment
against does it pop good on the one ends
is significantly increase cooperation in
on daughter
decided the basic demoss are a free tour
lines meter or not at all now
for the sake of completeness this star
our attention say 90
markets if only one party is anonymous
arms counterpart is not be no sure
eighty
at neds same parties before doctor can
benefit from the sentence from be
from Matty your mind and is forced two
strategies
as any pollution you would do before he
died on the spot if then I'm
was party knows about 0-10 studies she
she can once again she's placed order on
and is really interesting because shows
that while
operation in a nurse if we can I'm
markets extortion can
33 see me anonymous economies therefore
I get some good news culturally whole a6
recommendation
was your day traders these are the key
takeaway
I would like to leave you with for today
so please bear with me for one minute
long
to smile unity markets in a cheap
corporation
even ounces of processed the party's
even in absence
of escrow service stories corporation
can be sustained even when traders
are anonymous feinstein is an effective
instrument
escorts traders from the fact but meet
at because
is possible to get store adversity knows
about 0-10
strategist we simply see adjust our
strategy to maximize
our own pro prop before this six
recommendations
0d traders are the following: first do
not delete an honest readers
if you cannot ensure you know anonymity
second
escorted the facts and by practicing
brinkmanship or casting a shadow the
future
never decision your account ther
respond consider punishing the faction
promote cooperation by you
either does not do anything yes for it
seems your day
or option is a routine audit its value
this fighter
4 that dissenters blighted
first interested in one thing deal fifth
learn about secret strategies playing
the awnings
are of course in seats forever defects
if you see the factual what the name
non sparking and have not be finest the
phone
added this pretty much eat us for as
their egos
of course in order to put this
recommendation of their missing
grounds experimental the station is to
be iraq
so interest these be before
rock ya I have one last remark to me eat
today so
I would be speaking about got a good
course it back in the box non saddam
therefore I'm reminded about bees all it
wants a
the way of an in the death misery newest
calmness iraq many in music same
now if you like me believe that
insecurity
or depresses or I meet the gate was
price
is the misery of our I'm if you believe
that is securities timmy's Erie
although our time and at the same time
you let me
are also sunwin about our ability to
obtain better security for adults and
give to our children the chance to reach
confidence in the process
we stay within just business then we can
paraphrase
is a mango is say that so we are hoping
the death insecurity there's these
columns
iraq in music inside us sick then
activity spicy the should be
any questions
you
no s okay thank you