substitute deposed for years has been
when Amazon
a pic of me it's supposed to
gets here and just really just from some
lover in verse about journal as we have
spoke with him
on stage a
I i think is work asked me to lose
come the his main ideas own research
sure disclaimer I'm gonna tell you
about humane ideas and that added value
which guys made
most identification
of all abilities and
the iOS devices
ask all the questions to the authors oh
this
research convict someone to plunder the
Fun Fly
important point is d
turn to bob for university the guys who
have applied
their hands to any research lab security
identifying T tax has the
are well fathers many
me know Christopher order to a new
weaning
here
I'll others over the oldest
I'd sits to for what the guys are
actually doing
his recent she
least Houston
she ship are Internet of Things up
anything could diminish the web
interface
this referendum analytical agency
she arranged in an implant shows settle
goes
Andy number devices that have
up
some coastal bays and
with it was mean home
router's web cameras tonic York's could
be even
wifi two's russia's which could be
switched on remotely and other things
mean most
3 to her this 30
was published recently studies on
back doors which were
she Ventura
she really see Manish the device
though knowledge 0 login password to the
user's
show the users and managers placed
ranchers account
as an example
you have devices to be a solution
and 507 to change show after
starring it was identified and
dorms any person has access to this
particular
but doing
getting username and password to pose
one and the same to prices and they
could managed
racism so these questions ok and we
approach
systematically United service
identification these drawbacks
before this summer's gillooly
those amendment proposed
delivered a little bit later but let me
get you to example where drawbacks would
like to find out
don't fight we would like to attend
by I'm 32 I'm so
are
the back first hardcore
login password is addition procedures
you
and to local but you were too secretive
a special control you compare
the midline difficult coincides that the
greater access if it's not
teacher could login password the user
who has charisma itself more open
coincides again it's good if it's not
done goodbye
first time job completion you will call
back door a possible to throw open
bypassing us to the cation second type
of drawback is right about the hidden
administrative interface he did you know
that you don't have to enter a secret
for example
delivered put means the
its con prison
web admin consisting of
Klein teather to rent some figures like
one
00:05:16 idea for cetera moving
on this bus you can get to tournament
function
without entering open password and a
third time
we should get in scope of work
Wilner ability the web interface
Control Panel huge
allowed to introduce OS command
ice planning or remote code execution
example if your old time allows
you to make pink you get that
in to the entry field know is you on a
pink
in fact this entry get this entry and
you formed
the system command Linux
that the router pink works at
pink arguments don't you have entered
into and assistant commander should
perform
therefore is the user entered the
correct way
you can add any command through
and
it could be executed in a persistent
these three types horrible tease
go to this couple just more clinton's
the
are called possible to purpose go to
cation
or simply victorious well-known examples
who described Ward these
the ideal system analysis him that
advises
research shows these but they were so
all can do can
so a blissful nobility models if in the
program there's no are too big Asian
procedures called we believe that the
program is
marble this approach does or because the
procedure dedication might not be
available to know who must admit
school that monitors all the bills and
then it is gage procedures when it told
the
worship the customer base we cannot
setup same signature we should
applicable
cool Linksys and
tooling cameras and other electronic
clocks so what is also
in people that static analysis research
bears is hard because a written
to printer picture rearm
to without initial code is earnest and
meet to have a sadistic know so the
binary code
dynamic dennis is hard because they
don't have access to the
which clear that works with the so
excess
such says that you can observe and
monitor the environment
time moments and also most opportune we
cannot determine that
and disbursed because have
the salute ring signature approached
so that's a problem so how
it is proposed on when idea
to fired Gazprom men India
search for Knotts the apps
earns so I don't gay identification
procedure but
search for the opportunity to get access
to critical function
which must be close with the cation
procedure
kiss without entering secret
in other words you realize my room can't
fireworks and really need to get to the
program to get to the secured from
Shinedown
means that many the possibility to go
around indication Plaza modelers
approach
on
the peas procedure
candies officially
at a secret which only user knowles
knows scobee allies to the school in
so dizzy connection
between busy I'll
and
in case we have the access to critical
function some
Indies medication we have a chance of
choosing listen to determine
the shower calculated Kim having access
to Bynum
coat we should love to get this class
that's
the that
it is proposed check question is with
what methods
it was said before problems for dinner
weathers who is shown up
buckle the paper said a clue dunno will
have access to digital
a clear is that would have had to use
status quo analysis
give you mine developments to differ
that the pictures we need to somehow
unifying internal
are
no need to unify the approach
so turn the first their second idea
is how we are won't understand
ratios own lust les fagen proportions
critical
where we can all get access without
getting sick with
for schindler that America noted is
stone a possible
about a standout and therefore was up
suggested
to the analysis is to get specific
cation
rich cultures who love critical
new channel mentors
within the remaining in Lizet
and specific functions which we protect
access to
with which matters it is proposed to
soldiers john Lynch and
have been betting in specifications
functions
there with Greece first we have this is
a man assists
and for each crude to cold
function we build 'em
Burke slice which allow I
a Los to get all those a up program
operators
which input data that move
from the users into to this very
critical function and an each make slice
sent to the
same dynamic small occurs execution
procedure
the end
she can get Pacific inputs
or limitations on the input data which
would allow
buzz doing shown in this box lies
reaches critical function so after we
received her known limitations on the
input data allowing
to made to pass from the beginning over
suffered
to the critical functions need to check
that it was not
holes just truly implantable
so then we make this third step which is
authentication my purse
check like you this
and today they were found and the
players and the
found really
bypass and these other day to schmooze
Bijan
to the input if he didn't find out who
can say anything because
our methods will not lower but J neural
real mine be shoe
some extent that this software
on there's no
possibilities for identification
procedure which
II told about the show and a slut and
I'm going to skip some slight I'm going
to go exactly to Z tools
which worsens implemented
for automation old
these malice is this on is called
by from loves to upload
22 special environment the analyzed
certainly can she
get the right over I'm any laws of any
verbal noun
this to muse and I reworked at the guys
have written
can make dynamic
symbolic execution to the required point
the third
this such or laos to make back slice
to the quirk point
still these functions
supported by the framework
which was later to get help
he
urged to use tests maybe
right comments into this reporters
propose a wreath and possible to write
about feedback whether it works or not
as a
link to get help and address email
address
where can ask questions too that's
I think for
polled by them in India tall so you
there are questions which I might me
able to answer
the head task
book which has a garage attention
and that until two o'clock we have a
break