senior so how way I'm
cassava counteract combat so threats
service I'll talk about the trance about
what's going on
and
so first issuers by the company the
company was set up for
in 2003 and and it grew out of a small
lamp for
just pure skill happened on the way and
and we separated
and became a an independent company so
there are two independent
group for an hour product line
Acer solutions so for corporate
it. security solutions and this is our
so nothing but that so this is the most
important so
certain have achieved a grade your
success in this era mccusick corporate
security
socialists we r company number one
and and Sun and wind here have lots of
clients more than 350 clients we have
most to them a large companies to large
corporate
corporates assault let's this
speak about the the this
this scene so how to look so from the
viewpoint of corporate to
Securities said the beginning of the
century I worked as a day
here to hear of enteroviruses so that
was the most important task of IT
security was
a was
worst to to speed up to exchange
information and it was the order of the
day and
so then the function of functionality of
the system syn sustainability and
availability
so for us says has security guys
so that was a time to protect ourselves
sir
companies from viruses and a soda can
changing so new viruses new trends
appear to all the time so we had to
protect it lasted for a certain period
of time
until until it turned into you are
her so the viruses keep popping up and
so three hundred thousand
viruses pop up every day Paso the keep
changing morphing into something else
and the sub trying to ward 2
security measures so that the same from
this point the service so that just got
worse
but nothing changed and and there are
many more so but we got accustomed to
something
inevitable and so now we learn how to
react quickly respond
properly kinda and sure everything is
more or less okay and Emma about
something other than the
GOP security her era
started for 2000 2000 mind and so they
realize that information can
leak can be stolen and et cetera can
disappear
and a
so I called it certainly in a
far-fetched manners called it an era
because this year
goes on assist you there others in your
trend now
more and is trying to assess are
protecting your IT perimeter
against weeks and fast under Obama
security secure storage
data and transfer of this data and
surrender the paradigm that needed to be
changed disodium
documents were made the for my work
paper documents paper exchange paper
flow
about to bite on 210 some the majors a
documents became
electronic documents on the concept of
protection on this documents
to change naturally and by 2010
per server realize that to GOP
protecting on the documents is not
sufficient
like deal P does 78 just two forestall
other risks so which keep
and so we decided to so the era of a
business protection services
fighting comforting Oreskes because like
mushrooms
corporate in corporate started to appear
so
the company says so offering your
protection against the risks
said simple software difficult software
and a sec within Excel table that
picture flash tourists many
consultations which is a way to protect
the company from urs
are still young does that just guess
consultation
I provides consulting services
everything you it's all related to risk
for and we fully realize that their
that if the information is lost that's
bad
it's very bad
so there's no need to talk if we
a so than how to protect against a
leaks of information because at the end
of the day so we put up a minute or
so on all channels so we a
catch this information analyze it and
then we either block it online
and so that that happens in six to
seventy percent of cases
or just three let it go through but then
provides information to the
security officer so that this
information
I was an attempt to still this
information than we do
the monitoring and they're so when I
just who how
where to soccer send us information as
to the concept of GOP
and they're so now the trend she's
changing so just where to send it two
hundred and how to call
what to call it so we I say to continue
I'm aanu any product category decided to
our caller internal threats information
security because
DLP is actually something some extra
some extent these internal affairs
information security as well
so than in-house mean house
threats have protection but we decided
to
her name actors itis us that we calling
this new york I and you
abbreviation was a different look and
European itis so the future too
a to isolate suspicious trance
and to block so we did not analyze the
entire gamut
are home a corporation but only his own
that we deem har suspicious
with them suspicious and %uh so I just
have been doing that for many years
about 10 years so we'll know a lot about
that under
and they're so with the reporting as
well so how do we
leaks are organized and in which way
should information is leaked
inspirations
and the so you can see so for example
the channels are
are a leaks so in 2014 the Trent
about faced over the summer so well
someone was saying they were paper
documents that was the main channel of
Los
than in 2014 the main a channel is
network
network is clout its clout this is where
the first and now the clout to closures
came to power
culture alive send them sup now so
they're
happy that manages information can be
stolen from the clout
this berries so paper documents assault
became
so second in importance losses for
example I
I left my my tablet
attacks a car for example although I
lost my smartphone or
I had my double a stolen services has
sixty 60 percent this is number three
and the rest for example email that is
protected by corporations is on a number
for
researchers far behind very interesting
chart because it shows
what channel sleep protected and
so we so the statistics is so we
collect statistics on all the cages that
we identified to depress
in the world published information about
the leakage so we put it on
on the list and they're so 2014 so we're
marked one thousand 1700 leakages
a took place and then to analyze counter
which channels
to understand that this selected just
sent to the press this is that toppled
as purpose under one percent got into
into press
but even judging by this one percent can
get them in GQ
get the curse action and identify the
trans
and from the viewpoint of home types of
information
ninety-two percent personal data leakage
minded why
it's all this on personal data is liquid
can be sold
its know-how can be used her
and so they're often its the client
databases
where they're so did the bank
the banks the top databases his stolen
and then they say so work in just over a
depositor 2 percent
cheaper for a long time one percenter
cheaper and
so then and people go for it then the
commercial
a secret is behind only four percent
the state secret is only 1.1
1.7 half-percent this is a lot because
it is quite sensitive because the state
secret occurs
so there are several hundreds of
thousands are leakage is all over the
world
1.7 percent for state secrets is a lot
there
and the service is the picture it sir
certainly it's very versatile
so medicine so broken down by
industries so medicine in russia its
banks
and medicine his global so global
linkages
my because liquidator Saudi they still
patients data and then the over certain
services through
to the patients one that can actually
can don't sell
done education institutions and a
special agencies and state authorities
number three and and banks and
financials
is on number six in the world and in
Russia
banking leakages number one Anderson
examples of sorry
Taylor
a big retailer for example that sales
food and had a database
their employees and 10 employees
so stole and put it into social networ
information about seller is put it all
up for everyone screwed
and this or the company have to certain
to pay
Anderson search for wreckage rich
kinda dented their financial position
then the second example is so
banking a bank employee here with an
axis
deal P always talk about this so that
people who have an axis
Lego access to certain so that's why I
saw them to access controls
and conscripting so it doesn't thousand
doesn't protect
because he has an accident since this
candidate about the VIP clients with the
been cold since your work to
you know stashed passed this information
I worry
and and cousteau 3.5 million rubles and
heroes caught with his hands hand
John aren't stop two guys there it is
thank you any other
IIT's the old days organization I'm
methods
commercial secrets regulations
procedures
dividing the rules access that's all
done it this is the front line
first thing so this is a big headache
and many companies
commercial
commercial secret malt
so sometimes it takes them years to
introduce the system and then there are
certain technical
methods of control and there are mom non
very good you install it and forget
about
to plug in Africa not they're not has
additional headache a big blow
Saunders riotous service is always
fighting
those matters there's a fight IT guys
security guys so one want to impose
other small to at shying away from it
and then they can certainly pick on a
block
an axis many thanks duder was blocked so
no
internet access is available that's it
period some banks do that and their
for example if the computer has
can get to internet so than a minute to
find the ways how to tiptoe around
manson's figure out a way to how to
organize a leak
and Emily will be much more much more
singers
and then so y spying
spying the staff so sign up for that
doesn't work
because efficiency is very low spying
have the personnel
for and then a so they comprehend week
let me talk to her about our
comprehensive approach to protect data
so our approach is different many
management companies not copy is
because thing that the main means to
protect is not software
such as a means to means think that this
is a software you just install it now
so there are ways to protect against
leakage is and leaking information
is the changing are day and are
month mental state several stages this
yr
up mindset sorry picture taken and
anti-virus understand under my nurses
looking for viruses
that %uh put on the database or just so
using
different algorithms how much remember
looking at one
catching leak for example so for bankers
soil company itself one vulnerability
for bank is another vulnerabilities
power companies another vulnerability so
they understand it differently society
want to catch a week
an there's one an oil company
someone will be looking for DS series
right another company would be looking
for certain documentation production
recommendation
so this fire no commercials fishman to
understand what is it that we're gonna
catch
amicus you don't know what i'm looking
for work and catch
decir southerners free GOP stage
which is where do the audit of IT
security social me what you got
and so when it comes to work but as a de
chimie
and then 11 data classification
Chris occasion because without it
doesn't make sense and then
hand and introduction momentum methods
how to maintain the commercial
secret on them software and the first
stage
weekend heard do the corrective measures
just maturing
us software and corrective measures
adjustments at other
proctor pre free deal P a certain is a
guarantee of successful program in some
in it to you
to give a list of Paul policies and
developing
house a lot so most missed a bit minute
to bid on them so the bent over they
developed a staged a
more successful the final installation
will be I like this picture
pass on
and the basement so usually before we
where movement in your corporation
everything is in the he PC on the left
side
and then we launch this program some pre
deal
p everything in its place everything on
its shelf and everything
green and nice and very neat and tidy
this and so with other with cash
time sure easier to catch if if it's not
just lying in the heap right hi
under so then the GOP stage it's a it's
a software
that does the announcers and Catchings
many
channels today kommt sahnoun
we connect Morris worse is huge
what's a memory stick and so we're just
gonna
some pilots working on it right now on
hand
so that's that's a big list them and a
new technologies
which her so intercept information
science kind of hybrid
announces last how to do
attach rates and and yours
this characteristics service using only
one technology
sorry this document is not milicich
then we and impose their opinion is
Asakusa digital digital prufer
a for the court us occurs
me cassius services as much rest
to fire a guide and to take him to court
versus not using then I just dragging
guys
reported guys I think it's wrong because
images
to see you them to start a national so
the entry into civilized world history
venture services
this will be much in demand there
so they will be issued and tried in
court
so I understand I just had to endure
what deal P e's
and so what the market is moving in the
where
we are moving and they're so there's
another solution are still coming
so that works analyze other answer
now this system are leakage protection
is not analyzing your for
so for example so then the a respectable
pronouncements about company social
networks asunder
GOP looks inside the company not outside
so the world is getting more and more
transparent the perimeter notion is gone
said resentment or intercept not inside
outside as well and that this is a and
and and and a risk models
satanic so
espy from another from the competitors
caster
I got himself hired and and eroding the
company from inside
so for example or I just a that takes
care of
and the corporate segments as fast to
deal with the thinks it's a special
suspicious behavior for example sir can
be isolated from the basis a special
behavior
behavioral patterns
behaviorist except so than a
found a chart of for connections
relationships and isolate
suspicious relations
or which ad hoc communications because
it may be just a love affair or maybe
collusion
you don't know what that is and thus
eliminate year
is at work putting together a certain
product research consulting plus
plus software which alone
the lines are certain principles isolate
suspicious
points and then sign does a suspicious
I'm once we identify so that people
should
hand by hand so using their eyes their
hand stamped work with those suspicions
guys
and that Parise is a great deal of
suspicion with us
and that's how we analyze and so we can
prevent
high-risk servicos mode but
not on at you to to see it coming on
had my documents to make sure that this
document
did not disappear and information
would not be lost
as and that information will stay
in-house
before believes walls that come from
and there's some local love for art
so to prevent that and to preclude
search systems
know you so when it to identify those
collisions
because we clear how to build a system
the question is who is going to be the
first to put together this
system and coming to the computer so so
do peace overtures
is information security document
security
is doing its job eighty percent GOP
solutions worker
so the cuban from nations site it's a
it's a
fights the a accidental
linkages not so good with intentionally
cages
not so well because for a number is a
smash in
orders for we decided documents by
themselves
remotely by themselves those connected
to people who analyzed the
p eople down with much too great a
degree of certainty you can identify
their be here
and five doser minutes stations much
better intentionally
not cannot turn a blind manner and I
think that the market is doing
was going just 2 into this period from
protection
documents to the protection Harper how
committed
in-house threats power mother standard
the is the announcer some personnel
else's house on the staff the out there
company so where the most vulnerable
companies will be closely monitored and
stop
that's all I wanted to see how quickly
so I feet into my time slot
if you have any questions out be happy
to take
your questions will miss
I get the best of us the not by the law
school
I'm yeah hi work
Paso Research Center hallway
in Germany sir
such proposals other important so how to
protect
righteously but we're very very serious
loss strict laws to protect personal
data
pretty personal data protection and that
not all the general
data personal data protection materials
corporate data should be protected so
how can how do you it's worth approaches
are
this is because this hit it
in Germany its it's very bad everything
is because Germany is the first
markets we would like just to go the
wanted to go and the immediately
so we really came up
traced to face relations protection of
and then please data on his job place
because it was a strange because for
example if your if you want to work
and if you're hired so then you should
work and not just think
about the protection excessive measures
of protection of personal data
so because if you're at work you need to
work and they're so
and then rushed for the GOP methods
that we're trying to introduce an hour
sir so the trade unions are against him
can't do that so the situation is very
bad in Germany
so the paradigm started to change after
this last year so once hold on also
spoke about the mass
scale espionage a perpetrated by the
United States
there so then de Jia a so how should you
possibly not protect the personal data
on employee
remembering in the back of our minds
that it's absolutely Press
transparent as so even our Chancellor he
is on the spot
and so that's right this this this idea
of protecting private lives
personalize becomes her ridiculous for
and asunder but the German society is
very conservative there was a changing
gears
slowly anything I think another 2-3
years
passed before the change the senate you
and
in 2009 try just axis
German market we tried to that for a
couple years
but we so we didn't find a single GOP
her as a in Germany deal demands
or not selling so there's a blocking
ports
and other security matters and paper has
them of
as deal P matters but they were not GOP
matters so
there was not a single business I'm that
read the OP could be introduced and
so done deal the her is not selling so
is not selling some now just the start
talk or maybe when it to wash
documents when it to watch closely the
employees so
less divided database or incidents and
on a special guy would have a Mac sister
their system
so the principal of or eyes
simultaneously with the key
so we're just open up the babies
database and see what's going on
so on on it then they can get them
access otherwise this access is denied
here second block it if there's a
mistake there and
so the and Sunday sauna spa mistakes
services artificial intellect first to
second order so there may be some
mistakes but you will have to
had to get them access to the database
anyway if we are to do anything about
the
security so theoretically
it's possible to that the software would
meet certain requirements
at the same time not to not to
not to violate the rules of primes just
personalized certain data protection
personal data protection system and
some but we need to understand tetanus
when nature improve this for ice
principal
than some other things serve them
there's a law on the protection
of her her personal data private lives
and Saunders or or law
from the story
storing information that mister the
store work ten years there's another
and there's a law that the companies are
responsible for
for data protection in-house
occurs which goes counter because they
cannot install GOP matters
and that's why there's a collision
kirker contrasting
interests because the they need to do
that the same time the can up
the measures protecting eventually so
we'll make a special version of software
jerusalem afterward
and Richard Merkin said that question
so that no business wants to control
hardcore for channels internet
but the same time there's no official
position that any person can come
to work with his own gadget independent
channel access to the base station to
Internet to his own much
email sumner tablets was deposit pointer
for introducing deal your system because
we can just a man
on so catch on to the official channels
but there's always send
another way out because interest because
you can just
block on a deficient channels but not
for him it's a certain
certain about says unit/units even just
to to close the the shut the front door
so this is important at the same time
understand this vulnerability so then
disperse upon bring your own device
at their one is promoting advising and
and advertising
Packers then on today I think this is a
disaster
for IT security this is a disaster
because the main
a source of leakage of information his
Marshall smart on a small computer can
do anything just like a big computer
and Bennett has more
have more opportunities so because it
uses other protocols
very difficult to arm to control it so
no
in the market there is no solution that
what
protected the information there I MDM
solutions
MDM a mobile device management class
that allows you
to control to monitor security but in
fact security setting
total do on their mobile devices but
they will not control the content
because it's a very
been complicated thing so how do you
arrange it on a computer very simple
at the end point and mainly in this is
server part
it means that we upload everything does
this server
them analyze all those two cultures so
so a technologist says so they
all keep working and then baby will
provide the verdict
tender if you do it on the mobile device
unit 2
took to mirror the information you turn
donde Stadium
to wanna wear and the channels are very
difficult very convoluted
as on the gym you can't you can make it
as an agent but but but but go to the
low-level
what do you mean are so unit to support
all the variety and now we have
approximately 4,000 types of mobile
devices with different operator
or I almost or or s and them
November including sight mount ok
cannot support all these zoo
so probably 6 or 10
cell phones would be supported by prime
the quantum point of view
you know so I meant ok tried now the
announced
but very few do it I mean this
protection
we for a long time we have been thinking
how to address it
on one hand we try to take 6m
no cell phones so in the fall
where going to come up with a solution
but then we decided troll
it's only 60 models so we decided to
tomb make our own device and the in the
fall away
shell go to the market with it and there
you know we shall try to I'm
at to market them very her difficult to
took to arrange such solution I sir
company
well are make a decision that they will
own this selector several versions and
near I will not allow so bring your own
phone
over different type riser we distribute
six types of say a cell phones or we try
to support those who but we know that we
shall have from
piano cribbing points so there is
no no but nice and working workable
solution
no so
on your right on your right
and so
I want to talk about those internal you
know behaviour
breaches and I'll to analyze them I'm in
a bank
actually we see more and more solutions
in the market but they have
very you know a a different %uh so highs
are you can watch show
what the behavior on the working station
or attempts to
up in a treat as ADB's or
try to find links and the social
networker
to find out if your employees is so
connected to some
criminal gangs same whatever I mean no
to to who will buy the quantum or
competitors says so
but there are no centralized solution
that would collect everything
into a console you're working on it
right but the most interesting question
is when
you're going to make it and how much
is going to cost because your costs are
very high
will the small companies afford it
if on
its affordable for big companies sold a
step-by-step
it will become affordable for so so far
there's a trick there's a catch
one thing is set to present
my sweet butter and another is to
develop such a solution
I'm not sure it's a absolutely possible
for us first
my even we have this cross-section
between technologists we shall have
connections or conclusions so that will
give you false results
and to and it's hardly possible so why
is a solution still not exist because no
one tried to combined we tried
to combine some graphical connections
or technologies that allow to
and to to oppress us trace negative for
and feedback in social networks so we
understand how to
look for negative for YUM
or feedback about that there is a kitsch
in
the user ID you can now link it to a GOP
but
am we are not sure
if this system can be develop at all
and I cannot tell you about the price
so I guess we shall come up with a new
version on the better version of this
system next fall but
you know speaking about the prices I can
tell you
as a rule the solution is so going to be
very expensive in the beginning but as
you scale if the price will go down
if it works we
a shall be able to reduce the price but
as a question-answer if the
solution will be efficient enough if
it's
possible to create it at all
can you please tell me a view lamb to
distribute this solution no
anti-virus s and cryptographic for
protection mincer are quite popular and
one you start to
to deploy use them there is that never a
question why
but speaking about deal PC
and a IPS and other
systems so people always ask why do we
need it because it's not going to give
us anything
it will only make our work harder
so from we have been promoting deal P
since 2007
we have a department and now on analytic
Department collecting Philly
exe reports on things like that we have
serious about it we
made a conference we publish books we
have a poor though about internal leaks
so everything you know within our power
we're trying to but do P has a serious
issue when I was showing my approach
should
free deal p.m. GOP and things like that
unfortunately
the company expect that deal be is
software like anti-virus so you just
come and install it
and eat will show you also mix and
sometimes one
people install it devoid and it catches
nothing
so companies get disappointed but this
so
thing does not work automatico it first
you need to understand what you're going
to catch
so why small companies to have very
little acceptance of deal P because
it they don't know how come to arrange
cheap consulting
consulting is always expensive they need
to
come they need to set it up but you can
more per
you know charge one dollar for it so it
means that
200,000 rubles a solution for a small
company
is either FAA all
or so with the Hampton Bays principles
so what we do we just
a make solution for banks for utilities
for sector 17 verticals currently
each vertical install so
the vertical to you but each company's
individual ATM
is a risk is that we're going to KH
something wrong
not what the company requires so fine
tuning for the company is necessary
in this respect deal p is
kind of tricky software because you need
to educate explain
fine-tune setup people have to
to to sweat over it that's why
base negative for impression look deal P
technologies only ten-years-old and anti
virus is 25
it's more mature so I guess so within
the next 15 years so we
shadow learn
they're probably remove this negative
perception
would like to request to you to approach
companies in a more aggressive manner
one day you visit us your
representatives came and then No
they just brought some brochures and
that's it
because how
else can we explain then prevailed a
poor upon our
management so after the conference a
approach me
we shall discuss how to become more
aggressive
to help you
hun with you in their company
so my name is further so
speaking about %uh promoting GOP
solution set
Ennis is software that this rather
positioned
as a.m. security want but what about
with the state companies we're
probably legislation
is a higher a motivating factor or
certifications
do have any Moussa in the
this respect local we have
for even Apperson in there analytics
Department
that to I studies legislation
in that country's probably ten countries
so where we
are present and own play information
security innovations
that can apply to the company
we track will monitor for instance so
look at the law on personal data
immediately we change our software to
comply
to for instance a a second across or
another law on
something we made it late right to
introduce
the relevant changes butter
we are a software vendor and we provide
this software
but not a complete solution we are not
an integrator
and if you need to a turnkey solution
that would the
be completely compliant it's not
to us we have partners we work with all
the largest integrators and there are
people who do it best
that a few need
to change something in the software then
your turn to us
but it's a very infrequent case
like low on personal data on for
instance the case with Germany they have
different up requirement on this
software has to be changed but want we
are not working fear we're not doing yet
we keep that in mind so thank you
I'm still here
if you have questions please approach me
privately thank you