law
Irish excited well
from the bottom of some be rid of
I am dealing with her well security law
of
applications and also in Tulsa
by may get there were no getting my
master degree and I'll talk about to
office
what is the problem at all customers
always approach
often approach us to I ask for
protection for their
web applications but the most to a prop
at protection for things like ABS now
and
wife saw the next generation robs looks
more promising the problem is there are
too many of them
and each of them is based on some a
special ideology and
some specific cities in terms of
integration in do infrastructure
and some special requirements for their
stuff
training and now I'd like to look at
laps from the point of view of for
protection
offer web applications
laugh miss to have
6 protection mechanisms to guarantee
data security for web applications some
of them are simple like care protocol
checks and
some others are more complex like here
there
mom
machine education I will
point out some of them for you too more
less understand how laugh
a gives you protection and know what to
look for star some very basic things
like protocol
no I'm verification it serves as
the limiting factor because it narrows
p area the for
in Tudor like Arab sorry to see check
or it to home
limits the number of parameters and the
length of parameters
so that no Meriton
enquiries look legal it also that also
checks I'll mmm for time parameters
in the finally for looking it looks for
illegal by its
the next be lineup protection
is blacklisting in the form of
signatures
signature is quite an old protection
Medford in the lab context is still
irrelevant the chromosome Weber
applications which
arm modern and which abolished
no and now are very subject to attacks
and
its actually beneficial thing laugh
for our can nom my is it has the
mechanism of
for Lannan model
building and ok
who where from gives you protection when
the
example mmm him model is not yet built
and it can also a fact the teaching
process and makes it more
clean if you compare different vendors
signature analysis you keel you see the
difference in the number of signatures
you can also a local at
know whether this culture is a scene or
is it is hidden
and also some vendors
maybe produce signature as a correlation
rules
the someone vulnerabilities even
well-known
I'm not always effectively fount
with just one signature it takes some
more them
sophisticated security policy which
takes into account the frequency of
occurrence
but the meaning of the headings there
angel IP addresses and other things
up to remove from blacklists
said moved from black lace
a on him more reliable Linux their
foreign beer
machine learning there are the different
performance
up the axis and the Gators there's the
Adlon model
and all the help in this has occurred
but to the model is thrown out as the
illegal
so it's gonna profiling
to compare different vendors im
it's hard to compare two different
reason because
the mathematical algorithm this
adjustable album is closest to publish
so that's why we cannot resurgent
misidentification away second problem is
that
old framework a lab research
there's never an can never get enough
light traffic because webs
they are existing in their real intent
with real threats
however we can estimate here to tools
like this
first me setting up the
parameters a machine learning and the
and objectives and look at two
and the actual benders some I offer very
precise tuning for example weekend goes
up the
and miss stardoll learning we can
highlight certain a prancer
ranges protested a for the
testing zone and so on other than urs
could never can I mean provide their
unprofor's apart from that duration at
the spirit and this is what should be
prepared for when you make
choice optimization the standard model
works
as the protection mechanism from the and
learning at the machine when the app
was changed by the developer I which
often happens during the cycle
development
in the Mile strides to Paul's nificant
the
the optimizer aggregates in according to
special commission there
a be up he's been sent to be learning so
by default
every hour the object
was found probably small zing and
there's
need to we learn we teach the object
we've seen slides
should
start when we built the army into our
standard model
and see the condition when we consider
it done
the next to word
protection SR user grows the serb
quieter setting
the point is that the operator about
them
up good
the applied level is down at things
validation par saying because
administrator probably
want something up his own a pen tester
tester
split the access to Web ABZ and so on
and so forth
and he is thinking how we should be able
to
and use others rules for internal so
what would give those opportunities only
two internal mechanism but I'll City
administrators the tool
here would compare two approaches on the
sly
there's solutions by two vendors this
solution at the same tests the
protection a web app from phasing
in one case 8 it can be a simple
correlation rules a certain criteria in
the second case
it's a simple its bold and programming
language so he can do whatever he wanted
so each would shoes
anything he wants depending on the
qualification his wishes
at the client's wishes so
if there's a ranger certain
details in the stuff would be able to
in I'll work on that its were choosing
the programming language but if
the the be administrator but he is not
qualified never needs to reckon certain
aspects
Danny be better to choose coordination
rules
other Remy criteria the next protection
too I would not say that it said
a must but the it's interesting the
context of
of bring in because
good
web suggests
earn the sky never service
at the first mechanism that's built in
many websites but mitigation
where size response her in there is
there just had written to the web app
which according to certain parameters
identifies whether they're this machine
has been infected or not so if machine
is infected
then probably good their
query that too came to it was the
partner their activity
a botnet and a scam javaScript can cut
off from the latter but that's when the
attack which bleed decrease efficiency
Mar
also their ass and dick needs to
word each had to de-ice but it's more
interesting to check out the
reaction said and the ways to
in which you wept reacts at the a pile
of course versus
bring forth charge perhaps other BS
heard this term according to the big 12
a column when
the machine at express its opinion about
the
by the transaction's legal or not must
a.m. the
the old sis improve work into its
opinion to guarantee that the machine
has been
spending resources so when our website
is under attack we
build n at this a task
into each piece onto the web app and
hence
a slowing down the source in making each
client
spend a certain amount of time to solve
learn
the task that we sent him if the
solution is wrong then we throughout
this kinda query
but as a rule if it's a real machine if
it's a browser
it will spend some time in just the
right response cell is kinda slow down
the source he reached his light on the
source
next mechanism is captured challenge
everybody knows this session is unable
to capture
and it's it's identified the human one
and shaping leggings and its level
we again you said line to every user
which job exited
and lasting here which is in bed and
wipes
its the integration overall life
is mourns protection data protection too
must be very well integrated into the
general landscape that's that increases
its efficiency
any efficiency entirely IT security
enterprise here it's important to
integrate into
them bowler body scanner and you realize
they were told build hashing function
be about medigap dates you upon our
abilities
is important to integrate quickly with
cesium systems
and
and another possible integration with
their natives activities in mind to
bring
web DB correlation and also
the modern trains like reputation
service service and
and fraud prevention services this is
where I would
probably finish my presentation for
today no need to worry
keep calm cheese you up so in a thing or
dial up to ask
a to show is show certain mile two
things at told you about this is the
the iceberg when I first address the
question
no above the one choice I made this huge
list
criteria where I put into NHA can all
those details to
the compare these products on more
academic bases in our
when new people we propose come to our
company we
get into this beautiful model I have the
understanding what is there what is in
their men stand on on thank you very
much will
gladly answer your questions thank you
mmm
more
can you talk to me I'll tell you
everything yeah
yea can catch me in a conference I'll
gladly talk to everybody if you have
certain questions to ask thank you very
much