mustering Yahoo's
useful for single module you
the cloth for she toured the first three
new system
mom was furman the former looking good
solution is mine lou
personen Suleman's
don't you goes to use it to you good for
the shooting for months
you could too great could the government
or bring those who believe in you will
which non-committal thank you
book or so cookies for me
you for me business lewke from someone
will need them pretty used 30
specialty solution W you know
them continues and you
robles mazda3 fool you the group was the
position and you put them %uh wanted to
move from switching for forty-some
approval to gym money could bring those
who believe in you
just means it is conclusion as the
concert cook Williams
too polluted to William
switching from renewable
much some those words to used
I'll who zoom work you
at the popular schools in with these two
was used to be. trip Mizzou's
she will do losing when used to
a communicable oozing with these people
children's wasn't done
to look for a solution the curvature
tour
new clues to shoot was accomplished he
mood you must not be reached for reals
from you must acquit
you midget
opportunity was he will probably lose
you choose you
so the teacher which homework solution
me to ship
mean was even small
to use to move you no me
missed you or chrome Liverpool really
lose
Duncan to some electrical store movie
would you
thought so be the prettiest was amused
to
me communion his phone call to military
reasons we boost
Muslim storms
to you is a person's the use with the
coaches meeting
do for them Spears position when you
choose you
gruza moving the stuff to go to school
Cotton Bowl City movie william
was doing it with us that it was cool
with you
move would you street use whose
we're just losing the support piers new
more a solution you move
bricks with you done in this the
joke we both liked hit
know where this might come in handy
him
cue who'll as you personally
yes he probably hold
any excess to resource in that sort
must firstly four-shot felt eyes
for access privileges however it can
easily happen
its such a validation is absent from the
Cubs
him or in fact
access rights system is faulty
saying in essence you realize it's
important to do be kind to those
example the project is over
for the developers feel to include all
the necessary checks
some Tomic be highly critical sister
Lee is simply cannot much the codes
alternatively
old you might wanna
developer better system for access
rights management
insured
the system is already running in
production belt
we might remember not initially
knowledge base excess responsible
systems where you so early where replace
with the role they systems
schools and over told
it was a stream of publications search
shows how you could actually
build role based system all total
man died the system used
which essentially means its own all
invasive approach to have all your bill
it's irrelevant
removal sorry has been around for quite
some time way you can actually
protection self
from data manipulation LCS arrest
attacks it
under case him
also on Monday
is as follows: we are a go to locals
real show this to lose will essentially
be known as a civil
my presentation researcher in
were parser for schools have a look at
the terminology that a little to the
service I client-side
early implementation issues the
all hip
I'll start with a couple terminals a
slow so make sure you speak the same
language
moved so
authorization for access control will be
used
interchangeably in this presentation and
as he is a
their simple opposition is Chris persons
specific user and password doesn't have
access to particular resource
heap love the long the underlying
principles here is her full
intermediation
which way so as well trying to dollar
diet
check the authorizations over every
access instance
every user to any party resource
hit
who hears a who world
look as health sector 1 and other plus
was work
you realize how we usually have little
sister developers
thing yet summer authorize a shindig
natal
Houlihan curse simply put force their
way it
you was hook
so they're up for policies available
they're all shows lawyers
please know that sir just
contributed that repeal based access
control lists the approach that is
essentially
see a lot of development so for several
years
baton on the underlying anti
here so you can actually scrub pretty
much
things like that in most cases you'll
see
that role-based access systems years
huge
world
and d be an ass he usually you provide
to our mandate based
access control which is actually means
he control information flows
systems and
Russian computer security mandate based
access control this little different
lets you fine-tune
on the country's in most cases
d covers callback or
similar approach this shellac schedule
based on grades
and
this which was a he released your
pre-tax him sorry to protect the system
from
top top-down at I collectors
wouldn't
him let these very simple here
a subject that or healers
have fun an old religious lol successor
should
north's be able to recent that requires
higher privileges in the system
to please not only for size and here
to select going to discuss in much more
detail later whatever
access control system you're using or
whatever policy
using all answers must be properly
verified and identified
as long as he hadn't done art year know
the leader illusions
access control hit a lot worse of
security levels
is also important to have who
keep you
that the user can access an entity
is and only if he has the right
privileges
the most importantly human that's why
I'm stressing it so much a teaser
peculiarity of the Russian approach to
information security
so the system polymers
cheese rick's president should not
really experience
in the AM the legal total close
who who
whenever we the talk about such an
approach developers for some reason
Linda
instantly turn to lol about a little
more toned and it's pretty difficult to
explain
their production a predisposition to
peel be was to build back 97 test for a
particular system
he has been showing over this the case
to be pretty weak
free
buggy birds have artist who uses the
bell about a little
for for a number of times we climbed to
its
the launch more orderly and much more
reliable
systems thoughts wills that would
support at least
been much more secure installation
but to no avail who his
him there is a huge
platform quarterbacks is actually runs
call he much mobile security forces
dank claims that sir bill a bottle is
officially simple static
intentionally overall great he's
and certainly we see that the years
fixed a BLT
will in fact fix a deal the if his
search for it on the web
me alone defiant who is consistently its
effect
fixed bilby is a Dell Windows version of
the LPI
the other was years in the very first
publication of bill
and little hold back when
they went experimenting where the
baltics operating system
so then see if that foster
he is Rick the two guests redraw its
to all the resources for within
she's to mandate so to speak however it
was only able to
used forces right
on us essentially or sporty his
clearance little for example have
confidential or secret files
sorry he has consulted on show access
rights claims that he can read
confidential and everything billows his
but interestingly he can only overly
earlier right data into the followers of
his particular level
in our case confidential board
it's pretty easy is it implement
the kissa that's later me too so many
additional checks
she however
thats terms to constrain the
functionality of all the processes in
the system
him and this is who we are going to say
in this list aerobics rules
he'll see
this is important to observe the rule of
session loved paying a call to
thinkin operation right which is closing
in the aerobic spaniel here
who see
hidden so interestingly Oracle a little
ass
has sold the same approach she
that's exactly what you see here this is
the read excess
changed his school
his while sitting in here you that the
system checks
where their who
theory operation you're trying to
perform force within the strict confines
opium and eight
want all security BMS
are essentially fixed on Bell the title
a model
school it's important to remember
the 40 hold or sell shares very rarely
distraught
here his
which means we don't really know which
particular
pillars particulars as basil initially
had a DBMS as a usually do not provide a
PO itself enable us to implement
overall rules him
the worst possibly nablas steel great
theory access control systems
I'm mentioning it because in other
systems he can actually get this API
it's fairly DBMSs forget it's not
available
all developers can obviously develop
their own API's
him but its
it is not really plaudits poly
contenders
speak now let's take a look
to what is going to happen if
sold you really really holds
to implement here all access control
policies on
DBMS and we have the following
constraints we can change in
infrastructure we can change the source
code
who and laws go into develop and you
service table so whilst or additional
data so we are going into performer its
in unknown invasive managed snow here
where dole in talking about sir
database management system says we'll
head out for some web service
functionality as well
so we're going to consider a two
different cases here long will be an ass
kill
database last day will be mine single
and the other
implementation like the your skill
system with a REST API
could be less text search color whatever
peyot 8
who attack
there are teas actress we can follow
weekend either
the to its it
I'm sorry on a little subtle denies data
rotor or low-dose ruth has the info all
you stand a week ago the way a framework
sir finals
who
usual in DBMS
his the right number of other
known approaches just were
non-invasive implementation reno scale
for example
axiomatic sir the well-known solutions
like but let me explain
bloody what is a the novelty that a
break here because and all the
approaches you see on the screen
the I there are based on access control
lists
and if I will based SQL injection
protection
no our approach is to show how you can
actually provide
mandate based access control he
shoe who moved
and how you can actually
make invisible to web applications Gould
which see here is a classification a
wholly pro-choice he saw in the previous
laws
no the clustered oh they're
to different buckets depending on which
part of the system
their address who
who worked on the possible
implementations he
we toyed with several ideas and what do
they really can show insurance card and
you have to agree that most this
mattress will tend to be quite difficult
to mount if you don't have a huge team
of developers who will know the source
code very well it will have an in-depth
understanding almost to the devices
but chances are you'll be successful
there is another major issue here
in many cases
people don't really understand properly
what mandated by East Texas
Comptroller's
because usually his only confined to
give
pretty you soldiers three words track
first tax this is this were to labels
I'm sorry and please remember as we said
previously
all the answers on the system must be
identified and verified
which means I if you tried to access
control at the level of DBMS
socially means that the minnow unitaf
date and dressing is all where you can
provide service access controlled
out Camire Pascale a
enables you to address columns but not
rose
let alone individual cells a literate
similar DBMSs enable you to address
individual cells
means I'll take you
rule maneuver 10 to say was that a your
access control
whose for medical this is Victoria
Assets Control lower will mostly be
limited by the structural
to be a mess force
whose to our approach is that's where
billion to the stylish proxy server
that's where we'll
me its streets access control policy
know we'll be right of super proxy
server and we also need to learn how to
properly most I'd ticket authorize a
user's
whose
you usually at the level of the
TB mas requests calls from different
each user's adults distinguishable
will you so
oooh hafer access control policy
implemented a it
role days mandate based on a hybrid all
the requests
well come in a jungle from the viewpoint
of the DBMS they will
all look like coming from the same user
so it's very important for us
educate the proxy server home
he can actually who identified
distinguished users
on this a little differently for us
Kayla
members killed database here
good no skill databases
and some searchable systems we can have
a REST API
Wellfleet works as I will have a ser
sorry will have a clogged
servers was his and discusses
like this with the label E is to century
class
saw your java scripts for different
clips so in your HTTP requests
as you'll see from the start you look at
us like this for example
this is what return requests can look
like
weird
people that way Yuki is an
application-level Charles
support sessions here
and any chips most
3,000 steel rails wears hearing that we
have a lot here's a nice
I'll or load balancer which means a
users have already gone through
authentication process there so it's
pretty easy
to at a user ID
from load balancer for example and a
little approx this year
slits can at least distinguish between
requests coming from different users
who suffer such a test infrastructure
pretty simple to citrus Ranch he have to
agree
we have all these requests coming
through the load balancer
and this isn't that this is indeed a
very simple example we are using at the
IP device here which
has a an idea I really interface the set
TCAL language extension and enables here
to address
all the old jets there are failing
available on this device
felt that way you can run pretty much
any logic you want say civil there is an
issue with checking whether
session exists and that always simply at
the
his RIT into the HTTP request
world and now we can easily
around easily or more execuse
security policy have a running on the
proxy server all that particular request
as well will only eat to Toys R Us will
to reverse proxy for us all
real excess which is going to provide us
with all the
labels last year's he could be car
protected directory or some internal
data warehouse used
now when you've learnt holdouts
it's pretty easy to apply all their
security rules and policies
you wishful
first knows will at this was gonna look
like for a pretty simple toned down a
REST API
firstly check whether he is or has been
authenticated its
not to thats we get a user's ID cool
and bass on his ID alias search his
clearance
after yard
we parse the URL which tackle whether
the user's clearance
Nationals the level of the particular
object he requests
he for a chippy requires
this notion also whole
request is slightly different bushel
following in entebbe mass
were all yes his
effects its easy route to that's when
you're dealing with HTTP requests
as the cold show solicit just here is
essentially a weight
fix the from the National a share with
the a little immortal
the this you will
dying slowly our own proxy server we are
able to simulate a proper Outback
policy you who CPU say
if we have the user who has secret level
clearance
each secret level access this meeting so
he is allowed to read all the files on
the system
in fact if he hasn't already
anything is allowed to write any data
off
any level however after his read
something
she saw reelection built within the
confines of the secret level he can no
longer write files
have any other clearance world when his
session is over
whole thing is refreshed spaghetti right
and his low score read it
whose you both out if we're using a
skill system such as
my signal it's very important for us
from there beginning to identify the
user's so we
piracy was your way using a load
balancers because
as quel requests are created
at the server level in early
sent to the DBMS earlier which means
that we can't really gets
who the attributes we had in the
previous example
so the way %eh
the worker who is out we need to develop
a more chill for the framework
skill into intercepts the request and
tents to the request some user ID of for
example
he can at patent
address session ID or he is raising as a
call and
in front believe vs killer requests old
little dung-wei this security monitor on
the reverse proxy
the old will be able to understand who
is
requests he was sort of information the
so cold croat operations
you they'll be pretty easy to perform
like that's because the tools
really require pennies talked
bottle flows of information old usually
flows like this will only be triggers
many have in that it square is like
that's you
clean again
he is cursors leaders or triggers
to get around it LA showing how he could
actually be done with cursor flows or
in that it requests so push
his now the easiest approach
as you see here is so the one that helps
the deal simpler than that its clearance
him to lie and say it's nuts who
seems we have user ID is who
and you I'm sorry since doesn't come as
part of their requests we need to parse
it first
well check the validity internally who
the it would be more complicated to
analyze individual routines
this is something that we haven't really
analyzed
as we understand that static analysis
who
tools could actually be useful pic is it
that way we would be able to learn who
actually sandwich procedures
kind of Los the triggers we believe it
could be done
but this is something we have not
performed yet
of pollution
Marchesa want to it him
who who
groovy to now in the SQL query in the
historic last week and also
integrates a real es for daytime
wouldn't we know that an attacker for
example Charlie changing the NZ here
in order to get the date on the user's
so give with me reduce on this request
by attending our own User ID in front of
it
we cover this vulnerability completely
we to him
who
you will no this was a fine all invasive
access control for protecting TPMS
level you now let's look at the web
server side
picture
who he
you any highly secure about applications
it's important
to protect the workflows his
now I'm referencing a particular
publication here that shows
workflow protection although it starts
hurts
is not really provided anywhere
also elves losses trailers
she used which means that
miles web applications that are socially
base
workflows have this series on our
ability she
was also
and a lost top 10
his people known vulnerability when you
have
indirect links whose
what other known approaches to
resolving or removing yes well-known
older pills
for seeking used to convey success who
if a web application
informal generates file name:
or name pictures something through it
each to who
he
she's and display so the state employees
in HTML we can actually eat
calculating how much at last play
replacing the hash
will be able to replace the attribute
alone the application firewall will
check list
can exist through doesn't whose off at
Wishaw issues
that could be over its heels move
reaches the new
attack surface considerably and this is
what somewhat security number of other
short
who you
who
please tell the same approach can
actually be a similar to results home
for her abilities and access control
you for example if a web server
generates some
heidi's times train resource ladies
initially in HTML who
he's the same token his to Saunders
hardy's
we who
speakeasies you any
hot checks can actually be fights on
browsers
on the user's in the browser could be
accessed with assorted cookies
have who well it's important for us to
tease on this string properly
to make sure that it's fuel injector
itself prone to injections
shooter then we can run the ash
action using a secret key there are two
protocols that are available
the key is social wise or session less
caught a cold full
essentially we can run it in a way that
would make sure that no data is
physically stored in the Tyrol up
hit
massage implementation he you can pre
sales
CS around as well as replant turks as
well as a number if not all
workflow attacks yes and also
enables to protection as hell big gains
it. many relationship
who can actually be implemented on
hybrids and walks
nice for a close as well as modular
trailers for Django
whose shows
he a list I was distraught
you can be clay gets for protecting HTML
elements
and for protections Hill some reason
nobody has a research whether saying
were deployed to cook his
and here where cold singing trust way
spider loves blog
and these are the guys that are
supporting what security and no not the
default
demand sleep promoting and developing it
so PE see what they say here
they've implemented this works his like
a charm
although they are experiencing some
cookie data issues
well I can assure you that our students
ish have looked into that and they've
shown conclusively that's a cookie
protection protocol like this could
easily be construed to see
so for every controlled coqui
if all the awards is to control the
caucus
all you need to do is create miracle
cream
he'll simply check don't
know they say the same if you also want
to control cookies scope
we should cover the domains where you
can go
it's tragic to rate its life
well done he will need to develop more
difficult course tracks
essentially that would be needed authors
conclude that will contain all the
stator
enough so that's she people this coke is
with all their value this
should just say where he also
add to their hash based on this session
key
for the device for user you
and that's way you can make sure that
all the client-side
is better clinical case can also be
Cumberland just
you
his or to if we'll see if there is a
discrepancy between the cookie store
internally
kid I guess generators you can for
example cancel a suction
delete all too late and so on least
weekly popular
previously was that he is a rolls
I would be assigned fire Co kiss his
or for example you could get a cookie
saying and Yankee iraq such officer
those a regular user world now if
in the web browser you fake cocaine
he can easily become an admin will
than is signed the cooking like that's
the national problems stays on in the
cult
the vulnerabilities cold
well the office price you pay for the
art is that he and now I have
twice as many cookies
hitch there is one more thing I want to
discuss
which was a hola go into control
the workflow processes used tourism
particular string operations you need to
perform another
save both but BOCONI on Amazon whatever
the first select the product
many countries or patron diesem
no layoffs about download the book well
if you find a way to download the book
straightaway he most cases maynes
successfully tax the work clothes mean
the notion of workflow whose
has recently been has very well
formulators
in identity-based cryptography the prior
stellar definition for
cryptographic workflow who
the only problem we have
he starts is based on colour sec
cryptographic choice if you want to
perform but the only to do its
on your browser relying on JavaScript
probably a base cryptography
is still the most potent me in the
jury's still out on whether it's good or
not
him
his people
there are some simpler approach this I
could be relied upon
good particularly
where dealing with this simple lanier
workflow
huge who
overall mood ship
he is either a simple kosher kind of
protocol
who were
hits whenever you're well
aunt every request both the culture
who once step ahead
push me say you'll have
NH back guarantee if you try to suck the
work
lol to go several stops the hens a cell
approach will be
to using Cubase protocol we in this case
in your web application firewall you'll
generate a set of keys for example ish
work local seesaw three operations you
will have three keys generators
who if and all this ray case will be
he is on the web application firewall in
a particular
predetermined order for example
if the user and walks submits a request
that discussed with the other in key
the system will not be able to decipher
it properly or
developer cash for it he which means
that his actions will be thwarted
and specialty terminate
list
lot in order to protect we're close
in order to provide a h-back
talkin protection who
both approaches we get they have to
agree that the
fun to cheer he said he don't store
anything on wall
whether ligation file he this
it on who need to install the section
secession
control mechanism as he wouldn't saw the
web service for example
thank you very much I'll handed over to
Michael
he's going to learn more about the
implementation approach he took
help
this is a prototype for years in order
to demoss real with me
cease he'll we have
authentication mandate based access
control
producer conceptual here this prototype
can be structured into
components we have them middleware here
frameworks inching up then we also have
proxies heart proxy purposes we is
MySQL proxy utility which is a
in most cases he is or load balancing
however
scenes he has built Ian interpreter
tokenizer Hulu enter
and parser which is great rose because
enable us to identify some of the apt to
say coming mentioned in the request such
as a DNS for example
know much but the successful attorney
the role tool
mandate placed polls has for access
control
the and my last polls me
supporters old email operators and the
other policies he is a
much already sone
analyze a particular requests for
illegal
top two got hot top-down processes he
can also distinguish between embed it in
simple
Aquarius he can also deal with multiple
and say hi rocking
for example if you have a label for the
DBMS
he will also be astonished
role clearest individual columns or rows
aunt hitting a table like this he can
easily reach years the Folin all the
information you need to configure and
somewhat supped
highs all the houses procedure
so when the when the first clarity comes
over rice
the SKL proxy the config files
will be retrieved and checks
for consistency of entities are labels
Qatar thats that type of query is I
don't
the curry sent a particular interpreter
which
generates set of labels and on this
labels
are a transfer to the entity that is
specially managers access control lists
which
execution flow can be illustrated as
follows:
so the first thing to be involved his
parser and the base on the day you get
there you can
analyze the hierarchy can see whether
the coals for example or maintain their
cool
no
for example if the user gets access to
the table but doesn't have access to
news
Cole will need analyze the car again
search for call the elite Tatum
identification mechanism
is important because it enables us to
sorry to
all Inc users to a particular request
for a query coming up
but please no
in style with a by it taking so
in the cold and snowy that patent user
ID's
and since this ID's can only exist in
the application
well this tool Iran's
is highly application or at the level of
the application are cases Django
according to the mondale there are
several ways to generate
he's your own queries are they all have
in common
is had the whole work with the back end
most popular class would be the database
rapper
which uses cursors from the
database fibers
so curse reserve he usually rocked
into cerska rappers and we decided he is
out for
this particular experiments CC that
we use the patching and the first query
processing
and after that we send all the
indicators and then we
take the query
well as rehear the way queria written
as we've mentioned to ready the random
number precious
replanted to
this process because the same killed a
socially is he is
inside to be mass because a
delivered as usual it's don't
distinguish between users 10
after all that there are first-team
honors Killa
singer DBMS should do not really have
proposal over security rules if you have
any particular access control mistakes
at the level of the application
here will experience her he will have
vulnerabilities as well
some users can access to the user's data
and the system we have destroyed shit
protects you against this vulnerability
because a
that way you will be able to
at individual conditions in the
following situations:
to this is how this conditions can be
generated and
muscle Ca 2+ individual situations here
first all will be a relatively simple
no classes here we have a column
in the protected table in this column
we have user's ID
well it could be plain text or otherwise
and we need to make sure that we have
some comparison routine
built-in and not to play way
should be able to teach cool weather
user has access Rice who this particular
column
I more typical case as this one we had
told her
for such a column in The Protector tales
but he can affect
a link the role so the table you protect
with an isaiah smaller table
cool
who have a many to many sort of
exemption on here
NEC that we start with a year select
query
which retrieves the Maltese over ladies
available
to the marginal ID's
are available to the user
so this could be done above the level of
the proxy
house while last month while the
application and
here we have this whole its together
with the early in the application level
you
all yours need to change your weather
cool at the table itself his preference
in the query or not
the way it do not is to check its config
data
good that's when the to find a location
where we can
include this conditions his essentially
days on the structure of the query
how we end this condition how we spend
time together
to the DBMS for processing think how
much attention
totally someone if you have any
questions please
mike is yours bud
are the first talk about mandate place
to grow Chandani talk about web
applications
which is sorta confusing for me
can hear mentioned particular
web application where such
mandate based approach actually makes
elsewhere top to bottom information
poster will be my first question has a
question clear sir
kit my second question on I know what
first us this question please
do you want me just to name a system or
ill you
both don't don't know him I have for
example
formal security requirements like that's
you'll
believable
sleazy his songs
ocean she both sides
like nice purchase pretty strong
only see here is that by default
which the usual week of system
you is implemented soon as long as we
come to identify
the users probably country really sure
proper protection
it
I'm sorry my question was different
would
whose it's a pretty unusual
requirement for TPMS
hurts user would built skiing writes all
levels
nato and the system
on the issue demonstrate doesn't take
into account user higher archaeological
links between users
Google any old-fashioned
D can deploy any policy like always him
is that you have some policy
we sold developing a policy
scary following a policy would also be
interesting topics
anyway not covering here told police he
wished he have some policy
also know we illustrate does a variety
is using
some very simple case s
who'll of us always
hoop
no but I'm asking us different
why I'm confuse here his thirty is seen
to be
bringing together two different concerts
the 10 the
told to bottom information flows
and the ownership logically call the
ownership laundry is a
it was a visionary only support Israel
rewriting SQL queries
and I'm not saying it's easy indeed it's
really important to understand the links
to know how to properly configure we've
shown it's possible
well
wondering whether you can actually 2002
real prices in relational
in case he needs help the British nurse
acadia we did it
as a piece a research shouldn't now a
short practice
I suggest you find a company that we
want to do that
his him
and I think I have an experimental
beyond would be run
donate the lakes have your holy index
push we will all have their
capability history and other questions
case did
have you tried implementing it
practically whatever's
here moon
now was the applied Delhi research in
other words
his
well as the network level we can easily
he is it with plastic surgery if you're
wondering about possible business
applications agenda level known this has
not been done
good
s to find it difficult to wrap my mind
around us
cities say
there there is this user ID sorry
user token and you attach some I
detailed
Kojima match this one of token
with the
Olmert told him that is maintained in
the database before
initial initialization za
speak primary initialization
whose parties all went well if he have
anonymous users
income have any access control also
raised
access control only starts working we've
gone through authentication
but a cask ale injection
onlookers hell such attacks can be
mounted
a gainst search engines you don't need
to
authentication their rights asians still
gets the data from databases polls well
in this case
yes availability of data
saw yes kill injection depends own
I'll issue structure access control
inside DBMS
cool awful
because ask elections simply crowds he
discusses the DBMS rights
used so if you have a proper security
policy running
only a DBMS we if it's properly
configured
it could be mandate role play so that
way you will be able to significantly
%uh limits that damage so to speak
his
the water by anonymous users in no
longer have
an anonymous user the web server sounds
like a wary into the DBMS
using sounds but see killer account
it's no longer an autonomous old
you who through the viewpoint other DBMS
nobody's anonymous
8 tools we're psyched about the same
thing but let's
wait to hear what it up thank you very
much ice chests a few have
any other questions for the speaker is
sir please course
speakers outside certainly will be happy
to provide you with additional
information