my name is reveal
I am a student are the physical
adversity in moscow
physics University Moscow and such to my
report is defensive Harbor Cole
I'll take your time he was but my
objective the objective is to
is searching for upon our bird is as it
should be
and develop the hardware to
if I am logged the malicious activities
so
in my presentation the mission was to
research department call analyze the
vulnerability said that but I called and
a research the concept %uh
the security nasa tip be for overtime
but the hard part a call i wud
told her about the if
all
prime okay
search for for an analog signal in the
field I was also dismayed digital
signals so
that's how we had about the hard product
called this the industrial ditch told
product called
I to transmit digital signal based on
their African see modulation so in other
words
old there's the combination
are the transmission but the different
frequencies
him so properly herds this logical unit
and logical 0 another such go on
and logical one is
12 hurts so this can be directly
connected to
do it
to leading devices and made a medium
level
and the first leading lead denies
is the usual
PO came the other is hard mode am
the war at the Selcuk
containing the part protocol devices
it
the second connections to the lead to
living devices
it you can get up to fifteen different
lead devices said
then Megan Smith only digital signal
here and the analog signal
his ease to power the
trackers so this product call as
vulnerable
old
his such as
the software vulnerability hip
cause the failure of the and the failure
thus up for a room with this specific
art product called
and also there was a vulnerability out
there a server with heart so if
there's still wrong IP header their a
hard the RPS server could fall
meal the other Wilner ability
Pierce that that the
put on the acrid low evidence could the
rutile India a sensor or replace the
sensor
world
so it the device is giving the
wrong I T and he had near
a.m. vulnerabilities that we need is
done we know that
is his
the system is now pitting DMS system so
for that we can use
world
used
hit sweet but there's a
our DT TM technology integrated it works
I am following way: and space in
containers Inc com Content urs income
objects
and integration the interaction have
space on XML messages so all the
information
that we have in the sensor holes
its packages into the expectation TX
email message
and as a result him we
heaved it did
if this century's I swapped
Canon dad special to inject a cement Co
there also are
certain vulnerabilities I
who would I in the military level and
ninety where users can urs cannot
protect that so would-be
want to do out the hard way that would
protect other three levels so that by
the nation
also who have three important points to
technological security
humor the specialist simple act
technical information technological
information from
the objects and sensors security at the
production
this for the special school manage the
and this option would be important to
give for
here we get information about the
problems that would appear if
a in the case have said to be and the
the
the third thing is of course IT security
yes
PA security instances and of course
there
directors also that world
so the hardware the said we have certain
modules
to analyze at the physical level sold
which below to control fictional
physical
features at the signal who'll
his his
make smile is the frame analyzes who
will be able to analyze the structure
%uh the transmit pictures base in the
frames
and find the violations over the loud
format there's a
model a utiliza comments
the data transmission who
weekend initially said this scenario no
with that and have fun the work happens
now cordis area that can be identified
of course
basic on their abilities would like to
find on their bills before
they have been exploited to shit
it
feel a protection is basin make free air
lead trance information basic current
network will be able to
the friggin sick a portrayed preach
signal
and will have the mile for each signal
and certain
a thresholds and gave
the frequency will be swabbed will me
will be able to identify dat
so now little were developing here
the the models them
the hardwood warrior the controller used
and will be making new firmware and
testing
in the near future