here
yet it's on the rooster Malo everybody
so my name is Alexander and today we're
going to talk
about the reason Kaspersky Lab
studies the target attacked
arranged by nation-state
this is a a nation governments and why
and how and what does the
tricks on the way so allow us to start
with the general things
our
Billard mister case lol waving his hand
so I am talking about the battle
warm Regine reg in bed all warm
and we published our report about it
her last year this is one of them Omnia
number types of proof of the level of
the spy program
malware program that even people all
that
her position make here to talk about it
and recently we've heard news about the
White House email
hacking and their immediately a
Russian hackers so have been accused
without
any through for details how and why it
was
and one was open to recently we
published a report to the about a group
named Duke and they
modification of the cozy Duke which
a is obviously of Russian origin have
that has been
responsible for the same intrusion into
the white house email system
but we need to understand that Dukas a
family of malware
mmm their programs we have been
monitoring
them for several years they definitely
have some Russian
jeans in it tender in their way is that
sir
an indicator that we as a Russian
company
will not
a tried to cover up for their
tax done
by Russian government a special service
history some boomer publication
which EU must have read when them
our company was accused her
for you know eaten
having fun with KGB agents in this sauna
Kaka so Kaspersky Lab thats that's why
Kaspersky Lab never publisher's
information about their
attacks with Russian origin but her
if you consider the truth it's
absolutely wrong
you we look at them statistics
up our published researcher reports sooo
since 2010 when we published
information about Stuxnet
them and snowballing
attacks arranged by different government
sir and in 2014
with published over 10 a reports
and articles about malware are
from origin eating from a estate
some government and that we need to
understand that the number of such
attacks her is going up
lately and
anti-virus industry this security
industry on the whole
now all companies are trying to find a
their own approach you because
issues arise and many companies prefer
to focus on the
something
very narrow for instance so companies so
that
only do Chinese target the text they do
it well
but they're completely ignoring
all other threats and very own phone
they don't have protection from malware
from other state
and it's no no joke one of such
companies still does not have
any Regine detection
where we started what kind of origin:
never heard about the
this name and I'm so
or what's happening when we have from
ideological battle
among countries and when companies says
ther
to play on once I start to be siding
or play it over national to
trying to fight to the
nm is and they're paying no tension
any malware
any other malware this is where you
there firm
many people selected but we selected
something else
the city's the
picture about company's server
specialized sir
on Chinese attacks so
first this crowd strike infographics
where 41
group
so 41 group of Chinese origin has been
detected
so everything they find is China and
I love and the
respect crowd striker have many friends
for
and they even I'm wearing the t-shirt to
but it is safe simple and safer
you know ever freeway but we
have decided
to do differently we decided to
to make no exception for malware
of Western origin or Russian origin
E with take their
latest most famous examples we
phone starkness do call
and others equation
that we discovered in February and then
we also have the same least
for Russian names me do Red October at
spy
cost me Duke and a pic to return why
did you decide
to study nation-state malware
their to
thousand pick one question that's
the movie the most interesting thing
over the last few years and all the
threats
can be looked upon as a pyramid
where they largest a bottom way here
is there conventional malware
by the people who want door total to
send spam
now
deaf event that the steal money from the
banks it's over ninety percent
of that traffic three hot 300,000 new
samples every day
them and family here that has to do
was targeted tax so hacker group who
can were ca by order
were that Kim worker you know
at random if we still something we shall
find a buyer for it
that's their motto
so some hackers are anonymous and
ideological AT&T very little
we will share our farm detected
attacks that have been originated
by government by states that bad the big
the juiciest beast in the security
industry
so today we
show have a discussion where
we'll try to
come see either the both coins
work both sides of the coin as we
publish all reports
we present at various conferences but
offline we meet people sometimes
who probably
have to do with those malware
software we may
read something we may you learn
something else was a great crime
and it
enables us to I am
think like those people on the other
side
how they do it why do it and want to
think about us
and today so
over on behalf of those says hooks their
vitaly
is going to talk on behalf of the
cyberspace
my name is vitaly and they work now no I
I don't work anyway serious
so
for for the last ten years I have been
working in Kaspersky Lab but
no I he I am NOT working anywhere
I'm not officially employed so I'm
I can now speak on behalf of the other
side and
I'll protector I'll defend the
the state to owned a
malware services we're just better you
seem cool
we you wear the the the suits still
our office no we address the in a
comfortable
casual style we're not wearing any
insignia
then we have unlimited to access
to
the Internet and a differently
we have intercity interception over
is it best to fiber optics we have the
best programmers
may have guys quit doctor for us and
limited budget
who can have more and
most important to us. waiting here how
are you going to make a presentation to
make it compliant we don't care
we are compliant because we are as a law
so speaking about the anti-virus company
different we home
we who look up to them we
have for limited budget we have some
30 percent R&D of the budget for 444
for research but those people have been
concerned though they don't have to
spend on marketing and sales so
while we have to and the
we for are in permanent search for a
good balance
researchers and indeed sometimes it
takes years
to find a good expert
for instance Kaspersky Lab
virtually well for two years have been
searched Ching
for the experts in Israel well
seems to be a country that's packed her
with a good programmers and security
guys but probably
its I'm her our plank is too high or the
situation is so poor
that it takes a two years to find the
proper guy
but then no no no they have been working
for you for a long time you didn't just
know about it
well that some that's an option anther
angry year
indeed we improve our technology
probably is a breakthrough
revolutionary event has become the cloud
in particular we call it karma Kaspersky
Security Network this is
our main tool which enables us
in a real-time to detect
new attacks globally we used to wait
before when the user's find something
suspicious
for in this computer send it to us then
we have a look
and then we detect and we don't know
their holistic situation
now 8 hair
has turned around completely we can find
it
easy we fastly and a no matter where we
kind of you know go like to a
supermarket hey let's have a look
what are the suspicious files in Vatican
we have clients in Vatican to clients or
in not in the North Korea
and in this way in the region us who we
are where we
we can suspect some threats weekend
easily find them so we have a really
cut the response time we understand the
for what we are looking for is just the
tip of the iceberg
probably one percent of all the target
that tax arranged by
nation-state to agencies
but differently we see that there's much
more but we focus on a single
task in this situation we need to
protect
our users people pay this money people
trust us so we need to
protect them independently all the
origin of this malware is it and
an individual hacker once
22 inches while it or escape
who wants to control this guy there's no
difference
so that's why we were how we work thank
you for the clout
because it goes through I'll Fibre
Channel and their
let us arrange a small
show of the arguments and I would like a
to show here that you are free
to 'em side up with us
dark side or the white side and we would
request you to vote
for the strongest arguments so as for
the zero-day vulnerability
we have unrestricted unlimited excess
we have our own exploiter
writers there's black market who which
where you can go and
anonymously by any exploit for any
product
we have our favorite
vendor least but we prefer
colonel exploits
because their them most efficient we can
now
be successful once and that's it
then you don't have to worry
and chose to build your infrastructure
when bitterly says
that they have many 0 days that's true
but its their week wink
in the chain veer
exactly zero day addictive every target
attack
arranged by estate try
uses 0 day von their ability
and that when I go back two years so
that we spend the fighting there
conventional as cybercrime urs so 0 they
probably you know we could detect once a
year
but when we look at their I
government state a software we discover
now several 0 days a year
so somehow 0 days for Windows
and Doman Java now search for these 20
days is our favorite
pastime as to stimulus impetus
why because sir virtually always
even we find that there
something new 0 day that's us yeah
and tell you more we
target our technologists in products
and are traps technology and collection
technology
exclusively 40 day search
we focus not so much
malware exports find
you find that the rest this is a
starting point
you to on wrong you know role
row rollout the change in to
permanently use more and more 0 the Acer
and for them their problem
is after we find it the immediately lose
a law lot of tools of their
efficiency and efficiency really goes
down
and its ones we discover this zero-day
veer you years
of their activity are down the drain I'm
have you ever
gone mushrooming to forest have you ever
seen
mushrooms that somebody collected and
put that's what you're getting guys
alright tell me as for the crypto
we finance it
we boost
your mind sir so that you would the
great wonderful crypto algorithms and
then
we can sign our own
malware with wonderful certificates
that we disseminate and you believe that
they use wonderful cryptography and you
can trust
the digital signature we define three
force you to select
the proper on stamps and we create
standards once you deviate from this
standard you are not
so-called orthodox programmer
and to for
our home malware we select right cost us
with more D
fireball algorithm so for you know
was a do we just send their trash
to people but we and crypt our protocol
in a very secure way
well when you sign your
malware with a certificate Microsoft
this way you actually Subhash
the bases of information security
across the globe yes all
infrastructure of crypto keys
is built on trust there is a
certification center
that issue a certificate so that should
control
the execution and everybody believes
this system
is built on trust and at a certain
moment
where getting air mister come look
from and ABC Company who just a
well-taken
use certificate Microsoft certificate
sign programs and then Microsoft has a
to re retreat took her to revoke all the
file some
met lots of problems what's your last
name
services this is
so we're doing everything is to make you
happy in more words
we have examples of successful
you solve our fighting attacks feel some
date
when the state computers trying to
download
the Windows updates &
Windows Update something else in store
also spy
software is installed will stay the
Windows Update so any
similar technologies so they destroy
the security environment and
become such a release your and and the
use of Halle
types of crypto algorithms sites can
never
around iraq for us and thus overlook
have to so file which communiques
server and
and screw encrypting the data
and so the c6 algorithm for example
so whole president left in the world
gone can use this
horses 6 so they're quite or very few
okay organizations like that who can use
such
freshen your pressure developed
algorithms
and this by the way a sign at work or if
I such a tax is the most challenging
and we attributed to and they're so we
think that
estate has initiated this one Hesse
because
RC 6 being so complicated so if you want
something
simpler to use Camelia another point
our her mile away is the best its
the most complex and where do the
research cybercrime research and
so overuse zeros more miles so this is
just nothing so serious and
peanuts compared to you this one so you
think that you sent the
said the plank said the site Sam
law no hackers it's not so they saw this
the so this at the target was set for
much higher and
many how much earlier than you did
summer where cyber crime is nothing her
because cuss our modules no one sees
no sono no one sees our old kids
because will not work try again where
you will not be able
I think of a looking for us and because
we have many
attributes over your standard file
systems
and so we put all his best together we
can and compression
in encryption and we can keep our own
files inside
no one would what's it mean Iran idk for
a
and an advanced IT guy work people I
would even think that this file system
could be
about on top of this kind of stores and
history
for camp even a so we can now
output viruses in your hard drives and
so we can do anything say micro Colts
can be
had damaged as well can be in fact it is
well we can do the
is this infection and the south and
malware Harper inserted into the hard
drives
and so then in fact it hard drives
sorry so that's that's a bad thing
for a surprise for us sign for acting
the hard drives
and I can tell you that it's a great
challenge for us
right now sir there is no a single
technology in the world right now that
would be capable
homer taking out of the system
identify the changed to
to change that software because for
example
your your hard drive for hasn't been
modified with the help of this program
or not
and
and soured on the way to fight to this
thread is
if you suspect that your hard drives
have been compromised
so don't have to do is just to take your
hard drive and
and destroy it with a hammer and a and
throw it into the garbage can trash can
as the only way to fight for
this malware Anderson hatcheries
modulus so they're so the
days to have so those who refuse to how
to do business with us
have this this in fact that more jews
constitution is not as bad yes it on
your roster
to represent because the more technology
the use
the better they try to hide Adams to
hide the infected files and the system
so using the core of the system so the
more they attempt to do that
so the more the
the more chances that will find them
will find because what we're trying to
her I saw
Kansas helps us to find a way to to
fight with firmware
there's no breakthrough unfortunately
but detection on the FS system said and
parsing is quite possible
Anderson taking the hardware looking for
so malware module so so this has been
done to it it's a standard
de facto her system so we can see that
the southern army officer protection
which risk and can
can fight those attacks in the
guaranteed fashion
and suffers daily users spokes
and indeed getting to the Turkish has a
traditional cyber
criminals and what is it reading
this Canada sup across any this
subsector discreetly
this work unit now and their and so
there is no defense
against us and your you think so we
cannot defend
defend yourself against terror attacks
so remembering
how budget and and our capabilities it's
impossible to fight against her
so even if you try we can attack you
from different things work and explore
I work and go through your provider for
example that provides data centers
hosting internet channel so we can go
through your provider
and if ur the difficulties with the
provider
we we're headed in fact country and
so they would only way out so then the
so we can just go through the fiber
optics to the
think internet or
or just for her on a budget that's your
watch ever satellites
can hair put our own centre-right some
next to your satellite that would
intercept
hold the waves and all the transmission
signals
go to the for the
your satellites will everything
solutions racial
intercepted by our I am
I I don't know what to say
because the things that those guys are
doing so the quite
censor it difficult to to stop
very difficult 27 difficult to identify
and isolate them
therefore can stop in later said because
when the company under attack
or our individual cannot possibly
protector
himself for with the help of available
technologies
because there's always Alamosa level at
which
an attack kar occurs but such a
actions force different countries in the
world tour
develop injured you're certain you level
so protection at the national level
and I was stalking server has ordered
everyone wants to two separate their own
national side
on the internet and build their own and
develop their own rules because this is
certainly the implication I work
and they were snowed in force them
because either slow then told the truth
through the whole world in how the
special agencies
United States are spying on the Internet
and
some not just you all know that Russia
recently has taken a lot
are steps not on a nice lady about
technical I'm efforts to isolate those
segments
but now the situation is the task have
protection of companies corporates
a the individual so living and a certain
state
his responsibility of the state now and
there is no higher
to authority
and and the service riotous these
budgets
so we'll have to fight other countries
budgets and eventually it will be a
hassle
erase a snowball
under the problem most noble and this
will ensure air
so the so the burden
will will well well several
before every company so we would use
because we're
needs to be implemented would be
implemented by the state
this August making it easier for the
company's factory
and then so they would beat them strip
that too take measures to just try to
destroy the security system
are home the or the state sorted 10
to to invent have a virus that would
destroy the system
they will not go around AntiVir solution
so they will replace
with someday with her with the
compromise to
severe Windows updates without windows
update
if you do not release patches so you not
install them
so everything everything just chill will
stop functioning so
I saw it here in Chinese so well will go
and start hacking
all the computers and campaign in the
world sort people
are apps destroying what day
need themselves for their so I'll so I
did I just trying so this
this sacred cow updates window updates
and
so than in 2012 gore was saying at the
time
did not know about the 75 collisions
and Ashley Moser said a judge generator
so I falsa microsoftr
certificate one-on-one completely
combine was king coincided with the with
illegal
certificates instead of cryptography
dick
the
the cartographers so another tour
on the 10 or 10 persists in the world
mathematicians
the highest level can do that her so and
then
have huge computing power they require
only ten persons were can do that
and so very few countries can do that
pursue their
so they're ready to go to that expense
to
replace one certificate with another one
but at the same time
days infrastructure security in general
gets destroyed
and and that's why it's a dub double
hedged
a sword that will
that will stab you in the back
eventually given a
no updates a summer produce a small a
small amber saver can hack
there so we can do something else are so
your progress report you have the
prospered updates
down the whole world his shaking with
fear
so let's talk about the victim so who
are you attacking
with the King work in attacking Iran
so we don't have to be modest everything
is legal
providers do some operators here it
all Kiss Kiss Kiss Kiss cutter does
anyone
jean-jacques is Qatar do have any crypt
over for us here
doing you know kiss his cutter
kiss Carter person Belgian tripped over
for
and we were helping him to to select the
this magic Constance
that work the best she she spoke about
that
and and us are here
is Makosi to
political political
for some has no direct access to the
computer works
Federer through me so any nenu victim so
when makes them with terrorists are
using the same cold
so once a written euros everywhere so
very efficient
and the works miss the profession so
these guys
i doing Harley this here they're saying
that they're doing on your work is legal
so they keep saying that they love it
surveyed appeared as a mentor
and that the foldable from
and the and comply with the law but once
we have to study this attack
any kinda but accuracy that that
the that the victims are her specific
conversant you
different plan so victims and when it
when it goes to insure the public domain
and
and becomes known to everyone so there
despite this espionage was illegal
this act of spying was not only illegal
but to destroy the relations between two
states
brought about many many conflicts eso
the
hacking farrakhan that's what the hell
for the combat warm
has some behind which the British
Special Services
stilled yes I'm not only brought about
the parliamentary
hearings in the into dudes Belgian
Parliament
the problem was escalated was created to
the level
the turkey in Union
the her because to two countries members
are the see your and in a two-member sir
and her us they all were concerned is it
legal
long definitely not was illegal and the
and what they do so the they stop for
the policeman 28 doughnuts not they
the restricted they restricted the
relationship with the
with the British special services
because
can bring about to the the worsening on
general
relations sir so much using the same
malware platform to attack different
victims
and missus one of the strongest one of
the biggest challenges
for the for the government spies
because what we need to do is to find
one module and then we immediately find
all modules
because there's always a platform so
there are more juice
and then there is a certain handling
infrastructure so getting the module you
get the platform in them
and then the way identify midler all
victims along with the world
irrespective for
ok with a heart and it and it was saying
about the
america's hate this is a real story and
their
and are not
are not naming this mill where program
reckon course in earnest ignition the
way
came to the company were found one of
the victims in German
and a so the only the only victim in
Germany
actually and hi you
you heard that custer's killer oratory
for
forecasters the worker Germany is one of
the biggest national markets
powerful car spares your lap and they
have good relations
where with the German police and so or
maybe you have the biggest market
because
because we have good relations with the
police and they're so we
were transferred all the information
that we have identified
to them in
or Sunday detailed a special group for
for check
and ass after house are you hit the
jackpot guys
hand and within say
who is the victim but her but they were
very grateful
this that we hit the jackpot finding the
the victim
because the plank was very high and the
person who are so high
so high standing person dead and never
came across as before
and on Sunday Merkel's a
Reese there were some mentions about
this underwent when the programs I use
to simultaneously
at the in fact the members of the
government's and
simultaneous to the same try on is used
in fact Islamic terrorists
and so we have no choice now
where I left no choice and finding these
things we have to talk about their
when there were no to when it to make it
does does reprieve providing
107 you're saving the world I was saving
not only from infection not not only
Merkel's ain't bad
the by the bad guys terrorists are saved
as well but you
you force us to do that and
so the Dells circus ex-nasa because the
play by the rules
and we churry don't work in you were
officially so
re so which do we don't have to comply
with the time
it's true
collect everything interest you
everything so we're just bad guys in
love collecting stuff
so a correct method data from your
documents
pasa Iran Iran remote finds a way even
if you insert
and a memory stick you think it's clean
it's not end there so we take your
remote
documents and we appropriate them site
under protective computers
way you're not year you're not safe from
the screenshots
and make screenshots captures keyboards
accordion
and your Internet traffic sign on your
no much your your favorite programs
everything and nursery you steal
everything we collect everything in
store care for
so the least is is endless and
writer not being modest three take a
call
and then one day we'll analyze sage is
better to say for sure
firms so then
does irresponsible thieves
from now this clip to clip the Manics
they all follow some this this is
propensity to
steel everything to catch everything to
intercept everything
and %uh so this this desire this urge
this urged to get as much as possible
under
sure so that can be easily caught
Patrick
because anti and and icky at anti
a keylogger attack works and it works
very well
and them so than so it looks like this
guy should refer
phat about them but the more the
contractor
Demi Moore their presence in this system
is is
is all this and a long as they steal
and hi these is huge
so they missed you too much traffic is
still a huge truck
which is easily detected
and especially so they're urge hurt you
to pump out this stole information in
of powers some on her and
someone at night for example at the
office
so the computer that no one is seeding
so all of a sudden it starts to send
G gigabyte so of trafficker
outside and the service is the weakest
spot
and that's right how to catch them
because we can
red-handed know what they're going to do
but not this is the simplest method
to identified and that the science that
that's old is
volumes of stolen data this is something
that allows
us at a later stage when the publisher
on income interest in
be can make too big news because
the media the media leave big love big
figures
so some resembled a nuclear energy
ministry of so done
prism they don't have such mister sir
they stole two megabytes
worth information and nothing say the so
the
the nuclear power industry yes I have
scorer said after terabytes of
data so then certainly the year so the
journalists love that kind of
figure those kinds of figures and
attracting the attention to what they do
so forces them to spend more and more so
since the change
programs to hide their activities
and to back on for them
so your numbers helping us us
we love those how many terabytes of data
we have stone and so maybe it counts
scores of terabytes of data helps us
to how to get good compensation
so when everyone starts praising us
so then I'll malware lasted
we we a right good mobile web picus
quality
throughout the best programming
engineers bath best
mathematicians and I'm always the best
don't make any mistakes most
and so we have the best encryption
we had amassed best matters of
compression sir can I can just
injure our algorithms just sorry
limited to change your archiving
missions the southern
summer can just write any any passive
developer
orchestrator some Module Manager adapter
have plugs in a into into the core
because if you're right in the core so
then the coach should be absolutely
immaculate that's how we are right calls
and our modulus not crash
maybe once in a thousand years
happens
yes out there developing wonderful no
have to give it to him but
we hashers searchers s computer geeks
some businesses most challenging part in
our workers
every thing find it turns out to be the
most challenging
interesting technological the perfect
and I remember trying to cram
when there were when Roy study found the
program's
percent now I got this is a top this is
the coolest
the coolest thing south the cold war so
wonderful so miraculous
assault human beings can do that
and then five years later service every
time so this plan goes higher and higher
and this is very interesting for the
analysis much more challenging
and then a than a Chinese have to lug X
you know continuous unexciting
stuff for and and the same time
Solr have a lot to
to pick at the dick inside the
called system and a cursory public today
in the cold because very few specialists
so can't
do such researchers because this is the
at this is the top
her how to reverse engineering and so
certainly love to look for mistakes and
the same time we come across sir
a little bug in this ideal cold that
that took years to
be put together and %uh so find a small
mistake sir
which crushes the entire system a
herself for example crypto algorithms
other systems crashing on stacks so they
they found it on a bit closer on the
computers crashed so that time and froze
all the time and then it started study
hall what caused it
Anderson if these guys make a mistake to
make
huge egregious mistakes and then I have
to accept the consequences
and certainly the have the printer
problems
problems ripcord but called quality nasa
sensors
founder yeah so its military on that yes
we have in our
surveillance in our staff
so and here there's a crash is their
fault
knows illegal migrants from space
her so they aliases their fault we don't
make in Reseda more to get into the core
the more a day be the
increased incidence of Crocker of
crashing this system
and a and then that's what exactly
we're looking for this and this we start
to dig at once
you make a mistake and can go for the
jugular
technological description system in this
state
so if we see the computer crashes hand
there then certainly there's something
interesting
behind if after this presentation number
of circles
so will decrease he did decreases
for this certain related to the
improvement of the quality of cold
so let me let me
draw some conclusions from prime whether
we have been
discussing certainly what we call
sophisticated to complexity
of any target a tech is automatically
at a medical attract our attention them
or
a a sophisticated the attackers
the higher the opportunity it's done by
the state
then them working with the kernel where
children were taught files
burma hardware eighties
to the the the that triggers you know
for instance
infecting their at Merkel's aid we
immediately
starter running gives us a a
it triggers our activity zero-day
attract attention that because it's
interesting its route 40 useful
and the crash of this is to move the
system
Crashers say for attract attention
so massive infections
in specific areas if we see that the
same
malware keeps attacking power companies
across the globe
immediately 8 becomes attractive
so whatever we do we just do our job we
respond
to this things that they themselves
me a give a give us a cool
they cannot work different things they
have to the rule have complicated
program software with rootkits 0 days is
a need to infect specific targets that's
what we use to catch them
to bait them so Eve Hui go back to the
first live to when we see that last year
we published 11
articles on research so faces the result
are froze the quick adjustment
so far
team to such threats we can find a quick
find it quickly and
thoroughly and probably make the world
better
and safer okay
report to my process will manage so
we still have some time for Q&A so let's
about and I want a question
I want to vote okay scream at him
party's over to the visible know so are
you jobless as well
just like me look
we didn't start this arms race we didn't
think was not us
they started and this eternal
conflict you see you first we have for
better arms and ammunition and then we
have better shelled
better shells armor yep
I agree that me damage them
we harm them Bay hell tomb
incur a multi-million costs but our
costs are much less per billion here
give or take a billion here expenditures
yes its to you contested
how much does it cost to find in
we the moon it is pointless
so so what kind of currency are you
using
dollars have you ever thought about the
vulnerability zero-day cost on the black
market
100 Sohus percent it's not the cost
differently but the cost probably if you
divided by three
by to roughly rules
and indium
nothing is cheaper than any Indian guy
an Indian developer
know we are looking for the box
its us some like mushrooms
but have they found it have the develop
the bugs so it's an open question I'm so
okay time to vote
so raise your hands for a bit early
voting is an progress so
attending yeah with the arguments you're
all mine
and the rest are working for us
the others are working for me
yeah ship and and some people have not
decided yet
so loop the same presentation
a few days ago was made by
our colleagues in London
at issue and spokes conference a small
room people
only from the government area show you
know what was the count
further
fred's 44
.1 44
versus one you can't anti
virus company essentially are driving
are fighting a losing battle
we have
chances but we shall see
should school if used to you
work somewhere come to us yet unemployed
and they join us thank you