good morning I realized that I'm the
last speaker before the lunch break
sulfur I make this relatively quick and
get us all out to lunch this
presentation is based on some work that
was done for the IETF traffic
engineering working group we produced a
best current practice document that
documents how cable wireless traffic
engineering on our IP backbone I'm going
to go over the material is presented in
that best current practice as well as
some of the background material to that
and then I'll open up for questions if
anyone has any questions they don't ask
here my email address is on the slide
you can feel free to send me email so
again the scope of this is to present
how CMW does traffic engineering and
some of the reasoning behind it this is
not the one true way no matter what some
people might think I believe after
private discussions but this is the way
that works for us and has been fairly
successful using it for a number of
years originally cable and wireless at
the time internet MCI was one flat layer
of routers on its network and that was
through 97 98 on 96 or thereabouts-- the
ds3 direct router to router circuits
were replaced with OC 3 ATM circuits and
the routers were completely meshed over
an ATM course so every aggregation
router on the cable wireless network was
mesh to every other router on the cable
and wireless network on the internet
John network time then in 1998 we had a
network event we added six or eight more
routers in somewhere in Chicago I
remember if it was Willow Springs or
downers grove but it was enough to push
the poor 7,000 at the time Cisco 7,000
Sauveur the edge as far as igp
calculations and we had a complete igp
meltdown it was an educational
experience as an educational experience
that lasted about a week as we rebuilt
the network and got everything stable
again at that point we decided that we
need to add some hierarchy to the
network to reduce the flat IGP mesh at
the time of the event there were over
380 routers in the mesh accounting for
approximately 30,000 PVCs in the network
in each router was maintaining
approximately 760 direct ITP
associations again very flat not a lot
of traffic flowing over those IGP
associations or routing information
because every router was directly meshed
but still a little bit too much for the
7000 s and earlier 75 hundreds to keep
up with but first bullet point is the
same as the last one the last line must
been doing this on a plane or something
currently in since 1998 we've added a
level of hierarchy so now aggregation
routers I should have a diagram here and
I don't I'm sorry aggregation routers in
a pop are meshed with other all the
other aggregation routers in a pop as
well as the core routers in a pop and
then the core routers in each pop or
mesh to every other core router in every
other pop so we have a two layer two
level mesh fairly common today that
means that for us there's no more than
any router 80 no more than 80 routers in
each
in any particular igp mesh the the one
of the things that we do do now getting
this in a minute as we do calculations
of all of our traffic engineering layout
offline so before we added the layer of
hierarchy it was taking us approximately
four hours to calculate the traffic
engineering layout of the network using
some homegrown tools with the decrease
of the diameter of the meshes in
discrete meshes that time period that
time has gone down to about 20 minutes
we've also done some soccer optimization
but the big thing has been going from
meshes that calculated 380 routers in a
mesh two routers two meshes to calculate
no more than 80 in a particular mesh the
one thing on that hierarchy as well as
we do run to layer are two level is is
the core routers sitting level two and
each pop the aggregation routers and
core routers in each pops sit in level
one so the core routers are the level
one level two meet point online versus
offline cable wireless is an offline
traffic engineering shop we do our
traffic engineering offline we don't
allow the routers to do it in normal or
even in most failure scenarios we like
to know where our traffic's going and
like I said calculating optimal networks
on our software today still takes
approximately 20 minutes to lay out a
complete done network with both primary
and backup routes that's on dedicated
Hardware now using dedicated resources
with we believe that doing that online
and taxing processors to do that online
they're not going to be getting optimal
solutions or your solutions may be
changing over time
as resources come and go on the network
we'd much prefer to do this offline and
pre-plan all our primary backup routes
we also do traffic engineering so we do
it offline and we do it at layer 2 not
layer 3 useful utilizing igp metrics
some other people have mentioned here to
adjust traffic flows on an IP network
lead to a network-wide and sometimes
usually unplanned affects a large
network due to flooding ie if I adjust a
metric on one link to steer traffic from
say Chicago to New York over a different
set of links I might have the unplanned
consequences of pulling traffic from LA
to New York over those links as well
unless you're very very careful the
equivalent for those of you ever gone to
county fairs or state fairs the midway
game where you take a mallet and you hit
the head of a groundhog that pops out of
a mechanical groundhog that pops out of
a hole and soon as you hit it and the
one pops up somewhere else similar
effect when you start playing with igp
metrics on a very large network as you
adjust metrics in one place to resolve a
local problem you create problems in
other localities so our belief is we
prefer to layout the traffic flows at
layer 2 and use IGP simply for link
failure detection
in our case we use the IGP our igp is is
only for link state signaling and in
normal and most failure mode scenarios
so every element on the network has at
least two paths laid out over separate
layer two halves to get to every other
element on the network either its core
router or another aggregation router or
between core routers therefore is is
simply indicates that the link is
available it's really not used for
routing the only time would be used for
routing as if both the primary and
backup links went away due to different
failure mode group failures where we
lost both the primary and backup
resources at which point I GP would be
used to find a multihop route to the
destination on the network but that has
very rarely happens on our network I
could probably count I've been in kimmel
wireless three years they probably count
on one hand the number of times we've
actually had multihop failures one of
the things is our metric deployment we
really only use a small subset of
metrics because everything has direct
adjacencies we really only use two
metrics on the network one to indicate a
primary path one to indicate a backup
path we do MIT by a certain links as
expensive so in case of a multi-hop
failure we do end up using local
resources rather than global resources
to restore that failure so the example
would be we might use a metric of five
to indicate a primary route between
Chicago and New York we might use the
metric of 10 to indicate the backup
route and we might use a metric of 20
say to indicate for all links going over
the ocean which would prevent traffic
going from Chicago to New York that lost
both the primary and backup route would
pick another set of routes in the US
where
other than prom boning over to London
and come back over the global mesh so
things that add long latency or that are
valuable resources we tend to protect
with slightly higher metrics in case of
a double a double failure next is what
we're doing for our lair to traffic
engineering mesh since 96 it's been a TM
it's been a TM until last year when we
started a migration to mpls and
reasoning my grade and pls esa p.m. /
PVCs of ATM of PVCs traffic engineering
mesh work quite nicely except for the
ATM overhead and except for the lack of
high-speed router interfaces and there
are some others in there but all in all
we had no problems with using ATM at
worked it was a handy tool but the lack
of anything faster no c12 interfaces on
routers and the overhead on some
expensive links became a problem so we
actually then started looking for
alternatives and settled on mpls is
probably the most reasonably supported
solution from our vendors to replace ATM
we do treat it as basically in the
traffic engineering core there's
actually two separate mpls networks at
cable and wireless one network is a
network that provides MPLS based
services ie mpls VPN s layer 2 and layer
3 bpms and then there's the MPLS traffic
engineering court we do not allow those
two networks to touch the MPLS service
network actually rides over the traffic
engineering core and I can talk to
people offline until the two in depth to
go into here the time remaining the MPLS
traffic engineering core is really
created simply an ata and IP friendly
ATM actually it's more like frame relay
in fact i use frame relay resources i
use
frame-relay signaling to access that
mpls court we actually use CCC and we'll
be using martini and calf later to
access the mpls court not way the I GPS
of the mpls Corps are not shared with
the igp use of the IP network there are
two distinct I GPS that way a failure of
RF laughs and the igp network I mean the
IP network an igp flapping IP network
doesn't destabilize the traffic
engineering core and lead to one
unstable network trying to recover on to
another unstable network so we actually
use a PVC like signaling in this case
VLC is between the core routers and the
traffic engineering switches the MPLS
switches so the IG bees are between the
two networks are totally disjunct will
lambdas replace mpls in the cable and
wireless network um only time this would
really happen we would consider this
would be when the bandwidth required for
any router to router pair approaches the
bandwidth available from a single lambda
so until a core router to core router
flows say again on this case ones in
them to New York or Chicago to
Washington approaches 10 gigabits
there's really no reason to use lambdas
to using active traffic engineering
layer rather than mpls and in fact
there's some disadvantages to doing it
namely that for each lambda you need
very expensive router interfaces and
router and router space on the router to
places interfaces so if you're talking
about a fraction the core router decor
router flows being a fraction of a
lambda it makes more sense to aggregate
at the land at the MPLS label level
level rather than the lambda
the other is the cost report on an o exy
would need to be significantly cheaper
than the equivalent bandwidth port on
the MPLS switch that's probably a
reasonable argument you could make today
but both of those things have to occur
and before we would consider replacing
mpo us with a DWDM based traffic
engineering learn when that occurs we
would provision lambdas just like we do
the MPLS LSP is on our network today hi
they would be statically laid out and
they would be statically signaled static
and offline laid all laid out we would
also make sure we would add resilience
etc GM pls maybe the technology with me
we would use to signal those LSPs hang
those on lambdas dislike mpls is sit
used a signal LSPs today but I we would
not see merging the MPLS networking the
G MPLS network together those are still
be disjunct entities tools currently the
tools that we use complete the paths and
they configure the layer 2 and layer 3
equipment with those configurations are
all developed and maintained in house we
do sex some accuracy using tools like
opnet and wanda land some of the other
network modeling tools but the actual
devices that we use to measure to
measure the traffic flows and to
actually lay out the paths are all
in-house tools some of them have been in
in development for over six years a
continual development tweaks cycle and
some of you who have originally word
internet MCI and now moved on to other
places would be happy or horrified to
know that ATM gen still
cysts and is still being actively used
today so future futures today because we
run ATM as a static entity failures are
detected at layer 3 ie at the IGP level
so we lose an ATM linked today IGP text
that and selects the backup route with
mpls we are looking at doing that at
layer 2 rather than layer 3 which should
speed restoration times significantly to
do that we are looking at signaling with
RSVP to set up the LSPs a strict strict
route signaled LSP however we do not
plan using the resource reservation
characteristics of RSVP the network will
continue to be set up completely offline
and there will be no bandwidth
reservations for the individual LSPs the
bandwidth reservations will take place
in the offline tool and the traffic will
be laid out using the offline tool with
zero make a zero megabit per second or
gigabit per second reservations on RSVP
so there will be no bounding on the on
the LSP CEO space will be allowed to
burst to whatever diameter they need to
reach and we will continue to deal with
that statistically offline rather than
allowing the network can deal with that
dynamically password undhan see we
believe will grow from two to four paths
/ router pair making use of multiple
paths / LSP again as a restoration
mechanism we would prefer most failures
to happen without the igp layer 3 IGP
the IP igp realizing this when a failure
so we will probably end up going to four
paths instead of two to give us complete
resiliency across the entire network
whilst trying to hide has made the
failure
from the IP network as possible some of
the things we are looking at to better
optimize our network layouts and speed
our network layoff times is there have
been some developments and optimization
mathematics for circuit path layout on
circuit boards and analog circuit design
that we believe could be useful for
laying out solving the network path
optimization problem and we will be
investigating those as possible
algorithms to deploy in our tool in the
future so the other things is today this
traffic engineering court only handles
public IP Internet backbone that i EAS
3561 this traffic engineering core
though is not necessarily limited to
just carrying IP traffic as an MPLS
based core that uses DLC eyes to ingress
to it we could theoretically layer other
services on top of this I an MPLS
service network which would offer VPN
services technically even voice over
mpls or other services that we might
eventually decide to put over the
traffic engineering core and share one
common set of resources could be laid
over this network with no impact and
that's the end of the presentation so I
thought at this point opened up for any
questions hi my name is still Norton
from equinix I really enjoyed your
presentation I found it interesting for
one that the offline approach was used
for you guys I'm furious first how often
do you do that process and make the
adjustments on your network maybe you
said it I just missed it sure are sorry
about that guys for popping to Mike we
normally do our bandwidth layouts about
every six months or thereabout so you
normally happens a couple times a year
if we have a significant loss of
resources on the network say like loss
of a whole undersea cable system we may
do a tactical redesign of the network
because usually undersea cable systems
take weeks to fix but in the case of a
terrestrial cables failure we usually do
re plan around that because those
logistics in terms of hours or a day or
two so the network is usually reap
landed about it six-month interval
unless there's a major a major hit
somewhere so i'm guessing the
utilization is relatively low of the
bandwidth you have available the
utilization we actually because we're
running a traffic engineer Corps for
about the last six years i have six
years worth of trend at a couple men
intervals for every router to router
pair on the network so i have fairly
good statistics on growth patterns say
of traffic from New York to Chicago or
from London to LA that I can draw upon
and basically plot curves out to say 9
12 months in the future factor in any
market conditions so really we plan
every six months but we use bandwidth
requirements for about a year out every
stick at every six month planning cycle
so we're always a period or two ahead of
ourselves okay and then one last
questions because there are people
behind me they've been chat offline
afterwards the analysis you made about
router to router pairs and the 10 gigs
being sort of a point where you would
prefer to use wavelengths I was curious
if that was simply a financial analysis
or is that really a broader analysis and
that is a price for a bit point here
hitting it's more than a financial
analysis if you're only going to be
flowing a gig or two gig or three big
across the link between two router pairs
why drop to one expensive 10 gig
interfaces on your on your mpls traffic
engineering switches and to why waste
the front panel bandwidth or the front
panel capabilities of that box and going
to put some interfaces on that box and
it's much better for you to try and pack
as much bandwidth in the available real
estate as possible otherwise you're
going to be for flipping that box
earlier then you even do now
yes from don t the fact that you are
doing everything offline could you speak
up please sorry the fact that she'll
doing everything offline does it mean
that you have only explicit honesty yes
explicitly routed all space right then
in case of failures then do you have
explicit buck up Phyllis p or how do you
manage that we basically have to
explicit LSPs each made up of to
explicitly routed paths yes just a
clarification for cement a question
today your explicit rotted LSPs are you
using RSVP to set them up or is that all
set up statically also there's Yves
sorry they're using RSVP to be set up
and as you're looking into we're out at
Blair to with set of IP are you looking
at local repair versus end-to-end LSP
with hair and have you looked at the
detour versus facility backup proposals
we're looking at what could best be
termed regional repair so I'm not
looking at local repair or faster you're
out what we were looking at is basically
end-to-end repair but the ends may not
be the entire end end of the network it
may not be the origination and
destination IP router there may be
multiple LSPs stitched together along
the path to give me a restoration time
of a certain number of milliseconds and
signaling any other questions
thank you very much