hi done well we'll see I'm Jeb lindson
from earthly and yes I wanted to preface
this with a few things I'm not here
really to talk about earthlink mostly
talking about other people and some of
its confirm rumors and hoping it will be
useful information but it's also a very
non technical presentation more business
oriented I wanted to acknowledge a few
people who contributed to it before I
really get started from earthly my
company Josh flies losses my partner and
crime now appearing coordinator equinix
pretty much all the guys Jay John Rich
rossman bill Norton they've all
contributed Sigma Brady folkert LC on
Karen Owens from EXO Craig's too Foust
key and the formerly of EXO martin levy
they had a lot of insight from Gipe
sasha firmer makmur yahoo brokaw price
and finally I guess Steve Milner from
level 3 has just sold us finally our
carnival c12 background in relation to
that it's kind of brokaw that pointed
out that the something that i didn't
really catch in the peering game the
thing that has really allowed the the
new aggressive appearing to happen with
tier 2 and content providers is
notwithstanding the low prices on
transit that we can get these days with
slow prices on transport so that is
really what started us off on the path
that we're on right now hope it's
interesting I think we got a little
diversion of the presentation up here so
I'm going to probably have to flip
pretty quickly through some of these
slides this I was going to hit this
anyway just for purely for convenience
these definitions tier 1 i'm basically
referring to in this presentation as
those who serve transit to others but
don't buy transit themselves tier 2 is
those who buy it from others another way
of putting it is just what I've got up
here on the board those who provide
transit or internet access to autonomous
systems and those who provide it to
individuals the next gen peering centers
it's been fearing centers is something
I'll talk about a little bit more here
but forget the idea very quickly and the
last thing that I wanted to say is you
also see the term nap in here quite a
bit when I refer to nap I mean a legacy
map of NFS days of yore in SF the the
things that I want to cover here very
briefly are the motivations of economics
appearing though I'll flash through that
quite quickly the cost appearing as you
know applies in history and then very
quickly things that have happened to
disrupt the market for peering
especially with regard to fear too and
content but also to some extent with the
tier 1 players and what those
disruptions are then briefly what I
believe that those disruptions will
cause to happen in the near future
address a little bit the fear
uncertainty and doubt factor which will
always get them making ideas and making
presentations and what expects what we
expect to happen in the future and there
are a good number of slides that I've
actually left out of this presentation
this is from an older presentation runs
about an hour but if you download it
will realize that there are a lot of
slides and backup which you can refer to
offline but I won't be talking to up
here the role of peering differs pretty
greatly between what I call tier ones
and everybody else to the top level tier
ones as you're probably familiar with
from the Mortons presentations mission
critical is the description for these
essentially if you're not buying transit
from somebody you rely for your business
on peering you have to have it and it's
essential to the business you can't
provide vows to your customers without
peering to the rest of us on the other
hand most of what we do is we use
peering to supplement transit in order
to save us money and in order to
increase the quality of our routes this
is not new information to almost anybody
here what I am going to propose that's a
little bit controversial is that fearing
is usually not mission-critical most of
us that again your mileage may vary as
it says they're there are some who
used puing so aggressively that if their
purines were to fall apart then the the
capacity that they built for themselves
would not allow them to run so most of
us we save money we improve our routes
but we can usually withstand a bit more
outages than someone like a Tier one
could for example the requirements
differ a little bit as well but I'm
going to slide over this one pretty
quickly the it flows along I'm going to
pass by this one this wasn't intended to
be here historically the cost of peering
had a lot to do with why we did it what
we essentially found was the cost of
transit a couple of years back made it
very easy for us to justify the peering
options that were available a couple of
years back these the numbers that are
here are real numbers but they're
actually a little bit skewed the transit
prices from a couple of years ago the
map prices for naps one two and three
there are legacy map prices but from
just about five months ago so you see
that if the price of transit where it
used to be it was really quite easy to
justify putting in circuits to peering
this is on a per meg basis and we'll see
this is this graph is similar to let you
see in some of the building Orton's
presentations I use his method for
graphing on the per megabit basis
justification was easy we saved
ourselves a lot of money and we improved
our routes but then we had a disruption
in the economy the economy of peering
because transit prices started to drop
just plummet rapidly suddenly appearing
is not a bad option but you really had
to be very very selective about how you
did it you can save money in certain
places but you have to be very selective
about how to do it if you're using a
legacy map and some of the legacy maps
you're not saving money on at all the
the next thing that it definitely kind
of started to happen after people
started realizing this and this is still
a while back is you realize pretty soon
soon that you can supplement or nap
hearing the private peering and this
works actually quite well you can get
prices down under a dollar
dollars per meg and the sixty dollars
per meg range without a whole lot of
difficulty the problem with this in turn
is that it doesn't scale all that
problem the fundamental problem there is
that when you try to scale private
peering on a circuit by Circuit basis
you have a repeated expenditure on
newports every time these circuits every
time and you frequently won't realize
more than anywhere between 20 and maybe
seventy-five percent efficiency on any
given circuit so there's really a limit
to how far you can go with this it's
still a great option there's no reason
to stop it but you might be able to do
better the largest tier 1 players as you
realize that the lower line representing
the cost of private peering versus the
upper line which is the new cost of
transit they realized that they had to
do better in order to have to be more
profitable fundamentally the profit here
is the area between the curve between
the top curve which they're selling for
and the bottom curve which they're
buying for innocence conversely with the
tea or tues and up here and content
providers rather than profit that's you
could consider that our savings the area
between the curve so anything we can do
to increase that is a good thing for
pure ones or for us that's the approach
is fundamentally a little bit different
so far and we'll see how that goes so
once they realize that they needed to
improve on this a little bit on pacify
this a little bit they came up with this
idea for large but at the top we've home
the Seven Sisters the the largest seven
tier one's got together and work on this
informal initiative called I don't know
it doesn't really have a name I call it
the next generation Piron initiative
like I said it's in the formal I'm sorry
you have a little better
okay they got together and realized that
the solutions that they had in place
we're not scaling as well as they'd like
to and so what they decided to do based
partly again on Bill Norton's economics
were to choose common facilities to get
into acquire fiber lights or at least
wavelength rights to them for a one-time
expenditure and then once they've laid
out the cash for the one-time
expenditure of getting in there just
tossing cables across the walls to each
other and peering at OC 48 OC 192 etc
this has a lot of advantages for them it
allows them to become more independent
from the ilex the air box to basically
any any provider and ascended provider
it improves their fault tolerance
because of the fact that they can choose
very specifically their own fiber routes
and make sure that these new facilities
by RFP have very high levels of
redundancy and fault tolerance in
general and the provisioning time is
fantastic once you've gotten the dark
fibers in there in the first place you
have complete control over how fast you
implement and deploy your services and
your new peering wings the largest tier
ones I'll skip over the next part the
largest tier ones have a great
motivation to be in there for peering
with each other and it's kind of unclear
at this point where they're going to
continue to peer elsewhere they probably
will but it remains to be seen looking
at it before and after very briefly this
is fundamentally the problem and you're
mostly familiar with it already if you
want if you were one of the so-called
Seven Sisters and of course these
acronyms are chosen completely random
the the number of links that you have to
pull up in each of the major major
peering markets which are about eight of
them are you know n by n n by n minus 1
over 2 which is in the newer version of
the presentation sorry but the problem
is you're still dependent on the our box
you've got terrible provisioning time
you're
mostly doing this at OC 12 level there
are a few SC 3 is left over but it's
mostly a c12 sometimes to bios to 12 and
if you can imagine laying a mesh like
this on one of today's metro sets of
fiber rings it you can really imagine
how extremely inefficient this topology
is on the other hand if you choose a
sailor peering center in a particular
area and you have a one-time acquisition
of fiber or wavelength you can very
easily just have what essentially
becomes a star configuration but of
course you're still working with full
rings and you have good quality control
over your fault tolerance each I've been
maintains their own ladders in the same
room just toss the cross-connect able to
each other it happens very fast and very
efficiently the next thing that happens
after this is not applicable so much to
the tier ones as at least largest tier
ones as the smaller to one's the tier to
use the content providers basically all
the rest of us recently what we've had
is the appearance not specifically of
Metro Ethernet but the ability on metro
ethernet to do VLAN peering between
diverse organizations there's their new
multi-point fast ethernet gigabit metro
ethernet services that will allow you to
do the vlans not just the point-to-point
VLANs but also multi-point and what this
fundamentally does you'll probably
notice of course that this is not a new
idea there's there are no new ideas in
here but the one thing that is a little
bit knew about this is that you can
suddenly provision a single port and
then over and over again provision more
and more piers on it it's not even just
eliminate appears you can pull up you
can use that same court for transit
connections you can use it for local
loops on your point2 points if you want
to the efficiency is the thing that
makes the big difference and if you can
see the yellow line there I'm sure you
can see it on at least some of these
projectors the cost point is
tremendously well it's much lower than
what we can usually get on a regular
points point service ps3's OC 3
Oh see 12 when you have to pay over and
over again for the court you can realize
prices on the order of thirty dollars a
Meg for 100 megs of peering to multiple
peers around a metro area and if you get
up to the gig level you're down in the
ten dollars per meg region which is just
vastly better than transit pricing or
for that matter traditional point2
points another look at what these
disruptions really mean we expect legacy
peering methods have already started to
lose popularity that people have come to
realize that they can just do better
cost wise now this is heavily moderated
by the fact that the level of the the
legacy appearing methods the maps for
example have a great many peers and you
get access to many of them at once new
things take time to take effect now some
companies at this point has had been
saying that they're staying in the naps
and we intend to stay in there not just
for the fact that they were saving money
but for the fact that in marketing your
services there's there's still the
impression that you have to be in the
naps to have a good quality service this
is a mixed bag as far as advantage
disadvantage now of course them still
have contractual requirements as well
the pressure has been increased in
general and across the board to find
cheaper peering methods well the next
the next gen tier 1 peering initiative
of the of the largest of tier ones has
caused several things to happen already
and I should probably break for a second
say the ones that I'm talking about here
are for example you may have seen recent
press releases by equinix there may have
been by one by level three and of course
snap of the Americas as well which is
kind of a not involved in the same RFP
process as the others but it was spent
in kind of a de facto next generation
hearing center from the beginning these
centers have started to draw the smaller
to your ones to them for the purposes of
fearing people have realized that once
we get in there we have the better a
better chance than any other place of
hearing with the largest
dear ones once the smaller tier ones are
in there with the big ones this draws
the tier 2's draws the content providers
basically anybody who wants to peer with
those above them start to gravitate
towards these new centers this has
already happened you can easily see this
in how rapidly the new centers at least
some particular ones have gained in
population just over the last four to
six months the other the next part of it
is that once you've got a certain
critical mass of everybody larger all
the tier ones tier 2's content this
constructed rabbit ate the smaller
players the miscellaneous players those
who just want to be able to have a
captive market for transit services and
I've got everybody who provides transit
in the whole region in one building have
been compete with each other and if you
want to just peer it's a great place to
do it so the question is what happens to
all the other colocation well don't
panic yet if you're in one of the other
colocation centers because the fact is
with the next disruption of Metro
Ethernet becoming a major viable option
for peering you find that every major
colocation Center in major cities have
already been met with one or in many
cases several players of Metro Ethernet
so it becomes very easy for you to
appear from where you already are
there's not the tremendous of need for
you to move on however well I'll get to
that minute the pressure will probably
increase to replace the legacy circuits
oc3 SOC 12 with Metro Ethernet that you
can realize higher efficiency on by
putting on more peers and the legacy map
viability has become already dependent
on their ability to accommodate Ethernet
links now this is I don't want to shock
anybody but this really is introduced
any of them of course casual
conversations just over the last few
days have showed that they all know this
and they're already working on next the
next option
very briefly i'm going to go over this
because you pretty much get the idea
already the old picture of private
peering looks something like this I an
attached to you to him to the old map
and the old map I get those guys over
there I get OC 3 as OC twelves but again
same with the tier ones the efficiency
is low the cost is high and the
provisioning time is slow the new
picture is I get one port in the
building and already in on an attached
by point2 points to several people I
attached to the public peering VLAN
which many other people can attach to
and if I'm lucky maybe the next
generation fearing center is willing to
even connect them connect to their
switch into the public peering VLAN
there's been some talk about this it
hasn't happened yet but we might get
lucky this is efficient cheap and fast
and it overcomes the low efficiency high
cost and slow provisioning that we had
before the last bit is just a few more
words about this metropolitan
multi-point pride appearing that is what
I've generally been calling it it
addresses some of the limitations but
not all a private fearing you can get
many pairs on the same court you can put
public hearing private peering transit
even point-to-point local loops on the
same chord and there are a lot of
configurations available so you really
need to be careful if you're going to
start with this it is a new service you
can pay by the port your utilization
allocation of bandwidth with bursting
they're the type of VLAN that you pick
is very much up in the air you may have
to pay more for vlans the the technical
options are there's a myriad and there
are many that haven't really been worked
out yet the broadcast limiting
configuration in our mac address
limiting and filtering the configuration
of the switch is the number of switches
failover etc private peering in this
level will probably not scale to tens of
gigabytes unless you know we scale it
with 10 gig Ethernet down the road but
that's if he will see when that happens
at the higher levels of peering you're
still probably going to want to
gravitate towards the curing centers
even with 10 DB from that it'll probably
be easy for you to get into the new
center with a single link and then start
throwing you know cables over the walls
as I said before it appear with multiple
people the last point on the metro
ethernet peering is that you only get
the best efficiency if everybody in the
metro area picks the same Metro carrier
that's a big part fear uncertainty and
doubt I'm going to breeze through this
really quickly is it unfair
non-inclusive anticompetitive we had
some emails about this a while back the
fact is it's only common sense and it's
not being limited to only certain
players if they were going to appear
with you before they probably still will
will this increase your transit prices
know if you go into one of these centers
you have a captive audience you can get
great competition between them what
about the old Colo as we said thanks to
the new chief Metro prices most of these
centers are very viable and they will
probably be pressing very hard into the
new markets to make themselves you know
value-added carriers even beyond where
they are today the tier ones are they
really going to do this that question
has come up a lot fact is it's really in
the long term the only viable
alternative and they've invested heavily
in it already but Metro multipoint why
start now the fact is you can start with
just a 10 gig link and you might as well
just start doing it for whatever you
want to do whenever you turn down
whenever you come to the end of the
contract you can pull up a new Metro
Ethernet you can start early you don't
have to put in a big commitment pretty
much any other people doing this only
have one year commitments anyway what is
the robustness of the service frankly
the robustness on the metro ethernet is
roughly the same as you would get on a
sonnet service some of the boxes are a
little newer but the redundancy schemes
are identical
finally what about the financial
stability the vendors that we're talking
about here that are in the game now like
sigmatel see on XO yates there's a lot
of uncertainty about the stability of
those companies the fact is you don't
have to commit yourself heavily to make
good use and save money in the short
term so just be careful use short-term
contracts and the fact is if they go
down you've probably already saved
enough money to pay for it by the time
they do just switch vendors technical
gotchas to watch out for the management
overhead is just what you're used to
again there's nothing new Under the Sun
this is not a brand new thing so your
management overhead is well what it
always was but you do have to be very
conscious of what the broadcast and
congestion issues are with the new
service because they will differ a bit
the bottom line is be careful through
your own research mitigate your risk
with short-term contracts if you're
going to get into this sort of thing
just watch out for yourself these are
vendors to watch I wasn't actually
intending to put this up here but a
number of these have already made
service offerings in this area a number
of them have rather scary press reports
or leather very nice press reports in
the recent month those are the contacts
I just reeled off a little while ago and
finally points of contact here at
earthlink anymore how long have you got
okay let me just get one other slide
real quickly what I expect to happen in
the near future the reason I want to
bring this up is because people have
already started to ask about this a
little bit I expect to see large
companies moving into the next gen
peering centers mid-sized company is
having a split between the mid side of
the next gen parent centers and new
peering Metro Ethernet peering and the
small companies will probably start
small stay small for a little while ago
with Metro Ethernet peering as a nice
new cheap substitute for the regular
private period and if they grow as they
grow they can migrate themselves into
the new hearing centers that's it
questions
I thought that was a very good
compilation of a lot of information that
people have difficulty finding so that
was very interesting hope so I guess my
main question about the metro area
ethernet I 2 comments one of the Metro
parrot metro area Ethan had one on the
peering supercenters the metro area
ethernet my concern is not what happens
if one of them goes bankrupt right not
that but what are all the one that you
had up there already went bankrupt and I
place a lot of money down a bet that
most of them probably will and so that's
an interesting because I can do the math
and see that they can't make money doing
that so that's where the Super Centers
you know there is the value chain of
bring all the people in and then other
people come and they could eventually
make money somewhere else so that was I
guess my first comment is it's difficult
to justify putting a lot of time energy
into something that isn't clear that any
of the companies will survive yeah
because I i would also disagree i think
a lot of tier tues you peering as
mission-critical whether it's for
marketing whether it's for quality
whether it's for cost they do view it
the other thing is that today it's not
actually clear that the ROI is there for
people who have existing tier 1 minus
networks to go to the Super Centers
because the mate pricing and quality is
sufficient I can get fifty sixty dollars
a Meg especially at OC 12 scale that may
change as some of the trends that you're
pointing out show up but I don't want
everyone to think that the ROI is
necessarily there today but good summary
in my opinion and thank you accent I
want to hit the first thing that you
said they're just a little bit from one
of the things that's coming on in
conversations just recently last couple
of days and with Martin over the last
few months is that the Metro Ethernet
thing is a new technology these people
may not stick around you never know of
course you got to watch carefully but
even the our box even the ILX have
started to realize that this is an
easily viable technical solution and
from what we understand right now
they're just trying to figure out how to
position it so as not to mess up their
sonnet service but I expect the Metro
Ethernet option
stick around you might see that bottom
line driving a little bit if it does but
one way or another once Pandora's box is
open I think the technology is going to
stay it'd be great to have that become a
tariff service although for competitive
reasons they'll never put it on tariffs
will be there you know nice hi I'm Jeff
agron with merit can you tell me what
the essential differences between the
opportunity was available to the old
naps in the new ones is it a
technological underpinning that's
changed is it just the newer centers are
newer and they get another chance and so
forth is it a difference in the players
what is the fundamental underneath all
of this that makes it work fundamentally
there's not a tremendous difference
right now it's the fact that it's a lot
of it is perception a lot of it is the
fact that because the I guess in the
seven major cities plus Miami which was
kind of a foregone conclusion people of
one common set of RFPs at the top level
for the tier ones to actually make a
commitment to go into there and they
quite visibly in you know vocally have
invested very heavily in getting an
implantation in the centers so you know
you can pretty much rely on them being
there once you've talked to them and
confirmed it for yourself of course that
is a big part of it right there a lot of
things that went into the RFP to
guarantee that it would have run into
some of the bottlenecks that the legacy
naps have run into for example being in
buildings that are in a very large very
expandable having lease options on new
buildings for example for very high
scalability the fact that in general v's
our vendor neutral facilities which is
an advantage but not it's not
unsupervised at their more and they have
new fiber plants going out to them from
just about anybody you could buy fiber
or connectivity from it's mainly
convenience the fact is any of this can
happen with the legacy maps as well
there is certainly the
opportunity for them to move in overcome
some of the bottlenecks that they've had
in the past and moving just a little bit
more of this listening for cost model
thank you thank you