I'm going to speak a little bit about
pseudo wires and also l2tp v3 here the
goals of this top of this talk this
afternoon is to first define the term
pseudo wire and identify its relation to
an LC bpn secondly is to show how the
studio wires can be used for network
convergence third identify where else TP
fits within the IETF pwe three working
groups framework in an overview of lttp
as a tunneling protocol for pw III over
IP and i'm actually going to get down a
little bit into the protocol details so
and leave more of the application space
to Jill who has been using UTI which is
a precursor to lttp in some of the our
Cisco products as well as he's going to
speak about LC TP going forward and has
some ideas that he has for using it so
assuming everyone still awake after a
little bit of protocol details then
he'll get into some more the application
space so first to shoot a wire it's kind
of a strange name it's sort of like a
wire but not really
it emulates the essential attributes of
relay or to service so this is this is
actually in the pseudo wire PW III
framework document talks about this but
basically the idea is to take your frame
relay your PDP or t1 your Ethernet
what-have-you and create an emulator
wire over your core network or or
whatever your packet switch network is
so the standardization is actually going
on within the IETF pwe 3pw III is pseudo
wire edge to edge emulation the three
e's there making the III so here's a
picture I'm going to talk a little bit
about the layout but again leave the
rest
so Jill in this picture you see a core
IP network with your serial lines or two
lands Ethernet LANs or what have you and
the tunnels connecting them you're
probably seeing this kind of thing
before anytime you're talking about l3
VPN so essentially a collection of
pseudo wires together creates your l2
VPN so one of the applications for su
dividers network convergence and
variety of types of network convergence
today so this is kind of a very simple
one I think I grabbed it out of some
marketing slide somewhere basically you
have your parallel networks before your
IP backbone and the frame relay backbone
if you can call it that and I substitute
it in Miami here but anyway some global
backbone and your maintaining both of
them the idea is after you go through
the convergence you still have your one
global IP backbone but you can still
have frame really connectivity outside
the outside the backbone at these
different points of presence so what
this is really doing here is tunneling
over IP now one one note here PW III in
the in the ITF actually covers any
transport of MPLS as well okay and some
of the draft party me and stuff which
were the basis for this so it's actually
PW III is extracted above the packet the
PSN and the PSN the packet switched
network can be IP or MPLS okay that's
how the standardization effort is moving
forward in my talk today I'm talking
more about if your core network is IP so
there's no MPLS here and l2tp being the
tolling protocol to provide the service
to handle the layer 2 connections over
your IP network so 3 tunneling
requirements the do PW III over IP I've
distilled down to here there there may
be one or two more but these are three
important points first you need an
efficient layer 2 tunneling and
multiplexing encapsulation because
you're sending these layer 2 going to
point connections all over your network
so the lttb v3 encapsulation is is
actually quite simple if you look
between your right above your IP packet
is just a simple 4 byte session
identifier is the first thing you see
and this session identifier is designed
to be optimized for the fastest lookup
possible once your IP packet arrives at
your edge node in addition there is an
optional cooking
field and we'll talk a little bit more
about what the cookie does but it's it's
another opaque field that is used for
integrity checking to make sure that
when the packet arrives and you do the
session lookup it really really really
really is for that particular tunnel and
then you have your payload and inside
your payload is all your framing and so
on and so forth and this is different
for every type of pseudo wire okay so
and this is actually what's defined more
in PW III is the stuff above the
tunneling and the lttp provides the the
tunneling over IP for this the second
requirement for tunneling PW III over an
IP network is easy tunnel setup easily
extendable and an easily extendable
method for signaling pseudo wire line
events state changes etc so that lttp we
have a control plane now lttb in its
simplest form is nothing more than the
encapsulation than you saw a moment ago
but that lttp in its simplest form lttp
also has a control plane that as we see
on the slides here it's a simple in-band
control plane for tunnel setup and
maintenance so if you want to set up
your tunnels using using this control
plane I'm actually go through the basic
steps on how to do that that's what DB
operates its own unreliable datagram
protocol that operates in band over the
CETA wire or between the PE through te
routers this is documented as part of
RFC 2616 one this is not mu delta t v v3
this is the same one that we've been
using for years and years and years it's
also copied into essentially with some
since you know different wording and
such into the lttb base draft and there
are some slight modifications some of
them that were simply a result of the
interoperability experience that we've
been gaining over time and actually
we're taking out of an lttp dist draft
that we had that's now defunct
it's also designed to easily set new
messages and definitions for reliable
delivery across this channel this is
and we've had numerous drafts that
actually define this to set up phasers
for setting up an lttp control
connection or for a pseudo wire for
tunneling is begins always with the
control connection what we call a
control connection between two PE
routers this is three simple messages
for starting as a request to reply and
then it connected so the three-way
handshake that says here I want to be
able to set up tunnels with you and has
a few features like optional
authentication which we'll talk about
and things like that and you can also
advertise you know in by the way I
support these types of pseudo wires
what do you support so it's a simple
three-way connection and once that's
established you have the ability to send
whatever reliable whatever messages you
want reliable between those two points a
little bit like TCP here but it's
simpler and it operates in band so that
as I alluded to in the previous slide
the lttb control connection includes
this optional challenge handshake mutual
peer authentication that mechanisms
establish identity this is just a very
this effective this is a very simple
honest man block between the two edge
points to make sure yes you are who you
say you are it's not exactly once the
control connection is established
multiple tunnels which announce the TP
we refer to tunnels as sessions may be
set up automatically as needed you want
to bring up five you wanna bring at ten
you want to bring a thousand don't ring
at ten thousand okay it's all this is
this is the steps that you go through
just to automatically set those those
sessions up session established similar
to the control connection establishment
it's a very simple three message
exchange request reply connected and in
here you can identify I am the pseudo
wire type ok I'm operating in this mode
or what have you
once the tunnel is set up you can
maintain the tunnel you can maintain
line event now in the simplest mode of
operation again emulating the simplest
types of pseudo wires
you may not need any maintenance
whatsoever in terms of line events and
so on and so forth an example is just an
Ethernet or somesuch
but if you're trying to emulate a frame
relay and you want to actually it
depends on how faithful you want to be
to the layer 2 connection and you want
to signal your you and I and in and ie
them then you need some control can some
some ability to send a message to your
peer and Elsa TV provides a reliable
connection for that and a very simple
way to just fire a message through the
other side and we use this in our in our
PPP emulation with lttp in the past for
various line events list you keep your
state synchronized between the two
points with these control messages you
have the luxury of having a single keep
alive to cover all your sessions between
two edge routers so you have a single
keep alive that says yes my state is is
is the same on both sides and by
definition is the same on both sides
because even the signaling everything is
happening on both sides so this is just
a just a side point so maintenance
includes not only a very simple keep
alive between the points for dead peer
detection and so on and so forth but
it's also ability to send a message for
aligning this so TDM emulation that
actually is covered with in Swift and pw
III actually doing the timing and all
that business right that actually
operates above l2tp else if you he's not
involved in that finally light and heavy
duty security options the heavy-duty
security choices LT to be security RFC
3193 this is securing it lttp with IPSec
from the very beginning we thought lttp
when you really want security use IPSec
and transport mode underneath it lttp
still doing all the tunneling here
it's just IPSec is being used for the
encryption or authentication or what
have you and this gives the operator to
turn it on and off once you get you out
to TP tunnel UPS been working turn on
your IP set if
you need it if you don't need it turn it
off and you've still got all the same
tunneling features above the light duty
options are run the control connection
authentication the honest man's law that
says yes I am talking to who I think I'm
talking to on the other end before I set
up this session this is a shared secret
simple password technique in addition we
have the cookie field which I talked
about earlier and this is a random
64-bit value it's tucked inside each
packet now it's the same for the in for
the for the life of the connection you
pick a random value then you put it in
to every packet of sense for that tunnel
or for that session so it associated
with each session to protect against a
malicious blind attack so we're going to
talk about what exactly I mean by a
malicious blind attack or inadvertent
insertion of data into the tunnel stream
and by inadvertent I could mean a packet
floating out on the network that happens
to have the same session ID and it
arrives later you don't want to insert
that into your customers VPN so to talk
about the attack a blind attack the
attacker has no ability to inspect the
data flowing on the target network at
all this is actually this focuses on a
very small subset of a potential attack
only the ability to insert spoof data at
will so it also assumes that the session
ID is predictable so we have this 32 the
session ID that you would have to guess
but we want to keep that open to
whatever index lookup mess methods or or
what-have-you
for your particular hardware platform to
optimize on so if you wants to use just
the first few bits for an index lookup
you can and you don't have to worry
about making sure that you're not
picking something that you just you know
one index value that you just used last
session and all that kind of mess
you can also set certain bits to go to a
certain line cards you can you have the
full flexibility of those 32 bits to
optimize your switching or your your
your lookup of your context info when
that pass packet arrived
so that's the that's so if you assume
that such an idea is predictable then
anything you know anybody could insert
data whenever they wanted to so this is
why you have the cookie so the the
64-bit debate way it works in order for
the packet to not be dropped the
attacker would have to guess that 64-bit
value now why do we choose 64 bits if
you did a little back of the napkin
calculation you talked about brute force
and insertion and that's what we're
protecting again and if you look at the
goal to get 140 by spoofed packet insert
into the VPN at OC 48 speed 20 bits
takes 130 milliseconds 32 bits is under
10 minutes but 64 bit takes 75,000 years
so that seems reasonable enough
we'll see 192 these things going to be
all these values get divided by 4 and as
you go on they get divided by 4 again
so it's look close for that and there's
some rounding error in there
so still you're at 18,000 years at 64
bits so what all people ask me what's
normal to BBB 3 especially the people
that are familiar with lttp from the
access and broadband world the majority
of the functionality is unchanged in
26:51 the turnout set up the control
channel the mainland's all this stuff is
essentially unchanged there are small
modifications there is a completely new
encapsulation defined this is a small
part of the whole thing that is lttp
this new translation was directly over
IP in 2660 one we run over UDP there is
and this is still a valid mode of
operation and if you need the the
flexibility to run through Nats
firewalls and so on UDP mode is actually
a bit more friendly to that especially
now um however if you just if you're
running on a core network at the high
speed you can run directly over IP and
then we've is erected the cookie field
the cookie field was actually something
we called it a key field that we had
five years ago when we started all of
lttp was a 32-bit value in addition to
the session ID that's there now
but it was decided we decided to get rid
of it we figured well we'll just
randomize the session ID and that'll be
good enough but as we want to optimize
the speed and push things down in the
hardware every side you know that was
you know I awfully heard some some input
from various individuals that said hey
why don't you have a cookie field or a
key field and we're like yeah yeah I
remember that thing and we resurrected
it in addition in lttb b3 something
that's new is a separation in 26 61 we
actually define l2tp and PPP tunneling
all in one document the single documents
there and as we see in the little
timeline here people started using lttp
for things other than tunneling TBC so
we this is more of a documentation
exercise and editorial exercise than
anything else we separated out the PPP
part into its own draft and as a model
for Ethernet and ATM and frame relay and
or what have you so the timeline here is
it begins in August 96 of the first
version of l2tp the first version of the
internet draft was published the we had
a multi vendor interoperability bake-off
in 1997 the first version of LTP over
IPSec I put that in there to show that
from the beginning we've had close
relationship there in terms of what we
wanted to use IPSec for in lttp and then
in august 99 the the RFC 2616 761 was
published so just to continue on the
timeline in June of 2000 Ethernet over
l2tp and an address was submitted this
is the first time someone publicly
identified use of lttp for something
other than PPP and so since we came up
with the first delta t BB three and so
on and so forth and then finally in
August 2001 the PW e3 working group meet
and Ahmet and that was a culmination of
the any transport of MPLS as well as the
work that was going on an LC GP to carry
things other than PPP the reason that's
for that that's how the the merging
success
so in summary real quick we got to move
on to Jill he's got about 10 minutes
this off see the wires provided network
convergence by emulating a variety of
data links and lttb v3 is based on a
history of operational experience in
sanitation in the IETF now being applied
to PwC tunneling and I when you get
these posted out on the net there's a
set of references as well thank you
so this talks about to the wire service
experience from a service provider based
on the first implementation called you
design and Cisco technology
I will first introduce the drivers for
third wire services one driver was the
marketing driver was to add a new
service to the product of the portfolio
that emulates secrets like connection
over single or multiple IP networks
meaning over Internet AAS for
point-to-point circuits or point to
multi-point surface another driver was
more internal driver was to have a kind
of performing on flexible tool box to
build customized solution in case we
have some conflicting routing policy of
peering policy as a bank background
information Ebel network has different
yes we have regionally asked and we have
a twenty GS in those ask the peering
policy is different so we have open
versus restricted clearing publishing a
third wife was to interconnect at high
speed physically visual networks by
building a kind of overlaying a last
drive was to interconnect Ethernet
networks transparently our requirements
for UTI were at least the most important
transparency so we need we didn't learn
any change to make any change you are
routing architecture within a month
implementing new IP protocol it should
run over plain IP
should be high-speed capable from g1 up
to OC 48 or even OC 1 and 2 should be
high performance can be accessed by
hardware for the uncocks elation the
encapsulation process should be flexible
in terms of type of fellows or any type
latest fellows with PhDs any friendly
ATM or Internet the provision should be
easy and fast we should have some
security building
let's also add the introduce our March
with the general session ID or the
cooking it should be stable so we need a
kind of mechanism for automatically or
automatically setup the tunnels the mean
the over has should be minimum so here
in that case forward to applies and it
takes benefit of the statistical
multiplexing of the IP network so let's
go to the service part the obvious first
services I previous vehicle is lines
where you create the kind of a Malaysian
of hdl-c dp/dt family ATM internet
end-to-end you transport the layer two
packets and plan it's a point-to-point
service so you have a single via to this
hyper physical interface it's a
one-to-one mapping where you bound one
zone to a single interface here is an
example well you have ethanol between
two post interface or two Internet
segment examples are lentil an
interconnection another example is for
instance a replacement of Clear Channel
ACH Francis
you have no thread cards available
anymore for particular speed or your IDM
is not capable for instance for VG for
foresee and the service would whatever
be for router to router interconnection
here the big advantage is that you have
a finer granularity in terms of
boundaries of grades by using existing
IP rate limiting tools the last is very
interesting service that you can offer
kind of a backhaul for customer for
nicely in some country another country
and build a kind of virtual presence at
internet exchange there is no need for
expensive please line to that customer a
second stream of service is called I
that I call ID MV ll so it's a
point-to-multipoint service we have
multiple butyl is line for silicon
interface how do you do that simply by
creating soup interface on the physical
interface is the help of the Aussie is
VLANs ID attitude at 1 2 or PPI design
and you bound each of the surf in the
face to the chorus tending to know what
kind of service can you do with that you
can do lay through PP VPN provider
provision with your private network
where you can have different topology a
bespoke partial or fully meshed you need
only a single interconnection Society
customer managed is on routing at us and
the journals are provision by provider
it can also be used as a kind of
friendly again extension the case we are
not offering family services or as a
tool to migrate of emulate at the end
when i PB p.m. the views are so UTI as a
technology to build an overlay network
typically here in the drawing network D
represents our transit networks networks
AMD represent regional networks a
natural B we present the hosting centers
the whole system should have all the
bearings from all different networks
networks a had an open peering policy
network D as a respected foreign policy
so we achieve you have all the pairings
in network v by building this so do i
overlay another time service has green
room service really blend of different
service on a single interface an example
displaying is transfer connectivity
which multiple direct connectivity to
original hearing or you build a layer 2
ppm VPN with internet break routes and
also kind of extension cords cords to
the managed hosting auditing services
that's representing that picture can
imagine also made for transfer online
service and even breakout this plasma
online service to remote commands an
interesting service as
we have different yes so hooray yes we
need a router so if you want to do a new
service in your pub we can use one
device and just backhauling to the
corresponding network for providing this
one of the service the customer
like-like-like IP transit or in
connectivity to a different regional
networks we can also offer kind of
treatment service with different us
requirements by building multiple
channels and the last quite interesting
feature we have asked for is villain
rewriting or sweeping so on the left
hand side you have the kind of overlay
networks between switches instead of
trying to achieve some consistency and n
between the villains ID you just rewrite
at the end of the channel UV lamp so you
don't need to care about it an example
I've already thought about on the right
hand side as the internet breakout
coupled with an inter connection
directly to an Internet exchanging
switch where you are removing at the end
the villain ID so to finish here our
future requirements like having a
control plane for the funding plane some
more enhance security automatically
general setup and also a layer 2 layer 3
tsunami mechanism therefore you don't
need to have the same framing at both
end points I've also put on the slides
two tips one of the first it is that
them to you at the end point in the
second action should be load and the
maximum current view - the 20 bytes of
the IP hander header
- the forces of ID of the channel header
that's because UTI doesn't support
fragmentation
the last step is that the eius eius
hello message of pallets to the maximum
and - sighs so to avoid this you can
either disabled at all you can set the
correct them to you
thank you any question on this I'll
grade from eBay I've cost about the
security of I guess not just Ltd but our
protocols in general something that has
been addressed for a long time these
covert channels every single you know IP
TCP protocol is vulnerable to some type
of cover channel like you have HTTP
tunnel and no tunnel and all those
different programs out there and even
IPSec vulnerable to a cover channel at
this time I just wondered if anybody has
any direction of everything towards for
doing stuff over general attacks are we
there okay yeah I'm not I'm not certain
exactly what you're referring to when
you say cover channel if you I mean all
this the the light-duty security options
or even the heavy-duty security option I
guess this assumes that you know where
your interfaces are and what they're
connected to you and what your you know
your your filters are set up but I might
be missing exactly what you're what
you're referring to and how it relates
to this I guess it doesn't lead directly
to it but I think the security system
missed almost no expiry protocols or
network protocols in general because I
need network protocol came right past
you know especially tunnels just make it
even worse because they're sitting
behind the firewall and just allows it a
way in I just quickly by passing the
fire with the Cobra channel they may not
may or may not even be firewalls in this
killer right moment I think of a
security perspective when taking
security in their town sure yeah it's
about concern I would say Cobra channels
are bad yes cool thanks
hi Tony pal virginity
um what laughs I've had a point about
you control plan for the data phone
that's what was that about I think I was
directed to yes that's research that's
referring to what's going on in the GB
version three so that you have a
mechanism of building automatically
adults without having to complement
manually oh so like in the end control
nope