hope
tales are ready on today my name's
run-a-ball
I'm Jim Matthews can make today she's my
PhD advisor Clarkson University
compasses are working towards my PhD
dissertation
us layer 2 network security a
virtualized environments or
is a little about myself Hama the
computer science PhD student at I Heart
University hermoso full-time lecturer to
I'm sorry Polytechnic Institute in New
York
I'm also a software engineer for Excel
sink Armada fair for all
and not rome new york animosity owner
about consulting company called at
around
IT solutions doctor matthew is an
associate professor for the department
which science
Clarkson University I'll case someone I
basically over the at check to my
research
I'm talked a bit about virtualization
just a brief overview mom talk about
multi-tenancy
common and go over some virtual
networking options like bridging is
watching
on the talk about layer 2 network
attacks which mostly cash cow be
familiar with already
on then I intend to give a demo
hopefully it'll work out well for us
are discussed my results and then hope
we'll have some time for discussion
is a cloud services or raise public
cloud services by now
most likely mark I'm reading this room
is using some sort of formal cloud
services
I'm specifically looking at multi-tenant
environments offer virtualization
Thompson is a virtual machines are
typically all connect to a single
virtual network
a device within a single host RBC's
could be using a virtual bridge
or virtual switch depending on the
environment nominees are just software
emulated
versions about these physical devices
wing
so the question I pose this is all
client virtual machines are essentially
connected to a virtual version of a
physical networking device
a typical layer 2 network attacks that
work and physical device is applied to
the ritual counterpart so can we use
things like Mac flooding
UN hopping and what not to actually I'm
infiltrate these virtual devices
oscalus important question explore
because all services that are in the
cloud that rely on virtualized
environments could be vulnerable to
these attacks
ominous includes data centers hosting
you know client said today to
I'm in their environments I'll so let's
look at a hypothetical case your call
purses pappy
especially to rival coal companies on
what if they host their data services
the same provider I would it is virtual
servers were called located on the same
host
and with what there was a fairly easy
way for once again gain a competitive
edge over the other
Wong it's a basic overview
virtualization we have a bunch of
physical servers we consolidate took
them to a single host a lot more
resources available to it the not the
actual other machines
giving us energy cost savings our music
giving us a better efficiency at our
resources and utilization of our
resources
the new typically would have so in this
case i have a web server email server
file server application server
all consolidated on this larger
virtualization server
if we take a look at the inside this box
we can see the host OS would have 32
gigabytes of RAM
maybe sixteen CPU cores and then we see
all these machines are stuffed inside a
each
taking a little slice of those resources
that are available from the machine
what arm so at SUNY up Ali we we have
the centralized virtualization arm
environment that we use for our school
arm so dorm user's computer lab users a
remote users K
all access their thirst drop
environments within this
the single server I'll allowing them you
know
access from all across the campus are
outside the campus or what not on all in
a centralized environment
and we have a heterogeneous mix of
systems that are on there
on this is different for decentralized
virtualization which a lot of people are
used to with VirtualBox VMware
I'm reaction have your own host your own
system may be a laptop
or another physical a larger computer on
this hosting virtual machines was more
isolated and actually I a centralized
solution that has many people using the
same system for their virtualized
I machines little so multi tennessee is
basically cloud service providers are
trying to maximize the resources
so what they're going to do is gonna
take a bunch of the answer to budget for
clients
stickam I'm one box in and pretty much
try to use all the resources they cannot
that box toolbox come saturated
on the Maven overextend things by using
something like a thin provisioning for
for dry space are what not these are
heterogeneous environments they have
different operating systems running
different services will give when X
Window System sinus
environment you must be running web
services FTP services
application servers or whatever I'll but
client access the VM's very so someone
can be former privileges you going grab
an Amazon ec2 instance you can actually
no
set up your own tea and install
everything from scratch the forward
access
on someone actually give you prick and
tablets com some may restrict
arm what you can do with me to give you
the PSD just give you a shout
restrictive access you can get weirder
was not on there
I'll so you're just a couple of examples
and multi-tenancy impostors writers have
him as I need to sue Microsoft
as irv Google phone service is known as
a buncha fly by night dps is out there
who dis Google virtual private server
even find tons of
on different virus out there a
brick-and-mortar data centers sought
most your post.really with someplace
maybe in your local area that's hosting
for local clients or what not
i mean they have all the local area
clients host on virtualization servers
in their environment our server racks
all connected the same physical network
maybe some your competitors are each
other
on but they're all hosting in that same
area so the similarities a visa summer
running some form
open source and are XenServer some use
VMware hyper-v
combo although share a single network
connections between the tennis right so
they're all on the same physical holster
maybe bulk of its cohost everyone and
that single physical host
is all connected to either virtual
bridge or virtual switching device
well so here's a certain kind of an
overview multi-tenancy we again see our
host OS with 32 gigabytes of memory
16 CPU cores in this case sexual Coke
and Pepsi
I'm just you know they both have web
servers they both have some DNS servers
on the same host
maybe an application server I was a
pepsi has DVI serve around here working
on it maybe they're dealing with the
tracking information
ombre their customer base informational
on but the idea here is that they're all
hosting on the same physical server
hosting the virtual servers I'm in all
the information is is using
sitting on the same fiscal hard drive
space using the same Ethernet physical
adapter going out to the physical
network on and maybe it's just you know
bridged or switched cool
here we're seeing to physical network
interfaces one is dedicated for the host
OS for administrative purposes
and the other ones actually dedicated
for the virtual machines to use to get
out the physical network
now when I don't show is here on you
know we would have some sort a bitch
first would have some sort of virtual
switch or bridge
under those machines are connected to
actually is bridging over to that
physical interface
while okay so let's talk about bridging
on physical bridges connect to a more
layer 2 network segments
I'm going to separate collision domains
us we should have some sort of isolation
of traffic
Rd maintain a mac address forwarding
table for each other side the segment
I'm so basically if if some machines or
premise at the segments missions over
the other side the bridge
army from if the machine on one side the
bridge wants to send a packet over to
another she on the same seems to the
bridge
it will cross %uh the bridge or to make
the communication
on but it was sent packing over to the
other side the bridge in that packet has
to cross the bridge
aren't to get over the other side this
is based on the mac Address is in a
stable
so just a basic image it that we have
three on one side three and the other
because the mac Address is so that top
machine over and once I want to talk to
one on the bottom
it's not gonna cross the bridge can hit
that side the bridge to say I look at my
table
home I see the mac Address is still on
your side on your segment source going
to keep that
arm network traffic on that side of the
bridge otherwise will travel over to the
other side to say you know the top she
wants talks mill machine on the other
side
and we traverse the bridge on texan
midtech communication happening
so virtual bridges are the simplest form
a virtual networking
the use 8.o 2.1 d Ethernet bridging
which is built into Linux kernel
and then we use this user space opera do
tells package or actually
work with those bridging on the Virgin
kernel driver
uses a virtual cap interface to connect
these machines to the virtual bridge
and it's just basically a userspace
network at comet simulating that where
to when we play our connection
between the machines and the actual
networking device while
to have inserted the virtual bridge in
this case it's in San world's called Br
I mean we have attacked interfaces I
need to the virtual machines is
connecting to that bridge
which eventually gets down to that
physical interface that they need to get
outside to the real world
physical environmental but they are all
correct that physical bridging were also
immersing separate individual network
segments here
what so this differs from switching
comps switching does
operate a layer to hire such as layer to
like bridging on switches are considered
as multi-core bridges we all probably no
one here
they do separate collision domains each
port on the bridge is so little
collision domains
the big thing this %ah separate switches
from bridges we have a cam people
ominous camp there was talk on to
address will memory arm
it's similar to the for a table we see
in bridges however
basis is a dynamic table that maps the
ports to the mac Address is that the
machines that are connected
that poor now we could have multiple mac
address is assigned to that poor because
we had could have
switches that are daisy chained to each
other that portion of all the
Mac addresses that are basically you
know %uh plant to that one single core
arm daisy chained up the other switches
sus allows us which is too intelligent
police are some traffic from one part to
the next are based upon what mac Address
is a connected
so that you know we're not broadcasting
that traffic across the whole tire
switch
as in the case of a hop on really with
that with the switch needs to do this in
his check the frame header information
are not the Jeffrey am going across a
network for that mac Address
I meant for traffic based upon the mac
address after it looks at his campaign
was okay this
missed is on this port over here this is
on that port over there
but the big thing to know here's the
switches are embedded devices now and
have a finite amount a memory available
to them
I'm so was that can people fills up as a
going to a hub motor a fail-safe mode
I which ends up basically stopping all
the traffic to every connected device
were here except picture Ethernet frame
we see the preamble the destination
address which is extracted out
common especially with the switch needs
to know in order to actually for that
traffic and
we do have cut-through switching in
store for more but really both I need to
know what that destination mac Address
is
Order Complete activity of sending that
the network packet while
cool so here I just %uh sure switch I
have a few machines connected to differ
port so we can see the mac Address is up
on top there we can see is just
basically a cam careful
I mean we have one mac Address playing
too poor to one back in just 24 /7
and so on assault force of the machine
up or two would like to talk machine at
4:14
on basis ends up the packet the switch
trips up but the frame Hatter
looks for the mac address after the
destination matches against scam people
and then sends the packet accordingly
across the switch onto that Singapore so
the flooding of course
on the traffic across all courts all the
machines canción
cool so virtual switches in advance for
the virtual networking just like their
physical counterparts they can
deal with layer to hire information
depending on the switch in the
capabilities that switch
I'm so we can do things like you last
the UN configurations performance
monitoring
and so forth on content filtering if we
get as high as I
application layer switch Tom and they
they all connect somewhere like a a
liquor
a bridge were using those virtual
interfaces arts connected devices to the
actual switch themselves
while so here we see I've replaced
average without with a virtual switch in
this case NBR 0
in which the virtual interfaces for each
other machines the virtual machines on
that post environment are connected to
that virtual switch
I'm in iraq attacks that fiscal network
interface to go off the fiscal
network well so their variety a virtual
switch is available
on typically these are associated with
some sorta different um
hypervisor environment we see open peace
which is usually on nice n environments
or Citrix XenServer uses this by default
I'm Kb environments approx max is
another hypervisor the uses open the
switch
on the Cisco Nexus 1000v serious eyes a
VMware the sphere add-ons which you can
also use the Microsoft hyper-v
environments
arm and is a Microsoft hyper-v virtual
switch was the default virtual switch
for the hyper-v environments
and if you look at yes XI for free
spirit they have their own default
I V switch available to so the Nexus
1000v is something you can buy separate
or use the free addition to can
incorporate that in
on all these are considered as
enterprise level solutions sole
from open the switch which is the open
source piece which all the way up to the
six
us a Cisco Nexus 1000v they're all
enterprise level switches
she would think they would have some
sort enterprise-level functionality or
protection against some sort of attack
okay so basic network a layer 2 network
attacks on Mac flooding how many guys
done Mac flooding in here
misrule case you people rights pretty
easy to do is run a command just want to
network with a buncha mac Address is
arm what that does it fills up that cam
table on forces the switch into a hard
mode if it doesn't know how to protect
itself against that
arm so that all the frames are forward
across the network and everybody can
hear what's going on that's which you
can start eavesdropping on traffic
replay packets
all that good stuff I this works well
I'm most physical switches newscorp well
for about 20 years almost physical
switches so this is something you would
think would be
fixed in the software version of a
physical sweat right
I'm when we go to emulate these devices
we could look at it you know all the
the vulnerabilities or so share with
them and should according to look for
checks or what not to actually prevent
this from occurring
arm this is typically mitigated on
physical switches by using port security
which Cisco has invited the most the
devices I'll
the only virtual switch offers this type
uva protection would be the Cisco Nexus
1000v but the enterprise level one you
have to pay for
this free version does not offer this
protection I'll
UN hopping is another layer to attack on
base in which you can do is take a frame
its II
utica up machines actually plug into a
truck Porter default the UN
I'm so has access to multiple virtual
and I mess which
on me know what you can do as you can
modify the deal and tagged
on your frame and try to put yourself I
was other view as the target UN you want
to get on president view and you
currently on
I'm so get requires access to the
default the lawn or the truck for
are many could be mitigated by strict
%um configuration so basically any
devices that are connected to a switch
port is configured as a truck for review
and
it shouldn't be a should be just connect
to a port that you know specifics that
you end up that
device should be I'm associated with so
can mitigate this by strict feeling
configuration the physical switch ports
while DHCP attacks so we could put a
rogue DHCP server and virtual network
arm we have two main DHCP server was
giving addresses
maybe class start associating to this
role ok on DHCP server restarts entering
the requests
I'm so then they start getting these
rogue services like DNS and TFTP so what
happens if we get I'm
associate with a DNS service actually
poisoned when %uh things like baking
sites and I want to make it look like
real but they're my site you know and i
got plans for so for those in capturing
passwords
I'll or what not cycle poison that DNS
server TFTP if we got devices like cell
phones are hard phones
arm envoy plant our phones usually
Poulter TFTP information
are based upon what they get from DHCP
so forgive a role TFTP server we can do
is
maybe put a malicious some firmware out
that phone
a subpoena physical environment an NFL
QB you know sending packets out to some
other destinations we can start
eavesdropping on those conversations
can also create create that denial of
service %uh situations by giving
duplicate addressing on the network
I'm so we can actually start blocking
out services based upon that
so it can be mitigated by forcing static
address in Beckett's really cover some
in a in a very large environment so
when you're dealing with like 1000 10000
she's an environment you can rely on
DHCP it actually
push out all those addresses accordingly
baby has a static address in for your
servers
I'll most of the store different DHCP
server on there and tell your client to
grab a DHCP addresses
some laws are gonna so sheets that rogue
DHCP server war
those are personal things just
broadcasting fake are our prosecution
Pattaya
messages to a network used to hijack
traffic put ourselves in in a man in the
middle to eavesdrop on traffic to
manipulate flow of traffic
arm this could be mitigated by using
static our country's
again the overlooked in our cable on a
machine and you're dealing with a
thousand ten thousand sheen's
wants to go around and modify our tables
on every single machine under static
countries is just not
not feasible to do I'm Susa something
that's hard to prevent
cool so it's looking a malicious p.m. in
a multi-tenant cloud environment
on here we go again we see the host OS
with 32 gigabytes a memory
16 CPU cores and we have all that the
servers around there before but also
call close a malicious app server
comment the next something that's
actually coast are trying to eavesdrop
on the traffic the patch is generating
so here we see that that motion zaps
arbors not connected to the same virtual
switches the other machines in that
virtual network I'm so we can see that
looking at the lair to attacks are just
discussed you know something could
happen here
I we tried to Mac flooding attack on
this environment and possibly start
eavesdropping on all the traffic this
going across the network
he said like to give a little time on
this and I would have done so far as
I've actually
I'm done the Mac flooding attacks and of
like to show you guys that here right
now
on the show you that this is actually
effective in certain environments
ha so this is a the Sony poly a cloud
security reach
Research Lab whichever a dedicated
server rack aunt
for this research us here we have many
different hypervisor environments
arm in this rack ops want to show this
to you guys we actually had this really
large dracula much good stuff in it
0 yet so the first attack I'm gonna
shows a Mac flooding attack unabridged
interface using Gentoo Linux
open source and and when it's cruel
bridging they intend to show a Mac
flooding attack and virtual switch
interface using Gentoo open source and
in the latest
open the switch arm and the Mac flooding
attack and a virtual switch interface
using
Citrix XenServer I'll show hands who
thinks that the bridge
attack is going to work little
okay what about the open peace which me
model
and what about Citrix XenServer in okay
sheesh let's go up here and try to sell
cool I'll
so we can see here this just using a
Gentoo colonels
of three to 10 to seven young
what and I've got a bridge interface
setup
on the second interface on the server
which is GNP 4s 0 for
over on this side each of these systems
has out to Cali Lynn expert or machines
on them I have a
labeled as Kali one in Kali to on Cali
one is going to be using
links to actually just access the
internet and a star surfing the web page
on Kali to is is going to be running the
Mac flooding attack in a mosque in the
running TCP down Texas that the traffic
attempt to capture that traffic among
so let's see training a screen session
here
while
while 1
little so I gotta love script running on
each of these this just basically
running TCP down
and is targeting but in this case Cali
one I'm specifically by the
IP address and I'm just looking for HTTP
traffic I'm going across the networks
I'm just kind of filtering out for the
HTTP traffic
I we could see a lot more if this
actually worked if I didn't do that in
fact she was going for the full network
rather than just a single isolate a
machine
but in this case we're just gonna go for
a target
she's switch over to the while
cool his summer start running the Mac
flooding attack and Callie to in this is
going to start slowing things down is
almost gonna cause a denial of service
because the networks the status of
flooded
I'm from this so here we go or just
flooding the network
WAM and then all-star surfing the web
cool me
so if this would work to work we will
star single
traffic popping up on the other sniffing
interface here
good ever really nice seeing anything
happen on this bridge interface
little which is to be expected because
Woodbridge is doing is a has that
forwarding table knows what I once I did
that but that graduates on the other
side of the bridge
on and if it seeing all these random act
address is popping up
on baseless saying i dunno relatives and
those things so what it does is it ends
up dropping those
those are packets so it'll actually
crossed that segment on
salt bridge mode seems to be a fairly
safe I networking
I think to use in a virtualized
environment so if using something like
Citrix XenServer using open source and
I highly recommend using bridge mode
while
she let's see what happens if we
actually do this and open the switch
environmental
and was
so again I with this is a a Gentoo Linux
machines oldest
what why and then if I do
well while
yes to go up to that the she cool
what we can see that the virtual switch
configuration here to showing all the
different virtual switch ports the
virtual interfaces
I just to show that we actually have an
open the switch configuration on the
system
I'm so over here I'm gonna go over to
the Kali 3 p.m.
her account cs3 Kelly be in here
the accident and targeting got that
first p.m.
I miss this host mmm
should run links on again while
while
and are on the Mac flooding attack again
little
Wang
case I did just transferred there it's a
little bit laggy because the next one is
working here so she start surfing a ser
the web Uranus may take a little bit I'm
what course is going to take a lot of
time
in
cool
well this one should actually work arm
up there it is it just it's a little bit
laggy on but we start actually seeing
packets going across
may take a little bit I'm fresh
stressing all the packets I'll
but we should start seeing some source
code for the for the white pages here
while
just taking a little time cause but but
as we can see that the open the switch
environments allowing us to actually see
the traffic across the network here
I'll what I can do is i'll show that the
pottery a little more
show the video or text you really doing
it home after this
little
says I'm just surfing the web here we're
seeing that we're seeing traffic
from the other machine mom on this
network
while cool
so was the be switched environment there
was an abrasion environments
enterprise-level virtual sweat you're
actually able to snap the traffic
I'm once we start doing a Mac flooding
attack all so let's look at Citrix
XenServer novel
were the Citrix XenServer uses an older
version of open the switch
by default so good cease using a redhead
kernel here
while
so we can see that the open the switch
configuration on the system
while thing so in this case I'm not
going to target a single machine I'm
gonna what is right on the whole entire
network unless you what happens with
that
while
me let's see here for a little bit
before start doing links
mom it is a Saturday this is on the
school network there's not many people
there
on but what I'm expecting a star seeing
here is what happens
but I found out what happens in a Citrix
XenServer environment is just that
I V generate any traffic on the virtual
machine yet but I was targeting
but we're seeing that that the actual
Mac flooding has left a virtualized
environment
and it started to actually flood the
physical switches this is traffic
and the physical environment now I'm not
showing all the information to showing
the header information here because you
know I don't wanna show other people's
on traffic because that would kinda be
not legitimate on but we are actually
flooding the entire network now with
with packets
so this is an enterprise-level solution
this is the latest version of Citrix
XenServer
and I'm actually able to flood the
network and start going out to the
physical world
now if I go back to my art
makes version here we're gonna see that
the starts working but it takes a little
bit I'm because the lag time because I'm
flooding a network like crazy
I'm but eventually we should start
seeing account lead at CSIS in the IT
I'm DNS resolution here going to a spike
thats yes that's an 88 you which is
hosting my web page here
on there it is right there at the bottom
so we just saw the traffic from that
virtual machine so not only was it
effective in getting the virtual machine
traffic but was also effective in
getting
other client VM's when I first did this
arm I was gonna run this flooding attack
and had a couple students in the lab
connect to the physical switch the third
the server was connected to
on they were doing some lab write up the
stuff in there searching the web a
little bit then running attack and
obstinacy all ur
first %uh clapping screaming what just
happened I'll
and I when I looked on this cruise what
they're doing and I was sitting there
traffic
and the physical switch so this is kinda
scary on
the week actually do this cool so I
decided to text are looking in other
environments like by VMware and actually
hyper-v environments to see how they
worked on those
on different environments as well common
opossum other interesting facts based
upon that
warm killed us out here
3c I killed the Mac flooding but because
the delay it still kinda thrown up some
information here but eventually it does
stop
when we don't see any more information
passing through Wong
k so again what if there was a fairly
easy way for one to gain a competitive
edge over the other so they were in a
Citrix XenServer environment
or is an environment we can see that we
could sniff traffic between them in a
lot of these
of live on a DPS is they just run up you
know a regular
open the switch environment running on
open source and with someone its
distribution because it's free
mom something or subscribe 26 you put
your informational and the environment
you may be successful this kind of
attack or even if they're using Citrix
XenServer you may be successful this
kind of attack
okay so this is %uh I was actually doing
this in Cali with Dom
with Wireshark as well mister showing
the results the bridge interface
I'll adjusted over TCP dumping links in
this case because his lizard over ssh in
renal
location but it does work as well just
as Poland where sharks and still sleepy
dump is just a command-line version
Wireshark
also the bridge information we see
nothing really happens here
but if we do this without open the
switch in this case was to rise or 90
we see I was able to sniff all that
traffic on as I was actually
running the attack
so stable shows on the other virus
attack saddam we can see that
on lennox bridging is not vulnerable so
if you're running a Citrix XenServer
environment
my eye recommendation is put into bridge
mode
you can do that and Citrix land on they
do allow its defaulted to open the
switch but you can go to the
configuration changed over bridge
environment
which prevent this kind of attack I'm
receiver anything using open the switch
is vulnerable to two packets nothing com
if you do the next morning attack
on Microsoft hyper-v I try to on both
but the Windows Server 2003 full
addition
I'm as well as dr. paper the Free
Edition and I found this was 2008
I thought that was intolerable it wasn't
because the piece which
it's because I'm Microsoft 2008 server
has built-in protection against Mac
spoofing
I meant for some reason that helps
against this kind of attack because
we're just basically splitting a whole
buncha random act addresses
and server 2008 protects against that go
Microsoft for one thing right
I'm the so
it seems like a better environment this
kind of a case
are then using open the switch but
performance wise say
happened after I can't really talk about
it artifacts what happened in VMware
because the end-user license agreement
prevents
on for talking about the performance
error testing on based upon that must
get written consent from them which I
did not get
but I will say that Microsoft did base
their environment heavily upon VMware
soul
take it as you well tested on your own
issue which think arming
what was that again young are
I haven't tested with the shield running
in the environment yeah I just tested on
the basic I'm default ESXi configuration
on but that's a good point that's that's
something I should look into thank you
for that
cool so in conclusion all where to voter
boys discuss your targeted towards the
virtual networking platforms and not the
hypervisors themselves it's important to
recognize here because
I'm not targeting hypervisors I'm just
starting the actual networking
on this going on there the results show
that the virtual networking devices can
be just as vulnerable to the sex
attackers the finish physical
counterparts
arm so further for the research is going
to be looking at these other taxi talked
about the beginning here without you and
hopping in our school thing in
DHCP attacks on as I go down the line
but for right now I was just looking at
the Max legacy for was feasible to
actually progress onto looking at this
information
I'll Suzanne server and other solutions
using open peace which are vulnerable
onto the box
default configuration on its kinda scary
so if your network administrator out
there are you putting the senate's
things and just blindly
on display you're trusting that they've
they've taken care the stuff your kind
of
you're looking at a false hopes the
issue really look at tight in these
things up a little more maybe look at
deploying some things a little more
secure
on the just using something is open the
switch we can also look at maybe using
something like software-defined
networking open the switch does
allow for that collectivity on where we
catch start defining certain flows and
specific clothes and filtering traffic
based on certain characteristics
start you know preventing this kind of
activity from occurring
I'm but not everybody is really well
first I suffered a fine networking
on in a lot of people just accept that
default configuration
cool so single malicious virtual machine
as a potential snow all traffic passing
across a virtual switch
I'm and as wish as I showed this can
actually pass through the actual virtual
environment and and affect the physical
network as well
estar daisy chaining down the line to
all the uplinks taking on off switches
which interprets the view and separation
as well as we saw traffic that was not
I'm
died isolated virtual and that my our
server was on a certain scene traffic
from other virtual environments as well
on sis is a significant threat to the
CIA have any information passing over
that virtualized network
in so I'd like to think of you people
for for this work oMG my PhD advisor
i'm nick moretti was here's why with his
%uh see it poi-dog
soon advanced they gave me a lot of our
equipment Rackspace's stopped using a
lot better kinda wreak havoc on the
network
to this research I'm have a close to
research lab assistants do along again
spear
which help we can set up this
environment I'm
my department chair Chris Irvine which
got me funding for some love the idea
could be in for some suffer using
odd city Polytechnic Research Foundation
after finding some in this research
as well see polly and cs5 was kinda here
in strength to support the stock for me
today
so with that any questions and share
this: she questions in the audience here
best here me
yes order
better thing
go so hard were based virtual interfaces
using
who were s so the question was at what
was question can I couldn't hear the
first part
good here while
here good
okay so was the question was SR already
if I can actually virtualize the current
affairs factor
wing yeah I haven't done anything with
that right now but that's something I
will look into
thank you for that on any other
questions I'll
yes
head
I'll yeah I talked about
brick-and-mortar
I'm so it's ok you're talking about the
Bucs about commercial arm
data centers or just commercialize PBS's
yes commercial I haven't asked this on
Amazon ec2 any those other
commercialized environments
on but if they're using open the switch
in their environment and they're doing
default configuration
I think they're gonna be vulnerable but
mostly the summer those bigger companies
are taking other precautions like maybe
they're using other higher layer
appliances
a fortress kind of traffic on to prevent
that maybe these insulin OpenStack which
does use St and actually create flows
I'm so they can actually prevent summers
attack from occurring on
but I haven't actually taking this out
to that to the cloud at which I to do
intend to do eventually
on but I know what Amazon ec2 you need
to actually
talk to them about what you gonna do
under fire you can just are contesting
the environment and the blue
on the guy can to get the permission to
do something like that I'll
so that's something I do intend to look
into anything else
in at the questions
cool while
okay well thank you all