right I know a lot of people say this
but I'm
I'm really knows but public speaking so
I'll try to avoid eye contact
amp but thank you all for coming
the title over talking with gone in 60
minutes
a practical approach to hacking and
sprayed with your sOooo and if you are
the two lead for you it's
I'm and we'll talk about it invited if
you get time
I'm practice get sad though
I am sorry up it's called its pronounce
author of 100
and I I look at the director of security
said its security companies
create a pen test company based out of
China Canada
um in my day-to-day job I do
pen testing on and this is what I love
doing in San an excellent at the contest
on getting two min admonition is an
added bonus
to the job I'm I started off with over
the engineers that but always
have at had a secret crush in reverse
engineering I'm
and I'm a Jew treat with bad eating
habits
an adequate to beauty products so
and Steven Hall as you can see not
much is known about me like to keep it
that way my workouts are up
when I don't get on his nerves too much
and I am fortunate forgot my Santa hat
so you can also see me in Toronto
walking the streets in the middle of
June
in a santa hat bank though I wanted to
set the record straight that
with the you are now at this table talk
about not going to be dropping any other
day there won't be any says
a.m. but something more important than I
showed if that make sense
and so it said if the nail
so you are on the red team engagement
are you actually trying to break into a
company you are in a city there
and you bypass physical security
which is somebody the to you unless you
have to those ties are nato dating does
its front page pretty much TV to buy
possible security
you bypass knack for some 15 test out
the kinds that they implement
network access control I'm does not have
a the bipartisan acecomm
the gyroscope this talk but from Mikes
be at the most common one is to just
look for unprotected not coached
if you see a router hanging from the
roof arm
are lying down on the floor yeah that
the moment
up about two to three miles and
right what next though what are you
going to do after that are you going to
run our liberties Canon
that's probably a bad idea pick at
ok I
because it then if I double any rift
added
all your all the net to forget the
device is a slight a bad like a
Christmas tree
step and a are if they're the Vigilant
network admin
that but there is a catch you for share
so the problem at hand is that
thereby possibly the six physical
security they bypassed Nakamoto extract
data
from the network and to it as quickly as
possible and get out of the net
get out of the premises up but we can't
under 1mb scan it because it's too noisy
tho
panetta today creates Canada basin so
200,000 the request
I'll we have to be stealthy and quick
I'm iffy but on external network we
could use Google Docs ohtake sites
blink in URL to find specific
applications thank
and then I am go that route but we can't
do that on indians
internal network so
may do show that come from and that
thing was to play the part
me so a wise man that I used to work for
it I think it was real true love telling
when said there's not a boat what it's
about bed and
death insist that with increasing
security awareness
and to Lebanese security to manage that
all the network devices are becoming
spotter
and because up increasing awareness on
it but Apple admins hours to becoming
proactive
I know lot of time the conference me
me moan about how bad the security if
but that things are improving
and for you would find lesser time the
network devices being
now configured in a secure manner and
began to really difficult if if a
network admin if you're dealing with a
net admin who knows his job
becomes difficult to bypass after
thirteen states
I'll so the key is to find that
11 members there were are a service open
poet an application that can let UN
and unfortunately when few went to get
access one-time
it becomes very easy to paper two
machines are compromised by the system's
to gain further access so
where do you find these weaknesses who
doesn't love tom cat
nobody wouldn't have a target on the net
to relief requested
crew doesn't like a boss
how many people know about goods and
Jenkins
one 23 so Hudson Jenkins's
pretty much bill automation tool they
were nice enough
in building this service to
give you a shell access by default
with the script consul so
in the top top screenshot is from Hudson
Jenkins
it lets you run groovy scripts which is
Java pretty much so it gives you this
shell by default that you can run
whatever job you want into it
what is not to love about this
still we wrote yesil
what it is its a ruby script
that scans for vulnerable third-party
applications
it's not a vulnerability scanner we
don't actively gloat
we're not like missus and be safe K I
love this stuff is a problem
we look for applications I have no
issues
and exploits we support
most if not all of the web application
stuff
from Metasploit so we scanned for URL's
that show
that these applications exist on this
server
which gives you a pretty much
a starting point for where you want to
look
why did you write why did you write this
so if you look at exploited be there's
about 12,000
but different exploits on therefore tell
if I
are five promo code execution file
upload SQL injection
stuff that can give you shells
and the best you the common application
that we just talked about chavis by to
Tomcat
damage on sale actions in I mean
everyone has a different style a pen
test but
the Dunham was common application I do
not make me happy
that you like by doping test it but
very anti these are not the only
application they i time the weather
that's kinda that he said that out there
so I can barely remember to look for the
top five
I can't remember much less 10 does can
anybody in her
remember that much so X
up we're hiring would you like to yep
yep so the thought process behind this
was
it's kind of the way to say hey I can
remember all of this
I need something that can for me so
we decided to go about and write this a
Ruby told to do this
i know i know: sign be getting it away
I know did poet on me here with on
tonight
be definitely did not play tonight I
think we spent a good amount of time
writing that
code is still crappy but we spent a good
amount of time writing this thing
we we encountered books that we didn't
know existed in various protocols that
amazing
so up what we used to do before
and everybody knows that all the stuff
runs on like 8080
or 8,000 so unless you to skip to do
this yourself you go around you poke
manually
and shown a large network that can take
far too much time so recently we're on
an assessment
where we scanned 5,000 hosts
with Nessus that took about 24 hours to
complete
from start to finish we ran
or two against their entire range of
about 26,000 hosts
and it finished in two hours we found a
boat
2525 so we thought about 25 instances of
stuff on the network
that we could easily gain access to we
did
we got domain admin enterprise admin
from there
and we call it a night went home very
happy
delivered a report and
I slept peacefully knowing that I have
shells everywhere
so what's currently out there
the stuff up there it does some stuffs
similarly
but this is more select our tool is more
geared towards
finding stuff that has known
vulnerabilities in their it's more
targeted
to stuff that is an exploit DB as well
as
Metasploit 3 trying to create something
which was very targeted to urge
finding on able to gauge when have an
application for a step
for whom they exploit already out there
the Kansas by it that you feel can just
find
the applications and we can just go and
exploited
we don't support exploitation I'm and I
suppose maybe viewpoint to put
expectation
beget the problem is because the full
expectation for the application so
who is exploited that in minutes but but
that other exploits and
on exploit EB and I don't know if I
trust
on a temp so it won't device gonna our
behalf to just execute as
that particular exploit up the there's I
loved it
Fitch options that are provided by your
so on
so their stash F actually decide the
dash are stupid
using dash are you can collided up IP
address or IP to a screamer this
the standards format that and map takes
if you don't want to see it through a
tooth ken I'm you can
you can candy network do it puts can
using and map
and adjust if there is a in XML formats
and then feed that fight Chu to use to
love it dash athletes
I'm and then on other cities I sent it
to and map to be done use action and
method you use axe and map night british
with me also for the dash are we also
support
input list similar though the way and
not
the newly separated values go a bash
beef which
it could force and im if you choose to
brute force they perform
form-based authentication so for example
I find application and
8 protected Betty Ford a weak prospects
and you want to root first that
say too good for that for you beat fund
is a vindication or
STP basic are typically attribute first
bought the damn
so if you choose and Ashby form it'll
only brought forth
application bitshare came back wit
phone-based authentication
with SDP basic 82 routers basic
authentication
sense that bird so I was working on my
flight deck I was ovitz making this flow
chart and mr. you think they're the
PowerPoint
and does she teach you to know that and
my life walked past me behind me and see
that you know that looks like a really
shitty
for a shot hand I'd I told her why did
you do it at the she came up with this
man down
I'm sorry if you can read it but I did
not have the boys removed from
from my flight ek have
so the Floyd night if you if you provide
Ashar 3/8
with boat photo I P range RM I P
IP address then sits stock the in maps
can you can map a breeze
now if you play dash F and and the file
on
which from disk and that you already
perform it to
intake that file stock pot thing that
fine
and then it looks were open so
open ports open that this post so as to
DPS DPS
supr to their best and so on and so
forth look at all those boats
after that it creates a preemie you out
as the protocol IP address and port
number
then it's actually adding the default
path stock see if the file and we'll
talk about it file in a while
I'm and socks leading defile application
part one at a time
in this appears the final URL start
sending out the Kress
see what the response up it's from the
server and based on that
if it comes with two hundred and it
looks far
if they're the login form and then it
dynamically extract
the lockdown the login farm he's an
imposter parameters sent out a request
and to see you if that one of the
default password exist or not
yard dog crate if it's not and it at the
same farm
love basic STP basic authentication
if if it doesn't find any basically I'm
net4 to be clubbin trenches and it moves
on to next part and then on to the next
port
what's in the box I'm so when you
download if there's good
I'm you will find you feel which is the
main ruby script
then there's a response to 100 job it's
basically deals thread the form-based
authentication
I'll hundred-person this t4 patter see
if we would have the key file it
contains all the signatures
and also contains the Pats 21 exploits
associated with that particular
application I'm use this to txt pastor
txt
contains have a basic list if he's an
imposter X
I'm it depends what you want to put
pressure on
ideally I would want to keep the fish
are pretty can either provide your own
you the names and passwords in there
and up to this is what I'll defied
patootie if if I look like
for that the first real is def iPad
application
the second feel as they exploit in
minutes rights for that particular
application
and the best buddy that we tried to make
it really simple for you can add your
own Pat
and leone exploits the format it's just
simple
I'm if you want to be really really
stead amp and you do them rekon
beforehand
so take when I go on a pen test I'm the
V keep a job that particular companies
the most important is to me because I X
is this excessive build without any
authentication you start digging
see what kind of applications install
would kind of the pic manages to these
companies use
and then you can just remove all the
applications from the list and then
target like a couple of applications are
tutsi applications and find a network
random cat picture good
have what's happening behind the scenes
at that
it detects was posted so I'm if you come
across one of those leftovers that sent
two hundred a4a one back
far each and every garbage find that
request
and so so what we need to do if we
create a book with by
and I think it is called bogus fight now
and it's it thanks to requests to the
cell with that filename
and if if he gets two hundred or 4 2010
dirty to take back
then be discard that particular part
addendum to the miniscule chance that
she may be missing alleged an
application but I didn't want to get
into that
at this point in time I'm it also
automatically extract the login
fun and once it finds the login form to
automatically extract
up the username and password fields and
sent a request
to the seller arrest
temple
civil in
we have hopefully sacrificed enough to
the devil got Lord
not there's here he you think a comment
let me think me
alright on
okay that did not come out right would
befit
I did not initially looks like with all
the options
this is not a virgin Cedar Point mines
that we had this idea be created a
prototype
there's a long list a feature that we
need to implement and
hopefully we will implement in
so for the paper the demo already
performed a post anything and map and
see if the output file an exam and
format
which I'm going to use but missed him
so I'm using dash be switched to
brute-force of the beach on base or St
Pete
basic art it's better to screw put
everything
and crash no sending
they'd found an application called
fabric and now it's beautiful thing
login credentials at this point of time
be
like we said like the username and
password lists and application list
can be we to
match whatever technologies are using
their so the request
will among request you sell will be a
lot less
fun couple of other applications that
meet epic application
I am then it found tom cat
I think talking is just there by default
I think sometimes
it automatically in stores that sell
them I've seen it so many times on the
network I I don't think people in
started deliberately I think it just
comes up somehow
and there that be getting caught testing
other love you I think it's largely used
to
to remote code execution as they in the
end it to display a list
ap kit be still working on the table so
and yeah
ya that make tables and Ruby are without
using the gym
it's actually surprisingly difficult I
maybe we just don't know I could be
any with out said the first feel if the
the application that it found up the
second feel if they exploit associated
with that particular application in
Metasploit the continual
that exploit after this and the third
field and forceful
a default username and passwords I'll
the for the first application
someone said the strong possibly did not
find DBQ the name and password
up but the second application actually
if he if you scroll up its eighth note
indicates shootin'
the first application because I think
they did not find the credentials
per second application fee look here
eighty
eighth the login page not found let's
make this instance
his senses on it indicates a actually
that pace if not implement
a username and password so you get
access to it and not indicated
I'll for the third one they get again
phone form-based authentication and
starts to shorten that
and find the password admin you the name
admin and the password as password
and finally Tomcat Tomcat and testing
this is that guy I couldn't have makeup
a huge interest sector to
for demo but I like I said we did
against 26,000 IP addresses ripon
when to stop um and just got to me an
admin to show
in light PR system yet
me
the summer the Chinese would be a
fitting for initial even may be studied
writing that be tight
yeah I agree with that but also to other
applications
but exploit BB the crate research but
I'll the entries are not consistent the
which the application name
the version number application name
Brett two brackets and it was number are
there's no application name sometimes
there was a number I just application in
a large number though it's not that easy
to park
ha sitting out soon yeah so a
actually try to parse split EP 4
application name and the URL and
unfortunately
unlike Metasploit they don't have a very
standard format across
anything so trying to programmatically
bill that out
is a nightmare so we'll
unfortunately be resorting to the
greater nightmare both doing this
manually
unless anybody has any cool ideas that
they want to talk to us afterwards that
might help so I think we we analyze and
then you could practically extracted up
for
around 6,000 entries and for remaining
phyto then we'll have to hire interns
I'm the other challenges that too many
to extract the
the login form automatically and then
you the name and password
abt its always it on Hulu based on the
red X pattern rhinestone
if the pager then French are any other
language stand
at be doomed basically and to be treated
basically a white going to Paris for any
pen tester
think that beast staining US I
a future development up be very real
implement worst mother was in detection
I am weeklies we think not
adding support for mass can begin with
it's the it's very
in the states to scan the internet and
then they already scanner those out dead
and it would be just convenient if he
had been mapped I'm ask an output file
split getting Ds too early to start
finding minimal applications
and harass them meanwhile over again
act support for obviously more whenever
applications I am
add a second signatures to put them up
to very common file or directory names
like PHP
last login or PHP its rage anorexia we
want
want to add a second re signature so
that's be
actually find what you want to find and
not from divested up
I'll make the code is really crappy
night
up you can have a look at it so it's
good but it's deliberate I'm afraid if
you open the file it may break Sep
in attract will try to admit it
spreading to the thing and
was the so scanning the 26,000 IP
addresses
in two hours was on a single thread
so yet
I maybe maybe we will result to
going to 3 feet instead of exploiting
the big cap repeated often research it
it's the Liberty aggregators store the
data and my secret database
the maybe to be there to to fetch from
there
I maybe not I'm any conditions
Arnott's
sick yep
a
no not that stupid on a time now day I'm
Dean only see a lot of threes can only
see a lot of for non STP
but about cool
absolutely after a dental applications
that right
up
so it did not treating it a device and
certainly felt
the kind to lift that I know you have to
scan fight on IP for and
that's okay I know you would have to run
efforts but Monday when can you try and
see
if you can do something as and so that
the network admin stone pick it up
and we did not hear back from the
network admins for that night's
hey we are certainly other than a cat on
make a cut down version I wish to be 2.2
put all the username and password
be only cap like admin admin admin blank
a 2003 Honda nations that's it
hard up
absolutely
it death the you can prove a soap you
can either use task I'm switchin provide
an IP range
and it to perform in oppose can you can
specify port 8080 whatever
number board members I M if you don't
want to do that you can do your own in
maps can
export the output in XML format and then
feed that fight to
to the tool and to take it from there
your
word yep
I unassigned be in not getting owned
part can do using and map library
to do that yet know it you can grab the
code from there
and we're out of time right though
yeah you can download the code from the
ghetto I will try to keep it
updated I'm Leggett said that the long
list a feature that we need two billion
and so will continue working on it you
can contact us for any
additional feature it fast as you have
them smart idea I'm
I'm sure you do I'm if you do however
want if any abuse
are any complaints about this thing then
up this Steven and go to H
and then the perfectly logical email ID
is perfect for that thing