are a good afternoon how you guys doing
I retard ignore the
we will be such a bitter a horribly 1
through their
we'll get through it of power so drink
cruelly
how many people here use power still all
yes ice are employed amigos would have
been tense talk
you much good are normally like to do is
talk
Hong there's very few people in early
use power shortage their power shows
like you a lot of basic stall
george RR this good get yours
alright schorr didn't know we're going
to talk about system administration
versus Security Administration
wide use PowerShell a overview
we're talking about word scripts are you
sure she's you missed region is a
response compliance
you're really gonna do it your models a
good role model
of your good alright
so over this is not is intended to make
your burger
where my kids take you step-by-step like
been to that
think I'll not going to you would be
dire
we're not going to Snyder make an expert
and I'm not going to Microsoft anywhere
you know I will
all other brothers alright so local
about us played way
I'll mics bar or your
OK Go I'll Zack
this is not jack is a is this just in
this is Justin
I'll Zack couldn't make it
emergency is little shorter
guys rule out hyper I'll he's not here
others yeah it causes costly
up so he's not here just as good take
his place
I'll I'm started out as legal
performer but solutions like the Seattle
what's yours
I'll but I mainly when those babies just
your 18 quite long beach she wouldn't
rule
fusions double pipe on a partial for Zn
art I'll yes your road
yes you did you dark
about the red team learning more about
offs and no
so that they can understand the
defensive side maybe they were
40 I'll readable to the outside
all I gotta go the other way I think
that as a system administrators you are
more about security
well so that are they understand why
they're doing
things are going on your system why they
could insert controls
I'll because a lot of times it's just
hey do this in like new
celebrate my Asian I'm it works fine as
it is I'm not do it
because they don't understand the
Securities show
leaders more secure administrators
marlys
ministers so in order to get there
joint region partial new car show not
just you
your defenses I'll years registration
use you're still
wall white car show forget what you did
Parkville the every word right
its is it easy do you use
if you have Windows in your bar our
souls order
I'll got a lot built in style
very easy to use you can make tools your
usual across your entire enterprise
I'll it's there %uh
me to see times your money the remote
administration you can control your
policy
it's it's time to do is learn it or
people were
well so has it coaches third-degree
store using powershell started his just
take that step
art show this basics the whole
through work as you guys would bend your
yearbook
bird now get all he commanded
your help about whatever you're going to
abortion
didn't know about underscore or knows
exactly how to do it
usual once deformation judging learn the
only books
sobel stoplight and you know what
crosses
run yet process her now
then your day did you play good urban is
a pipe does
takes the output from the for statement
send it to the next artist statement
so here you should get process nor
assorted
you sending I'll they were going to
select the top 10
you can you make really long commenced
sure you
art so for administrators ya fish
why would you need it patching
how to most administrators final word
patches installed up
I'm how many clicks is a date to go and
find out what but ad-hoc fixed volume
alternate
she review
square there's stirred
stop her and did not fix
she competitors mission is passed
okay a real
van then you can go yeah hotfix
hi where he equal
your whatever you really are sure
looking for specific patches
your star you wanna see if your hatch's
long certain the new ID badges her on
there you look specifically for those
Key Beach I'll was really easy
your
goodbye
two demos looming solos
yes probably ordered your new who
always are judges I as a year to use a
king
consul I issued in your
huge you know marching
she's are a sole hotfixes
are well local account information the
season you know that
my created a new account was that
512 COO group all
and change change your
all in because no
execution policy don't use unrestricted
free
and your
reset you know more from
I'm this board
Stan all
all our no
and a new prison ministry here that's
why
his general sheen's
for her reason the
are now straight
your
are
these are heard you for the inspiration
yes 0
your order Manzana you buy out review
it pops is nice little when two of its
horrible
you scroll of it as a water filtration
I'm you can do
export CSV exported to whatever all
his rule using in senior account
information
insist moment for you guys run that
ended
orders liberation yes %uh scripts for
also
running power going so you know i uses
are song go through all these
she's good
years art blog review
your bill or she does your that
horseshoe large group certainly been ID
Sports if somebody you know
is logged and more up arms and
so many sectors same tells Bill 0
all these groups or withdrawal Euro or
what Floyd you doubt your
I'll closest ministration to school so
is a response in a mouse's forensic
psych so
Hong with scripture Gravatar restore
Poor's
while information yes for church usually
your your the other %uh
im or use work or yours movers use items
armored wall stock truancy is released
compliance
you may have to do a compliance yummy
PCR
nurse whatever well is it your rules are
unsure
local growers what users are
privilege rates you also partial
soul now gold rose use group together
priroda module
so way we figured out in the last
your real reformers for you're doing the
essays are given this group
did this guy would run it mister I we're
on it and they come back to see where
your script on workers
is Joe all what did you
noted stunt work all is it okay
so almost gerchas started adding 0 hash
so it was good run you would have wished
skirt while
it would help with that and you there
she is
your dish for your whatever so they're
gonna call me see your script bro
see what Shugo it's only the Hessian if
it doesn't match my master Ashley you
change my script I'm
just my ass not ok there you go I do
really
yes you did his ashes differ you changes
I'll
so that can only be added that but I
still ahead
all these troops passed out everywhere
sewers are gonna write a model
we can all the screws we have built a
role model
and they were you so group also includes
local
I'll you all our systems male models
there is preloaded
now accused old grunge mayors so
you not turn the bureau written modules
%uh this summer's software built into
this one it's actually been updated and
you're one is more like thirty you know
I'll but future she never forget all
time
reboot I mean by care when lesser boxes
through
for important up in the reboot yes
that al-ahzar word
yeah
well how do you determine if it's been
here recruiters like
six different things you gotta check
I'll
anybody use enterprise tools yaad McAfee
yes us mirrors lol downing
constantly will cause your boo your box
to be building a reboot
carsey lock Paul I'll
even aboard badges are under your you
rate your patching
gotta run any word lined up your cap he
probably got song
this bigger review first and urged all
software in use be doers
are show me tell
on me we're good you
are saw all these groups
yours years
sysadmin module which
art
so many blogs all is actually not were
difficult to do
of the government are all we do is list
of auctions
slashed a man would slash functional
units
whose or actually wearing
the first me power chill there are Colin
Stuart from a notable
functional unit so use and they decided
they would change that to you
meaningless so in here we list all our
folks are units
or portions um and they were just
up we do a starter
which is comet so it's easy to track
your father will start function Wong
and up in your head is this code block
up %um
the better yet arts org O
yet this is the top which is listed the
functions
they're good i'll make comments toward a
fortune Warren
function whatever it is diminishing
influence on you had this
this block to rate your synopsis
description example
in you football examples now what this
will do
this is all you have to do so what's
Islam models loaded
somebody who's ok yet hope
for Machinery Co you all the information
comes low
is right here you know that you're
eating else
yet Nashville forgive me She info is
going to show you this information
not heard of go running after right
little man peach
dispersible I'll
to you now and we had
parameter your name put this in all
along
I'll Lord Patten outlook quality water
not always but the computer name
that way om you can always do
dash computer name or for days your day
and was though
0 all system there are you can do you
would ask your
he did a while are good I was aired out
in
it basically is go down and up
you produce scripted I'll whatever it is
now all the nice info modules you add
these two lines throughout your program
this structure right now dash for bush
in right dash
you go an important test
and I'll show you what will happen when
I want to run the modulator
I'll it automatically at book you
propose to your
schroeder's all my your you today you
said this to you
writer Shrek in Burgos in the book is
all my Google to
for some work you now
down as just all screwed this is Laura
and they were closed for action and
other would you function to
it dollars bowling module
um we have a template a blast
is not our website yet will be right to
nighter
by the Norwegian ominous models out
there to your
the updated one I'll Sol
now you go to module Marie mean this
change is good
your most
all who
machinery in its assessment chart type
as much
our action I've written a module to ps1
RPS in one file this for module should
now to load that up
or yes do you is are good
here's your eyes when news
she's 32
when those power show the warrant
modules create a new folder
give it does
seen name is your module Capitol auto
capitalizes be syntax Pacific has be the
exact same manager module
woo
grab your far all
from
drop it in there
now in Europe in a partnership marshals
close going to do that
or
school organism Minister
I smell a discarded
bass module sheepish dash list available
and years missus 7 module
number imported in
no longer get dash
coming and she pays dash module
bulls are all the commands available now
through
not Verdugo writer
who all age groups you have its total
use your word go to module pushed up to
that
older cross your car rise now all those
commands are now available
so in like I should be before so if we
do you
did so
on did up time
there's a coup that
color block user enters your whole now
I didn't do anything except putting some
examples in right
she offered to use maintaining dash
examples banners were examples
generators maybe and rear
you want your code below dollars example
stirs hell all it's all there you can
now pipe to results to you export CSV
were disliked UK
any other any other commands impartial
I'll
that worker what's up
or yes which imported under all
yes you were you at
says all new instances yet
Res yeah everyman's what yes but you can
set of hong
you to set it up so the all for your
profile
are you logged in all these models are
automatically install
word so I i say is persisting do that so
I do you
any all models are my crucial wrote that
hope right as recession
are
so rear-ended uptime dash
computer name Cup
her much
of course Norris own typing but
are dash for Bose all I was that right
daschle bows
the seer about Cooper
local host do all I added in this group
was right dash for Bose
and water text on a show going to
debugging
I'm raw like what was right dash be
bogged and Mike
my strange now wanna run it
he was bout to perform actions on local
Lowe's
confer continue with his operation yes
no or yes
all his then we're gonna do I do
anything you did your I right days
the book sold you can add a lot of
functionality
very easily with this soul
youthful what's that
you cool technique
on them all
I'm and traded for yet
hi I don't know yeah inches his
you doing are are low that's a good
question I'll look into it
yeah I O in the posh a geyser
now okay you had ball
0 mall well low for lossy
model a
I think yeah I think that's it but I'll
look into it
musher you
for world 0
showed were
heard
up artsy
thirty-minute so a very clear on this
pretty simple
all your questions on global model
I'll do it it
through art so or go into now a good
goal but I'm
home heavy Python guys getting here
1220 vision alright so
me if you judge them by their website
good to your issue we created a
products all does employers
she is a windows box checked Willard's
comply with PCI hippo
miss to watch there's wrote it 100
percent power still
Whitney eros in a way to botch goes well
as Jackson luxury product
100 to check it out skurdal all
solution wall was to use the for water
you know what action bar why won't you
sing all
wooden boxes so just as written quite
launch group
that will I'll base with you 1rm
your when will bark injure all our
Joker into soul
are guys your parcel you rather
so he's gonna go through hell we're
going to explain what he did
mom love to see a senior exec me to use
disney will when does is going to do
chrome college books where you got it
from the one who
mark route you or him and peek at the
pie
initially started our because we didn't
have a tool
rivets originally intended for doing
promote compliance evaluation against
right hand Red Hat derived
operating systems that were not locally
run
where they could be locally run it
doesn't matter but when
I when R M came out and that's when he
said to
makeup or the peek at application
and with that as a lot easier because
all the fine you know the pics code
everything is organizing a CSP already
so as was most workers exodus writing
conversion programs to actually generate
Python modules based on
the compliance date out at the peak at
database
and Israel or sugar or group yeah
said Oh for net with a huge like up
because without the
mix version is growing it out by hand
can have an existing data
so that was went from late May all the
way up to the began July before that
he said it was done and the
peek at the pie is organized with the
flossy a train to you
I am emphasize simplicity not having
sections a code that are thousands of
lines long
so no file should be any longer than a
couple pages
by any means it just has to be that way
and it's also meant that should be
simple to understand and easy to extend
so that's where and having then used by
when our am
and being used against when missus
windows-based systems came into play
and the sophomores organized and
acne-like last fall architecture where
there is a wrapper that
is used to interface with the user to
accept commands and switches
based on what you wanna do and also
populates the piney models to happen to
exist
and thank you for C nine here's the
source for its not that much
so it won't take me long to you kinda go
over it
let a.m.
you need to start cell 'em whether the
help page just like with that
at market model had and
this version had does have debug levels
Vegas 2023
and 0 will be no appetite whatsoever
except for an HD mouth is generated
you go with wine it's very minimal just
showing the finding that happens the
processing at that time I am
and if its compliance or noncompliance
and then with two
give some description about the finding
as it they're going along and if you go
up to debug level 3
blacks you return the standard out from
the command it's running remotely so you
can not only tell
rapper findings compliant or not but
also
the output that was used to you this I'm
why
and so that was very helpful and
troubleshooting
and the other switches to the president
you can have to seeing
specifically nose candy fining or syriza
findings with the banks which where you
can have it go after entire postures so
if you want to ski and I E
a or rail 6 or Windows 7 2008 r2 12
doesn't matter
just as long as it exists and
the underlying basis that allows us to
work is
I'm there is a model called para mi Co
which allows you to build an SSH
sessions
in Python and actually connect other
systems based on SSH
so that's what use for doing the else at
the house
meant for everything when does highway
Rams what's been used
perhaps so since this year
sticking with our show on I can explain
the SSH parliament is gonna go to when
are am
and well the session and then wanted the
findings
model scene see what it looks like and
each those models they all look the same
they're just
and you know custom built based on what
the pics could
and the checkered is
so every pic accession
a rare peek at the pie session I am it
will always have
some kinda I'm CLIA member to it
by default if you do not specify an SSH
switch already a winner and switch it
seems a local costs of those that's what
you get if you don't own anything else
and with that hafter that there's lists
opinie models that are imported be
somewhat you select
and that's when it leaves through when
its second remote system
and there's another member I am your
its you can generate an HTML reporter
on the obviously not be populated if
it's not the number port its main
and then finally the mic debug mode
itself
services the met bid for airing on
saying the debug level you know stand
mediate
and obviously the to crystallize
i'm for the win RM he carries at the CSD
data is highly for a man to rise
particularly the checks the pics goes a
lot easier case you actually get the
actual could execute
but the checks themselves you know it's
based on a table
up operators and what type find it has
to be always talk about issues we did
what we did was
me we talk reissued power field
our show horse I'll
although all the different staters well
this UCI book reports all updating
build one massive 0
days it actually is this yeah it looks
like this is his massive
on network issues generals who all
so going to talk about days this work
grow yeah nice of ask on
okay his massive ash so
with pssht lie it's pretty
straightforward all as you do it is
XQ command against bass cash astaire and
standard out
but with he when are am and based on
the fact that all the data for doing
checks is parameterized
the consul class for when rm has a lot
more
inspection and mutation methods to go
along with using system or Paris shell
so it specifically their shell methods
want for doing
just system calls only then there's a
shit a.m.
a method for doing PowerShell calls and
since the majority of the findings are
actually
I'm registry equality operators with the
words I decide to put an inspection
methods for clearing the registry
without having actually specify the code
to do so each time
so all over yep use your a beer
I'll see grows all I'm his words
importing the power snooker
yet so
a try
you look Cup words at a time mind
yeah
see which yeah how's that
than up issue okay
when it starts getting astronomical
here's 36
her you
act yeah it that's probably a little
much
but
ahead take it back
squint you know
forms yeah right now the only form it's
like putting
and is for the presentation class I just
had it generate
this standard AR that you would see with
a different debug levels and also basic
HTML report that I'll show you
in this is this like a complete your
rightway
5 yeah but you just did the math it's
really registry
sec add it not up all so there's another
thousand buying to add
but then after that incomes Paul Scheer
that was rude lol those were Ruiz's
viewers like in you actually get it at
extended she where you want your
yep that
our debt solutions workers salute you
was like were you know I'll
yeah okay your they're gone so
I'm sleepy and its method inspection
method for any word
few words binaries
you have strings of the strings and
that's it here's our poll
an finally sec add it and
okay hey here's a finding
class itself and every finding is
a class definition did
the oh look very somewhere and that's
what actually populate from the CSV data
itself
I'm every fining always have you know it
net members
for you know her both switch out but
tickets generated
and its complied or not and you could
see
shares titles identification most these
are actually Stafford static map is its
return static text
day get next shit out from the exit from
the
excelente Street near that's right so
optional methods are checked and six
depending on what's populated in CST
so biking here for here this wine is
it's a
you know get reg D word and
it be it's got you know get equal to 1
so
this is where the those methods came in
play from the when are include Coia
object
so instead of typing out the you're
having at put into power so can't do all
that
and get out clean format it's just going
to message that we don't
earlier after the pics good this is
already built made it feel like
when the two meet Asian methods for that
so
this was parsed directly from this ESPN
just put an ass
on CL I power showcases hers three
parcels
exact I'll in those days were greeting
reg
years you were you
is you I don't that sector
are use yep all
sold yellow like going guys like work or
now yeah major boxes for your love it
parties and one thing's the one thing to
be aware of his be very
careful with quoting between strong week
quoting
in especially with the president so what
could also be a
escape sequence like with the tech
center right now out seeing
escape sequences all throughout here so
usually
for particularly with pics good I'm
always always treating as a raw string
and saving single quotes for I'm
you know close actually within the
command because those with those
regular kweisi be stripped out the
string and you get syntactic
syntactic wires coming back from
PowerShell
but other net the rest the four thousand
bindings look pretty much just like this
just nearing at configuration and also
if they actually have picked
so Abington
am peek at the Thai has to emerge either
put in the scan mode road just out at
the system
show what's opening and it also has a
remediate which will
actually go an attempt to your immediate
spines if
the fix is something that's not
subjective so
vertically registry settings for I it's
a good example those are objective nexus
their specs coke for that so this
command this is dying
and on speak at the pie but didn't scan
mode
you can see it setback pays when R and
switch and
on and passed for debug level set three
and I told
posture for and 07 and that's going
against a virtual machine on my 10 year
old laptop
at so
when it comes through their a.m.
particularly with the huge base in fines
we have now
there's an exception handling for
invalid syntax for
I'm populated by needs and that's where
this came up with but this is what debug
level 3 looks like even though you
probably can't read it
activities was there any running are
man's
you scheck you yep and
aid took the labor you doing this
beforehand so you actually get HTML
and center waiting on this the finish so
I am earlier this morning at eleven
o'clock
I'm had to generate the I'm
H&R 4x4 peek at the Tigers game the same
here %um
same seen p.m. and this was just doing
this game without needing any findings
and the second certainly raise
so but the report it's pretty basic I
don't know that much each team out just
what I learned on demand to do
with so and there's obviously a
compliance call
based on severity of it the high medium
or low
yeah I'm yellow be a lil media might be
orange
and hi i'll be read and with the eighty
opinion which static methods were
present and the particular funny module
you'll see that posture group ID
happened heartbeat solution ninety
and plus the affirmation assurance
standards from your GED
I'm ATI 853 er i so
in on the details I am you have a title
plus information about the pining and
also the
casting doubt that his return based on
what yep
use K that's pretty much it
and that that that's it a
you
yet so mom we say we're not trying to
make
years programmers developers for which
are to be rude to school
om presentation is to show you what you
can do
power or all very the building for major
there
all using your extra
your UC build modules you george group
girl xD I the power so run it from 1x
I'll I mean there's a lot you can do
with it always did you guys
motivated you go out for it and
start using it going questions for us
areas here orbit solutions dot com
exact likes beer exactly spear about
this
birdies or go so
back the poppins you
and the it is it good
ever model you could
ha said points to
was yours she's and yes
yes good well yes yes
you remember that the module is your
only for me it and study the
you before you like goat herder bird
equals d-conn said
bought from there in the wrong for me
and you would use
brought your guitar part that your
YouTube Twitter
yes univac him
up
all Hugo it's easy
you go yeah you know where the HTML is
generated in the context
the Python interpreter those who are did
all
Yahoo HTML are those
all it was pretty good home
you know I'll uses worked as you see
me Aug your goals for building agrees
free from the longest rooms sucks it
yeah good
I'll it's not too bad did you go about
your
done that you know I love you are
because all-seeing
60 all if you really want to know who is
in a mock
for more remember you like that OC yep
where r
CPU being call though
parcels you I'll also
slight low water bottle
all X drag drop build the reason that
a result are market so
where it go art
thank you on