the a
ha
good take a look at this camera now
history hope
Adrian have fun in this out you
alright mom
are you gonna sit down there
okay
now you're set I wanna try to give a
threat of violence of its three-year-old
on stage which is like a live
demonstration upright model
so
so get excited arigoni was where people
are not
re: is a lot of people man why I'm
really loud
my really well yeah I was probably a
little more level that you wanted right
if you have a car yet why why
what was back solos like calling it was
pretty good
CIR on 2 I'm a lotta level
this is fun on only utilize it for the
best
anyway um this is a lot of people talk
about right now is they're really loud
know if I like I just feel like all
here's my cell
it's okay it the lawyer tell me sir okay
meant something else in my school and
sup
so anyway I felt kinda bad I got this
talk accepted and then I discovered that
your spots like brand all the shit you
do
really hard lead shell-shocked and
things like that so I went looking last
night think it
I should come up with some cool names a
graphic so the first thing I thought of
was
right down that sounds really exciting
and I realized I was
actually Stephen Colbert graphic that I
was letting people might actually
recognized that
are so they know what some threat level
so threat level midnight
there's a graphic I can lift a I was
also at bay
arm giant actually not seen but it's the
duty office keep growing up as a
receiver on the night
one person's the speaks highly to its
cinematic efficacy I guess I go to store
not want to know what I don't like me
fancy graphics any got Steve Carell to
do it a
and I was like a threat vectors like
I'll fucked on france ceded that
on but progress is pretty cool and I
really like to hunt for October so the
new title this talk is dark red october
that was my opening joke
I'll rest the talk is all doubt I'll
I'll hi shrew at him
at don't fuck you %uh this is the guy
name shrew right away Aug there's
actually a person named sure without is
God given name it was his ex-girlfriend
given name
up the white so um
we may have a license plate that says
shroom arm
yeah and as Ricardo met cuz hydro bit it
so I told them I would pay for its tags
that he got tags that said Heidi
so smooth now drives the drives a car
just
spiteful license plates that just say
heidi soft this is the kind of person he
is you're currently Tigers petrol
with my wife's name just as a show spite
what I do you owe him a tag be which is
I think
125 American 125 bucks I was 100% come
down by lower
a payment Vic Kohring up bring it on
are anyway I start all my talks with the
same basic premise is that you should
not leave anything I'm about to tell you
I am a college dropout II went to school
what occurred for dropping out of school
I went for four years
I never declared in a major of which is
a challenge in most universities I went
into the graduation of it he said
I said hey I like a graduate how do I do
that you're like what does that mean why
I'm literally
don't know how to graduate like what's
your major by
I don't have much like bats on possible
might look it up in their little
computer
issue looks like holy shit I've never
seen anyone so how are you doing here
like four years
who's your advisor I don't have one like
I've just been enrolled in the class is
it going to whatever the hell I felt
like
like some sort of like you know Walter S
exploration myself
and and failing my toy and eventually
she was like me like 40 credits to
graduate at which point for her I with
this in rowing
what school %uh this is the final
solution University Alaska Fairbanks
any other your way up the rhetoric no
are any other
yeah I
i've asked that question hundreds of
times I found one
graduate from the University Alaska
Fairbanks that's it
its really amusing I have what
whose advisers probably be there just
were no advisers that's what they just
tell kids like
don't live in the clerical just give us
money and eventually we and no one
remembers all 19 Association have to
maintain its great
on I had no certs arm
I a know says Pino chut ki got I like 10
account there's nothing is not in the
picture there
are picky pitcher what
no pitcher are your cheery yes yes the
idea you want your pursuit of anonymity
I use my real name
but no picture as opposed to the
opposite which would provide be more
privacy but it's cool
its I I'm doing the cyberpunk think
wrong apparently
of made cyberpunk joke too much people
who got internet after 2000
arm
I give a lot of talks are I don't you
want a real work anymore
actually City OK ponder about
small ish cybersecurity research and
engineering company outta
ok it's an email or call part
technologies so
we do basically heart problems for money
I try to put that are sick to work and
sometimes quite quite an
yes are most times they don't know how
to provide a little more fidelity and
Matt
but are in general I am executive riney
I get it
when what's the status here
what are you doing good okay that's
this their use high that's a good place
alright up
this is better this is this very
entertaining welcome to Derby Conn it's
all a family affair occurred during his
trial at this stage if I tried so we're
just gonna let this
we're just gonna let this happen
eventually develop through and then
he'll have to go to jail cell
soco so what do you dislike 17
and he goes to prague that's the shit
out shown
slide 3 om
what is struck my eyes or ears gone
threat modeling
had what actually decent number arm who
here followed the Microsoft
SPL print modeling process reasonable
number
people how many people in Middleboro
shit actually
this talk is going to be a combination
of inventing your own shit and Microsoft
stock
are all just papers that right now it's
at lost two people right there just left
the relics current I'm out
where sound way too complicated on
we've been doing a lot of right now it
for clients for number two years and
over the last few years as security has
become more and more important to people
of it become more and more interest to
our clients so I'm gonna tell you what
we do
murder occurs you take this with a grain
of salt and do with what you like
arm but honestly you know it's been
interesting
I think the last two or three years if
you went to the Board of Directors
have a major multinational corporation
in 2011
and said hey there are external
adversaries
inside your network right now you watch
the owner stop you don't even know that
their
you're there what u tin foil hat wearing
mother fuck it out like all security
leave right and temple will be needed to
rate it will be in saying that you're
special breed of different
why fix you get kicked out on premise
that I get out
arm white in 2014
everywhere directors very fortune 100
company knows
their external adversaries insider
network you know once right now and I
really worried about it they don't know
what to do
and three years time we've had a cosmic
shift and how executives
and basically everybody within these
companies you security
so this industry this thing that we
kinda you know
come together where black t-shirts say
goodbye I get drunk at
on you know we thought at skewl we get
paid well it's fun it's important
but suddenly there's a lot of visible
right Mata visibility go to CNN
every day I mean if you're a masochist I
guess you see it and where you get your
news
are and you know you see breaches is
Yvonne ability ACC
all manner of security problems in
mainstream media every single day
you know for small their credit card
reaches period
right your car dealers get used to using
online reviews in a retail store
have used it all it's been it's been
taking just accept it
I love these interviews that people will
do like pacer random dude of the street
what do you think at the Home Depot
credit card bridge
arm and it's terrible I'm not to use
credit cards anymore
taxes much really that's the response
like okay whatever you
go get your gold server like I can
appreciate you know what's in the Glen
back whatever you gotta do
are start making right-wing jokes that's
going to give a shot Louisville
on I'm sure concealed carry laws here
really good
on I have a baby disrepair had
on and so things like arm I think what
we used to do
which was securities important and under
skin a white tell you all about it
delightful we should fix these days
because they're bad on the basis that
doesn't fly anymore right we have a lot
of attention and we need a basis on
which justified
this is more important than that you
know this is why you need to carry out
the smaller delivers why you care about
this possibility or why you need to
spend money here
persons here and one thing I think
threat modeling gives us
is the ability to formally describe
here's all the threats against our
system
in Iraq fashion you're setting controls
ago against it and
the serve as the basis for basically
future work that we're gonna do
arm and so threat modeling which i think
for a lot of people just been kinda like
a
closet fascination what we do it
sometimes for a lot organizations
becoming mainstream like they really
want to do it so
arm you know I'm gonna go through I'm
kinda our process that we
crater last few years and I say we I
mean like
people I work with not sorry my company
just kinda watching our way through this
hopefully if you have questions are you
guys gonna differently I would love to
hear
hear any kind of the backers were going
through itself on the face of it
there's this equation I pulled this
squarely on my ass but it's roughly
mobility type probability time in fact
people risk right there's other ways you
can
you this is you know different different
ways that kinda premise arm
so this is an interesting way to think
about rest well
the singer's you need to know all upon
abilities in your system
to understand all the risk in your
system thank you sir our been Smirnoff
ice is in this some sort of joke like
i'm suppose that
right I got ice that's it
I wanna save those for the engine
it is really walruses under no
circumstances a cold Drake
like this is it yet anyway arm
I want to tell a story but you probably
got my talk so are
the challenges you're unlikely to know
all the vulnerabilities in your system
right like you don't have the time to
run around whether your system is
a web app your developing or whether
it's something more exotic you know it's
your entire enterprise whatever
not identify all their own abilities so
what can we do what we can look at front
modeling
on as a way to examine examine potential
actions that result bad outcomes here
systems
right it's effectively a surrogate for
knowing all the mall abilities like I
don't know if there's a bar will be here
but I'm gonna pretend that the reason to
think about what types attacks are
possible
and how they relate to other potential
vulnerabilities in mice my system
what what what do you need something cuz
I'm all for your body whatever you need
no okay are all you're gonna be good
321 all
I
arm secondary things you get outta this
is you can rank your threats respect the
likelihood and impact in a structured
passion for you know like these are the
biggest threats facing us
lower priority for us you can also
identify the controls
used to address it solo dry patrol
starts out like
audience p when it's important to
understand if you have a Western like
that he practically
150 controls you know that's what it
takes to defend your enterprise
you should probably understand why
you're doing something and not doing
otherwise
on so the stock has its roots in right
places on this lot academic papers out
there
this really interesting what's right
molly bassist security requirements
he character allowing all recommended
reading it are a big fan of controls our
security requirements love you departed
organization
so when you capture controls should be
capturing awaits
consistent with the way you capture
software requirements cybercrime is a
test
older traceable verifiable all the space
you anyone go through all your
requirements class
in college that he dropped out over may
have graduated
fancy arm
you know maybe in your hand what what a
good require it looks like
you know it's actually pretty cool you
start to treat security controls as
requirements
it's something that's actually quite
useful especially when you go two years
activity that just because I like
why don't you know in dollars to do
whatever the hell did you try to you
on there's also the Microsoft STL from
modeling tool and process
which I do wanna talk about for a minute
Microsoft to spend an awful lot of time
talking about
threat modeling very publicly reading
books and tools that are out there
are they have you know up processes that
they're very open about
and and very engaging about on for a
long time they had like a busy or plugin
that walk you through the creation
up the threat model now there's like a
stand-alone tool
and that seems to work pretty well the
problem I have with Mike's of Ramon
process reason
giving a spot secured very developer
century
right in like it speaks to developers
there's a game
has anyone played escalation a privilege
game it's a card game
and you can actually like put down cards
and why do the threat modeling thank
and it's actually need i mean it's a
good way to elicit security specific
information for people that are security
professionals
but damn do you get no weeds on that day
and if you have to do a large complex
like not software system
it gets on wielding her you end up with
a good giant listed things and it
becomes
really intractable so arm I don't like
it for that reason
even aid software land I have better
things to pay my developers didn't play
got in car games no pets
I know they put a lot of time into that
try to make it fun but I try to come up
with something here that's a little more
compelling
on and works without getting as deep as
Microsoft one
on if you're at all interested are
encouraged you 1 I'm gonna touch on
today's kinda service all stop compared
to what's available
and Microsoft's website on you know you
can get the pockets
others couple versions of the but there
are other good rituals are used to play
with
actually cut talk about them on in a
minute
so why threat model why did you all show
up here
to %uh warned about probably I can send
one the biggest things you get out
brought my way his contacts okay this
idea that
when I find a bone building a system or
I find some weakness that I care about
but I can say responsibility is this
important in this
grand scheme days and if I don't know
what the grand scheme of
is I just look like a security prima
donna bitching about security stock
right
how many times we had a conversation
what you gotta fix this
why well it's important because it's in
secure
starter Brett like a three-year-old you
know it won't fit but good
that's not really justification it
doesn't work with him
are manifest respect the poopy
oh no I
are anyway subcommittee jokes about my
three-year-old again
are well you know thats let's hear it on
so it gives us that ability to have
contest right which is super important I
think
on because I encountered in my life
whole buncha security professionals
who think that their sole job for a
company is to do
the security things and that's what the
company's mandate as I used to work at a
big
all say to me registration company
are without getting into name morning
and the security staff that I lead at
times felt like the mission of the
company was the pay the security staff
to be assholes
white they're just gonna sit there and
park and say like me to fix this mess
you can't do this I'm gonna get away
everything what
no no no as a security pressure your job
is to facilitate the business
to operators should assured manner as
possible given
like the actual mission up the business
it's not to stonewall
everything okay right may actually have
guys like well we want our people to VPN
remotely
that's cool you do that but we're gonna
go to their house and we're going to
inspect their network to make sure it
secured
what no no you're not 100 other
circumstances
are you going to let go Nessus can
people's phone networks
like so many things wrong with the heck
like not released which have all the
shit you find it's a legal that will
have to report like will spend just
all year dealing with the FBI don't
could be pirated software I cannot
govern us was ap-
someone locked in the basement books I
found them arm
you know it's things like that so her
body in that context for both the people
that aren't security professionals as
well as security professionals
understand like
here's how important this thing is in
the grand scheme of things so
there's a ride a people I think can
benefit from do in front my way
who are developers right pen testing
let's start with back
in the prima donna is on security land
pen tester is ranked as number one
maybe even just be the alpha prima donna
right I am a pen tester how many
protesters in a room
you can admit to its cool distorted
parts of I expect some kinda like West
Side Story street fight later on we can
we can go get it on I'll
I've met some Ricketts smart man tasered
I got one guy works really just a doctor
system
we got on site we could use our images
could use any merger rules
and you just destroyed now dodi and
commercial product using like
fiddler and chrome why does a train ride
like well do I have to remain
administration right city I was a girls
gotta the world like
that's awesome but easy there cowboy
ice let's keep this in context on
so I think it's important that when when
pretest you want to understand what a
potential tax records in the system:
what you know we say that pen testing is
a way to represent attackers you right
often times where I see is it's a way to
represent reunion of all attackers
you not to an attacker right there
sometimes we go in very specific like
I'm in a protected
I am this organization that organization
have this capability that capability
but oftentimes attacker just rolling
around looking for every delegate in
are and sometimes a black-white
organized crime in a way in the door and
then I'll applications they want the
inside right
like a fish dish it out to people and
then I'll get persists you know it's
like well you know there's lots of
different ways
in this or maybe a few scattered acting
like all attacker rather than all of
them
it would be more realistic reach out to
people so I can send your urine test
doing a truck model had a time
understanding where we can see might be
an what actors may work against
weaknesses will give you more
credibility we have to tell your story
%ah
back on secondarily had testing and we
all know this
one of the worst part is it's a are very
discreet
tactical view our a small subset of
problems
in an enterprise to demonstrate
sometimes
yeah at Wrigley our ability to get into
a system and its import
right because they are still people
Tuesday may even have internalized very
bad guys internet were trying to get a
but they don't understand actually how
they get in the paint S is a way to
viscerally show them white
I use this little box i plug in the wall
and I scanned everything I owned you
when
II I stole your car arm or whatever cool
thing that you did
on it's very hard to place that path
that you took to the
whatever crown jewel your tacky in the
broader context to be able to have a
threat model
you say hey here's the landscape even
walkway
what your face it we took this happy
right
is important because then they see like
you had this little pleasure that you
work through there's probably crack so
over this
that's what we need to go get angry arm
products essence and risk assessments
one thing that we do a lot of our
product a risk assessment
people had to sit back and say can you
break this and then we head back a
little pieces later it said
yes should we destroyed it would you
like to know how
arm it helps us of target the assessment
an
brief assessment out the end in a more
cohesive way when we do product
assessments we look for two primary are
types a
errors there's an implementation I and
architecture
rich just inherent in the system no
matter how good you you build it
if your protocols flawed we own it
anyway and that airs an implementation
right
there's an implementation become very
interesting because on you know
on the face with this is somewhat secure
some dude in 0i the proper whatever next
thing you know a Reiki material %ah to
some system on the problem is
implementation can be huge
and we need to know how to target right
we need to know where the security
sensitive
sections in system are and we're likely
candidates for complex
components are probably been implemented
incorrectly where can we focus so
on you know during upright model helps
us focus on that
are provided like people always ask you
special services like hey what is your
report look like
that's like the frikkin Holy Grail white
Professional Services report writing cuz
nobody likes to do it
and always seems like it's not quite
good enough on so I provided like eight
years
sections in our report everywhere
consultants you report writing grants
wine grape January go now the words
happened quite its
a political process %uh right now
modeling for developers
I don't want to be done this too much I
will say developers are not security
experts
of money re what his shot her twice but
not
missus this is amazing on and not only
are they not security developers
offering to our security our experts
oftentimes they don't wanna be security
experts right
they don't give our shit are at the end
of the day
developers are self-absorbed assholes
for trying to get
to delivery as fast as humanly possible
so
you could tweet that shit but somebody
else's name on it arm
so so end
the way the reason I say that having
that the other side table from the
developer like throwing the phone Adam
arm des bottes is like the ultimate
manifestation other developers
looking of the rest the enterprise right
like I don't like it. see you know what
I'm gonna do
Papa and shop in all this shit and it
just gonna like you know virtualized the
cloud and
things happen fuck you I T and life
infrastructures card mather Mike Doughty
no
arm if you have a live the dev upstream
I encourage you to go do that
you so you can see what that meant arm
but honestly like you know any so I i
have been
had this conversation with the number
people who do about security starts
arm about all the potential good they
can happen
any security with that loss play all you
can you know able men all these tests in
your code all the time and they get
integrated in your Russian server and
also the crap you can do all these cool
things
net netflix has like this really you
know interesting view security and out
of here it's like
al-manar you know basically look at all
these attacks are ongoing costly get as
much of it as I can
what reason I was events and then in
real time I can basically code against
these attacks
deploying continuously doll my system
and respond to threats
I'm like that's great if you're fucking
Netflix right
like it's the same thing about microsoft
was Microsoft has a wave running code
that you
if your writers are you can write code
like that most the world can't do that
most the world can't constantly be
looking at all the security in fact that
things are happening their prize
because they don't have that much money
to do it right the developers just don't
give a shit so for everyone
net what's there's 99 people out there
like to
and like they don't care about security
Aug
right molly is at least no way for
developers have something to hang their
hat on
is a I kinda know what I need to worry
about in the securities perspective
developers what pragmatic start and by
pragmatically mean
can you do my job for me like that's the
ultimate developed manifestation we go
in we do security work for developers
really you see me somewhat design
patterns is a real commenting like
security design patterns what well
that's merely specific to what you're
doing I know but you know maybe could
use right all the security
specific functionality and what walk you
have to do everything securely it's not
like there's security specific
functionality like
well we could you just do that with that
chick job what you got
you're asking me to actually do your job
well you are consulting
place I guess that means I ride in
steerage
on
like we ride for class michael Fisch
that's the way it goes out
are anyway up from only for operators so
this the same kinda
kinda rant like hey you know are talking
about from on way to not actually talk
about what
right Israel last 20 minutes on actually
gonna get off the slider
actually so here's what I can't add
a threat right missus largely pulled out
my ass
arm everyone's always asking like when
ID from other what is that
right it's like what is a risk white you
need to construct
English seconds in words that describes
our thing and it's a relatively abstract
concept how do I do that
and so I've at least ride the template
eyes a threat
into it's basically set a variable actor
does action asset resulting outcome
because the motivation
I wanna touch on all those in a minute
we're done threat modeling
you're going to have a list of threats
that by and large it here
so that grammar K I think if you keep
this in your head
it'll be useful actually shows up to
about you know again I'm a good song
repeat this in your head it's been in a
bottle but slides the starter
you know read and live the dream that is
actor does asset
action because outcome at Crockett I
lost Aug
so the first their star witness actors
there's a relatively small finite subset
of types of malicious
actors in the world in those sets actors
there are huge collections of them but
they usually fit into a small set a
bucket some PI like by buckets the five
buckets I was that your other people you
six
I can't read what the sixth is are you
can disagree all you like
white in general there's people look
like nation states with a set of
capabilities as people look like
organized crime in a different set of
capabilities a different setup
motivations each in the post five
pockets have a different set of
capabilities motivation there a largely
similar
right start with those in your threat
modeling think about the differences
the nice thing is there's a lot of
public art
out there about all the capabilities
that these people out
right so we have activists want to have
Warwick
things like that right what we like to
da shit you like to break things that
actually get lower level not
sometimes those people get a rest okay
that's cool on
we have organized crime what's an
example that every
work in Greece that's out there we get
more and more evidence
and then nation-state there's an awful
lot of evidence now converted two or
three years ago
what capability exists there you can
abstractly think about this
what do these capabilities these
organizations have then you can get
concrete
in your organization are there specific
product is that you care about because a
pass incidents are other things that
have happened
for instance Bob from accounting and
kinda sketchy
way he's constantly serving the file
sharers
we're always catching him late at night
in the parking lot I can't seem to get
his ass fired so
bob is a threat actor now call jupiter
is standard you want to call it a
particular nation so I made one up
all our Herman with the guys name
president hurricane style
you thank you thank you he said and that
was one of the greatest quotes all
presidential runs ever
arm and Fat Tony for the senses people
in the race so
anyway pick your poison find a pro
doctors at work you document them
the nice thing about for doctor less is
it tends to be relatively static
regardless we project our sister doing
if your company makes widgets the same
people that want to steal the widgets
today are probably save you want to
steal the widget next year
right if your company makes widgets and
random people come by or doing drive-by
things and dropping crap on your CMS
systems those same people be doing it
next year
ship actor CMS's arm so
Dr the you can use this list
over and over and over and over which is
really nice now what's interesting is
you have to balance your tractor list
with reality
I will give you an example a real-life
example
that I had I was so were small
it's all the company we're small
consulting company for joining a regular
partner
on your small consulting company people
ask you to do things the answer is
generally
yes whether or not you know how to do it
or the clyde is likely to pay you'll be
like yeah we can
we could do that like I built lots of
electric cars like that seems legit
0 so we have a small company ICS
national control system company paying
us and today we need to hang on the
security thing we know
there are some concerns and people got
hit and we're
you know some forward on my okay that's
cool companies based in the midwest
up the United States okay which heat
that might
I'm having a call was it a should know
what do you do our job is Bridget
two and three wire things that plug into
this critical infrastructure bank sell
about exploring the air like that's me
what are you worried about all mostly
worried about the NSA coming it's the
only all our stuff
I'm I'm sorry what was that and I waited
for the laughter. like you did sad but
there was none
like are you serious delivering the news
we're
were really worried about the NSA
company is doing our stuff like
you're you're in the US right leg I like
and your US citizens in make things that
support US critical national
infrastructure
yeah what do you think yes it's gonna do
with that information school for UF
they were still a defrag be like I don't
know but we're just worried about it why
okay like this
you your throat doctor was need to be
called a little bit there is literally
no secondary tried actor
what the reason they called us was
because the garage life
shit of we did not take them on as a
client
um apps not a thing that was going to
happen so
I'll the next thing I actions
so these will vary this depends on the
system depends on a cracker
will get into the specifics about a very
out that the actions here in a minute
up but in general they were all very
dependent actor and this is where your
creative you'll start to come into play
on as you move forward up assets
so assets can be a dirty word your
organization
like pay what computers do you all
that's a fun question to ask most
companies that I A
you know there's the data center and
ought then
there's a buncha laptops & well that's
the computers we only got snot
said technically an answer the questions
work like a geographical where the
things you own exist
we're not actually like a numerical like
we own and number laptops
other companies say really about $500
laptop so we do an inventory like
30 2011 top-flight that's in importantly
large difference
like how many employees you about all
that's a good question do you
I V to their families think so Aug yacht
so you can go about like do asset
discovery but that's not really what I'm
driving your
when I'm really driving at on is a
system representation
so understanding what assets are
involved in the system that you're
trying to print model
and even this can be kinda hard problem
because
again developers even light system
network engineers
oftentimes build things at the end a bit
there like I don't know what I bills
right it works 30 even my own staff like
we did a little tiny prototyping for
this quiet
and the I asked them to keep their heads
a problem like show me the network
there were six hosts and four they were
all in 3some that's connected together
like deep all routes morning in every
direction I might want to be a building
like we don't really know
like it they work sometimes
like that spell out its deterministic it
was a deterministic well you can
certainly don't like
on packets are
she Wow arm
so anyway I'm it's important that you
find a way to represent your system
in a consistent fashion I want to show
you some examples and then provide a
recommendation
on sis record representation cosmetic
work now I see
first preface this by saying I was
network engineer by trade
of her number years actually give a talk
at the site Las Vegas
years ago about what how to build good
network diagrams I hey bad network
diagrams I'll stop beating its dead stop
henry factor network diagram before
anything else happens like
don't mix players like if you're drawing
a layer 3 diagram and there's a like a a
photo realistic picture of a switch on
it
I'm going to burn the projector to the
ground like that is not allowed there's
all kinds of things that you should not
do whatever diagram
because you're trying to make a reader
understand
understand what it is you're doing not
tried to blind them with your idiocy
for example
this is somewhat home network
what thats you think you're a geek right
whatever geekiness you I i have a
samsung
at Snyder whatever like going out this
guy has you out pic by several orders of
magnitude
on including his home automation al 2000
arm
this I little when I troll the internet
finding like
bad network diagrams and that kinda pay
of and this was one of the worst
on the flip side I think one of the most
concise art was this one
which works very effectively for you to
understand how you get from your laptop
to your email server right
so I was really down with its like the
colorants
consistent the farts consistent like
this is all good
so I would encourage you however not to
invent your own sister representation
mechanism
on in the one thing that i think is
really use wow I we got slide transition
there that was unanticipated like that
Woods
that's when you know you saw slide from
somebody else slide deck because it
transition in right with it for
I I didn't hurt this at all that was not
obvious
I'll so anyway microsoft has created is
kinda comin
a I think all the DFT data flow diagram
so
it's actually very useful for on having
a consistent way to capture
I your system when you're trying to do
print model
it for a couple reasons 1 they really
really capturing the
kinda base elements that you need to
understand what you're doing threat
modeling
secondarily you can use their troll to
do this or used SEO
or even are god help you if you're on a
Mac you on the gravel or whatever
release use the same consistent set a
very simple no
there's no photorealistic servers here
there's no 3d people look at all happy
right there's some boxes in some lines
another line another circle right
this is University you need to care
about when you're doing from modeling
I'll example diagrams I want to walk
through mostly cuz I'm
already running late on time so on what
you got clear trust fund raising have
data stores your data flows
this is what you need to worry about
when your front mock
Microsoft again has resolved
documentation around this
you have these ideas level 0 1283
leveled the FT's
on where basically definition is
levels heroes like their high-level
architecture
level one is more detail level two is
more detailed level 3 is
even more detail that's definition
arts pictured you to find a level detail
which you are comfortable on and which
does not result in this comment or
outflows
shit you're trying to analyze don't
really pay attention to your reminders
of stuff hope it that
levels too much because of this corrupt
up around it
on outcome so these are the bad things
that you would like not to see happen
so somewhere like we're great in your
throat you're gonna have white
hey you know crimes committed her ID was
stolen her but she's got
over cooked or whatever the hell it was
like some bad things happen as a result
about this thread after obviously that
outcome will be very specific to your
on your system that you're looking at
again Microsoft this are really
diversion what they do arm
they have this thing called strike then
went on from ours tried before
you find it useful yeah lot near
so as security professionals like we
understand that outcome
right like we can talk about violation
confidentiality integrity and
availability or whatever a
your choosing I arm was kinda joking
array
on never rights too early in the day for
that one
on she really well as she stepped out
flatly
robbery of not going into work at all
noted will throw that one away
made to feel like a stand-up comic is
trying to material like of the cocky
sometimes it works
sometimes make a CIA joke go anywhere
arm anyway so they have this thing
called strides moving to every
repudiation information disclosure
Dawson television a privilege
first of all fine repudiation
so fun non-repudiation and don't get
confused between the two
right you know what I had a lot of smart
people
night hours on it and they can't keep
repudiation non-repudiation
straightner head i cant what with what's
that's what you sir nothin nothin okay
it I mean honestly I'm not trying to
beat right legal all the things that
turns to throw at people that you're
trying to
make clear threat modeling repudiation
is not return to you
right it was I'm just dead's what what
it has a car like I was that really
strikes me is like well
i havent st. I D E I need in our
watch Justin repudiation I'd call it
good
um so what they've done is is very
structured like if you ever
external HD they can suffer from
stripping a repudiation it's actually
above about
that as lawmakers including one that's a
question mark
reissue may or may not have any view the
data store like mr. just occupation
there's a question mark
like no no no no no like you you'd have
to be like
mare like that that's not something
that's okay
um anyway I feel like this gets really
should try very quickly I encourage you
not to use tried
there again is on a whole lotta evidence
out there documentation if you choose to
go down that route
I think I found Nemo security
professionals you just think
you go I know what about you don't need
a pin them in the pocket except maybe if
you're curious
Sega reporting on motivations as a lot
of people about doctor in years
feel like hey I really don't need to
care about the motivation that people
gonna do bad things
you know some universal truth I disagree
motivation change over time threaten
virus change over time
because it that some rights will be up
yeah I like to give joy 10+2 is I wanna
have
ok I thought I was just he was being
really excited about motivation
I'll so um you know it it's really
something that you know as an example
arm you know when some hacker group made
up
or chanters the side so I go watch the
world burn
are like they're gonna go do stupid shit
and they're gonna like
go do it for like the most bang for the
buck why take down as we're or something
you know and so when porch and all
pissed off at the world
I bet threats had having to do with
whites repeating activism
are gonna become more 40 when like 4chan
is off
because it jewish Liberty units for them
to stop watching all the Ford
are my porch and his jokes are brought
or genders in the room Germany get
docs later because it that so I'll
nobody what's my dudes I wouldn't be so
sure sir
home anyway so at the other day have the
assets actually actors been that bad
things will happen
unitary sec well what what can I just
look through that
like if I know all the actors I have
like a dictionary attractions
and I know my assets up could I just
moved through it all
like together sorta massive comet Oriel
explosion
and I posit know you do not want to do
not under any shaper
your circumstance are you end up with
like this idiotic list
really began to well broken down
completely useless
this of threats because what a computer
do your job for you
mister developer arm you know you how
you end up with things like nation-state
does dawson wrote her
Gordon organized crime dawson wrote her
insider dawson wrote activist also
router
okay next asset Nations AP forms Dawson
web server
organized crime does Dawson web sorry
like what useless
right so actually when I get to hear the
second is you can actually
the still some of those down to
something simpler so he say what
all these different doctors can do a bad
thing to a router it looks like the nile
service
their motivations may be somewhat
different but the outcome the same
motivation actor doesn't matter that
much to do in this case so wanna say is
never base now service
takes out the router and you can get
your shit call that's a
right right I should probably captured
up 1
as opposed to like five discrete ones
were called up actors individually
because it's not that important
this get the 1i cortelli arthritis as
specific as you need it to be
if there is a material difference in
because I've one actor versus another
or what action versus another one
outcome person another then
they're two different threats if there's
no material difference but altogether
make your life easier
this is something that I think that when
we do this practically have seen people
really struggle with
and when I encourage you to do is go to
Colorado get really baked and you try
modeling because you learn to just
let low rather than getting ready I do
not encourage drug use
acceptance that states where it is legal
as Leo with your employer to do so
so Aug anyway donor rap from the actual
you know finally is common denominator
and run with it
arm so here's a suggestion got a break
from gotta find some sorta coverage here
so from what you I normally do is
take a DFT right down and then go
through
and look at you know for each element
what cyber attacks repost where the
trust ponders reading important things
right down the price associated with it
no take a breather
come back do the same thing for actors
take it's a big rack
it takes a while I mean it separate take
something that's a little bitter proxy
used to once you get used to it you can
pretty rapidly drive down trees with
rights on it is really just the exercise
we take your time
thinking about it check check check that
you got this right after that right
after that right after that tracker
and working your way through it on later
on I mention hey
then you should validate this someone
else someone else in with your workers
if you like a
I've been dealing with organized crime
lately and their TTP has been vs been
doing the point of sale systems
I don't see that showing up here ok cool
on through that
as right so Katrina
rights be pragmatic are you know capture
the controls
kinda running right now jerry cans or
chrome exactly five minutes
arm capture the control the same guy
okay when I say controls me
the things that stop the threat right if
there's a denial-of-service
I would like to capture what kinda ways
I can mitigate that Valle service Wed
so the end in the front line when you
look and say oh I need to go
yet you know for in Cloud Player or
whatever
you know again three-peat roles as
requirements don't get overly
prescriptive about it but
there certain times we think very you
know easily get specific troll
on also out you should capture
likelihood and impact that's what allows
you to write it
all word on that miss
800 30 risk assessments
and corresponding thats 119 I so these
are documents I'm sure you all have
memorized
I are anyone ready 130 resort
yeah how your cheeks like good work like
us your special breed a
government worker arm
so I think what's really interesting
about a hundred thirty is it provides
on descriptions likelihood and impact
they're relatively tangible and people
can rally around
now this list 30 reach high medium low
out some people use port some people use
five you like Google like
risk likely but in fact you'll find like
these major seasonal have white anywhere
between three and five data points each
axis
I like this because honestly I think if
you start debating the difference
between like a while when a very low or
high to very high
you better things to do with your life
like go to Colorado get paid
arm saw all you recall like it's true
arm well what's really funny is the
likelihood description
sector to makes lot of sense the impact
description like a god damn paragraph
right
in reality it's really only a few words
are a different light catastrophic and
severe
hearses serious Spurs is limited that's
all you need is a cover for some reason
this like got
super pedantic like when it was called
it super catastrophic things that could
happen like
I understand super catastrophic as a
concept you shouldn't need to then write
a paragraph so
I know dislikes like symmetry and stuff
so I wanna like right that would be like
you to expand this one or shrink that
one why do not give me
is to think that they don't fit on one
damn slide
like this just looks empty and this
looks ridiculous so as a consultant I
get annoyed
up but I felt like I should put this
here for you as I needed some sort
yell about so you get hired right now
wondering
when the talk was gonna and so 0
practically what does this look like
when you're done you've identified
your throat doctors your assets you
develop data flow diagrams
you sat around it fought really hard
about the ways they could be attacked
what does it look like you're gonna have
a list of things that look like this
Hey look acted as action asset for
outcome because the motivation
right you're going to have a list %uh on
in our experience anywhere between maybe
a
K all weapons 50 depending on the side
the
the system on along with that
you're going to capture are likely to
the impact
and then again that matrix supplied
Revit readers like these respects a
if it's a high wrister high-impact Union
likelihood it should be declared a high
risk or whatever so he say
risk is high cuz impact is high and then
who's realistic controls right hear
things you can do to mitigate
this right I would encourage you to
counter this as a stretchy
not as PowerPoint slide because it is on
god damn
you'll be in power point on you can make
yourself and I've done this
an Access database
Aug I've coded Access databases twice in
the last six months and I felt like I
was back in college
I was like for snowball where's the
sequel
like I can't rights equal Kors record as
an Access database and yes you can but
it's like this art thing that has to
happen
not access is only psychoses as it was
last time
at and access last year okay I'm sorry
oh my god it's a lot of heads I think
there's a talk to give your eyesight yes
my three-year-old son is on taxes
program us
that's where we're at with access on
so when the models complete you have
anywhere between 1850
right up what I would encourage you to
do is take your coworker friends say
a I made this he spent an hour looking
at it tell me what I mister what you
think is
Gregory cracker right you're wrong or
whatever on
collaboration is good because you can
get kinda myopic looking at a specific
set up prices are thinking about a trio
thank you get kinda wrapped around the
axle if you like are you missus and
higher
thing on this cross boundary so have
enough extra eyes on super important
in summary the process was like this
identify the product
start with that was the five that they
gave you still down more specific one
partner County whatever he
create some sort Asus representation I
would encourage you to use Microsoft
yet the true or similar instruction
iraqis
school just take the five elements they
have been represents
not bashing if you already have good
documentation
use it but if you already have good
documentation is like a left-handed you
record right this is not something most
organizations out
on and the ones that you but it did you
record your extra rare
is its that's wild ride shitty analogy
you
because I have a lot to your cores with
the best search for all right handed so
Aug
anyway brainstormed restaurant assets
that actors an action or whatever way
happens to work for you I'll rains you
remember when people used to take notes
not I got my camera look like that since
picture is our protocols here is it not
gonna I see speaking of my private
collection
Aug but don't its outright
okay up rainstorm in the controls are
you know it's a tirade sorry threats
that right on review validate
you okay that's the basic process that
we follow
we've had a lotta a yeh Jo is excited is
the municipal
yeah and up now what of I honestly
didn't think I'd get through all my
slides
so
Scott so um depending on what your
during the prop on going forward you
know go off use it
testers like stopping prima donnas
understand that you took one little part
the security card
arm assessments whatever on
also well yeah but said the results
because
whether you're doing this for your own
enterprise where you can read you some
these artifacts later
or your dirty consult like me where you
can reduce our role or text later
hopefully remove the right person the
client names
whose up I've never done that
what they don't better data in there
like also I saw your working for GM oil
as I guess I was elected I'll
gems are required example on
probably so anyway say there's also a
lot of will be reused later
a word on reuse on review sounds good in
this space pretty can be dangerous
because if you get in the game are
cutting into a senior UN Security stop
you're trying to get a comprehensive
view of things
oftentimes you'll screw up cuz you
forget stock usually
it is you're cutting and pasting that's
my cutting and pasting voice my
um I would
on anyway um that's that's all i care
questions about rightly
I don't know if you want anything
yes there's a question thank God
so so the ranking so um if you you can
grab
likely impact on it on a two-dimensional
chart basically
are and again this is where like you can
pick a model here that works for you
go to Google and take a look and see
what people think but on
you know there's this basic calculus
like it the highest rating for 101 like
it want to meet him once a high
you know yeah so you just picked pickard
to mention that you want to read against
editor that you want to build that
equation stick to it and recommend or
you get more complex than that but for
the most part about its not unusual
in the back
I said
is there a reason
okay cuz out to us it's okay you would
like to dispute a charge
no no no go over there just because I
need to exert my part so I
bush you look like Cartman so we could
just run with it
Aug I its to you guys
for a question about my biggest security
and
your bro
game right
so
how do you overcome that it becomes
extra problematic in like agile and two
where a lot of people are going and this
is where I find you either need to just
totally blocked up and pay the money to
embed developers in the front pair
that security experts directly into
development teams are not expected
developers B train on it
for all to pay a large security staff to
be outside it basically on it the shit
out of things that are happening
trying to educate developers respect to
security: is
euro and not necessarily great use your
time I would encourage you just pay
security people to live next to
developer be over shoulder
that's where we've had the most success
I think I gotta go now so it's been real
fix my truck