this thank you hi I'm very happy to be
here and thank you for having me
as you said my name is Amit and today I
will be discussing Chrome and web RTC
and how we can combine these two to
cause some problems and for those with a
keen eye I've used the - EQ from
PowerShell because of using PowerShell
this is a concept though so you can use
this concept - not targeting
specifically Chrome and you'll see what
I'm talking about in just a sec so as I
said my name is Amit I'm a security
researcher at Viterbo and what we do we
do file sanitization and I'm doing the
security research at motivo and prior to
that I was walking for checkpoint
focusing on exploited kids and I used to
scare it I swim and I play the guitar
and that's pretty much for that okay so
exposition for this research is quite
interesting for me because I was when I
first read about WebRTC I thought okay
this is a very cool protocol for me it
allows for peer-to-peer file sharing and
webcam and audio and whatever you want
to do and it's easy and you don't have
to install anything additional other
than the browser so it's very cool but
on the other hand the slightest misuse
and you can do very nasty stuff with it
and that's what we'll be discussing
today and how i'll be showing two
scenarios that i came up with
but obviously i'm aware that there are
most scenarios and so if this talk
inspires you and you come up with fellow
scenarios please contact me I'd be more
than happy to to learn to see them and
that's pretty much it so before we begin
this is a post exploitation talk I'm
discussing the case where we are already
in and now we want to stay there and we
want to get the data out without being
detected and I'll be addressing at the
end some critics about post exploitation
because some people are claiming the
most expectation is not as interesting
as the expectation itself so let's save
that to the end post exploitation so
it's very interesting in the
organization part to consider post
exploitation because it can tell you a
lot about what's going on in your
organization if you can detect the
machine as an infected one because it
has some sort of a weird process or
something or if you dig deeper it might
even help you identify what infected
your machine is it the banking portion
is it a ransomware or so forth and if
you look at the information that's being
transferred in and out you might be able
to know what's being targeted what are
the secrets that are trying to get
what's the the main goal of this
infection so this is the general concept
of what to look for in post exploitation
and what's actually being done is for
example I can look at a specific process
in that machine and I can ask myself ok
how did this process came to life what
spawned it does this process 3 make
sense this is in terms of a process I
can look at the domain is if this
process is contacting some kind of a
domain or IP I can ask myself is this a
legitimate domain it is this a
legitimate IP maybe it can help me
identify the specific malware type or
Malvo family and I can also look at the
traffic if I can actually go in and see
what's being transferred like him I
might be able to realize what's going on
on my environment and so this is
generally what it looks like for example
suspicious a suspicious process tree
we've got W script it's a Java Script
launching a decoy war document and doing
some stuff this is a Bitcoin address in
the process name so this is probably not
a good thing and if you see this then
you might be aware that ok this machine
is infected and I'm not I might want to
look further into this machine but it
doesn't tell me a whole lot about what's
going on I have to look deeper for
example if I'm looking at the domain and
this this is from the ransomware tracker
website these are all payment gateways
from runs
and I'm sorry that the consumers are not
so are not so fashionably lately because
we've more we've gone to crypto jacking
in crypto mining but when I started this
research on somewhere else where the
latest craze
so these domains are related to run some
wells and if I'm seeing a machine trying
to reach one of these domains I might be
able to know okay this machine is not
only infected it's been infected with
Iran's owner maybe loci maybe server and
so on and the last part is the data for
example this is an exploit kit infection
the last the the line before last is the
actual exploit it's a flash exploit so I
might be able to know okay
this machine has been or is trying to
get infected by Internet Explorer using
flash so these are all steps that
organizations can take in order to
realize what's going on in their
machines but the thing is it's never
ending so you've got a malware it's
doing something you catch it
that's the end of this cycle and in the
other cycle they do something else and
you try to catch it again and the
process continues so I looked at this
and I said okay what if we can come up
with I don't know a generalized formula
which will help us achieve a better post
exploitation stance and I thought okay
if I want to exfiltrate data out of an
organization and which is I guess a main
goal of every infection I I need to
think very carefully on three specific
things I have to think about the process
that's the main in fact or the process
that's expert rating the data I have to
think about where the data is going and
how it's actually being transferred
because I can get caught in on each of
these steps separately and ending my
infection so I suggest and obviously
this is not my film a formula guys have
been discussing this for a long time I
suggest that if we use a legitimate
process communicating with a legitimate
server and using an unidentified
hopefully even better encrypted traffic
and our chances of getting caught would
be decreasing so this is the formula and
we're going to tick off one by one until
we'll reach a generic attack which we
can use and then I'll show you some
scenarios that I can came I came up with
and I actually want to start with the
last one unidentified traffic and in
order to do so let's talk about WebRTC
how many people here know about you see
heard of it oh cool
so web RTC is been around for five six
years something like that I think being
developed and it's the abbreviation of
web real-time communication and
basically what it does allows you to
have peer to peer communication user to
user using the browser not it's they
like to claim that it's only the browser
but you have to connect to a server it's
called the signaling server in order for
you to be able to connect to the other
user but once you've been connected you
have a completely peer-to-peer
connection you can do a lot of stuff
with this and Google will go over it in
a sec and this is a big deal because we
don't have to install anything
unlike torrents that were in the past
and you had to install some drivers you
have to install some programs you have
to configure your firewall you don't
have to do that we're about you see as a
protocol takes care of all of this using
the mediating server to connect you with
the other user and then it's completely
working and to build on top of that
WebRTC uses UDP which basically doesn't
have any security or encryption protocol
but the WebRTC guys have implemented two
security protocols DTLS and SRTP each of
them works for a specific part of the
WebRTC
phases let's call it so for example I
log into the web RTC site and then they
worry about is it tries to connect me
with another user in a peer-to-peer
fashion and this is the DTLS this is
what the DTLS comes to play it's the
Datagram transport layer security very
much
the TLS protocol but for UDP packets and
once we've been connected we have the
SMTP protocol which secures the data
connection the peer-to-peer connection
encrypting the data that's being
transferred so so far this is all I want
to go into able to see I'm not going to
discuss how it's being implemented and
what's going on this is the general
concept this is the communication
protocol I'm going to point for you guys
so now we can check this off the list
we've got unidentified traffic so far so
good
moving on I want to have a process
communicating online and I want it to be
as I don't want it to be suspicious at
all and if I'm looking for a non
suspicious process talking online what's
the first thing that comes to mind a
browser right everybody has a browser it
doesn't matter which kind you can either
use the big ones or Internet Explorer
it's up to you and everybody uses them
it's not suspicious as it has been in
the past and as it so happens web RTC
is implemented by default in all of
these browsers sense these versions and
I think Rome is version 60 something 70
now for example so since version 28 29
it's being implemented by default you
don't have to do anything and it's
enabled by default it doesn't need or
require any flags it simply works so I
have to ask myself are we done is this
enough for me to call it checked off
let's call it well almost
because when WebRTC was developed the
developers we're aware of these
capabilities and how you can abuse them
and so they thought ok we will add some
security mitigations restricting the
usage of security of WebRTC capabilities
only after the user have allowed them
specifically by user interaction so if
you want to use your webcam using robot
you see you have to allow it with this
prompt same goes for the user feedback
that you get you get the audio feedback
the screen capture and so all of these
stuff are very bad for me if I want to
hide my activities from the user and as
it as it turns out you can actually
supply I'm discussing Chrome but it
works for other browsers as well you can
actually supply the browser upon
launching it some arguments which will
disable or enable some capabilities and
for example if I'm doing some automation
testing and I'm using Chrome and I want
to test WebRTC these annoying user
interaction prompts will be very bad for
me so I can simply disable them upon
launching Chrome I'll add use fake UI
for media stream and then Chrome
wouldn't bother asking the user for his
permission the webcam would walk the
screen capture would work audio works no
fast no nothing simply like that and now
I think we can actually call it complete
don't you think because for example if I
covertly launch Chrome with these
arguments and point it to a video chat
site I can gain hidden surveillance on
my victim okay just for example and
let's put a pin in this will go back to
this later on and so far we've got a
legitimate browser and we've got our
legitimate unidentified traffic and just
to show you the connection between these
two this is from the WebRTC security
documentation it's talking about the
browser trust model and it specifically
says that if the browser cannot be
trusted then all of the security
assumptions made by the web RTC protocol
could be dumped because it's based all
all security assumptions on the browser
if something happened to the browser
then this protocols security is
worthless and so browser
unidentified traffic so far and let's
move to legitimate server and I'm
guessing most analysts here can identify
a suspicious server or suspicious domain
just by looking at it you can look at
the till these
right dot X Y Z dot top dot Apple
whatever and you can look at the Whois
information and see that the domain
owner is unknown oh it's lacking all
sorts of information and so forth you
can look at the suspicious subdomains
you know where's my money
Apple pay back all of these kind of
stuff and you can look at the ID ends
and homographs and as well so what I'm
trying to say is it's pretty easy to
identify a malicious or suspicious
domain and what exploit kids do usually
they have two ways of operating they
either spawn these domains and they live
for a day or two and then they switch to
another one all what they do they use a
compromised site so they hack into a
site make it host their code or they
inject redirection iframe or something
and then it's really hard to realize
what's going on because the site itself
is legitimate is just being hacked and
it's being used to redirect traffic and
all sorts so this is similar to what I'm
trying to do here since web RTC has been
developed some guys have developed
WebRTC sites you've got group chat video
chat file-sharing and so on and people
have uploaded these sites online for
free for the community to use and test
WebRTC and these sites are completely
completely legitimate I mean there's no
suspicious behavior going on and this is
exactly what I'm aiming for I want to
use these sites to hide my traffic and
so far I think we can call it a
legitimate server complete and I think
in terms of the formula we are done so
we're going to use the browser
communicate over WebRTC using these
sites as the cover for our communication
and we hopefully we will be able to
achieve some covert actions and so I
prepared as I said two scenarios and the
first one you're going to have to excuse
my animation skills you understand what
I'm talking about in a sec so the first
scenario is pretty easy and as I said
I'm not discussing infection whatsoever
so the infection stage is done ok the
user has been in
affected and what happens let's say it's
a document right so the user has opened
the document has enabled content and so
forth and so in the background Chrome
has been launched and has been
redirected into a legitimate web RTC
video chat site using the use fake UI
argument to disregard all security
mitigations and this is a predefined
video chat room that the attacker has
already set up in advance and once this
all happens the attacker gets a constant
stream of video surveillance on the
victim which is pretty cool but the
thing is when you when you open the web
cam you get this tiny LED showing that
the webcam is is on and usually on the
latest laptops it's hard well into the
webcam so when the webcam gets power so
does the LED and there's not much you
can do about it with the software but if
we use only an audio feed that does not
turn on the LED then you get a constant
stream of audio surveillance in the
background and you can you might say
it's persistent for as long as the user
does not reboot his machine the process
will remain there and you'll get an
audio feed on that user and I'll show a
video now and I've used it for the video
surveillance scenario because it looks
cooler but I suggest audio feed because
it's more cover but you do you and
before we begin okay so this is the
attackers now what we're looking at at
the attacker is setting up is chatroom
it's called the attacker and then it's
gonna decrease in size and we're going
to see the victim opening the document
infecting itself and then in a small
corner above we're going to see the
attacker spying on the victim while the
victim is playing solitaire so yeah as
you can
open to LTC that's the site completely
legitimate and this is the infection
part as I said not that interesting the
user can be infected in either way yeah
well it's good the user continues with
his activities and check the attackers
side above and you got some more video
surveillance on the user and yet this
just keeps on going I play solitaire and
I I lose at the end by the way okay so
this is bad enough right cool what do
you think so far okay
thank you and so when I was showing this
to some friends of mine they said okay
that's cool but you know let's talk
about you know second stage payload then
how you can how you can do something
like wars with this and apparently we're
about to see supports file-sharing as
well and there are specific WebRTC
file-sharing sites which you can use and
I'm guessing you you you kind of realize
what I'm going with this so this is the
animation to show it so we have our
peer-to-peer connection and which ones
for the malware to the user for
execution and the way I chose to
implement this and I'm aware that this
is might be this might be not the best
way to do it and you can do it in memory
and not save anything to disk but I
choose to do it like that because it's
easier so for example you were infected
the user was infected PowerShell is
running and it writes a local HTML file
to the disk it has an iframe connecting
to that web RTC file sharing site and
the mainframe called controls the iframe
with JavaScript eventually downloading
the file I know it's it's a lot to
comprehend it's kind of a mess but when
you write a local HTML file to the
machine trying to contact an HTTP file
you encounter the same origin policy
that's being enforced by the browser
which is a problem that's that's exactly
the same file trying to access HTTP but
the browser so currently supports the
disable web secure
the argument you can add that alongside
they use fake UI if you want to and then
you shouldn't have any problems
according to Chrome's documentation so
this should take care of that but
apparently this is not enough because
now we get another problem we've got the
local an iframe which it's origin is
null trying to reach an HTTP website so
that's because of the frames that we
used but apparently if you add the user
directory pointing to a random directory
so the whole thing about the user
directory in chrome is that you can have
two users on the same machine having
different configurations and you can
tell chrome okay you start with this
configuration from this directory or
start chrome with this configuration
from this directory according to the
user but as it turns out if you point it
to some random directory which has
nothing chrome will spit out the default
configuration file and this is what it
takes to make disabled web security
works I don't know why so I asked them
and they said it's by design and it's a
no fix you can check it out this is the
the bug details and so I said okay if
it's by design and it's a no fix by all
means I'm gonna use it and so this is
what it looks like we're gonna see the
victim infecting itself and in the
background logging into this file
sharing website and after that you got
we will be moved to the attacker and
we'll see how he sets up the malware and
actually transfers it to the victim
interesting thing about chrome is it
doesn't let you upload exe files so I
kind of change it to dot malicious which
is stands for nothing but the Malik and
my powershell script can actually handle
this okay so once again
yeah okay so infection this was well
obvious but this is the attackers
machine I don't know if you could spot
by the malicious Mickey Mouse but this
is the so these are just actions that
I'm doing because you know chrome does
not support XE as I said but you can
have it whatever you want so now I'm
logging to the predefined file sharing
and as you can see there are two users
logged in me and the victim I share the
file which has been shared successfully
now we're gonna get back to the user and
I want to point you there will be an L
but check out this part of the screen
see this is the chrome download symbol
and the Marvel were actually done was
actually downloaded to the Downloads
folder because this is what chrome does
and you can continue your doing and just
in a few seconds I didn't edit it so
okay there we go so we have been
infected with the server encrypter it's
an imitation of the selber ransomware
and so forth I got this from somewhere
so infection right but this as I said
these are just some of the scenarios
that we can discuss for example about
this is supports file sharing you wanna
have an active spying on your victim by
all means do it if you want to exchange
data you can send you you can use web
RTC as a data channel to send comments
to your implant or you can receive data
from that implant using WebRTC it's
completely encrypted so nobody will be
able to know what's going on in this
machine and I don't know you can use it
for crypto checking it's kind of hot
recently so I added this I guess you can
do it without what about you see but
it's cool so okay so a few quick notes
and I'm ahead of time actually so I'll
talk slower this guy which I don't know
how to pronounce his name
he's uh he did something very cool and
quite similar and he used Internet
Explorer so edge supposedly supports
we're about to see but Internet Explorer
does not and this guy what he did he
said okay I'm infecting my machine not
very interesting and now I am using calm
to initiate and a let's call it Internet
Explorer process in the background and
because Internet Explorer supports
WebSockets I'm gonna use WebSockets to
communicate with my domain and have my
commands go like this which is very cool
actually it's it's quite different
because for example WebSockets whelk
anticipate and we're about to see on UDP
this is not encrypted this is what what
you see is encrypted but the the general
concept was very similar so I thought ok
it's worth showing but if you are if you
don't want to use that you can simply
install this plug-in I saw it online
more than whatever downloads and it's
supposed everything and once you've
installed that you've got WebRTC working
in Internet Explorer which you can
launch with calm and I really like it
it's really cool and that's pretty much
it so yeah I know final notes it's kind
of a head of time but yeah if we
consider incident responders looking at
these attacks and trying to figure out
what's going on so in the signaling
phase well the the machine first connect
to the mediating site to the signaling
server let's say it's HTTP so you can
see a machine connecting to a web RTC
site and exchanging the signaling data
but if it's HTTP then you can't even
tell what's going on in there and the
site is legitimate as we say as we said
and the communication is where UDP and
encrypted so far so good
appears legit taking a step further if
we look at the second scenario where
I've downloaded something to disk it was
actually Chrome downloading something
into the Downloads folder this appears
to be regular behavior of Chrome nothing
to suspect so far and in the audio
server
violence I've I've saved nothing to disk
I've simply launched chrome with
arguments and so there's nothing to
suspect in this sense of the attack and
as I said I wanted to address the post
exploitation critics and a lot of people
have been telling me ok so you're
already in the machine you can do
whatever you want you know you want to
exfiltrate data so exfiltrate the data
why do you need to go through all of
this fast to do what you're trying to do
and I I say ok
getting in is only half the job if you
haven't planned what you will be doing
after you got in then this attack won't
succeed so if you wanna steal something
if you if we think about a thief going
into your house and then walking outside
with the TV I mean this is something
that you might be aware of and you might
be able to stop so getting in is only
really half the job you have to get out
or stay there or get the data out in a
covert way in order for this attack to
work in order for you to make money
because you might be getting money from
getting in but the actual money that the
attackers make are from stealing
something or getting information to
someone so this is follow the post
exploitation critics out there let's
talk about some blue notes if you want
to protect from this attack you can
disable about to see hopefully it's not
that easy as you think I mean you can
specifically tell the browser using the
chrome flags page disable what about the
C communication the thing about what you
see using the signaling protocol is that
WebRTC tries to find open ports it can
use so it it's kind of hard to block in
terms of firewall but you can trying to
inspect web UDP ports to try to see if
it has we're about to see communication
traffic or communication aspects and
then you can go to that machine and
check out what this user is doing with
WebRTC in terms of the browser
specifically chrome you can prevent
other processes from launching Chrome
you can say only the user only I don't
know which one I'm launching
from and moreover you can say this these
arguments are the one I want to be
supplied to Chrome nothing else no use
fake UI no disable no nothing Chrome
this is how it goes any other way I want
it blocked and notified and so forth and
so this I'll these are the blue notes
and I thought about some red notes as
well because when I started this
presentation this research Chrome and
Firefox did not have the headless mode
which is relatively new so I launched
Chrome and using PowerShell I
immediately caught the window and send
it to the background but you can use
Chrome headless mode or if you don't
want to use headless mode you can use
popliteal or selenium which are
environments you can use to control
chrome and actually I've found out that
puppeteer supports arguments for example
use fake UI for media stream so it works
and what about mobile devices so in
terms of iOS I'm not so sure but in
terms of Android what about UC is
completely supported so you have to in
think about your infection mechanism and
everything but this works in WebRTC web
RTC works in Android so feel free to try
it out and some cool research that I've
seen along the way so this is the
WebSockets an Internet Explorer some
connectionless backdoor ideas I highly
recommend you to check it out if this
interests you and this guy what he did
he used a browser to transfer commands
to his implant in the machine so it's
quite similar I'll be sharing this slide
anyway so you can have a look at them
afterwards and quite ahead of time but
I'm I'm finished so questions questions
[Music]
so yeah so we have a peer-to-peer
connection and that means you would be
more or less in the same case as on the
machine trying to transfer again from
the other side I'm having a hard time
understanding this okay so you you
compromised the machine yeah and then
you transfer to another machine using
peer-to-peer using WebRTC from from that
machine then you have to do it again
because you are more or less in the same
situation I'm not sure I understand so
you establish a peer-to-peer connection
yeah you transfer already the files to
the other machine so what do we do there
from the attackers machine yeah whatever
you want yeah but would you not consider
this machine vulnerable because you have
a peer-to-peer it's a multiple
connection to a specific victim which I
have an implant within that's in my
control so if I got the files I can
close the peer-to-peer connection on my
side the attacking side and then it's
done okay good thanks yeah
you were talking about the suspicious
process tree yeah and in your example of
the file transfer actually it's Marshall
executing web RTC and then monitoring
the variance of something in the
download folder is that right oh yeah as
I said the infection part is less the
thing that I focused on I mean you can
have for example a user being infected
by a world document did de downloads
something that sits in the background
and after two days writes an HTML file I
mean you can play with it as much as you
want this was just a plain example to
show what it looks like
my question was did you because you were
writing a HTML file a local HTML file to
bypass array of settings and then passed
the arguments in chrome to disable
security features did you dig into
further how if you could make this HTML
file these are an launched chrome to be
completely self-sufficient without
requiring a PowerShell to execute the
downloaded file or being able to get
commands over WebRTC to browse files
just from the HTML file and then upload
files from the victim to the attacker
and so on so the reason I chose local
HTML file with an iframe is just I
wanted to address that this specific
file sharing site which which had a
download link so it was in terms of the
site but if you build your attack and
you know the file sharing site that you
use or you set up your own legitimate
file sharing site that you can work with
it whatever you way you want thank you
thank you
is it possible to enumerate the initial
UDP connection to the RTC stuff like if
you want to write a rule let's say
you're on Ubuntu and inside there Ubuntu
you have Windows machine but you are
trying to in fact whatever and on your
body you want to write some a snort role
would be possible to like take the
initial phase of the UDP connection but
there I haven't tried it sounds like you
can like from your question I think
might yeah but I don't know haven't
tried it okay
more questions ok so thank you thank you
very much guys
[Applause]