thank you sir
that's cool that wind saved us five
minutes of time i think we'll uh we'll
use that straight away and we hope to be
in time for the next speaker as well
so we've got a challenge there
i was here in 2019 and it's really cool
to be back on stage in person
three years later
it's good to see that the room is very
well filled
we've gone we're going to talk to you on
offensive hunting
and how we use blue team techniques to
do red team ops because
let's be clear usually the blue teams
are well ahead of us in in structured
way of thinking and how they approach
their problems so why not learn from the
blue teams as i hope that blue teams
will learn from us in the end
the first a short introduction from
myself my name is mike bergman i started
in in 1999 as a coder on
mainframes i wrote cobalt i don't have
gray here yet well they're starting to
get there but
i started writing cobalt still regularly
get called do you still write coldwall
can we hire you because apparently
there's a big demand i didn't really
like it so i moved to offensive security
in 204
which puts me already up to 18 yeah up
to 18 years of offensive security
experience
at this moment i'm working for outflank
where i do red teaming
and with do red teaming i mean we
perform the red team itself so we are
hands on keyboard red teamers but we
also talk to the business
do all the aftercare so we talk to the
blue teams that's usually the people we
heard during the red team and we try and
make sure that they get the maximum
benefit out of the out of the red team
because i think one of our
main lines is that the blue team needs
to learn from the red team and if the
blue team doesn't learn the red team
failed
yeah okay
my name is mark smades pretty easy marco
mark
also colleagues of each other so
interesting discussions in team meetings
marker mark
going back i would say i'm infosec class
of 1998 hobby-wise just poking around on
the internet to see what's what's there
professionally 2006 when i graduated
from university i went to a big
consulting and advisory
firm
where i also co-worked with with mark
a lot of big fun big clients corporates
all over the world advising
back then it was still called pen
testing i guess and nowadays we have
got this brand new environment called
red teaming coupled with blue teaming or
adversary simulation whatever you like
i'm a red team operator i like to build
all kinds of tools that make our life
easier
i'm also a vivid trainer we have lots of
trainings that we do i really enjoy
bringing that knowledge over to other
people
and one of the
stints that i did at a bigger bank and
some other clients is
jump from the red side to the blue side
and just see how
defensive units work and bring that
offensive mindset to
the defensive guys
and like when said
we're not really into the blue versus
red we see this as as one and it's also
one of the core values when
in 2016 when we uh
we're two of the four founders of the
company called outflank
we are an amsterdam-based company solely
focused on red teaming doing offensive
security or adversary simulation
whatever you like
uh and along the way we also brought in
some trainings and we have a commercial
offensive security tooling product
but the reason that we jumped on red
teaming in 2016 is that the market was
ready for
proper
adversary simulation
and
we also find it very important to share
the knowledge that we do by putting out
the blogs by doing the research by
sharing
code about proof of concept tooling all
kinds of stuff by putting it out there
we help the blue teams to evolve as well
and you can go to the websites that are
listed over there uh you will find all
kinds of different tools one of the
tools that we um
have released and i'm thinking into this
in 1819-ish is called red elk
and that's one of the tools we'll be
discussing in this presentation it's a
core
aspect of our daily operations
seems the reach is just a little bit
short
okay i think there you go
if there's one thing that you are about
to remember from this presentation
hopefully it is this
it's not red versus blue it's together
it's together it's it's sparring it's
preparing the blue team for the actual
threats the sole purpose of the red team
is to improve blue
yes we do this by sparring yes we do
this bit real punches it really hurts
when we're in operation and we
get to do that strike
we also get hit bet but
head back but it's important to
understand that the whole purpose is to
improve the blue team
and you can resemble this with sort of a
sparring match
it's core value of a company it's not
that we want to come along
smash the opponent down get the goal run
away and start laughing no it's about
improving both in operation as well as
in documentation reporting afterwards
think of boxing this is how our boxing
ring looks like
it's a lot of stuff in there i want to
give you an overview of how our
offensive infrastructure looks like
during one typical operation
and we have multiple operations running
in parallel just to give you an idea we
have multiple command and control
servers coupled together with multiple
redirectors or reverse proxies something
in between to hide rc2 server we make
use of domain fronting all the time we
create lots of fake identities
multiple different websites we create
we track with pixels everything every
email send out every action sent to the
to to our target
all kinds of different web servers
different delivery methods
and there are some back-end systems as
well
one operation roughly 30 infrastructure
components
multiple operations parallel
this is becoming a problem in that sense
so we have lots of data to get track of
now let's jump back to
when we released a tool called red elk
red being offensive elk standing for
elasticsearch logstash kibana
this was presented in 2019 as well here
in hacker in paris i want to give you a
quick overview of what the old tool or
the old concept actually looks like
we have typical challenges and the
typical challenges can be divided on two
aspects we're having difficulty with
having oversight and difficulty with
having insight oversight as in
30 components per operation multiple in
parallel it's just too much in that
sense to keep track of every operational
infrastructure component
if you look at
analogy would be to we're having
difficulty managing the herd of
infrastructure components
and if we have so many sensors out there
on the internet part of operation
scans gone by but also blue teams start
poking at our infrastructure
and this is where i want to introduce to
you mr edmund lukach a french forensic
science a person back in the 19th
century he introduced forensic science
and he is most known for his adagio
called every contact leaves a trace the
luca exchange principle
if we have so many sensors out there on
the internet part of our operation and
it's technically impossible to
[Music]
do a contact to well on a crime scene
but as well as on a
technical operation
it's impossible to not leave a trace so
that goes both ways we as offensive
red team as we try to hack into
a network
we cannot touch those systems without
leaving a trace and that's why blue gets
triggered and tried to find us and do
stuff
get us out of there
the same thing applies the other way
around as well as soon as blue starts
investigating
they interact with systems they interact
with our infrastructure and they will
leave traces
so this is where we start thinking well
is there a way to have better oversight
over systems and have better insight on
what blue is doing during our operation
we are in that sparring match we want to
see that punch from blue coming before
it's actually on our face we want to be
one step ahead
we looked at the public uh code
repository there was nothing like that
we need something to manage to hurt we
need need something to get insight into
what's happening this is where we create
a red elk there are multiple links in
the slides where you can get the
background information
on a more
architectural overview
just to give you an idea where red elk
actually fits into our operation on the
left you see the target implant on the
target network
normal operation it connects back to our
c2 servers via redirectors or reverse
proxies and stuff like that
let me try this one again
simply doesn't work okay
this is where red dot fits in uh it's an
elastic search log stash kibana it has
all kinds of data indexes it does
enrichment of all kinds of data it
allows you to do searching it has fancy
dashboards
it gets a day it's data from all kinds
of data feeds coming from redirectors
traffic data and both the c2 servers
operational red teaming
data
and also copies stuff like
screenshots
collected downloads from all kinds of c2
servers and still things like that
it allows the white team and the red
team to do easy searching with there
and
this is where the fun happens as soon as
the target blue team starts to do some
type of investigation
um
things happen they cannot interact
without leaving traces so they start
interacting with our redirectors from
their point of view the implant connects
back to a specific ip address or a
domain name and they start investigating
in there
if you have insight into that
operational traffic data you get the
same type of information as well
they also make use of
public
threat scanning security sources
security service providers spamhouse
virus.org ibm x4 is domain classifiers
all kinds of
publicly available security vendors that
give you ratings about fb addresses and
all kinds of other stuff
the funny thing is again every contact
lease it trace those security service
providers get that data by querying our
infrastructure so when we know
a traffic that
some virus total things are happening on
our great characters or ibm exports is
again scanning our infrastructure and if
you have the possibility to have that
insight
you're one step ahead
that's where the whole scene
functionality comes into play so we
query those security service providers
we gather the data from all kinds of
free director traffic data etc etc and
this is where
we are one step ahead
allow me to
switch just to a different screen
yeah
you might wonder why is it so important
to have all this data in a red team
operation
on one hand uh an attacker gets better
when he knows everything that's
happening on his own infrastructure so
you can adjust to what the blue team
does and how to respond to you but also
as said we're trying to service our
clients we want to make the blue team
better so also from a consulting point
of view it's very important to have this
data so quite often we can phone the
customer meaning the board member that
gave us the assignment and tell them we
think your blue team is on to something
and if they dig hard enough they might
find us now within a few hours
so even if we
deliberately
expose ourselves to being found we can
still manage when and how we are found
and inform the customer even before the
red the blue team really escalates that
an attack is going on which helps us to
optimize the exercise we're doing with
that with that client
exactly yeah what you're looking at here
is the kibana graphical interface over
red elk instance
and it has a dashboard view and it has
as well a discover view i will first
talk a little bit about the dashboard
view it gives you in one oversight
a proper
oversight of the entire operation like
the amount of unique hosts you've got
beacons on the the hosting the systems
the entire uh period of operations all
kinds of different
primary data that might be of interest
um
i talked about all kinds of alarms stuff
if i click on this area it will
give you an overview of the alarms that
somehow get generated and those alarms
could be
as you see right here
maybe just a little text a little bit
bigger
we're talking about traffic alarms ip
addresses over time hitting your
infrastructure
it also talks about different files or
different services which have a md5 hash
and that md5 hash got queried by
virustotal and virustotal or hybrid
analysis said well yes i am aware of
this hash if this hash is known by
virustotal and that hash is specific to
our operation and we did not upload it
to virustotal guess who uploaded that
specific file well the target did so a
pretty big alarm that something went on
there's also other type of data
regarding your
reader vector the traffic or the
different ip address that are accessing
your infrastructure if you provide the
configuration to a network of all the
known ip addresses that are allowed to
connect to the
actual redirector infrastructure
and allowed to go to the sea to back end
all of a sudden a different ip address
comes in you get an alarm and you can
even deflect the traffic still on your
redirector but you still get the alarm
giving you a heads up in that in that
battle so you have to see that the url
our implants talk to is really unique no
one can guess that it's only the implant
that knows this url and when we start
our engagement
any ip address is allowed to talk to our
infrastructure and as soon as we
determine it's indeed the laptop of the
victim of the client
we will narrow down the ip scope that is
allowed to talk to our infrastructure
and being allowed in
and then if we certainly see the same
query from a total different area in the
world to our infrastructure that only
the victim can know it's pretty clear
that some investigation is going on an
alarm is raised here and if we deem it
important enough we usually also
configure that we get an email stating
that in our inbox saying hey your your
operation might be compromised act now
and then we can choose sometimes we
choose to disappear so make a new c2
framework if the
customer wants us to play an aggressive
but very sophisticated game that's what
we'll do we'll just make that c2 channel
drop that and move to the next and we're
still in the game
but also we have often customers say
i'll let them investigate let them play
around with it for three four days and
then we'll reveal that a red team is
going on so it really gives us the steer
in the operation on how we want to
proceed with this with this attack and
this
this test
i switched to a different view no longer
dashboard this is the straight discover
interface of kibana and what you're
looking at right here is what they call
the redirector traffic index and right
here i have filtered on a specific url
which was in our case for this example
this specific url the training beacon
and i have focused on a specific attack
scenario during an operation we have
multiple scenarios running on parallel
this one is called dump to 12.
so you see that filtered in here there's
a pretty
standard view you can open up such
events and in there i just gonna gloss
over this just to give you an idea on
the enrichment that we do for example
because we configured our directors to
put in extra data in there we have for
example all kinds of header information
and we extract the user agent we extract
the exported four we extract the status
codes all kinds of different extra
information that gives us
more things to
act on so let's say we could exclude all
the user agents which are specifically
this it's a simple interface i just hit
the minus mark it does re querying and
all of a sudden i see
all kinds of other implants or other
systems that were connecting to the
same url and the same attack scenario
with a different user agent and it
becomes interesting because all of a
sudden we have different source of view
addresses
this is more manual searching but it
does give you oversight if you have 10
different infrastructure traffic
components one central interface to see
what is going on
there are multiple different views in
here i'm switching to what the what we
call the red team operations index and
i've
exfiltrated or filtered out some types
of information i just want to give you a
quick overview in here let's open this
event again it says an attack scenario
it
tells you for this specific implant
traffic uh it is for this username with
this host name and this was the actual
output of the message
scrolling just a little bit it tells us
in this case that the c2 program is
cobalt strike and this was the output
that the implant gave back at that time
if i scroll down a bit there is more
type of information shared here the
external ip address
guip information enriched from there it
has all kinds of information about the
windows version all data that is within
the logging of your c2
framework
quick oversight there are multiple views
but sometimes you just want to have easy
access to the full
implant log file that's why there's an
easy
direct link to the full log and here you
have i'm not asking you to try to read
this but it shows you the raw
beacon log file and here on you can just
hit
your typical control f and you can
search to the specific thing that you
want within you this output by the way
is a cobbled strike implant i guess i
hope most of you are familiar with
cobbled strike as a red teaming tool
uh
either though the gui is quite
responsive searching back in data for a
command that you commissioned
eight hours ago or even days before
usually as a hell so as a red team
operator we're also working in red elk
constantly during our gigs because why
execute a command if you already
executed the same command yesterday you
can simply look it up
we used this
google-like interface pretty easily
i do not know if which specific beacon i
entered that specific command was the
abc or one of the other 20 beacons this
is one centralized view simple quick
query style
there's a few more
different types of views in here easy to
use
it's a quick overview of all kinds of c2
credentials all downloads all specific
iocs you go to that you click the
download generate report and you get a
full overview of all the iocs of your
operation screenshots keystrokes all
kinds of as well as what we call signals
and here it gathers the specific
attack miter attack t numbers that you
can plot into a
navigator interface and tell your blue
team or your wide team what was going on
nothing new here this is default tooling
that was existing for quite some time
indicator of investigations is how we
like to call them let's say if we make a
division between the direct actions to
our infrastructure we can easily get
alarms for
let's say rogue user agents blue teamers
using curl or python command line stuff
to investigate our infrastructure
boom immediate uh alarms if that if that
happens rock rp addresses like already
mentioned deflected traffic if you have
your redirector with some smart uh
logic in there deflecting to a certain
endpoint with an alarm tag in there you
get an automatic alarm
and if you have a range of known ip
addresses of blue teams you can put it
in there any action coming from known
blue ip addresses is immediate alarm
stuff worthy
indirect more talking about security
service providers let's say the
anti-virus hash or the nd5 azure for
file but also blacklisting of ip
addresses of our infrastructure and
domain classifications if it changes
things like that immediate alarms this
is basic seem like functionality
i see we missed with three minutes so
the timing
awesome
yeah let's go back to the the current
time we made some additions to redder
because well
we started thinking if we've been using
this in operation
with happiness um we're using it to give
better
oversight and better insight
we want to have we want to optimize
operation and we want to do more stuff
to detect blue let's look at how blue
has evolved over the last few years and
if you look at how blue teams operate or
sock or whatever
they generally progress over two main
access one
more data just connect more data sources
more is better is bigger it's it's all
good maybe some something to mention
there are there any blue team is in the
room here
of course
yeah i must say that that i'm surprised
with how aggressively and fast the blue
teams have progressed over the last few
years so kudos for that it's really
going fast and
making our operations and
actions and the criminals actions a lot
harder which of course is the goal in
the end for the blue team so
um
you can call it detection engineering
threat detection whatever just
connecting more data sources it's easy
for us with the redoc concept
another area what's really interesting
is what they call threat hunting a more
of a hypothesis based approach to catch
well known attackers that somehow
slipped through current defenses
it's a bit more free format search you
require different tools if you put it
into our perspective
so that's what got us thinking
remember this image we added a few
things on the left side we have added
the ability to do
more queries on the implant side more
queries on the inside of the attackers
or the targets and network
and on the right side you see two things
neo4j allowing you to import the output
of bloodhound for attack path
measuring within your target
and also jupyter notebooks allowing you
a bit free format more searching in all
the different data sources that are out
there
and that's exactly what
mark will be telling you first before we
move on uh
do you does
i want to see some hands who does not
know bloodhound because then i'm going
to explain what it is to keep you on
board it's bloodhound familiar tool i
see a few hands who is familiar with
bloodhound then i expect to see the rest
of the hands
cool yeah okay gives me an impression
i'll i'll do a very short introduction
bloodhound is a tool developed by
spectres ops
what it does you drop
some code in the customer's network and
this code will start querying active
directory so it will gather all data it
can on users you have groups you have
sessions that might be there so people
being logged on to machines
information on these machines themselves
and so on and so on it gets all this
data
basically your whole active directory
puts it in a database and you can ask it
to draw a path so you can ask it i've
got this user i want to go to domain
admin is there a path in between
and if there is it will say yes there is
this user has local admin to that
machine where there is a session of an
admin who's also admin to this machine
and on that machine there's a domain
admin administrator logged in and if you
steal his creds your domain admin so
that's roughly what bloodhound does gets
data and allows you to draw a path from
point a to point b
a different way of saying that it's
google maps like navigation within a
target network i'm here i want to go
there i've got this
information about possible routes
just
bring me to it
yeah so so bloodhound there's a lot of
data on what parts could exist or are
existing in the network but you don't
have the starting point yet but red elk
on the other hand has a lot of
information
live during your operation every step
you make on every command you type
bloodhound knows about that so if we
combine this combination you get sort of
a golden marriage and we're trying to go
there in a bit
uh this would you don't have to read
this all it's just uh in couple strikes
someone types ps give me a process list
and this process list shows a lot of
processes including one of the user a
johnson and you want to know
does a johnson have by any means a path
to the main admin because if he has i'm
going to inject into that process and
walk down the path
and on domain admin and that's the goal
uh where the technical red team at that
point is so what do we do at least what
did i do in the past and i expect most
of you you copy and paste i i johnson
into your bloodhound
interface and see if there's a path and
there might be a part that might not be
a part
next you'll land on a citrix machine and
there's 25 users there does that mean
you really have to spend the next one
and a half hour copy and paste user
names to see if there's a path
from one of these processes to the main
admin is that why we became red teamers
we thought not
so we decided
as mentioned here i'm not going into the
details there we didn't only include
neo4j we also included jupyter notebooks
basically
a web interface where you can run cool
python snippets it's way more than that
but for this talk
that will that will be sufficient
so we thought let's see if we can make
it work together so let's make red elk
and bloodhound play together first we
note this jupiter notebooks where we can
write snippets of code then we write a
small snippet of code that says connect
to red elk and allow me to run any query
then we write another snippet of code it
says connect to neo4j the the graph
database behind bloodhound and let me
run any query
and then you write a query
i'm not good at writing so i'm really
happy you cannot read this this source
because i'm not a good developer there's
a reason i quit that job quite early in
my career
but hey it works
so first we query in red elk for all com
all pps commands so we'll get a lot of
lines back with every line that includes
a ps we parse all of these lines so just
some hacking and string cutting it up
putting it in the table
and once we have a very structured way
of showing all the ps or all the
processes in all the ps's we've done so
far we can and for each of these lines
for each of these processes run a query
against bloodhound seeing is there any
way that we might have domain already
already a domain admin already so first
we the first query is at a 09 94
a johnson nothing found you move to
another box or something changes on the
box you run ps again and the tool for
you will just run this this path second
round nothing found then you move to
another box and you find admin a johnson
at strobe.local and voila it will alarm
you straight away domain admin is found
maybe with this name it's quite obvious
but quite often you can find really
obscure parts with bloodhounds and i
think in 99 of the times this tool is
way faster than us doing copy paste into
uh
into near 4g
so that's one way and one addition we
we brought to red elk
and as said what our goal is with red
elk is one
to optimize our operation i think this
was a clear example of optimization
where you can perform your red team
better and faster but there was another
important thing detecting the blue team
we want to detect whether or not the
blue team sees us doing stuff so we can
either adjust the course of the attack
or we can inform the customer management
saying they are on to something good
that's a good learning experience what
do we do now what do you want us to do
so let's dive into that how can we
detect if blue team is on to us
one of those might be a reset of the krb
tgt
not necessarily we have it already had
the the golden key of the of the domain
controller so to say not necessarily we
have it already but if they get nervous
domain admins they have a tendency to
change their own passwords and change
the password of other important items in
the network so if that suddenly changes
that might be a very clear indicator
that something's going on what you see
here is the powershell to to request
from the domain controller what this
what this reset date is and we decided
to build our own dll our own piece of c
code that does the same thing
through the active directory servers
interface rc interface which is
quite
safe to query as it's really hard to
detect such a query and we can ask out
for example kbtct but also all the
members of domain admins
and if you have a rough idea how long
these passwords are valid
and if someone changes his password
halfway that might also be a reason to
be alert like i'm doing this move i just
compromised this account and there's one
admin certainly getting shaky and
changing passwords it doesn't mean we're
detected but at least it means we have
to be on high alert as well
so we wrote some some code around that
as well
so first we again we prepare elk we
prepare neo4j and we download all the
security tools that have been queried
because you can run the
this kind of blue checks you can run
them all the time
we also have a similar
dll written not for password changes but
for security tooling so we query
on a system
what kind of security tooling is is
present usually it's an av there might
be some some
edr tooling presence and we take that as
a baseline so your first query and what
we find in the first one two or three
hits and if they're similar we take that
as a baseline and then we keep the code
running
and as soon as we see extra security
components pop up
then we need to raise an alarm
trying to
enhance the zooming just a little bit
things like defender things like
all kinds of cis internal tools things
like that
so first we uh
the baseline we said was a system
activity monitor and windows defender
smart screen and over time we see
there's nothing there's nothing new
there and then suddenly a new tool is
found this is internal process explorer
and that's a reason to raise an alarm
like saying hey we've got internal on
the machine where you were performing
actions the blue team might be might be
on your tail so act accordingly
and there's a third example which we
haven't written out yet but we're
working on that
another thing we quite often see that if
we do stupid stuff we make a mistake on
a laptop or an end user device they tend
to one isolate the machine so completely
block it off or sometimes they tend to
move the machine behind the proxy so
they can do ssl inspection trying to
figure out if and what kind of c2
channel is being built to the outside
world
another reason might be that another
thing might that might be that they
won't pick the whole machine and put it
behind a proxy but they found either our
persistent code or the initial code we
used and put that behind the proxy as an
investigation
so one of the checks is check the
certificate so do one ping to one one uh
do one reach out to a domain
name
check for the uh the certificate that's
on there
keep that in mind and as soon as we see
the certificate change
raise an alarm apparently someone is
playing around with the stuff we put out
there and that might be a valid reason
for us to stay on high alert an
investigation might be our way
so we've got we got a few more picks up
our sleeve for the upcoming time
password resets we mentioned that tls
interception was mentioned the security
tooling was mentioned log forwarding as
we if we certainly see a change on one
of the systems that we're on where logs
are either forwarded somewhere else or
more logging
is enabled that's also reason for us to
stay on higher alert because there might
be some changes at hand
changes of security config is also a
reason to stay on high alert and
accounts log in
if we certainly see a local admin log
into a machine where we've been messing
around that might be a clear indicator
that someone is trying to do some
investigation if you're in a blue team
though be aware that logging in with a
high privileged account to a machine
that you
consider owned is the same as giving
away that account so take care there and
don't don't do that but if you do will
likely see it think of the whole tiering
aspect the tiering architecture that
microsoft has put out as well as the
clean source principle
never log on to a lower tier system
because you will need credentials on
that remote system on that untrusted
system
so after giving you a lot of information
on how we uh progressed as red team i
think it's time also for a shout out and
thanks to the blue team because we were
merely looking at the techniques you
guys deploy as a blue team and how we
can mimic those because there's there's
a lot of lessons learned in the progress
that the blue teams make and we just
want to copy what blue is doing so take
the concept they're doing to get insight
in their environment and do the same on
at least on the machines we own by the
time we are halfway during the operation
so i think there's a list
that we see happening on the blue team
and how we want to implement those one
is sending samples to the cloud for
analysis that's a cool thing and that's
also a heavy measure against any malware
that's reused because if customer a
submits it to the cloud already
an attacker cannot reuse the same
malware
at customer b because the cloud will
already know it's evil and kill it
straight away
heuristic analysis so behavioral
monitoring
that's also what we're trying to do
we're trying to monitor the hosts we're
working on and if one of them pops out
and for some reason that might be a
reason for us to be more alert
application whitelisting very common
technique on the blue team part we're
doing the same on on our side we have
whitelisting on either the c2 channel
and the ips that we allow in or even on
giving out our payloads if there's a
payload on a web server you would only
be allowed to download that if you come
from a range or if you send a query that
we expect we don't want any random
sandbox downloading our code all the
time
because that wouldn't work and i think
last on the list is artificial
intelligence that's the buzzword guys
we're not going to implement on the red
team side and we don't hear them even
even the blue teams have not
successfully implemented it
i dubbed it i highly doubt it
so the summary of this talk i think most
important is and people everyone for to
the blue teams and the red teams in the
in this room remember the goal of the
red team is make the blue team better
yesterday at dinner i got asked if you
do your best to be just below the
surface and give the blue team a chance
to detect you
don't you consider the red team failed
if they catch you hell no
i consider the red team failed
if the blue team learned nothing
it doesn't matter if i get caught or not
the end goal is the blue team being
better
the bigger end goal is the company not
being ransomed in half a year
so essentially blue teams and red teams
are not against each other
there might be some
angry faces now and then but it's like
that's like a strong soccer match
sometimes a bit of pain is needed to
improve
but the blue teams are there to serve
i'm sorry the red teams are there to
serve the blue teams in getting better
and please blue teams if you feel you've
got a red team on the other side that's
only punching you and never gives you
anything back
report it work on it improve that and if
you're a red team and you think you feel
if you get caught forget about it you
feel if the blue team doesn't learn
anything keep that in mind and ask your
customer as well if you do a red team
engagement the end query the query at
the beginning should be what do you want
to learn what do you want me to simulate
if you do red teaming without flank you
don't want to know if outflank can break
in
i can almost say we're confident that in
most cases we can
no you want to learn if an average
ransomware guy from a certain area in
the world can do a very aggressive
attack and succeed or maybe you want to
learn if a very skilled adversary that
takes five months and builds his own
tool can make a persistent connection
and listening on your data over the next
few years two totally different
questions to totally different
approaches for the red team for us
and and still it's important that we
mimic what the customer asks and stay
close to those adversaries so the blue
team can improve the blue team is not
there to kick out the red team
the blue team is there to kick out the
criminal
so please keep that in mind
red elk is here to help you
for the blue for the red teams but in
the end also for the blue teams because
in the end of the operation we can give
the blue team a list of every command
when we did it how we did it what the
parameters were and there can they can
tune their defenses to make sure that
next time we do such a thing it's
detected so that's one go to get up
check on the alarms codes that's in
there just the simple checks that we can
do to spot the traces left by blue it's
for your knowledge as well but
essentially red dark is of course
created for red teams it's here to help
you and even and as a blue team you get
most of the tools you can just download
and repeat the steps
do it yourself make sure that the alarm
triggers
how how a waste would it if a next red
team can do the same trick and still
succeed
and then
the ioc overview from red elk quite
often either during the operation if
management gets stressed that some real
attack might be going on it's a piece of
cake for us to check was that us give me
a username give me an md5 a file name
anything and i'll look it up and i can
tell you exactly whether or not we touch
that machine during our op
and in the end while cleaning up the
iocs also really help to clean up the
stuff that might be left behind
quite quite often we find leftovers from
other red teams clean up your stuff and
if you can't ask the blue team to do so
and give them the information they need
and then of course blue team think of
your opsec
if we can monitor what you guys are
doing the criminals can as well and we
might use red elk for the benefit of the
engagement and for your benefit if a
criminal would use something like red
elk it's not going to benefit you it's
only going to make your life harder
and the attack more advanced if we have
to give a penny to every blue team that
tries to investigate
a certain
url of our c2 implant
by first accessing it with the actual
implant and then trying with python from
the same ip address of the corporate
network and then switching all of a
sudden going to talk
and we see traffic coming in front door
to that specific ap address
please think of your offset don't don't
don't send the url by whatsapp to the
team members whatsapp will query the url
and we'll see what's up coming in okay
someone found our our c2 url and
forwards it to a colleague
please don't okay
i think that's it for now any questions
we've got five got a few minutes left so
if not we're going to to give the five
minutes that wind saves us to the next
speaker and he can you can use those
i see it's just ready
yeah the question is do we only uh which
c2 frameworks do we support actually
well corporal strike is a very big one
that we support we have our own c2
framework which we support we're working
on several others which have partly
support like uh porsche c2
and i'm interested in i have basic
support from mythic and i'm looking at
sliver as well but
it's
it's an open source project i'm
welcoming any type of help on this
any more questions
either i was dead clear or i was dead
boring
[Laughter]
thanks a lot for your time we will be
around for the remaining of the
conference if you still have questions
hook us up somewhere in the
outside thank you all for your attention
thanks