this conference will now be recorded
all right everybody my name is rod soto
i'm here with jonathan rospero
and
we coordinate the meetings for hack
miami today
we have
uh introduction to how we're hacking
with honey
uh and uh we
uh basically uh invite you to join us at
discord i think rospero
uh already posted a link or he will post
it again uh other than that respect do
you have anything to say or
no i'm all good here
all right then
uh i'm gonna pass it to honey she is
a member of uh miami she's also been at
defcon uh and she is actually part of
the
howard hiking village uh and we're gonna
let her introduce us into uh hardware
hacking 101 take it away thanks can
y'all see my screen can you hear me okay
yes
awesome all right i got my subtitles on
hey uh this was probably the most
challenging presentation i've ever made
uh and i want to apologize in advance
i'm sick
so i'm not feeling great today so
if you hear the sniffles in the coughs
i'm sorry
we're gonna work through it um
as rod said i'm a volunteer i've been a
member of hack miami for like
i'm not saying how long because that's a
long time at this point um and i've been
part of defcon hardware hacking village
for like
about six years at this point uh you can
find me on discord if you want that's my
specific honey i'm one of the many
um i always do disclosures and liability
statements at the beginning of all of my
presentations for hack miami because
um i i don't know what you guys are
going to do with this information that
we covered today and therefore i can't
tell you whether or not you're doing
something that you might not want to be
doing but i will tell you that in
hardware hacking you're definitely going
to encounter dangerous substances
you're definitely going to incr
lead toxic fumes
metals all sorts of good stuff so you
want to make sure that you are
protecting your bodies and keeping
yourself safe
and also you're going to avoid all the
warranties on everything you touch so
just know that and it's your
responsibility to stay within compliance
of
state federal national global whatever
laws that's on you folks yeah avoid all
the warranties man
right to repair
all right so um
i'm all about that but um just so you
know that's on you fam all right so
moving on uh
so after doing all this research on
hardware hacking i now get every joke in
that episode that i did not get before
uh wait let me go back
so
i'm honey i started out in hacking in
the se world social engineering as a
defensive skill
and once i
because i got hacked pretty hard and i
wanted to make sure it didn't happen
again so i started learning everything i
could learn everything i could get to
um
and i liked it and i was good at it and
the more i learned the more i realized
how social engineering is really creepy
and
ocean is even creepier
and i kind of wanted to start
researching
what i considered to be the polar
opposite of those skills which was
hardware hacking um after this
presentation i'm i'm gonna stay where i
belong in se and in uh ocean because
this was meaty for me and i i hope you
guys gained something out of it i
learned so much doing this research so
um yeah don't break the laws uh safety
equipment also just you know you're
gonna inhale a lot of these fumes and um
you don't get prophetic visions from it
you just get brain damage so please just
make sure that you're protecting
yourselves
and also make sure that whatever
substance especially if you're soldering
or de-soldering whatever um
solder falls down so make sure that it
don't solder over your lap or over like
your skin and if you're gonna do that
just wear natural fibers so that you
don't burn your
stuff off
right okay
um so what is hardware hacking um it's
not what i thought it was when i started
this presentation it's not what it's so
much bigger than that it's so much it's
huge
basically any alteration of an
electronic device or machine that makes
it do something that the original
manufacturer didn't intend
you can add parts you can take away
parts you can speed up your clocks we'll
get into it but pretty much like
everything can be hardware hacking so
uh i went down the rabbit hole pretty
deep on this and i came up with a good
spectrum of stuff i learned some stuff
about electrical engineering so if
you're going to be in the hardware
hacking world you're definitely going to
want to do some some basic electrical
stuff that's that's
it it's also fixing though and
repurposing making your own use for
things
so
hardware hacking is such a broad topic
that
i i figured like pretty much like
everything at this point um
hold on i'm just checking the chat so
yeah i put the
roster i put the subtitles to spanish
the people who speak english can hear me
sorry
all right so um
yeah so making your own use for things
um
does anyone remember furbies
furbies are where this rabbit hole led
me pretty pretty early on and i gotta
tell you man i didn't like it
oh they're horrible we're i'm gonna show
you yeah we'll get there all right so
all of these things can be considered um
hardware hacking it's not just the stuff
that you think of like the rubber
duckies and the wi-fi pineapples it's
it's the furby hacking too
it's all right um tools that i recommend
that you
start with and and the other thing about
hardware hacking is it's super super
um
project specific
it's very project specific so depending
on what you're trying to do with what
device on what interface on what chip
with which sensor or whatever
you need a different tool set so the
ifixit kit is pretty much considered
your assembly disassembly kit like you
mix this with the soldering set and and
that's your
your hardware components for the most
part and i fix it'll help you
disassemble some really tricky stuff too
not that i'm trying to plug it it's just
i mean you can go and get all of those
tools yourself
but um
the kit just kind of has everything um
using that kit you'll void the warranty
right there
um
so and some kind of interface a tool
that lets you interact with the chips or
components that you're trying to use
i'll give you the top three tools that
when i did some interviews i came across
and um
we'll get into that in a later one logic
analyzers and oscilloscopes those those
get real specific and there's a whole
argument over which one to use
in what circumstance so it's very
specific to the project that you're
trying to use um i read an article about
a guy who hacked a
projector a lidar projector using just
an oscilloscope but in the end he
couldn't decipher the data that he got
from it because it was in such raw
form so
again it's very project specific um
you're gonna need google you're gonna
need github you're gonna need reddit and
a raspberry pi and an arduino can't help
and this is just my first um
of two only two hardware hacking village
defcon plugs um
they have a cali distribution a cali
with all the tools loaded on it
everything you need it's updated
regularly so it's got all sorts of uh
functional stuff and i've got links
every every part of this presentation
has links to either the article that i
got the research from
or to the product that i'm telling you
about so that afterwards i can send you
the you can go ahead and
go on a click journey like i did
uh
uh yeah okay so we're still on the
furbies okay nothing in the chat um
all right so you've got to be able to
communicate with the devices
in their language uh and these are these
are pretty much the top three
common uh protocols languages
anyway it gets real deep into electrical
engineering like some of these aren't
really protocols but just a jake tag is
not a protocol so
how you program the machine when you
first uh
inject the code i guess into the chip
and some people lock their jtags some
don't this the jtag is like most
synonymously used with the xbox 360 hack
but really you can use them for
everything um and they do use them for
everything
um some people lock their jtags like
some manufacturers will lock the uh
not the port but the ability to use it
and a lot don't so it never hurts to try
and jtag when you find
a concrete definition for the word jtag
you let me know fam because that was one
that i had a rough time on too
um
okay so depending on which protocol
what you're talking to and and you just
google it nobody remembers everything so
you just google okay i'm trying to
interface with this microcontroller you
just google it and it'll tell you what
what protocols to use and what machines
use it so everybody uses uh google and
github
no matter how experienced you are you
can't remember all of this stuff
all right so
um i tried to include three different
these are multi-protocol variable
voltage tools you could say that five
times fast and i'll buy you a beer at
winter hacker festival
um if just take a look at the boards for
a second um they're super well labeled
super well labeled i hope you're not
trying to watch this on a phone
otherwise it's like
way tiny
um
the tiger is the newest of the three
and my hardware hacking buddy bunny who
is our lead at hardware hacking village
defcon this is the one that he uses and
recommends but he says the bus pirate
does more but it's kind of a shaky piece
of equipment sometimes it works
sometimes it doesn't um but it's great
and it does a lot but the tigger does or
tiger
does
what it does very well
and you can see they're almost the same
they've got the same pins little lights
that tell you uh what you're using i
like the on off switch for the two guard
tigered
can you see my pen
if i use my pen my laser pointer here
i'm gonna use my laser pointer this
thing is cool this this eliminates like
a whole
whole side of these boards because you
could just toggle this on and off
um
no no weird programming needed so
but the bus pirate does a million things
um there are links to each of these like
when you click this it'll gain you
and i included the adafruit one the
adafruit one is the cheapest of the
three it does the three main components
um
you can see right here it's got all your
grounds it's got all your ports um
they're
variable voltage means that you can use
them in three volt or five volt the
seaguard goes all the way from one point
eight volts to five volts so that's kind
of cool
um the eight is the smallest but it's
also the cheapest um
and it's always in stock so that's
always nice
it does ic2 you can see it here they're
labeled very well see if you want to
just take a second to look at these
boards and these are what help you
interface with
whatever you're trying to interface with
whether it's a screen that you're trying
to see if it works or if it's a
chip on a board that you're trying to
look at
i kind of just want to give you guys a
second to
look it over and zoom in can i zoom in
here oh i
can look at that
all right
and the goal is
it is it zoomed in
yes
there we go and and i legit i just
straight up stole these pictures right
off the manufacturer website so it's not
like this is some secret and i give you
the link to the stores where you can buy
them if you're into it they're pretty
cheap considering all the functions that
they do
um
you can also buy an individual tool to
do each of these things if you wanted
and that tool would probably work
wonderfully but then you're carrying
around a box of tools which you know
some people don't mind
some people check their luggage when
they go to defcon some people carry a
backpack i'm one of those backpack
people
um so on top of these devices that help
you interface with
whatever you're trying to interface with
whether it's a chip
or the back of a teddy ruxpin or
that one was horrifying
that that was that was the one that's
going to be in my nightmares tonight the
teddy ruxpin i found
um
yeah
but whatever you're trying to interface
with so this is what will help you
interface with the hardware you also
need to interface with the software so
let me turn off my laser pointer
there we go
um this is just this is just a drop in
the bucket there are literally
hundreds of different softwares that you
can use free circuit analysis oh thank
you thanks mike that's what's up
excellent uh guys check the chat for a
free circuit
analysis and design
excuse me sorry to cough in your ear
folks um
these are all included and then this is
my second hardware hacking village plug
i promise um and the only reason i
include this link
this is the link to their their cali
distro on
on github and it's got all the tools
that
they recommend using and that i say we
recommend using but this stuff is
it goes real deep so
these are some of the tools that you can
find the software that you need because
once you interface with the hardware
then you've got to find a way to
translate what the hardware is saying so
that you can read it and interface with
it most the bus pirate the
um
and don't google it backwards because if
you google pirate bus
you get a whole lot of really weird sea
shanties and a dude who converted a
school bus
into a pirate bus so the bus pirate um
they come with their own software
libraries too so if you are interested
in that hardware then um
it comes with the software that you need
to read and then cali is always the
recommended everything for everything
uh oh yeah great that is like another
thing thank you um oh phil what's up hey
hey honey
who are you
oh my god hey you tell me about the
great foot i i've been talking too much
tell me about the great
no i don't want to jump in here on your
speech but uh it's a good little gadget
it's a great little gadget um i haven't
really taken advantage of it to its full
potential but um
it does all the same protocols
uh does you allow you to do like
interactive uh programming but the
coolest thing that does is allow you to
do um
usb
uh emulation
so there's some pretty cool attacks that
you can pull off by emulating a flash
drive and then simulating a whole file
system so it's really cool attacks i've
actually been wanting to do a talk on it
for a while
but uh it's a little bit pricier but
it's a really cool device
you know what that you pay for quality
though so and especially if it's going
to be something that you use more than
once or you or it becomes part of your
everyday tool kit i i say it's worth it
to spend the money but i also
buy a lot of badges at def con so um
but yeah all right thanks yeah great fed
is one of the tools i came across um
it's so you can't list every tool there
are so so so so many out there which is
why
i say that if you're interested in
learning um hardware hacking that one of
the best places to start are those
blinky badges from from any con you go
to i just saw one that had a mechanical
lock that opens it's from a con that was
like last week it was a shape of a lock
you program and it had a mechanical like
it was a
it looked like a locker lot like a
combination lock super cool um and those
are some of the best places to get
started because
one you're going to be in a community of
people who are trying to do the same
thing you are and that helps and two it
gives you a focused project to learn on
um
and that is invaluable because if you
just go
okay i want to learn about hardware
hacking like i did
i started with okay i'm gonna hack my
vacuum and then i was like oh man i
really like my vacuum though and i
if i break it which is entirely a
hundred percent possible because if you
solder the wrong thing or you pop
something like that's it it's done and i
like my vacuum my little um we got one
of the ones that's smart enough to to
make it around the house without falling
down the steps but stupid enough that it
doesn't map the room which i'm really
grateful at because we also found that
there's a really amazing hardware hack
for vacuums where the lidar is getting
hacked and it basically turns your
vacuum into a listening device
did anybody come across that ever in the
the hardware hacking world the hack
against it it's just like a year ago or
so
super cool
so um these are some of the example
softwares that
that i want to say i recommend but i'm
really that are popular and then the
cali distro on the hhv
github has so so so much um so i wanted
to give you some
some examples of what i've come across
um
from common to
up weird
um
all right so this is the this is one of
the things that people love to do
hardware hacks is to crack your to crack
your ex this is an old xbox it only
works on a certain xbox before a certain
date and i had one and i lost it in my
divorce and i'm so sad about that but
it's uh it's what it does is it allows
you to bypass the
the uh the control mechanism that
prevents you from playing cracked games
and you can run homebrew on your on your
xbox and it's gorgeous uh this is the
inside of the box again uh when i send
out the powerpoint for this presentation
you can just click on the title that's
underlined that's actually a link
and it will take you to uh the article
that i read on how to
how to jtag your xbox 360
which is such an old device at this
point i'm not i'm sure that there are
emulators that are so far beyond this so
that's the other thing about hardware
hacking sometimes there's just easier
stuff you can just
buy it but if that's not about the
adventure you want to be about the
adventure
so cracking your consoles there was a
crack for the original we too that was
awesome and then it just lets you play
your homebrewed downloaded games so
fun times
um these are probably two of the most
widely known hardware hacking devices
you've got your duckies and your
pineapples um
i don't know if you consider the
pineapple a lot of people consider the
pineapple of a hardware hack because
it's a repeater so like the signal was
only supposed to be within this certain
area and you're repeating it
and uh and it allows you to do like man
middle attacks and all sorts of things
and then rubber duckies are
the ducky itself is not a hardware hack
what you're doing is you're exploiting
the key uh the usb
by
it's expecting a keyboard or something
friendly so by plugging in
this thing that reads as a keyboard and
it's a key logger it injects programming
it does all sorts of cool stuff
um
has anybody ever used one of these uh
that wants to do a swim someone who
isn't me used one of these and
you guys are so quiet
should i lean in and wait in the silence
or should i move on
sure i've used a few of them
uh rubber duckies for an attack and a
few um actually like uh arduino-based
ones that have multiple payloads
um made a
staged payload using one it was a good
attack
good time okay
did you have to pair it with an se
attack or did you just walk in and shove
it in the back of the computer and there
you go
yep basically
um i actually i made a variant for uh
the point was it was supposed to assume
no privileges could be used on a guest
account um and it worked for different
variations like 32-bit 64-bit and
os x this is like six years ago um it
was a fun little project
that's what's up that's what's up yeah
that's the fun part about any of the
malicious hardware hacking stuff usually
and that's the funny part that i didn't
expect when i started researching
hardware hacking and i started into this
world i started with soldering like
everybody else but i had no idea you
have to pair
the delivery of these devices with some
sort of usually
kind of sophisticated se attack to get
them
where you want them to be because you
know plugging this into a
crazy radio from mouse jack attack hey
mike do you want to explain that out
loud because i understand all those
words separately
yeah i'm sorry i want to jump on
you're awesome i'm
just really enjoying your presentation
i know it's actually when i when i set
up social sect over here on the
southwest florida uh was one of the
first demonstrations i did for the crew
uh just showing that you can buy a
simple crazy radio pa
off of amazon or any other electronics
place alibaba or whatever
for i think it's less than twenty
dollars or something it's super simple
the snag one
and
you could
uh just use uh the jacket kit
uh and some cali and
just sit out in the park lot basically
and just scan for
the um
the radio signal that's coming off of
your
wireless mics and keyboards
and once you see them showing up then
you can just
intercept the signal and basically um
inject
keyboard strokes
mouse clicks stuff like that
and so we we did a demo of it and and
basically took over computer and and pop
notepad and calp just to essentially
show what was possible with a because
people don't typically update their
firmware on their wireless mice and
keyboards
and it's uh it still exists out there
um because most of the vendors weren't
pushing those updates to the their
firmware little the little universal
usb chips you get with every wireless
mouse and keyboard uh so it's it's a
simple demo to show people
and it still works
that's
unsettling dude
that's unsettling
um
i'm i'm a little like
unhappy that apple's kind of getting rid
of all these ports i still plug my
headphones in when i can and i'm just
like not ready to move over to bluetooth
for everything and i feel like i'm being
forced and i really don't like it
i'm gonna i'm ready to go back to my
walkman that i had when i was a child
although those are back in style now
so um
also another example of a hardware hack
this is definitely not what the
manufacturers of the gas pump intended
and it's just a little piece of hardware
it just slips right in there um
when i was googling this just checking
my sources over the last couple days i
came across a news story in michigan
where they did a random sweep and found
like
i don't know between 15 and 20 gas
stations in this area that had been
compromised
and they think it's all the same group
so
these are another example of hardware
this is i started with the malicious
stuff because i know hack miami is at
its core security group uh but i gotta
tell you hardware hacking gets uh
oh this is for you hack miami
oh bay can i have the original one
can i have the linksys
do you have any old hack miami people
here like like
i wonder
no probably not we have the original
linksys with the percent 27 stickers
that don't exist anymore
somehow my husband ended up with it
so
um any favorite war stories on this guy
does anyone know who this guy is
our
wrdt54 the classic i mean like i know
it's a classic but i feel like i'm
talking to a 101 group who wants me to
like lead them through and i'm just not
there you know it was uh oh here it is
here it is
thanks baby uh let me
uh at least i brushed my hair for this
hold on where's my camera
i think one my thing is in full screen
it's not going to show me anyway but we
have the original one
it's crazy old so
when they distributed this linksys
router they distribute it with um
linux
and it's uh
well it's super flexible
it's a super flexible wonderful piece of
machinery that people could
use and manipulate and boost your
signals and do all sorts of malicious
on
and um
after this comes out uh
you know the company kind of backs it up
on giving people flexibility with their
programming and their routers
um
there's a link
to the i think it's a
vice
all about this all about this hardware
super cute it's old at this point people
do still use them
but like i don't know how it's
good times good times
so you could just basically
patch into this guy
change the firmware he can be caught
over everything
all right so
i think here's where the weird stuff
starts oh no okay all right so i stayed
these are your blinkies and your badges
this is this is where i would learn
honestly this is probably going to be my
next step is hitting my def card badge
for this year um i know most of the
hardware stuff on the defcon badge this
year let me zoom into oh there we go to
the back
um
you know it's a don't stop the signal
thing like if you look um
can you guys see my mouse no you can't
the guy with his mouth open and there's
a binary code above his head there's a
little pill there you're supposed to
oh spoiler alerts in case you're
actually going to do this yourself
spoiler alerts
yeah but if you haven't looked this up
already i don't think you're gonna so
anyway you gotta like follow the signal
there's a pill here there's one um down
in the bottom left hand corner as well
and uh basically you desolder one pill
and solder the other and that changes
the path of the signal and when you're
plugged into your computer and you've
got your programs running it'll give you
the next step of the code
uh the next step of the code is to
connect the et finger
you know the e.t michelangelo
finger uh to the space needle or to the
ground because it's just the space no
it's just a ground anyway um
yeah and that gives you the next signal
so
this is a great place to start because
one it gets you used to interfacing
between your computer and a board
um
and again like i said about the con
badges they get you together with other
people who are interested in looking at
it
did you just drop hacker boxes you did
okay i love hacker boxes too
hold on sam says
[Music]
yeah
but that router was um
that router was a classic sam if you
want to take a second to explain the
glory of it you guys can do it better
than me
um
these are just things that i found on
the rabbit hole of what is hardware
hacking
just in case sam samuel wants to say
that the open wrt is just it was just
the original
it was a very good router for what it
could do and it was people could figure
out how to do it
uh i mean they they do have some modern
5g variants in the network wrt also
called like wrt like i use in
i think it's an open then and open the
wrt 1900 acs acs and whatever so they do
have more modern fi fi fifth generation
wi-fi ones with the firmware
that the fcc requires lockdown isolated
so you can still edit the device
so
what are the benefits of being able to
edit
edit the device like what are the cool
things that you can i mean while i say i
have another one right or like they'd
like have a netgear
the netgear equivalent to the
54g would probably be the 3700 i know it
was a workhorse a lot of people were
working with including me
the advantages have a you have a router
that's five to the extent you can do it
is when some of these are 10 year 10 15
years old at this point aren't they and
there you you can still get modern
updates for them to the extent that you
haven't overflowed the available storage
space on the device
so you can
so you can put mesh networking in them
it's very common to see mesh networking
put on these devices or
if you want to install pretty much
anything linux on them that fits they
can
i mean i mean one like that one wouldn't
have usb ports but newer devices would
actually i don't know if the 54g did but
the netgear i referred to does and
they're
i mean i have the 1900 version has a has
usb 3 on it
you're kidding
so you can then attach so it's basically
a device and you can then attach so if
you want to plug this you you want to
put have your networking device do file
sharing it can
or
is that
oh man is um
uh jax are you here is that how he made
his pirate box it was just a box that he
used to carry around then it would just
you could leave something or take
something we'll use something or take
something it was always powered always
on and it was just this tiny signal 15
20 foot radius or something like that
and it could also have been a raspberry
pi in that case but yeah i think either
use the wi-fi pineapple or a raspberry
pi
it's so fun i miss him i hope he's
coming around the winter y'all better
come the winner half professional
if you're willing and able to be in
person i think it was a pie but it was
like
yeah that thing was cool um
all right yeah the
do we have interest in making a hack
miami uh mesh network i thought we
talked about it at some point how close
do we have to be together to do that is
it a couple miles or is it less than
that it's probably less than that
it would depend if you're trying to
operate under amateur radio rules or
yeah or if you're trying to operate
within the fcc
allowed output of a device like that and
how directional you can point all those
antennas
okay right
i think it's one watt limit for for
wi-fi you'd have to start getting into
like microwave links or amateur radios
he's saying
like a principal there is one amateur
radio group that has a link
runs a wi-fi link all the way from
from delray beach to florida atlantic
university and that's how they get
internet
that's awesome no it's
tough to remote shack yeah
that's awesome
can you drop do they uh do they have a
link or something where we could take a
look at any of any of that could you
drop it in the
we got all sorts of great stuff
like i know the link exists i don't know
if they formally comment about it
anywhere i think actually two amateur
radio groups to get their internet
through florida atlantic university
but that's pretty
i think it's personal i think it's
overkill but it's just where they were
they couldn't get
dsl or anything where they put repeaters
also uh check out linus tech tips had a
video he's done two of them on uh like
prosumer grade or um
directional like linked link microwaves
so that you can get like a few
kilometers distance on like i think
ubiquity makes them
um but again it's it's overkill and
their point to point you have to have
you know line of sight from from one
tower to another so
it doesn't make sense
hook up your cantennas people
right
you have those those silly what's their
name which you're playing with uh
the
low speed
mesh networks and trying to load the
planes the laura's yes yeah yeah
yeah i came across
in my
in my in this rabbit hole of looking and
i was just like
i'm not covering anything that has to do
with radio
i'm not doing anything that has to do
with that because i know we've got
experts in the group that are coming up
with a talk for that for the next round
and i'm like i'm gonna learn
about that a little more before i
even touch that with a 10-foot pole
with my cantenna
i've given two talks on it and it is a
rabbit hole don't go down it
can you just give a quick quick
explanation because i know there's a lot
of newbies on here that what is laura
real quick and then
and then i know you're planning on
something for later or i don't know if
it's you or someone else but i didn't
want to step on that talk
uh laura i'm not giving a talk on it but
laura is basically just a a low power
wide area network and i think it's based
on
they're all open like imf frequencies i
think it's based on four four four three
three megahertz
um you see them used a lot in things
like uh i think
i think they use them in what are they
called like those energy meters
um and and other devices but they're
pretty low bandwidth but the nice thing
is that they they have a long distance
and pretty low power requirements
well that's what's up all right folks so
this is definitely something that we can
we can expound on some more um
all right so back to the blinkies and
the badges which is about where i'm
comfortable because i uh
i love those hardware arts and crafts um
and then i just gave you a little piece
of what the terminal would look like
how to reset the buttons oh god i love
tindy
tindy anything
they've got to be somewhere in this
presentation
all right ah
so this was actually the first thing
that i was going to do because my
courage is broken and so i figured hey
let me hack my craig and then
i started my master's degree so um this
is some other dude hacking his correg
and he also will go to the next step of
plugging the water into a water source
that's forever on so that but you still
have to put the little k-cup in you
still have to put the cup in so i'm kind
of like unsatisfied with this hardware
hack but it's it's don't let me talk
it's actually a really good hack
and it's
he made his career wireless
so he just like signs on to a little
website in his morning and like presses
like initiate and the courage starts
brewing but he has to put the cup in the
night before um and then he wired it up
so that he no longer has to put water in
the tank but that it's hooked up to a
permanent water source as well
and um yeah so it's pretty cool um you
still have to put the cup in at the end
of the the night uh
so that was the only hang up and um
honestly it's beautiful and it's a
brilliant hack so now his courage is
wireless and there's a link to i
you not like 20 pages of directions on
how he did that and i went through them
and it's
the you got to have patience to be in
hardware hacking because it's not i'm
telling you right now it's probably not
going to work the first time you plug it
in there's always a something there's
always something like a resistor you put
on backwards and you can't really put
resistors on backwards but like stuff
like that like and then you gotta go
through your steps and uh okay wiggle
every wire make sure you didn't
bridge anything or have any gaps
anywhere did i program it you know so so
just a little bit of patience in
yourself
what button down
no it's a joke you know like you said
have you tried turning it off and on
again so no i'm joking because i was
like oh am i on mute oh god that
would be the worst i've been talking for
like three minutes now so
we i i
i know every single one of you
has felt that moment in the last online
year of oh i've been on mute this
whole time so
oh here we are
here we are folks we've made it to the
1980s hardware hacking which i got to
tell you
people love this stuff
people are not in the community the the
most
die-hard people that i've met get the
most excited about this kind of stuff
like people who have like
phds and or whatever you get for
electrical engineering that makes you
like
the at it i don't and they look at
this stuff and they're like oh my god
it's so cheap so she didn't even
hack the bear for this one
she
she so she i want you to just take a
look um this is a snip from the youtube
which was as creepy as you think it's
gonna be by the way it's actually as
creepy as you think it's it's worse it's
gonna get worse from here folks we're
only going downhill from here
um so she's got it it's like a a
three-track
cassette tape
reader writer basically is what that
thing is and um i want you to take a
look at the cassette tape in the bear's
lap
and i just said that sentence
i'm getting my master's degree folks
take a look
at the cassette tape and the bears
those two little uh holes on the sides
though the ones that are far left far
right if you tape over them it lets you
tape over the tape so what she found out
was that
when you look at this tape there's a
frequency there now there's a track for
the
for the audio like what the bear is
saying
there's a track for the music you know
the background music and then there's a
track that is inaudible that makes the
bear's mouth move
so if you only record over the part
that's the bear's audio you can make him
say whatever you want
with the music behind him
well you i guess you can record you
could have the bear be like
you know what let's not get weird folks
okay so you know what you can make the
bear say whatever you want by recording
over the proper track and as long as you
pay attention to where
the the audio signal is for the bear
to flap his and he blinks too
it's a double freakiness yeah he flaps
his mouth he opens his mouth and he
blinks um
as long as you
get up you know you make the bear say
whatever you want and he does now other
people have gone a step farther and you
can also get teddy ruxpin hacks there
where they have integrated a raspberry
pi because there's a hole in his back
where the cassette tape goes so some
people have pulled out the cassette tape
hardware like entirely and just
integrated like their own audio speakers
and everything into the back of the bear
and then you just put a shirt
you just
close it back up um
and he says whatever and it's it's it's
truly creepy it's truly horrifying um
yeah so i i linked you to that video
there
um where you can watch the entire
process
of her
and
she's really like a normal looking lady
too it's quite it makes it worse
um in my opinion yeah
and um this was a 2 a.m find this was
too and i'm never up till 2 a.m like i
told you guys i've been um i've been
sick
so i've been up late doing my school
work and my own research for this and um
this is what happens when you mix
circuit bending uh circuit bending is a
whole
weird awesome music a lot of music
a lot of that
since
music that
hardware that defcon is all about it has
a lot of electronic stuff in the
background that's circuit bending
um
so people took like the circuit bending
plus the teddy ruxpin and furby hacking
and this guy is actually he's actually
kind of he's really he's really freaking
cool man he does this with like a
gameboy wall too like he circuit bends
all sorts of electronics like honestly
like it's his day job so like yay for
him like
live your
live your bliss bro um
it's kind of creepy that that's what
this dude's bliss looks like though
because it's an organ of furbies and i'm
it the videos that i've got here they
don't the video doesn't play i just have
a screenshot for you but what he does is
he integrates the mechanics of the furby
into the synthesizer and when he plays
it they all sing on different pitches
and they open their eyes and mouths and
this is not the only furby hack this is
just this guy's furby hack
and there are so
so
so many others
yeah
it gets real dark
um
and all of this is hardware hacking um
the raspberries you definitely want the
raspberry pies and the arduinos because
they offer you um
a lot of accessibility and they're cheap
um but everything from the duckies to
the the gas tanks to the
the blinky batches and the furbies it's
all considered hardware hacking which um
i basically found out when i started
researching it's like giving a
presentation like what is hacking and
it's like okay here we go
you know it's its own it's its whole own
branch so
um i have links to
oh yeah special thanks i download all my
slide templates from this place called
slides carnival i figured i'd keep it in
there because they wanted me to um and
then bunny at
the defcon hhv village is my hardware
guru and he's helped me design the
winter hacker festival badge that we
gave out a couple years ago it was a
real simple circular
pretty little
purple pcb that had six blinky lights on
it and a battery and um we that was the
first thing i had ever
that's the first board i had ever
designed and it was really a cool
process and he was going to help me with
that and he's the one that helped me
today
um
so um
i don't know if you have questions or if
you'd like to throw those in the chat uh
if you'd like to organize a hack miami
mesh network that'd be cool i'd be down
to aim an antenna at some of you
and um i put also links to some of the
articles that i found that really helped
me because um a lot of a lot of hardware
hacking is also understanding electrical
engineering and i kept a lot of that
stuff out of this presentation for i'm
not gonna lie to you for one reason me
explaining that was real rough and i
would rather hold off and explain it at
a later talk when i understand it better
than to come in here and try to explain
to you the
the benefits of the difference between
serial and parallel bit transfer like
because it gets like that so
um
are there any things that i can answer
or help y'all with before we go ahead
and break i'll make sure that this
presentation the pdf version is
distributed through our discord so that
you can clicky all the links if there
was something that you liked that you
wanted to find but please make sure that
if there's a link in the chat
um
oh that's what's up yo i'm glad that you
learned something um come to our
meetings we've got experts in every
field next time i give a talk it'll be
on uh osenter essie when we're ready for
another one of those
there's a whole new suite of uh
tools in that field that have been
released because
you know businesses get smart services
get smart they start blocking you know
how we search you gotta you know you
gotta come up with new ways so there's a
whole new
world of that so i'm happy that this was
um
yeah discord uh respeto can you drop the
discord link again and then i'll um i'll
send respedo or rod the uh pdf version
of this
um
and it should have all the links active
and all that good stuff so that you guys
can click around see what i saw and i'm
sorry about that because i'm telling you
2am furby organ was a little bit
the stuff of my nightmares now and you
know what's the weirdest part i didn't
even hate it i kind of was vibing on it
that's the weirdest part
i couldn't even be mad at it i was like
okay this guy is actually
pretty decent with this furby organ it
was cool and he's got a game boy he's
got this it's a whole youtube channel
it's kind of sick
so
yeah all right more more details to come
on winter hacker festival and um
thank you all for
going down that weird hardware hacking
rabbit hole with me
thank you for uh the presentation
any questions
this is the time
also we also do have the
hardware channel and the learning and
help section if anyone wants to
post questions in there after a meeting
and
do we have a hardware channel because i
was looking for it
it's a