this conference will now be recorded
alright good afternoon everybody um
today
uh we have a privilege
uh having um the reverend patrick
that is james ball uh one of the
founders of
hack miami uh james is
truly truly truly a person that i
respect
and admire and i had the the privilege
of being his friend
james for me is an american hero james
is an original terrorist fighter
um freedom fighter uh he's very humble
and he will never
you know tell you all his adventures but
he's incredible
and maybe one day i'll just sit with him
and we'll talk about some of the amazing
things he's done
and uh you get to see how a person
really truly believes in what
he does uh how he helps others
and he simply doesn't say anything it's
not that other people are
posting about stuff that they truly
don't do by the way
so um thank you james
for giving us this time um you know you
are one of the pilots at miami you're
one of the founders i know you from
uh now quite a bit of time and uh
very happy you're still with us even
though you're no longer in florida
you're in uh
in the west coast uh and uh we're happy
to have you here
and um without further ado
this is uh james ball
hi everybody thanks for like uh
fantastic introduction rod
uh that was very very nice
let's see
so um
so this i'm gonna this is gonna be the
red team in the cloud
basically this presentation uh
i decided to do this presentation
because i've been getting
a lot of requests and engagements where
they wanted me to go
attack either an on-premise enterprise
cloud environment or like our a full
base
ip range in the cloud or or also
um amazon instances so
basically i've been getting a lot more
requests to to attack more cloud
infrastructure
and um so during this time
getting this request i decided to do the
the more the most recent
science training on the um
on cloud penetration testing and
to my surprise and also to my surprise
when i was doing the engagements a lot
of the methodology
that i've used for web application
hacking
and basically the other type of packing
uh basically
followed through to this environment as
well
so it was it was a pretty much easier
pivot to go from web application hacking
which was my um
my forte efforts into this
so i'm going to keep it high level i'm
not going to show any demos or anything
because i don't i i don't really have
any targets live
that i can legally show you right now
but uh and i will
keep this focus on aws primarily
um however you know azure microsoft
azure cloud
you know that's also uh very similar to
this as well as google cloud computing
and alibaba
so what what i'm going to be discussing
here will uh will work across
all the different types of um or all the
different vendors in cloud computing
uh but uh this will be primary with aws
now when you're going to be doing cloud
computing uh or cloud-based uh
penetration testing you are going to be
using
the tools associated with the
environment so
when you be testing amazon or aws system
you'll be using their
aws client command line interface or
their own tool and most of the attacks
will be based on your knowledge of
the of those tools itself so
that is something that is also quite
interesting that
the tools that you that you'll be
needing to do a lot of the um
privilege escalations will be the
built-in tools
so if you are so if you did manage to
compromise
say an internal system though you
wouldn't have to be
worried about installing extra tools
because more than likely
these tools will probably be in one of
those uh
systems
so this here's another brief
introduction that i wrote into the
presentation about me
you know i've been here for very long
i've been doing this for a very long
time
i really couldn't give a better um
introduction that rod has given to me or
given to you guys earlier
uh but uh i will also i will go into the
types of um
[Music]
the types of things i've been into
recently i did mention
i've been going to cloud computing
recently but i'm also a subject matter
expert and web application testing
and api testing as well as single
sign-on technologies
which which was very well into
um cloud-based uh testing
so as i said earlier
the the cloud the cloud is being adopted
by many industries and many industries
are going to go
fully based into the cloud now
when i mean the cloud i'm also saying
azure and um
aws you can use it on application
software's other services such as um out
um office 360. that's that's a type of
cloud-based uh
thing uh infrastructure that would be
that's considered software as a service
so one thing one thing we don't go into
is the types of cloud-based
services that we can test and the
scoping around them
um
oops
okay so yeah
so in this slide i described on the
types of services that we see in the
cloud as i mentioned earlier
software as a service here here you'll
be only
able to attack um the instance of the uh
organization's implementation so uh
you'll be attacked is say tesla's
instance of
or office 360 as opposed to office 360
itself
so now we go to platformer services you
know
these things these are things that we
see that allow developers to call an
existing environment
and when we have these type of tests you
are expected to stay within
the containerized um
area of that instance so
basically you if you're testing say
something like um
uh sharepoint you you'll be only testing
the say tesla.sharepoint.com or
something like that
and it that the basic the basics um
understanding of this
is that when we're testing cloud uh in
infrastructure and cloud uh
environments we're gonna have to make
sure that we're only sticking
within the clients uh or a target
organization's uh
instances of it we we generally would
not have
the permission to actually go
say attack amazon.com itself or azure
the instance itself but we more than
likely will be attacking the
implementation of these instances
um the last
thing i have function as a service uh
this is uh basically uh
aws lambda and uh azure functions of
virtual functions these are basically
one-time
things that could be spun up and down
basically when they're executed on
demand
uh and a lot of these functions have
permissions that are higher than the
normal user permissions
so we'll be we will be able to
potentially pivot
though from those functions of service
or these one called one-time use
functions
onto another system
okay so here's like i go into
um we're testing the uh software the
service i have here is the uh
salesforce os 360 dropbox
uh it basically exchange um the types of
access controls that we have to focus on
the tests
let's go to the next slide
so this this is what i said earlier in
other slides here
uh where i uh it's basically platform
services on the the containerization of
the application
so we're going to try to stay within our
own containers when we're doing um
these types of testing
so here's infrastructure the services
these are the ones we're attacking the
virtual machines
the storage devices uh storage services
and blocks
such as blob services uh what would be
when we're testing those things we'll be
test
we'll be testing basically how the
client or how to target configured
their uh the permissioning to or access
to
said storage storage services
um now um amazon web services
allows for testing of um
freely testing of the of their services
as long as they stick to the client that
you're testing so you stick to your own
platform
and your own implementation of it they
allow you to test it all you want
um the diff with azure
however if you want to test anything
related to microsoft services
you will you will have to send them a
notification email
uh but aws will allow you to test mostly
all of their services
they're mainly the main restriction for
all the types of cloud-based uh
testing is they do not want you to do
the knowledge service attacks
where you go where you affect other
customers and their own
infrastructure and they also do not want
you
to uh to do something where it was pick
up too much resources
and then eventually called another uh
outage
so their main concern is that when you
do testing on a cloud environment that
you're not messing up other people's
implementation of it
so here's the stuff that azure and i
said they allow you to do
this they do a lot of they do a lot of
test virtual machines and
also the security monitoring of it but
they they want you to um
get an independent notification and the
same thing
same thing applies for azure and aws
when you're doing a uh
a proof of concept attack they don't
want you to
uh to drop like a command shell or
anything
uh malicious on the box so they don't
want you to drop a ransomware or
anything on it
they want you to basically do proof of
concepts demonstrating that you can
that you can access the information
here i go into some information on types
of containers
that are packaged uh this is basically
going over run c
this uh this is what you see in um
it uh mainly um the linux environments
um doctor docker requires
this to run so if so when we when we um
when we do things with docker you'll
notice that they do have to
use run c with their um
with their containers to run excuse me
now now container d is another uh
container function uh
it's basically a gamer that a damien
that runs in real time
uh they use um they use a protocol
uh grpc that you see in the background
uh and that's how they communicate with
uh with the uh where they started with
their services
via under containers if you you'll
probably probably see
uh grpc calls when you're doing
wireshark um
uh inspect uh inspected of network
traffic using wireshark
um but for the purpose of um what
i'm saying here or this presentation
um this is basically letting you know
where the technologies are in containers
but
for this on this presentation we would
not be exploiting this aspect
so much
so what i mentioned earlier um
today is that i was when i started doing
the
cloud-based metroid testing i was
actually um surprised
about how very similar it is to web
application testing
um to the point that they were refused
there were a few uh slides
in the training itself that referred you
to go take the web application
training as well as the advanced web
application training um which i've done
already
so and the things that they did but the
things that they demonstrate
in a lot of these trainings are are
things
that what i when i try to do in the real
world
are not as prevalent anymore about two
years ago this was more prevalent you'll
be able to see open
uh mongol databases and open radish
databases but not so much anymore
but it's still it's still always good
practice to always check for it
even though they're even though um
there's bug bounty programs and there's
tons of internal teams uh there are
still
you still might get an instance of um
of a rogue basically the developer spun
up something that
maybe forgot to spun down and that could
lead
to a pivot into another uh instance in
there
but from what i've seen over the last
few years
when it comes to uh infiltration of
enterprises
um it was either done
it was mainly done via phishing and
social engineering attack i would say
about 90
of of 95 of the infiltration done at
enterprises nowadays
is done by a phishing attack or a social
engineering attack
um i have i have i have seen
other types of attacks where they
exploited the apis
of many of these services
i myself was able to exploit apis
of iam the identity access management
protocols which we'll go into in later
night slides
to get in for basically make your basic
api
calls via um over permission
tokens or sessions that are
being sent in the api but
uh when we were first starting out doing
these enterprise tests
very large cloud-based testings
you may not find things coming at you
first you may scan
a very large pool of ip addresses
and they will not be they will not ping
back back to you
because they um they've already been uh
patched up or not
so well so often so what we're going to
be going to mainly now is
a lot of these things will be is if you
already did uh
plus exploitation after social
engineering on some
on an employee or if we're able to gain
uh
information via an exposed apr
misconfigurated api or
or other web vulnerabilities
so the tools that we've been using for
um cloud-based testing
are basically these same tools that
we'll be using for um
web-based testing um burp is my favorite
tool i use it for
every test it's a very um
a robust tool burp is a proxy tool that
you'll put
in between the client and the server and
it it will intercept
the traffic from the uh your your client
which would be your laptop or
the browser you're using into the server
and postman is basically
a client used to make api calls
when developers develop apis
uh they often use postman scripts
or postman to test the api out without
without actually having to develop a
full front end for it
so postmas is basically a way to do
a front end for apis if you do not have
a an application for it
um i i like to still use burp
in lieu of postman um when doing these
call when doing these tests in my
experience when i was using postman
in the past uh postman
will oft will often time add their own
encoded
value or they will they will correct
an encoded value so if i were to put
a um a percent 27
which is the hack memory logo into um
into the postmatch grip instead of
setting the correct
20 it says instead of sending percent 27
it may actually just send the apostrophe
itself
whereas burp i can guarantee it that it
will not
alter that um that encode that url
encoding
when i when i send it i've only had that
happen a few times
in the past but that's the copy i've had
when i've used postman
now mass can and we'll be using
for um when we get an ip address range
that contains
thousands or even millions of ip
addresses
uh most oftentimes this will also be
internal ip addresses too that could
this was an enterprise environment you
know we would be testing a pretty
long wage of um vms and um
ip addresses there so we're going to use
mass scan because mascara will be able
to
to scan all of these in a in a timely
manner
the downside of using mass scan
is that you know you'll be so you'll be
sacrificing accuracy
for speed so what i
what i like to do is i would like to use
i would like to use mass scan
to go scan a large range of ip addresses
first and then get the results from mass
scan like any
host that it finds that was up and any
of the
any poor statistics up and then throw it
into nmap
because nmap will also have extra
scripts for it
such as well i'll go into it later on
but if i find like a mondo database i
can use nmap
to verify that the database is
actually there and i could access it
um as i mentioned earlier you know if
you're going to do
amazon web services or amazon
cloud-based testing
we'll be using the aws cli tool
and for azure um they have the azer
command line tool
and for recon we're going to use open
source tools for
especially at a scale one tool that i
really like to use
is crt.sh
which is a great way to enumerate
subdomains and i'll get into that
i believe into the next slide
but um since this io is like another
showdown
um it's based they they already scanned
internet and if you put in ip addresses
they already put they'll
display what ports that they that they
were able to take to open beforehand
uh robtex.com is um something i've used
to map out
large um uh asn's
or uh large network bomb air
areas uh they also provide other sub
domains or other
other hosts or host names or domains
that are relying relying on the same
host
now now i would i could talk about these
tools
and go into how to use these tools but
they're i'm pretty sure
that you guys can find the research into
using these tools yourself
there are a lot of um uh um
there's a lot of documentation on how to
use burp there's a lot of uh
things out there for all of these tools
so i don't feel it's necessary for me to
go into
how to use um typical calls and stuff
there's a lot of documentation out there
i'm sure if anybody have done any um
training or any uh any um
like information security you've
probably heard of some of the tools
you know one being at least nmap that's
been around since the matrix
so this is still a tool that's being
used today
so i mentioned crt.sh
now this is this is uh we're using the
certificate transparency
uh tool the certificate transparency
was a way to uh it was a way for that
browsers
and uh and
wait for browsers and clients to know
that the certificate the certificates
that are being presented on the websites
are actually their certificates
and not a spoof certificates or
malicious certificates
so there's these uh there are several uh
trans
certificate transparency records out
there that we can go look through
for certain domains one of them is a
crt.sh
facebook has one of them as well um
but we're going to use crt.sh because
it's free it's online you can use it
anytime
okay so here is here is an example okay
guy comment
goldbuster is good but yes um there are
there are yeah these
there are several tools that are
definitely a lot more faster now
uh one reason why i like i mentioned
goalbuster and dns
recon that py is because um
uh one of them was written in dot go
whether they're in
go language and everyone's in python
language uh so they're usually used
they're using universal on all operating
systems so
that's one reason why uh we like to like
when we use um
we like to go show out of scripts
written in python or go languages
so um here i gave an example of
how i used um i tried enumerate some
subdomains of
um testblood.com and i used the
crt the circuit transparency site and i
use the wildcard of the percent sign
there
in front of tesla.com now the reason why
i put
the wildcard.tesla.com is because if i
just say wildcard tesla.com
it will pollute the results with some
that could have something with
before the word tesla in it so if i put
wildcard.tesla.com to make sure that i
have
i get more subdomains out of it and here
you see
um we get more subdomains that we can
see there's a
powerhub that energy.tesla.com
uh gridlogic energy.tesla.com uh the
list went on pretty long but here i just
want to show you what this could look
like and how you can enumerate
other other subdomains by using this
certificate transparency tool
i forgot to i i didn't mention in the
last slide but you could also
uh pair up dns recon
uh the python script with the results
you get from
crt.sh to uh to get even more
uh subdomains and then you'll you then
what i would like to do is i will use
goalbuster
to get the um to get the director
basically the directories afterwards
see if we can enter any directories
after the domain
so other things you want to look for
when we're when we're exploring
enterprises or um
enterprises or their cloud-based stuff
is that we're gonna look at the github
repositories
um i've i myself seen in the past where
developers will put up
a project they're working on on the
external git
and then they'll have uh ssh keys in it
or
hard-coded credentials oftentimes their
own
credentials for their own work
environment such as uh
active directory credentials uh
so and they might even realize that they
even that they put these credentials in
later on and they'll go
on to go back into the into the get and
remove it
so i've seen in the past that even
though they removed the passwords
they did not they forget to go back to
old commits
and if you go back to the old commits
they are you may see some credentials
leaked in there
oh here's where i mentioned where i
could use the um dns recon
all right with the irs so um here's
here's i
heard i mentioned i uh going more into
the other services indeed
uh in more detail uh the census io
showdown
uh services um
you can i'm sure you guys have seen
these searches already so i won't go in
too much at them on them
okay so once once we scan things we
might see
here here are some databases that are
that are usually uh
sent from to like aws functions or cloud
functions and we'll notice that they are
we we will see port 27001
we'll also see the reds part 6379
and uh these were these were
often uh released out there
not intended to be externally facing on
the internet
so a lot of times these databases may
not have proper authentication
or authentication item at all so once we
find these we can use
nmap or other scripts to try to connect
to these um
databases
so now we're going to go into
trying to um we're going to talk about
amazon's um
aws uh implementation of the cloud
services
so amazon has a amazon aim which is used
for authentication
authorization it's the identity access
management
uh mechanism of it you know it handles
to permission policies
allows access via api to various parts
of the uh
of the net or the system or the or the
services
um they offer group permissions and they
offer
federated services one thing uh
we're going to go into here is how a um
aim i i am is both
role based has role based access
controls and
attribute based access controls
so here are some quarks with the access
controls and
um and uh um and uh this was good this
and aim excuse me
so one thing that aim supports is a
resource policy
meaning that i if you explicitly give
the
give the uh permissions to the users
say you explicitly in this example i
explicitly gave jimmy the uh
the permissions to list read write to
the sv bucket
but sarah she don't have permissions to
the s3 bucket
however the resource entry book can't
have permission can have permissions on
it themselves
so even though i i as the military could
explicitly have told sarah
that she did not have permissions to
this resource the resource could have
been
could have been somehow provisioned to
have
the um they have this on the um
they have sarah on a resource so what
what could happen
oftentimes is it say sarah herself
moved on for another uh department or
another uh division
and they took the resource off her name
but it's still the what the permission
offer name but the resource is still
allowing
for the permission for her to get into
it
so uh here's here are some other things
like service policies
lambda functions uh they have these
policies on their own things and our own
um
instances and we
so when we have these policies of
service we we may be able to
use one service as a pivot point to
interact with another service
function where the user does not really
have access to that uh function so if
say
say there's a function that makes a uh a
call to
billing uh it's like a one-time use
function
now a user may may have access
to um to that function
but doesn't necessarily have access to
billing so maybe a function could be
maybe that user can leverage this
function
to access something else so
uh this is this is one of the ways these
these are
these uh functions these permissions or
these functions
could be a way to pivot to another um
aspect of the cloud
so here is here is one we have for
attribute
based uh control so aws has a
tag system so in this in this example
um you have user jimmy he's tagged with
the team
he's tagged the group team and dolphins
where sarah is team is in seahawks now
the resource
is is his here is tagged that with um
going to a lot of seahawks team so
it's already going to uh deny my team
but uh allow sarah here
uh what the one good thing about
attribute attribute based um
policy the way you administrators use
them is that
if they want to remove a lot of policies
or add a lot of policies
to assert to a certain user or a certain
resource
they could just add a tag there and if
the tags are not
there or not the tags are there they'll
let them in
the tag is not there then it won't let
them in so
this way um say if the
in the last example where sarah went to
another department or something
if regardless if she went to another
department if the tag is not there then
that resource will not have that amen
another thing that aws has is um user
versioning so say
say sarah went to say sarah went to
another organization again and went to
another apartment
and now uh but her user still had what
was called a set
default policy on the user initially
uh so what could happen is sarah will be
sent to another apartment
and she they'll probably re-permission
her to go to
this to have this department um have
this apartment's uh permissions but not
the last apartments of permission
so what sarah can do if she wanted to go
back
and look at the last policy the last um
the black permissions she could she
could run the set default policy on
herself
through the awsc uh command and that
will revert her to the old policy where
she had the um
the other um the older original policy
and she could go back to old department
information
uh if you could find other users that
have this set default policy
on there we could potentially leverage
this to get
access to other areas that we didn't
have access beforehand
so this is something that uh i've
exploited
quite a lot in the past um and it's uh
something that a lot of people
who are developing on aws app or
applications or struct services don't
realize they have
aws has an instant metadata data service
it's basically like an api call where
you it'll provide
json information of the other running
services right now
uh so so basically like a serverless
function like a lambda function could
call
this davis metadata service function to
get
a new session for itself based on its
role or to see what's running on itself
uh it's it's usu is only accessible to
the ip addresses within the amazon
instance
and it usually always starts with
169.254.169.254.
um so what we what we
are going to do is we're going to
leverage other vulnerabilities to get
access to this metadata service because
this metadata service
is what we're going to is is what we can
use to get
uh live credentials onto uh
onto a um onto a certain resource
so this is the typical structure one of
the typical structures of this metadata
service
it is not documented by aws because they
don't want the bad guys to really get
this
but it's it's basically what i call an
open secret nowadays
uh if you were if you were to go onto
the aws
or an amazon cloud uh into this into the
network
you're able to you you're able to call
this uh url
it will basically it will basically give
you
the live token right now they could use
onto
onto the service um we will see the
username
you'll see the password and the and the
uh session with
it with the service well
what we're going to what what we want to
do is once we get these informations
we could actually use the amazon command
line interface or the tool itself
to create our own profiler or our own
user
to they'll access the service on its own
and the reason why we do that
is when we create our own user and our
own profile
that looks to have legitimate access
it's gonna be real it's gonna be a
little bit harder
for the blue team to actually see that
you know this was this was access
because now it looks like a legitimate
user's action this a permission user at
that is accessing
the um amazon instance
so this was the um this is back on the
serverless function
uh where i mentioned this earlier these
are basically uh they run once in their
call
and once needed uh these are basically
service calls
and i said we'll be able to use these
functions to pivot
to another point
uh i want to get this slide to show you
the difference to show you different
terminology between
aws and azure and i'm and you know and
i'm using these two because these are
the
two prominent ones i've seen um there is
also uh
google cloud computing as well and
alibaba's coming up with one of them
but i haven't had much experience with
them but these are terms that
that we've all seen quite a lot but we
could probably see a lot
while doing um these testing or probably
like even sign it into our own
enterprises
so you know we the ec2 for aws will
become azure virtual machine
the virtual public cloud becomes virtual
network and so on so on
so uh as you can see uh aws has
aim where azure has active directory
uh services or azure directory services
which is different than
the standard active directory services
they see on an on-premise
site
okay so as i mentioned earlier one of
the main entry points to uh cloud
to the cloud infrastructure or any
enterprises are
our web applications and even
web applications that access vpn such as
cisco
ssl vpns have web interfaces to access
the internal network via a web
application
uh you know there are so we're going to
use these types of um
applications to leverage the leverage
vulnerabilities to get further into the
cloud
i will i will show an example of how i
use uh
server side request forgery to actually
get
that metadata metadata service potential
so uh last year during the engagement uh
we were scanning an internal cloud and i
noticed that
we were kind of ip address range and we
noticed that uh
there was an instance of this graph on a
cloud
uh deployment we saw something like
prometheus
and other types of um
metrics this was like a metrics
reporting platform uh i didn't
i really don't know exactly what it what
it does i did from what i saw it looked
like it was like an
observation platform or it was
definitely some kind of reporting
platforms that system admins or
internal people use to basically gauge
the usage of the cloud
but we were we noticed that
uh there was a function there that that
uh
called another url so
what
mainly as open redirects i
i can now use it as basically
a service side request forgery so and so
it's in in this instance
instead of um re redirecting to an
arbitrary
um an arbitrary site i decided to
redirect it
onto something internal
so what i did was i decided to i noticed
that
i went to the vulnerability that was um
that was um
that was described here cve 2020
uh 1379. uh it described the server side
request forgery instance that
i'm going to uh describe to you right
now show you how it works
so what it did was it took
it took the the avatar parameter
anything after this avatar uh
session you could put anything in there
and
you could have it redirect to one site
and then
if you change that redirection to
another site
you can have it then go to the uh
the meta service the metadata service
which is uh what i've done over here i
was
i attached to the metadata service um ip
address onto
the redirect here and this was the
result
here we were able to get the access key
id
which is basically the user of the um of
the
other other application um
the secret access key which is like the
password and the live token
uh these tokens are used usually
by default are good for six hours
so if this token is not refreshed or
anything after six hours you could
always come back here
to leverage getting these credentials
again
these sessions and then um
creating a profile with it and
installing yourself onto
onto that um onto that um
service
so uh this was something i've seen uh in
a while
several times at something that is a
cork with aws
so one thing that's also that's uh often
overlooked while on deploying on
these these applications or services is
that they rely on api communications
and oftentimes these apis could be
overly permissive
to get information from other places so
they may want one api to call
billing to go call as well the same api
to go call
say provisioning or maybe
called you know some other department
so if you rely on certain apis that
could that could have
access to these sort of depart these
departments then you could you could
potentially use the same
session from the um api to go
access another a session it will access
another
resource so
one thing i found is if i were able to
get a token from uh
one api that called say billing i was
able to use that same token
via a user that didn't really have
access to provisioning to then provision
another user onto a system
so that is one example of how we could
uh have apis are exploded
what i've noticed in the wild often a
lot is that
apis are often overlooked
in this fashion i have often been i was
i was often able to
to um basically do you get information
um from these apis because the api
session itself
is uh is always valid and oftentimes
when you're using a web application that
has an api they they want to tie
a web application session to the client
or a gui
that calls the api and the api has its
own session
so while you're using whether you're
using the client or the
application you you yourself may think
that there's a roadblock
here like it may gray out all the
buttons for you
uh or might prevent a roadblock and
stuff but the api
has its own permissions on token so you
can still call you can still make a call
using an api token to to a service and
get the
results back in like a json response
instead of
uh instead of going through the gu going
through a web application gui
um and this is something that
uh is still being uh i still have to be
checked in across a lot of organizations
because um i've been able to gain a lot
of information from
platform like from lots of information a
lot of information
uh via api leakage and
improper access controls on apis and
a lot of functions in the cloud rely on
these apis where there's no gui
a server to server or aptitude app or a
functional function
and these apis are often
overly permissive
so that's the conclusion i have for this
right here um
i will i want to open up for more
questions and answers
um i didn't want to go get too technical
into the uh
into this and given too many technical
details because i could figure that
might
be too boring or too excessive but i
will
um i'm open to any questions or
or statements you have regarding
enterprise testing
or cloud-based testing
what do you think is next oh sorry yeah
go ahead
go ahead sorry i got ahead of myself
this is just like an interesting topic
to me
so what do you think is next uh for um
enterprise penetration testing in cloud
well i see i see a lot of organization
going
uh towards azure a lot more in aws
what's going on next is you know as
we're getting more
and more uh resources into it we're
going to see
we're going to see a lot of um
configuration spun
up and we're gonna see a lot of these
similar things i just demonstrated here
with the metadata service um
exposed so i expect um maybe later down
online
uh they're gonna close they're gonna
have more defaults and more secure
uh but i do see a lot more uh
people probably going to a google cloud
um
platform as well alibaba might make a
stake in uh chinese
environments uh chinese companies
uh they're already starting to have
their own cloud services there and they
look a lot
i believe a lot like uh google cloud
computing services
uh but i i do see more organizations
going from going towards more of a
hybrid model
or where to have on-prem stuff and uh
cloud stuff
to even more flat out of a cloud-based
model
and i do see you're going to see us a
lot more in the future
as a follow-up um do you see
um organizations kind of outsourcing
this kind of penetration testing as i've
been seeing has been trending where like
you might have like a pm
that you know manages a few people that
are in a team but aren't on on
even on this in the same country um does
that
is that something you see happening um
so i so
i i've seen it happen this this is how
i've seen it in my
in my field um where i work at where i
work uh they have me
uh do uh pen testing on enterprise and
under look enterprise or internal
systems a lot
um they have me uh see if i could do
ransomware or stuff like that
or anything against the cloud they also
hire third party
um vendors to go do
uh assessments as well uh
vendors such as ibm mandy and uh
they i've seen them um
i've actually over i've actually
overlooked them doing the testing as
well
uh and i i see them come across all
they use testers from all across the
world sometimes um
of my team i have i have testers in
other countries i have a tester in
canada
um as well um i don't really think
that really makes any of any difference
um the actual work that's being put into
or what resources don't come out of it
but i do see uh more requests
being done for these types of testing
especially
on their implementation of certain
instances so
i have seen uh calls a lot of people
making
requests for office 360 testing or
or their own uh their own sharepoint
text
testing or their an implementation
of things i've seen that a lot and i i
see i say i um it's a pretty big selling
point
for a lot of uh these third-party
testers too uh
when i when i talk to them and have a
conversation with them
uh they they uh they have to have
multiple uh
uh testers or people on it and i've even
seen these engagements go up
to be up to about three months long so
some of the engagements
if a full red team assessment that
includes social engineering and stuff
so i definitely see um
this being uh sent to internal teams a
lot
for certain things and and being
outsourced to third parties
as well just for some expertise in it
thank you
i guess i can keep asking questions okay
so what are some of the juiciest bugs
you've seen
um besides some of the i guess the more
common ones that you just showed us
um that you've been able to discover
so um let's see
[Music]
so i was able to exploit um uh
identify identity access management
of uh of a customer
from from enterprise uh basically uh
i was able to pivot from a customer's
like uh
ap access token to get into
um essentially
a uh a customer care representative
terminal from the make from the outside
from base
basically from the um from the external
facing website uh i'll give the example
of a
a tesla.com it wasn't tesla.com let's
get a good example
uh from the central tracy's website
tesla.com
i was able to uh use the api information
the api
calls from the iam to go pull records
from the uh because from basically the
building department
as my own user uh basically via the
uh exploiting the improper controls over
a iam um
i was able uh i thought that was quite
interesting because at that point i was
able to get
a full info just by um
enumerating customer ids
uh and i thought that was quite
interesting to do and what was also
interesting was that when i was able to
do that
uh it didn't look like it was a
like a bad request it looked like a
legitimate request
so i was able to work with the
development team or the um
that development team i was actually
able to work with the stock right then
and there to have it fixed right away
because i was able to actually get
credit card numbers and
a lot of pii information that we
shouldn't have gotten and we closed that
bug down
within about 30 minutes so i was able to
get that
uh pretty quickly it was quite quite
scary too
for your aws trick i thought 80 of aws
version that api so you could get a new
version where
the first time their damon started on
the virtual machine it pulled a one-time
token
and if that damon ever died you could
never access that internal api
again
what was that like is that is that is
that something you've seen
i thought it was something they did
already but i'd have to find a url or
something referencing it
because i'm tired of people going after
that
yeah so they they have tried they have
tried to do that in version two
and version two but uh
uh so the way what what happened is they
uh
they tried they they didn't invert it
through they tried to uh what they did
that we said
but um i was still able to see this in
the wild
and i still use the same old methods um
i was i was um
still gonna do it every i was all i did
was i created a profile
and i made it i kept on calling that
call and it still gave me a new token
i haven't actually seen it implemented
but it would stop me from that in a
while yeah
here's a another question that if you if
you have any resources
for exploiting aws api vulnerabilities
or any white papers you can recommend
um so
there's a resource i got for this
orientation i got from the uh
i already got from sans uh their cloud
computing training
um other resources um
i don't really know the top of my head
right now um
which chance one the one that moses
teaches yeah the one of moses uh
teachers yeah
oh that's awesome yeah guys moses is
sometimes and the discord or slack so
you can actually reach out to him
directly that's awesome
what's the the the number of the course
it's a 588
588 awesome right so um
uh i i so like i i gave so what the
distribution i gave basically um
a portion of that that training i
condensed it a lot i didn't want to
completely like
rip this stuff off as well but i i also
put in
my experiences with actual testing of
enterprises
and uh cloud-based systems and in my
experience
um i was actually surprised because like
when i was testing cloud-based system
before i took the
before i took this training and when i
saw
uh that metadata service thing uh in a
while like that
um and i saw it it was basically a
textbook example in the training itself
uh so i i thought that was kind of funny
to see that
so uh but i i was i was able to
the stuff i've got from really api
testing and everything i was i got
all the um my training just by hands-on
testing
it's pretty good any ctfs that you know
of there was a question
before um
no cts that i already know of i haven't
i haven't really
uh followed ct i followed ctf my last
two years
like my cts have been you know they give
they've given me a real life one so i
haven't really
i
here's another question yes yes
clients actually follow the rules a lot
of these will go away
i mean if the developers follow the
rules a lot of these will go away too
uh but you know but things that wouldn't
go away
are inherent or inherent things such as
um for instance if uh if if
they still had uh resource policies
where they their policy allowed of the
person
explicitly go into it that could still
allow things
and if someone actually knows the
command line tool of
aws they could even though everything is
set up properly and you did everything
right you could still
get a compromise say if i was able to
steal somebody's password
or um or a system
and as i said like um 90
of the infiltration that i've seen in a
while
has been straight up fishing and social
engineering
one of the most recent phishing
campaigns that i see was successful
was they used a toastmasters template
to get to get some toastmasters people
to go click something
so you know it could even be you know
groups that you're part of that
they could go fish a template out other
uh social engineering aspects that i've
seen in a while are
um you know linkedin
linkedin on recruiters trying to send
you a document
to go safe to go she they go show them
oh here's a new offer
you know you have some nice pretty lady
on linkedin showing you some offers or
something
you click it potentially on your work
computer and now that that could be
a source of infection right there
james in your experience um you know i'm
working with some of those other
companies that have
also done testing alongside you and your
company
what um what what did you find
uh if you had any knowledge to what they
found versus what you found and what was
you know who found more and tell us
about that
so so in my experience um
i've been i've mainly been on par with
the um
third-party testing uh or i've i've
often
a lot of times i've found a little bit
more than they have they have found
uh one reasoning behind that and that uh
a lot that my managers and
people have told me is that because i'm
internal i have more
i have more at stake to do a better job
and finding stuff than say a third party
because you know
third party probably won't care as much
as as much as somebody
internal to it so however
um you know i have seen some novel
things that there
some third party has done so i have seen
uh
ibm for instance they were able to write
a uh their own tool to extract
uh symantec vip tokens once they were
able to uh
access a client uh in real time
and then they're able to access or
access the vip tokens from memory as
well
uh i thought that was a pretty novel
thing that they actually wrote a whole
tool to exploit that uh
that vip uh access the samantha vip
token
um but uh i would say uh
you know i was i i was actually quite
surprised sometimes
a little bit disappointed that i really
so a few times
i um i've i've hired
some third-party testers or third-party
vendors
to do some assessment hoping to find
something novel
that they've done and i haven't really
seen much um
anything more novel than what i just
showed you right here
um and even even even when i do it i i
still pull out a lot of things so
i mean i was quite surprised a lot of
things that i think should be easily
fixed
that you know by basic security are
still out there and easily
exploited
also i i've also had experiences where
um a third-party vendor
did not do their job when i first came
to
an organization they were hiring a
third-party vendor
where all they really did was ran a scan
and printed out the result
didn't even go over to scan for false
politics or anything
and they charged the organization 100
grand for that
um and i thought that was appalling and
i came in there i was
i did i did the same test i found so
many things wrong that they had to fix
right away
so it's also has to come on the
awareness of the organization
as well to make sure that they're not
being um hoodwinked by some
by some of these third-party vendors and
i believe that
after after i got in there and after
they got it they got a
a more developed internal team we were
able to look at better third-party
vendors and see better reports out of
them
any other questions i do have another
one
you know it's my impression that um or
what have you found have you looked in
the areas of orphaned
instances and what did you find
um basically i mean like um vms that
were no longer
being like looked after or that are no
longer
like for instance like they're no longer
a private group anymore
is that like what you're referring to
yeah
it's my impression that um you know a
lot of people probably aren't really
keeping track of their um
you know instances very well because
they've got you know so much
and a source of vulnerability
that needs to be highlighted as well and
i was just curious
to how much you saw or even
did you have an awareness to look for it
so
so in my own per in my personal
uh experience i experienced being an
orphaned um
person out of the azure directory at one
point where
they had me outside of all direct that
they had me at my own department at one
point which was
interesting but now when it comes to
uh orphaned or or orphan uh
resources that really depends
on the asset management of the
organization
i've been to some organizations where
they had um
a full overview of their assets now they
knew
exactly what what each host was uh what
was spun up or not
um i had organizations that had a
somewhat
of a decent view and i had organized
i've seen organizations where they had
no idea
what was going on in their own internal
network um
so in those organizations you know
there's going to be a lot of
orphan things i've seen i've seen many
times
you know applications or cert or
services that are completely demo
applications
that you know the developers spun up see
to see if
to see if something worked and forgot to
spin it down
and um these things are often are riped
with
uh are full of vulnerabilities uh one
thing i've seen was i've seen like a
uh some like an internal ec2 instance
that had
like an application that the i think
developer is working on for college or
something it was completely unrelated to
the organization it was like a book
selling invoice app maybe it was
something
to trade himself on something but this
application
was was called was a php application
uh that was calling a system function
that i was able to go
uh go we basically exploit this this
application that nobody knew about
to go to go pivot to another box or
pivot on this same box
um higher privileges because some
developer wrote something up the test
and this left it there
so you know it really really depends on
the organization's asset management
and their um and their monitoring of
what's being upper down there um
orphan instances or orphan things could
definitely be out there
and if they're not using any resource or
any
utilization they may go unnoticed for a
very long time
any other question
all right i'm gonna hit stop recording