this conference will now be recorded
all right welcome again uh my name is
rodzotto and today
i'm here with uh jonathan rospeto and uh
we're gonna have our very own michael
brown
he is an expert in
policy if you want to know anything
about any type of policy even if they
have it in a draft
michael is your guy like michael you
should call this guy
if you have audits all kinds of
questions about policies
michael could probably teach an entire
year classes about policies
this dude is amazing he always helped us
he's been in all our conferences
he's still with us and for that i'm
thankful michael uh and today
he's going to talk about something that
i get for example approach
many times people comes to me saying
son of two can you help me with this uh
there is a lot of confusion of this and
this is why this is a great presentation
because for some for some reason people
confuse this software security
operations
um and uh you know sometimes i have
placed things like
oh no i know suck and then people will
comment
and and tell me things like how you know
suck you're not an accountant for
example that was something that
uh i was told i i knew that you needed
some sort of a
a cpa knowledge today we're going to
find out about it
because what happens is many times
people think that this is something that
you can do with
i guess many security professionals the
answer is no
uh you had to do this with very specific
companies have very
specific skill people and i am
personally looking forward to seeing
this presentation today
because uh i i
admit it i don't know much about uh sub
2 stuff so
i'm going to make your presenter michael
uh thank you very much and uh
take it away okay
let me see yeah and questions please for
the end
okay
are you guys able to see my screen
yes okay
so as i have to do you know this
presentation on on soc 2 reports
i will not claim to be an expert on them
i have i've had a lot of experience with
them and exposure to them
and so because of that i felt that i was
could do a good job at this so okay
okay this is a background on myself i've
been actually in nit for
over 20 years but half at an infosec i
actually started out more the sysadmin
and
over the years i found myself kind of
pulled into
what i would say more more compliance
type work
you know you know assessments and
governance risks and
compliance and so forth last seven years
i worked as a consultant helping a lot
of organizations with
um being assessed for hipaa compliance
helping organization with soc2
with preparing to be certified for iso
uh being certified for um
high trust and and things like that uh
also doing some pci work
i now i've moved on i'm now a security
compliance manager with a company i'm
helping them hopefully helping them to
get get a sock too which i've actually
done with some of my clients
active with various organizations here
in the area uh some of the local
chapters of several national
organizations
so i'm going to get some background some
terminology that way when you hear some
of these things
regarding sock 2 you know at least
you'll be a little bit more familiar
talk a little bit about what's in a sock
2 report
talk a little bit about you know why you
would use sock 2
in that's about a tool for vendor
management
and then probably more important for
hopefully some of you guys there
is what if you are faced with your
company needing to get
themselves a sock too and some of the
things that i've done in helping
you know my clients you know get ready
for that
and then i always try to give resources
with all my presentations
to kind of you know point you guys you
know everyone in the right direction for
further information
uh beyond what i'm able to cover here
so i thought also i'd touch on my on my
sock to background so i've actually
helped several clients
with uh stock2 assessments um
most most particularly i was where i
worked with two clients where i was
there referred to as a virtual cso or
fractional cso
uh to help them get sock two type two
reports
one was a kind of a strange retail
conglomerate company
uh i came on board worked with them for
some over a couple years
developed and implemented policies and
and controls
uh making sure the evidence was being
gathered to show this
um i also want to you know as part of
that you know helping them with you know
security awareness training for their
employees uh helping out with the
incident response testing and dr testing
um
making sure that they did pin tests by
other people i
put together what's called a system
description which is important part
report i'll
touch a little bit more on what the heck
that is and then when the
sock 2 assessment came in i was kind of
like the center point for that
in terms of lining up who the
assessors need to talk to working
directly with the assessors answering
their questions
uh kind of like in the middle of all of
that um
which was was quite a bit of work um
and of course we were successful in
getting a a good uh
soc 2 type 2 report at the end of that
uh the other company i worked with with
us which is much smaller company
uh dealing with what you would call
incentive programs
um if you're not aware this is where
like you know various companies will say
like
hey you know if you do these things and
you like i see a lot with some of the
health care companies
health insurance companies they'll say
like hey if you do these sort of things
we'll give you a gift card
so this is something that this company
would do um so i came in
uh looked at their policies and controls
this company was different they actually
had
a decent set of policies they had pretty
good controls already in place
i kind of looked over them saw some gaps
we
filled those gaps we first had you know
they first went through and did a sock
two type
one engagement that was successful and
then
for 12-month period we made sure that
hey we had evidence of the controls in
place
they came back for the sock two type two
it was a
pretty you know easy engagement because
they were you know had things pretty
well on hand and
got their sock to type 2 successfully
both these things were done actually
last last year
so one thing i you know at first part of
this i'm touching on various different
things i was trying to do this kind of a
logical matter but sometimes
some of the stuff it was hard for me to
like how would i put this in a logical
manner
so one thing i need to make clear about
is there's a difference between
you know i'm not sure what we should
call it assessing there's also you call
it
certifying and whatnot versus assisting
and this is the thing when you have
different organizations that come in and
certify a company or assess a company
you know to give them like a
certification for
iso 27001 or you know the c
the cpa firm that comes in and does the
sock 2 report
um if you're familiar with the new
department offenses cmmc
scheme uh getting certified in that
getting started
in high trust those entities those
companies that come in and do that
they cannot help that
company they're assessing get ready you
know they can't come along and
say like oh you know your policies
aren't well you know here's some
policies that you can use and this sort
of stuff
they have to kind of separate that out
um
even cmmc is very clear on that they
have
two different kind of of uh people they
have one that can come in and do the
prep work and they even have a training
scene for those people
and they have a training scheme and
certifying scheme for people who want to
come to and
certify and you can be both but you
can't do both
with the same company you know so if
your organization to a
if a company comes in and helps a
company prepare they cannot be the ones
doing the assessment or certification
so in some cases you'll have companies
that kind of just focus
just on the certifying assessment type
stuff
and they will leave the
prep work assistant type stuff to other
companies so sometimes they'll team up
with another company so the company i
was with we were more the
helping out versus the assessing and it
was actually kind of funny in that
all of our clients that were doing
getting assessed for saktu
all wound up working with the same you
know audit you know
audit firm um accounting firm you know
so we were like
doing all this assistance and it was all
the same authentic firms so in some
cases
we were kind of working you know kind of
with the same
same people but we did it we did realize
we had that separation
uh between us uh so that's what kind of
rod
talked you know mentioned was that with
this with a sock 2 report it
can only come from an accounting firm
you know and i've never worked with
accounting firm so i could never have
been
someone who's actually assessing a
company to get a sock to
but i can go and help them get ready
which is what i was doing
so what is a sock 2 report i said it's
actually one of several reports i'm
going to
talk about what those different ones are
done by accounting firms
you know and these are important because
the the sock do report is they can is a
report on the controls of a company
which they then use to provide to either
potential clients or
current clients to say like hey you know
we're partnering services to you
here's this report on those services so
that you can
trust that they are working and you can
rely upon us and so forth
so it's a way for you know clients
potential clients to say like yeah we
want to
do business with this company because
they can provide us with this
third party assessment of their services
and we can look at it and like
know that oh yeah everything is working
good and so forth and we can trust them
and we don't have to spend all our time
assessing that company we get this
this good report um and and honestly
this has become
more and more uh important
um and i said a lot of companies were
coming to us
for help you know because they need to
get assessed because
their clients are coming to them and
saying like well we're only going to do
business with
you if you get a a sock 2 report
or some of the other reports that are
out there like i said high trust
in healthcare iso 27001
and honestly i don't see that going away
i see it actually increasing
so again when you what what a sock sock
you know we we oftentimes hear sock we
think of security operation center
that's not what we're talking about uh
for if you're more of a techie person
you might have heard the term a system
on a chip you know like the special you
know the
chips in your uh smartphones and whatnot
that's not what we're talking about
uh the term sock used to mean service
organization controls
and now it's been renamed as system and
so and sometimes when people say soccer
i had to think are you talking about a
security operation center are you
talking about a sock report
so that's sort of the things
so what do we mean by a service
organization and this is actually a
quote from
the documents it's an organization
reporting services to what they call a
user entity that's basically a a another
client or company
you know for which these servers are
likely to be relevant
to those companies because it has an
impact on you know finances and so forth
in terms of a sock too this would be
things like they're providing
financial services as billing and
processing and payload like
you know we're a small company and you
know instead of us hiring an accountant
to do this sort of stuff
oh we'll just use this application from
adp
or someone else okay great if we're
replying it relying upon that
uh let's get a report you know that's
gonna be doing good
um and more the tecla know stuff we'll
see you know people who are doing
sas services cloud computing
virtualization
you know i'm i'm instead of me building
a data center i'm going to go and house
my servers
in you know rackspace or paramark or
whatever
i want to know that those systems will
be protected and so forth
you know i'm relying upon another third
party for web hosting cloud computing so
if i'm whether i'm using
aws or azure or google cloud or what
have you i want to know that's that's
going to be taken care of and if you go
to these different companies
they will actually have on their website
yes we have
all these different reports and
certifications and so forth you go to
you know aws they have a good aws i have
like a compliance page where you can see
a list of all the different
certifications and
attestations and whatnot you know
they've got you know a sock one two and
three report
and they're iso 27001 certified and
they're
high trust their pci and yada yada these
companies get these things because
they know it's a good selling point you
know that way they have it
you know you can then you know use a
potential client
can trust that things are good because
they've got they've spent the time and
money to get these reports
and you can go and check them out
so i mentioned that with you know there
is more than one
sock report and so aicpa that's american
institute of
certified public accountants they're the
ones that had this and they called they
now called their
suite of services and at this point
there's actually five different reports
there's sock one
two and three uh sock one is
about financial reporting so i don't
have
much experience with that because i
really don't really get into you know
the financial side of things
uh sock two is what we're talking about
here and that's one i have experience
with
this what's good what they get in what
they call trust services controls
which is security availability process
integrity
confidentiality or privacy
you know and stock one and 2 have what's
called a type 1 report and a type 2 port
i'll talk about that a little bit more
shortly there's also a sock 3
which is basically sock 1 and 2 have a
lot of very sensitive information
so because of that you can't get a sock
one or two report
unless you sign an nda
so if you go to a company that has these
they will say on the website they have
them
but they're not going to put them there
you know if you want them you'll have to
contact them directly
and maybe agree to or sign off on an nda
um where the sock 3 is more general use
so they could actually put that on a
website
i know for myself i actually got aws
sock2 report
because i used to have a free aws
account you know so i had kind of like
you know kind of signed off on things
and i can actually go and access it and
you know i had to then kind of like you
know sign off i got on the nda
and get their sock 2 report um but one
and two
are under under ndas so that's why
they're kind of restricted
uh there's also socktube or cyber
security that's kind of a new one
and i've never seen one of these yet not
have anyone asked for them
um though i am familiar with it i've
looked at it i've gotten the book on it
actually did a present
presentation on it um but don't know
people doing it
and the newest one is this new one for
vendor supply chain
which gets into you know
production manufacturing distribution so
these are for
you know sock 2 is good for a company
kind of providing
services that get into these you know
security and whatnot whereas the vendor
management this is more for a company
that's doing
you know you're building something
you're producing something
in the supply chain and you want to be
able to show that hey you got controls
about that
um i don't know much more about that
that's when fairly recent
i know that up until very recently it
was always coming soon
so i mentioned the type 1 and type 2 and
one thing i should mention i've seen a
lot of time people will
will write these as roman numerals so
some of they'll see type 2
it was as a type roman numeral 2 which
is really not correct but
i see that a lot a type one is basically
reported
as a point in time they come in take a
look at the controls
give your report but there's no
guarantee that those report those
controls have been
in place for a period of time so you
know so it's like well maybe they
they put them in place two days ago
you don't know because it was there's no
you know a period of time
type 2 is more valuable it's over a
period of time
so not only they look at the control but
they look at evidence going
back you know a previous period of time
now i always was told it was
9 to 12 months some of the things i'm
hearing is that it could be as short as
as three months which honestly i don't
feel
there's much value because what most
companies want is they want a type 2
report
that's from the past 12 months yeah so
like three months is like
that's not too good unless you're then
gonna
you know do another report very quickly
for a 12-month period
and every time you do a have someone
come in and do a sock 2 report
that's time and money so
most times it's it's 12 months and
usually once a company starts getting a
type 2 report
it's going to become an annual thing you
know you did it
last year you know in august you know
hey they're going to come by again
in preparation for giving you a new
report for august of this year
and you know and so forth so it becomes
a cycle of it
and that's also important because like
if someone gives you a tight you know
sock two report
you know and it's like older than 12
months old you're like
uh where's the newest one are you in the
process
you know let me get a can we get what's
called a bridge letter because
you know that's kind of the expectation
and i'll talk a little bit more about
you know what we mean what they're
looking for in terms of evidence and so
forth
so as i said these are the five trust
you know
criteria security availability
processing integrity confidentiality and
privacy
now one thing anything about these five
is you don't have to do
all five um my understanding was always
that kind of like the default
three was you want to do security
availability confidentiality
if you need to typically because your
clients are demanding it
you might do process integrity maybe
privacy
uh one of my clients unfortunately they
were like basically told you know we
went all five
you know and the assessor was even
saying you know
because they're they're being pretty
decent about they're like you know you
know
what criteria do you need because you
know if we can
keep it to a minimum we can keep your
costs low you know which is decent than
to be
to have that you know you know attitude
and they were forced to do all through
five uh security as i understand you you
must do security there's no way out of
it
all the other four is optional
um but my my thinking has always been
security availability confidentiality on
the basic ones
processing integrity may not really
apply for some companies
privacy same thing so if you don't need
to don't do it
in addition when you look at the list of
the controller there's actually
additional additional controls
in the four that again are optional
you know that's something that people
sometimes don't realize when they get
the list of the
trust like you know the the controls as
i look at it there's like
over a hundred like oh god we gotta do
all of these i'm like no no no no you
don't um you know you can actually you
know
the assessors will work with you and say
okay these are what's important what are
appropriate
these aren't these don't really apply to
you you know and and so forth and so you
wind up doing like a
more of a subset of them um i think most
of us
know what we mean by security
availability means hey this is available
confidentiality you're protecting
confidential data privacy
you know it's optional because not
everyone will collect
you know personal information from
people uh and processing integrity if
you're not really
processing information if you just kind
of like you know
taking and using it not making changes
to it then
it's not really applicable
um so what are these reports based upon
and i meant brought this because i hear
these terms as well
they're basing upon a series of
accounting standards um
so when i first started getting exposed
to this i always heard sas70
um and that was you know statement on
auditing standards so
it was sas 70 was a standard for a sock
2 report for many many years
i know when i started forgetting that i
heard that all the time 770
you know that was replaced by ssae
16 you know to see statement on
standards of attestation examinations
really really fun uh term which
um went in effect in like 2010 2011
however it's been replaced as you see by
ssae 18 as of
2017 which is you know
almost four years ago yet i find it
funny is i still see people
making reference to ssae 16 and it's
like
come on that was for freaking years ago
get up with the times
you know sort of like someone still
talking about windows 95 when it's like
we're on windows 10 now i think you need
to get up to date
and if you're really a gun for
punishment you can actually get these
documents
and read them there are they are really
boring
so uh you have been
um i've been i've touched i've mentioned
control several times i just want to
make sure people understand what the
heck i mean by
controls because unfortunately sometimes
people don't
um you know basically there are
activities performed by a person or a
system
designed to ensure that certain
objectives are being met yeah get it
yeah yeah get it get it get it get it
get it hello hello
someone needs to go on mute um so these
kind this term comes from the idea of
internal controls for for businesses
um and but of course we we in infosec
are really
not under fall under i.t so we really
talk about i.t
controls for ourselves and there's
actually a term called i t
general controls itgc and it application
controls
you can actually um if you want to know
more about this there's actually a
decent
wikipedia article on it and itgc
include topics such as change management
you know source code version control you
know stuff uh
software development life cycle incident
management
disaster recovery backups and things
like that things that
you know we as it infosec people do deal
with that's actually
part of it general controls um
and what some people don't understand
because i actually had a
kind of annoying conversation with with
someone once where they asked me
they actually kind of challenged me out
do i did i understand what controls were
i said
sure i do i worked with these policies
and procedures and you know i
you know i got a really negative
response from this person because this
guy this person did not understand that
yes
policing proceeded are in fact controls
this person thought that
they're only only technical controls or
controls and that's just not true
um you know they start off as policies
and procedures
you hopefully they are then implemented
in technology
so for instance if you have you know
password settings you first have a
password
policy that sets down that hey
you know our password must be
minimum-based characters you know
make sure upper and lower case you know
you need to change it every
you know 90 days all that sort of jive
you define that in a
password policy that is a control
that's an it's what an administrative
control and then hopefully you because
you have that now administrative control
you then take that and you implement it
into technology
into your password system that way when
you go to
you know create a new password that you
pick something that's in line with
policy because the technology is
enforcing it you know
but yes policies are controls ideally we
want technical controllers to put in
place but
that's how it works um
again that's what i'm talking about here
about password policy
um we also talked about you know you
know for for
it to control framers there's actually
two main ones there's
cobit from isakka and the other one is
from koso they're internal control
framework and this is what sock 2 is
based upon
there are other control frames for
information security we talk about
control frameworks
is things such as 27002 and
uh nist sp 853
and the cis control which used to be
called the critical security controls
and the stuff within the nest cyberspeed
framework
those are all security controls these
are things that
hopefully everyone has some working
familia familiarity with
i wanted to touch a little bit on coso
only because again if you're getting a
sock to
you you'll hear it you'll hear it on
occasion in fact one of my um
when i was working with one of my
clients the uh the assessor kept saying
you know you know coso standards and he
kept mentioning koso and the guy you
know the cio who i was working with
you know returning he's like what the
heck is he talking about with koso
he had no idea what it was because he
was a technical person and i had to like
say
that's just where the controls come from
so coso
is it stands for committee of the
sponsoring organizations of the treadway
commission
it was actually when they had um uh
the enron uh scandal with accounting and
whatnot this
a group of five um organizations that i
listed here things like aicpa and other
as you can see kind of accounting and
professional organizations and i.t
audit and whatnot came together you know
as a committee
and they uh set down some standards on
internet control risk management and so
forth
to hopefully prevent in the future you
know accounting fraud and so forth
um you know you might see these two
things floating around
referred to as the coso cube of how they
kind of put these things into there they
have what they have with
all an enterprise risk management
framework and internal controls
framework
that was you know put out i have not
seen these documents
um i've kind of thought about getting it
just for the heck of getting it and
looking at it but
you know all the sort of stuff even with
the sock two stuff is like
really really really dry reading and um
kind of boring but that's where it comes
from and that's about as much as i'm
going to talk about when it comes to
koso
you can go to the website and you can
bore yourself to death if you want to go
and
take a look at it but having said that
as i said the you know the trust
security criteria
of sock 2 is based upon these what they
call kosovo principles
there's 17 of them organized into these
different groups
and this is kind of like the high level
grouping of the controls
and some of the stuff at the top you
know like control environment
and communication information and risk
assessment these are more of the
upper management type stuff where in
some cases i don't even necessarily have
a good visibility because
you know i'm more you know the infosec
i.t level
you know and i'm not i don't know what
the heck's going on and like say
you know the senior leadership team and
the board and this sort of stuff
uh it's down in these other ones here
where we get into logical and physical
assets
access controls and system operations
and change management
this is more where it gets into the more
it's type stuff
that i'm used to i'm sure most of you
guys use are used to
this gets into like hey are you doing
backups you know you have antivirus in
place
know you have um are you managing
account creation and deletion and you
know
doing pin tests and you know
assessing controls and patching systems
and all that sort of stuff
that's more in the in these lower areas
and whatnot that
you know the sock 2 gets into that i
think for most of us we would be
you know but the thing is that people
don't realize is that
also gets into the upper things until
like that what what the management team
is doing are they
you know taking a look at you know
what's going on in the organization and
setting down standards and
you know what what we refer to as the
tone from the top
yeah that they're set
then
okay i also wanted to touch upon us
versus international
the thing is that these stock reports
are are pretty much
american and american focus and they
have little or no value
outside the u.s um and then something
i've actually seen with some clients
where
um you know some will go for a sock 2
report and some will go for
certification iso 27001 which is
probably kind of the closest for an
international
you know comparison um some might do
both
but um you know so if you're if you're
working here in the if your company is
here in the u.s and you
only deal with you know companies in the
u.s then a sock 2 is probably more
valuable
you know uh than an iso 27001
whereas if you're more of an
international company doing business
overseas
then you know 27 0001 maybe more value
and you know sometimes people get both
you know so i've seen that as well
um you know it's just this depends
and there's actually is a lot of overlap
between the two i think even um
aicpa actually has some crosswalks
between
sock2 and other frameworks including
so if you're really curious you can you
can go check it out
so what is actually in a sock 2 report
and i've actually seen several and i
i wanted to show you guys one to you
guys but unfortunately i said
because the fact that you had to kind of
sign off on an nda and whatnot and
figured this would probably be a
reported recorded session i
didn't want to risk anything so um this
is kind of a high level overview kind of
what
you will see so there'll be like a
letter from the assessor company they'll
be a letter from the company itself
uh honestly these are kind of like
boilerplate sections i i kind of skip
over them
i want to get you know as i'm if i'm
looking to report myself i want to get
into the meat of it
so the next part is the system
description which believe it or not this
is actually written by
the company itself and then this you
know
it gets the format of the assessor so
with one of my clients i was actually
the one that actually wrote the system
description
um so the system description talks about
the company
you know itself what services it
provides and of course
you know again it's it's what's this
report is on and i'll talk a little more
what i mean by that shortly
you know what third parties they rely
upon because that's something we
you know you might not think about it
but you know many companies
you know maybe a providing a services to
a
to a client that they themselves rely
upon
other third parties for their you know
for what they're doing so
if you think about it like if you know
if i'm you know
a sas vendor selling my sas you know
software service services to declines
you know
my system might not be in my you know
back back office that may be at a data
center
or in the cloud well that's a third
party
that i'm relying upon for the servers
that i'm providing to my clients and so
you know i need to go their sock to
reports and
take a look at it and show that i've
done so and that's part of it
uh then it goes into the control
assessment
you know on all the controls that
they're assessed against you know what
was the outcome did were they tested or
not tested
you know and that's not a negative thing
there are
there are in some cases where that you
they actually
couldn't can't test something um and let
me explain let me give you a couple of
you know actual examples um i mentioned
one of the clients i worked with was a
very small company
uh they were about 15 people and one of
the things that they
that you they test they get tested on is
you know
how you handle your onboarding of
employees and your off-board of
employees
so this can be like 15 people and they
have not had anyone
come on board or leave during that
assessment period
so since no one has come on board and no
one has left
how then could you test your processes
for
bringing someone on board or having them
leave you can't because there's nothing
to test
so it's not so it's not a negative you
you actually can't test it
um or even like you know if you have a
process that you
do for handling of a security incident
and you haven't had a security incident
you can't really test per se
you know that you know you can do like a
table top exits but that's not quite the
same thing
um there's also of course the outcome of
the test which is of course you know
that there was
it was all good and it was you know no
exceptions found that's actually what
usually what they say if that's if it
went well or
if there was a problem then they found
exceptions which you don't really want
because that's not
good um and so if that's the case
then this last section is what you what
you will see where
management of that company then has to
respond
to why they failed these these
these tests and actually one one stock 2
report i saw
i was rereading recently that was the
case
um uh i'm not gonna do give you too much
details but think basically what it was
was
due to the pandemic they decide to like
be a little more looser with some of
their controls
so then they got kind of like spanked in
the report because of that and then they
had to kind of like say
you know well you know we we loosen the
controls through the pandemic
and that was a mistake we won't do it
again type thing
so you you know as a company you want to
have a report that comes out with
no exceptions that's what you want
and thankfully the two companies i work
with no exceptions
so one one big part that talk to you for
is part of vendor management
um you know if you're a company and you
want to assess the vendors that
rely upon to run your business like i
said
you know and a lot of companies you know
that's just the way it is now is they
rely upon
third parties to be able to do what they
do
you know i said a lot of companies are
you know they put their
computers either in the cloud or in
data centers from third parties they
want to make sure those are managed
uh they may be relying upon you know
like adp and other
other companies to provide them with
like accounting and payroll
services and this sort of stuff so they
want to make sure hey that's all
copacetic um so because of that you know
you
how do you then you should do due
diligence and and be assessing
these different vendors and you know if
you're especially if you're providing
them
your data you want to make sure that
data is secure
and not gotten out and now in you know
the healthcare industry we
call this a business associate and
that's very very critical but outside
that you want to be able you want to be
managing those vendors and know that
they're doing written right
so how do you do it you know and either
this you can make it
a lot of work for yourselves or you can
try to make things easier you know
one you can do like sending them to a
questionnaire that they then have to
answer to say like
you know do you have policies are you
doing
you know do you have you know you have
antivirus in place are you doing do you
have a disaster recovery plan in place
have you tested it
have you have instant response blah blah
blah blah blah blah
because i see a company called shared
assessments that actually will sell you
a very good questionnaire for that very
purpose
uh to make it easier
or you can save yourself a lot of grief
by saying
hey you know either fill out this
really tiresome questionnaire or
give us your sock 2 report or
some summer reports like that you know
and then we'll kind of go away
so i said you know doing your own air
even if you're doing like soft you know
even if you're doing like a shared
assessment site thing
you still have to look over it you know
asking for that
third-party important just makes things
a lot easier um of course the caveat is
you do have to freaking look over it
like i said i saw a one sock 2 report
that i think
was over 200 pages you know and there's
a lot of details and you got to kind of
go through that
um you know but having that you know
kind of
makes it easier in terms of vendor
management but the thing is
is that there's a new new stock 2 report
every year so you need to
be on top of it as for the new one and
so forth um
and so because of all this vendor this
is what is actually what's driving you
know
the need for these companies to say like
hey you know we're working with you
um either give us a sock to reporter
we're not gonna do business with you
the money we're being at least gonna be
reasonable they're like saying like okay
we know it's gonna take you some time
and effort so
we'll get we'll give you two years to
get get the sock to report
uh otherwise we're gonna stop doing
business with you yeah so
so the next thing is is that you know
that's what you're being faced your
company is
is being told they have to get a sock
two report and
you know you may or may not like you
know get pulled into it
you know um again why are you why are
they pursuing it
ideally it's become is done because
their clients are asking for it and
because i've actually dealt with all
these questionnaires i see that a lot i
see like you know we want a sock 2 type
2 report
you know or we want you know 27 000 one
certification or
two or three others and so forth um it's
important of course that you have that
executive report of support
because this is gonna take time and
money you know if
you know i know that certainly you know
if i'm focused on getting stock too for
from for the company i'm working for i'm
gonna be spending a lot of my time my
time is money
i'm gonna have to be going through a lot
of other people and say okay i need your
help on this and
you know we need to fix this and this
sort of stuff um hopefully man
understands that
how much time is to take it's not like
you're going to knock this out in
a weekend or a couple of weeks and
this is going to be an ongoing cost this
means that someone will need to be
gathering evidence all year long
in preparation for an annual assessment
and the
authors are going to come back you know
every year and
spend you know
several days you know gathering evidence
talking to people on this sort of stuff
you know and again that's going to be
not only you're paying them
that you have money to do that you know
you have to deal with
someone running around gathering all
that information and talking with them
and so on and so forth
um so people need to understand that
that's that's how it is
um so set things up for success i said
what is your time frame
you know give yourself at least two
years as a worst case
it can be less um like i said
the smaller client i was working with um
i would i would say that
it took you know for us it was you know
to go and get them
from nothing to get them the sock to
type ii was basically a year and a half
you know i came in helped them out
we did the sock two type one um
in like august of 2019
with the target of them coming back in
you know
again to do the type 2 uh with a august
2020 of course that meant that they were
actually here a little bit
earlier to kind of do the evidence
gathering and so forth so
start to finish about a year and a half
you know
so that's that's how it is uh again you
have to get that management backing
hopefully
they're the ones driving it but like i
said you need it for for time and money
um what is the scope the assessment this
is something also important to think
about
is you know are you doing your entire
company
or just a subset because this will
affect your costs and your effort
um like i said the two examples that i
worked with
in one case it was the entire company
because the entire company was doing
you know the incentive programs so
everyone was involved in that that was
that was the service they were they were
selling so it had to be the whole
company but just
that's how it is with the retail
entity that i was working with instead
what they did was they
they instead of being the entire company
which was
been a nightmare thank god they didn't
do it because i probably would have gone
insane
they actually shrunk the scope very
small to just being
the two entities that were providing a
software as a service service
and that was it they left all the rest
of the entity out
that in my mind made it much more
doable also reduce their cost very much
so that's something also and you know
that's something someone had to be
thought about
if you have like maybe an international
company you know and maybe the stock 2
report is only on
your u.s business and not the stuff
overseas that could be done or
you know if it's just you know you're
you know you have a large interview and
all kind of different things but
you know your services to clients that's
it's more appropriate for sock too maybe
just a small subset
great just do the sock to report on that
um yeah so and even if you look at
things like without with aws or maybe
with microsoft
they actually have multiple sock two
reports because it's on
each one on just as a small subset
service because again
microsoft is a huge company they're not
doing a stock coupon on the entire
microsoft company it's inside it's not
just it's only on
oh you know our azure services or our
office 365 that's
it because you got to think about it
like microsoft is also like
xbox and things like that so they're not
going to include
their xbox business into a sock 2 report
that makes no sense
so that makes it more more easily done
another thing here what i talked about
is like you know because they're having
a consulting company coming to know
assist
you know the company i work with this is
what we did for clients we came in
and helped them out um you know
we would do things like we would look at
we would assess their readiness we'd
look at like the
what controls were in place you know
what policies were in place
what need to be improved help them do
that because sometimes people in
in the company were just maybe they were
really other things or just hadn't had
that knowledge of expertise
and so having that outside expertise
expertise coming in and
helping them out you know could really
assist them
uh and even some other other clients we
were helping with you know
maybe we came in and just helped them
with the information gathering
for the assessment itself and some of
the things that we did
to kind of help them out
i didn't determine scope i talked about
that about the scope that's a very very
important thing
another thing i mentioned earlier is
about those those five trust services
do you do all five or just a subset um
you know that also will help you with
costs i mean i think personally
in my view the id should be the minimum
is doing the security
availability confidentiality and if you
can
leave out processing integrity and
privacy
um but that can be determined by your
clients so that's one thing that we
that i had to do with my current company
was take a look at some of these
um questionnaires from our different
clients to see like
what did they say about the sock 2 in
term like what controls that i had to
include and i only saw a mention for a
couple
you know couple mentioned security you
know one also
mentioned confidentiality that was it
you know
so that works another thing is what i
mentioned
earlier is that do you go for the type
one report this year
and then work your way up to doing the
type 2 that could be good if you
are uncomfortable that you actually have
a year's worth of evidence already in
place
because you don't want to be going and
jumping in to do a type 2 report
and find out that up you're missing
evidence and now you're going to have
failures you know in that report um
or do you feel that you do have that
year's worth of evidence that you can
jump in and do the type two
like i said with the two two companies i
worked with one did the type two
immediately i was a little bit scared
about that but it was successful
the other one we did the type one and
then the type two
you know that's i was kind of told
that's not the normal thing to do
um you know and that that worked as well
preparing for the assessment like i said
you want to assess those controls
what i typically did was i got a i had a
spreadsheet that i had
obtained you can get these look them on
the internet actually aicpa has them
that basically listed
all of their the it the controls
and then i went through and said okay do
we have documentation for these
you know let me actually write down the
policies that exist
or if we don't uh i need to go make sure
that we have that in place
is there evidence in place you know and
if so do we have
a year's worth of it um i should have
added this here
as well is what i would also recommend
doing is
going and noting who should be kind of
the subject matter expert for that
controller what not because when the
assessors come in
those are the people that you're going
to probably have interviewed on
for that so i went through and said okay
these are more hr type stuff
so it's going to become the hr people
and i actually was able to get
you know the right people's names and
put them there and like
oh he used the more i.t control so hmm
you know like these one here i think
it'd be this this this guy here who is
doing this area so that he'll take care
of that and these controls that's that's
gonna be this other person here
um so as i really kind of identify who
the person i would go to
to kind of like validate that we have
evidence who would be the ones that be
enter
interviewed so i mentioned about
evidence so these
you know unfortunately i'm not seeing
like a listing that says like okay for
this control
they want to see these things um i
really wish i
you know that i don't know if that
exists or if it's just not available so
what are they looking for when they talk
about evidence
obviously they're going to look for
written policies and procedures
that's that's a given um other evidence
would be like reports like if you're
doing a pin test report
vulnerability scan report if you conduct
a
disaster recovery or incident response
tabletop exercise
they should have a report generated from
that that said this was the results
any output from any systems like you
know log files
virus scanners backup systems and so
forth that show
that these things are going you know
happening you know
and doing properly um it could also be
things such as if you're doing a
training you know you want to have it
you know
in an actual system that evidence of you
know pay people did training or
you got people signed off on you know
uh contracts and you know employees sign
off on nda's you should have somewhat of
a system
that that's all kept in because you use
that to provide evidence
um you know configuration settings like
say like i think the password settings
and stuff like that if there's any
screenshots being provided as
as evidence you need to include
you know a date and time stamp um
i think it's not just because sometimes
you don't think about it other evidence
says we're saying like org charts
job descriptions and so forth uh
sometimes evidence can be kind of weak
and you want to make sure about that i
mean
you know i'm sorry you know someone
taking notes in a notepad
application saving it is weak evidence
you want evidence that can be
not not questioned for being valid you
mean you don't want something that some
some you know idi just kind of wrote up
that oh yeah you know i did this
you know on this stage this at this
state that i have no way to validate in
that
yeah did you create that six months ago
or did you
create that today yeah something else
they do is they also will sample
evidence um that's important because
you know if you're giving a year's worth
of evidence that can be just too much
um you know just as an example you know
if you do security awareness training
for all the employees
they're not gonna say okay you know you
have a hundred employees
please give me the record for every one
of these employees for the effort for
them going through through training no
they're not going to do that
they're going to do a sampling they're
going to say give us a list of your
employees
okay and they'll go through that list
and they'll put it they'll pick out a
random sample
set you know maybe 10 or 15 and they'll
they'll come back and say like
okay these 10 15 people
give us evidence that they have gone
through training that they assigned
their
you know nba agreement they've signed
that they have uh
will abide by company policies and so on
and so forth
you know and then you need to provide
that evidence and that way
you know it's not like you're giving
them a hundred
copies of things but you're given you
know you're giving a sample
that they have selected from that's a
random sampling um so that's something
that they do
that they will do a lot um
so it's it's it's a lot it's a lot of
stuff and that's why also i said
you know if you've got some in the
person who has been gathered so this
stuff over to over a period of time then
it comes
because much more easier when that when
the assessors come in and start asking
for you to give them stuff
uh the assessment i said you know that's
when the assessors
you know from the accounting firm come
in and start doing their work
uh they of course be asking for evidence
they will you know have some kind of a
system to make it easy uh
you know an ftp site or what have you to
upload all the evidence
they'll be very clear about what they're
looking for
they will set up interviews for key
personnel
you know executives management hrit
people and so forth and a lot of it is
they're kind of validating what
you know what's going on if that you
know if the policy says xyz
the other person said okay you know tell
me how you do your job
you know because they looked at the
policy they want to make sure that
what they're being told is you know what
what is matching up and
they'll even go further we'll actually
have the person do things and whatnot
and say like
okay hold on let me take a we'll do
screenshots and this sort of stuff
as i said the the system description
that i talked about that
you put together this is usually the
first year that's done
that has also provided i said one of the
clients i i was one that wrote the
system description
that i spent a lot of time understanding
the company and so forth
then i took a template that the the
assessors had and i modified that
with what i knew of the company and you
know we did a little bit big one
there was some back and forth between
myself the assessor some other people in
the company
to kind of hammer that out but that's
how it came from
now the thing is with with the
assessments is that up until
kovid all the interviews were on site in
person interviews
and would typically run you know
depending on the size organization two
or three days
maybe more at least the ones that i've
dealt with because the size of the
company
um i would think probably two or three
days but for work a really big company
i have no idea what how many how long
the interviews would take
now with as i had my my two clients i
worked with were
last year and due to covet everything
was remote
you know we did this over like a two or
three year period
you know doing the interview spread out
over that two or three year period
um it's our two three week period
um so that's a little bit different i
know that's something that um
aicpa is kind of allowed for because in
the past they wanted they expected the
assessment to be on site and that's
something i also think about when you
talk about cost is that
you know if you use like a local company
to do your assessment
you know then you don't have to worry
about travel costs versus
you know oh here we are in miami and i'm
going to bring in a company from
from dc to do my assessment uh oh great
i'm going to have to
you know put them up in a hotel and yada
yada that's going to come out of
what what you're being charged for the
assessment versus oh yeah there's some
local people and they just they just
come on over
and for the day and whatnot so
um now after the assessment you know the
assessors of course will take all the
evidence they'll go through and
they'll review it um they will someone's
come back and say like okay i need some
more evidence here or this isn't clear
and this was that there might be a
little bit back and forth on the
evidence
um they will then draft up and this
until the draft report will take usually
a couple of weeks or so
they'll draft up yeah at least at least
this is what i dealt with there was a
couple of weeks i think again for the
bigger companies
you know it might be longer than that
they will draft up a draft sock 2 report
it'll get sent to key personnel for a
review like i know i got it as
i was one reviewing the draft report you
know i was looking for
not just the basic stuff but just making
sure that this was
it was accurate it looked good um i
think with one of the reports they
they there were a couple things where
they had dinked us on stuff and i went
and kind of
went back and said i don't know if
that's correct you think that's on this
i don't know that's true and
we did some back and forth and we we
worked it out and it was um
you know it went when it went okay um
and you know so i think if there is
issues around the evidence
you know then of course you can respond
to it and if you
if they can't address it then
unfortunately you're gonna have to kind
of write up a report that kind of
that's much more serious to say like you
know you know yes we did we didn't do as
well
this is why we're not gonna do it again
so on and so forth
so overall this whole process might take
two or three weeks
um that's why if you want the report and
say in august
they're going to come in like a month or
two before to start the evidence
gathering the interviews and
developing report and this sort of stuff
because you know once august hits
boom that's kind of the cutoff point
they can't take any evidence after that
anything that
intake has to have been dated before
that time um
hence that's why they have to come in in
advance of that to do the evidence
gathering
interviewing and this sort of stuff
because they do have to be
you know that cut off point and no
further
um so again you know and this is you
know for me i had like
basically the first time doing it so you
know the first time is there's a lot
more work
you had to create that system you know
that system description
it's the first time being assessed for
those controls and so forth so hopefully
you know when the second year comes
along and the third year comes along
where
you know if as long as there's no no
radical changes in the organization and
its environment
it's just more of you know you gather
the evidence you make sure it's in place
they come by they take a look at the
evidence everything looks good
boom you're done you know we'll see you
next year type thing and i hate to say
it it'd be kind of routine but
to agree it does but you still have to
have that evidence and so forth
uh otherwise you know there's gonna be
some problems
again once the report is complete you
know if you if the company wanted to
they can actually add a logo on the
website saying that
they have a sock 2 report you know hey
do business with us we get stock 2. um
they can then provide that of course
with an nda to
potential clients or actual clients
as i said they have to appropriate they
need to preparing for next year
um hopefully if need be maybe improve
controls
maybe improve evidence if some of the
evidence was kind of weak
uh and but they accepted it but you know
let's let's do better
they get more strong um advanced getting
is it can be a lot of work you know
it may be you need to create a a whole
bunch of directories and save stuff
or there's actually these things called
grc tools which
you know makes it more automatic and
there's people i know that
their whole their whole job is basically
pulling in stuff and putting in the
chersey tool and making sure the
evidence is gathered and so forth
you know i don't know if i'd want to do
that but that's what some people do
um but that's what kind of helps making
this as an ongoing activity
there are source resources you know i
would say the best one is just go to
aicpa
they do have a lot of things that you
can download uh there is a there is a
spreadsheet
of the trust security controls you want
to look at for the
2017 version that was last update of it
um you know i went and grabbed it
another one you can get it's called dc
200 which is the career for system
description you know these are you know
you can you can find these for free and
whatnot
um if you want to go further you can get
the book
which is the guidebook which i have a
copy
it's uh clocks in it uh oh 460 pages you
know real fun reading
um but this covers everything it has in
it
all the controls and they talk about it
they have they include dc
200 and all that sort of stuff um really
boring stuff i
i'd admit but you know if you want you
know if this is
if you why not happen to do uh a sock to
assessment in your company or help them
out
you might want to get it and i'll be
honest the best place to get this is on
amazon
aicpa has a website but i've actually
looking at it
it's actually cheaper and easier to get
it off of amazon
and if you're if you're really really
curious is actually actually another
book for the soc 2 for cyber security
if you're curious about that i did do a
presentation on that a few years back
um but the funny thing was i actually
talked to an assessor about this
about a couple years ago and she told me
that no one
had at that point and not just her
company but everywhere
had you know gotten a sock to
uh for cyber security uh the title of
the book is right there in the slide
guide socked your reporting on an
examination of control at a service
organization blah blah blah blah
um yeah so search on amazon for like you
know
guide sock 2 and this should come up it
comes from aicpa
published by wiley came out in 2018.
um it's uh it's a kind of a kind of a
boring stuff but you know
what i would say as a as a starting
point you know you guys you can get the
spreadsheet
you know for free uh and let's look at
the controls
um it can be a little bit tricky so you
might want to you know get the boat to
kind of help you out if that's you're
serious about it
they also have some good like pdf
documents that kind of explain
stock 2 reports and some of the elements
so you might want to get those because
they're free
as a starting point kind of look look
through them and read them before you go
and splurge on getting the book
um it's not too expensive you know
i want to think it was like 50 bucks or
something like that but you know
it's not too bad so
yeah again the title is in the slide
yeah so with that
um let me see how do i
stop sharing nope
ah
okay that was an amazing presentation
uh if anybody has any questions you can
type them
and see if we have any questions so far
see what we got
cause the link you posted
yeah thank you very much this was a
great presentation any other questions
guys
uh if anyone from that's watching on the
discord as well
if you want to type that question in on
uh the general chat
we're actually going to question
streaming this into a discord which is
pretty cool
yeah but you have the echo because you
have both streams
sorry i'm not mute right now
so you mentioned some of the grc tools
there's still an echo i've been getting
a lot of ads and my whole company has
about stock in a day tools which
isn't gonna happen but they are
advertising as these
like ten thousand dollar tools that are
basically document storage yeah that's
basically
checklists integrated yeah have you seen
those provide any value
because it's something between
the only value i would see in them is
just helping helping you kind of
organize
the evidence gathering that you need to
do because when i started thinking about
it because
you know a lot of stuff i i don't do
i don't use tools just because we didn't
have the money for tools
yeah i would do a lot of spreadsheets
and this sort of stuff and so something
i'm thinking like okay if i'm
you know gathering all this evidence you
know what's the easiest way for me to
kind of
gather it and manage it and all i can
think of is like creating a
pardon my friend just shitload of
directories
because the way it is if you look at you
know at you know the sock 2 controls is
that they're
you know just it's a spread you know
just listening so you have
you know 1.1
and then underneath it there is four or
five
possible controls so
1.1.1
this sort of stuff so i do have a whole
bunch of nested directories
or what have you and then as i'm getting
evidence i go like okay
i got this evidence for this month i'm
dropping in there oh i've got this money
for
evidence from from the next month i drop
it in there and then i go in there and i
got like
a year's worth of evidence either
gathered
either weekly or monthly and it's all in
a freaking directory
you know all these sub directories it's
like oh my god and you know how do i get
it into
over to the assessor and it's sort of
like so a lot of the grc tools that's
what they're all about is that
they're helping you kind of manage these
these sort of uh
uh these sort of things like there's
like service now
and you know audit board
and and so others which they're ones i
know of but i just
you know it's and it's they're not just
for sock too they're for
like all these sort of auditing and
assessments and so forth that that
are out there that you know
you know like sarbanes-oxley and 27001
and pci and and everything else
you know that just becomes you know even
some of these tools where actually you
actually will
put your actually your whole policy set
in them and so forth
so you know it's it's really kind of
crazy so
you know it's a whole business i mean
when you go to like an eye soccer
conference
and there'll be like probably two or
three vendors
you know just on grc tools
yeah you know rsa has one ibm has one
and yadda yadda yeah i'm seeing this new
class come out that they're not
full-blown grc tools and i say that
because it's not very customizable
it's we've got sock in one other
framework and they're separate
pieces of software that we sell as sas
applications
yeah i get the value if you have three
compliance things and you need that same
piece of evidence to be tagged in
different ways
but i just didn't know if you had seen
somebody actually
find value out of one that's
specifically for sock two
and not a full-blown grc tool
not really that's something i i i'd love
to uh
learn more about because you know
as i go forward and doing more and more
compliance stuff with companies
you know i want to see like what what
tool would i want to use
it's even funny even like you know the
accounting firm that i was working with
you know initially for for their system
for even uploading and giving them
evidence
it used to be basically an ftp server
which was a real pain
and they went to another system and i'm
like i hate to say i'm blanking on the
name of it
but it was it was um it was like a
more like an excel spreadsheet on
steroids
in that you had an excel spreadsheet
they had all the controls
but then there was an area for oh i can
just drop in the evidence for
that you need and it was uploaded to
them and then i know and then
then they could mark it to show like
okay we got the evidence everything is
good
you know who they're going to talk to
and this one so it was a great way for
us that
you know to track the progress what need
to be done what was there and so forth
and i'm blanking on the name
of the product um
yeah i want to say share file but that's
not correct
but it was it was you know it you know
when they went to do
to use that with with their assessment
it just made things a lot easier
especially able to just do drag and drop
and so forth
you know with the assessments
it was another question about free
materials to do um about the it audits
or
at least to get started what would you
recommend to get started
um i've actually kind of had a hug learn
on my own but
uh i kind of looked up to isaka
for i t audit type information um
because i kind of view isaka as the uh
i t audit and control organization um
another one is iia
the internal audit association that i'm
not really involved in but i'm involved
in
with isakka so they have materials and
whatnot some of them it's only
you know either you have to pay for it
unless you're a member and then and if
you're a member
you know you either get it free or there
are some training and i think they've
done some i think recently done some
training
um some certification programs
um on it audit that's um
fairly inexpensive so that's something
to look at
you know they've even done some other
things that are kind of interesting um
yeah they have one that they have one
certificate called uh
a cyber security audit certificate um
that's something to look into uh they do
have training i think even
you can get like a book from them that
you can they can just read through and
get prepared for it
and they also wasn't thinking with isaka
as they recently teamed up with the
cloud security alliance
to come up with a cloud security
audit knowledge certificate
which is the first so and that's
something that's also kind of you know
that's
it's also kind of uh you know
bothered me because as more and more the
companies i've dealt with were moving
the cloud am i thinking like okay
how would i audit that and
um you know understand that what they're
doing is okay and now
now they've got this
any other questions see
all right this was an amazing
presentation uh thank you very much
everybody for attending um
if you are we have time free today we do
have
a securing kubernetes talk
uh at 2pm pacific uh for pacific hackers
uh and i'm sure it's gonna be an amazing
talk if not then i'll see you guys
in discord and keep in touch because uh
i'm sure we will have uh updates for uh
defcon and other conferences
thank you very much and i'll see you
soon