(audience applauding)
- I have something here, because
I'm gonna be talking to you
about Automating Analysis
with Multi-Model Avocados.
So, I have some shirts here
with some avocados on 'em.
I might just throw
them out to you guys,
but you might have
to pass them around
because the sizes
are kind of funky.
So, if you get,
like, one and just
pass it 'til someone can use
it, I guess, I don't know.
Here's a shirt, woo!
(audience laughing)
Alright, cool.
By the way, the
multi-model avocados
I'm talking about
here is ArangoDB.
It's a database, just in case.
By the way, I
predict the future.
There's my Twitter handle
right there, Forensic Matt.
Follow me, because
I have a feeling
at the end of this presentation,
you're going to say things like,
Oh, where can I find that tool?
Where can I find
this information
you're talking about?
Well, I'll tweet about it,
throw up a blog post later
'cause none of that
stuff is done yet,
so, you know, just
follow me on Twitter.
So, when I talk about
automated systems
I don't want you guys
to immediately think,
oh, this guy's trying to push
a find everything forensic
button, or anything.
No, it's not really like that.
But, when we talk about
an automation system
what does that entail?
So, oftentimes, when we
do our investigations,
I'm just gonna set,
well, you know what?
Here, here's another shirt.
All right, oh, that one
has a fox on it, actually,
because we'll get
into that in a minute.
(audience laughing)
Alright, so, when we go through
our forensic investigations,
this usually entails that
we're looking for
very specific things.
We go, generally we're given
a forensic image, right?
Or, we made the forensic
image and we wanna
pull some stuff out, look at it.
So, we do an extraction,
we run a tool on,
let's say we're looking
for past executions.
This could be Prefetch, right?
So, we pull out Prefetch,
we run a tool on it,
we get output, but we need to
know that something happens.
So, let's go ahead and
extract out the registry,
let's look at the Bam
keys, the Dam keys,
'cause we need to put
more information together.
So by the end of it,
we've extracted out,
I don't know, 20
different artifacts,
ran 20 different tools,
and now we have to
do something with
this output, right?
So, automation system,
we want to use tools,
we want to take that output,
ingest it into a
storage of some sort.
Then, when it's in
the storage point,
we wanna do some type of
analysis, so that in the end
we get meaningful reports,
and it would be great
if we just didn't
have to do a whole lot
between then and the tool
or the image in the report,
so that we have more time
to do meaningful stuff.
So, in looking at this,
we, the better the tool,
the better our output can be.
And by having better output,
it enables us to
do better analysis,
and better analysis
leads to a better report.
So, we have a tool
problem, though.
There's a challenge here,
because when I look for a tool
I want all of the artifact,
not just some of the artifact.
But, I'm scared that
the tool thought I said,
give me a lot of artifact.
But what I want is the whole
artifact, I want all of it.
But, the problem here is that
there's output
that's for humans,
and then there's output that
we need that's for analysis,
and the two don't go
together very well, right?
So, when you get
output for humans,
you're looking at TSV output,
you're looking at
comma-separated
value output, right?
Excel, right?
It's very linear.
But, the problem is, when a
tool starts trying to give us
things that it thinks
we would wanna see,
it can start skipping some data.
Because in reality,
the data structures
behind these artifacts
are very nested.
They're not flat
data structures.
And so, when you try
and flatten it out,
you get a lot of
either duplicated data
or there's some
data that just like,
I don't know how to
show this to you,
because it's too much
for a human to look at.
So, we need that
output for analysis.
Why do we need this?
So, oh, real quick,
how do I go back?
Yeah, so, output for
analysis might be
way more complicated data,
because it's gonna be very
nested data structures, right?
So, generally, like
JSON-type data,
or XML, XML can be
nested, as well,
but it's very difficult to go
through that with a human eye.
So, we look at, why
do we need this?
Because there's
so many artifacts.
And when we take a step back,
the more artifacts
we can put together
the bigger picture
we start to see.
So, ShellBags tells
us something, MFTs
tell us something,
Prefetch, USN, all of these
things tell us one thing,
but when we start looking
at all of them together,
it shows us a much
larger picture.
So this is why we need
data for analysis.
Because when we have
this nested data,
generally we have things
that we're missing
in something like TSV form.
Because you're just able to
throw all of the data into it
instead of just some of it.
Now we can link these
artifacts together
and start looking at a much
larger picture all together.
But there's an
analysis challenge here
because if a tool only
gave us output for analysis
and not output for humans,
it's very difficult to
navigate that type of data.
If you had a huge
JSON dump, you know,
how are you gonna
go through that?
They make some JSON querying
tools that can help,
but it's just, it's really hard
to go through that type of data.
So we have issues
of navigating it,
we have issues of
searching through it.
Granted, you can always just,
you know, grep through it.
Why not?
But then, what if we
wanted to correlate it?
What if we had JSON
output from one tool
and JSON output for another tool
and we wanna combine it together
and kinda make it
relational type data?
It's really hard, right?
Not to mention the challenge
of formatting the data.
Because, in the end,
we can't give a lawyer
a whole bunch of JSON, right?
That's just dumb.
But then there's the challenge
of automating all of it.
So these are the
challenges we face.
So we need a solution that
can address those challenges.
I give you ArangoDB.
Not only is its icon avocados,
what's that, somebody
wants a shirt?
All right.
Oh.
(audience laughing)
The shirt didn't fly too
well and it's unwrapped.
My bad.
But the purple ones
are ladies' shirts,
so that works out well.
All right, so why ArangoDB?
It's a multi-model
database which consists of
a document store, a
graphing database,
and a key-value store,
all in one package,
which is awesome.
So we need a document store
because of our data structure.
It's nested.
But the problem with a lot
of no-SQL solutions is that
you can't relationally
connect your data.
Well, with Arango,
we can do this.
We can correlate values from our
highly nested data structures.
It has a great query language.
This is awesome, the
relational queries,
and great thing, it's
not written in Java!
Now, if I told you
Java needs to die,
everyone would be like, haha.
But if Jake Williams says
it, maybe Java needs to die.
I don't know.
Anyways, but the great
thing about this is
it still maintains a
scalable environment.
So you can still spin
up a bunch of servers
and create your clusters
just like you can with
something like Elastic.
And I'm sure some of you
in here have experience
with trying to put all of
your data into Elastic.
And then it's just
hard to go through.
Let's just not even
talk about Elastic.
Anyways, so, another
great thing about it is,
it ships with JavaScript
microservices,
which are fantastic
because you can spin up
your own interfaces, if
you wanted to write some,
and when your server spins
up, you can just access those.
So, and there's a great
interface that ships with it,
kind of like Cabana type thing.
So what can we do with ArangoDB
that really helps us to
see the larger picture
and created a automated
analysis workflow?
One of the things we
can do is correlations.
Shirt time!
I really hope I don't
hit anyone's coffee
and knock it over.
That would be bad, actually.
Maybe I should not do this.
Value-based correlations,
so in a second,
we'll see an example of
it, but this is like,
MFTs, they have file
reference numbers, right?
How many other
artifacts out there
have file reference numbers?
You can find file reference
numbers in the USN journal
and the log file and
Prefetch data, leap files.
They're all over the place.
So now we can correlate and
link these documents together,
which is great.
What about range based?
What if I wanted to
say, oh, I want to see
30 seconds of the given artifact
after I see something
else in another artifact?
What if I see something
bad in the Prefetch
and I wanna look at
historical records
five seconds after that thing
happened in the Prefetch,
or after we know
executable rate, right?
We can do that,
that's a correlation.
You can create your own custom
functions, which is awesome,
because a lot of the time we
process forensic artifacts
and we still have values
that are decoded, right?
PowerShell, base 64, right?
If we get PowerShell logs,
we still have to
decode with base 64.
So we needed some way to
do decoding on the fly
so that we can do more
analysis on the database side.
So then I'm gonna talk about
something a little
bit more complex,
which is pattern-based
searching.
And this is when you
can actually group
and aggregate artifacts and
look for very specific patterns.
And this is great.
This even goes back to what
the FireEyes guys
were talking about,
with needing some type
of resilient pattern,
resilient signature.
Talk about this in a second.
Here's an example,
ShellBag difficulties.
You're looking through ShellBags
and you see two folders
on the same volume.
In this case, it's E.
Did these two, are these two
folders from the same volume?
Now, sometimes we can
figure this out really fast
because maybe one's an NTFS
volume and one's a FAT volume
and we know that FAT doesn't
have the NFT sequence numbers,
which we would see
if it was NTFS.
But it's not always that easy.
But to answer a
question like this,
let's look at our
underlying data.
ShellBag data.
You have MFT entries,
this is important to us.
You have sequence numbers.
And then you have the
name of the folder itself.
What about link data?
All right, so you see here
an example of nested data.
The link file structure
is not flat, by any means.
It doesn't even resemble a TSV.
It's very nested.
But what are we interested in?
We're interested
in the file name,
we're interested in any type,
the volume serial number,
we're interested in
reference numbers,
sequence numbers, entry numbers.
So the cool thing about this is,
they're shell items per folder
and file of the local path.
So you see a
testfile054 up there,
you would have an entry for
that, a entry for testfolder001.
And what that means
is, you have parents,
you have entry numbers
and sequence numbers
for every single path
in the link file.
This is great because that means
we can correlate link files
and ShellBags together
because we want to know, were
they two separate volumes?
So here's an example,
you don't really
need to know what it says,
but the just is, we're gonna
iterate through our link files
and say, hey, let's compare
anything where the file name,
the entry numbers, and the
sequence numbers are the same
with those in the ShellBags.
Because in the end, what we
want is something like this,
where we can say, hey,
no, we found a correlation
and we can tell you
that these two folders,
while they're on the
same E, they look
they come from the E
drive and the ShellBags,
they're not the same volume.
That's important
because now we know,
if we were looking at
just the ShellBags,
we might say, hey, these
things, it's the same volume,
but no, it's two
separate drives.
ShellBags stores it on
a drive-letter basis.
So, tool shout outs!
Guys, I'm not making
this stuff up.
I didn't just generate this
data from somewhere random.
No, I used real tools
out there, right?
So thanks, Eric, thank you, G-C,
thank you, Dave, Dave Callan.
He's generous, he throws
out tools, it's cool.
What about a more
complex question?
Did a wiper run?
What files were wiped?
Where do we go to
for this information?
Execution artifacts, right?
We have file history artifacts.
So, two that come
to mind, Prefetch,
we can find execution
artifacts there, USN journal,
historic file
activity, great things.
What's in our Prefetch data?
Prefetch data has runtimes.
It has the file names in there.
What about USN record data?
That's going to give us,
on a per-change basis,
one, the reason the
file has a log in it,
which is why it was
changed, basically,
the timestamp of
the change itself,
file names, reference
numbers, again,
more correlation
points for later.
But what would a query look like
where we could say,
hey, did a wiper run?
Were there files erased?
What if we could
automate this process
and just have this
query that goes through
and it looks for
some known examples.
So we know, if we look
through our Prefetch
and we see something called
Eraser, we know that's a wiper.
Let's look for the
file system activity
10 seconds after we know,
between the time Eraser ran
and 10 seconds after it,
within the USN records,
to find out what was
happening on the disk.
When we run something like
this, this is the result.
And so we see, Prefetch was ran,
we find that from the runtime,
and then we're looking
from that point
to 10 seconds after that
point in the USN journal.
And we see something
real nice looking.
These look like wipe files.
We can see that
because our first file,
and in this example,
it's in plain text,
we see the data
overwrite change.
After that, we see that it goes
through a iteration process
of being renamed several times.
Finally, this same file has
a file delete
operation done on it.
And we know it's the same file
because of the entry number.
So, there's a problem
with this, though.
Well, first, tool shout outs.
All right, so, a while back
I made some Rust tools.
They're really cool.
If you're into turning
artifacts into JSON,
these are great tools for it.
Plus, it's cool that
they're written in Rust,
so they're super fast.
And you can find
them on the GitHub.
Links is up there.
So, real quick, so there's
a problem with this
and the problem is, we
can't quantify this.
We know, we see five seconds'
worth of historical activity
and it does look like erasing.
But we need to go further.
And we'll get to
that in a second.
So let's talk about on-the-fly
decoding real quick.
This is important.
This is a cool, this is
the Windows Partition
diagnostic event log.
And this is something, Jason
Hale wrote a blog post on
the other day, it
was really cool.
Because traditionally,
volume serial numbers,
which we were just
looking at in link files,
were only really there if
you had ReadyBoost enabled.
And now, it's very
rare that you have
ReadyBoost enabled by default.
So it's hard to link things
up with volume serial numbers
to their correct
device information.
You could do time range
correlations, right?
Where you could say, okay, well,
when was the last time that
a device was plugged in,
and then go about it that way.
But we don't need to.
Now we could do some
on-the-fly decoding and say,
hey, let's look at these events,
because these are
new in Windows 10,
and there's a hex string
of the entire VBR blocks,
which is awesome.
So it's within the VBR
blocks that we can pull out
the volume serial numbers.
But we need to make a
custom function to do that.
So this is basically
how you would do that.
The ArangoDB ships with a shell
and you can register
functions with it.
That works out great for
doing things like this.
So I want to do a
query and I want to
grab device information based
off of this Windows event
and I want to be able
to decode on the fly
those volume serial,
or the VBR blocks.
So this is basically what
that would look like.
We call our custom
function, WinEvent.
And then what's the result?
Something like this.
So those VSNs are being
pulled out on the fly
from those raw hex
stocks, which is huge.
Because generally,
your tool is going to
give you some type
of encoded data
and then you're gonna have to
further process that even more.
So now we can do this
all on the storage level.
More tool shout outs.
Events JSON was used
for those examples.
All right, so now we're gonna
talk about pattern searching.
So pattern searching is cool
because this is where
things can get dynamic.
Because the problem is,
you can't always
rely on an MD bypass.
You can't always rely
on the name of a file
because those things
change, right?
So we wanted to create
some type of query
that's able to aggregate
and group our artifacts.
And we want to look for
something very specific.
Once again, you don't
need to know what it says,
you just need to know that
this is how easy it is
to do the groupings,
do the aggregations.
Why do we need to do this?
Because let's go back
to the wiped files.
We can't quantify, if
we tell a lawyer, hey,
we know something's been
wiped, what are they gonna ask?
They wanna know what was wiped,
how much of it,
was it important.
We need to be able to
give them those answers.
So we wanna automate
this process, right?
So what we can do
is, we now know that
there's a pattern behind
our wiping utility.
Then, in this case, when
we examine the data,
we see that you have a
minimum of eight file names
being, when a file gets erased,
you have a minimum
of eight renames.
So you have the
original name that gets,
has the data
overwrite operation,
it has a minimum of
three actions done to it
before it gets
renamed to six more,
it gets renamed six more times.
Each rename, within
the USN journal,
that file name,
under that file name,
has five operations done to it,
followed by a seventh
sequential rename,
where it finally gets deleted.
So this is actually a
pattern that we can use
in being able to quantify
what all was erased.
So, we want to be able to
create some type of signature
that can look for
this type of activity.
And what's cool about this is,
you don't have to apply
this to just file erasing.
This is to forensics in general.
Like we just, we
want to look for
pattern-based type of things.
So now we throw our
signature into our query
and this is the
result that we get.
We found 138 files that
matched that pattern
that we can now say, we know
all of these files were erased
because it matched our pattern.
Here are the original names,
here are the wiped names,
and those are the times
when that file was erased.
It's pretty big.
So I wanna talk a
little bit about
how we can automate
this entire process
and why it's important, right?
Because we're seeing
a lot more that
lawyers are coming to us
and they're giving us
more and more evidence,
but they're wanting answers
a lot faster than we
can give it to them.
So a lot of this stuff
can be automated,
so it should be automated.
But we shouldn't have to
reinvent the whole wheel.
There's a lot of tools out there
that we wanna utilize in this.
So can we make a system that
utilizes other people's tools,
uses the output, puts it in
a centralized storage place,
allows us to do analytics on it,
and then gives us more
meaningful reports?
Because very few
times are we able to
just run one tool, get
one report out of it,
and just hand that off.
Usually, it's a combination
of multiple tools,
multiple output, having to
put that output together,
creating a report out of it,
and then being able
to hand that off.
So, here is an example,
here is a demonstration,
that this can be done.
So, we've downloaded
the ArangoDB package
from ArangoDB site.
It's a zip, which is awesome.
What's cool about this is,
you don't have to
install anything.
You can just stand
this up wherever
and it works on, they
have the OSX version,
they have one that runs
on Linux, and Windows.
And again, you
don't need the Java.
Who cares?
All right, so all you have
to do, it's this easy.
You just run, you
start up your service,
boom, it's up and
running, right?
So, and it gives you a
socket, much like Cabana does,
to where you can go there,
you're gonna see an interface.
So now we need to mount a drive.
And then, once we
mount this drive,
by the way, I love Arsenal.
This is one of my
favorite tools.
It makes things very easy.
All right, so we have
our tools folder.
This is a tool that I worked
on as a proof-of-concept code.
And what it does is, it
iterates through a volume,
a live volume, and
it extracts out files
and then runs tools
on those files.
So in this case, we're
looking at Prefetch.
It's basically looking for all
the files with a PF ending.
It's gonna run the
Rusty Prefetch on it.
Same with MFT.
We've got some journal in there.
And then the event logs as well.
But this is great
because we can just
utilize other people's
tools when we do this
and then do analysis
with that output
all in one central
storage location.
So, we need to open up, we're
gonna open up PowerShell.
We've gotta start
it in admin mode
because you need that raw
handle to a logical volume
because we had
mounted our image.
So that image is now
mounted to drive letter I
as a logical image.
Always give a dash-H, tells
you how to use the tool.
So what we're gonna do is,
we give it the source volume.
In this case, it's I.
Then we need to tell it to,
give it a temp folder location.
Because a lot of these
files we have to export out
before we can run
something on it.
So then, we give it the
name of the database.
So now it created a database
and our Arango cluster
is going through,
it's parsing out
all the link files,
registry, USN journal, MFT,
we see how many records
are being loaded in there.
So, and set up API,
Prefetch, right?
So now, what we wanna
do is, we can pull up,
oh, I guess I gotta
let it catch up.
By the way, it
doesn't go that fast.
I wish it did, but I
had to speed it up,
otherwise we'd be
sitting here for a while.
Python's slow, but it allows
us to do amazing things.
So then, oh, first we need
to use our Arango shell
because we're going to
create our user functions,
which we have done earlier,
and this is going to
allow us to create reports using
some of our more complex
custom functions.
So, now we're ready to
go to our interface.
Of course, there, by default
it's a root with no password
because why wouldn't you?
So here's all of
our collections.
We have link files,
USN, stuff like this.
This shows you, this is just
what that data looks like
within the database.
So here's the USN, USN
is relatively flat,
but we nest out the
reference numbers
so we can do those correlations.
Here is Windows event logs.
Event logs are great examples
of highly nested data.
So, let's run some queries.
So some of this we already saw.
This one is looking at
PowerShell script logs.
So this is what, we're
looking in the Windows events,
we see the PowerShell
stuff, here is an example,
I just wanted to show you all
what the interface looks like
because we're going to just
cut over to the
reports in a second.
But this is what the interface
looks like for ArangoDB.
So it gives you, just the
interface that ships with it
gets you past those
complex issues of
getting through the data
with searching, navigating,
the things I talked
about earlier.
So let's run some
scripts that we have.
These are going to create
template Excel files.
So now we went from image to
Excel reports, just like that.
So there's one of
the PowerShell blocks
you can see right there,
the DLL importing,
things like the virtual outlet,
things that we would question.
Here's a spreadsheet
of our eraser
and what files were
erased after that.
And then this one
is the wipe files,
using our signature-based
searching.
So, that just gives
you an example.
Yes, we can automate
a lot of this stuff.
That doesn't mean it's
cutting anyone out of a job.
It's going to allow us
to get to more important,
it's going to enable us to
look for more complex things
and just get rid of
the low-hanging fruit.
And one of the things I love
about this conference is,
there's so much relevant data
being taught in
the presentations.
I want a system like this that,
when I watch someone talk
about a new artifact,
I can plug it into this
system using their new tool.
And now, every case that
comes through our lab,
we can be accounting
for that information.
Pretty big.
I like it, I hope you liked it.
That's about all
I've got for you.
Right on, well thank you guys.
I have more t-shirts.
(audience applauding)