(techno music)
(woosh)
(audience clapping)
- Okay so, as you heard,
my name's Lee Whitfield.
I work for SANS.
I work for the on-demand team.
So as much as I love and
endorse taking the live classes,
whenever you attend
events like this,
on-demand classes are awesome.
You get four months
to take the class
and do all the exercises,
and everything else.
Wonderful. Highly recommend it.
And you know, even Rob
thinks it's a good idea too.
So go ahead and do that.
The last few times I
presented at this summit,
it's been a bit of
a mixed bag, okay.
Some of it is really technical.
Some of it's not
really technical.
And this falls into like
that latter category.
So we're not gonna
go and dive into
really deep technical
details about things here.
But I think it's still
gonna be pretty valuable
to a lot of people.
Why would you do
evidence generation?
Well, a lot of the stuff
that we do on a daily basis
is based on some kind
of evidence generation.
So, like for example,
all of you saw Heather
and Sarah this morning
talking about the
ASF generation,
which they quite
amusingly generate,
pulling husbands through
fields and everything else.
They know what they did
so they're able to
correlate that data back.
They can tell you
when things happened
because they were
there at the time.
So the tools which they use
to do these kinds of things,
do these investigations,
and the procedures,
and everything else
they develop as a result
can be more effective
as a result.
Because they were there.
Same goals whenever
you want to generate
any kind of test evidence.
So some of you may think
well, yeah you know what,
it's not that big of a deal.
I'll let other
people handle that.
But what I can tell
you is that some point,
throughout your career,
you're gonna encounter
that one forensic artifact.
Some random Chinese social
media application, you know,
or something else you
have to then pass out,
get the data from,
and figure it out.
Now that can be really difficult
if you're just taking
things straight off
a piece of evidence
because you have no
background in that whatsoever.
You have some indication
though what it's doing.
Unless you get down
into the meat yourself,
generate the test
evidence yourself,
with all the notes
and everything that
go along with it,
you may not get as good of
results as you're hoping for.
And you can guess
which always goes really
well in this field, um no.
Testing your evidence,
generating test evidence,
when you test your
forensic tools
is always gonna be a good idea.
So, as before, why would
you do test evidence?
Well you can validate
your existing tools.
You can then move
into tool development
if you find something
which is a bit more niche.
You can use it for
testing new hires.
You can then use it also
for testing current staff,
making sure that
they own things.
And then you add in the
educational components too.
So let's take a look first
here and kinda tie it together.
And there's various
different reasons
you might want to do this
for existing tool validation.
Now the first one is that
if any of you have ever done
any kind of lab
accreditation or ISO work,
anyone here done that before?
No. I don't see any hands.
You're all very lucky then.
I did ISO 17025
documentation for a company
I used to work for
back in the UK.
And it's a nightmare.
Any time you get
a new tool release
you have to use
your golden image
to then verify
everything that happens.
Make sure that all the data
outputs for the forensic tool
that are accurate.
And they're inaccurate
you have to go back
and right up a cause for
whatever report your generating.
Now obviously lab
accreditation, ISO work,
is not the only time when you
want to validate your tools.
If anyone remembers the social
experiment by Harlan Carvey.
Yeah I see people
nodding their heads.
That's one very very good
reason why you want to validate
your source.
It also depends a lot on
how you want to do this
or what you want to do.
Like are you looking at,
do you want to test a
full forensic image,
sub-set of that data?
For example if you want to
analyzed like registry keys
or specific registry key,
you don't want or need a
full forensic image right?
You just focus on
something smaller.
And generally that
kind of evidence
is really straight
forward and easy.
All you do is type
some stuff in,
maybe browse a few websites,
do some activity on the computer
and boom you've
got your registry.
There may be other things too,
very specific artifacts
that you want to focus on.
In that case to generate
those specific artifacts only
you feed them into whatever tool
or to whatever
analysis you need to
and then you can validate
your tool that way.
The next thing is the
testing of new hires.
Potentially your
existing staff too.
I've had a couple job
interviews in the last few years
where I was actually given
forensic evidence to test.
And I had to analyze that
data, produce a report,
and then my capacity
as a future employee
was evaluated based
upon what I found.
Now there's a few
different reasons for this.
Now yes you want someone
to be able to use the tools
which you are going
to use every day
but that's not really the most
important reason for this.
The most important reason is
that you wanna have someone
who will critically look
at the ways to do things.
Who have developed knowledge
and procedures themselves
that will help them to get
to the underlying evidence.
Yes it's great to able to
sit there and push buttons
on the piece of software
and for everything to
be going practically
but you don't need to
hire people like that.
You can have the
cleaner come in at night
when you're at home
it's really easy.
You want someone who
will critically think
through the whole process.
And then finally,
we have the
educational component.
How many of you people here
today are gonna stick around
after this one is over
and take one of the
forensics classes on offer?
Okay. There 900
of you by the way.
That's not enough.
If you choose to take
one of these classes
almost every single one
of the forensic classes
on offer here will
walk you through
specific evidence scenarios
that the authors and instructors
have created for themselves.
Further, you'll get to
the day six challenge
and the instructors, again,
have created those
scenarios for you.
And we heard Heather and
Sarah again saying today
that they have brand new
scenarios that they've created.
The amount of work that goes
into these is phenomenal.
I know talking to Sarah
that she has been basically
traversing the globe with a
backpack full of MAC systems
in order to generate
all of this data.
It takes a long time
and we'll get into that
in just a minute.
But basically for these
all you wanna know is
whether or not people
actually find out
what you want them to find.
Oh, also, just quickly.
Let's not forget NetWars too.
If you've just been in
the FIR NetWars this week,
again evidence data
which has been generated
by the instructors for you
to participate in that.
So all these things go towards
this is why evidence
generation is important.
So about a year ago
Rob asked me to
help him to generate
a new forensics challenge
for Forensics 500.
And we've called it
the Stack Challenge
because it's the name
of the person involved.
This one is pretty interesting.
I'd never done anything
like this before
and Rob gave me some
guidelines and instruction
on how to make this work.
And it was pretty
fun and interesting
and I learned a lot of
stuff along the way.
I had to come up with my own
set of guidelines though.
So first obviously
you need a plan.
You can't just kind of think,
well we'll do a bit of
this, a bit of that,
and maybe at the end of the
day we'll have something
which students in Forensic
500 will enjoy doing.
Nyeh, it doesn't work that way.
So I had to come
up with this plan.
I sat down with
my family actually
and came up with this scenario.
And if you're taking
forensics 500 this week
and you're sitting
there taking notes
really quickly and like,
yes this is gonna help
me on the challenge,
no it's not gonna help
you on the challenge.
This is all from a very
high level I'm sorry,
take notes anyway.
We sat down together,
made this plan.
We tried to figure out what
exactly we were gonna need.
Then we evaluated that plan
and we tried to find out
where the good and bad
spots were and all that.
We implemented it
and then we conducted
what I call the post-mortem.
And that might look bad,
it's just my own way of
saying post evaluation.
The planning phase.
The first thing we
needed to do as Rob said,
we wanna get all
of these artifacts
and as much as covered
in the material
we need to try and generate.
And that can be pretty difficult
and we get into why
in just a minute.
But what we needed to
do in order to generate
all these artifacts in the
appropriate amount of time
was that I wrote a script.
Now I'm not talking
about a Python script.
I'm talking actually
about a physical,
here's a bound
movie or TV script,
where we outlined this
is what was gonna happen
on this particular date.
This is why it was gonna happen
and this where it lines up
with the whole storyline
and so on and so forth.
And we all agreed we were
gonna stick as rigidly
to that script as possible.
And then once we had
that plan in place
we could then go
back and say well,
we can determine what we
need in terms of hardware.
That one got to be a
little bit interesting
and I'll get on to that
again in just a minute.
But one of the main things
that I was going for with this
was realism okay.
The last thing we want
is for people to open up
a forensic image and
for it to be like,
what the crap is this.
This doesn't look real at all.
And I've got a couple
of examples here.
The first one is that
when I was at University
I actually did digital forens...
I was one of the first digital
forensics students in the UK.
Our lecturer for one of our
group projects provided us
with a forensic image
and basically said
go and analyze this,
produce a report,
and you'll get graded
on your report.
Now from what I could tell,
he generated this over the
space of like a week and a half.
On a VM, on a system somewhere,
and it was this really
contrived scenario
where fishing and
anything to do with fish
was completely illegal.
So we had to look up
anything to do with fishing
and produce a report on it.
I find it really hard to
suspend my belief in reality
and so I didn't go along with
what the assignment was at all
instead I went about proving
that he set this person up
with all this fake evidence
because of him installing
VM-ware tools, it being a VM.
Lots of other nice
stuff in the registry
and everything else.
And my final report said
something along the lines of,
this is all fake, this is
a whole bunch of nonsense.
The lecturer very begrudgingly
gave me a very
high mark for that.
So yeah.
We wanna try and keep
things realistic.
Another instance that I
recently became aware of,
and I'm sorry Rob,
was that for the old
scenario in Forensics 500
apparently there
was a team recently
that they dove so
far into the data
that rather than doing
the outlined challenge,
they basically presented
at the end of the class
why Rob Lee had set up
this whole murder-suicide.
The idea is we don't
want that to happen.
We want students to come in,
to do these challenges
and for it to be,
this could actually be
someone's real computer.
This is something we
want to investigate
and get our teeth into.
So that was the plan.
Then we went back and
reevaluated the plan.
And we made a few changes,
because some of it,
while realistic,
was still bordered on
the lines of realism.
There was a few things we
wanted to look at first.
Can we do what we want
to do? Is it possible?
Whenever we put this plan
together in this script
we try to identify certain areas
where it was gonna be difficult.
And we'll get onto
one of those reasons
why it's difficult very soon.
We want it to be realistic.
We want people to actually
see this computer image
and be like wow this
could actually be
a real piece of
evidence in the case.
And then, what could go wrong?
And my first thought
was, nothing.
Nothing could go wrong.
And I was wrong okay.
If you think that nothing
will go wrong, you are wrong.
We moved on to the
implementation stage
and this is where things
really started to go weird.
I don't know if any
of you are familiar
with that particular saying,
man plans and God laughs.
Yeah I got a sense of
that as I was doing this.
So the first thing was,
this challenge revolves
around a single computer.
And so I thought, yes,
this is gonna be easy.
A single computer this
is all I'm gonna need.
Hmm. Well.
I was carrying around
the equivalent of a
small data center.
So we've moved on
from one surface
to a surface and a surface
book and a MacBook Pro.
Two iPhones, two wifi hotspots.
A nook, an android
device, an iPad.
Yeah all these things came
in and there was a few more
but they might give some
things away in the challenge
so I'm not gonna go into them.
This is what was...
This was the hardware
that we needed.
And then aside from
just the hardware
we also had other
things we needed.
So because of the
nature of this scenario
we needed to be able to
use the local high school
and their wifi network.
Now apparently the
school's don't much like
when 40 year old men hang
around outside high schools
(audience laughs)
with cellphones and computers.
At least that's what the police
said when they showed up.
We needed to kind of re-think
that strategy a little bit.
And we'll get on to
that in just a moment.
We wanted to use the
high school's network.
Another thing is that
we needed somewhere
for this person to live and
that's actually my house.
And if you take the challenge
you will have my own
physical address,
feel free to stop by
for a brief visit.
And then one of my friends,
and yes I do have friends,
also kindly offered for
us to use his house too
as a second part
of the scenario.
Don't go visit him, he has
a big dog and guns okay.
So don't go knocking
on his door,
hey I know where you live
because I saw in the show.
No don't do that.
Then we also set up
Microsoft online exchange.
And where we were going
to mimic the school.
So this was interesting.
In order to make things
realistic and believable.
Every single email
that I received from the
high school last year
I basically copy and pasted,
put it into a new email with a
different person's name on it
a made up person,
and then sent it.
You'll see if you
do this challenge
there's kind of a lot of this
realistic stuff going on.
We also needed an office because
if you go into high school
you get homework and you
need to do assignments.
And then another
interesting piece,
is it realistic if
you examine a computer
and there's no purchases made?
Hmm maybe.
But you're gonna expect to
see things like Netflix,
or Hulu, or Spotify or
something like that.
Even games right?
And it's not realistic if
those things aren't found
on that computer.
So we used pre-paid credit cards
and we go out and we'd purchase
these with subject's name,
I'm not sure the entirely
legality of that,
but we'll leave that alone.
And so we did like
Netflix accounts
and we did other things,
we bought other things,
using these pre-paid credit
cards to make it look like
this was actually realistic.
And then finally again because
of the high school issue
I couldn't go and
do that myself.
So I decided I needed
a teenage girl to help.
Apparently the police didn't
like this idea either.
But thankfully I already
had one at my disposal.
My 14-year-old daughter
Kaylee was starting
her freshman year at high
school at the same time
so very very convenient.
And there were some things
I had to give up for this.
I had to empty my
wallet first of all.
And second of all I promised
her she could accompany me
as my guest here and so
she's here today watching.
And this whole--
(clapping)
And so what's really
cool about this is that
this Microsoft surface
which is the subject
of the investigation
in this case
Kaylee she walked around
with that in her high school
backpack for like half
of the school year.
She was connected
to the school wifi.
She was surfing web pages,
using it for artwork.
The only thing
that she didn't do
with kind of ticked
me off a little bit
is that she didn't do the
homework for this person.
So I had to do all
the homework myself.
Don't know why I was
paying her for to be fair.
Another issue that we
had is that early on
this was not the
Stack Challenge.
Those of you who take
SANS classes will know
that there's a running
theme through many of these
and that's the Marvel
universe right.
Originally I thought well
no-one's touched Spider-Man yet.
This will be cool.
We'll have Peter Parker,
and we'll have Gwen,
and we'll have MJ, and
we'll do all these people.
So I set up all these Facebook
accounts for those people.
Then I went onto my
own Facebook account
and said to all my friends,
hey go follow these Facebook
accounts that I've created
so that I can develop
evidence for my scenario.
Yeah well that didn't work
exactly as planned either.
So Facebook around this
time because of the whole
election rigging decided
that they were gonna be
cracking down on fake
Facebook accounts.
And so I went to log in
after a couple of months
of generating data just
to find it had all gone.
So yeah.
Reevaluated and thought yeah
alright let's change this
because you know if you're using
comic book character's
names on social media
Facebook are probably gonna
find them pretty quickly.
Especially if I
go in and announce
the fact that they're
fake accounts too.
Probably didn't help.
We finally got the
whole thing done.
This took about six months
in total to do all this.
Once again realism.
You don't want to just
have a period of two weeks
where data is
generated on a computer
if you want it to be realistic.
It just doesn't work that way.
We got to the end. I
imaged the computer.
And then started to look at
what we did and didn't have.
When we compared the
plan to the results
there were some things which
I'd thought we'd generated
which weren't properly captured.
Now whether that's because
of the type of computer
we were using,
whether it's due to
Windows updates happening,
or something else
I just don't know.
Or delay right,
something made it
so that some of these
things just didn't appear.
We can get on to what
went wrong in a second.
After we decided what went wrong
and what we needed to change
hopefully Rob will ask
me to do this again.
What do we do, what happened?
Well, time is a huge factor.
I have a full time
job with SANS.
I also run my own consultancy
company on the side.
And then I also have my family
and other obligations
I got to deal with.
I would have alarms go
off on my phone saying,
send this text message now,
or do this, send this email.
And you know, if you're
driving in the car somewhere,
and that alarm goes
off it's like oh crap.
We'll put that down and
we'll deal with that later.
So a lot of time the times
were a little bit dicey.
Then there was the,
what we shouldn't have
really done at all
part of this and that is,
you kind of got
this plan in place,
you're following this plan,
and then suddenly Rob was like,
"Oh have you thought
about doing this?"
I'm lik, oh, ah, no.
Ah I guess we'll figure
out a way to put that in.
Yeah, mmm. That wasn't
really the best idea either.
There were times when evidence
was kinda force-created.
We had to change a setting
which someone wouldn't
typically change
inside a Windows system
in order to force
evidence to be generated.
So some of that you
have to kinda suspend
your belief in reality
just a little bit.
This was the major thing for me.
Like I said before,
my home address appears
in that whole scenario,
but there were a few
other things too.
And I've since learned this.
Part of the issue here is,
it's just the way the
scenario was set up.
We had this test computer
on my home network
connecting to wifi
and whatever else.
It could also see other
items on my home network.
Then when I went to
my friend's house
same thing happened
over there too.
It's not major data leakage.
You won't find
inappropriate pictures of me
or anything like that on there.
But there are some things
in there you might think,
huh I wonder if he meant
that to be in there.
No, not really.
So how do we protect
against some of this?
When we went back and
looked at and conducted
this post-mortem the
major thing was network.
You could see things happening.
Because of the
way it was set up,
my home wifi ends up
getting in there too.
So you will see that.
I went and spoke to Phil
Hagen about this a little bit.
And I asked for his
recommendations on things
and after sitting in his class
and him showing how his
home network was set up,
I've gone out now and I've
invested a good chunk of money
in updating my home network.
So now rather than
having everything
on one particular network,
I can say right I'm
creating a VLAN.
And that VLAN will be
specifically for testing
and evidence generation,
all that kind of thing.
Which is wonderful that I
can create a wifi network
which is specific to that VLAN.
That should separate
all of that stuff out.
And it's a great idea.
And if you're
serious about testing
you're gonna need a
set up similar to that.
You can't just run it
off whatever you want
because I guarantee something
you don't want to be
on that image will
end up on that image.
And then we have my Xbox. And
this thing really annoyed me.
Rob suggested we use one of
those pre-paid credit cards
and we download a couple
of games onto this surface.
This surface has
okay graphics support
but it's not like a
gaming system okay.
So we bought a couple of
games on the Windows store
and I let my kids play on
these games for a little bit
but they got kinda frustrated
with it immediately
because the graphics
weren't good enough,
and game lag, it was slow.
So I thought, this
is a good idea,
I'll put this girl's
account on my Xbox
and then they can play
the games on there
'cause like Apple have those
cross-platform games now.
And when I was reviewing the
forensic image of this computer
ahh maybe that wasn't
such a good idea.
At least not on my
own personal Xbox
because now whenever
you look on there
yes you'll see my login
information for Xbox Live.
Feel free to friend me.
We can play games together.
But yeah, was not
my intention at all.
All these things
contributed to...
personally I think this is a
really good piece of evidence,
there's lots of
good stuff in there.
There's only a ti...
I talk about this
like it's a big deal,
it's not, this is a tiny tiny
piece of the overall thing.
It's still a good
great scenario.
And because of the way which
we dealt with everything,
Kaylee walking around with
a laptop for six months,
me generating school
emails and everything else.
To make this realistic
we generated a lot of
background noise for this.
Whenever Rob handed
out this challenge
on the first run of this
people actually thought
this was a real piece
of evidence at times.
Just because of the
quantity of data on there.
I think we actually we made it.
Some of it it seemed like
it was a bit difficult
for us to do but we finally
made it over the finish line.
Now like I said, I don't
know how many people here,
are gonna go out and
produce full pieces
of forensic evidence
a full image of a disc
for testing or whatever else.
And this may be kind of
like a unique circumstance,
but I know there's people here
who teach University classes
who teach SANS classes, who
teach classes in other formats.
This has been a very
valuable experience.
Please don't make the
same mistakes I did.
Whenever you plan,
stick to that plan.
But make sure that
plan is viable.
Don't make things
up that are gonna be
completely unrealistic.
Don't have your person
traveling to another country
if you're not prepared to
travel to another country.
If you start going back and
messing around with data
after you've already
generated it people will know.
People who take these
classes are not stupid okay.
They're smart people who
probably work in this field
for a long time.
If you start going in
and changing things
you will leave
footprints every where.
You know, USB history,
log files, time stamps.
Whatever it is you change,
people will find out and it
will detract from that realism.
So that's my plea to you.
If you're gonna
generate evidence
make sure you generate the
appropriate amount of evidence
whatever it is
that you wanna do.
If you choose to go down the
whole, complete image route,
be prepared to
invest a lot of time,
a lot of money and
a lot of thought
into how you're going
to accomplish it.
When you do that, guarantee,
you'll be a lot better off.
And you're test evidence will
look absolutely spectacular.
So that's all I've got.
(applause)