uh during this talk we're gonna talk
and explore falco in particular we're
gonna
we're gonna see what's happening uh in
our system and now
falco uh traces everything's from the
kernels upwards to provide us the last
line of defense
especially in cloud native security
contexts i don't know maybe how familiar
you are with kubernetes containers that
kind of that today we
have fun with but basically that's the
landscape that file
falco targets so ends up who already
knows who
what falco is here no one okay i can go
away bye-bye
anyway if you want to know more you can
go on github falco security slash falco
falco
and spain so what falco is so maybe you
can take a look after
the tour to our guitar so briefly before
to really start
a bit of history falco was created in
by ces league as an open source project
from day one i don't know why since they
did it i don't know why she pays me a
salary
but this is life i mean and since the
beginning
the focus of falco has been to pass
liberty speed events
libsyn's p events are uh basically
events from this libra library libsyns
which is another open source library
from uh cisco from sisdig that
handle cisco's proc file system
information metadata from containers
from orchestrators like mesosphere
kubernetes and things like that
anyway the scope of falco is to track
everything's happening
in at lowest level of your system and
match
these signals with security policies and
i think eventually and hopefully fire
alert two years later
2018 falco was donated to cncf the cloud
native computing foundation is a branch
of the linux foundation
and falc has been the first ever uh
sandbox
project in the security uh topic uh it
started to gain some re
some really serious traction to the
point that me and the other three
maintainers had to
basically start a boring weekly
community call to which by the way i
invite anyone to participate
on wednesday 5 pm italian time
so past january falco has been
officially
incubated by the cncf uh
branch of the linux foundation and we
don't know where
we'll we'll end up with this we'll see
when mai my name is leonardo donato
i'm an open source software engineer
assistant where my daily job as
i probably already imagined now is to
code falco
evolve it and maintain it in case you're
wondering yes
i spend all day on github because i mean
that's there there is the source code so
basically my workflow is github and
kernel so
let's see it uh if there's a photo of me
that i use usually in talk
in talks when i go in usa
states and other parts of the world i
suppose i imagine i should have
removed the caption here about italian
and gestures because
i see that these jokes does not work
really well in italy
so you can usually find me on twitter
github
usually the webverse with leo did the
nickname feel free to
follow me send me direct messages
whatever i like to socialize we can talk
about everything about bpf kernel linux
and security so the plans for the next
30 40 minutes are to look at beautiful
photos of
our country when it does not rain like
today and
uh to get the skin you know falco tries
to solve the runtime security problem by
uh even for cloud native runtime cloud
native environments by
basically tracing all these c schools
happening at the kernel level so
this talk is played in three parts first
of all
we reason about the runtime security the
concept of random security
in modern contexts in cloud native
contexts
uh that for which for which fog is made
for
so then we'll focus on how to secure
all these environments by tracing
the linux kernel why and now to make
cisco's coming from linux kernel
with container metadata container
other information grabbed from container
and time apis
kubernetes audit logs and so on we'll
see how falco
engine then asserts rules as a rule
language or rule engine that has
that is easy to assert those rules that
define policies
against the events that we collected and
finally we'll try to have some fun
about some cities on kubernetes and some
other
detections that i will demo
so what does security mean to me
how to characterize the security concept
i don't know you but
i personally don't want anything
happening in my system without me even
noticing
it i want to control things that can
happen and things that cannot at least
in this context
and since preemptive control is not
always possible and we know this
i also need deep visibility
into my system to be able to know as
soon as possible
what just happened basically i think of
security in terms of
two words prevention and detection what
did you worship in comma
someone wants to reply i don't think so
policies both concepts use some kind of
policies right
uh to describe the allowed or disallowed
behavior for a process in the linux
context
in terms of system calls their arguments
and asterisks is
assessed the difference are that the
first word
prevention is about
is connected to the concept of
enforcement do not allow some actions
of from some persons to happen at all
because of some policies tools in this
category usually
change the behavioral process by
preventing system calls to
even happen while tools
in the other category paul the policy
concept in the other category
is a bit different the concept there is
to
define some policies to monitor the
behavior
of processes and be notified when they
steps outside so that you can take
countermeasures
then so we also can think about security
in terms of this uh i will not say the
economy
because they are the same phase of a
medal
but we can also describe security
uh looking at these two aspects in terms
of enforcement
and not versus auditing
not versus is important i will explain
now why i think so
some example anyway of enforcement tools
are secamp
second bpf c linux hypermore
even the authorization mechanism like
kubernetes rules based assess control or
the policy based
admission plugins that we have in
kubernetes fits this category
since they will prevent something to
happen on your cluster
depending on some policy while tools
like odd and falco itself
belong to the other side the auditing
side of the security topic
a topic that especially in cloud native
in modern contexts
has not been solved there's a lot really
a lot to do but
now can falco solved
all our security concerns in these
contexts
i have to be honest not at all i mean
software is made of layers like these
image shows
and so it's security so and this is even
more true in cloud native environments
nowadays
as you can see this came here i drew in
the slide
these are environments that embrace
changes as as they're constant as the
fundamental part opening to those to a
lot of possibility but also to a lot of
unknowns
i mean you have orchestrators that
brings down
pods with services brings up others on
others know
different nodes differ with different
maybe also
adaptive uh limit and resources so it's
change everything changes here
constantly
and the simple rule of the world is that
sometimes like this year for example
unexpected unexpected things i will not
say shitty things but unexpected things
happen and i mean
world have you ever expected in the
pandemic to be to
assist to an in-person conference i
would not
have expected so unexpected things
happen
and anyway we have to respond uh to
those event in a timely and
accurate way so farco is here to
enable us to detect intrusions
malicious behaviors generally security
threats
at runtime but let also me
be clear about
this fact that security is made of layer
and
we i'm not suggesting to use talk as a
solution
for everything i already talked with
someone
some people here that were yesterday
dinner about this concert stress people
about this concept
we need to use prevention tools
and detection tools together in a
layered fashion for example we have to
implement what's called a defense in
depth strategy defense in depth term
is a term that derives since your room
from a late roman
military strategy that was a bit
different from the
software concept that concept was about
intentionally setting ground to organ
reorganize and then counter attack the
opponents
and because they had not all the
strength to
govern all the borders all these attacks
surfaced
in computer science defense in depth
means that
just means that at every level every
degree
you have to use a technique
a combined techniques of prevention and
techniques of detection
maybe creating a feedback loop
that continuously uh monitor and
continues improve the detect
the security posture of your
environments for example
let's me let's make a concrete example
you could use falco and there are
companies that do this is also very big
companies like like shopify they use
falco and they find policies on farco to
detect
a very strict set
of policies they're interested in and
every time they
find that somehow someone inside someone
outside
uh stepped outside of those policies
they immediately have a team that
creates a farmer profiles
for the containers and the kind of
explode that have been found so they
basically
continuously day by day week by week
improve the security posture
they have on their clusters and they in
their flight machine i mean their
machine is very
their fleet is very big it's like 300
servers so
so what's runtime security in the
context i've just described
runtime security can be seen last like
the last line of defense let's try with
the metaphor
she was kelly look how beautiful she was
my little dog
uh i have a lot locks on my door and
those and allen
think of these like compliance rules
but she alerted me when things were not
going right
policy violations when little bro
was misbehaving with my mama think of
him like
compromising inside there is still is
very very big compromise inside
my house or if there's something
suspicious
happening outside the nearby anomalies
zero days
so she detected runtime anomalies in my
life at home
and she was may she rest in peace very
serious about her job i mean look at
the photo she was very very serious so
while prevention is about locking
the doors detection is about
continuously monitoring
the inside and the perimeter
the full unique way to do this is by as
said
tracing and detecting everything
happening
inside the box from the bot on the
kernel up
instead of using the usual top down and
side cars approach
like other security monitoring solutions
and engines do nowadays
but how that's possible
how to i mean okay we trace cisco's
other shoes and then
then we need an engine that's able to
create a mechanism to match what we
found by tracing the syscalls
to what we described with the policies
so we need basically a language and an
engine that's able to after a parser an
engine that's able to
pass this to towards the data set of
signals and events coming from the
kernel plus
signals and events coming from container
and times container metadata
kubernetes audit logs and so on
okay so maybe
someone at this point could argue why
tracing the c score why going so lower
in the stack
well nowadays the production
environments are filled with i said with
so many pads
so many services side cars containers
monitor tools things change
every like 10 10 seconds and i try to
draw
an abstraction diagram here on the right
side
don't criticize my designer
skills and this basically exemplifies
the
today's typical production environments
it turns out that exactly this
complexity the one that i tried to
abstract here
and the one that was some slides ago in
the
layered environments is the exact reason
we
should go look under the hoods if you
think about i mean
in the end whatever program we are here
at whatever point in the stack
disregarding the language is written
were c sharp
whatever c c plus plus javascript
no with node.js with some other
javascript engine roof
who knows whatever whatever the language
whatever the cisco
wrapper it's it uses it can be
uh it can use muzzle it can use lmc it
can use whatever
and in the end it will run uh it will
making will end up making a lot of
cisco's
in the kernel a big this because at
least for linux the system calls
uh only not not no honestly not only
there are other
little things but are the principal
mechanism
to basically tell the machine
to do things on the hardware to do real
things
and so whether the task regards
networking i o
processes so this does not matter uh
at all so that's instead of looking at
every layer here
putting a sidecar in every pod in every
system that
our clients says we just grew under the
look under dude under the table and we
don't give a
sorry for what the about what's
happening above us
but to do this a set of unique
challenges
arises honestly uh i said cisco are
basically the api that abstracts
the hardware for us and they are very
powerful mechanism
but not very much from my user's user
space perspective
this because to bring a cisco there's a
separation between camera space and use
space to bring us c schools happening
to use the space for example you have to
do another cisco
guess what you have to do if you want to
know the time and event is happening
i mean time in security i think it's
very important guess what
another c school except for the very
braves playing with air dtsc
things like that but that's another
topic that's a world completely
different story
also there are a very a lot of c schools
and
with every kernel release they can
change and they do
they can gain new parameters they can
gain deprecations new cisco's can be
introduced
and things like that so it can be really
really
painful to keep falcon track
but we can do we can't do otherwise i
mean otherwise the next talk title will
be
how simple is to bypass falco using new
sea schools
and that's by the way the talk that i
will give you rubicon america in
december so please
join me come look at my fast falcom i
too
so um
furthermore as we said we need to com to
combine
this huge flow of kernel events we are
obtaining tracing cisco's with data
from other various tools that are very
common in today's
very complex setup this because
cisco's are the main interface towards
the kernel
and the hardware that it abstracts but
cisco salon will not be enough
and we all know this will not be enough
to create a software that deals with
runtime security in real time
we want to connect these kernel events
that we are grabbing from there with
kubernetes metadata
or with data from the container on time
with
all the logs from other k other
other source of information for example
if you need if you use
falco to monitor your
aws something a wsck yes cluster or
whatever
you may want to combine
the ciscos that are happening on the
actual nodes
with cloud trails audit logs so
to basically combine together more
informations and gain more visibility
more
actionable insights but
there's another issue here cisco's are
very very
fast and performance they happen at a
rate that's completely different
to the rate of docker demo container the
api
things that we need to go look to gain
these other actionable insights
which are by the way is ways lower uh of
the cisco
so there's the i did another
another difficult point here was to
basically
create a way for falco to asynchronously
process every kind of information coming
from kubernetes container metadata
or other sources in a secret way and
reconcile the data later
with the cisco's information so to know
that
at the end the result
was and this that you know the container
id the container name or the kubernetes
node name the kubernetes part where
that c schools for for example mounting
a tcr etcos
and dumping a lot of data inside
basically dosing
the nodes of your cluster was done so
that way you would be able to know
exactly the container that was exploited
the container where the
shell was spawned and you can do some
kind of forensics
or past that analysis
or in real time if if you attach the
falco alerts because
falco alerts can fire alerts via syslog
by a grpc
in various other ways you can attach to
that
other tools to then do something
automatically to for example
eradicate that container block that that
zone of the cluster
and things like that always in the logic
that i told before
to integrate the prevention and the
detection phase
so this is in summary what the falco
drivers do
and we are going to dive a bit into this
right now
let me ask you a question uh how to get
cisco to user space
and use them as one of the falco
inputs i mean the first thing that the
first option that came to
my to our mind was to write a current
module
good luck with that really good luck i
will not have
that ever participated in it
i mean doing a kernel model comes with a
lot of downsides
above on the development side named
kernel panics
like two or three times two or three
times a day
and the deployment want to
for example imagine that you you
ship a new version of falco and a new
version of the
kernel module input and you need to
contact people that's using falco maybe
with the triad inflate
300 machines fleet and say well you just
need to update
your 300 dos just write a script and
update all you
all the kernels there and maybe you also
need to tell them you also need to
compile the camera model for because you
have that camera really
released blah blah blah so i mean it's
not always
suitable like as a solution
also because in some environments like
banks
canada module season is not trust okay
loading camera mod is
not not allowed usually an alternative
so we need an alternative and we
said we told okay what's alternative now
we started investigating and we found
okay that's
this magic this new cool kit technology
called dbpf
does anyone know what the bpf is here
no one good pretty good i'm the only one
knowing
linux here i'm joking evpf is a new
technology
really new is 2014. honestly it was
created in 1992
but it was limited to
packet to packet tracing
at that that time then it was extended
by alex say
in 2013 2014
to basically create a technology to make
us able to code the kernel without
risking
to panic it and without
risking to expose holes or
safety issues in the end it's
this because in the kernel has been
created a virtual machine
which uh puts likes on safety and
security
a virtual machine that when
receives the bpf code which is just a
set of
restricted c statically analyzes it
and then just in time compiles it for
performance reasons
and uh does some optimization and while
verifying it the code that it receives
before executing it
it verifies that for example there are
no new point or the references
that there are not unbounded loops you
cannot iterate so it's not turing
complete
bpf and things like that
so to avoid it happens and it happened
to me
personally that the avpf virtual machine
which is which should be safe and it's
advertised to be extremely safe
in reality it is uh can expose some bugs
uh that make it makes it makes it no not
that secure anymore but that's another
thing i mean that's something that will
be happening in our field
so uh i should not spend other event 20
minutes talking about the bpf otherwise
giovanni will
will kill me but maybe that's the topic
for another talk
uh okay in case we maybe
uh even last thing on the bpf a bpf
is uh performs expose the same
performances of the kernel module
uh there there is just a bit of lower
red but in the
five percent so it's not it's something
very
and it's only usable on newer linux
kernel i mean
4.4 but we suggest 4.14
4.16 so if you have a fleet with the
of centos machines with 3.10 something
kernels you need to use kernel model if
you can't
we there are other ways to input things
to falco we are working on
one it's pdig but it has been made for
other kind of
services it has been made for things
like managed kubernetes services for
example when you go on your cloud
provider
and you install things
uh a kubernetes that because you don't
want to manage and handle
kubernetes installation and i feel you i
mean in that case
uh but usually for example on amw as far
gate
you have no access at all to the last
machine
so you cannot install an bpf probe
neither a current module
no and so we created pdig pdig basically
it's a ptrace based
producer that runs completely in user
space so you don't need the kernel that
leads runs completely into space and
looks
the kernels happen in the the ciscos
happening the kernel with the ptrees and
magic with the
assembly trampolines it's very hackish
very very active uh slower really slower
than the other two methods but i mean if
you have no other options
this way you can you could still install
falco
with pdig and monitor your aws target
clusters
because i mean who knows what happens
maybe you have compromised
insiders maybe would you trust your
cloud providers to be able to
uh active to timely respond to any zero
day or an anomaly or cv
that happens i will not so you need to
monitor things
okay here's there's a diagram describing
in a bit more detail how falco works
when using the kernel module
as an input driver as you can see
there's the separation i was talking
about before between the kernel space
and the user space
in the current spaces where the kernel
module leaves
at the upper boundary of the user space
there's falc on top of a two other
libraries which are the very important
libraries that we do
extensive use libsyns and libs gap
the camera module attaches to the start
of execution of every cisco of every
cisco that we track in the current and
also to the end of every cisco's to grab
the argument the start and post
execution uh with a mechanism we call
fillers then the kernel modules
basically
augments makes the arguments of the
cisco human readable somehow
and finally it also grabs contextual
information from the operating system
and for example from the proc file
system
on linux and finally
puts all this information in a ring
buffer well it
it actually does not put things in the
ring buffer it
puts in ring buffer only uh
the memory pointer so basically shading
that part of memory for
performances reasons but what's a ring
buffer
a wiring buffer that's a vital part of
falco
a ring buffer is an elegant circular
data structure with a fixed size
eight megabytes in case of falco acting
as a first thing for start queue
it's very important because saving
millions of ciscos
per second and having to process pass
them a match against a set of rules puts
a really hard requirements on
performances
and this was for us the only way uh
for falco to be effective because we
don't need to shuffle memory around when
other events come in we
with ring buffer things just circle and
you just
get last one so you don't need to move
memory to do copies and to do things
like that that are very very
time consuming and
uh when this is when you use the kernel
module
basically the concrete implementation of
the ring buffers there's one for cpu
will be created like a dev devices
so you will if you have eight uh cpu
you will have that falcon zero the falco
one the falcon 7
and that would be the concrete
implementation uh of the
this mechanism uh
mechanism between the kernel and user
space that we use
once we have data in user space
which are grabbed through libs gap uh
libsys printers the games and does that
thing
of reconciling these ciscos with the
other contextual information about the
context where they happen for example
grabbing the container id the container
name
the container image name maybe you have
maybe someone created an executable in a
container
you want to know which image has been
uh which image has lost
its immutability and things like that
and then it everything comes to falcos
there's the engine for the language and
the policy matching
then i said companies uh they want to
use to or write to you hey falco
seems very
very very cool but we we cannot
allow to insert the kernel module
because
blah blah blah i mean i gave reasons to
do
to disallow this session of kernel
module and
after a bit time we say them well we got
you no worries
uh you can have the same exactly
functionality use this
using this new curved technology bpf
[Music]
uh since we built an ebpf probe too in
this case
as diagram shows there is no ring buffer
involved because the bpf virtual machine
does not allow you to move memory
between the kernel and the user space
and for reasons i mean its purpose to be
very safe would
have been complete garbage if they would
have allowed that
anyway luckily a bpf
has this feature very very cool called
maps as you can see in the diagram here
basically the maps are the vital part of
the falcor
architecture in this case in this use
case here we have
a library lipscope that's responsible
basically to get the health
of the company bpf source code
parse it past the ebp of map sections
that he found said pass the road trace
point
that we put on cisco's the normal
transponders that we put on cisco's
the other things that we do you probes
and things like that to
grab other informations and mount
everything with the everything of this
in the kernel in the bpf virtual machine
and
so let the bpf probe of farco
run when this is running
uh libscop also receives from the map
that he created
data through the bpf maps
and this data will flow to libsys that
against us
the the same game of before so
reconciling this data
with kubernetes data container metadata
containment data
it took a while for us to reach this
point but on
the top level of the diagrams that we
we've seen right now there was falco
with
the icon of falco and what
what remains of falco is just very
simple
continuous loop that reads those events
uh by calling the next method of
validity perspective instance
and outputs alert about security threats
you declared with falco rules
when its engine finds a match i mean i
removed a bit of code here but this is
what basically all falco does it's very
very simple
and all the magic is clearly in the bpf
probe or in the kernel model probe
here there's a bit of magic with engine
with
with the language but nothing really
cool
as the other two things notice also that
the falco rules language as
uh as we will see very soon uh
operators and filters provided by libsys
which is part of falco implementing
for the filtering mechanism
of those events so maybe asking yourself
now maybe i bored you so much okay leo
but what
how do we define policies go straight to
the point how would do we describe
what is a security threat for us
and answer is pretty straightforward
with the falcorus language
the falcon rules language is also very
simple it's a yamon subset
and this is this is make it very very
easy to learn and very hard to indent
correctly but that's
yummerfold not my fault sorry and
and no love because i love always
sorry and unlike other policy languages
where basically i don't know if you ever
tried to write uh
a ceiling policy apartment things like
that yama is
very simple the only defect is the
indenting of the example but it's very
very simple to
to to learn you can write conditions
you can group conditions into macros to
later reuse them
you can write lists to have more easier
comparisons in conditions you can give
names to rules you can even
customize the output data rule when
files
will give you uh customizing the output
field that you want maybe you don't want
the continuity you just want to continue
you can change you can change it it's
very very
simple and very very soon we're working
on
also another thing that's accepted for
rules because in some environments maybe
you want to you don't want fire alerts
for something that
you know that can be an issue
but it's it's an issue that you can
allow and so we are working also on
exceptions for for rules
what else we have a very very big
default rule set
uh i don't remember how many rules are
and now but it's a huge file there are
like five
uh yaml files one for
i mean linux security another for
applications like databases things like
that
you can find them over in the rules
directory of the
falco repository go there grab them try
them
but other things that
i mean there are a lot of rules we could
not spend we will need a week
to to look at every every rule that we
provide
but two things two rules humongous two
things that uh
i would it's worth mentioning in my
opinion right now
is this poland macro that's a macro that
you can use to
briefly in a pretty straightforward way
create rules to detect
when someone spawned the shell in your
containers
in your environments whatever or the
cloud metadata from container
basically a very common pattern in cloud
native contacts
is to abuse the
the container metadata server to
grab some credentials and secrets and
that link put a rule that's used
by falco users to detect when someone is
using
this uh mechanism this approach to
exfiltrates
credentials uh tokens from the
the cluster and so on
let this is let's now see
this this is another example of another
abnormal activity detected by falco
i'm referring to a very very common
remote code execution use case
called container drift this means that
in some way someone changed things
in the container image changing the
immutability of the control images i was
saying
before a subset
of such changes are executables
creating uh in a container at runtime
detecting such behavior can help can
really help flag
critical security issues related to
remote code execution
so as you can see this slide here with
the final rule to fire
an alert with when a new file
is created in a container with
execution permissions and
we use the ease open exec filter of
libsys that falco provides us
but i recorded a demo on ascii cinema i
don't know
if i can click here and try to
[Music]
let me try if i found the mouse i don't
know where okay
nope come here
okay let's take a look
okay for the sake of simplicity i
already created the
the rule set containing all only the
this rule
to detect container drift as you can see
the same that they put in the slide
there are some macros to the to
basically exclude
docker and run c container on time from
uh throwing this art because we know
that we are using docker and
basically we are using this open exec
and even type dividend of cisco is open
open at create
we are in a container and not and this
action was not done
by rancie or by docker
so basically we now
start falco with dash air giving this
yamal to falco falco starts
and now we will try to run a container
maybe an alpine and a boot i don't
remember what i ran here
and we try to write in the container
with the tool chain of the container
that
exists in the container this is a reason
why you should never put two chains in
containers
in production thank you very much
and basically
we we will try to now
create a malicious little c file
compile it and execute it and we will
see if falco is able to detect it
on time or not
i don't remember if okay basically we
are creating here
uh we are doing a cisco a creative
school
and on a file called blabla
we compile it and we execute and filter
the text that basically someone
in the container created uh executed a
command addatta
with with a file creating a file blah
blah that's
a new executable and you're done
so seems to work function i don't know
now i don't know how to come back to
farco here
if i found a mouse
it's on the right
yes yes yes yes
okay but okay
let's move on can i come back to this
one
okay let's move on
so
bad things can happen right for example
recently kubernetes
cv has been found and it affected
a lot of kubernetes versions
i mean we all agree that detecting
exploitation attempts
of this vulnerability is critical right
dcv
is was a bit critical because it was a
server-side request forgery
in a in the kuber controller manager
basically allowing certain users to leak
up to 500 bytes of
arbitrary information from unprotected
endpoint
within the master's host network such as
loopback services
this can be caused by an attacker with
permission to create a pod
or a storage class
with certain volume types to
cause the kubercontrol manager to
execute some get or pass frequencies
uh from the masters of us network which
means you can grab credentials
and things like that the good news is
that
with falco and uh
[Music]
language that that guy was loving so
much
it's very easy to write rules to detect
this
and some at least detect this then the
mitigation can be
done with other tools but to detect this
basically
you have to write a condition like this
we are a kubernetes event we are in a
pod in a creation phase
that's going on with sas system
and there's one of the
that the affected volume in the pod and
that's
the macro affected volumizing pod that
basically
lists scalar you could buy glass refresh
that where
the volume providers uh affected
so basically this way you
detected half of that cd and in the
other
the other way the the other part of the
cd was about
not part but storage class so again we
are writing a condition
that says okay is this a key ft a
kubernetes event and
a storage glass as is being created
successfully with one of the affected
storage processes that's just a list
and a macro that uses the in operator
because farkas all these operators
pre-match
in contains things like that it's a
language and
so this way you can like in
zero time if you have falco on your
kubernetes cluster
detect if someone is using
that cd on your cluster
we should probably move forward and know
how much time i have
but and probably i'm starting i mean
i'm hungry so we should so we should go
with something now
but nevertheless for the very bravest
interesting learning more about falco
the importance of runtime
detection even in environments like
kubernetes
and containers that should theoretically
provide better resolution i mean at
least this is how they advertise
containers kubernetes isolation
theoretically in reality
there's a lot of fun out there i put
here
two pointers that i consider worth to
to take a look at they are two very very
recent
cds that have been discovered yes
against kubernetes cluster
the one on the left on july that one
is like one week 10 days ago
so the one on the right is a
the one on the left is about exploiting
a bag
in the kubernetes cubelet that was
basically uh not considering uh
in a completely correct way uh the pods
mounting atc us so basically letting
the attacker mounting ethicios in some
cases
and putting a lot of data in like a lot
of data i mean one megabyte two
megabytes and it is
atc us file basically dosing
your nodes with just that so basically
create a pod that mounts a tcs
and puts a lot of data inside it is us
the first things that he does when iran
when it runs it will bring your nodes
it will dust your nodes like the nail
service so
it's a medium severity one
and i put the link there there's a link
on how to
detect it with falco and mitigate it
with the apartment profiles
as soon as detected on the right side
of the of this slide there is the other
cv
the very recent one that was discovered
in reality was used on kubernetes what
was discovered
has been discovered in the packet socket
facility of the linux kernel
it affects all the linux kernel greater
than 4.6
so a lot of versions since we are today
to 5.85
5.9 and basically it affects all major
distributions of linux
it can be used to gain root assets from
unprivileged local process
so also from continents and pods this is
why they use
it on kubernetes it allows a bad doctor
to trigger memory corruption that can be
used and exploited to hijack data
resources and the most severe cases take
complete control
of your system of your machines so i
would
consider to go read this if you have
like 10 minutes
of spare time because it's very very
funny
let's say this way as promised
at the end the year in the slide i put a
bit of resources for those interesting
maybe in
learning more about btf this technology
that we use to
trace all the everything happening in
the linux kernel
i did a podcast for google about a bpf
you can find
it at the first link or you can read the
book from michael league about
bpf florence fontana are
if you're just interested in looking at
the ring buffer implementation or the
fillers to
make the cisco's data human readable
just go there for people that loves yaml
they can click to the last link
falcon default rule set so they can look
at like ten thousand lines of yammer
so that's it if you have any questions
please feel free to
throw questions with me uh otherwise uh
you can find me on the kubernetes lock
on the falco's lock or the cncf slack
i'm ludido
uh everywhere feel free to contact me
being me over twitter follow me asking
questions
thanks to everyone
you