okay
so
no chit chat we're gonna we're gonna
begin
our round table and
so the
let's say again uh the round table is
the challenges for cyber security
conferences part two
we
have met here
exactly one year ago exactly same set of
people
at phd stem to discuss pretty much the
same problems but back in the day
they were
new for us we all we all struggled we
all found a way to get over our
struggles and now i want to
get like postmortem of what have we
learned have you learned anything
actually or not but i would like to
start with the introduction because it
one year later we figured out that there
is no still there is no bio on the
website uh so it's good to have
in recording the introduction of each
one of you i think i will start with
igor
okay now my name is igor lukic i i live
in spain i have a congress conference
called hakron
and my background is as i think like 99
we start when we're kids
get in the underground space whatever
get in trouble
and learn about technology learn about
the hacking scene get around meet people
thanks to the conferences like this
and
my background just pushed me to to make
my own conference
and
i don't know just get into the
geek space and
and die there
because it's once you get in there's no
way out i think so that's my background
then the first
on the screen is asim
hey everyone i'm
assim jacker i'm the co-founder of a
cyber security company called biato
we have three pillars in the company one
of them is conferencing where we
organize two cyber security conferences
nulcon and hardware.io
the other one is consulting where we do
security assessments for iot embedded
cloud and yada yada and the third one
which i look after is the
products so we are working on two
cyber security products one is
uh geared towards automation for
security assessment of iot products
and the other one is
scaling up first testing
for
native and managed code applications
dylan
ah
hey guys dylan here founder of hack in
the box i think i'm probably one of the
oldest people on this panel
so i feel very honored that they still
call the old man back to share his
thoughts
but um
basically my history is that i've been
running this hanging box thing for like
22 years something like that
it's my day job it's essentially all we
do so we run conferences around the
world we're in amsterdam we're in uae
we're in singapore
we don't do consultancy
[Music]
we just run competitors we have a good
time uh we run ctfs yeah if you guys
like playing ctfs then you probably
played one of ours as well or you should
uh other than that
[Music]
yeah i mean i started hanging such a
long time ago that you know it was days
when when the modem was something that
people actually knew what it was right
and now yeah nobody knows what happened
coffee and
yeah yeah i do other other things than
than than hanging above stuff but yeah
on occasion i still run a conference
uh well then i will say that i'm the
youngest from all of you
uh my name is timor yunusov i'm one of
the organizers of positive hug days and
i'm also
the organizer and the founder of the
payment village
so
surprisingly i've been at each one of
your conferences over the last 12 months
i didn't do this on purpose but
life life needs to
keep rolling right
uh
and since our last talk we all you you
guys all had at least one conference
and the
my first question is obviously
we were chatting a year ago hey we're
gonna have this we're gonna have that
we're gonna have to rebuild this redo
that reconsider blah blah blah
what actually happened
in this 12 months
what was the biggest struggle for you
what was like major accident that you
had to go through as an organizer as a
speaker as a participant of any other
conferences
what has happened
who starts you do okay
well i think the the worst thing is
still to figure out the covet situation
that's that's always called kobit you
know this thing that for the conferences
it makes everything seem crazy because
in the other hand yes we can have people
then
in my case
they were constantly changing
rules
like that the government was like okay
you can have a conference the last one
we did
back in in february in march sorry
and and we were like okay can we have
people yes you can
two weeks later no you cannot have
and and that thing at least in my
situation is the worst because you
cannot plan accordingly uh there's so
many things you have to do physically if
they're public
indoors it changes the complete
background if it's hybrid
it's another challenge
but in my case it was again online
so this didn't change a lot i had to go
back to the same thing you learn some
from the mistakes but others you keep
making them
like the bandwidth thing we had an issue
with the bandwidth the worst thing we
had keynote speaker in the middle live
because we do it live which is a mistake
by my
why should we do it live there's so many
mistakes can go wrong
so just pre record it it's the same
experience and you can even edit it and
make it like a netflix remember deal on
hack flicks that we said that kind of
stuff like make it more immersive but we
i still made the same mistake like just
to what whatever
it disconnected yeah we had a keynote
speaker in the middle
the the router just went crazy and we
had this delay i don't know a minute and
a half
the stream went down but no one still
was watching that yeah no no we were we
had to we had and then you get crazy and
you have to back online everything
freaks out
and and i think my biggest mistake or
fear
is to do it live
that's why we do every single recording
just let you know
oh yeah live live is a big challenge yep
guys
yes all right dylan you won't go first
oh yeah sure uh yeah i mean life is a
challenge life is a challenge
[Laughter]
but yeah i mean
you know i mean
for us we were kind of lucky because
um well we have three conferences right
so
over the last two years everything was
online but at the end of last year the
kobe situation in uae was improving
enough that we could
somehow another
pull off an in-person event
it was by no means easy because uh as
like you know pointed out the
the government rulings logistics all
those things are constantly evolving
from day to day it's in
what's okay today it's not okay tomorrow
and then day after that it's okay again
you know so stuff like that makes it
extremely difficult um
but we took all the learnings that we
did over the last two years so you know
because we were doing everything
virtually for two years we we have our
own streaming platform we have our i
mean our video streaming team is like
super locked in we have a very strong av
team
uh we know what what works what doesn't
in terms of like remote audience
participation how to do the q a with
like live
uh we had a uh normally we have a
virtual studio everything is
pre-recorded by the way we don't do live
talks when it's virtual conference um
for the exact reason that it becomes
problematic occasionally we do do it
live only when the time zone is suitable
for the speaker other than that as in
the speakers in the same time zone when
the conference is happening fine you
want to present it live because internet
latency is probably not going to be a
big deal if you're local but if you're
in the u.s and you're trying to speak in
asia or something like number one it's
going to be ridiculous for you to stay
up it'll be like four o'clock in the
morning and like why would i put you
through that right i just recorded it
bro you want your best presentation not
because you're alive so what you're not
here so we never bother with like you
know getting too caught up with like
whether it's live not live whatever but
you know we took some of our learning
from the last two years about what works
what doesn't which parts you can stream
which parts uh don't work in streaming
um and we took our virtual studio and
made it into a physical studio that was
centerpiece within the exhibition we did
virtualize silent stages so everybody
stays in one room so there's all the
contact tracing is in one space
i mean there's lots of small things but
would we need to do it after this
maybe not after a year
i would say at most we're gonna do
this kind of like you know physical
distance kind of thing it's just overall
people's comfort
but in different countries people have
different level of comfort you know i
mean in asia we were just talking about
it before the session started that like
here people are complying they wear mars
blah blah
in europe like in skipper you don't in
the airport yeah in shipboard which is
to me it's like oh that's crazy like in
the airport which is an indoor building
with air conditioning with so many
people you don't need to wear a mask
it's not mandated i'm not like
different risk right i mean it's how
you're gonna weigh it but um yeah it's
been interesting it's been an
interesting two years but i'm more
looking forward to what's ahead i always
look ahead so
i'm excited to kind of like see
how conferences will change because they
have to uh the simple reason is that
what was last time was oversaturated
right i mean there's too many
conferences the experience is all the
same it's like doesn't matter you got a
black hat defcon why what the hell it's
the same thing
why
right i i've now because i haven't
traveled for two years i've gotten so
used to staying at home right like that
i i feel like the inclination to make me
go to an event needs to be like
something
above and beyond it cannot just be like
yeah you're gonna see some talks like so
what
some new zero day yeah bro get in mine
zero days every day to watch online
just just
read read the white paper
yeah read the white paper you know what
i mean i do like you don't need to see
on stage you're not going to see banabi
jack level kind of things anymore people
have stopped doing that man they
probably are no more excited yeah people
grew up there's no more exciting talks
right people come and they have some
cool name but the cool name is not going
to wait for the conference for them to
drop the presentation because
it's a business they need to make money
from the exploit from the whatever the
hell they found the white paper or
methodology whatever they release it now
not wait for the conference they might
talk about it at the conference and
recap but they would have already
released the white paper in advance
there's no excitement you know what i
mean a lot of the times even the big
presentations i will explain why why
there is no excitement because technical
people
struggle with deliver
content really well we are not actors we
we not we're not gonna ever present
things in vegas in oh wait a second we
actually have uh
because
it's rather easier to go and read white
paper to understand what's going on or
read an article from a well-known
journalist that will be able to put
things in a narrative
than to sit and listen uh so i was at
newcom berlin a few months ago
and i seem i will let you talk about
that just like in a minute
but
i i
i sit there
and i see
all these people that doing amazing
technical stuff i will never be able to
do in my life but they struggle to
deliver the idea they struggle to keep
the audience engaged even in 45 minutes
slot i understand that the current
teenagers have a 15 minute span of
attention but still you you can you can
create an amazing story there were guys
from korea i believe who was sharing the
story how to hack metaverse uh setups
like different metaverse pieces of
hardware software in the end what i've
realized metavirus is just normal web
application
to be honest yeah but but but but the
story would be amazing and they were
like obviously they were not their
native speakers english was not a native
language but it's still it's so bad yeah
like and and that's why
again there is no point coming spending
all money to sit there and listen on
this mumbling and jumbling if you can go
and read the paper or or read the
article or
like
listen it in recording at least if you
want to hear the original original is
always good because it's much better to
get the knowledge of the actual author
or the research but just watch it in
video yeah
i mean i would say that only sorry to
kind of assume before he gets started i
would say the only reason right to go is
not so much to listen to the talk but is
to meet the author
to meet the presenter
that is something that you cannot do
from the white paper and usually the
email address will bounce or some
or they just never read it so
if you
you go to the conference to meet the
presenter you don't go to the conference
to listen to the presentation
that's the thing that people have
forgotten about it's like nobody's not
flying about the paper bro
right i want to know what this guy is
working on okay well meet and then what
ask ask ask for a signature
question
maybe she has some exploits that i need
to buy from you i want to sell to you or
whatever the hell it might be man
opportunities right like usually there
might be something i'm stuck with maybe
you have some idea on how to fix it or
how how to solve it you're the banking
guy for example right if i'm if i'm
trying to pack some banking thing who
would i ask you
obviously so you know it's kind of like
for that right it'd be easier if i just
met you buy you a beer and say like can
we just chat five minutes you know what
i mean i just got a quick chat but
anyway i said go ahead bro go ahead go
ahead
i mean i i was i was going to say the
same thing i mean you if you're going to
a conference you're not going to
you know just sit down and listen to the
talk you're actually going to
you know to meet the the author and the
presenter because
and as as uh
didn't mention the reasons could be
varied maybe you want to buy stuff from
him maybe you're working on the same
problem right
um and uh
you you're stuck in a roadblock so you
go ask him how is he making these
changes and all
and
from the
last team cool
yeah i think i assumed
oh no
he got to he got to the point of like
the actual concert in the question and
they cut it off the government
it must be conspiracy conspiracy
yeah i mean
also job opportunities right i mean if
you know somebody who's working in
i don't know
uh whatever project zero let's just give
an example right like trying to get into
zero via the like normal route forget
about it dude it's just not gonna happen
but like if you wanted to if that's your
goal it's in like you know your dream if
you're a young researcher and you're
like man you know if i was part of
project zero i'd be like
i made it whatever it is that floats
your vote right the fastest you need to
approach them on the stage and say hey
can i have a job or what
no but it's more of like hey i've got
research that i think is worthy of
project zero can you take a read can you
take a look
and if it's not worthy or if you think
that my you know maybe the research area
that i'm working on is it something
interesting for project zero what are
you guys researching on i'm sure they
they're you know fuzzing all
sorts of crazy
and so maybe they might look for people
who are fuzzing lua or some crazy crap
you know what i mean
so but there's no difference if they
will approach them via email right
i mean well yeah i mean i would say that
by email they'll be like how many emails
do you get bro you know how many
emails i delete
from random nonsense don't
see me stupid that is like you
girl i got no time to answer your
question but if you came up to me and
you said bro can i get five minutes at a
time i got a question like you know i'm
trying to get into whatever whichever
market i'm trying to go into netherlands
i'm trying to get a job in somewhere
right i would take my time to answer
your question
because you know it mattered enough
right sending an email is no effort bro
i send thousands of years it's just like
uh i seem can you hear us all right yes
yes yes
yeah so uh i i we faced pretty much the
same things from the conference
perspective uh so one of the major
decisions that we took for nalcon was
that we moved the gowa conference to
end of the year september and we decided
to go ahead and do one in europe
this was a major decision and part of
the reason was because of the
uncertainty and we were seeing that
europe was opening up
so when we decided
we finalized we publish everything and
then we see the
the number of cases in india going down
and the number of cases in germany are
increasing and again the same thing
there's no surety the rules keep on
changing
but i think
we were we were very lucky because
things started to cool down and before
the conference and
you know they were
they were finally we had rules where
you could go to a conference without
there was no cap on number of people and
you could you know remove your mass so
not not have mass in in public
but on the online side
i think we didn't work on the uh on the
you know
online plus uh offline mode of the
conference we stuck to uh offline
and i think it's just another year as
dylan mentioned things are going to go
back so
there's there's already too much
overload of online stuff like webinars
and conference i mean
even if it is good i will still
not prefer to you know sit down for the
webinar or the conference because the
whole aim of the conference is to go and
meet people right whether it's the
author whether it's you know uh
companies or
or
depending on uh what your aim is you
know
just exposure networking yeah yes yes uh
so in fact yeah the the guys from
payattu
uh
nilcon hardware.io they probably
had the biggest challenge
but they decided to make themselves of
just moving the conference to completely
new location yeah in new country in new
content well this is
like
thousands of miles away not like city
within within your uh
country yeah and yeah i guess this is
this is the biggest challenge and it
really paid off yeah i've been at newcon
uh in in in berlin that's that's amazing
people talks were really really amazing
the the the conference the vibes yep i
mean the only ones in i personally miss
i miss goa
yeah uh so the second question is
what eager mentioned and i completely
agree and you all probably agree on that
is like we see
less and less connections
between cybersec conferences and what's
happening in the reality
uh
does that mean that conferences
exhausted themselves that like ccc
defcon we got these wipes 20 years ago
30 years ago
and now eventually it it it lost
the essence because because people are
like they just go and do their like
hackathon or comic con yeah just like go
see people collaborate but there is
nothing to do with the reality nothing
to do with the threadscape nothing to do
with the
uh
whatever but but i mean the the i would
say that the only thing i can think of
before i even start uh asking questions
yeah exactly what you guys said at least
you can go and meet brands you can go
and talk to people they're still
grounded this use this is the only
connection i can think of but but like
okay hacking metaverse how many people
gonna go and hack metaverse how many
people can go and do things other people
doing like what what do you think
what is the future of the company you're
telling the cyber crime right like the
reality no not only cyber crime but
white hacking black hacking
any kind of hacking
word with between us as friends is
compliance i think when conferences
started to do sponsorships compliance
and governments and everything you have
to have a very
thin line between what the black hat
real stuff in the beginning in the early
years i think in the early years the
conference like dilo mentioned is like
what 22 years you said or like so many
years in the beginning every there was
like a community and that community i'm
sure in the beginning
was divided there were like some people
crossing the lines and you know at least
when i was lives were different the
reliance the problems there's so many
lines so many like like this is the
light i don't know this yeah exactly
people were stepping from lines to lines
and now conference is not they're
disconnected conferences had to
make it look legal
uh they made ctfs they made uh speakers
and academic people
uh do their researches in demo
environments
nothing is
real production
everything is like aligned
to be in that sort of way
is other conferences for that that talk
about compliance info security of course
eu
like pci
i don't know something something just
from my point of view
in some part we get lost and we just you
send exhausted
maybe not exhausted but maybe you just
follow the trend
and the trend is i don't know why
it's like business
yeah business first and and it's not
very
it looks like you're talking about some
illegal stuff
so everybody stays away from that it's
like no no no don't talk about that
stuff we are not here for that everybody
gets you know i don't know i
i think it's about
compliance
that's my point right okay
i don't know what our friends think
about
dylan
yeah
why isn't anybody presenting any cool
like what's actually happening in
the underground was that your question
yeah no the question is
we do you feel like hug the box
presentations and the conference itself
for the box
especially yeah like cyber week
don't have any connection with the real
hacking
whatsoever
is like is that
is that where you were going to stick
for the next 10 years this is going to
be cyber conferences for the next 10
years or we're going to have this
groundbreaking hacking back in the day
you've mentioned barnaby jack yeah is it
is it going to be anything like that or
or not anymore or not in our generation
and we'll have to have a next generation
to come up and step in or what
i have a feeling that uh so it's not so
much that we
we chose it to be like this right as in
in the early days we had pirate bay
we had you know wikileaks
i mean hd more i mean if i go back even
further like you know there's
lots of people that came about and i
presented some crazy basically and
it was awesome because there was a
actually a community not as an industry
growth that's the main difference
there was no security industry you know
i mean there was commercial guys there
was government and officers
the hackers it's the congress
it's just a column here
it's just kind of like how the things
evolve right i mean it's unfortunate and
i mean it's pros and cons right as in
it's not like everything is up
you know what i mean it's because
there's no community the community
evolved listen it's changed
there's still a community but it's more
that people have
have jobs you know they have vested
interests they have career that they
want to plan for right they don't just
throw that away by like you
know dropping some
crazy ass stuff without doing it
responsibly or coordinatedly whatever
the hell the new term politically
correct them for you know not being an
yes
but um
yeah there's a disconnect because
there's the underground which is still
going to be doing undergroundish kind of
things as in
whatever it takes to make money right if
that means ripping off all people and
installing malware on their computer
like i don't even man i want to
make money
and so you can't present about that
you know
you can't present about what that like
you know you can talk about maybe
hunting them as in but that's not as
exciting as actually like hey check this
out man i own a botnet with like you
know 500 million nodes or
something like that right i mean
check out how i built this botnet and
stuff like ain't nobody gonna talk about
that man like how they managed to do it
how they maintain it how they call cnc
controls like nobody's why why would
they do that they're going to like you
know help their adversary
and
their adversaries as in their
underground groups are competing for
each other for like trying to secure the
end points right because it's the way to
distribute malware it's the way to
whatever the hell you know do your
phishing campaigns do your click
crap for like
you know facebook
ads and making people you know think
differently all of that stuff right like
you need control of all these endpoints
right
so nobody's going to talk about that
that's just ridiculous to expect that
somebody's going to come and talk about
that because there's no there's no
reason for them to do so number one it
would be like exposing themselves to
crime which is like ain't nobody going
to go to jail and number two will be
giving up methodology techniques and
stuff that they've worked for years to
hold
right the underground didn't buy this
for cheap man
right
so yeah
you're you're asking for something that
it's obviously not going to happen
because the there wasn't an industry the
last time exploits for zero days didn't
have a value nobody gave a it's
like so what you can hack some phones
like oh wow i can install my own
software on this man i can customize it
let me give a like jailbreak so
what what about jailbreak screw it but
now your banking is on it right now like
your entire life is on it i jailbreak
that if i can put a memory implant
into it that that can survive a reboot
whoa
awesome sauce man right
that's worth money i'm not going to
present in a conference come on
i've seen what's going on yeah there's
no agree i agree with yeah i agree with
the
intelligent so
so the way i see conferences is as as a
source of inspiration so they may not be
directly something that would lead to
you know
uh
the underground coming up with something
but it's more of a
more of an inspiration that you know
somebody comes up and says hey i found
this methodology to do this see how neat
it is
and that becomes an inspiration for you
know black hat gray hat white hat
whoever whichever hat the person is to
develop something
and how they want to use it and uh
and as as dylan mentioned unfortunately
unfortunately this has become an
industry and there are a lot of things
that have uh attributed to this i think
i see bug bounty as you know one of the
major game changers in terms of
changing the whole community aspect into
a fully blown industry where
you know
young folks are more inclined towards
you know finding an exercise and putting
it in their resume saying as
i i you know i found this vulnerability
and i'm a bug bounty hunter and stuff so
i and and
and people are getting paid for
these things so why waste your time and
energy on something else over there
and in
in terms of
people who are okay to work alone it is
fine but that's not how humans work
right we are a community and we will
always remain a community whatever the
community is whether it is cyber
security or hunting community or you
know i i don't know you know
banking community whatever
we we need a community to to survive so
you can work on it solo for a long time
uh but eventually you will need you know
uh
to fall back on some some kind of uh
community and that's where
the uh the conferences play a key role
so they will be there
depends on how the industry shapes up
they may or may not be too much fun in
the future
but they will still be there for people
who value community
yeah that that's my take on it i want
just to tell me one thing and to the
rest uh
there are underground conferences
i'm sure you guys know
uh plenty
and they're still running and i'm seeing
this trend of
not giving the location not giving
people like conferences around there
also building on a low profile
not
sponsoring hey guys we have this super
underground conference come come and
join us so
i don't know i don't know i think some
people go to there because i'm trying to
think
and speaking while i'm i'm thinking
they maybe the profile of red teamers
offensive hacking
i think they have more value to be in a
community
which is more towards this one
and the other full-blown industry in
ours conferences i don't know i'm just
thinking like why if they exist and
there's a trend somebody
wants them to exist and needs this
community the same thing i think but
again because
it's also business yes as much as our
business well our is multi-billion
theirs
is no but they're trying not to do
business around it they're just meet
friends
yeah of course but the old days was like
look this thing i hacked
and they just show you the laptop
remember those days it was like and
something exploits yes
and change exploits and all this stuff
this is happening it's not something new
so i think
that thing is getting more and more
underground thing just
very far from our industry and and it's
in parallel worlds i think they're
talking about stuff that maybe we
disconnected a little bit status quo has
changed status quo now is that cyber
criminal is just a criminal yeah 30
years ago it was it was um
is he is he a criminal is that is that
because there is no special law on that
now there is and now the
establish it's a witch hunting the
establishment thinks hey
if you violate the cyber cyber law you
go to jail
yeah if if the
well that's that's the problem
um
so the last question
new trends yeah like what is ahead of us
because
what i was really fascinated about
is
uh again
nukon i believe
ah no that was cyber week abu dhabi
uh
2017 or 18 before even before the covet
uh adam laurie
started making this radio
hacking
uh challenge remote when he had his dr
and it was translating the radio signal
from somewhere at his home in england
and he was doing the challenge there in
abu dhabi using the software
the sdr and network and sending this all
the way through now we have can kids
where back in the day
you need to bring tesla and
expensive cars on the venues now
the can kit fits in three suitcases the
same with ics stuff the same with
expliot
all these kids are now go and join and
i'm
like i started doing the same things
around payments yeah like online atms
special network setup that shows the
card payment attacks over the network
all things like that what what is really
fascinated you maybe what you're gonna
pick up on new trends because you i know
you you you're a big fan of ctf attack
defense you wanna you wanna it's always
been niche yeah we have done attack
defense for years but it's it's always
been niche so any any anything that guys
excites you well if you guys i start i'm
getting in this attack defense i want to
learn more about it because we're still
basic in that field we were jeopardy ctf
for me i think ctf is the it still
is relevant
and if you make something cool around it
it will really bring the tension that we
were speaking about like why should i
care to go there
of course you can do hdr remote and you
can do ctf remote everything can be
remote but some things are better to
touch and feel and talk with people so i
had the photos of people who called
yesterday to moscow of course buying
food in the supermarkets and i
remembered how we were doing the same in
like
stocking up before the night of the
hardcore hacking no sleep things like
that yeah because there's some things in
remote you cannot recreate but yeah the
trend i think is just to
be creative i i think that's the biggest
thing at least my head is always
trying to be creative trying to be
something new because it's content
what was the most creative things you've
come up with
i don't know some crazy stuff that
didn't work that's the problem like you
start thinking in your head yes i want
to do this we wanted to do a weather
balloon that would go really you know
throw it in the air but we didn't get
the permission from the airspace
controller we wanted to do something
with the sdr we were doing i remember so
you were putting a your logo on the
built-in in in telerif uh we were we
were spilling out a lot of things
between all of us like can we do this
can we do that bring them the atm
did it happen
well no we had to take the local one and
that was a disaster then i was trying to
bring the atm to tenerife that was also
a disaster but
experts brexit a bitcoin bitcoin so i
don't know it's about
people need bus
right the bus
be you that said bus hmm okay like it
needs something
to ring a bell to say oh i want to see
the atm i want to see how it works i
want to see it inside i want to touch it
i want to play with sdr i never you know
had interaction about it if you make
this setup like you said mobile and you
just put it in the conference people can
interact with that much remember lock
picking you just sit in a table and
there was a you know person just
explaining your lock picking you start
opening locks and you're like wow yeah
like 10 years ago maybe yeah
yeah but new people are still
always there will be new school trying
noobs trying to get on board and we
cannot forget about that because then we
will just keep the whole
situation i think well maybe not lock
picking you do nfc hacking or whatever
and that interferes with idea that
business first yeah for many people for
many conferences like okay businesses
first let's do something established
yeah we're like hey i come up with this
gi genius idea i need a lot of money and
it's it may not work yeah can you can
you give me money who will say yes for
me it doesn't work all the time but i
mean there's a complete disconnect
there's a commercial conference where
they will not do this stuff and there's
some that still have it in the heart
right you still need to make money you
still need to be a business but the core
value is about hacking community and
it's about talking about that stuff
getting a beer i think that still needs
to be there and if if you lose that
magic it's i don't know i just make a
security conference with suits and
stay there and not do anything about it
it's about creativity i think
yeah
you can call it asr you know it's like
rsa in reverse it doesn't matter what
you call it if it's just about the food
brothers like yeah call it whatever the
hell you want but you know i mean uh i i
completely agree in the sense that the
community
and the whole reason to have conferences
is
while we think like i love picking who
wants to learn that you know what i mean
but at hanging the box in cyber week for
example you see a lot of young
people
and students as well
and you know there you look at their
face and how much excitement and
determination is the key and you feel
there's hope yet for our security
community it's not everybody it's not
about like oh i want to sell exploits
and stuff so of course like majority of
people who have grown up but
there are still folks or still kids uh
the younger generation that are looking
at these things and getting excited by
by
wow you know i can i this is a powerful
thing to learn this hacking because it's
not oh i know how to press this button
or write this script whatever the hell
it's not so much about that but it's
that exploration of technology of like
wanting to learn stuff even though it
has no commercial bearing like we've got
all sorts of villages in our
i've seen uh many villagers in abu dhabi
on cyber week this year that was amazing
when everything was just set up i was
like villagers villagers i was also one
of the villagers and you also were yeah
we had we had the oil factories being
broken and things like that yeah so
hands-on yeah the answer is hands-on
something that excites
the audience
yes and excites yourself as in when even
when you are organizing it right like
just doing stages with thoughtful stuff
it's not exciting right but i want to
see that oil refinery thing i want to
see the ctf in action you know i want to
i'm not playing it but it's still
enjoyable to see it and see other people
enjoying it and there's a there's a
satisfaction in being the organizer from
that standing point you know what i mean
it's like if you didn't organize it and
you didn't put your effort and energy
and heart into making this something
special these dudes that showed up
wouldn't have this experience and
there's value to that it might not have
a dollar value but
you're not born to make money right
you're born to have experiences to make
your life meaningful because if you die
tomorrow your bank balance means
all bro it means all
it's like how many people did you touch
how many lives did you change you know
how many people came to your event and
met somebody and because of that meeting
like their lives are no longer the same
if you didn't organize that conference
they would not have met
if i'm gonna die tomorrow no one will
notice they will no one will notice well
will remember me as a guy
who who brought the atm to the hacker
or cyber ring
are you joking oh it's dylan just
mentioned this point and this is the
most important i met kids who said igor
i found my first job in cyber security
thanks to the conference
and that's the point and that's one of
the points the other point is business
yeah we made business because we met
this i don't know big company in their
government's contract
i don't know it's about connecting the
dots and i mean and you just try to make
the best
i mean you you all know the company
calls imperium right like
luke abraham who is the founder of
imperium and people now i don't know how
many billion they got so far like they
got like zack ops is another company he
got like listed and
he's he made it basically right
i know zuk when he showed up and hang at
the box and he had just this concept for
this thing that he was going to present
on stage in amsterdam and he was looking
for ideas and inspiration and he wanted
somebody to chat to and he was like so
like you know really stressed out
because it was his first time doing a
presentation on stage like it's
big conference you know and
um look at where
because of those opportunities and
because he had that presentation and he
met a lot of people in amsterdam and you
know who knows what conversations were
were had
and where he ended up right right so you
know everything has its place and no
matter how big or how small right like
you don't know how things are going to
play out you might think that it's
insignificant like so what you had a ctf
that some 15 year old kid had a good
time but you don't know what's going to
happen to that 15 year old kid do you
yeah so that's exactly my question what
things inspired you what what new trends
i seem
yeah yeah so uh coming back to the
original question about you mentioned
about adam as well like making uh stuff
remote
so that was that was i think part of
our learnings from covet where you had
to do this
so
as we all know the saying necessity is
the mother of uh all invention so we had
to do something where people could not
travel and people who were there uh we
still needed to have something like
radio challenges or hardware challenges
and
and and that's when you invent these
things so for uh for 10 days it's the
same experience yeah it's just that now
uh instead of having everybody locally
people can do it uh
manage the the village or the ctf uh
remotely as well um so i i remember when
we started working on one of our
products the iot auditor bit of
shameless marketing here but
one of the things that i wanted to do
was to be able to give one device to a
user where they could do some hardware
stuff and radio stuff with the device
but connected to the cloud and and and i
think after six months uh covert hit and
i didn't realize holy like if you
have this
you really do not have to go to the
location you can just send it to the
customer and they they can run it right
so
so we are enabling things but at the end
we're still trying to do uh uh uh
the same thing right people get the same
experience what they want to do with the
uh the ctfs you mentioned the
the the villages in cyber week like
there were villages after villages after
uh villages
and uh
and
there were people coming and uh and i
think
in in in our village as well there were
people coming
sitting and soldering on their own and i
could you know
see the happiness in their face you know
because when you've not been out for so
long and then you do the real
and that's what is
exciting for people
yeah
i know from my point of view just make
new things don't stop just not
get stuck in this trend because it's
super easy to get stuck
yeah that's that's the problem that's
the problem back in the day we were
doing things all over again and now we
had the disruption the supply chain
disruption and the that's what i was
talking about exactly last year we need
to use this as a boost for being more
creative for creating stuff to cover up
much broader audience without them being
on the stage without them being
in in in person yeah but but that's
again that my you have only so much time
in your life so instead of
thinking of hey
five years ago you would think how can i
do something on defcon
with people who gonna come and see me
that they're gonna be excited this year
i will be thinking how can i
not go into defcon
do exactly the same to cover much
broader audience you see the focus is
changing you have the tunnel vision and
we may end up losing
the innovation thinking about broader
audience but not thinking about
innovation that might be the problem but
so far so good i really like
all things that i've seen over the last
years explored these
amazing small boxes that i've seen was
bringing guys on cyber week coming
hacking things with their fingers and
laptops
uh
hakron hackron
bitcoin atm a lot of things on phds all
right thank you guys thanks uh this
presentation will be live uh on on the
18th yeah i would like to thanks all of
you and i'm really looking forward
seeing you
this year next year
in person
virtually
yeah stay safe guys thank you so much
thanks for coming and thank you thank
you guys
thanks guys
bye