my name is philippe peters and today
we're going to talk about discovering
cnc malicious speedy app right so this
is my contact at twitter at playbears
and here some information about me you
can find other talks that i've been
talking in different events
and my github here you can find other
projects and articles that have been
published there
and my linkedin as well so if you'd like
to exchange something with me so i
really appreciate that okay so who am i
i'm a security researcher at sapporo
supports a company from switzerland and
i'm responsible for creating the
intelligent behind of this project
basically i'm creating i crea i'm
responsible for creating different
attack modules for the attacker
perspective and i create this logical
this attacks
based on on cloud on on-premise
environment and i send those information
to the developer and team and this team
is responsible for creating intelligent
for
this specific product so the idea of
this product is to working with the
specific cyber resistance and give this
information for our customers okay and
i'm security advocate at singapore since
it's a company a global company
responsible for providing different
solutions but it's economy of the
previous access management right and i'm
advocate of this awesome project called
hacking is not a crime basically the
idea behind of this project is to talk
about this concept calling hacking
because hacking is really the
kind of lifestyle that you can use in
your life not only of course we we are
talking about about security about the
technology but how you can use your
creative mind how you can implementing
this not only in software but in your
life okay so that's the idea because
when you let's suppose that you are a
lawyer
if you
executing bad things you're in this
moment you are a criminal and not a bad
lawyer right so that's the difference so
when you see something uh like like
specifically leaks of the informations
or
some company that have some data expose
it basically this is about the cyber
criminals not a hacking hacking it's a
mindset and how can using this this is
project started in the us but we have
advocates you know around the world
okay and i'm is nick ambassador based in
this specifically open source project
the idea of this nick probably you know
about that so it's a sad solution not
only is a solution but the idea behind
of this
technology is to talk about the
developer the secure development process
process basically so when you create a
specifically app or code so how you can
create these in a sec in a safe way or a
security way so how you can give this
knowledge you mean knowledgement or this
things to the developer team okay and
i'm a lead of the dcg5511
it's basically a small group a small
community in in brazil in sao paulo as
part of the defcon groups and i'm
instructed writer and reviewer those
three magazines here in europe by the
way i'm brazilian i'm talking um in from
portugal because i'm living here now and
let's talk about our main topic today so
what is exactly thread before to talk
about them
our main topic today it's pretty
important to put all those people on the
same page so it's a simple definition
what is a thread because when you're
looking from there specifically
investigation analysis and stuff like
that we need to understand first what is
exactly a threat because you don't know
if these malicious or not or you you
have a simple you have a specifically
artifact but you need to investigate
more of that so what is a threat
basically according to iso is a
potential cause of the specific incident
may cause arm in the system or
organization but what kind of
a specific incident or cause flip in
this case is a software attack type of
intellectual property identity death
sabotage and information distortion are
example of the information security
thread so if you see here model
many of those things that i'm talking
now is about the software so if you
think about software first you have a
code so basically a thread it means is a
possible or potential in this case a
potential incident but all those things
is related to it specifically in a
software it's it's pretty interesting
and basically this is the definition
from these either it's not a philip
definition but this specifically iso
okay so
first of all when you have a
specifically artifact or a sample you
need to go to this specifically staff
the first step is identification step
because you don't know if it's a
malicious not or not you haven't
specifically um you can have in the
future when you execute these
investigations you can have a mower it's
a acronym of the malicious software or
you can have a maldoc and a malicious
document it's another uh contraction
like this let's say this way okay so you
can investigate that of course you can
use indifference methodology to using
this specific analysis those
methodologies call the analysis static
or statistical analysis and dynamic
analysis basic on those two
methodologies maybe you are thinking
about the reverse engineer if you don't
know basically it's a technique using
in ethan the thought specifically
methodology okay it's more deeply of
course into looking from the assembly
stuff like that and other things like
this
okay so when you perform a specific
analysis my recommendation to you is
always you're writing those things
right why
you you you need to do that because when
you write this in some
thing like this you can learn more about
that and not only that but you can
understand how the attacker is using
different techniques
to bypassing different security sensors
and and other thing that you can use
when you write this those things is to
create a specific report in this report
you can present your manager your
coordinator it's very interesting
because you can improve this you can
improve your defense's mechanism it's
other point important because when you
understand about all those steps
performed by the attacker you can
understand what techniques used by these
attackers and specifically i don't know
fyro abs or
ips or you know um
antivirals or idr or other you know
solution that you have in your
environment you can understand exactly
the technique
using by the attacker and you can
improve your security
defenses mechanism and you can provide
specific information for a cyber threat
intelligence team and if you don't have
this is in your organization you can
create that of course
and you need to
not only understand that but you need to
have this specific straining cyber
resilience because the the threads are
changing all the time so okay so we have
a simple we have a specifically um
artifact that you need to investigate
okay so after that what the steps so if
you see here first identification after
that you can choose what the best
methodology you can apply statistical
analysis or dynamic analysis so what's
that means philip in this case
statistical is basically a simple
definition usually is the first step
using them our studies why because this
process describes this the analysis of
the program code or the structure or to
determine
specific function let's let me explain
more thing about that so if you have any
specifically dll or a specific library
inside of your system operation this
library is responsible for call for call
and
specific are using specifically function
in your system operation or all those
things is necessary to run specifically
binary so when you analyze
more deeply about that you can
understand all those program code you
can structure those information and you
can move
more deeply in this case but the program
itself doesn't run at this time that's
the idea behind of their statistical
analysis so in this case it's make this
process more safe okay on the other hand
you have a dynamic analysis another
different approach a different
methodology than you can apply and this
case is based is based uh solely on
behavior in this case the interaction
that the malware or the simple or
artifact has when is executed in your
environment or in your
you know
lab basically this in this case the
analysis in runtime so if you see some
two different approach in a runtime
analysis another is a no runtime
analysis okay and of course you can
automate at this and this um this
methodology basically you've been using
this and one of this uh concept is
called sandbox when you have a
specifically controlled environment you
can execute your sample inside of this
and you can see those behavior but think
a look at this pay attention on this
when you have an ascent box you have a
virtual machine inside of this virtual
machine you have a different engines you
need to have these engines inside of
your sandbox why because when these
engines will be responsible for give you
the result of this specifically behavior
inside of your environment okay so of
course you have a different sandbox open
source like a coco like
others or you have an another
online cloud sandbox or antivirus is
kind of like a veristo for example or
have the cloud or joy sandbox and and
others to execute your sample inside of
this and understand if this behavior is
malicious or not okay so before to talk
about the physical and enlarged
structure of the pdf i would like to
explain something about um more you know
more idea about the identification step
so how important it is to understand
those things so i have here and
specifically two artifacts here i have a
regex dot python and simple.python two
files that i have here in my virtual
machine okay so first of all let me
check what is exactly this file so if
you see here i have a here in a python
script okay it's a text file but in this
case it's executable so let me read and
more let me execute this no no i will
not execute but i will read this
information in this case as you can see
here the bing python i have this
information here the utf code the
encoding the encoding responsible for
this if you see here removing special
characters for a string by regex it's a
simple python code responsible for
removing removing the stringings for a
specific regex as you can see here okay
and i will send all those information
for a specifically said underscore the
text so i will cut are you as a good
spider i will uh removing special
characteristics and sending for this
specifically file is a python code okay
so if i try see here another
is a pdf sample version
uh
1.7 you can use you can see here and zip
the flat encoded probably i need to it's
a good something to uh the code here
probably but let me
show you something about the how you
need to understand about those
identification steps okay so remember we
have here two different fibers okay
regex.python and
sample.pdf so if there is a good here
pdf id
it's a very interesting tool from dda
steven if you see here a simple uh tools
to
looking from more informations about the
pdf in this case and if you see here i
can see the header informations about
the specific version
the quantity of the objects the
streaming and other things so i will
talk more about those steps in
after okay but
pay attention this here so how
in this case how the file works in this
case because i'm looking here and then
in the identifier this file has a pdf
script but existing one information
pretty important that file
using to collect those information to
identify that so take a look at this
what is first what is a file in this
case is a specifically tool that
determines file type okay you understand
that but what is exactly information
that you can see or you can use it when
you execute the file command here is the
information based on the manual pro you
don't like to read the manual i don't
like to but we need take a look at this
this file
have a magic number stored in a
particular placer near the beginning so
basically file using and specifically
database
to collect those magic numbers here and
based on this magic number that you can
find inside of this database from file
they will
identify what is exactly the file type
let me explain more details about that
so let me using here sudo no no
yeah this is my add or text sorry about
that so if you are frustrated but anyway
so let me go there and i will put in
here i will change something here so let
me put in there we'll take a look this
percent pdf
pdf
1.7 and let me save here take a look
this i save here and now take a look
what happened in my specifically file
wow we have a pdf document version 1.7
you see so if i try to read again take a
look at this i just change one
informations here but in this case
these information is based on this is
the magic number of the pdf file so if
you're using here pdf ide once again and
i put the rig x dot python take a look
this this is the ink station it's not
this tools checks not based on extension
but basin on the magic number if i try
the cutting here take a look at this
this is the identification of the header
and the how many objects this pdf have
in this case zero
don't have any streams and other
information but is a really a pdf
even
the workstation
don't appears disappears as a doc pilot
you see
so but if i return here once again and i
cut
this and save once again take a look
what happened
i o regex and now i have a python once
again but let me move
once again for regex
doc python but i will i changed for a
pdf
so now
take a look what happened i have a two
pdf files file react x dot python
continue be
a if i try using pdf id once again
but now it's a pdf in this case take a
look this is not a pdf document why
because the magic number is
a python script not a pdf you see so
it's very important
you understand how you can or how you
will use your tools in your environment
because based on these tools you can
receive any specific
results
right so when you're using some tools to
help in for example for um
reversing engineers the same case we're
receiving specifically uh response from
these tools when you perform some
comment we receive some results about
that and that's the point here so we
need to understand those bases when you
understand that you can move it for the
next steps okay we're learning here from
the a presentation so uh let's in let's
understand something about the structure
of the pdf so we have our header you
have a body you have a cross reference
table or x table and you have a trailer
responsible for identifying some
information inside of this pdf basically
okay so
if you see here first we have a version
in this case a version inside of the
header remember
1.7 when i execute the tools okay
inside of the board you will have a page
image fonts and stuff like that this is
a shiny thing inside of the pdf and the
important information you can find here
in the x table i mean in the cross
reframes table it's a location of this
object
ethan the file for act for random access
i mean basically you have a specifically
root file
first one you're having specifically two
tiles
the object two and object
three
and you can have another like uh for
example in uh object two can have
another different object like a three
four and five like that three you can
see you have a hood in them in the
middle in the beginning you have an
other extension of all those objects so
because of that it's very important will
you understand those flows inside of the
pdf file okay in the trailer is a part
of this access
of this or the certain object inside of
the party okay all those
if you see here in the pdf structure all
those objects
are connected okay so let me show you
this specific demonstration that i
recorded because we don't have a time to
executing all those steps because of
that i recorded but i will explain more
about that so i receive in a cve
basically a resume okay in a pdf so
first i check if this pdf
was a really a pdf document in this case
it was and of course i
i looking from
more details about the structure to
understand that and if you see here they
have a 15 object as you can see here
right and other information that you can
find here it's about the streaming in
this case they have a two streaming
usually not is
usually when you see this streaming is a
part it's a good opportunity that
attacker is using to put in malicious
things inside of this string
it's of course you can see other parts
of this all the other structure of the
object but the streaming is a very good
part that that thread actors or
attackers whatever name you want
less hacker okay
you can find malicious informations okay
so and other things that you have here
is a job script so we have a five
javascript or or 5v reference of
javascript so maybe
some thing is not
it's not common when you see when you
can when you find this in a pdf okay so
first of all executing pdf parsers
another two another two
from dj steven okay so we can using some
commas
like dash s to search for and
specifically informations or
something like this so first i try just
to confirm where is exactly the place
that you can find the javascript so we
have enough first to reference object
one all the references object seven and
object twelve three reference all a
javascript remember remember that three
reference another is js
the second one so if you see here object
1 and object 12 two others reference so
if you see
make totally sense so first i use
executing pdf id so i perform this
specifically scan to to check these
strings and after that
i execute the pdf part or tools through
looking more deeply about that okay the
second comment that i used
and this
in this specific investigation it was
dash
or
or no dash w in this case if that means
the run output for data and filters
because my idea here is
was
open the run data inside of this
pdf so take a look at this
first we have an object one this is the
first remember
the three okay
and if you see here we have
six reference
two three four five
six and seven
thinking about the three okay and in the
middle we have a specifically object one
and six other informations behind of
this object one remember the child
object okay and we have here some open
actions and javascript so philippe
what's that means in this case open
actions so i will explain more about
that so take a look this behind you see
the open actions in this case the open
jackson is a functions inside of this
pdf what is this open action is
responsible
basically if you're working in our
specifically hdr team
you probably receive resume or cv a lot
if you work in a financial team probably
you receive many voice per day okay so
it's a normal behavior we will open the
pdf because you receive these
informations okay okay so
let's suppose that you are these these
people and you will open this file so
when you open this this is the only
click that you need to execute in this
pdf you receive your resume from the
your candidate email okay
and you receive this you click you will
open this pdf this is the first actions
that you only not only first but the
only action that you need to execute
after these actions will executing and
specifically automatically
open actions
why do why
because in this pdf this pdf has this
function so after the user open the
document
will be executed
something in the background
why
i don't know when you investigate
but
this action is totally linked
with the specifically job script as you
can see here so in the
part of this block
the the of this no block but this this
this is this a part of this document in
this case this open action is totally
linked with the this job script so
what that means in this case when the
the user received the document and
clicking the pdf
javascript will be executed in the
bitmap machine
what is the result
i don't know we don't know so let's move
on and this investigation to understand
that so
when we already understand this process
open action and javascript let's
continue to be
to see here we some information but we
and these tools probably
don't have the mechanism to open these
information objects to nothing three
nothing object four we have another two
reference or two another remember those
three the the the three remember that
object one other reference okay on the
child for per object okay
nice object 7 reference object 10
here some informations about the
javascript some reference
object 80
format images stuff like that not
uh value information here and reference
again one of the
those child's reference itself okay
in object 10 we have another object 12
and maybe you have here the javascript
and take a look at this here in object
one we have the first streaming
in this case as you can see in object 11
we can see the content is streaming and
having a specifically filter in this
case the
the filter all the information inside of
this stream hasn't specifically left in
this case is 36
and they have the flat the code tag i
mean in this case i need to decode this
information inside of this
specifically streaming and other point
his is the left in this case the size is
not too big it's 36 it's it's a small
size okay but maybe you can look in from
the object 11. in object 12 we have
another reference object 13
and maybe let's see here
in object 13 we have the second
streaming remember we have a two
streaming in this case the lat is too
big when you compare with the first okay
so maybe this is
uh should be the the main object to be
to investigate because
the side the left is it's high it's not
high it's big
and you know you have here this
streaming okay if you remember they
probably haven't specifically javascript
here because here is the reference
object 12 remember the the child so
basically object 13 is a child of the
object 12
okay
so let's move on it we had
15 object remember that so here object
uh 12
uh i mean the 14
and another is 15 okay so let's move on
for the another tools
so if i will need if i need to looking
from the
streaming probably i need to using other
tools that i can
extract
the streaming information and
in this case i execute the pdf tech
because when you're using pdf deca you
can
compress those information inside of
this specifically streaming not only
compressed but you can uncompress the
information so that's my idea if i can
compress i i can
uncompress right or recompress you can
execute in different things with using
these tools and or you can merge pdf as
well so in this case is a good pdf deka
i set the document and i request
what i request this
output and this output i request the
uncompressed information as you can see
here right so if you see here i have the
dump so i can investigate more
informations about that so when i try to
looking from the dump informations take
a look what i found in object 13 i have
here the javascript the
route date of the javascript in this
case this javascript
are using a specific technique this
javascript
is of course obfuscated so this is the
first technique used by the attacker so
the next steps i need to deself escape
this javascript so
first of all i copy this code and paste
it here to understand all those
informations and if you see here take a
look at this i have here some evil
parameters
and i thought when i performed this
specific investigation so if i if
i were
if i'm i was looking from the
specifically job script maybe we i can
looking from the html uh file or i can
try to read this in a specifically uh uh
web page that's my thought when i
perform this uh investigation so i using
this specific level parameter to rewrite
this document because of that i put in
this the the this specifically tag of
this parameter actually from html if you
see here then my ideas to using this and
if you see here take a look this
standard behavior if you see here ladder
percent number ladder percentage number
it's
very very interesting behavior
non-behavior but the standard
the pattern actually the pattern of this
information so i rewrited this file i
created a specifier and that i call it
sample
and i give the permission to execute
itself
in
in a specifically browser to open those
information to understand what that
means in this case it is javascript
obfuscated so i described this code and
take a look what i
found
in this case isaac this and wow we have
here and specifically payloads you know
what that means
payload is the package or a code
responsible for download this in the
victory machine in this package this
piece this piece of package is
responsible for performing the callback
of the commanding controller from the
attacker so i found the javascript
obfuscated and after that i found the
payload
so if i found the payload i just i can
move on an investigation more about that
to try to find
the
specifically the cnc from the attacker
so after that is executing some
investigations in unix platform but
if i think flip just using the unix are
using linux as well let me show you here
let's move on yeah i copy here the same
page the same payload as you can see
here
i cop this and i using other platform in
the windows
environment so if you see here are using
mouse zilla to collect this information
so first of all
i pass here as you can see
because in this case the attacker using
another technique basically the
unicodes technique bayesian and in two
different bytes because you can use in
for example an ascii or unicode ask is
based on bytes and unicode is based on
two bytes
and the attacker using this specifically
encoding techniques here but it's kind
of old because the attacker using the
ucs2 as you can see here below
this is an encoding technique so i need
to decode this and convert this in a
decimal file as you can see here you
click here
and after that i have then specifically
exa file
payload okay
after that i generate and specifically
binary why do that philip
because the binary
is responsible for executing in the
windows platform right
so basically this is the format of the
attack okay so i
creating this file cnc doc bin and after
that i use ensure to try
maybe to find to try find some
informations about the attp
inside of this binary and if you see
here using short search other two from
dda stevens and if you see here i found
the cnc
from the attacker this is a commanding
controller too right so i find here this
information so if you see here in the
end where is the place
that the attacker are executing this
specifically uh
attacking
basically is from estonia in europe so
if you see here we have the we found the
cnc so here i finish my presentation so
here's some books
that
this topic is very interesting so you
can investigate you can learn mainly
about that in those
four books
from
pact it's very nice and if you have any
question
guys so please let me know i i it's a
pleasure to be here to talk with you
about this talk
and uh yeah if you have any question
please let me know