my colleague anton was expected to
present but you see
you're not lucky you have me again
however i'll try to convey everything
that anton wanted to say this is anton
and he is the author
in fact you know the most important
person behind this research
you know is his work his ideas
that were implemented in everything i'm
going to talk about he's a virus analyst
he's an experienced hand in cyber
threats
now he's working very hard
on actually making his knowledge
available to more people
now i'm the head of
the development fighting malware
my department is actually responsible
for malware fighting elements of
positive technologies solutions too
we talked about rose kids yesterday both
kids today
so this is the plan
and we are going to you know
have some respect so to speak up to the
previous presentation
there will be an introduction next we'll
talk about uh detecting
old boot kits legacy boot kits
as well as deduction of uh
modern but kids here
sequence actually we can spend a whole
hour talking about the individual stages
but
let's talk very generally there is some
preparation
then there is the
kernel loading and finally everything
else gets loaded in the operating system
this is like the simplest way of
explaining it and the boots kit sits in
the first stage so to speak
and it's there to actually impact the
way that the operating system
is loaded
is
to screw up the legitimate loading
process
so the objective or the purpose of the
buskit is to start up as soon as
possible
because the sooner it starts the more
difficult it will be to detect
moreover this way it maximizes the
privileges it gets
and the opportunities it has for a
compromisation and installation of its
own malicious code
[Music]
like the sooner a boot kit is started
the more we should doubt
you never know you know which computer
will be secure and safer which will
and others are designed for you advice
so how we go into research and identify
boot camps we'll need hypervisors and
virtual machines for that
so when we're dealing with a computer
that you know is restarted we'll you
know kick into action again we will not
really have a reliable tool for tracking
the whole startup chain
so naturally we need an observer so to
speak who will actually be able to
monitor this complicated process
which means we need a hypervisor we need
virtual machines that will well
effectively reduce
what a regular machine does so when i
say hypervisor
i mean
you know our favorite tool that we
always talk about
naturally it's not the only tool like
that
um
so we can be using xn or a kvm though
the best combination is kvm
and uh
like additionally you would want to have
more things attached to it let's put it
like this and if various hypervisors
will use various apis but in any case we
will want
to
standardize many operations and that's
why i leave vmi library has been
developed which is like an intermediary
between hypervisor and the abstraction
which will be human readable so to speak
a chain of events
happening and for every event
you will be able to do things and you
will therefore be able to impact
the work of this system you know without
uh leave them it would be very difficult
on top of live vmi we have a dragon and
dragon booth
actually provides the right level of
obstruction for a programmer
or a security analyst
a symbol into an address and obtaining
objects from the system and process
lease and what-have-you
and then you know go from these objects
to additional information
on processes
identifiers what have you
stopped
and again let me stress we are talking
about some fundamentals of how boot kits
work we can go into details
but that will take too much time and
they do have some common denominators
that are
interested in exploring for this
presentation
so
why do we care about legacy buyers boot
kits well it's 2022.
inventors are actually producing reports
on
finnsby
and other
you know
legacy buzzkits really so
it's using both ufi and legacy
version so to speak about kids
so this is one of the explanations for
why we shouldn't turn a blind eye to it
you know it's still
sensible to use because virtual
infrastructure
in many cases
is actually legacy based
and also we need to remember the country
we live in right
in this country indeed
many machines are still bios based not
ufi based and absolutely we need to take
this into account
so this is the
operating system startup process for
bias
the codes
i guess it's a bias code kicks in
which actually
prepares
the computer for some primitive
operations with memory and hard drive
and then you know mbr
takes over
a boat record finds uh the active uh
portion and uh produces a vbr from it
volume boot record and volume boot
records will contain a pointer
to a larger
chunk of code than say mbr
which will parse the ntfs structure and
will extract the code from it and it's
called ipl
it doesn't take too much space
but it actually requires more space and
vbr to enhance this transition
next we have the boot manager and boot
manager
extracts uh both configuration
parameters
and it prepares the next stage
which is a kernel launcher
not that important finally and loads
will start loading the
core the kernel of the operating system
and the rest of the runtime will be
started after that but we don't really
care about it for this presentation so
this is the startup chain
now it's very important for the kids
to be started as soon as possible
now can we actually start at the buyer
stage wouldn't that be great
the thing is that's in different
computers it may be dramatically
different particularly if they're coming
from different vendors and a mistake in
code
if it's at the bias level you know it
will probably break the computer so it's
now feasible
you know some uh
virus
chose to attack mbr
so with mbr naturally you will you know
manipulate the master blue trackers
and it's important to remember
so the first thing a boots kit will do
and here we can either create a new
active section
which will point to its own malicious
code
or alternatively we can
take the current vbr and
change the code in it or we can
manipulate actually
pointer to ipl you know so that it
points to our own payload
and both kids should really choose one
of these options they need to attack
either mbr or vbr
so the infection itself is pretty simple
you know in the user run time
so in the user mode there will be an api
that will get access to the hard drive
it's like raw xs and then
an entry is made in a certain sectors of
the disk
there will be shifts there but probably
we shouldn't be talking about it today
so there is an api
and infections with such a boot kit
can actually be registered in an
analytical environment
the same will be true for a vbr and ipl
infection
because you know it's a similar type
effectively of access to just different
partitions
this would be like another
implementation of the same
so what do we have here with the legacy
bootskins
now we can actually check mbr vbr at ipl
no potential spots for a boot kit so the
start of our analysis we can calculate
hash sums of these sections at the end
of our analysis we can get hash sums
again and if there is any mismatch there
must have been infection
and the methods previously described
must have been used for that
well naturally
whatever the methods you know we should
make sure we should make sure it doesn't
happen
so on drug
we did not really have functions that
would enable drug wolf to read the drive
of a vm
in order to perform this uh comparison
i've just described
so we had to do this extra coding
we updatedly the vmi library and you
know it's uh now able to
read
different formats
these are fragments of the codes there
is nothing difficult really this is the
usual sum calculation
and comparison
it's really a very easy way of
identifying lots of boot kits in legacy
systems
okay
alas this year we do have this infection
now let's analyze the process of
operating systems startup after
the business infection
it is actually going to rewrite
the processor for drive operations
because every boot kit will need to
intercept this particular interrupt
so all the known legacy
yes this particular method so we decided
that we should also check that
so we need to see if there is any
interception of this particular handler
which means that the pre-boot stage
we need to actually get the control
because
hijack it
so that we can actually see if such
connection is performed later
this stuff i'm not going to show in a
slide
if you ever
analyzed uh libraries in user melody
must have seen that is uh often very
convenient to
set a breakpoint for jump minus one
instruction
well that's why you know the instruction
will jump back to itself in assembly
code
it will look like eb
so we did it's pretty much the same so
we took mbr
and the first date we would actually
rewrite with
eb
this way
[Music]
to reboot a virtual machine wait some
time then connect jack wolf
and then you know we would know right
away where we are we could stop the
machine anytime and you know substitute
the bites and so on
when we get to the products uh products
part of this process we realized that
it's taking too much time
so we found a special call
which
will take us to hypervisor it's
so-called uh vm call
and
it results in the same thing as you know
the knob instruction and assembler
so it does take a bit of time
while requiring very little capacity on
the cpu side
so we put it in a cycle
for extend hypervisors
and then you know a drug booth
would kick into action
it would restore the bite sequence
and then we do the interception of the
ivt table this is what it looks like
so we do
this hooking trap in the ivt table and
you know once the break point is
triggered
we'll actually see which particular
handler was overwritten so this is
effectively additional information on
how a particular boot kit prefers to
work
quite successful
next element of malicious code in the
idt table which is analogous to ivt
so idc
you know it has interrupts in the first
half of the table but not the second one
so the zeros in the second one were
rewritten by robnix with malicious code
and then it's a handover control there
so we
tried funny where this handover is
happening you know
to secure mode and this function is
called
bm
maintenance
is the part that works in real mode
while boot monitor dot xz works in the
secure mode for the cpu so in the first
part idt gets initialized
[Music]
kicking into the action and once we are
in bml we can actually check the state
of the idet table and if in the second
half of this table there is uh something
bit besides the zeros we realize that
something must have been written there
malicious possibly so
it could be
or some other busquets
we can actually see that there are some
simple operations here
so we are comparing bytes to zeros and
once we see that there is something
rather than zero
there will be a message that you know
we've got somewhere in identity
that shouldn't be there
so this has been an interesting
challenge
stage you know because previously we use
it for user mode and kernel modes we
called it a drug wolf 16 like arsenal 16
which is uh you know a
nuclear research uh city in uh former
soviet union
so once a dracula 16 has done its stuff
you know it hands
the operations over to drug roof
i mean i could have given you a more
convoluted picture had i you know drill
deeper into the ufi
element in this flowchart we won't
really be talking about the uefi
initialization about the initial the
individual driver is firing up there
what we care about is that there are no
state
and then
it's sort of handed over to the program
blocks which are sitting in ufo system
partition
and all the other elements of uefi boot
managers
and as well as nts kernel which is
obviously sitting elsewhere but all the
other stages
they're actually very similar to what we
had in legacy
which means that the objective here is
the same uf5
boot manager is doing the preparation
and now done it loads the kernel
so all the interesting things happen at
the ufi stage
so what do the modern boot kits do
those that are targeting systems
so we have ufi system partition which
stores some of the critical components
such as the boot manager
or substituted for example if you
you know remove it and so you put
boot manager another one maybe even in a
different folder
you know you re-initialize the bcd
so that it's pointing at a different
file
well then you will be using a little
different file for
starting up the whole system you know
it's a primitive way of doing it but it
works
so fiend spy recently rediscovered you
know
had the same kind of vector the same
kind of peculiarity
so how do we quantify all these
components
we have to find this a ufi system
partition and this is gdt markup right
which means that we're using gui guides
here and we're looking here for type uh
guid and then we do fat32 bursting
which we actually did in drag with
itself and then we would take the files
and folder lists
and now we would you know check the
checksums
i mean it would take the hashes
but x 64. it's actually backup of the
regular uefi so if the first one doesn't
work you can actually leverage the the
backup and bcd
is a host of uh bcd predators which
impacts the way that the operating
system is booted
then you know all this content we would
hash
just like the list of photos and then if
we discovered that you know something
got changed then obviously we were
dealing with the boot kit in the system
partition
i guess it's a pretty
pretty obvious stage
not all this will follow
this is something that happened in 2018
when low jack's boot kit was discovered
[Music]
some post kits were discovered for which
the initial
infection vector was uh discovered for
most it wasn't
now lojacks would actually infect sbi
and they would rewrite the
firmware so when we're talking about ufi
boot kits you know the big question is
how do we infect sbi
so there's a vulnerability issues in smm
what have you you know they're all
designed to actually infect the sbi
and we are going to discuss the most
interesting elements of this particular
infection
trajectory
so i'm showing here an excerpt from
study
on how lojax works
they both used
a driver called rv everything
which is a legitimate driver in order to
interact with the firmware
neat isn't it rather than redo
pile of code
so if you want to if you want to detect
at least some infections you can
actually
search for a driver like this you know
if it's emerges on your system there
must be a reason for that both trick
boats and low jacks
later on use the same approach
we need to write information to your sbi
we need to get access to the sp
before that and
every pci device spi included has the
so-called pci configuration space 256
bytes long and here in the center you
see this large
white
quadrangle called base address registers
so
this is the place we need to get
so with a certain shift you will be able
to find there rcba
rules complex base address register so
this name suggests it's a register and
it's a contains a particular value
which shows
the place in the physical memory of the
computer
which will contain
rcrb
complicated isn't it
i can go again through that
you're losing me
so there is a register that contains
values which uh point to the physical
memory where other registers are listed
so it's important for the driver to
obtain the information about where in
the physical memory of the computer this
list of registers can be found so these
are managing registers for dealing or
for managing spi
so low jax
will actually work with this registers
and you will see lots of uh
you know
weird abbreviations alphabet soup there
and you know there is a sequence of
comments on uh how to read
them and how to write back into sbi
governance
so the question is how do we
say configuration space how do we
actually get access to it
particularly given the offsets
well there are two ways of doing
that the first one is shown here
and it's actually the one that was used
both by the trigger and lojex
so we are using here
in and out assembly commands with config
address and config data ports
so this way we can write or read
into the address space of a pci
and as device there we will be using say
the address shown in green here and this
address is coded
from initial information on the bus and
the device
and the number of the function
yeah and the fourth parameter is the
actual register offset
well we actually need to do the writing
of the reading
so there is a formula that actually
encodes all these four values into a
single figure
so this slide at least all the actions
you need to perform in order to detect
uefi butt kits
now let me walk you through this logic
again because i understand that you know
just listening to this probably
helps little so first you need to use
emails instructions
for specific words in order to get
information on bci address space
when you have the ability to read data
from this space
you will be able to read uh rcb registry
value register value whether you know
references to physical memory space and
there you will be able to find
information on
specific registers and you can use their
address value
to read and write data from or in spi
there is also a way of uh getting access
to sbi address space different way you
know in modern chipsets
let's say you know managing register
register
but we decided to do exactly that
because this is considered a more
reliable method and this is how budkies
do it now some people say that mapping
of physical memory when it's you know
virtually represented may result in a
race condition
i'm not sure this is the case we haven't
tested it
but
what was a decisive factor for us was
that you know
you know it's on our to-do list
and we wanted to
develop a detection routine
so we are looking now for in and out
instructions because the effectively
about escaping from a virtual machine to
the hypervisor
well without them you know the
hypervisor will not be able to analyze
the state of the virtual machine
there are many assembler instructions
that would result in something like this
for example hey
there is also rdt sc instruction which
enables you to
check processor time intact
we didn't really know how to leverage it
you know it was not available only bmi
or jackroof
or in accent api
so we actually had to update
and
[Music]
the instructions for handling those
situations when you know there is a vm
exit for an in out
and this way we can actually process it
in direct move so we set intercepts for
every case of
escape from a vm for any email
construction and then we check which
port is being addressed so
if it's a particular sap say config
address board
configuration space we will be guessing
that somebody is trying to read pcie
configuration space which is a good
marker that something can be going wrong
responses naturally may differ
so for example
we can talk about like secure votes
writing to sbi without any issues
were like smm modes which was leveraged
by lojex
responsible for two other bits enabled
one of the bits to be put to zero or one
of the streams could be put into azimut
mode or race condition could be
leveraged in order to
switch off the other protective bits so
these different manipulations
are available for sure
but you know if you see that you know
there is
a request to the firmware
somebody is trying to record obviously
you have enough time
to sport it
naturally this is not the end of this
research we obviously realize that
just to be on the safe side we also need
to consider other vectors such as smm
mode code execution
and we're even thinking of uh developing
an event tracing system in uefi
so that you know we can actually see you
know how modules are invoking ufi apis
the most important problem right now is
that in the current version of xsen
there is no information on sbi there is
in fact no opportunity to properly
analyze the smm modes which means that
you know additional code development
will be required so i've got more time i
should say that actually updating send
is a headache
because they will accept patches to
their projects
you know the old way through email
so
several times we tried doing that and
they blocked our email account
because we're sending div files
you know when we were able to get in
touch with the key people at xsen
you know they kept giving us feedback
on what else they would like to change
but you know what we're not mobile
developers we weren't really in the
business for a code review and
refactoring
so we're hoping the community will step
in
but we also have it in our pipeline
the stage or the state right now is that
we are going to make it public on github
obviously
there will be a new blog in there called
bootkitman
where we are going to deploy everything
i've already described
uh national dependencies for xn and
leave vmi
so
the current state is that you know we
are polishing it we are finalizing
development
right final thoughts and conclusions so
there are boot kits and they differ
however
they do have some common denominators
we may not care that much about a
particular family given
belongs to
because there are ways of you know
identifying them very early
where they don't differ
but we need to be able to register the
bad events
you know if we do that ahead of time so
to speak or if we do in time
we won't even care
if we don't really know how we can do it
outside a virtual machine outside a
sandbox
the biggest problem we have is uh
cheering the pre-built process
lots of interesting things are happening
and we would love to be able to get some
visibility there so that we can actually
identify something
something weird something suspicious
and the solution we have developed i
think is an interesting architectural
find so please help us save the world
from malicious good kids thank you very
much and look forward to our plugin
[Applause]
with over 15 minutes for questions
uh
i won't give you any fancy
recommendations really
because if we're talking about the
firmware and if the firmware has been
infected
it's not a typical
you know case like one thing when you
can deploy you know snapshots of an
operating system
like the same operating system everybody
knows
but you know firmwares they're all so
different and some users don't update
their firmware
i'm not sure there is a you know a
reliable automated solution
i think you can
do for example
dumps memory dumps of chipsets and boot
records if we're talking about the
legacy systems
and then restore from that
site
or potentially you may want to do edr
i'm not sure there is
even you know a centralized solution if
possible
and how can
i actually participate in the
development given that should get loved
further evolution will be available in
uh drug booth
so what i've been talking about is an
announcement um just like that we're
almost ready to make it available to the
public you know making sure there are no
stupid bugs left
to open the doors
going forward we'll need to teach a
hypervisor to support
more modern chipsets and just like i
said uei tracing is another element in
our roadmap
now we've been talking about this you
know forensics case really analysis post
facto so to speak
what about prevention
[Music]
what you need to prevent is not the
buskit but rather installation of buskit
because uh any malware before it drops
the boat kit you know will do lots and
lots of things like recon
and persistence and what have you so
this is the stage where you would want
to intercept it
in order to install a legacy bootkit
obviously you will need rights to write
into the boot records
you know the raw data in the bush record
in real time that's what you need
[Music]
well you may also want to track the
access to mv ram variables and vram
variables
some of the risks
you know there is so this close
functionality for some commercially
available laptops like this
so this is something that you should be
able to do in real time
which are the things you've
listed will be required if we have a
trusted execution pass if we have a
proper boot guard
if we have secure boots
well they do have their problems for
sure
but all the known cases of say implants
in the firmware at least in
public knowledge you know they will all
be abusing misconfiguration of the
platform or bugs in the firmware
do we really need something like this
you know on the preventative side if
we've got everything i've mentioned
questions
to
well we've mentioned two ways of uh
gaining access to registry mapping so if
we don't know how to take the address
out of a cpi well you can completely
skip the stage for detection
will not allow anything right
because
aspi is only available from system
management mode
yes absolutely but there are bugs in
system management modes which can also
be abused
so when you've got boot guard and secure
boat and the whole
route of trust
you know the only
vulnerability
remains in the smm and research done by
various inventors including boy uh bono
and alexander mitchell
many vendors make this mistake
you know so many products in the iot
world now they get released with bugs
and errors
so indeed you know you can disconnect
some of the productions from smm and
then
drop your boot kit
effectively we need to analyze the
firmware in order to you know find
obvious box in the smm
our approach so far has been different
you know we've been looking at how we
can identify a boot kit which is already
there which is a forensic kind of
exercise
absolutely
it's a forensic exercise on a test
system thank you
question
my question has already been answered
yes yes
thank you for your presentation
i've got several questions
and there will be like an automated dump
of the original hash and the modified
one
it's an open source solution i guess it
can be integrated into other systems as
well
so the way we've done it is that for a
legacy boot kits or a legacy system so
rather you know
we can provide you with an option to you
know first restart the system we haven't
done that for ufi yet
this option will not be available there
for the moment
if we get to the stage where we will be
able to register the facts of uh right
operation into spi we should be able to
do the dump you know firmware before and
after and to run our comparison
when you talked about this interaction
with sbi
interception and analysis
i was wondering
about the other tools such as chipset
for dealing with sbi
so how did you choose effectively a
customized solution
they're all designed for
the operating system interface so to
speak
but here we're showing you an example in
the wild so to speak
you know where with you know it's
constructions you can get access to
you know physical memory map
otherwise interacting with the firmware
itself we haven't found if you know them
please talk to me later
i actually believe that you know if
there are other solutions available you
know we should integrate them as well
uh
[Music]
it's going to effectively detect issues
uh based on checksum division or will it
also be tracking for some
because activities know some companies
have for example do
you know they have lots of hardware
they need to
install new firmware on a regular basis
how they're going to use it
then such research could be easier to
perform
[Applause]
is effectively a small operating system
because there is an sdk
for it
like it's it's in our roadmap
but we also want to strike some balance
between the amount of resources it
requires and the demand for it really
because you would really hate to spend
too much time doing it and then saying
it's not used by anybody well hence i'm
actually talking about here
this is how we are gauging potential
interest in it
anti-semitic things technologies used in
ufi
also targeting budgets
products can be activated illegally
or by actually
touching the sbi
[Music]
will not change
now
for a solution that would be deployed on
numerous user machines so then
everything would be locked
you can actually redesign the image of
the virtual machine you can actually
build it there
then it will be considered a legit part
of it and this environment will be
no different from whatever is used in
the organization will not be considered
you know malicious
but you know the sheer effect of
automated installation of it well you
know it goes into the product once you
know you will discover the buzzkid once
because you know it does act as a boost
kit but it will be just you know a
single false positive right
[Music]
so you should be able to avoid further
fast positives like this
double-edged sword
because you know you can do it because
you know
this is how you do your cyber security
or alternatively you know it can be done
with malicious purposes you know to spy
say on a bunch of users
so it's a security strategic decision
i think we actually need you know to see
you know one signal like this
and then you know you can whitelist it
you know you can respond it and then you
can wait list if it is
not malicious
we still have like three minutes
questions
maybe we have time for one question
thank you very much
i hope you're going to use it