dear friends just couple of minutes ago
are attackers
they were able to
execute inaccessible event and organize
certain problems with purchasing of
tickets
in our transportation company that was
deployed in our replica well very often
main reason for such events in real life
are real vulnerabilities which exist in
the infrastructure of the company
and
how can we discover them properly how
can we properly inform about them and
how can we properly close them we're
going to speak about it and i'm going to
speak with la vadim soul of your hello
body but him is the head oh
threat analysis and information security
team in positive technologies
you
have my dear viewers you have a unique
opportunity
to hear the most interesting
things from vadim's presentation which
you will hear in positive technologies
this and when your presentation will
happen my presentation will happen
tomorrow okay we're ahead of time
today we're going to
look at results of what's going to be
spoken about tomorrow i think this is
wonderful hello buddhim hello julian can
you tell me please
why
are you working with vulnerabilities why
well i think that this is this was my
evolutionary process i just had to do it
plus all the trends are moving in the
direction that
management
yeah
the vulnerability management
and proper timely processing of them i
think this is what the future lies
if vendors are not going to remove
vulnerabilities and researchers and are
not going to inform them properly
in full volume and responsibly which is
very important
then the world can be
encoded by the encoders you know so we
have to work with it okay but jim i
think that positive technologies is
involved in discovery vulnerabilities in
the course of
20 yes as long as positive technologies
lives that's how long it does it so in
the course of this long period of time
children has grown up went to
universities and got married
and worked with vulnerabilities also
have changed
so how in the cause of this period the
process of search recording closure what
has changed in the life of the
researcher well i understand your
question
i think we have to first of all speak
about the break-even point which
happened last year when we've been
sanctioned and at this moment of time we
did feel that reporting process
has changed especially in the
side of the benders who are being
reported too we have american and
non-american vendors because american
vendors they
uh communities didn't have any right to
communicate with us because they have
their own regulators they have their own
orders and we've been searching for ways
around how can we inform them about
their vulnerabilities maybe not openly
maybe not to official channels so that
they in any case would be able to fix
this vulnerability and would be able to
provide and deliver
update patches to their end users and if
the users will be uh secure this is the
main reason why the informational
security leaves for so that people could
use informational security
software
hardware and
different
and not be subject to any risks so that
somebody would exploit a vulnerability
about which they have not been informed
well tell me please when you communicate
with vendors i've heard on many
occasions about different stories
stories that one vendor is working
properly another one is stumbling very
often another one does some crazy things
so let's look at your work with vendors
as a as a separate process can you tell
us about some interesting
pictures which might happen with vendors
and which we can get rid of and
simply by our life
well the biggest feature is when the
vendor is not reacting to researchers at
all does it happen yes it happens very
often
it's an often situation when vendor
has never faced any vulnerabilities
maybe if it's a niche product and they
never had to work with researchers so
they receive a letter
in their main
when some unknown person tells them okay
dear vendor we have discovered
vulnerability let's communicate about it
the vendor is getting lost they don't
know what how should they reply
so they are hiding and do nothing about
it
what should we do we should search for
options not only through the email maybe
some personal connections to this vendor
when you will be able to explain in a
human language that we fight for the
good it's not a blackmail it's nothing
but we just want to help you we just
want to make your product safer and to
protect your users this is an obvious
one
the second situation that we face is
we start communicating with the vendor
you deliver information about
vulnerability they look at it
everything's okay
but they never patch their product so
this process of vendor notification the
main objective is for vendor to produce
the patch and to keep the users on the
secure side so on a cognitive
subconscious level there's a certain
video
goal
to
have certain achievements as a
researcher i have discovered the
vulnerability but the main goal is to
defend end users to the update or patch
manufactured by the
vendor but if the vendor is not making
this patch it means that this process is
halted and broken
but why vendors do not make those
patches well it does happen and there
are different reasons for non-patching
why vendors are not baking patches and
i'm going to speak about it tomorrow
okay good any other stories from the
lives of uh
different vendors
it might have been a totally shocking
research
and
they approach responsible
discovery and they do everything
properly and sometimes it's an auntie
story but in a positive key when vendor
does everything properly and you think
that okay these guys fine finally
they're ripe and then you go and tell
everybody in the course of the week
they've reported you reported this
product to this vendor and they've done
more than you expected you shouldn't
tell them how to receive identifiers in
different databases you shouldn't ask
them to request
links in the advisor they requested it
they know everything they took
everything they inform about the
deadlines when they will have
publications when the patch will be
produced and just
before the page they will make a letter
okay dear researcher in the next week we
are going to make this patch which is
going to close your vulnerability please
keep it in mind so it's an ideal picture
and it happens once in a while so things
that you're telling me i think this is a
very mandatory minimum from from the
vendor to
make a link to the researcher to refer
to the researcher what's so good about
it can you make an example why is it so
good well
good side of it is that only few vendors
follow these good practices only few
vendors practically go through this path
and they've repeated it on several
occasions and right now they are ready
to reproduce this procedure
[Music]
on every situation that's why
it's it makes you happy when vendor does
everything properly
i cannot say that it happens every day
amongst the foreign banners russian
vendors no we should not differentiate
them
we cannot say who is better and who is
worse and we do have companies which do
everything properly within these
discovery vulnerabilities process from
their side so this is a process of
removal of vulnerabilities and speaking
about foreign companies they do they do
have a lot of companies like that and
they do it successfully so when you
write identification to the vendor that
you've discovered in their product
certain vulnerability
other certain live hacks or maybe
certain templates or forms how can you
write this notification is it a template
or maybe there's a certain requirements
object hello dude i've discovered this
in your program if you want i'll show it
to you
well it's always different it's always
different and it all depends
okay relatively speaking it depends on
the level of maturity of the vendor
his maturity in the process of
vulnerability of removal for example has
a big inflow of vulnerabilities from
researchers vendor does know how to
process them and they try to optimize
this process the most obvious thing is
to place the policies of vulnerability
discoveries which says how the
researchers should act if they find a
vulnerability in this vendor's product
and then they will have contact
information and this is the simplest
option of corporations for example you
google the name of the vendor
you google disclosure policy and
disclosure policy has all the
information the more complicated variant
is when they don't have this policy and
you have to apply skills of searching in
the internet at least to find any
context from them
okay we're going to call those things
with their own names
of course
you are searching for their even mail
for example one a chinese vendor was
reported through the sales they've
entered and by the way they've reacted
very fast to these sales at the same
time security of a certain mail they
don't have anything like it so if
you will come one time second time
through the sales and then they will be
able to roll out the page with policy of
disclosure of vulnerabilities how it was
happening with this chinese vendor
because in response to our letter after
a certain period of time
they've told us okay we've made this
page you will find the contact
information and if you will send
something please follow this link
this option
is also viable
then also the company is represented in
a certain bank bounty platform or the
link in this situation the platform
connects the company with the researcher
and with the help of the service or the
web formula
information about vulnerability is being
transferred from the researcher to the
vendors so they have to fill the certain
form you should provide them certain
detailed information
you write something or you just fill the
basic form well if you feel the basic
form under link
they do ask about some certain basic
things about vulnerability and then they
open a ticket within this ticket you can
communicate with the vendor
pro
well i'm going to tell you tomorrow
about it some fun cases when you could
report vendor to the back bounty
but then
the sanctions have influenced this
process and how we've been searching for
the way out of this situation so you've
been you're going to be speaking about
some fun cases how many of those fun
cases do you have well about 10 of them
can you give me one today once a day
just as a
teaser
okay
i will speak about the one that i wasn't
going to speak about uh tomorrow
it's a simple case it was a very tragic
case for us as researchers
at the same time we had a happy end for
the users
it's a sanction related story when we
try to get in touch with bender the
vendor does not get in touch with us we
are searching for this vendor to all the
channels we're writing to this vendor
then finally we find russian rep office
and we find a russian representative and
we say to them we send repo to your
headquarters organization nothing
happens
do you want us to send it to you so we
send it to russian rep office
we send a report and it was accepted to
our personal contacts and we've been
informed that this report have reached
their own research team
inside of the vendor company they've
looked at this vulnerability they found
it they were able to produce the patch
and then we've lost the contacts
for long it was continued for a certain
period of time but after a certain
period of time they came back to us
through this russian rep office and
they've told us
yes
we
have discovered this vulnerability we
have fixed it
so now users will be able to install the
update but we are not going to mention
you anywhere
yeah i wanted to hear this tragic story
yeah because the researcher wants to be
referred
because he needs to have a little piece
of glory after he has notified the
vendor that i've done his job at least
say things official things somewhere in
the news can you show my name or
whatever
i do remember you've been telling us fun
stories when you had to feel a
notification for the vendor so when you
submit information about vulnerability
to manufacturers or to the vendors
vendors should receive and give you cv
and you've been telling us how it was
happening
you give spoilers about tomorrow i want
to speak about it tomorrow please but
briefly speaking just in couple of words
without any details we have taught our
vendors
to receive cve for their own
vulnerabilities but tomorrow you will
have different
and more detailed information well
these can be automated and it would be
the right thing to do writing to do from
the point of view of researcher to
understand
but if bander denies you in getting this
id it's not always because they don't
want to sometimes it's just because they
don't know and you have to help the
vendor
okay can you give us three top three
advices for the researcher how to
properly you can prepare the vendor how
can you prepare your vendor how can you
teach the vendor to work with
vulnerabilities well the most important
thing is uh the human factor human
relations we need to understand that on
the other side we also have real humans
so should we send get pictures no it
could be the end of the communication
process and discovery of vulnerabilities
but in the beginning you should be very
serious but friendly
and so that on the other side on the
side of the vendor people also should
understand that you came to them not to
blackmail but as a human to another
human you want to share these
discoveries to make their product better
and safer
and i think this is a step number one
step number two well i have a question
please don't forget about the step
number two and three but i have a
question i work in the press
public relations department and my
working mail receives millions of
letters and sometimes i receive letters
like
well i have discovered certain
vulnerability in one of your whatever
can you reply to me well honestly i
think that this is fishing
and this is the end of my communication
with this address
you can redirect these letters to me and
i'm going to tell you whether it's right
or wrong so i should send them to you
copy me
if ask will approve it i will look at it
but
how can you write a letter so that you
wouldn't be considered to be a fishing
attack
first of all you have to introduce
yourself because when two people even on
the street when they want to get
acquainted with each other and ask
something from each other first of all
the
good command code who are you i'm this
and these days i do these this and these
so give minimal information about
yourself that can be checked
then you can start telling about some
things
and which
to the fact that you do know
about the product or you've discovered
vulnerability and some minimal details
yes it's understandable that you should
disclose all the information as a
researcher because
who knows
if as a researcher you have approached
the wrong person
and
maybe you're delivering information
about the zero-day vulnerability to a
wrong person it's not a responsible
approach
so first of all you have to build a
connect with bender and you should
understand that even on the side of the
vendor not everybody should know about
technical details of certain
the vulnerability way to do it would be
to find contacts of those people inside
of this vendor company who are involved
in
what removing vulnerabilities in their
products so this is advice number two
you should
try to specify why is he denying you
why don't they want to communicate with
you maybe
it's not a negative story one vendor
says well i don't want to deal with you
maybe they're afraid or maybe they miss
some information and you need to help
them because not every vendor knows
which place in in the total process they
take because in the process they have
users and sometimes vendors forget
because we do everything for the user
and sometimes perception of the user
inside of the vendor that well they can
buy a new piece of hardware it will be
more safe than the previous one with
vulnerability and let them do that it's
also irresponsible and you have to
explain this to vendor
you have to explain their position
towards the end users so
that they wouldn't lose connection
with reality
it's not just about making the money
well in the end run it's all about the
money okay can you tell me please in
recent years or in recent six months a
lot of things have changed in our lives
and in cyber security as well and
definitely these changes have involved
vulnerability operations i know that
there are new requirements uh from the
side of regulators about updates and how
can we build our work in these
conditions well i'll give you a
recommendation on how can one properly
test and update the software we still
develop those recommendations but
nevertheless the idea is following
by now we have faced a situation when a
number of western and not western
foreign vendors have left russia
at the same time
sometimes
the sales are continued or some
employees are staying in the offices
here
but product support has been halted
so basically speaking russian buyers and
russian company which uses these foreign
software or the hardware
they have based the situation that
support was stopped but the life had not
stopped and global researchers they find
vulnerabilities in those products and
they inform vendors about it bender
produces updates but these updates are
not coming to russian companies
and this is problem number one problem
number two
when these updates can arrive but they
can have some non-documented injections
or drawings or some destructive
components which
after this update will shut down the
software or the hardware it's not a nice
situation and we would like to have a
certain instruction we would like to
have a certain recommendation
which
the company could follow in order to
safely test this update before
installing it
that's what i'm speaking about thank you
very much for team dear friends i would
like to remind you that these and many
other things for example
does a russian
meet friend needs
to search and do we need to search
vulnerabilities in the open source well
but dean is going to tell you about it
tomorrow in the framework of positive
hog days program which is going to be
started tomorrow but today we had a
brief spoiler vadim thank you very much
thank you julia please don't switch off
because i'm going to be replaced by
vladimir zapolianski and in his studio
he's going to have a new guest alexander
morozev and vladimir and alexander are
going to discuss problems of a cyber
defense on the side of organizations
and
how fast hypothetic
criminal can penetrate inside of any
company stay with us