let's continue talking about interesting
and unusual topics
and from space ships flying in outer
space
we're flying to the
theater we're going to speak about how
complicated technical not interesting
topics
can be presented to people in such a way
so that they can be
astonished
they would become happy
and start acting so we will speak
how technical topics can be
brought to ted speech and i have two
guests here
i'm really happy
in order for you to understand who
you're speaking to oxana
is ted ex
street
yes i remember
was able to
promote his topic very complicated topic
to this ted speech
twice
yeah twice he was able to do it twice
and it's not the limit
so i wanted to discuss this with you
this situation
i hope you're going to tell us do we
need topics like that and do people
expect news from the world of cyber
business and cyber technologies yes of
course organizers wait for something
like that and if you will look at
organizer as the architect of the event
and taking consideration the fact that
this event should uh contain information
about all the spheres so technologies
are something new constantly developing
has a quotation or a quota for this
technical presentation
but organizers usually go to people that
everybody hear about of course i would
like to call
edward snowden if i would have a choice
or maybe who else is very popular david
young evgeny
those that everybody know
everybody heard ivan such golf until
recently
but everybody else
they speak about themselves
they speaking themselves to their own
brand
and then they come to tedx or maybe they
have to write to the organizers and of
course we want to know people want to
know because this is where the future is
they'll probably understand you
that these topics they have to be
carried by well-known people or maybe
people
who are well-known and who are super
professionals in their topic they can
also speak at the tedx and be
interesting speakers there and become
interesting for the organizers but for
the organizers it's not always
understandable to all the technologies
but these topics have to be presented
but another topic is
how many of those ideas inside of the
cyber security topic or technologies and
everything else
i think that we can dig very deep
because we've been speaking about
robots will they enslave us or not if
it's not going to be punished and then
we've been speaking about
the data that should be treated properly
everybody speaks about it
the one who wants to speak he needs to
search for a new aspect of the same
topic
can you tell us how you've been looking
for the new aspect
when you've been getting ready for the
tedx
he participated in the tedx two times
and you had topics about what
it was long time ago it was something
very popular
it was about personal confidentiality
and how can you treat
your own pictures
where you can lose your personal
confidentiality and how can this be
negative to us which threats we can see
the first presentation was an overview
presentation and then i tried to say
that
cyber security is very important and we
can't even imagine which consequences
they cyber security from cameras from
your phones from computers from the
internet devices
it can lead us to
very real negative consequences in the
physical world when people have been
losing their apartments
they were not able to enter their smart
houses because they were tuned
improperly
what do you think is that that and it's
a task it's a task for you
your favorite combination of words uh
from your work life
computer incidents okay something else
in this accommodation there are two
words i begin one uh begins with t
another with h
threat hunting so the task
oksan is with us and we are the
examination team
you have a task
you should invent how you're going to
tell us about threat hunting in such a
way so that it would become
interesting that would be exhilarated
and we would think that this topic is
worthy of ted speech
threat hunting
it's very difficult for roxanna she
doesn't know what it is
well i know these two words
informational security this is a
separate area of activities very
important activity because the most
important activity in threat hunting
is to make hypothesis
for specific infrastructure specific
companies for
maybe industry
information
in the area of informational security to
make hypothesis and these hypotheses
usually related to the question of
discovery of
fraudsters inside of the infrastructure
and then you start to check these
hypotheses and you have to try
retrospectively
look at
whether there was a penetration of a
criminal in the infrastructure if it was
or was not is it a truthful hypothesis
maybe it has to be specified or improved
and thanks to these
you should find in infrastructure those
hackers that you were not able to
discover previously and when this
hypothesis works once through its
attacks
then the process is built in such a way
so that these hypotheses should work
continuously and ideally it should
become a new detector new knowledge of
informational security products
and it would search for hackers without
humans
okay can you repackage this term can you
tell us story about it
we can give him 15 seconds to think
about it well first of all you can use
some metaphorical statement a bright
example
for
dummies
which idea comes to your mind well it's
not the most important thing about this
explanation of something it's a good
thing
in simple words what complicated things
but what is also important is to show
the usefulness for the one who is
listening well the usefulness for the
one who is listening
let's flip this story to another side
because honestly speaking at the given
moment of time the informational
security market has a big
thirst for
qualified employees
and others for those people who are
burning for their work and they love to
work and many people when you speak
about computer science computer security
information security and when you speak
about this technology many people think
that this is boring not interesting
mathematics physics
some complicated technical skills but
honestly speaking it's not like that
honestly speaking it involves colossal
field or creativity and threat hunting
is one of those elements
related with creativity so speaking in
analogies
make a hypothesis
that i want to fly from one mountain to
another mountain which wings i need for
that
for the first time you can select
unsuccessful form of the wings and you
die but
usually you try try try trying to
discover something new which is gonna
become useful become important and this
is a colossal element of creativity it's
a very important charge for your brain
and
even people who can find parallels
between different spheres of life
they can because what about digital
technologies well digital technologies
is the mirror of our real life that's
what digital technology is and honestly
speaking we have to transfer
those things
in which we have skills in our daily
life into the digital life same for the
threat hunting we need to discover uh
threats
for example when somebody approaches us
in the street can i look at your wallet
how much money do you have in your
wallet well how much money
can you give me your phone number to
make a call well that's another one
and everybody understands it everybody
makes an assessment uh
but in some cases you can give a mobile
phone to a person maybe really something
bad happen with the person and this
person needs to make a call
so we do know how to make assessments
and during the evolution we know how to
make assessments is it true or not
should but when in the messenger
somebody writes you can you give me your
phone number of your email address
please follow the link give the password
and login doesn't include those factors
so how can we transfer these factors
from real world into digital world and
how by using these factors we can
discover criminals well the flight of
the bumblebee the flight of the
creativity
interesting topic
in your conversation alexis
i've heard five different directions
which can be divided into five different
speeches
the most beautiful things already have
been verbalized you should have one idea
and one topic and some specific steps
which users should make here and now
because they are not going to remember
two ideas three ideas
but it's an interesting topic especially
if you have invented well
informational security
well it is so interesting because it
might involve this this and that
we have a lot of fun
here can you tell me please is it
difficult
because when you evaluate who's going to
be included into the program which
criteria do you use
for the future speakers should there be
known people or the topic should be
interesting
well well people it's if there's a topic
you know nothing about it to the
authority you will definitely be able to
convey this message to everybody else
but usually i have three criterias first
the availability of the idea because
even if it's a cool well-known speaker
but he has no idea that he wants to
share with other people
then we don't have this presentation but
what is idea can you give me an example
of an idea well i do have the ideas
while sitting here
idea which can be packaged into a
twitter statement which is a short but
not basic for example if you take a
speech of one of my favorite and one of
the well-known ted speeches
ken robinson about the school his idea
that the modern school kills creativity
and we have to change it very good idea
but then through stories through
personal examples he tells us it in such
a way so that we look at his
presentations and we cry and we say that
yes the school has to be changed and i
will start today with my kids i will
treat them differently i'll follow their
individuality
so it should
lead to a certain action not necessarily
but at least
it should be verbalized if you can
verbalize something it means that you
have understood it and remember the
second thing it's the expert expertness
it's not necessarily that this person
should be a mega superstar like elon
musk yes of course it would be wonderful
but it's not necessary and it's
sufficient if you work in a sphere
which is connected with your idea and if
alexi for example is going to write to
the organizers of anybody and he said i
will speak about the flight
to the mars what the mass has to do with
it are you flying to the mars are you
researching the topic of the mosque
well the previous speaker was from mars
so the expertness should be related to
the topic this could be a number of
publications this could be some
i don't know patents
which you have had in your sphere maybe
inventions you've had in it and the
earlier person starts working his brand
the better it is for other people in
other spheres and number
three some presentation skills at least
basically it's not a commercial
conference
so we want to keep a balance between
efforts that you spend for preparing the
speaker
and the result
is it difficult to prepare a speaker
yes and no
if the speaker wants to get ready
nothing difficult in there but if he
doesn't want he will never come to you
there are complicated stories when we
have very strong public relations
manager and he says well we're going to
prepare with somebody else good person
good topic uh but not something is not
working so if the person has no desire
to invest into the training nothing's
going to work
do you agree yes i do yes i agree
well the question you ask the answer you
get
it is
difficult to stop
speaking technological language and try
to explain in simple words
in understandable words in analogies
especially to those people who
understand nothing in computer security
and things that you do or why it might
be important to them
so a selection of these words proper uh
metaphorical comparisons this is the
most complicated part
when i was thinking
that we have to talk
to each other i've googled
what presentations we might have
especially those related with cyber
security on ted and i've discovered
three big areas one of them is
confidentiality and personal data the
second area everything which is related
with our favorite gadgets
all this stuff and direction number
three about
how cool are those hackers okay so both
of you tell me please what do you think
why these three topics
[Music]
resolution
well speaking about the end users they
ask themselves a question why am i
listening this
because maybe
something complicated
and it's very difficult to build
connection with the end user and maybe a
state commercial secret nobody has
prohibited in any country technologies
are developing very fast they're
entering the area of strategic interests
of those countries where they are
invented so there should be a proper
balance between all those things
not don't you think that people don't
know anything
and that you have to tell and speak
about new stories
maybe i need to explain
but there's a interesting for a person
what he understands and something that
is closer to him
so if you will speak about some
peculiarities
of highly loaded systems discovering on
the flight something something something
some samsung even you not you'll be
interested in such a speech so if you
build connection between usefulness then
of course
it's going to be interesting
but these are topics which are on the
surface
that's why
when the
cream was removed from the surface there
will be people
desiring going deeper into these topics
and tell us something new something more
accessible something more difficult in a
more accessible language well a
philosophical question to both of you
let's try to philosophize why
why you do what you do do you do ted and
why
she doesn't why do you participate in
this death who's going to be the first
one
i'm going to be the first one
well ted
yes
i'm really confident that events like
these terrorists
are changing our society around
they make people better they help people
to get expressed
for ideas to be expressed
that well it was so important for me i
wrote a book
it helped me to express myself it helped
me to receive certain support
so it's
it's a human growth
yeah somehow it is and it's always nice
to be in the company of same thinkers
good and cool people so it's community
that you build around yourself it's
always wonderful
at the same time
no
looking at what i do in my work
i separate it as a hobby
when you say why do you do that you
create a community of people who are
interested in working with each other
so we in security we work like you
in syria
we find interesting people
who are interested in talking to each
other it's an interesting concept it
really has touched me and i will think
about it for quite a while
why
did you apply those efforts to speak
there
well it's a new experience tedx getting
out of the comfort zone
and second of all cyber security it's
kind of a box in itself but we are all
boiling in this box together with each
other we're communicating the bird
language and we're not leaving this box
but there's a good analogy
with the rules of the road
because as soon as cars started
appearing here
we have evolved
and the person has learned a lot of
words this is zebra this is the light
street light
digital technology is penetrated into
our lives so much that when a person
receives smartphone in his hands he
should have a dual factor authorization
etc etc and if we being in this box
we're not going to tell the rest of the
world about it the world is not going to
change but if the world is not going to
change
these bad hackers
will become more and more successful
in making their cyber
crimes and it's going to be much more
difficult for us to win them and make
this world more secure
so the laziness moves the progress
to work less
to
work easier so let's try to educate our
users so that they wouldn't press all
the links plus 25
to your discount thank you very much
my dear friends today i was visited by
alexander proskovaksan thank you very
much the organizer of tedx
please google it
google her in social networks
partially prohibited in the territory of
our country but
go from another state
if you would like to see what's
interesting he was going to tell you
on the tedx and please don't forget that
each one of you
is a lot of interesting topics
and you can tell us about them don't be
afraid
disclose new horizons
and enter new doors including ted i'm
going to be happy to see cyber security
more of cyber security and right now i
would like to give studio to vladimir
zepolanski
[Music]
but he's going to stay here alone in a
couple of minutes but alone
and he's going to be joined
to online
he's going to be joined
by alexey eugene
and they're going to discuss
cyber security problems fintech in new
realities i think it's also a topic for
ted