and our next talk is going to focus on
inverse substitution
this is a topic that's been relevant for
the past uh several months and it's here
to stay in order to understand better
what's happening i have with me maxine
phillip of director for development
business development positive
technologies
hello
talk about empire substitution and let's
start by your assessment of the current
state of inverse substitution being the
process was initiated some time ago then
it was intensified and something should
be happening right now so what is the
current standing of input substitution
let's start with your maxim
well
from outside of our company and i think
we have a pretty objective perspective
on the things input substitution today
has become a process that studied let's
go and you don't need to persuade people
in anything last week there was a
presidential order uh which said that
from 2025
and no uh
protection means from
not friendly countries should be used
but even before this order came out it
was became clear before the start of the
military
uh operation but even before that
actually like i said uh
foreign began to leave the russian
market and import substitution is a need
that must be addressed quite
quickly
it must be addressed quite quite quickly
i mean
today uh customers are building their
processes so that here and now they can
solve the problems that they are facing
because of a certain position of some of
the vendors all vendors take um
different routes to leaving the russian
market and we hear which we hear stories
we know from our customers that
some
updates uh
some updates led to a freezing of their
products uh other products are not
updated yet other products were left
without support and we know that cyber
security primarily is expertise
expertise and updates
that
should be downloaded that should be
installed and the products can be become
obsolete very quickly in absence of the
updates in an absence of the expertise
and support and this is part of our
new reality we see that many of our
customers are looking
to substitute the solutions that are
leaving the russian market or
potentially are under the risk of
being withdrawn from the russian markets
um it's the new normal
what about you what do you think about
empire substitution today well i agree
with what maxim said i um
i also wanted to talk about the market
in uh general and my feeling of the
market in general in the last three
months the time compressed
and empire substitution
before february
[Music]
before february was a hobby
or maybe it was a kind of a pretext and
not to do any substitution some people
believed in it others didn't but uh
today i agree with maxim time has
compressed and i don't see around me any
non-believers in the near future it's an
irreversible process whether we like it
or not is going to be done
today
trust your foreign vendors
[Music]
i mean the answer to everyone is clear
one way or another
substitution programs must be launched
and the customers are doing it as we
speak
this is a double iron curtain double
iron curtain
there are no external technologies and
internally uh the customers do not trust
foreign products and i do not want to
buy foreign products
we even have
uh maybe not very positive cases from
the market but um
we we had contracts right to supply
foreign vendors products the contracts
were signed before february and now the
customers are trying to revert them the
customers are returning the products and
they are asking for a refund
well
what do you do well we are negotiating
i'm talking now about the markets
attitude to foreign products really it's
important
the customers we are also in close
contact with the customers and they are
saying that even if uh
today you uh do a kind of a mental
experiment all the foreign vendors are
coming back um tomorrow and they're
offering huge discounts many of the
customers will say no to them in the
past this risk was
seen as a hypothetical
is just a threat the governments are
negotiating that way and we are
businesses we are outside of
those negotiations but now the risk is
real and even if they come back the risk
is still yeah many customers in the
future would not be
willing to place their bets on the
vendors on the
uh suppliers who just like that oh no we
because of geopolitics many companies
want to be outside of geopolitics it's
our business we
don't want to be involved with
geopolitics but they can't be left
outside of geopolitics
they can't stay neutral uh
you are as a customer
i mean customers are the greatest
treasurer uh they must be the number one
priority but uh the customers are being
set up
what about you what about numbers do you
see any differences in the import
substitution
do you see the trend accelerating
well actually i will agree with
colleagues and
before foreign vendors left as the
substitution situation was well first of
all
substitution can be split into two parts
there is infrastructure and there is
information security infosec and these
are two different
processes
for sac began to develop russian infosec
started to develop much earlier and it
started with the development of
technologies and products while
infrastructure
impr
uber substitution uh studied later and
there is a big difference between these
two components the process of
transformation substitution information
security started a long time ago and now
it's more obvious
and it's more visible as a result
we have today a lot of available russian
products that we never had before in the
last three months we saw
a surge of
new uh new vendors
well do they came out of the blue it's
just that they were not visible well
they adjusted they were not visible but
now there is demand for these products
our partners our customers have demand
for substitution of this or that product
and suddenly you see companies that were
developing some niche products for some
uh one two customers but now they are
going national they are going big time
and
it's one of the probably benefits of the
current situation these technologies are
becoming more available these
technologies perhaps are not very mature
yet but soon they will become mature
as more and more customers use them
as to the demand
we see in all segments the demand
growing in infrastructure and infosec
all kinds of classes of solutions but
the most important
thing probably that we felt is
protection of apps and web services and
infosec web
and network security exactly now
security something we discussed
yesterday
you asked about numbers
this year again i would divide into two
parts sales request for sales and
requests for other services right
they demand in
sales
is growing at 20 30
every year which is quite a traditional
rate of growth
there are sales but i mean we are
talking about now right yeah we are
talking about the start of the year
but what's interesting is
we see a great demand for new products
completely new products
in march we'll launch the website it's
called abner vistos
that are you
update yourself that are you uh where
you can find a rational analog to
foreign makes in the last
say 45
days we had about 9 000 unique kids
there unique users
uh those who came to the website to find
a russian analogy of foreign products
wow this is an interesting topic russian
analogs
do you think we'll be able to
[Music]
substitute foreign products
well as lava brought up
demand into the conversation
all our sales happen through a partner
network
and all of our partners
are feeling quite positive
to their clients
uh various technologies
and customers are asking for our
products in particular they are saying
where is positive products
and partners and and customers they are
planning their input substitution in a
very precise
manner the infrastruct security
landscape
is being substituted with russian
analogues
the departure of foreign vendors
and i would estimate it
at 80 billion perhaps rubles yes 80
billion robots
and most of that market is addressable
with positive technologies products they
are the segments where positive
technologies has their own solutions and
today the biggest challenge for us is to
build our relations with customers and
with partners in a way that will enable
us to be efficient and commercially
successful
the value of infosec market
we are not sure if it's going to grow or
not
there is this big segment i mean we are
talking about dozens of billions of
robots here
that's been left and today the market
will be redistributed between other
players
let me add something to maxim's words
in infosec market
in this market
you have
different stacks of solutions and these
different types of solutions have
different
deployment cycles
in infrastructure
the cycle time will be longer and will
be
more costly and labor-intensive
what i was talking about look what kind
of range a year two years that's the
normal cycle for a project
implementation
another thing is that not all solution
stacks have
russian analogs
that can be a one-to-one match
to foreign western
solutions
so you have to be creative
the paradigm that we are broadcasting to
the market today is that
you need to approach input substitution
with good thoughts i mean you have to
start with your current
landscape
a trusted environment can be built with
a residual use of
western solutions
there are good analogs
for
security
monitoring systems like the products
from positive
and also security monitoring systems are
a good defense against cyber attacks and
they must be built on the basis of
domestic solutions but again you have to
think about the time
time frame of the
project deployment i mean customers can
already get results within six months
and
since today we are fighting cyber war
i mean these solutions are very much in
demand and since we're talking about
deployment and long times
once you
open the door to a customer and
substitute a foreign product there the
vendor can stay there for one time
because to change it back i mean if
tomorrow the reality is different and we
get back to the old tracks
the president's decree
talks about 2025 and 2025 uh the
landscape must be free of the solutions
from unfriendly countries
and many people in the market comment
that this is such a long time such a
long time why not now well i think that
it is a short time in fact we don't have
much time many heavy solutions of
information security that require
designing
of the infrastructure surrounding them
uh
left alone the i mean without even
mentioning the installation the
deployment and live systems i mean this
is such a short time frame and today the
customers have already started to run
and i think that this is a hard to
achieve deadline
this presidential decree also says that
uh
the solutions from unfriendly countries
must be substituted while we
know that some countries are neutral and
last week one of the top government
officials said that one of the
government meetings i show that the list
of unfriendly countries will not be
different by december 2024 so the
question is what are we to substitute
all solutions not everything well i
think that all of the stack must be
replaced with domestic solutions
what about industries which industries
needs
member substitution immediately
well from the industry perspective the
government has always been the driving
force i mean governments owned
state-owned companies have always led to
the process for them is critical
as to
the future
of various industries i think that we
should primarily think about
financial structures transportation
energy telecom these are the industries
that have great need for security and
they are often victims of all kinds of
cyber threats and also potentially this
market is open to russian products
historically in the russian market of
cyber security one of the key drivers
has always been regulatory requirements
i think it's something that we should
still consider and factor in the
presidential decree defines the
structures and the legal entities for
which
that process is critical the
system building the government-owned
government
authorities but what we see today in
fact is commercial banks commercial
banks have nothing to do with government
[Music]
ownership
they are running very very fast
because they feel their needs
they feel the urgency
it's not some
[Music]
you know
government official
regulating something
for the sake of the greatness of the
country but it's the commercial
companies that feel
they need cyber security cyber stability
is the same as business stability
non-stop operation of business and we
see this demand coming from the market
today
and to
summarize say
it's irreversible i mean the process is
irreversible
and it's going to last for the next
several decades
why am i saying this hypothetically even
if all the foreign vendors come back
tomorrow there is no more any trust to
them when trust in a sensitive area such
as cyber security
means
lots it means loads
like you you come to your family talk to
the family doctor knows everything about
you and then the doctor panics and
leaves you and says no i'm not going to
treat you anymore and i'm going to tell
all your secrets to all of the world
and then in the week's time the doctor
comes back and says to say hey i
panicked i was wrong uh let me treat you
again i don't think you will continue
your relations with the doctor when you
enter the infrastructure you become a
trusted doctor right a physician the
client trusts your technology the client
trusts
your expertise you develop the protein
technology together you make it better
so just to
change you know the positive solution uh
for some other vendor solution it will
be uh
it will take a long time it will be
expensive this is something that our
customers have to do now they are
changing foreign solutions
for domestic ones and they're doing this
because they really do not have a choice
but if they had a choice
if they had a choice i mean this is
expensive it's expensive and it takes a
long time if they had the choice they
wouldn't be doing it and they would be
uh in their right so when russian
infosec
vendors partners enter the landscape of
a customer it means that they will stay
so again that's why i'm saying that the
processes is reversible uh for the next
decades it's irreversible and it's
ambitious
because
we all now enter a new field of
opportunities there is demand from the
market there is regulation there is
support from the state
there is cyber war i wanted to say thank
god there is cyber war but well there is
cyber war everything we are doing now is
not going to be tested not on a virtual
mock-up at the standoff is going to be
tested in
real life settings and if we can
demonstrate the
infosec uh
uh invo sec maturity of russian
solutions then it's a good opportunity
yes exactly i think that in the infosec
russia can offer excellent products to
the global community we can demonstrate
that in the country we've got efficient
solutions that can achieve
infosec objectives that can
make
unacceptable events impossible
and is built on the stack of
technologies that are developed and
produced in country and we don't have an
option
we do not have a choice yesterday we had
several interviews uh where we mentioned
three global leaders in uh infosec uh
everyone agrees that the united states
israel and russia are all leaders of
information security russia was also
always mentioned as one of the leaders
of infosec we've got
brainy guys here guys and girls who know
how to code
so the market is huge
right
the products are available what are the
risks
at the same time
i can talk to this topic
i see two main risks
one risk
as always i'm responsible for sales and
the nightmare of a salesperson as the
customer runs out of money in normal
budgets they can't pay so the one big
risk is
uh customers will not have money they
will not have budgets
the degree that we keep referring to
today because it's such a new regulation
comes directly from the russian
president that says that information
security is a priority for the state it
is a priority for
individual companies
and institutions that's why i think that
i mean it is the answer it's going to
address the risk in a way and
information security will be budgeted
for
risk 2 is country related it's
everything that's
related to hardware this
risk is
still with us
the positive uh develop solutions but
our software solutions recommend
hardware platforms today we have
problems
in this area and some projects have been
suspended or postponed or slowed down
because of the lack of
hardware
distributors who are bringing in
hardware and the customers and the
government even are trying to find
solutions they are trying to
get the support they are trying to find
uh hardware
delivery channels for our software
products and we are thinking about it as
well well at the moment we can overcome
this shortage of hardware new platforms
we hope very much that it will be model
next several months but this risk is
significant and i'm going to name it as
the second biggest risk
our
strengths is in the people is in their
brains and in the level of training of
the people
it's a risk
it's not a problem it's a task that must
be
solved must be addressed we also see the
support from the government secondly the
industry itself begins to renegotiate
the customers the vendors the partners
the integrators they
come to a new uh agreement that they
need to replicate themselves that is to
say they need to invest into training as
a basis for our development
and maybe i can add something to maxim's
words
in terms of budgets a year ago at phd um
at the plenary session i was saying that
the top
managers of companies need to pay close
attention to infrasecurity so you have
to be careful what you wish for right
today
it's always think about it
well i got repeat foreign vendors come
back to russia why am i saying this then
the process if they do the process will
slow down and uh now we are being
propelled uh very fast in the
development of these technologies and
promotions products in the market
we are catering to the demand that
exists but it can slow down if
something goes wrong if
uh
the sanctions are lifted if the foreign
vendors are making a comeback i think
that this will be a new risk for the
development of domestic technologies
i think today there are plenty of
opportunities for the russian
technologies to
be
not even in the top three to be the
number one in the
i've world receiving use of this cyber
battle there were three hacks of the
railway
so import substitution is a very
relevant
topic especially for the companies and
industries on which we depend
and i'm
happy to hear the optimism and your
words i'm happy to hear you have been
optimistic about the future of the
russian infrastack a market
let's do good products let's make
secure products reliable yeah that's
what we are working on