and i'm going to be moderating a quick
session here at positive hack days on
the i.t and infosec market analytics let
me welcome our guests we've got with us
ceo of national credit ratings agency
alexander
t advisor analytical center
colleagues
security is something that is the focus
of our attention here from any
perspective uh things changed uh since
the end of february and i was
trying to analyze the market my stuff i
don't understand where to start
what should be the starting point
all our
traditional methods do not work
the reports or past reports on how the
company uh
or any company would be growing it
doesn't matter anymore
well thank you very much it's my first
time here thank you for inviting
everything's changed uh dramatically
and historic
data is no longer relevant
dynamics and external
restrictions create the situation of
complete uncertainty
in march
things were very quiet
people will be planning just for one day
and they will be analyzing uh in the
one-day dimension
we have a better reference plan and in
our racing agency we focus on the future
and the best
uh helpers uh to us in our work other
companies themselves
before february
take an outsider view of the companies
we could work with
public data
now to get
quick feedback from companies through
interviews or questionnaires is perhaps
the only way
over short periods of time
we are not
making any plans even for a year maybe a
quarter two quarters ahead this is our
current uh time frame
and uh and now i wanted to address and
use this opportunity to address the
companies and the industries not to
close off uh given the circumstances
there is huge trends you
cut off information uh supply well we
didn't have much information anyway well
yes but now we are having even less than
less than that people are
using the current situation not to
disclose anything about themselves but
think about your future shareholder
value and market capitalization
it's not going to disappear right so
let's share the information uh and use
it for anal analysis
okay which parameters can we analyze
today alexander
companies i mean how do you filter them
how do you sort them a company is
in operation today and it's gone
tomorrow today it's a
an immersion startup and
tomorrow it's gone because it cannot
pay off the credits
well um analytics or intelligence
consists of several segments right
there is
qualitative and quantitative analytics
there is analytics
for the purposes of forecasting and
of historical data
in the
times in the last two years
it became much more difficult to do
qualitative analysis not all companies
are happy to disclose their numbers and
they are
no longer willing to share their
forecasts already in 2020 2021 it became
difficult to get the forecast out of the
companies caveat changed the market uh
substantially and it was hard to predict
what would happen tomorrow now it's next
impossible
the special operation killed off
analytics right
well yeah kind of not all of it though
of course you can't do much with
qualitative analytics
but uh or rather quantitative analytics
but there is qualitative analytics and
your understanding of trends
and the understanding of the demand
when talking to customers you can make
assumptions as to
which of their products will be in
demand
yes but
it's hard to get numbers today
like you were saying i agree
today probably we need to
focus on analyzing trends
and the impact of the macro environment
onto our market rather than what we did
before
when we would be drawing pie charts and
growth crafts here on here probably you
can do it today but it would be
meaningless
yes
i mean you see how fast
things are changing
working with customers and with their
information is
probably the only source
that we have
budgets are changing budgets are being
reviewed together with priorities and
financial capabilities the companies
respond to the current situation
differently someone some lost there are
some companies that actually won and
from uh what is being happening right
now so we'll
analyze that
and companies themselves like i said
they are a good source of information
especially the information can be
verified through third parties
to go back to pie charts and market
shares
now the number ones the number twos
exactly yes so now
currently
most of foreign vendors left the russian
market or they suspended their
operations or they are you know sitting
on the quiet and uh
it would be impossible to get any
numbers or any other information from
them
but
in the information security markets i
mean we have
hundreds of players and we have dozens
of segments and these segments are not
disappearing
so we will continue analyzing russian
players and those companies who decided
to stay and for them the numbers will
not be predictive rather they will be
analyzing the uh past periods data uh
especially if you have data a year by
year the annual reports
but does it make sense to to do this
kind of analysis like like you were
saying
today the
only
the only uh thing worth analyzing is
qualitative information but okay in a
particular segment you have one two
three russian vendors but
not more than that i mean we all know in
every segment who is number one who's
number two and actually even those
numbers are not important they do not
matter there is a leader there is the
follower but does it make sense to to
report market shares or anything you're
a gift
well actually yes i think it makes sense
and we are not it's not about the whole
market of information security as such
but we need to identify the segments
that the customers want to see products
in and in those segments
there will be top fives top sevens top
tens it's not like we have a couple of
companies only in each of these segments
is not for the vendor only a rating
exists also in the interest of the
customer
the customers use ratings to uh
to organize attendees to enter into
negotiations with different vendors
speaking about uh various pie charts and
everything the market size but you have
to also remember about the general
financial situation of these companies
what their financial standing is to go
back to the
meaning of business they want to attract
investment they want to
be financially sound information
security has always been a closed market
but they need in resources even in this
market it's pretty high and in order to
get this need
addressed the outsiders need to
understand what these companies
look like
how they feel themselves
i talked to many vendors
and they were saying
it's important for us we need to see the
numbers to talk to financial
institutions we need to
present ourselves to them exactly a jp
morgan report uh on a particular sector
its dynamics its financial standing its
indebtedness its uh revenue dynamics so
i agree we need numbers we still need
numbers we need time series
so that
when the years go by we would be able to
see how the company survived this period
uh what was happening to them in the
difficult times
a quick comment the investors who
wanted
to find startups
with international ambitions many of the
investors are now switching to
domestic players
they
understand all about improv substitution
it's gone beyond government sec the
government sector
it affects now not only government owned
companies but also the commercial sector
so the potential there is very high
investors are
looking at the sector and they need the
numbers to be guided by and then there
are regulators surface beef stack
the ministry of industry the ministry of
telecom they also need numbers
why do they need numbers
[Music]
well to provide support or to offer
targeted support to different players i
mean there are all kinds of uh or not to
use or not to apply exactly or not you
apply any targeted support
the numbers can be
uh used as an argument in the dialogue
with the regulator when different
initiatives have been launched not
enough to
harm
[Music]
how
sensitive how painful
is the departure of
idc gartner
forester as far as i understand
these companies also
suspended their work here because i mean
many again were guided by the
opinion of these companies because they
are big brands they are well known when
we did analytics ourselves and our
analytics
was not treated the same as the analysis
performed by international companies
doesn't give us a chance as analysts
to
for our voice to be heard better all
this niche will be left unoccupied
well is this a good thing or a bad thing
i think it's a bad thing
still
because competition is always good and
it promotes products it promotes
industries
you have to
uh think better than your neighbor you
win in this competition so it's bad
it's bad whether it's a chance or it's
not a chance for russian analysts well
yes of course it's a chance but it's a
chance that will not be
becoming true without any
feedback from the customer companies
of course we do not have as much
reputation as international uh
colleagues had
and it will take time for us to build up
this reputation but we have several
years to do it
i agree it's not like it's a chance but
it's it's an obvious
thing i mean it's uh apparent that you
need to move into the niche now that
it's vacated and we did it and we will
continue building up our uh capacity but
if you review key reports of itc on
the main industries that they made
public
they are mostly analyzing foreign
vendors foreign vendors are no longer
with us
so
the methods that the idc used
they used questionnaires they used
interviews
they
you know they've been using these
practices for years
and even if i idc stayed
they wouldn't have much to analyze left
analytical technology right another
important aspect is analysis of
technology and analysis of products
[Music]
what they know how to do well
is
promote their vision
the western markets
to change we will not be able to follow
it closely we do not have our own vision
here on the other hand
well i think that we need to build up
our own expertise we need to
educate people who will have experience
and understand the technology and
who will have hands-on experience and
who would be trusted i mean it applies
to any industry especially in i.t and
infosec
what they need
to to
to grow up so to say they need a
comfortable environment they need a
support environment a supportive
environment and investment it can be
cheap
this expertise doesn't come cheap
very well then i would like now to turn
to
analytics monetization we know that a
gardener report is expensive and they're
monetizing their expertise through the
sale of their data here
everyone
is used to public information
information that costs nothing
information for free
do you think they will be able to have a
switch to the western model
well we also have closed reports
uh probably we haven't been using this
model as actually as the open model but
we do have
reports for sale
[Music]
in
analytics they performed qualitative
analysis and i think that's something
that we need to uh
we need to go deeper into work with
vendors work with customers
create better reports
the model is quite workable i think
to the interested parties and here we
must go back
to
the idea of communication with the
companies it may sound like a for-profit
story but in fact there are many
interested parties there from the
government all the way to corporates
yes customers should also make their
suggestions on which analytics they need
and they should be open to analytical
companies by providing information uh by
alerting themselves to be interviewed or
questioned
we have five minutes left
there is another
topic that i think we must discuss
many big customers
today are switching to russian analogs
they are substituting foreign products
with russian analogues
and they need to be sure that the vendor
that the manufacturer has a sound
financial situation and a vision because
it's a risk we are paying several
million dollars today and in a couple of
years the company will be
dismantled the founders
will leave the company
start a new business
well uh
there is one tool the credit ratings
that's what we do it's what we
specialize in we are assessing the
financial standard of the company's
regulated industry it's been around for
many years and unfortunately
not even information security but rather
the whole i.t sector just because uh
there we do not have many classical
listed companies public companies
because not many companies are listing
are trading their bonds
in fact it's quite an inexpensive
service that can answer many of the
questions that you've just raised and
russian international western nation
investors will all understand the credit
rating
apart from the regulated uh segment i
mean you need to look at the company
history uh the company track record and
its current projects as well
whether the potential bidder the
potential
provider has many customers on notes how
stable his orders are
i mean all these things are not
regulated
but
we collect this information into a
public knowledge database
basis
it's a
an efficient tool
competition is very positive the more
different opinions there are the better
it is for the company itself
one contractor i mean
you might suspect that there is vested
interest but you have to have
many sources of information
and another quick question about the
startups markets
[Music]
i think that
we can forget about startups in russia
for the near future i am of the opinion
that the market will consolidate all the
small teams will be immediately
brought up or picked up
by bigger companies kirill what do you
think
well the classical definition of
startups
like a company existing for
i don't know in the next year or 18
months there is no market of angel
capitalism anymore so yeah
no classical stops
here but maybe inside family offices of
big investors
we may be seeing some uh small teams
emerging it's not it's not a start-up as
such but it's a capital-backed um
development it's not going to be mass
market definitely
yes there is no
well there are fewer angel investments i
agree
but
you know that we we have ecosystems we
have spin-offs and inside and around the
ecosystems the
nurses can the niches can be taken by
small companies spinoffs from ecosystems
the companies that are set up with the
money of big investors big corporations
when companies work for big customers uh
the developers see a niche and the
customer would be willing to finance as
a
project like this
uh with different motivation schemes for
the employees
well yeah i i think that ecosystems
whether we're going to have three five
different ecosystems in a while i think
here the market will segment
itself
a number of ecosystems
affiliated with big government on
corporations
in many cases it is already the case
look at ross telecom we'll look at spare
bank or ross adam ross adam has lots of
different stuff
actually
[Music]
yeah the important thing is not to lose
that
because it was a positive
development of the last several years uh
it's important that we don't lose it and
we need government support for it okay
colleagues thank you very much
it's been a pleasure
thank you to all the viewers and
listeners for being with us see you
later
stay tuned for public and not very
public
analytics at our websites