can every company be broken right now
we're going to speak about the level of
company defense
and how fast criminals can break into
organizations and we're going to speak
about it together with alexander moroz
of the head of uh
testing penetrate pen testing
department in positive technologies
hello sasha hello vladimir
okay let's begin with the main question
can every company be broken it's a very
good question but it's also a wide
question
so i will make
sure i will give you a wide response
first of all in the beginning i would
like to tell you what do we do
which projects do we have types of the
projects and i can tell you also about
approaches to
hacking
so you decided to prepare us yours we're
doing this this and this and this and
yes every company can be broken in okay
wonderful wonderful can you do it well
you wanted to hear my reaction i gave
you i gave it to you
well uh we have a more scientific
discussion right that's why i would like
to convey to our viewers the full volume
of information okay let's look at it
we do projects we analyze external
perimeter defense and the simplest
example of the external perimeter
is the website of the company we analyze
the level of internal infrastructure
defense and the 99 percent on the case
speaking about the internal
infrastructure we mean domain of the
microsoft active directory so this is a
must-have for most of the companies
so these are accounts which everybody
has authorization mail authorization how
to work in the internal network well
simplifying this situation yes you're
right
information level of the users we do
phishing distributions test phishing
distributions also we analyze wireless
networks uh security also we analyze
security of the access control systems
rfid cards for the access to
physical office or to a certain room in
the office
this is not the biggest part of our work
so from this point of view i'm not going
to emphasize too much so you're looking
at what can be broken then you check the
possibility of this vulnerability in the
company to all possible vectors all
different uh ways of accessing wi-fi of
id cards a corporate network possibility
of getting connected to a from the
external network to some infrastructural
facility yes these are projects where we
are not limited by one vector
and we have complex big projects very
often they are related with the red team
specifics when armed work is also being
responded by the internal defense team
but most of our work
is done on the basis of the contract on
the basis of the desire of any client to
check something at this point of time
like simulation of the hacker behavior
yes yes something like that
each of these projects
is one or another side of a simulation
of hacker activities okay let's go back
to your question can any company be
broken
well what's good about it
anything that can be measured is good
let's look at the numbers upon the
results of our work our colleagues
from the analytical team
they make
the annual statistical reports which are
publicly accessible of course without
any personification
you will not be able to find names of
the clients but these statistical uh
reports are available in our
ptsecurity.com internet site and
i would like to suggest i would like to
recommend you please compare those
reports for several recent years
and
from what is available right now
it's the analysis of our work for the
period
second half of 2020 and first six months
of 2021.
so the numbers for this period are
following the external perimeter
was broken into in ninety three percent
of cases by pen tester so if you would
take 93 if you take hundred companies 93
of them can be broken in from the
external perimeter
speaking about internal infrastructure
so from outside like i'm sitting here in
the network and i can get connected to
the infrastructure of that company
respectively to where am i located yes
you're absolutely right you're just a
person with a notebook and the internet
you don't have any privileges in the
company you don't have any accounts in
the company you just start from the
scratch from the street well roughly
speaking from the street
then
speaking about internal infrastructure
analysis speaking about getting maximum
privileges in the domain this number
will be even higher it's going to be 100
so in 100 of the cases you will get
privileges on the level of domain
administrator or similar
sorry
which means if you are getting connected
from inside of the company
not as a usual internet user which has a
laptop and the internet but you get
connected you have the access to
corporate network uh right then hundred
percent right yes
moreover i would like to
continue your idea very often we have
projects when we penetrate through the
external perimeter and we immediately
start making internal pen testing it's a
complex approach
complex projects
and in such cases
we in 100 of cases get admin privileges
well i should make a small remark what
are those privileges and what do they
give us
i will try to simplify everything but
having these rights you can enter any
server
and you can
execute any software on this server you
can enter any workstation of any
employee and you can execute any
software code
okay
in order to make it more understandable
for example i have
a file with salaries of the employees
so i have the file with all the salaries
of the employees on my laptop
and you can get access to it
yes if your workstation is in the
corporate domain which was compromised
and penetrated into of course we can get
access to your computer and we can
discover this file with the salaries of
the employees but if i have an access to
the system of money transfer if i have
an access to
some other secret information system
we can do observation over your computer
and we can launch
any
software we can emulate any actions that
you can do on your own laptop uh
and i would like to make another remark
coming back to the numbers
this 100
number that i was calling in the
beginning
about the analysis of the internal
infrastructure this hundred percent as a
number follows us all the years since
our department exists so the situation
is not improving from year to year
however
attentive viewers they have noticed uh
that we are speaking about something
that was happening one year ago and this
statistical information ends in the
middle of the year 2021. do you have any
fresh information yes we do
and right now we'll give you a spoiler
because this analytical report has not
been published yet however
right now
serious if you will look at the
data from the beginning of the year 2021
until today
of penetration to the external perimeter
is also on the level of 100
which means
that every company
at least from our statistical
information any company can be
penetrated into
from outside
by any person with a notebook and
internet
previously it was 93 and right now it's
100 because you have improved your
skills or the defense uh became worse
of course i highly evaluate the level of
professionalism of my team and from year
to year it becomes better and better
so partially it's a success
of the skillfulness of my team but on
the other side it tells us that
[Music]
as you could break into many companies
before the same companies can be broken
into right now and right now we have
this round number 100
this is awful things you're telling me
about
yeah we'll cut it away
company
you can break into
so many companies and there's a lot of
little organizations which have access
uh and they have a lot of important
financial information available in their
networks which means that all of them
can be can become
victims of hacker
which means that hackers can be anywhere
this is the main conclusion that we
might come to after my story and yes
unfortunately this is the situation
can you tell me please which are the
most vulnerable places from the point of
view of penetration
how hackers break into companies usually
you mean
testing the external perimeter or
anything else what what is the most
typical
penetration
tactics of hackers how they get inside
of the company well i understand your
question speaking about
real criminals
not about ethical pen testers and we are
those but speaking about real criminals
who don't approve any actions with the
company and they have certain
uh money-making motives
in most of the cases 57 of their cases
of initial penetration is using social
engineering methods
what are those let's discover them
which social engineering is mostly
applicable just recently i had a
situation
i get a call
you get a call
and in a rough voice without any
introduction person ask me
can you give your phone to your wife
they've been asking me to give my phone
to my wife
i stop the call and then immediately
they call me back from other numbers to
my number and this is also social
engineering it's not directed to
penetrate into the infrastructure of the
company of the employer but it's
directed against me as a human being and
it was the first time when i've been
attacked like that and this is also
developing
which are the most vulnerable places on
the side of the
social engineering and working with
people
you are right the methods of criminals
are developing
and this case was directed against your
bank accounts
but not access to the company that where
you work but speaking about getting
access
to
corporate infrastructure first of all i
should point out methods of
facing distributions
when user
receives a malicious code or the link to
malicious code
so this is an outdated method because a
fishing
distributions they've started long time
ago since nigerian spam
when rich
heir
of big amount of money of a certain
prince which lives in some african
country
is asking you to participate
in a scheme
of a money distribution and in order for
her to get this
heritage she'll give you 100 bucks it's
an old way and people still are
fighting for this yes it still works
and we do have a lot of statistics on
these
and i will compare
far-fetching
situations for example if you look at
the year 2017
according to our statistics
sixteen percent of users
which received uh the malicious letters
have launched these malicious code and
eleven percent of users
followed external link
and they have introduced their
authentication data
if you look at the year 20 and 21 and if
you look at their statistics it's going
to be much worse
and the launch of malicious file was
done by 31 of users and following the
link and introduction of authentication
data was done by 39 percent of users so
they don't learn anything yeah they
they are even forgetting about what they
have learned previously
i think this is forever with us
i wouldn't be such a fatalist i think
earlier or later our security will
become absolute
and it will reach zero however it will
still be viable for a long period of
time so the most vulnerable piece is
social engineering human beings phishing
emails they follow the link they put in
some
account data
step one step two and that's it
well speaking about the
real tactics of real fraudsters who
follow lucrative uh motives these are
fishing distributions
okay let's speak about different
industries is the level of security and
the level of protection uh against
hacker attacks depending from which
industry is this financial manufacturing
transportation
yes this is a good question okay let's
look in this direction first of all i
would like to tell you that it depends
first of all on the company and on a
team of i.t specialists that work with
this company but if you will compare uh
in white strokes if you will compare
different industries then perhaps
i can say that ahead of everybody from
the level of defense credit and
financial sector is ahead of everybody
and this is cognitively understandable
from the basic point of view because
financial sector
involves leaving money
and
when
criminal penetrates into a bank
with the availability of certain rights
to which he gains access he can transfer
to the swift system to the account he
owns or she owns or get access to the
atm network and launch malicious file
which will give a command for uh
printing out the full balance of the atm
but if you will look at this from the
position of numbers
as you know right now we actively
develop the topic of resultative cyber
security
maybe our viewers don't know about it
but can you tell me about this
yeah with a great pleasure
well resultative cyber security and i
will tell you in my own words
it's the security which is oriented at
result but what do we mean by that
very often
cyber security companies are perceived
as a certain type of process
there are some kids
which do something with their computers
they have a small budget and they should
continue and do their security they will
install antiviral uh
software but if something very serious
happens with the company and we've been
discussing it with alexey novikov when
some inadmissible events might happen
with the company when big amounts of
money are being transferred for the
company or malicious card will be
executed in the source code if it's a
technological company
then who's going to be responsible for
all of this
so first of all responsibility from the
side of top management second of all
department
information security department as a
partner which provides
protection from these situations and not
just formally any paper but actually
being able to avoid it that's what i
call resultative cyber security changing
the perception of cyber security inside
of the organization increasing its
priorities and the result
that non-admissible events will never
happen
well it did work
what i wanted to tell you about if you
will approach the question of
resultative cyber security in a
formalized manner we have to speak about
those events which should become
inadmissible for example if hacker
entered the bank he will never get
access to the atm network or if the
criminal have entered the production
factory he will never get access to
technological processes so
the product of calculating we do have a
number of projects as risk verification
when clients are coming to us the
factory the bank or any other
organization and they tell us we have
the list of those risks which are
inadmissible okay let's look at whether
you're going to be available to reach
them for us in a certain period of time
usually this is one month
and i do have certain numbers so let's
look at them
speaking about the industrial sector and
i'm speaking about factories plants
in the course of first month
we can realize 87 percent of
inadmissible events 87 of these
inadmissible events in the industry yes
speaking about the financial sector
speaking about banks
inside of them this number will reach 62
percent this is still a lot
nevertheless it's still more than 50
so we do have a big difference in these
numbers that's why answering your
question i can confidently tell you that
according to our experience the more
protected
financial organizations are more
protected what do you think the certain
measures are being adopted from their
side to protect them or maybe it happens
just like that
well i don't think that it happens
accidentally it's a complex of measures
which are being taken
and it involves higher budgets in the
i.t sector
second of all
this is a more proper approach to hr
policy and to forming defense team
also this is a consequence of team
building proper processes
the final question that i would like to
ask you about not about companies not
about corporations but i would like to
ask you about humans about people
devices in my pocket i might have a
phone and i do have certain things which
i consider
inaccessible for example leakage by
photos some banking data access to
social networks
doesn't matter
different people have a lot of different
important information
tax deal so as for me as for the person
how should i make these inadmissible
events impossible so that hackers would
not be able to find this key
to me
well it's a big question
i will give you certain basic
recommendations everything else will
depend on specifics of every certain
person well we are not going to speak
about long passwords can you give me a
more interesting advice well vladimir
you put me in a dead end this is the
first thing i wanted to tell you yes
simple passwords it's a very big problem
insufficient password policy
passwords should be very complicated and
unique
so that if you compromise service a you
would not be able to use this password
to compromise the service b
on the side of the same user so if the
user
i don't know
one password should not be used for all
the services and this password should
not be in his work computer
okay that's number one number two we've
been speaking a lot about social
engineering
so we need to differentiate legitimate
letters from letters which are sent by
criminals how
how can we see this difference
it doesn't say well in the subject this
is a letter from criminal
it's not a legitimate letter
well if
you
suddenly receive a letter from nigerian
relative which offers you to participate
in interesting scheme
on uh laundering several millions of
dollars it's fraud it's understandable
so look at some doubtful topics
if you receive a letter with the
attached file that you don't expect and
this might be not just executable file
with xe or scr
but it can be injection
even a document a microsoft word
document regular office documents can be
an injection
launch it in a sandbox or better better
ignore it and don't launch it at all and
well not speaking about phishing
if the file was coming from the internet
you should look at it with a certain
level of doubt and
your main working machine
don't launch all the executable files on
your computer any final question for
them i have an iphone and i don't care
do i leave an illusion or is it true
[Music]
well
well well
as for iphone in our department we have
a department which is involved in the
safety of mobile devices
do you have an interview with caller
from this department yes i do have this
interview i'm going to have and you can
address this question to him from your
point of view of the iphone computer
iphone is a computer with a certain
software
and this computer has a number of
vulnerabilities as well so
speaking about publish
vulnerabilities
ios has a certain number of coe
identifiers which tells us that it does
have vulnerabilities and they can be
exploited by criminals
okay thank you very much sasha we've
been speaking with alexander morozov and
we've been speaking about that any
company can be penetrated and not only
the company and any human because we all
are surrounded by digital devices and
iphone is not an armor
it's the same computer but a small one
and nice looking one in your pocket
so please be careful
and
unadmissible things that you're afraid
of in your digital world shouldn't
happen
be aware