can you hear me
uh good afternoon all of you my name is
andrei pruschen
i'm the head of consulting
to build security operation centers on
premise
with customers of telecom solar
i've spent quite a lot of time working
as a consultant in professional services
implementing information security
solutions and one of the projects was
about security operation centers
i'll talk today more about the
specificity of building them how to make
it so that you can build them themselves
yourselves and how to avoid common
mistakes
had we had
uh not such a big stage and had it been
closer to the audience you could ask me
could you ask me why a company that's
doing information security services is
going to talk about building on-premise
socks
so the answer is quite simple
not all customers not all companies
are prepared to pass to outsource this
function and they want to try or maybe
they already build such a center
within themselves
also i would
ask you to pay attention to the three
trends the first one is the geopolitical
situation as it has been
exacerbated since the end of last year
uh which pushed people to
uh
prioritize stock building and also
secondly the company
the companies that
own
critical information infrastructure
sites
have finally
approached a situation that they need to
implement monitoring function
they have
done a configuration categorization
implementation
of
information security
infrastructure and have now passed the
next stage also and the third
factor
was that in the beginning of may a new
degree of the president of the russian
federation has been
published for
additional
requirements to information security in
the russian federation
this
applies to both
federal
executive our bodies and other
organizations
so all this led to a situation where the
number of requests uh and questions
about building your own socks has grown
considerably
so let's take a look at the
typical
points that arise when discussing an
on-premise sock the classic picture uh
how to do it with high quality fast and
uh not in in not expensively actually uh
this can all be implemented this can all
be complied with
but of course there are certain risks
that can uh your company can face in the
short midterm and long term let's start
with the most
interesting
option where you want to do it
with high quality
and it's not expensive
it can't be done but for this you need
to have an expert or a team of experts
who already have
practical experience kind of an
in-source consultant
who will
help
you to avoid risks
so that you shouldn't come back to
re-work
but this
entails a lot of risk so if this person
leaves then your company you're staying
with nothing
it would be difficult for you to
continue the project if the pro such a
person leaves it the next option fast
and cheap
it can also be done but it looks like a
potemkin village so on paper everything
would look fine all the components would
be there the processes would be
described the content will exist within
cm but the first pen test will show you
that the sock doesn't see anything
no detection and response is happening
so again it looks like there are a lot
of risks about this approach
and the top right
corner you have with high quality and
inexpensively
this is also and
quite a frequent option uh that people
take
but there are risks about the time of
implementation so it may take years
three to five years for instance and
also there are such things as a lack of
funds for instance you're going to have
a small team at the starting point and
you're going to have certain
technologies missing that you would not
be
able
to
tackle with this team so you implement
something and then uh a year or two
later
you start implementing another
technology but then you find out the
previous technology doesn't isn't
compatible with the new ones and so you
can you know
go this circle
over and over again until you find so i
think uh the uh best approach is to do
it with high quality fast the its only
drawback is that
you it costs a lot and the only way is
to
attract or invite consultants who
already have a lot of experience uh to
avoid the biggest
hazards
that people run into when implementing
stock
if we consider a project to build a
in-house security operation center
different people have different
attitudes
some people uh
think it's quite
easy and simple implement cm hire people
and
start working but we of course
understand that it's a
more complicated story that
takes time and also has a lot of
building blocks so that you need to put
together a certain way so this would be
unique individual uh combination uh that
should address the unique risk of each
specific company so we was placed in
three
phases uh pre-project
phase where you collect information
about the situation the second is
building and launching a security
operating center and finally uh
operation and maintenance
so at the pre-project phase the main
goal is to understand the risks or
inadmissible events that can affect the
business the company's business
all
this requires either a bill sohib
or a security operations center
if
the soc is already there and
you want to modernize it
then a maturity
review would be useful what to do so
that it could move to the new level and
finally
the most important phase
is to create a concept
considering all the inadmissible events
all the attack scenarios that you have
identified in the first phase so you can
build a project consisting
organizational measures technical
measures administrative measures in
order to create this team
split its operation into phases of
prioritized projects and this
will allow you
to uh cover all the inadmissible events
that apply to this company with high
quality and one by one so what does it
contain the design of the soc systems uh
it's not only about cm but other other
systems it's the content
the most important thing what you have
inside these systems and again it's not
only the cm content is the content for
all other systems so this includes
processes and kpi metrics
employee training and a lot of other
things
and once we've done all this once we
build all this it's important to keep
working with this so you can't uh treat
a sock project as a project that has a
start and finish you need to keep
working on it improving improving it
because new threats arrive new people
arrive and
so
you can use red teaming exercises as
part of further maintenance
cyber exercises and such expert supports
activities as forensics early detection
and other similar
things what you shouldn't forget soc
can't be separate from all other
functions of information security if we
take a typical and classic model of
cyber security framework there are five
main elements there soc
third
they
partly cover
three of them identify
of as identification of assets to detect
a detection of infamous security
incident and respond that's response to
information security incidents but the
system system is not going to be fully
fledged without a security system that
you'll have to implement in the protect
phase or without the training and the
inclusion involvement of
the team
that will have to uh provide for the
restoration if the incidents has
happened and here unfortunately we have
to state that there's no system that
will cover
in assets or a business process company
with 100 reliability you always have to
consider that remaining risk as
a reality
uh what you should start with there are
two approaches but we believe the right
approach to building an soc because it
requires a lot of investments both
direct investment and in terms of
the efforts of those people who work in
the company so therefore you should talk
to business the business customer
quite often there's a problem here
because uh
sock is us to be built
from
the assets up
but not from the business logic so here
we
propose to split
it into the two goals or
let's say
two stakeholders it's business what
support for them in the soc to analyze
the inadmissible events that can happen
and how it affects the company's
business and try to minimize such events
and the second
thing is to understand the level of
investment that you need to make the
priority of these actions and how they
will affect the minimization of risk
for the information security chief
information security officer
it's just not been mentioned here
so they should have a single language
the same language to talk with business
why we implement
the soc or why so much money is required
exactly uh to foster those in municipal
events
so what does this eso get
the
unbiased and accurate indicators of the
current
uh security level
uh
drafting the target
state of the soc just like normally the
current states
target states and how you uh pass the
way from the current state to the
desired states and
we
here come to conclusion that you i need
to start with planning rather than
buying the systems and what includes the
analysis of cyber risks that's
individual events and
working out a concept for the soc we
have our own method methodology for such
work
that matches inadmissible events with
how the soc functions in fact this is
provided by several components
the scenario detection
the phase
structure of implementation
and
the
coverage
so all these things
should be defined at the outset
including the pace with which it should
happen the most frequent question
on premise or mdr
i actually started so with this
quite often when the customer arrives
you say oh they say that according to
the new uh decree
and with the new requirements uh
we uh want to build an soc and i very
much like uh how it works in algorithm
with another customer i just want
uh something like that actually uh which
way the customer should go depends on
several factors the finance the economy
the economics
and you have to assess a lot of
components hardware software and people
that will allow you to come up to the
amount the second point is politics
some companies have
a policy
not to pass
information security to our sources
so they need to deal with it themselves
uh there are also uh some uh
restrictions in some cases for instance
if the company works in such a region
but there are not enough
uh qualified talents uh there's no
qualified not enough qualified talent in
the region
so they just won't be able to hire the
people
and so finally some companies have a
reputation
component so we're strong and cool and
we just want to have our own soc he's
just like the best guys so
usually
based on our experience
we have seen a lot of such situations
and the graph here shows a picture what
does it say
it's usually the planning uh goes for
the long term uh three to five sometimes
to seven years
so if the picture uh compares
uh with the talk online the option of
your own implementation uh when they
build their own team or use their own
technology and at the bottom we see
different variants of the service model
and we run the comparison around the
comparison
for you to better understand
what is
this comparison if you're not linked to
a specific system or tool
so we have compared several
cm1 and cm2
options and different ownership models
clouds and sun premise and you see
that in five years on the five years
horizon five-year horizon the mdr model
wins
it quite often
it's quite often you better use service
financially but
that doesn't apply to all criteria and
that's normal so what's what general
recommendation can we give even for the
time of implementation whether companies
build building something of their own
uh
it's not the
best things
to pass
it's actually a useful to pass a
function to an outsourcer
just to learn
how the
not to outsources and functions firstly
to give some experience to your own
specialists and also
to get experience responding
so you'll have to respond so whether you
outsource these functions
uh later but before that you need to do
it yourselves
and the third point you'll do a fast
start and we'll start
returning the investment that the
company is
making
a risk-oriented soc
does this concept exist at all and does
it make sense
well it's a matter of debate actually
i've already spoken about two different
approaches start from assets and start
from risks i believe that the
risk-oriented approach
is very promising it indeed helps
setting up and implementing
a security operation center project
correctly and with admissible risks
this is not a new methodology
here we see several examples
at the bottom of similar methodologies
they're quite new
in
line one is information security 2.0
from positive technologies then
the
there's the stack methodology and
american consequence driven cyber
informed engineering
created in the department of energy of
the united states for the critical
infrastructure sites and they're all
talking about the same thing you need to
define inadmissible events uh draft to
detect vectors understand which systems
collect events from which systems from
which sources what kind of slas
are enforced and what
security tools need to be implemented to
mitigate those attacks
but the point is that these
methodologies are focused on building
an uh information
security center
uh
all the five functions in our case we're
talking about security operation center
and all this
chain
leads us to risks
to kpis to scenarios and to slas so how
different scenarios how fast
you need to respond to them and respond
enrich and work with them so this is the
approach
from
based on risks
you
shouldn't forget
the fact that unfortunately i will never
be able to see to achieve a 100 of
effectiveness there's always the
residual risk and one of the solutions
is to get it insured uh they're talking
about this quite a lot you can do that
you can try it and what's the point
you implement a lot of mitigating
measures they already minimize the risk
and this residual risk uh remained not
to be too large and companies who
provide the service look
at what has been implemented how it's
been implemented and they
work with a lower
insurance sum
and which makes this thing
of interest to the customer
either
how you should approach
and how you uh
how you can avoid typical mistakes
so the first
thing is feasibility study
feasibility studies
happen everywhere not for soc but also
for other systems and firewalls so
what's important take into account here
you need to combine technical analysis
so it's not
just questionnaires or
interviews you should technically and
systems that the customers using have
expertise to do that and see how things
are set up
so what soc related capabilities are
already there
[Music]
you should also you have one on one
interviews with customers business
because
you can
learn a lot of information
just an example
let's say with the industrial control
system when
we attach uh industrial systems to soc
those who've done that know that there
are a lot of difficulties there the
thing is that the systems are not always
so modern in terms of information
security it's very difficult to collect
the required events from them
if
they
exist
they don't have enough information
and
there's the general problem of
installing anything
into and operating uh
environment and in order to understand
how the soc
now will work
we offering an opportunity to
roll out to deploy uh the systems that
the customer has on our
test beds
including plc or scatter systems
and understand
what logging capabilities
exist how they can be set up and then
you can come back to the customer
showing them the solution that's already
been tested in this case
we
give a detailed presentation of
the
function of these socs function
that you can provide the next point cm
content manually many of you many people
understand it as a rule president's rule
that exists in the cm system uh in
actual fact it's not exactly this way
content consists of a lot of uh diverse
information uh some list exclusion lists
for instance
uh used in by the correlation rules so
that each students
should
work out and the analysts could work
with them
these are connectors normalization rules
enrichment
mechanisms and finally these are mockup
files
for the dashboards
for the analysts to see the information
so the process of implementing or
passing some content to the customer is
not as simple as it would seem you
shouldn't approach it as project ftd so
you've implemented cm you've implemented
the content and so please do a customer
use it unfortunately it doesn't work you
need to do three things in parallel
first to develop a process
so that the people who are going to work
with the internet should understand how
they work
to understand the output the outcome and
could affect
uh
affect the work through the exclusions
and secondly
it's the third line of work so the cm
engineers could understand the structure
of this content and could
develop enrich it and modify it through
their own efforts and the third
item is
training you need to train the teams not
only just train but also to do the
evangelization as we call it when we
need uh to
explain to the customer why uh the
structure is like this why it works like
this and why is it correct so that they
could
get inspired by that and could work with
that
so on the outputs you have the project
and specialists who can maintain
and develop it further and finally the
third point say incidence response is
called so-called playbooks what is this
it's a certain algorithm with
uh response responsibility areas with a
slash and a
flowchart of how the response team of
the soc inserts are going to work with
an incident should it happen
and so there's a subtle point here
usually when a
nsoc is implemented the number of rules
is measured is in
dozens
and
maybe even hundreds
so to develop a playbook
and to maintain it in a workable
condition after the implementation is
not the simplest of the task
so as a solution
for such large projects uh to use a
catalog of atomic rules
in the playbook
they're often used the same between
different playbooks and of course the
consultant methodologies takes a lot of
it takes a lot of time to
draw it up for each
uh process so the catalog of such atomic
rules allow
the allows people to refer uh to uh the
uh common uh things uh so if you want to
change something you do it in the
catalog rather in your specific process
so it
applies both to a manual
response definition and
automated
approach in the automated approach to
this catalogue
approach is very useful
and the output
we are getting a reduction of costs both
in the implementation and in the
maintenance of this playbook said
further on
conclusions first
uh please bear in mind those
inadmissible events
uh match the soc
structure to them and to the risk
analysis results second
consider all stages of building an soc
not just a cm and hiring look at the
picture broader
support
interaction between teams
at the implementation
phase
so if you would do it differently with
i.t people with uh manufacturing
engineering and others
they all should be inspired by this um
common idea and work together
it's not a trivial thing to do but you
need to strive for that because
otherwise
if you if all of you
does something
separately
you'll have to deal over the resistance
from your colleagues same thing about
consultants
the more
personal face-to-face communication
the more you can learn that was number
three and finally number four
work with reliable partners because
there are pitfalls
everywhere
and
so
choose reliable partners
that's all from me and if you have any
questions i'm prepared to take them
and if you have no questions
i'll be happy to welcome you at our
booth
and again
please don't hesitate
come to us with any questions we
actually have specialists so they're
both risk analysis technology things
and i'm sure we'll be able to find an
answer to any of your questions thank
you very much