and i've been doing independent research
and back bouncy for a long time and i
love talking about it
i'm working for a psp now
and if you're interested please join us
we do have some interesting uh
job opportunities we shall be talking
about fishing today
i guess everybody knows about classic
fishing and in classical fishing
the attacker will send a link to the
victim
to a fake website it can be done via a
message
an email
promotion on social media
or
so the naive dixon will think that okay
design wise it's very similar to the
sites that they know
and the address as well so he won't
really check the security certificate
he will simply follow
and all the data
will go
their fishing form there
it's a similar scenario but you know
even the
paranoid
users who will effectively check the
digital certificate of the website
will still be
defrauded in this case the user will
never be able to distinguish between a
rail and a phishing page
today we are going to discuss
how this can be achieved what are the
typical attacks i get you there and
we'll also discuss
several examples from bug bounty and uh
the recent notorious cases as well
so that is like this
an attack is uh performed by the hacker
and he uploads a phishing form on the
official website and the users tend to
believe official website so they don't
really check us
in fact we can
think the same way not just about
phishing
but also
owning a webinar pages or landing pages
or
airline booking sites
the more horrible the attack will be and
the more people will suffer and let me
actually tell you of some recent
examples
so
somebody hacked
a yandex go group on a vegan
and you know they send links to users
giveaways
in a different case you know
with a twitter
where
you know as attacks of disgruntled
school kid who has not been able to pass
his exams
but it could have just been
for example
you know
failed
where
an employee of the unified site exactly
system needs to ensure his or her
credentials
and you know if this uh login and
password is stolen well that's
interesting for kids
now some people
lose hundreds of rubles
on the index others lose millions of
dollars in btc scams
companies often do not want to
compensate them for losses and very
often they don't even have the
infrastructure for that
that's also a problem is that most
attacks they actually seem pretty stupid
check this out for example you know this
giveaway page it looks horrible
nobody has really prepared you know the
audience for that which would be the
case for proper giveaways like you know
in a week we're going to do that please
register and so on and so forth and
design-wise it's horrible
you know this
scams are extremely simplistic and
stupid and maybe because of that
fortunately there are not too many
victims
now let's discuss the kind of systems
that can be hacked and the kind of
problems
this will create
so you see we have a company and the
company has a website
and
they will probably communicate with
their users using email campaigns and we
hope that this company has happy clients
well the reality is slightly different
there is a cloud
or maybe their internal network there is
a server there
then some magic happens
and their clients get messages in social
media
instant messages or emails
and in reality it would look like this
and we're not even showing their
employees or their contractors or
contractors employees or contractors
partners and so on
so there is this cloud
sitting in this cloud and numerous
systems running some hardware
and they all have their vulnerabilities
their internal network
also has its holes and phones
there is also a separate system for
making outbound calls sending messages
and emails
they're also landing pages
and landing pages are often created
not by professional programmers
or information cyber security experts
but rather by marketing people
there is also the tech support group
where users will want to discuss things
that matter to them
where they may even disclose some
sensitive information
and there are also industrial specific
services and lots and lots of things
which i'm not even trying to show in
this diagram
to you know manage all your
communications with all sorts of imp
systems and what have you for whatever
one dollar a month
which means that potential targets are
very numerous
any services
that are effectively a touch point
for the user
it could be a site
for example you know a fishing page may
be uploaded instead of europe
landing page
or your page on social media can be
hacked
and you can start selling say
memberships
with a 90 discount and then users will
be really frustrated
will hate you for a reason
or for example your messenger
channel maybe
owned in order to advertise some ponzi
scheme
and your clients will be unhappy because
they will lose their money over it
and then you can say well it's no
problem for me i wasn't involved but
does it really matter to them
or about you know they stole your
account on an sms gateway and just sent
a harmless joke to everybody
you don't even have to hack the account
you will often be able to subscribe to
their news updates or you can request a
link to an application or a product
and elements of this request will
actually go into the sms and this is how
you can actually send
something more
than a regular sms text
you can also
hack a crm system or a ticketing system
the more advanced the hacker is you know
the more interesting things can
design for example if you can hack your
rivals crm system
you can actually
you know
send communications to your rivals
clients that will
pull them and they will stop using their
services
rarely will you see
direct links to various um
web pages
in sms in text
most of them are shortened and lots of
link shorteners
are very shortly programmed
last year for example
it was very easy to see an access vector
and this is how you would uh find it
very easy
to
hack the account of the person in charge
of marketing campaigns who would be
using those
links shorteners
that's how you would be able to you know
lead huge traffic of people
targeted by a particular marketing
campaign to a fraudulent website
there are lots and lots of systems they
may have their vulnerabilities
it's not that all of them have huge
holes in them but there are so many of
them
this would certainly be holes
i mean some services will have logical
issues
it will also be difficult for the user
to identify whether a particular page
so many passwords are being leaked now
including passwords of people
running those systems
there was for example this a recently
published vulnerability was about a week
ago
a pretty popular european service
enabled you to get access to somebody
else's site you know when you substitute
the password
and fortunately you know it was a geo
rewarded and a backbone in a back
boundary program but you know sometimes
it happens differently
another case of a sub domain takeover
where you can actually link as a free
sub domain to your account so for
example you have a cloud service for
creation of landing pages
you follow the instructions you create
the domain you create sub domains stand
here
change
the account information
say two months later
you forgot to pay for this service your
account will be blocked
and then
which is very often the case
the domain will stop uh linking to a
page because it hasn't been paid for and
it can be relinked
in the worst possible case you have a
valid digital certificate associated
with this uh with this page which gives
the heck a great opportunity for fishing
we forgot about sub domain we have been
using it for 10 years and we realized
it's no longer needed
or maybe
the employee was responsible for it you
know he resigned and we don't really
know how many sub domains were there
where maybe the subscription is over
or
for some reasons this international
service has decided to delete your
account now somebody else should be able
to link the same page to themselves
or maybe you've just started using this
service you've created a domain
you haven't been able to add enough sub
domains and they've already been
hijacked
and it's happening because these attacks
are very easy to
automate this is
this is very well known a repository of
a nuclei template and it contains a lot
of automated checks
that should enable
better
cyber spotting
that's why many popular russian services
are not there
magazine
a european internet store will very
quickly learn that their sub domain
may be stolen
a russian store made easily
often companies don't
show much interest in it because you
know some of them may think there is no
direct damage to them
i recently
got access to three sub-domains of a
largest russian company
and as part of the bug bounty program
they paid me
thirteen thousand triples which is less
than two hundred dollars
which means that you know you can
actually publish something on the
website of the largest russian company
it will have valid certificates
and you know with the amount of money
you will be able to get for it you won't
even be able to pay for your
participation in page days
it has been around for a long time we'll
have a lot of services which are not
very popular or totally outdated
and they will contain some xss some
simple issues and there should be ways
of manipulating content there
they're not even mentioned in the bug
bounty program because you know say was
some news uh
site that was established five years ago
and has not been updated since then
but how do the users know this is the
case
we may bring the user there with a
phishing campaign
we may tell them
register here get a bonus and they will
think okay it seems credible the address
is seems to be okay why not
there is another issue
that is
external
and again there will be lots of logical
issues there
particularly
you know they do some email campaigns or
sms campaigns you know often you can
actually
maybe
or you can do you know exhaustive search
and
effectively
hijack the site administrator account
now let's talk about
password leaks and weak passwords this
is this particular case from the bug
bounty program the password there was
pretty difficult
and the login was not obvious
however the manager of the sms agency
decided to use notion
and you know they inadvertently
published a link to this page so i found
it
i checked that the password was valid
and this is how i got access to three
sub domains
this you know huge russian corporation
how come we see so many really dumb
clicks
is that most companies have too much
data so much data you know they keep
updating passwords
to ever-growing number of servers
they need to be stored somewhere and
need to be administered
and
it may easily happen that you know you
have huge turnover of employees and
generating unique passwords for
everybody
is difficult
how about we just store it all a notion
many employees don't care about
passwords
as long as you know this password do not
really protect them bank accounts
they have negligence
same often happens to contractors who
tend to store their passwords in a weird
way
what's also funny is you know how many
cloud services are greedy let's consider
notion which i love so much
for free
[Music]
will be able to read but not edited
if you have more people working for you
you will either need to register a
professional account so that you should
be able to add editors or make it public
people you know prefer to save four
dollars a month or maybe you know they
cannot really pay dollars right now
given the sanctions
so they make the internal documents
public
and if you want to make some pages
particularly you know critical and
sensitive you will need to pay even more
so a lot of data gets leaked
it's not clear however
because you know so many sources really
need to be analyzed i've been doing it
for a long time and i can give you the
statistics
you know for every million
documents
leaked and analyzed manually roughly 20
000 will be interesting
and roughly 1 000 will contain passwords
and roughly
100 will contain passwords
to
you know interesting services
or for you know assets of companies that
offer bug balancing programs
one
roughly
contains something interesting and one
percent of that contains something
interesting
commercially speaking
you know very often people don't even
know where to look for links
so we have documents and they are saying
cloud services
but your employee for example
may publish their login and password in
a telegram channel don't ask me why they
did it
but this is what happened
this is how you know
somebody made some money in a bug bouncy
program
from
an email campaign
the services
of a cloud storage service changes every
day
take for example
this case of the russian company you
know i just chanced upon it
[Music]
i mean i was uh going through some space
or notion
i found nothing interesting but i forgot
to close it
so i opened the same tab like two months
later
i update it and i
see there are passwords now there you
know had i just you know checked it and
closed it i would have never found it
so the big question is are you really
sure that the perpetrators
do not have access to a cloud system
even if nothing has changed there yet
like it may very well be that you know
i guts you know the password to it
there is nothing critical there
and you know as a hacker i'm just
waiting for you to upload something
interesting
the problem is that you know you won't
really get
full-fledged system locks in most
corporations some companies are running
system logs but they're not doing it the
right way
and it can actually lead to even more
serious issues than a potential hack
for example if you're not so serious
site gets hacked
and then you decided to find
whoever is responsible for the leak
and you turn to the police
and the police asks for logs
and inspects the locks
and it turns out that you know an id for
your employee was not really shown there
properly
for example a secretary or a manager or
administrator or a manager
no didn't configure their account
properly and you know they may
have to pay pretty dearly for this
even if they were not responsible
in some services you simply cannot force
the users to change their passwords
with some services
all you can do is kindly remind the
users to change their password
well they will say yes sure maybe they
will add one to their password
and keep it like that
as a white hat
or researcher
you need to make such an effort to find
the leaks
oh this is good because this this means
that you know hackers also have a hard
time
unfortunately for us
not all services are so bad some of them
actually are well protected
and quite often you will not be able to
steal anything in a single goal
what if a particular email service he's
if indeed a classical sub domain
takeover
you can delete the sub domain
within several days or
hours later
malicious sub domain is a malicious uh
constant will not be there
now what if it's an emailing campaign
service
you know if uh
account gets taken over
no it's effectively being run now
by
you know they are advertising to your
bonafide client telling you cannot stop
it you turn to the support service
and several days later they may respond
please send in some proof that you
really own this account somehow we don't
believe it
and if you are not lucky
and you reside in a country that's
laboring under sanctions
and for some reason you are
still using a service uh provided by a
company which
observes all the existing rules to see
chances are they're not even going to
help you
now let's talk not just about users and
clients but also about employees because
employees obviously are a great target
for fishing
you know your employees will be using
all sorts of weird services
they like chats for example
in a large corporation
some of them are still using icq can you
imagine that and they're still using icq
to communicate with their contractors
some of the services by the way are used
unofficially
most of the notion pages by the way
i'm
who is tired of storing all data in
confluence and they want to have a
convenient elegance interface
and
if it's a cyber security employee
probably won't be able to jeep him with
a simple invitation to test you know and
use service out but if it's a courier
who has been you know is really tired
after a long time
and then he is informed
in a chat that has been taken over
if you do not
you know fill out a form explaining why
you're late you will be fined 500
dribbles they will be happy to provide
all the information all their credits
without checking what the site
so your company may be very serious
about security
but unofficially employees
will choose something different for
their convenience
official systems
will often be as vulnerable as uh
unofficial systems
the problem is that you at least know
what the official systems are was
cloud system is leaked and you don't
even know it has been in use and maybe
lots and lots of interesting goodies
looking for them on telegram is not
trivial you know because they do have
their own
ways of uh protecting when you watch the
company against uh brute forcing
another
so you may want to look for a particular
chart that contains the passwords
at the problem
many trackers and planning systems will
enable you to create tasks simply by
sending letters to them
that my system is being accessed this is
no fun please do not screw up my working
process as an interpreter thank you very
much
so you can create
tasks and you know that will represent
how creative you are for example you
know you can ask for access to be
provided to a particular employee
or you know you can send a letter asking
for help in preparing a conference or
something
so this is it you know for
you know knowledge databases and what
have you
but it can also be
or knowledge management systems very
often you know if you get access to a
particular document
you will have more than just uh
right
writing uh privileges
and for example what you can do is add a
fishing link
so this employee for example has always
been using this thing
and he won't really care to double check
yes and the link will take him to the
fishing site
typically
many companies will see will experience
for example if you see that a particular
document has been leaked
and you have deleted it and you were
hoping that people would uh you know
change the password
but they
and you know people may still try using
it
or for example a new employee gets hired
he gets access to internal services or
cloud-based services
and they're in plain text
they will be able to see passwords to
all the services
[Music]
now you may say this is horrible and
this is a very
very low probability event but it isn't
or for example give uh
retain some marketing people
and they're using the same account
details for you as well as 50 other
companies
they are working with
and then you know by mistake
they give
let's play a bingo game
to entertain you a little bit
you may recognize some of the recent
incidents here
despite everything i've been telling you
you may have
made the conclusion that third party
services
are buggy
this is not really the case
you know the times when we could say you
know what an employee has an email and
phone and everything can be hacked and
every hosting every cloud
service provider can be hacked you know
these times are over
we now need to be
much more systemic
because of the sheer amount of data
i should be able to take your questions
now i have delivered my presentation
much faster than i expected so i will be
very happy to hear your questions
in your experience
you know it can actually allow the risk
that an employee of the company will
actually follow the link i will enter
some details or whatever
well i don't have uh personal experience
in this respect but uh
some stuff i can share with you
often the problem
is that you know this uh fishing
fishing classes
tends to
irritate users although they're useful
and use i'm sorry jiren classes like
this they often create
domains that seem to be very different
from the real ones and the attacks i've
been telling you about
but
they're more advanced because the user
actually has got no way of checking if
it's a phishing site or not because you
know you can even see the certificate
there
and the number of people who are
actually going to talk to
you know the cyber security department
is actually very limited
so what i'm trying to say is that
against such attacks it's probably not
going to help
hi i have another question
so we've been talking about regular
fishing
and we've been talking also about you
know more advanced things like uh
email campaigns and what have you done
naturally there are also
two-factor authentication
and other systems and on github
you can find at least two utilities
that should enable reverse fishing
so what can we do about it how do we
make sure that you know our employees
you need to control what's happening to
the corporate resources
this should enable you
to defend against well at least the
really stupid attacks uh on the website
of the company
and you should also delineate excess and
you know use the minimum privileges rule
because uh sooner or later
any company
large or small will have the admins
password leaked
up
authentication yes well you can bypass
it
in my opinion do not really undermine
the trust
website
[Music]
no it's similar to what i was talking
about
um
all the protective mechanisms
and the users don't really get to check
you know which website they're in so
minimum privileges continuous control
and uh thinking about what you're going
to do if things break no they should
still be reliable ways of protecting
yourself uh yes thank you very much for
this report
can you share with us you know cases of
the stupidest and the most creative
fishing
so there is this
service associated
for real with some company and it
contain a password to some admin panel
and a password to some exchange crypto
exchange
so you go there you see seven hundred
dollars
and it says that you know
you can actually withdraw money
as long as you know above 1 000.
i've
these are the examples i previously
showed because
attackers have got so many opportunities
because they often get access to huge
databases of people to defraud and for
some reason you know they're not doing
anything creative they're just telling
each of these people to give them 300
triples because they badly need it
i'm surprised they're not creative
enough do we have other questions
hi thank you very much for your report
my name is igor
my question is about passwords
there is this opinion
that if you keep changing your passwords
it doesn't really make things better
because users tend to simplify their
passwords going forward
and they often say
that if you want to
combat it
you should actually compare the
passwords that they are choosing
to the databases of leaked passwords and
demanded they change them if there is a
match
do you think it's a good idea
thank you very much it's a good question
i think i should answer that in dates
frequent change of passwords does result
in them getting dumber
and indeed there are good services that
help you check if such a password has
been leaked
i think it should be combined with
password change if this particular
password has been indeed compromised
or if the person who had access to it
has resigned and is no longer bounced by
any applications
so the problem may well be that you know
we had a single password it was pretty
strong
but now 10 people have resigned and we
don't really know who else knows these
passwords
a password check against the databases
of leaked passwords
tends to increase the strength of
passwords you're using because all the
simple passwords have already been
leaked so kubernetes one two three four
five will be out of questions
apparently nobody wants to ask questions
so let me hand you the t-shirts