[Music]
anyway
we are still at phd
it's a hacker's forum we are discussing
information security and we also um me
here investigate deep fakes
um you saw one defect behind me vladimir
yes could not leave the stage on time uh
and he stayed here for a while let's do
fake okay welcome back
we are going to
discuss something very interesting right
now we're going to talk about the youth
we're going to talk about the mass and
we'll talk about
cryptography and we are also going to
talk about a museum how all i mean these
different words that together
uh
you will find out very soon please
welcome uh
ceo at kryptonite
right what is kryptonite
and the museum of cryptography
what association do you have with it
we are a
research and production company
we do scientific research
in cryptography and we also develop
products
that are related to cryptography and to
big data
on
employing many
scientists many researchers
academics because we will also want to
develop the academic side of it in the
cryptography market
we are one of the best supplies in terms
of academic expertise
do you think that the younger generation
today is uh actually enthusiastic about
crypto something well crypto something
yes it's very popular you mean
cryptocurrencies of course
and
here where the
museum makes the stage
we
must bring back
uh
well rather we must
make signs fashionable again we must
explain to children that
science is not something boring and it's
not just algebra lessons in school but
it's exciting it's interesting
everything that they see around them is
based on algebra that they study at
school
and i think that this well
after a while it will
make
some of these children into good
scientists some of them will want to
become mathematicians for instance
and yes there are
kids who participate already
in
various
uh
cryptography
games and competitions and math studios
but the movement is still not very
massive
okay i don't want to argue but in my
world view when i was a young kid
i knew my country to be the best read in
the world but now as i am
following the news
very often i get to hear
that the country is very strong in
physics and math and russian coders are
the best coders ever
i mean the parents the parents are known
to be good mathematicians but not kids
why not kids
well i'm not sure about the first
statement that you made
yes later i would argue with that as
well
but even if it were the case
these are the people who grew up i mean
if you
look at
the teenagers
the 12 year olds 13 year olds
their interests
[Music]
they do not always extend to the
scientific
foundations of what
surrounds them they are more interested
in tick-tock formats
clips
small formats so yes it's a way to
engage them but our objective is
to eventually
get a good scientist a good engineer and
to become a good engineer you need to
study a lot and
you wouldn't be able to become good
engineers through clips um people need
to to understand that uh
technology is complex and complicated
you have to study it
we have always been strong in the soviet
union with the fund or you know school
schooling
so first a person would be trained as a
mathematician uh and later will be
trained to be
a programmer because they had this
excellent education and algorithms that
would become good programmers but now
what we are looking is this fundamental
initial training today things are
changing understand and probably we
don't need that many uh programmers with
excel and fundamental education but also
because of the quality of fundamental
training also suffers
what you are saying i think is rather
critical
um
what i hear you say
is
our
how to
perceive the world in a complex
way in a complex manner they can
perceive the world through clips but not
in anything more complex than that
well what we try to do what and by the
way yeah at the museum
we are trying to explain complex things
in a simple way
and it's something that that took most
of our time we actually assembled a lot
of professional
uh scientists so that together they
would be able to explain to us a 10 year
old how electronic signature works and
it's not easy
and it's not easy it's you have to be
stay true to the mathematical
background of it you can explain it in
an easy way but it can't uh demonstrate
it in an easy way and the components
that we are displaying they are intended
for the
people who have little knowledge or who
have this uh habit of clip thinking
to keep them interested
that explanation can be used as a basis
for another explanation you can tell uh
the viewer that that's the part of math
that uh
that that actually is the theory for
what you saw and you can go beyond two
plus two equals four you can uh uh
go deeper you can let kids play with the
with the basics first and then get them
interested and after that you can teach
them uh in more profound matters
how old is the museum
we opened it
at the end of last year end of last year
end of last year
okay end of last year
i mean
is this a different child now
you can stay there for five hours six
hours eight hours
and the museum is
it presents information different layers
uh uh every installation has a lot of
information so often people or kids come
back to continue their visit
[Music]
they want to press all the buttons
eventually
but once they are in we are also offer
educational programs we want to keep the
kids inside this educational environment
and we also add installations and we
also fix errors
can you say something about the
installation about the displays
two dimensions we are a classical museum
that is to say we display a lot of
classical equipment special encryption
devices and uh stuff
we've got enigma we've got uh
the violet we we have a lot of pieces of
equipment and we explained how this
equipment works and in addition to the
actual devices
we also explained the math we explained
why this device works the way it does
how it's built internally
what are the fundamental factors that
enable its existence so uh basically you
can come there as a viewer or piece of
equipment and you can also come there as
a more profound viewer who wants to go
deeper into details
historically the historical exhibits i
mean we have a lot of
pieces of technology
uh we re-tell the story of those devices
and we also tell stories of people
cryptography in the soviet union was a
closed off sphere and
the names of the people who were
considered to be experts were not very
well known
we bring back their stories there is the
uh
office of ketelnikov for instance
uh that
has
his own things his own belongings in it
so it's an interactive museum but it is
also a very traditional museum wonderful
i have a final question to you
what is the age
of your target audience
and would parents be interested in
visiting your museum as well well first
of all the parents would definitely be
very happy uh to visit the museum
probably the parents would be more
interested in
learning about history i don't know
there are some parents who also like
pressing
buttons has two kids
i'd say
10 11 12
is probably the best age well of course
you can bring kids of any age
but it's best if your kid knows how to
read at least thank you very much
well dear friends if you've got kids
aged 10 up
then please come see varathan's museum
if you do not have kids go and see where
towns museum
if you are under the age of 10 then
go and talk to your mom and dad and tell
them to take you to the cryptography
museum