[Music]
it is the new terminology that recently
emerged in the market but it helps us
understand better the goals of cyber
security now let's
talk to alexander bill b who is ceo of
rosatom digital solutions about the
goals and objectives of results oriented
cyber security
well it's a pleasure to be here thank
you very much for the introduction and
for the invite it's my first time here
and very often you get to hear
especially in hr management or hr
consultancy uh it tends to
speak about engagement or involvement
you can sell immediately that everyone
here is completely engaged everyone here
all the integrators the vendors the
participants and i envy you in a good
way because um in my company i would
love to see the same level of engagement
of my employees
well thank you very much for your kind
words you know that this is our 11th
forum and we've been around for a while
and our objective is to
uh showcase uh cyber security to
demonstrate which incidents a real
statement may face or to explain who
hackers and defenders are so it's uh
it means very practical they are hacking
they are considering scenarios but at
the same time we see our mission in
education exactly exactly and also uh
engagement self management and we will
talk about self management there all top
management also needs to be engaged
and uh it needs to be educated about
what information security is a result
oriented
efficient
information security for me
means mechanism clear mechanism uh to
protect your business from undesired
events especially under the current
circumstances the video hosting that
i mean people have been talking about uh
since last week this is such a huge
reputation risk and today it's reaching
a level when every top manager
not should not just follow a script that
yeah we've got a script and i'm
following the script of information
security but now as a top manager i need
to be engaged myself i need to
understand
uh what uh my innocence are what my
unacceptable events are what for me a
business unit is uh what does it mean
and based on that understanding cyber
security should be built engagement of
the punishment is key it has a digital
transformation it starts also with the
top management if you don't leave the
story then it's very difficult to
attract others
uh to the same narrative it's very
difficult to engage others and building
a safe and reliable enterprise
do you understand it correctly that the
digital transformation
has affected almost every single company
and business
here
should also be focusing on results uh
should also be resolved re untits
well totally
uh digital transformation what does it
mean
in essence we all understand
is that any
digital footprint or any digital trace
leads to
a risk of abuse
my voice is
in my pocket and you can rob me of the
wallet
you can take it from me physically by
upon physical force but in the digital
world i understand that i can lose
access to resources that i'm using uh
through other mechanisms so it's
integral integral part of your digital
planning whether you are planning
engineering software or industrial
software you must always understand how
you would be controlling
the
cyber security
and
abbreviating various risks
speaking about these unacceptable events
for ross atom what are they
technology or
ros adam digital technologies uh digital
solutions what are these events
everything that's related to
our
employees and their security we have
many people working at our extensive
network of facilities for you to
understand the nuclear industry euros
adam that's about 260 000 employees and
about 400 facilities
it's a big industry
we do not call ourselves a segment we're
in industry in ourselves
and
in ourselves you know we all understand
a nuclear icebreaker or a floating
nuclear power plant or a
stationary power plant if
anything happens there i mean it's
totally unacceptable
these facilities cannot stop they cannot
be left without power
and users will also suffer and they are
paying money to get stable supply say of
electricity so it's an uninterrupted i
mean it's a an integral process a
process or other processes that should
never stop
what is the role of cyber security in
the digital transformation and in
making the unacceptable impossible
yeah must
seville they all wrote good books
consultants heaps of consultants come
and tell you uh hey let us analyze your
current model uh give you a picture of
your target model and you can also get
from us agile scrum or waterfall or some
other methodology that you can follow to
reach your targets
for me digital transformation
and it's it's not
it's not revolutionary
vision really but uh
stop top management soft management
always thinks about p l
if i do this what will be the effects or
that at the end of the year i can tell
my shareholder here is uh that was our
plan and um
i outperformed it
the real problem is harm security is
very difficult to
quantify to monetize
we know it we cooperate with you often
and every time when we uh reach the
point in our discussion where we are
saying that if i invest one ruble how
big the payback will be well usually
it's zero you can't make money with
cyber security but you can lose a lot of
money with cyber security yeah cyber
security can make tomorrow better than
today i don't know statistics and it's
very difficult to sell actually i don't
know statistics let's talk about a car
you buy a new expensive car or not very
expensive car really how many people
insure
the car completely how many people would
buy complete spicy insurance you can pay
5 million rubles for the car but are you
willing to risk the car you can insure
it you can invest the money or you can
put the car in a garage and it will stay
there for for forever but you have
already paid for third-party liability
insurance and i think that top
management often thinks in the similar
way they come and say why do i need to
invest into heavy and complex products a
cyber security
software hardware installation pay for
installation as well
so it's
for me it's a matter of changing the
culture for me as cyber security is an
integral part of the digital
transformation and digital
infrastructure but
i'd start
with the key factors that impact the p
and l what's cool to
um
use another example steel and mining in
metallurgy the most expensive part of
the production process is the blast
furnace and
this is the most labor intensive the
most technology intensive and
the cost intensive part
if you optimize the operation of a blast
furnace by
half a percent one percent the business
will feel an immediate effect and using
these success stories you need to
persuade the top management that is
worth investing into
all kinds of digital optimizations
including digital or information
security
so what's the role of information
in this
narrative
it's an integral part of digital
transformation i don't know
when you
when you uh
when you look at digital transformation
usually you would see several blocks in
there like six seven and one of these
blocks will be
cyber security is uh a mandatory part
and what about unacceptable no i mean
cyber is security uh results oriented
cyber security maybe i'm
already
thinking you know ahead of your
questions but i'm no longer thinking in
terms of classical cyber security that
we discussed a year ago two years ago
i'm thinking about cyber security 2.0
results are in subsecurity corporate
culture must be changed and the top
management must be made aware
of the results results oriented
intervention security another example
for the listeners
many people especially top management
can say what is esg right everyone knows
what hge is and every top manager can
give their explanation of what is you if
you ask industry 4-0
anyone will be able to give the
definition of msp for zero but what
about cybersecurity you can do this kind
of a poll you can go to top management
in any company and
ask them what is subsecurity 2.0 no one
will be able to give an answer and it's
normal i think uh it's natural but it
must be changed uh thank you very much
alexander
results-oriented
esg i mean people understand what it
means industry for 4.0 they understand
what it means but cyber security
the results uh
oriented cyber security is when cyber
security is an integral plot an
inalienable part of
the digital transformation
and
prevents unacceptable events from
happening
ensuring the well-being
of
the business
thank you alexander alexander
the ceo of saturn digital solutions
thank you
[Music]
so
[Applause]
and
we continue our discussion of cyber
security
and
more precisely the results oriented
cyber security let's now uh certain two
banks please welcome ruslan
head of information security of absolute
bank
is this correct
yes everything is correct ruslan welcome
and uh
what do you think about cyber security
results are is oriented type of security
in banking
what is your perspective
what are unacceptable events for you
well you see julian results
is relatively
[Music]
it applies not only to banks or
financial organizations
uh what you have to
a understand
does what its business is
and
banks
mostly are for profit organizations what
is a for-profit organization this
uh guided and governed by market rules
the market rules are those of demand and
supply results oriented cyber security
is the one that enables development of a
company or a bank
developing
threat models you are being paid
for establishing practical security
dealing with compliance issues securing
the bank solving methods of digital
transformation helping build products
with high value added
if cyber security as a component of a
product is too expensive the product
will not be competitive people will not
buy it
so results
results oriented cyber security is the
one
that helps companies develop
that helps companies develop competitive
products
and
that will introduce technologies
that covers for all these needs with our
technologies will not be able to
comply with certain requirements
address certain risks and cyber security
will be expensive
the question is is to what a general
it's too vast it's too broad
i could talk for an hour to achieve this
question
okay that's good it's it's great that
it's such a
uh such um
[Music]
such a big
um topic
uh in the reply that you have just given
you use the words such as risks and
technology as far as i understand you
align certain risks with certain
technologies
uh with which you are covering or
addressing these risks right
well you see
there are different ways
to measure kpis or slas in the field of
information security there are different
models
we can approach it from the position of
compliance with regulatory requirements
there are goals for banks for instance
the
government all the state standards but
it's this state standard this cost is
just a set of basic requirements in
russia we do not have a single
information security standard that would
be adapted to
commercial organizations the bank is the
market
it acts in the market so if you comply
with cost it doesn't mean that you are
secure you are only compliant
risks okay you can be guided by risks
risk based approach is
an established approach in the market
there are many different standards
international standards as well
it's wonderful but
when you enter a modern organization
how do you define its perimeter where is
it
companies today use
outstaffing distributed teams clouds
where is the perimeter
in terms of
risks infosec will be very expensive
because risks are everywhere
on all sides
but there are some key risks right that
can't context you that should not exist
at all
well what should not be
is disruption of business continuity uh
for failure of infosec
you see we've got this notion of service
security
well we've got two we've got
we've got chief information security
officer
this that's the director for information
security right
and i associate it with the itils uh
standard uh an itu is for uh business
continuity and then there is the cso
chief security officer this is the
security that is aimed at the continuity
of the bank's assets banks operational
activity
databases
commercial secrets reputation etc
so a
disruption or violation of the
activity
continuity the integrity and
accessibility of these assets will be
considered the key risk factor it's
something that should never happen we
should prevent it everything else it can
be
somehow fixed addressed you know
matched but
banks develop products right
a business can call
and say
i want to work in clouds i need clouds
but to say that
clouds are big risks
what is this risk
i need to
[Music]
make sure that business gets the clouds
that it's once
a business wants a distributed team
wonderful i need to ensure that the
business gets a distributed team the
business wants a product i need to be
sure i may make sure that i can give
them a product and that will be the
result of information security so yes we
operate information assets and we
today
for protection i mean
well technologies it depends on the
concept
i forget about the period sir
[Music]
different models data centers apis
internet acquiring
merchandising i don't know
where is the perimeter
it's vague it's fuzzy
[Music]
such a business model we need to stop
thinking in terms of perimeters we need
to start thinking in terms of data
protection so we need technologies
that in such a distributed ecosystem
will protect the data
which technologies are they
how can we build a secure access
network access okay we can use network
access we can use whatever
but
there are a few vendors now a few
opportunities these days
well the opportunities are the same i
think but the number of technologies or
rather
the number
of the technologies representatives
is smaller
the
capability is still out there but it
takes time resources integration do you
mean to do it yourselves in-house inside
the bank
well no not necessarily
say
today in the markets
don't have uh access security brokers
right
as
brokers they are say part of zero track
network access i use crm of the alex
cloud and i need to protect the data
what is sas i
control my data and i manage access to
these data
and i i there is nothing else that i can
integrate into the system how do i
organize access to the data how can i
protect it
i need clouds for security broker cisco
had it um
checkpoint had it and then you come to
the russian market and there aren't any
analogues
was at an event where a representative
of the ministry of telecom was speaking
and that person said that they
expect this niche to be filled very soon
and that's how i
interpreted his words we did not talk
about any specific
means or products or technologies
it was a general discussion about what
is still missing
if the business understands that they
don't uh have something please let us
know and then after a while it can
be made available
i tried to build the same paradigm for
several uh
for uh we talked to infowatch about that
at that time
that's
we must be guided by the customer's
vendor needs
they are our reference points
the under integrator customer vendors
develop products integrators perform
work to integrate
but what the customers want the
customers want not to have a problem but
not to have a
headache
the problem or the pain
can be
the same as or it can
overlap with other products and maybe
the product that is available doesn't
remove all of the paint like crm systems
how many crm systems you have we have
today in the market what is the crm
system in a classical version do we have
a classical crm system probably not
because the markets do not need any
classical crm systems today
dioxide you know
data all these classical crm systems are
no longer with us they were around 20
years ago stay crm is the marketing term
and for some uh crm means
a part of xcr for others it's
something integrated with erp
okay what which which pain should remove
them
when we respond to incidents we uh use
two concepts cm erp sar and xdr
why their choice
security operations center any response
even through security operations we have
our own security operations center takes
some time
for instance
how can you
avoid a sandbox quickly under certain
conditions
company
[Music]
otherwise archives can be blocked and
the uh
bank simply will will not get what what
he or she wants what we do is we take
malware we encrypt it
we send it
the sandbox doesn't open the archive it
doesn't understand what's in it unless
it will pass through and if at the
terminal
there aren't any
nca or something else something similar
you can send a second message with a
password
you follow
you open the archive the user
opens the archive the back door is
opened
and
the attacker sees everything that
happens on the computer of the user
so we um we we do not have any um
anti-a we close the back door
it was not detected
it takes time uh for this information to
get ucm to your beat you register an
incident uh for our team to respond it
takes time it takes five minutes maybe
ten minutes
and the back door stays open
[Music]
um
so there is another problem protection
of terminals you are talking about
external right
yes it's the xdi technology what is uh
protecting the terminals the end
stations in the uh modern world it's not
anti-virus
of the junior level can
hack it but the terminal how can it be
protected you monitor the
workload how to protect workstations
three advice from you three pieces of
advice very clear and short advices
your money toward all of the workloads
on the working station we've got
endpoints for this
the ponyta pasta
remember that there are different
channels right you can
capture it via email but you still have
to monitor it exactly you need to
monitor it xtr if you set it up
correctly
he can
at least he can respond within the
shortest time possible okay rosanna
thank you very much for your
your advice
and xdr we talked about xtr yesterday
you can find the recording and find out
more
and
from absolute bank bank helped me
discuss
protection inside banking
infrastructures please stay with us
you