the next story will be about protecting
industrial companies because industrial
companies are surrounding us they
manufacture electricity they assemble
cars they are steaming outside of our
doors this is something that we cannot
live without our daily activities are
not happening without those companies
and we're going to speak about
protecting these industrial companies
together with dmitry dolensky the head
of a practical of industrial security
and positive and anton chapulin manager
for the development of
industrial cyber security from kaspersky
lab
hi guys my first question will be to
both of you can you tell us please
why should we protect these smoking
chimneys
we need electricity we need food
products we need medications we need
to use transportation so any industrial
company infrastructural or manufacturing
one it's the same id infrastructure with
same
computers unique devices
which also subject to cyber attacks
and the damage and problems which can be
caused by cyber attacks are much more
significant than the cyber attack
against some business center
yes dima is right the main objective is
to provide
continuous flow of operations in the
company to provide services to the end
consumers users of the system and of
course prevent their inoperability which
might lead to the catastrophes with the
loss of monetary
damage to the human health and lives and
this is done not just by t security this
is done by business this is done by
physical security functional security
companies and these systems become more
and more digital i t factor becomes a
factor of threat that's why
informational security becomes this
fighter becomes the
founder which provides uh continuous
operations of the company
this means that industrial companies are
being broken or hackers do break into
them and they make some
practical things well in real life we
can say that speaking about our projects
especially when we directly work with
the clients we do see traces and
consequences of cyber attacks but due to
traditions and specifics
in the security industry
information
as a rule
so yes of course there are cases
the damage is real
i'm speaking about specific damage but
not many mass media companies are
publishing this information
anton you see the whole market
especially the kaspersky lab in uh this
country and outside of this country can
you make certain examples of uh
break-ins into industrial companies well
there's a lot of break-ins and hacks and
but we are security specialists we are
paranoid by our main idea we show risks
to business and we always tell them
about worse options that
with proper investments with proper
efforts from this side of hackers one
can achieve very negative consequences
as a damage to life and health of human
beings but if you look at the whole
history of attacks it would be honest to
say that never this system has led to
mortal cases it does mean that we have
to relax
on multiple occasions we had arguments
uh about uh some death effects we didn't
have any mortal cases but with time
people forget the first case
very very loud case it was in the
beginning of the year 20 in the year
2000 in australia
fired employee
have been able to dispose
could dispose
and damage the environment and there was
negative cases uh so there were some
damaging effects of these cases in case
when the production was shut down an
economical effect was very negative and
the specialized malicious code was
discovered before this damage was caused
and we know of such cases return system
and
and new cases are well known to us when
just uh recently in the course of this
year within one week we have published
information about attacks against energy
facilities
we've discovered a specialized software
which was making an attempt of using
in-built protocols uh schneider
electric unrun npc servers
without using any vulnerabilities
it's just enough to get access to those
services and uh speaking
about
lng gas facilities and it happens right
now it didn't lead fortunately to moral
cases but it shows us that this is a
real danger and believe in those days
well there is a myth
that hackers
are inside of those industrial
communities they're sitting all the time
there and many of them are sitting
inside of them is it a myth or is it a
truth of life and they are kind of
hiding and they're waiting for their
time
well
the traces of presence the traces of
exploitation vulnerabilities the traces
of attackers are discovered practically
in every second research in every second
pen test and analysis or in every second
company
but it's important to understand when we
speak about industrial company security
we are not speaking just about
protection of discarder or technological
network because the attack against
corporate systems
production or business system they also
are able to shut down the business
activities for example the story with
same colonial pipelines
the control systems of re-pumping of all
products they have not been attacked or
broken the business system was broken
and the company had to
shut down
so when you look at the protection of
the industrial company well you have to
look at it wider in a scale of the whole
infrastructure of the company and not
just narrowly in some specialized
technological systems
so speaking about corporate systems
business systems in the industrial
companies traces are discovered and
hackers
been speaking about another aspect that
comedy does not exist in the vacuum
the company has a supply chain the
company has relations with agents with
clients with suppliers
and what happened with colonial
pipelines it said that while the
technological process was shut down
through the business process without
attacking industrial automation
processes they have achieved the same
result and speaking about this point of
view well everybody's vulnerable there
is no ideal protection and there's no
ideally protected companies we know
about that and with the consideration of
the growth of integration of these
systems between each other
these lack of ideality is growing that's
why this interdependency between big
number of uh
technologies companies components of
vulnerable components non-reliable
foreign components
and we are able to see that this is an
objective situation that we have to
follow the concept you should look at
yourself as if you have already been
broken in without thinking about uh some
defense measures using the zero trust
concept you shouldn't trust components
inside of the network as absolutely
protected because you can already be
hacked you already might have an agent
inside of your company that's why and
this is a right approach from the point
of view uh well it's a paranoial
approach from the point of view of risk
management of our days risk management
well this is a proper approach i think
but what is the main specifics of
industrial companies compared to
business centers for example
well the specifics
this question about approaches how can
we yeah the specifics of protection
protection specifics i'm not going to
discover a big secret when i'm going to
tell you that
the principal approaches to security
technological segment they are not
different we use
same methodologies we use same product
classes the approaches and policies are
very similar to
corporate infrastructure policies and
there's a certain specifics that there's
unique unique software unique devices
and you should know how to work with
them
there is no big difference for us as a
company which is involved
in
developing these uh solutions uh for the
safety of industrial systems we don't
see big difference here
and in principle uh protection of these
companies a big question mark
irrespectively to whether it's a
technological system production
management system business systems
these approaches are not really
different
what
differs them
the approach is being changed from some
formalized common approach for everybody
in the it security industry it changes
to some applied approach in order to
have applied tangible result of all the
movements which security guys are making
in the manufacturing companies and i
will tell you more
to that for example outdated
approaches everybody's uh modeling
security threats but if you look at the
standard threat
of security uh to security of industrial
company it's not going to tell you in
which direction you should run what is
to be done and how can you achieve
maximum security effect with minimal
investments
that's why from this point of view the
development of approaches development of
methodologies generally speaking not in
respect to some separate domains or
systems
is moving in the right direction well
the decree of the president from the may
1st which was in respect to the
production of the critical companies
that certain responsibilities should be
inside of the organization and there was
another part of this decree which tells
us that by 2025 everybody should move to
domestic products domestic digital
products how
this is reflected in industrial
companies from the point of view of
industrial security is there any
difference is this as a kind of a
division line between the protection of
the industrial companies before this
decree and after this president's degree
or everything is the same
well this is a new decree and we
don't really understand what's going to
be about the situation in the future but
we understand that industrial companies
they started moving this direction and
this decree is pushing people to do what
had to be done previously
with federal law 187
critical infrastructure security
related law and if i remember it
reinforces requirements to any critical
infrastructure facilities not only the
most significant ones and there's a
certain misunderstanding about them so
right now they got more intense they
started looking for alternative means of
protection and we see this through the
demand so it has reinforced certain
increase of interest speed
yes we need availability of a
responsible person and it is being
defined that there should be a
responsible department within the
company so
it reinforces the priority of
informational security for the
industrial companies but we are going to
see in the future what's going to happen
here
well i would like to add to anton's
words everything is right but the main
idea is that we have to move in this
direction and we have to do a lot of
things
as for us
[Music]
it's not a secret we always have used an
approach before something explodes
nobody will do anything so this is a
wrong approach it's like a post factum
approach
it has been informing us that well
the explosion has happened you have to
run and you have no alternatives
everybody have to do something in this
area yes there was a certain peaceful
period everybody was thinking that well
we will get around it everything's going
to work and right now we've been told no
we have to move in this direction
well speaking about those solutions
to protect industrial companies what is
the main idea of them
as i understand the kaspersky lab has
its own solution positive technology has
its own solution but do you have any
common idea between them and what is the
difference we have
certain common functionality
we
yes we have different functionality but
from this point of view i see that our
company and
positive technologies are moving towards
the complex solution towards certain
extended detection uh response xdr when
the information is collected from
different sources
everything is being analyzed
attacks are being discovered
and certain responses being
done
to block these threats
considering the industrial specifics
but our companies are moving from
different directions
from different functionality the company
tries to use
those technologies which these companies
strong in and build their approach on
the basis of these technologies you use
with the use cm and other management we
use our new cm
our sandboxes
our
industrial traffic monitoring systems
so we are moving in the right direction
into complex protection into complex
automated defense
so when we speak about solutions for the
market the focus is
now we should always focus speaking
about companies and our partners
integrators
their focus was always been stopping on
technologies and techniques like
software hardware
but
right now we are moving in a direction
that we are looking at these solutions
only as technological stack or product
stack but certain set of methodologies
and approaches with help of which these
solutions can be implemented
and even starting
with the story of making inadmissible to
become impossible
a stack of technologies and products
first of all
is using this technology and methodology
and this methodology is being offered on
the market so how the industrial company
irrespectively from the industry like is
it a steel mining company or electrical
energy company how can they
use this first approach
properly
how can they properly understand their
own risks how they can properly build
processes and how can they choose
technological products and solutions
solving this problem so from our side
our approach looks like that
do you feel competition between
yourselves on the market
well we do participate in all the
tenders and contests and this is good
competition is always good
so you don't let each other to relax we
are thankful to our competitors they
make us better
yeah they make us better
and stronger so this is wonderful
we are friends
and we are competitors at the same time
and it should be like that
this is wonderful
i'm glad to see that you have healthy
competition between yourself which in
the end ron will help you to make those
products
and our main goal is to protect the
industry is to protect companies and it
will help you
to make products
whose operation will prevent
explosions will prevent emissions will
prevent shutdowns of electricity or any
other negative events will be prevented
with the help of your products and we
don't want them to happen uh with the
inhabitants of modern cities
so fight
fighters
you have very good goals
it's to improve our lives and make it
comfortable thank you very much guys