once once can you hear me great
uh thank you all uh who've survived
uh
this session is considered to be closed
well it's not closed in the sense that
we're closing the doors and windows but
we just wouldn't like what's being
discussed here
to come out
on press pages so if any journalists are
still in the room please leave the room
if you consider yourself to be an honest
person
so all
and please don't
spread the news so we're here to
discuss the opinions i see some people
from marketing pr
and say it's them uh whom i'm addressing
they're all nodding their heads so
perhaps they agree
so the idea of this session
is about the thoughts uh that
i
was touring with uh when we were
preparing uh the phd agenda we're
talking about tectonic shifts but mostly
uh in the sense
that it affects
the regulators the service providers but
we don't discuss a lot how it looks from
the customer viewpoint what's happening
how in their eyes
the
information security
concepts get changed so this is what i'd
like to start with so we here have
panelists from companies that deal with
customers directly and so because they
are working with them face to face
talking
one-on-one with number ones and number
twos of the companies
so let me introduce my co-authors let me
put it this way
romantic ligand from positive
technologies
genius denis andreyevsky expert an
expert put it this way
a person with a rich biography let's put
it this way
dmitry i got a teen cough
so what i would like to learn
about is our joint understanding and
opinion about what's happening so the
words tectonic shift that we heard in
the first keynote discussion uh perhaps
do not reflect the current situation for
everyone it looks different now for you
security people friends how does the
current picture look what do you think
is happening in the country how
bad it is how dangerous it is in your
understanding based on your experience
uh both in your companies and in market
experience
well for any order will do
i understand you're laughing i am
already waiting for customers who would
say what's happening on their side let
me start look my story is very simple
and very vivid if the past all of us as
industry as experts
were
saying we as a vendor when we're selling
our product
so the guys were saying this to their
top managers when they were building
information security look there's cyber
security there are hackers there are
attackers and it all may lead to
inadmissible uh implications here so you
need to be build protection and the
asset was what is inadmissible these
things don't exist look in the media
it's all quiet nobody's being attacked
our colleagues are not being attacked so
i think
so if
we take a high-level view not even
delving inside so what's changed that no
such questions are being asked anymore
so what uh us and not being attacked
other people not being attacked if a
cyber security and not a
a must so
this thing has passed about attacks that
other people's talk uh because it's uh a
lot of there's a lot of curious things
beneath this top level denis may i ask
you
how does it look from fintech and
banking community
in my understanding what i see
the number of attacks
has grown
uh many times over uh so there's uh some
uh incredible amounts of you know
smoke black noise white noise
i think
the financially motivated hackers are
still financially motivated hackers
those who wanted to earn
some dao
are still there they did not change they
did not
re-focus on espionage but in addition to
this we got a huge amount of
height
of low and to medium skilled hackers
maybe kids of different level of
training not very high level
uh who organize ddos attacks
uh of whom uh there are 20 times more
than in the past and if you
take a look at most ddos attacks they're
quite simple in their structure
they are not really implemented very
smartly
and so you can't see anything new and
novel there
what kind of changes
that could happen in terms of the
government
groups that could attack
the government organizations uh it's
difficult for me to say
but
i saw a publication and they said that
they uh named the level of attack on the
russian uh companies and organizations
critical what does it lead to of course
companies uh who did not do security at
all of course they suffered from these
kids and from this low and medium
skilled level
with those who did
information security financial
organizations
they
had these attacks and had had these
attacks what's become worse
gi and security tools
is going away the international
community is disconnecting from the
russian
federation this imposes a negative trail
on
the developing information security on
its development vector
on the scale level of what we're doing
on the trends
that
exist in information security we're
losing uh some of uh threat intelligence
it's also bad we may not be able to see
uh some threats that may already be
happening all over the world and it's
not good uh it should be
counted
so considering uh that protectiveness
goes down uh the attacks go up my
personal opinion is that information
security in addition to what has been it
has been uh doing so far should revise
its approaches to the organization of uh
security if overlane security tools for
some organizations were okay
but saying overlane uh i mean when the
information security was not talking a
lot with business was not going deeply
into how business was structured it was
just you just installed several anti-aav
solutions and nothing more than that so
perhaps it's no longer the time for that
if business comes to me saying that i
have a process to work with personal
data so the security person
instead of saying that i have a federal
152 and the order 11
19 of f stack i think 199 is the number
of that order so he should
look back and ask business
can you avoid processing data at all
because if they can avoid the process
that process could be called security by
design of course it's simplistic example
but in the whole i think information
security should restructure uh regroup
in this direction to do it security by
itself and i mean everybody knows that
zero trust security by design security
in depth with all uh the uh different
borders of if the organization had a
firewall at
the perimeter and nothing else then
perhaps this organization is not
doing well with but if the organization
has been doing uh security in depth
including all the different security
components for different business
processes then on the whole they should
be okay okay if they break one of the 10
elements so it's not good but not too
bad
at least
they can maneuver so security in depth
if
the
company and the information security
people were following these principles
then
they shouldn't get any anything how to
adjust so perhaps
they
this could happen
later on uh unless they
become more serious
so we have these intelligence
incentives to
regroup
meaning that the market need is there
and i hope that
new companies will rise on that and the
existing companies will strengthen based
on that
there are enough of brains in russia
i'll come back a little bit towards
roman said in the beginning
to the effect in the effect that now
the management
uh is no longer able uh to not notice
what's happening in the world of
information security well uh i might say
that they shouldn't have done that in
the past because there were quite a lot
of
public cases
but now as we're talking with customers
we indeed see that this story has
received an additional push
generating a lot of interest and on the
same at the same time i
uh observe a parallel trend
that the number of questions
that
has become
of interest to the management
has grown as well i thought information
security is not the only one on the one
hand there is interest but on the other
hand the window of opportunity for you
to bring your ideas
has shrunk
so you know if your business is crashing
if your logistic chains
go down maybe information security is
not something that you would be prepared
you should spend all of your time as
the ceo
so this uh also has to be born in mind
and coming back to the question of how
are we to work with customers
i feel that uh from the point of view
of us as professionals working with
customers
we
see an idea coming on the forefront that
we should take more responsibility
well
the information security you know the
usual way is when we don't guarantee
anymore
and
we can't calculate how much we're going
to lose so i think we should cover these
two questions now
provide more guarantees to customers and
make the information security uh simpler
for a business that's an answer to your
question hey guys
uh i would perhaps like to argue with
dimitri i started with
the top management
but look the first point you made
foreign vendors have left on the one
hand it's not pleasant but look what was
the position if
you
are a good
state enterprise
so please invest
money and return it into the economy
country but not to
you know take it out the country by
paying for inventors if you're a
commercial company well it's up to you
this
thing has always existed in the russian
market and it's always been on the
balance
they left and it's not good because
indeed
some advanced technologies are no longer
available to us we lost
some
easy to use technologies but what has
happened to
counterbalances
see uh security people were wanting her
to cover the infrastructure i mean it's
okay within your organization but there
were a lot of companies that didn't have
either administrative or financial
resource to build uh security covering
all the perimeter all the key systems
and for them it doesn't matter
whether these products would be
forwarding made or domestically
engineered
yes they
started but but now they started
where they
need to
build something to protect
so on the whole
well it happens through pain of course
it's bad
uh but the effect is there on the
technology level and and on the
technology level i think uh it's more
positive and you get into critical
infrastructure
uh
as a matter of principle even for myself
as a person with experience in the
international market you know i've
always
voted for best practices wherever they
come from so my
philosophy is such that for certain
industries for certain
technology components it would be wiser
to use domestically
developed solutions
even
at
not talking about them uh being not so
user-friendly well colleagues i listen
to you and i was surprised by one thing
a gap in
the perception
you both said
that the news background and what's
happening is indeed
exerting pressure on the company leaders
there really knew that something is
happening in cyber security and on this
waves wave
security people
get an opportunity to have something
installed in their organization and here
i think that if a security person is
going to use this wave well i mean to
say i uh also exploit this wave and it
must be exploit exploited but
if they had not had dialogue with the
top managers uh before that this wave
will go away that's important yes uh so
uh the first failure and they say okay
good go away
i agree
uh what to do
that this dynamic should go away
well you know i mean everybody can
hear what they want
but what's the difference you're saying
the top managers have seen information
they use no they have found themselves
in the room where they had to make
decisions regarding cyber security
saving their business
as to the news yes they started to read
something more but what's radically
changes crisis committees and business
continuity committees uh rarely
intervenes in cyber security but in
these past few months several companies
have gone uh through the story of
creating uh crisis committees but i
still believe that the situation uh is
uh very bad had the dialogue not
been in place before that
it's not good
so
you what you have to do
is to build a regular dialogue with top
management so that they
could have an opportunity uh to make
decisions on information security so you
need to be able to speak to them
in the right language using the right
language
so had it not been
there before that this is a good
opportunity to start this dialogue
well we have a stop world called uh
decree
a lot has been said about it today
yesterday
we heard it in the keynote session from
the ministry of digital development uh
is perceived not so much as a carrot but
rather as a stick and
we
are interested in how companies are
going to feel uh in sprint
you know compliance is quite a bad story
uh it doesn't sell well uh with
customers it has
its clear restriction clear limit
connected to what we need to do as a
minimum so that the regulator should not
create make problems for us in the
future what dimitri has said is a very
important story because it defines who
is the decision-making person
for the ways of development of
information security in this
organization it's easy for dmitry to
talk because he's vice president and
he's in contact with number one and he
can
do
wage direct dialogue with a ceo which in
russian means that he
can get
what he needs if
you uh are linked to physical security
or
other types of security
you'll be proxied by a person whose life
experience is not
relevant
and as a rule
your concerns will never get to number
one
because the top manager
they
usually have a legal education
and they make decisions that they
will decide
based on their experience so there's a
gap between the cyber risk of the
organization
and
the
subject matter uh
that's typical of information security
also what i'd like to say
that we suddenly gotten new
opportunities a window of opportunities
but it looks uh that currently in the
moment
we have ourselves with a lot of contacts
where a lot
of information security tools that we've
chosen as best in the market or best in
terms of performance suddenly uh turned
into a pumpkin
and basically
you started getting information about
events
lost the opportunity to analyze them uh
there's a whole class of systems uh that
don't really exist in the russian market
and even if you if you uh you know
allocate a budget and identity and
allocate resources uh
it there will be
several months
of
gap
for you to start getting this
information the digital uh
sovereignty has not yet happened however
much we
were discussing about it
at another level
not at the level of cpu of
operating system so nobody has taken
away the problem with undocumented
capabilities
and when they get statistic
it's mostly about web ddos fishing
but as a rule this is just a background
for more serious attacks uh this takes
the time of the security resources
but against this background uh serious
scenario based attacks uh are waged with
novel
attack vectors
so i have a feeling
it's just
like
at the moment
where a parasitist
uh
jumps from the airplane i have a feeling
that in the very near future
we can run into serious problems which
just haven't yet arrived certain things
could happen
so invisible attacks that sooner or
later yes because uh they don't
necessarily have immediate impact it all
depends on their goal
you know
as a moderator i'll try to
move closer to you
and you know what's cool usually when
you're entering a discussion
anywhere you're sitting and uh think uh
about ndas uh what you can't speak about
what's not uh and now it's become so
simple
uh well i heard from you roman
that everybody started thinking uh what
to do and start doing well i agree with
thinking but not about doing
so math media were ddosed for a week or
so
math media were not doing anything and
then it did something okay three weeks
passed and airlines started to be
deducted and for some uh reason uh
successfully so i mean it looks like
airlines uh were watching uh mass media
being ddosed and uh
why should they come to us and now they
say oh what do we do we're selling
tickets uh-huh that's perhaps uh what
happened to us so you know the story is
like
that that some triggers have worked in
people's heads is only relevant for 10
to 15 percent of customers
so the national idea of the russian as
the saying says is until uh the uh
thunderbolt strucks uh the uh the
peasants
put across against his head so
we have started attacked at attackers
and uh we need to do uh ddos sock
run a pen test
in a day okay a day is too short let's
do it in three days okay an important
point
i didn't didn't say in which sequence
they started to do it yes ideally it
looks like this
but in real life it all happens just
like you said
the problem is that the coverage is now
complete so
everybody all industries are under
attack and very different companies from
small to large so my point was not so
much uh about the reason why uh they
have paid attention uh but about the
result so uh so they understand that
sooner or later it will reach you as
well so you need to do security
yes in fact you're saying
that it started happening but i remember
about five years ago you know in the
past
uh when we had this apt wave i was
uh visiting different banks and was
responding to incidents and like 24
hours of responsing
that was
the first time i understood i was
getting old i
went to sleep
at the computer
so
we uh cleaned the system drove the
hackers away uh stopped the incidents
the acute phase of the incident we were
going to leave and then be called by a
head of this organization i said dimitry
can you stay a bit uh until everything
is fixed so that it shouldn't get to
there once again first i wanted to swear
and then
gradually uh i exhaled and said you need
at least
three or four years to work intensively
to remove this
to remove the reasons that could lead to
this
and indeed so the guy didn't have
understanding number one don't have the
understanding that security cannot be
switched by a button and quite often
they really have expectations okay
why don't you spend another day or two
but make it
secure
okay
i would uh focus uh your
uh
point when you're saying that until the
thunderbolt strikes uh a
uh presence uh will not put across on
his forehead
uh you shouldn't
miss
guide your
customers or everyone says indeed
the market
has people who has done security of
those who haven't done security and
those who haven't done it now may
be i may start doing that
and here we
have to deal with the
subjective
uh vision of a person working in the
security organization
vis-a-vis their
manager the top manager it all depends
on their character it all depends on
their relationship if in some industry
it doesn't matter which one
ddos attacks are happening and in the
adjacent industry
you could
think that
it wouldn't happen to them so if people
don't expect these things to happen well
perhaps it's not going to change until
something really critical happens or
until
some revolution happens because you know
everybody knows that antivirus virus is
needed
on working computers not everyone okay
practically everyone everybody heard
about that
well i wouldn't agree i think most
statistically most people understand
that even
my home computer needs an antiviral
virus
so perhaps some more progressive
approaches will evolutionary uh reach
that but that will happen
well i think the av story uh is
actually a different story it's actually
a story about kaspersky
they spoke so much about themselves
that people started to think
it's not because you need to be secured
but you can't do without these guys so
actually it was part of brand building
from kaspersky and basically something
like that can be reproduced in other
areas colleagues let's continue
i
am imposing it my own psychology you
know i discuss with someone and the
feelings i've had over the past two or
three years is that either i'm in
inception or in matrix movies uh so a
week starts and it ends and you
think that it can't get worse and then
you know there's a knock on the door
life brings new surprises in different
aspects somebody uh
well did you expect the pandemic in 2020
did anybody expect
what happened on 24th of february
i've already mentioned this joke in the
keynote session
almost every day you know all about
every day
i
get a call like that hey guys strengthen
security
why there's information that tomorrow an
unprecedented attack will happen across
the entire territory of russia and way
to get this information
from is from secrets hacker telegram
channels
you know these secret telegram channels
uh i think are now being read by all
managers
whether they
subscribe to them or not but they're
there and then
we
see anonymous says who will say that by
the end of this week all atms will
become empty
uh there's a cybersec channel
that makes very strong statements by the
end of this week the nuclear industry of
russia will stall
we've got access to uh the entire energy
system and far east will be blacked out
and
you get upset
if you get uh and then it doesn't happen
so my personal feeling is that the
audience is becoming to get tired
and
the
uh they start stop believing that
security breaches may become critical
for their organizations how does it look
from your side from your perspective
yourself to talking to
your managers your top managers your
customers
do they believe in information security
the important thing is not to try uh to
deliver this information to the top ones
well we don't they read themselves well
if they've read something i'll let them
come to an expert and ask if they ask me
you know they do ask me periodically
i'm not going to give any names
yesterday i was asked dimitri can you
well there's so there's data from yeah
uh i looked there's my data there so
delete it please
i said i can't do that
i'm explaining how that basically
they're out in the world
but i'll i explained then that is
basically a hype do you understand that
your data
not
in the same volume
but
what would you just see
but you know many times over uh spread
across the internet i can find for you
you'll be surprised how many exciting
things can be found about you where you
park your car how you move what you eat
who you meet and so on and so forth and
this breaking point why does it happen
it's because of this hype the people
need to be explained
all this
has been in existence and it still
exists it's just that the information
background has changed in the past we
had a focus on leakages leakages from
banks maybe uh half a year or maybe a
whole year
all the news so media were talking about
that now they switched to hacker attacks
of these anonymouses
but i think that adequate people would
hardly respond to that
they don't read telegram channels
okay there's an alternative point of
view
do all
business
uh managers get under the influence of
this news
uh background well it usually happens
that
the
manager sends you a an article
uh and ask you to comment
if it's a small bank manager than the
ask details i would like uh to say
something in
roman's favor uh we were discussing risk
management and the sidelines and i think
the story here is that the function of
information security
should one way or the other
get
in
to become part of
operational risk management company
because at the enterprise level
cyber risks
are not considered seriously
but
operating or operation risk
are certainly considered positive
technologies uh offered a new approach a
platform
yeah yeah and roman perhaps
the main speaker who was explaining
how
you can do a prediction forecast i
already i'm really so i
just said i was
uh giving uh
baton to you
well uh it's not going to happen
actually i'll come back
to uh the discussion about these calls
from the mentioned this information what
do we need to do look
in the first period first days and weeks
and later what our company
facing
a crisis a cyber crisis they had uh
problem problems in their operation uh
caused by cyber attacks it is an
exercise everybody knows
which by the way
is
uh practiced even uh poorer and less
frequently than
business
continuity
so it's an escalation then security
exercises it's about business continues
here
so you
what happens uh there are important
landmarks to
convene uh the crisis community i.t
information security
er and hr
so they need to understand uh what's
working what's not what has suffered
people customers equipment life and they
start making certain steps considering
the situation where we are so people who
have heard
it and
are already panicking they can be
told okay uh you can strengthen the
security but you convene within the
organization and work through your own
internal communication should it happen
tomorrow like your attack tomorrow and
you're out on a vacation well it's not
funny it's indeed it was one of the
practices but then it was somehow sent
to our customers and partners as a list
of
steps to make then there were
technical components
i t i s forensics perimeter that were
the actions to be made momentarily and
here at the end of the day we were
taking this acute pain
of
the customer you did the same and we did
the same helping other organizations but
once the acuteness was going down then
another important question
was coming up on what next and then as
dmitry
said
so
can you hear me for the next three years
we have also seen uh things like that
but being a vendor uh we did not quench
this desire but we uh would say
something like this okay
uh you have now felt the brunt you have
now understood what's inadmissible in
your company you've really seen that
people
have started to
do differently now it's become clear
what's inadmissible
the site is down of the process
installing and things like that the data
is out there and now we're saying let's
build correct potential uh protection
after that
i hope uh
we'll have enough power
to
for the process to come to an end
well look roman
you are talking about the situation when
the customer faces a problem
but my question was different
some customers haven't met any problems
yet
and
who was broken
for example a metal producer the
e-commerce
companies
portals
nothing bad happened no
power company
the site was broken but electricity is
here
root tube failed what about routine what
is through tube it's nothing of course
you can
disconnect the site but you cannot
disconnect an
airplane
and
people
do not believe that
attacks uh can be really dangerous how
can we
tell
your manager that
invisible attacks
are dangerous you cannot touch them and
feel them
you cannot see them and but they happen
i agree it's very difficult to explain
you cannot touch it
that's why we have the hardware here
if
there is a probability
then
you have to do the retrospective
analysis
pen
that was shown to the top manager
and
they said that scada segmentation
physical
and any everything else
can be done
at the stage when
we
invited two persons and for three days
uh from the internet they went into the
scada system
and they said that they can penetrate
into the enterprise and stop the main
business processes
then it worked
because the main thing was not to press
anything and damage anything but just to
demonstrate that we can do it now
if you show that to the production
people
and show it to the top manager he said
well this scenario should become
unacceptable and impossible
pin tests are carried out
to
demonstrate to the top manager that we
cannot be broken but the real
uh target is what kind of attacks
can be taken and what
might the impact be
for example on friday night when
everyone is out of the office
then
what may happen
and the hacker will cho will choose the
the most
unacceptable hour the most inconvenient
hour to attack
at the fourth or five fifth pin test you
say that you are
protected your domain
is not
broken
it's all right but
that's about uh test four at test five
when you have test one then
uh the
result is
quite bad because everything is broken
everything is protected nothing is
properly controlled and so on
and the people who do the pen test first
disclose the important
gaps and vulnerabilities and exploits
they see the gaps where
there are no policies there are no
controls
then they get to
the people who have a lot of bridges and
super
administrator
rights access rights yes
but that is from our old life
that's right
this is all good but why those people
who attack us
every day
why didn't they do what you say before
because of the low level of corporate
culture even if an incident happens the
enterprise
tries to conceal it
and never admit it
[Music]
and now all those people
publish everything
but
sometimes they're fakes
anonymous said they broke here and there
but no one confirmed
there was no
great
impetus
i am going to continue about pin tests i
fully agree with you
the only thing is that the most
efficient story
is
pin testing
social
media
because it's very
easy to explain to a non-technical
person
when you have a story a detective story
without technical details
why nothing bad happened yet
this is not a big problem because a lot
of things have already happened
you
can have a lot of examples in different
industries
i mean my opinion about what you asked
for
so there is a lot of hype and so on so
forth
i think that people who
monitor
the real situation
the trends
and the tendencies they believe that
the situation may
deteriorate to such
an extent that any
cases any tools
can be used
including
events that can lead to catastrophic
consequences
if the situation deteriorates we shall
see such attacks
of course
i would
put it differently
talking
through attacks
doesn't no let's put it differently
i think we have to
display a more systematic approach
we have to talk about data security and
allow the top manager to
improve
data security
taking into account real attacks that
have happened
supply chain attack
library attacks fishing
perimeter breakthroughs
this is
something that doesn't work
they said well
so every day we have some kind of attack
there is no panic
we have such attacks everything is all
right top management needs a more
systematic approach to data security
and then sales
how to work with the customer
later
we have different customers who have
different buyers in the customer company
one thing is token taking to cfo the
other is chr
the other is sales
it's important to talk to
where if you talk to cto
then you have to talk about availability
if it's this is ceo
you have to show economic feasibility
and efficiency of
your security
uh solution please don't
frighten him don't try to scare him with
fishing
he said no i don't believe you
no no don't scare anyone
with fishing
i talked about how to begin
negotiations uh
if you
if there is no talk you have to involve
the person
to stir up some kind of emotion to make
people want to talk to you
a few days ago
someone said that i'm talking in terms
of
large-scale cooperation security but the
world is much
wider
and now i see the same dmitry is talking
about the processes
he has the right to
configure the process
in the right way you have resources you
have expertise
you you know business tasks business
requirements
what about the companies who have no
security people who have
no security at all
they have to
they have
50 of them is open source it has nothing
in that case the company comes
to us for a service
it says that your open source looks like
that
yes
this
proposal
to cfo ceo cto can
are different and they
can include not only attacks
and their possible impact
but
the the people who are decision makers
and you can help him take decisions
three options for example or install
this and it will cost you a million if
you do something lower it may be 500 000
and we can do it at 10 000 but in that
case you will have this and that and you
wouldn't have that yet at a certain
event i heard reports about insurance of
cyber risks
and this is a story that we cannot
launch
for the last for the last few years we
have insurance company and somebody has
already insured something and the
program is clear but it doesn't
work properly
we have four
options
of risk management insurance is one of
the four and perhaps we have to pay
attention to it because it's
more understandable to business
departments and it's more interesting
than
[Music]
in
detail
of course we have to take into account
force mature because uh companies some
attacks can be disregarded as force
majora where insurance doesn't work
it's just it's a common
dima operates within an optimal
operating
structure but we had a
custom a vendor who
tried to explain to our ceo
what is shock soc
why
talking
he they didn't mention reflection
contexts
red hunting
never just soc it's typical just because
the
top manager business didn't have
relevant experience if you talk to
the top manager
in the language the top manager
understands
the business language
these are the risks you have to manage
risks and to manage risk you have such
and such tools and levers
we often
bring in historical archive solutions
physical security
[Music]
physical security data security the what
is common there the word security and
nothing else
scenarios risks are quite different
and
we have to
be able to talk to cfo ceo cto
and talk to them
as an independent agency
with its own budget with its own face
i saw that
we
launched projects expertise
processes
in that case if you are not constrained
by some other layers until with that you
have to penetrate until you reach the
target
i have a picture
if
inside the company if the company never
dealt with security before
this is the good time to start
we have a good reason to do that if the
company dealt with security then
we have to explain what is new what is
happening now
what is
happening
in the telegram channels of the
attacking party
so
there is no
apocalypse in general nothing much
happened we
protected we do protect now
yes to explain why now we
have the new situation do we have to
exploit fear
do we need a different psychological
approach
we deal with
the army not because you want to
start a war but you think about
potential
[Music]
impact
yes
the probability of risks
is higher now
that is the point
now talking about risks
and cyber
stability
this story like bcm
often was somewhere at the background
but it's time
to deal with it now
cyber security cyber stability and we
have to do it
is the right way from the very beginning
not just to buy a new server but
let's look at the stability of the
company in different situation yes we
were talking about social stability
we have to explain
to the top management what is really
happening
why the situation is dangerous now
why some people are nervous
others are not but at this point i would
like to thank all the panelists and all
the
listeners who are coming to an end
thank you goodbye