hi there my name is alex hesmernov and
i'm going to talk to you today
about sca
challenges
what it is and what are the challenges
and how it all works
i'm here to
present profiscope and we do automated
audits and we develop automatic
auditments and
now we have a system for compositional
analysis
that is called code scoring
it's been a while since we started
analyzing source codes and we have our
own conference for source code and
open data science community we also make
free of charge open courses about
in particular about licensing of open
source
software
which is also relevant to sca but it's
not the topic of my today's presentation
and we're always happy to
raise the awareness in this matters
just to give you some context and some
numbers you all know the numbers that we
have a lot of open source code out there
more than 200 million unique projects as
they say
it does not necessarily add value
because the valuable projects are less
than 200 million but
at least one uh command was done by
around 70 million people and the number
of people doing open source comments is
going up and the usability
has gone up by 72 percent in 2020-21
we also know that the numbers of supply
chain attacks
increases
we are not going deep into the topic of
supply chain attacks in this
presentation but we bear this in mind
and this grows and the number of
supply chain attacks is something that
can't
be bothered you
and these are the data on packages
growing in package indexes the new uh
versions
emerging in the market and in the year
2021 alone at least one third of new
pocket packages arrived
cool right
and also so very many new versions and
you have to follow all of them you have
to update information on them you have
to identify
the necessary
resolve the necessary
issues find vulnerabilities for all
these new components identify licenses
build compliance etc
and here we don't even have space
for
javascript
in this slide
[Music]
the number of components in javascript
is growing and quite
significantly
those who really know
everything about devops and they know
how to release 10 times a day huh
a python
very similar to java
slightly less pronounced though and we
can see
around 300 000 packages in python and we
can see that in the year 2021
we have
around one third of new projects arrived
so it all
gets released and the new versions
uh appear in the market open source is
popular and this popularity
obviously spurs the industry the
development industry and development
becomes faster and also it was
mentioning that open source
contribution to the code base is
larger and more substantial
i'm not insisting but as a rule open
open source is the majority
according to title of 92 percent of your
codes 92 percent of proprietary uh
projects make use of open open source
code which is a big number
so
this is how we come
up with this pyramid was open sourcing
the basis of this pyramid like a
platform really
a foundation i would call it and we have
close code on top of it
the close code is the unknown it's
something that needs to be researched
in order to find anything something or
anything interested in it
and obviously it could be open or closed
to different extents and there is also
also open source code
which is known which is scannable
and a lot of researchers
dig into it and publish
correspondent information
on the kind of vulnerabilities
there are and how they they got fixed
and it's popular not just among the
developers but also among the
researchers
it's pretty obvious that you really want
to account
for the index of package used in the
community and in the code base and we
can see the popularity of packages
if you just take top 10
is
more researched and then 36 percent of
projects
we can find vulnerabilities and it's
interesting to follow these
vulnerabilities it's interesting to
follow this
progress
in the rest of the package base only
eight percent contain vulnerability
and popular packages are the ones better
studied right
and you know the vulnerabilities there
and people then shy
uh
away from
demonstrating and
actually
making public the exploits that can be
well exploitable
speaking of the growing open source
i would say that number of
vulnerabilities discovered year in year
is growing as well
if you look at the number of
vulnerabilities while open source
mobility
grows
in 2021
it actually breaks through the roof
but at the same time if you look at
separate feeds separate packages and
analyze github security advisory
these columns shows that discovery is
not even
it does depend on the
feed holder focus
the ones who process it if we look at
primaven for example in 2020 it was
very high
in
npm
they started to
um do something about vulnerabilities
around what two three years ago
the black are the critical ones as you
can understand
and then
pip
was of great interest in 2021 in 22 it's
also of interest but not
yet
we don't yet have too many
vulnerabilities identified
an open source much as we love it
is not secure yes we love it yes we make
use of it everybody loves it everybody
makes use of it but you have to
check it for vulnerabilities everybody
knows that it contains vulnerabilities
and you have to do something about it
you either scan it the whole of it
or read
some other people read the code
within the framework of sagdav
there is this whole concept of handling
the licenses because licenses may be
incompatible or non-existent
and
there are all kinds of risks like expert
limitations that may impact
licenses
that are not
exactly
approved
self-approved for example
licenses
and backdoors is a separate
saying
[Music]
they could be embedded into any kind of
software and then can be triggered
by various things and they are
detectable they are being studied and by
stat analysis in particular
and backdoors
when identified also gets their
correspondent code of vulnerabilities
and are published
so de facto they're also
vulnerabilities so in order to work with
that not just with the vulnerabilities
backdoors and licenses
you would use software composition
analysis and let me
give you some background information
about it just in case you don't
really know
what it is all about
so sca
is about studying components
of a software
and identifying this component so you
basically disintegrate
the packages and you
come up up with the list of packages
with all the material information
contained and representing this
information with all its risks to the
user so that the user can take action
more often than not it's pretty
straightforward and it consists of three
steps first one is inventorization when
we scan our code base and we identify
the dependencies we identify where we
have directive or direct dependence
dependencies where we have transitive
dependencies dependencies of
dependencies you know all these trees
and then all these
things we identify are checked against
vendor base
open base then we detect it and we
identify the licenses we identify all
the vulnerabilities that are there in
the database and so we take it
and
stay informed and formulate our policies
and take actions
speaking of actions this may start
was like a notification
you got a
dashboard a notification or a jira
identification or even blockage
but it all begins with inventorization i
think you would agree
so in order to carry out this
inventorization you don't have to go to
a warehouse and count your software
manually
there is a
possibility for using automation
and it consists of three steps first you
study the manifests
so basically it's static parsing static
analysis
which consists in parsing
of the correspondent notations in the
manifest that tells us of which packages
are used which versions are used
it it not that it comes without a
problem
i guess many of you have encountered
with data science and i love this
example
of data scientists in this context
independent says data scientists would
only give you the the title of the
package and that's it
and that's all
very understandable it's not their
responsibility but anyway dependencies
can be there they can be with or without
taking the
transitive dependencies into account
and it all depends on whether you build
a log
files credit log point a log or anything
do you do do you build your transitive
dependencies on your own
it's it's basically a cult your
development culture if you don't do it
then sca a compositional system
it wouldn't find transitive dependencies
and it would try to build it on its own
using the environment and using its own
discretion
so these are the two basic things
that
that you have in
sas scanners
and there is an additional functionality
i identification of
open source inclusion you all know
shazam application right
when you listen to a piece of music and
you id you you manage to get information
on everything from the title of the
album all the way to the right well
you're not very interesting in the
rights but anyway
same with the code sca
we will listen to the software software
uh we
get information on hashes and those can
be um crypto resistant or non-crypto
resistant and you have a shazam of code
and you have an open source inclusion
identification open source inclusion is
when you take an external
uh library and and then put it right
there in your code base and make use of
it because it's fast it's
straightforward
and you may
find it
alarmingly
wild but this is something that happens
and happens all the time and the problem
is that in this open with this open
source inclusions well they are included
in it and then they lie there idly
or not i believe they're being used
while the
uh sources
and and your own uh your own source code
starts to get
entangled with those inclusions and
these inclusions they get updated they
get new functions they contain
vulnerabilities
oftentimes
say
you get this inclusion and it works and
everything it works and everything is
fine and it's it's there for 10 years
and we have a lot of vulnerabilities
there
and it happens i mean it happens quite
regularly
so after
you study
the manifest the transitive
depends it is not just parsing a files
but resolving
uh the transitive dependencies and
identifying the open source inclusions
you get the so-called software bill of
materials or spom
um software bill of materials so
it contains
all information on all dependencies and
control sums that can be enriched
according to particular standards with
information and vulnerabilities on
licenses all that it it may contain
a lot of data
then um
how
sca system is used
it's
either done in the mode of firewalling
components we want to prohibit things
and we want to prohibit our own
discretion we have this open source with
all the components that flies in and
gets stored and we accuse of it
and on the other hand we have the users
who want to get something new at all
times and this is an issue and we need
to follow it and we need to understand
what they do and how they do it and when
they do it
then cicd security gates is another
option
when for each build we
look at and we analyze and we identify
what's wrong and also there is this mode
of continuous mod monitoring you know
that you have already released
if you are related to software
development you know that you released
the version is out
people keep using
using it and old versions are also still
out there and you need to know
how vulnerable they are
same goes to premise products and all
that everybody tries to update regularly
but
the issue with vulnerability of the
previous versions of your software does
exist and you need to follow it
the so-called shift left approach
is oftentimes mentioned by partners
rather than vendors but this is indeed
very
relevant and not just
it it just does not only concern the
the old versions
you also want to monitor the code that
you get here and now
you know out of uh deaf fingers
and you can actually monitor even some
branches when we develop separate things
there is this whole other thing of
integration into
idea
and according to our
polls
looks like this uh functionality is just
seen
as convenient
but it's only convenient for those who
know what they want and how they want it
for the rest of the
people out there idea function is not
being used
and this is something that needs to be
changed because
everything comes out of minds and
fingers of our developers so how it
works
this is sca firewall
when you have open source on one hand
with all kinds of npms and mavens and
python and all that
and we do understand that
one thing is to
put a link to github and on the other on
and the other thing when you have
um
maven um
central hub
there are more than 200 of these indexes
and you need
you need to gather this information and
provide it to the users and you need to
deduplify it and
find gaps and
remediate
typos and work with this information
so
when you look at your component base
and you monitor your component base
you begin by
creating a warehouse of artifacts there
are
various
types
of solutions you can use here
you can use git club
or anything else some of it is on the
slide then you have either a plugging
with sca or you use some programmatic
interfaces
and you get information
on whether or not this goes through the
quality gates or security gates
that
is identified in your sca policy
and after that it's either guaranteed or
goes on for development if it goes in
guaranteeing you get notification and
you keep working you keep checking the
package
for example if it's a lunch after a
particular
date you put it on test analysis or you
try to understand what goes on with it
same mode as
the second mode as a sca used for ci cd
so what we have is gitlab team city
jenkins on the one hand on one side and
sca system that checks our policies and
what it does
it fills our software bill of materials
and we can play with it
and it form forms particular logs that
you can look at and
importantly it also blocks build
so
if we see something
and we didn't have a
firewall we can catch it
before it goes to the build phase and
sca continuous monitoring
is when you
obviously continuously
look at vulnerabilities
emerging
and we understand
that the older things are more
vulnerable
well vulnerability doesn't really change
in time if packages do not get changed
but
vulnerabilities tend to get identified
publicly identified
and if they're public then they are
scannable and exploitable
policies differ
in this case
we are talking about sca policy
policies
so it's ifttt
if this then that
you may find a critical vulnerability
that
is not good enough
you get
a package in the top list
or you have problem with the license
sca is something that does it it's just
part of security development if you make
use of component that is not legitimate
to be used then at some point of time
someone would come to you and say
uh that's
that's not that's not
acceptable not necessarily your legal
specialist
and at some point of time you have so
many things attached to this
non-legitimate
part
that it's very difficult to take it out
so what
you need to pay attention to when
working with sca identifying
vulnerabilities would be the first one
you need to understand what are the
databases used
what are the feeds
used to get information on
vulnerabilities because this is the most
important field it's very important to
understand
uh how
deep the database is and
i'm going to
discuss it and we find
vulnerabilities in two public uh hubs in
cva database and
ghc ghca and also some commercial
databases
it's being updated analysts
work with it
well not necessarily in a good way
and sometimes it's rather difficult to
make you that you you really need to
connect correct the databases and
do it iteratively
and then i address this to others in
order to work with this databases you
have to
make use of various identifiers
more than 50 with more than 50 versions
of packages and the vendor names changed
and number names of packages changed
you
really need to understand how to
go about it
so in order to identify the package you
may have several practices
common platform enumeration the so
called cpe and
package url or perl
the second one is less
used
but not yet
deeply implemented so cpe is a special
identifier that allows you to
come up with a special factor that would
tell you everything about what kind of
software it is it also describes some
hardware issues
and a vulnerability match is done using
cpe dictionary and i'm going to have a
separate state
slide on it
so you see the vector
but it's kind of not native
uh we also have package url or pearl
a lot of developers sca system
developers
take it
seriously it's more native and it's
readable
it has
the attributes it doesn't have
the hardware
and there is a prop identification
problem if you use it in cpe
mode there is a human factor
that may be a problem the problem with
cpe dictionary is that dictionary are
not
are sometimes not
not really full people make mistakes
people make typos
some
sometimes the programming language is
not mentioned or some other important
attributes are not mentioned
or vendor name may have changed
products name may have changed open
source as it is right
uh everything
keeps changing at all times
and obviously
you can do something about it
but it's it's it's still important to
it's still important to do something
and you have to make use
of particular algorithms of natural
language processing
doing
very minimum
machine learning to find and test
correspondent
aspects
and it all gets
got gets added by manual
rule-based
rule-based search
it's a necessity another problem that i
would like to
talk to you about is transitivity of
dependencies okay we have five
components
ten components
and it's okay we can check it manually
well cool but these components are
dependent and these dependencies
can
mutually impact each other
have you um
have you do you know about
log for xiao okay you have great
how about search
in your component days
right you searched for it
so this is a well-known topic and those
of you who search for this kind of
vulnerabilities would confirm me and
saying that it's not
always that you can directly find it
through i mean through direct
dependencies
so let's do problem setting first it's
pretty easy
we have this
uh well-known group of vulnerabilities
that we started to identify uh
on the 10th of um december 2021
and we
started to remediate it it was very
unpleasant thing
and
it was all over the news
so a lot of devops
devsecops a lot of developers
they started to search for these kind of
vulnerabilities
all
all the way till it got remediated
and actually
they thought was it to go further or to
get back to the previous version of 10
years ago
so here you see
a google security
graphic representation
as of december 2021
after the first vulnerability was
identified we have all maven packages in
uh
maven central artifacts
and we have
the numbers that are vulnerable and in
the first
days around 10 000 were fixed
and i i think it's a nice rate for open
source you know everybody going ahead
and trying to fix it and i'm going to
explain why it's cool but then there are
30 000 packages that haven't been
repeated six days everybody's shouting
out it was like almost like a pandemic
everybody were going ahead and searching
for it i probably am exaggerating a bit
so why it's not that simple to
remediate log for shell problem because
it's deeper
if you use log for uh gene directively
and you work with direct dependencies
but if it comes to you through
transitive dependencies it's very dif
difficult it's it's much more difficult
in this picture you already have
certain transitive dependencies
if you have direct dependencies then you
remediate it and that's it
but
you also may have transitive
dependencies the dependencies who is
going to remediate that
we remediated the
vulnerability identified but how about
the maintainer of your
transit dependency source
how to go about that shall you do it
manually
and then update if you find it important
or shall you maintain it in
in any way
you need to do it
and it takes time it takes a lot of time
and speaking of uh depth of penetration
same graph i think it's it's rather
interesting if you look at those 40 000
packages
that had in it log for g look for
channel um
issue
not log for g log for shell
you would see that
in terms of direct dependencies
we only have what around fifteen percent
of them
only fifteen percent with touch were um
was uh direct
while the peak of melbourne is is in the
sixth level of dependencies if you
analyze all log for shells we see
that it's a big big tree a branchy tree
and you need to be
uh knowledgeable about the fact that you
have a branchy trees and
you have them nested in one another
and you necessarily have to use
automation
if you're a data scientist
or researcher and you have three
dependencies
then
yes you can just
put the last version center to that
but it's not really
a good approach you really want to use
right package managers and managing for
the security information around you
i could see you with nodding your hands
when i said that 10 000 packages in six
days is fast well indeed it is fast and
this is something that is changing
considerably in the market eight years
ago
an update
uh
i mean time to respond to a
vulnerability
would be
slightly more than 12 months
and that was
when we already had devops that allows
us to make thousands to release releases
per day
when defcecops manifesto and all that
since the 2012 we all know that it's
cool and great but in 2014 as of 2014 it
takes around 300 days
to respond and remediate a vulnerability
in 2018 it's
158 days and in the year 2021 it's 30
days
and it's fast 30 days is already fast
if you do it if you're specialized on
that
you can do it even faster or at least
they think they can do it faster but
anyway if in order to do it fast and uh
effective and efficient you really need
to make use of automation
so next thing i want to mention in this
context
speaking of
trends and
challenges
well i'm
talking to you about all kinds of
problems like and
dictionaries that lack some data
but well fast
is another issue
to know the known is not enough
to know the known vulnerability and work
with them is not enough
we scan it and we find all the packages
with all the known vulnerabilities we
don't have any up to date we found all
the vulnerabilities remediated it
everything is cool but
it doesn't work this way does it
i think you all understand that
that's why there is this
motto
sas dust and sca it has to work
as a group
and it works depending on tasks
but again sca system
looks through open source components and
identifies the vulnerabilities
but
sca wouldn't analyze the code right
as real at least the trend today
is that
major vendors now try to add sas on top
of the sca
a white source a cenotep
all of them
trying to do something about it
but the reverse
is true as well
i want to draw attention to the fact
that if you scan
all of your open source
which is a big chunk of your database
who's going to go and then go ahead and
analyze it
in the year 2021
they took all the pipey
and they
put zest on top of it
and 50
of packages are vulnerable
if you now look deeper or you read the
article you'll see that
uh
there are vulnerabilities uh
that have
rather you know sizable substantial
like um injections and all that
and you you you want to do something
about it right you want to work with it
and you can't work with it
i just buy sass without component-based
analysis without sca
you may believe that sas is really cool
but
we do understand that open source
project code
we have so we have so so much of this
open source code that you have to you
know
do something about it and you can't go
um with
sas so a ca adds sass
and sass
start to work in
sca mode so they kind of try to
integrate
and probably even mutually displace each
other at one point
another
aspect
that now lips to the eye while we've
been thinking about it for uh ten years
i would say it's karma
when i was getting ready for this
presentation i thought of telling you a
few words about what happened
lately
that in the last two years we have a lot
of deletion of packages from package
indexes just because the developer
wanted to do it
and i'm going to
tell you about it but one year ago
i was making a presentation
on sca
and i was told that yeah it's all right
but open source is such a good thing it
can't be vulnerable it's all in your
head
all the vulnerabilities are in your head
yes i laughed at them
really
out loud
i mean
you are
deep into the process and you know how
how it works and how it is being studied
and you understand that
no this is the code and it's vulnerable
go ahead and try to do something about
it
right
well i explained myself i was very
nice
in doing it
but the person who was posing the
question didn't agree with me
time has passed
and i think i now understand this guy
and yes you can be
um
you can
be very
verbose about it
the developers
started to behave
misbehave deleting versions of packages
while the packages are very actively
used and it's an issue
and package in this owners are not just
like microsoft
but
npm and pipey
and others
and people
people's attitude dif attitudes differ
let me give you some food for thought
we
let's say we have we had
google play and
app store what happened to these apps
they're being checked
and sometimes they checked for security
in open source
and again it's just by way of analogy
can you imagine in open source someone
to
find resource and stamina
to check all the packages that come into
the open source
i think it would just freeze the build
well
probably people would start to actually
look for vulnerabilities and the market
would grow
and
it would be a positive thing
but again if you limit the packages
coming
it's not going to
work to the benefit of the
community
because open source is open and this is
the way you have to work with it
and yes you can
take measures
say a popular
packet cannot be deleted or if it is
deleted then it has to give
some certain time
for people to catch something if they
want to
so this is one thing
and this is
related to
um
us to the security and to
the uh you know mental image of
vulnerabilities
sometimes people introduce malware
and they kind of
turn
turn the arms on open source community
and create vulnerabilities and it's a
fact and everybody knows that and it
exists
and
if we're talking about injecting malware
it gets vulnerability code and it's
identifiable
it's identifiable by sca
or
sometimes even by fast
if you wish to
read all the
updates of
all the new versions
which is
quite a task
you also need to follow popularity of
authors and how it all works
and if the person has compromised his
and his reputation
will should
check whether he is still in the
community
or probably a similar package right from
aside
you need to follow it
and this is an aspect that is not
related to a codeless it's
snl
you need to analyze authors you need to
analyze package popularity and sca's
today they analyze package popularity to
uh to underscore the vulnerabilities
that might be
of interest to you
in conclusion i'd like to say that sca
is a foundation
and a way
and and the preventive means
and it's not final
by all means we know that
after sca not all vulnerabilities are
found and you really want to get
integrated with
the neighboring systems
and it's a task for sca and sas alike
but anyhow sca is a way to control the
situation
and you get automation
that is rather straightforward and you
understand what to do next
yesterday we
had a great presentation on security
champions and i remember a question from
the audience where to start
it really depends on
the security champion person you picked
but sca is an interesting and
straightforward thing you just
use it
and this is a very interesting way to
start with
if you're a newcomer to a security this
is where you start this is how you start
to understand that okay this is
a software and you get the links to
exploits and then you get smarter and
you go deeper and work with those deeper
areas
it all may be uh fun and you probably
expected me as a representative of sca
provided to say something like that sea
needs to evolutionize
we still have issues and we know of the
issues
like ranking
like false positives
like dictionaries dependency
dictionaries component identification
looking vulnerabilities
rca has to be
more proactive and more integrated with
sas and identify
vulnerabilities
in new packages
before it arrives to assass
because before you arrive to sustain
already start to make use of this
package right
and you also need to bear in mind that
some of the vulnerabilities are only
there in your hand
we still want open source and we still
want to stay secure so let's do that
bearing all these aspects in mind thank
you
thank you very much
i
believe that the earlier you find
an issue
a security issue in particular the
cheaper it is to remediate it
say in
modern versions of
programming language compilators
their warnings and errors
they get
more and more to the beginning and
people understand that you need to
remediate it even in the stage of
studying or learning
programming languages but it's not there
in programming
managers there are some plugins in uh
i made it but they are external they're
not embedded i don't
have any i can't think of any that comes
out of the box
why is that
is it done on purpose
or probably uh we are going to
have package managers that would by
default one being installed carry out
this basic well at least basic
comparison against cvs
you know just to notify to get no
warning you you you you write the input
why why not notify him there and now but
it's not there now
well i think people are afraid they're
afraid to
expand too much of resource and to
send um
domino effect across the community these
data are not clean
[Music]
and npm let's take npm for example
you really have to have resource to do
something about it
if you
moderate all of open source i think it
would take
you know it would take more
effort than
uh app store and you can introduce
simple scanners
say should we have a package index we
would do it
so my my answer is because people don't
want to expand too much resources
and
despite the increase in popularity you
really have to live with what's there
thank you
thank you for this presentation
my question is
about check marks check marks is new
type of solution which analyzes
if commits are there in github and then
you look at the npm package and if there
is a supply chain attack and new version
of npm package is there without the
correspondent source codes these
packages are taken away do you plan
anything like that yes by all means
and this is how it's done
currently we're
working on it
it may seem to you
that i'm right straight
right from gartner
in our laboratory we have a lot of
things going on
and we are planning to
launch it into the market
when we are going to apply more of
a cloud approach than
premise approach on-premise approach
another
question also related to tech check what
works
they have an interesting feature
identifies in the library is a quote
that is not being used and if the
vulnerability is in the unused code then
it's alerted but not remediated are you
planning an integration
yeah or
two three years ago were telling you how
it's been done in our presentations but
you know what
log4j is used but there
is this open source code that you are
not used but vulnerability is still
there and i think it's a big issue
entering you know into the zest field i
cannot
guarantee that i create
guarantee uh that i do not create false
positives
what if yes the code is not used but
it's vulnerability still relevant
because of architecture you know
i i don't see the point
and i don't know
how check marks
and sometimes they would say that this
is used and this creates false positive
yeah thank
you and one more question
yes please
thank you for this presentation very
very interesting
to add on
to what
the gentleman said that it's very
resource intensive
to cover with sust anaconda
has its own
package manager
and tries to
moderate packages
but
they have less packages compared to
pipey
indeed uh
anaconda great are great there's a
commercial company behind them and it's
a specialized
area it's for science rather than for
everyone i think
this is what
[Music]
anaconda does
and
people who work there they don't think
of security
right okay but the problem is there
and those who work with anaconda they
are very happy about it
and just
i i also want to
tell you i scan pipi and i
um identify
malware and i report
this malware and the backdoors and the
report on it and i get feedback but my
question is this
if i have a
one day account
that was created for the sole purpose of
using
like skill like squatting right yes
and in the very beginning at the very
end you mentioned karma
and compromising the developers
who do bad things
are there any systems and communities
where you can address and
uh tell that look this package over
there
this developer did did wrong so you know
to create a database there is no public
database of
quote unquote bad developers
you can just report it and that's it
unfortunately at this point
no international communities like that
at this point we're open for dialects
all because we're very much
we think that it's an important thing
oh i'm sorry out of time sorry sorry
about that
thank you thank you for your attention
thank you for your questions