somebody understood what i'm speaking
about somebody don't but we are going to
speak about community habra community
the biggest in europe resource for i.t
specialists we're going to speak with
boom broom
alexis of the head of the department uh
which works with abraham
hello alexi hello vladimir
how comfortable do you feel how you're
being addressed in real life
very close people they call me by name
but in the internet in the course of
last 24 years
i'm used to my nickname and everybody
knows me by my nickname
and during this period of time nobody
was able to
have negative rhyme to my nickname i've
invented 98 we've been playing counter
strike in the club
and i've invented this nickname and i
still have this nickname i like it
and it's always free at all services yes
it is sounds very simple
but you cannot immediately spell it
well
how the hub community looks like today
and which changes do you have in recent
days
well i should begin by saying that
hubber is a ugc platform a platform
where the whole content has been user
generated so we divided editorial user
corporate however even in the companies
in any of the companies
they create this content and share this
content therefore
[Music]
once again we have a hack attack
once in a while our broadcast will have
such breaks which is wonderful it's a
certain action yes it is an action
so community hubble community is a very
tough combination of users uh corporate
representatives etc
uh register we have more than one
million users registered in the
beginning you've said that largest
community yes it is very large
and uh how many active users out of this
million regularly present on the
platform well regular ones i cannot say
exactly but
i have a number with my hands the
writing authors in the course of the
month about 900 people every month
authors who write at least one
publication in course of the month more
commenters more readers
but a complete number i don't remember
but according to social networks like
contact uh twitter hubber is the
small uh
drop in the sea but uh speaking about
very topical community hubber is a big
one
well
close communication of users and
companies
16 years
it's developing
which changes happened what communities
what changes in it
well in the context of the events which
happened in the beginning of this
there are year
events which were not specific to
previous periods years months
the first one is that we
have
type of users as read-only users with
less rights on the side
and you can anybody can get registered
anybody can get registered like this
in february march and april
there was the significant growth of
these users the growth of registrations
of these users so some time ago users
said okay guys can you give us an
opportunity to get registered to make
the line and give us an opportunity to
write personal messages we said okay
sometimes you want to ask something
communication is a good story
but then they say okay guys can you give
us possibility to write comments okay
you give them a finger and they will
bite your hand up to the elbow
they ask for the right and right now
it's up to the reverse story they say
okay let's close this door because
we observe the growth of registrations
of users who bring very bad usefulness
what do you think about doubtful
usefulness they don't write articles but
they think themselves to be experts in
issues of import substitution
immigration
production of different elders and other
things
and they send their
comments well not like experts as if
experts but they initiate different
discussions which very often are not
welcome to like political discussions
and
rough comments uh obscene comments
we are happy to all the users but these
users they bring certain problems to us
and the growth of their registrations
was noticeable
so we had to invent some moderation
tools so that we could
cooperate with these users
but hubber is a ugc platform uh users
create content
etc
so maybe this is not a really dynamic
story it's not that you can take
immediately and remove
some bad user from the site but
nevertheless
users
are detecting those who
to neutralize this person and this
organism is getting cleaned from all the
communications on several topics uh
trigger topics and they are kind of
showing the image that you like the fire
and all the zombies are running to you
this is interesting yes this is a very
interesting practice
many people are not happy they say well
we have some but people getting
registered but we understand that we
will see the number of registrations
growing
and those who don't behave well the
audience is not going to be happy with
them as well so this is the first change
which happened since the beginning of
the year it was
noticed the second thing we have changed
the character of voting so we have
read-only users without the right of
voting by default and we have
users
who have the right of voting so if
previously
seventy percent of votes of these users
were positive
right now the number of votes uh for
other voters is a negative one
there were positive voices and now
they're negative voices why is it like
that why is it like that these are the
voices for karma there are voices for
publications then in publications as it
was that's how it is users are
evaluating good material and negative
material they are kind of adding some
minuses
and the karma voices karma votes is an
explanation
that's how the political arrival looks
in the community when some event happens
and in a given case
this story
users start discussing it and in the
framework of thematical community not
everybody likes it and people
are opening some of their tools which
allow them to
more intensively return this story back
for example if you will analyze it these
minuses in more details
there are some users which just have
registered so this is a big organism but
it's a self-purging organs in places
where it's not possible we're trying to
help them go
self-purge well these are two main
changes and modifications some were
under the question mark
okay it would also be interesting to
understand uh what
mood you see on the side of the users do
you see any changes in the mood
which is more skeptical or maybe more
acute or maybe
other moods you observe or we speak
about big number of people about great
community
which has some internal composition and
state
it's going to be difficult to give you a
brief answer but different states you
can feel them
the first thing that would like to say
is that
it's doubtful that there are people
amongst us who are ready
for
such
psychological moral physical and other
and it was noticeable even by the
activities on the side
suddenly for a certain period of time
nobody was understanding what is to be
done
and the activity has dropped
significantly well weekly
we have calls amongst our companies we
discuss different matrixes
relatively speaking
all site content can be divided into
three categories uh cooperative ugc user
and editorial content with normal uh
temperature with normal market situation
the proportion is about 40 40 20 20
percent editorial and uh then uh users
and companies uh hand in hand
but after all this story has happened
corporate bloggers have stopped
significantly there was 40 percent now
it's 20 percent
users also didn't understand what is to
be done in our editorial office uh had
to continue shedding light on all this
story and the number of the amounts of
content in percentage well has increased
significantly increased
and in the course of one month these
mental forces was happening and in the
end of march they already have
stabilized this
so everything came back to the initial
condition
initially speaking about the mood users
indeed have
some feelings that well we have to run
somewhere we have to hide i need a
notebook for this work and i can do it
from anywhere else and then we could see
higher number of publications about the
topic of iit immigration
some people describe their experience
and they share it and harbor evaluates
it so there's a new topic
it always was available there
the immigration topic i t immigration
was always on this side it's a separate
topic at our site it's a separate hub
but it became the most popular here
on the second or on the third place
after the informational security
etcetera previously it was a flagship
topic
and people are sharing their experience
some people say well i was able to do
that i wasn't able to do that but these
some other people say okay
this was all discussed very actively and
people who was thinking about writing or
not writing they have understood that
they have to write they've shared it and
then we took all these publications and
we transferred them to our social
networks and some readers in social
network they thought that we are
lobbying
escaping
well this is not the tutorial content
this is user generated content
ugc
as it looks like they share their own
experience not like you've read the book
and then you
got information no they share their own
experiences
and this topic becomes more and more
popular but can you give us top five
topics which are very
interesting at harbor
well in the first place i think it
wasn't it still is informational
security it's a hub uh with the biggest
number of subscribers not the biggest
one but it's very active it's the
biggest by activity-wise the second one
i think
i would like to divine it but it's a
scientific popular topic and we're a
section
scientific popular
materials people are discussing
everything from
newspapers to telescopes and this spring
was really
well known by the topics
so i think due to this news it was much
simpler for the audience because they've
been discussing somebody made a picture
of the orbital space station from his
window somebody did something else
another topic which is really popular uh
recently it's import substitution this
baikal albrus
operating systems some software
they've been actively discussing about
okay guys okay
let's accept uh the situation as it is
given
and then think about the future let's
search for new tools let's invent some
new tools let's get united uh not all of
this was public among users and in the
comments
only maybe some first steps but if
you're interested please write any
personal mail but very actively it is
being discussed uh in this telegram
channel
so
no yeah button vision and i see how
people are walking around
which is an advantage because you can
see how people communicate
because we don't want to have all
communications on hub we want to connect
people
so that we would have same thinkers from
all corners of the world
so one of our main objectives
we wanted to maximize in these difficult
conditions
to maximize people without dividing them
into the camps because any war comes to
an end
and people will have to live on
and those who have been working on the
side of developers they will continue
working developers and they will have to
communicate with those people they've
been communicating with previously
therefore
all these political discussions
they divide users and we're trying to
stop it
uh our position has been announced about
the story in the very beginning but
nevertheless
users
if they
have some polarity of opinions and
somebody get a label to another one it's
going to be very difficult to rule out
from our side so our main objective
is like leopold hey
friends let's be friends
you're from this country he's from that
country let's be friends okay speaking
about the content consumption format how
do you think is it changing and
whether it's changing
not as it's supposed to yes would you
like the best one
well here's another question if you will
not immediately ask for it if you enter
web archive and if you open harbor 2007
you will see that most of the
applications were small articles and
rubble have purchased this that that
that it was like a tweet format
but in the course of decade uh hubber
have evolved in the direction of long
rates
practically every publication
is a very long like tens of thousands of
symbols and the audience uh looking at
the readership they read it pretty well
uh a simple example i've been
communicating with an employee
of bigger boy and asking how many
publications do you have how many
comments said thousands so i said okay
alexander
1 000 publications a day how can you
moderate it
well but understand sometimes
publications one picture we don't have
anything like that
[Music]
we have long grids
and the audience is used to them but we
understand that audience is changing
those who have had 10 years ago
for them it becomes much more
interesting to read some other materials
if previously they've been reading about
development right now they maybe want to
read about something
but also we see a new generation for
whom it is more specific to have a clip
thinking
so we are thinking about our own show
format
not twitter no stories not facebook but
something brief
acceptable
fast food
and the news as a separate format came
to us several years ago
and we had to introduce it by small
doses we have understood that people
read news uh from other platforms so we
liberate and always stay that pharma
didn't take this piece of traffic
previously and we're cutting away these
people
if we don't take this from it so we
created separate entities separate
section we've been we've been writing
not long read but short news
this has happened and the news has been
added and they've been discussing those
news and they have understood that this
is how they demanded they read it
and right now the editorial content
sometimes traffic wise
is higher than user or corporate content
irrespectively to the fact that
quantitatively it's less
so in the beginning it was written by
the editorial office but then we gave
the possibility to companies to write
news and then we've opened it for
everybody
right now news is a separate entity
users like this brief format and there's
a big line with long reads
and sometimes it happens that we have
new interactive things in different
formats like public polls research
we collect information with google forms
etc
thank you very much alexi truthfully
sharing information
in the community
it's very important to share information
because it's a very close community
and such sources as hubber harbor
they do help these
because when it is interesting for the
users to generate content
to share their experience and they are
challenging each other they give
challenges to each other and ratings to
each other it's a great experience for
us for russia in creating such platforms
i wish you
future development
and sustainability in current conditions
and search for new formats and new
authors yes we're trying doing our best
we have a lot of work but it's an
interesting work
11 yes i work in harbor sometimes people
ask me
don't i feel bored every day you come to
work and you don't degrade but you read
something new you learn something new
something
that
will be discussed in another place like
in one week from now or in one month
from now it motivates you
and you don't want to leave it you don't
want to live anywhere you want to boil
in this sport
and hang out with these people thank you
thank you very much