he is the head and developer of the
business
center develops business center of
fighting against cyber attacks response
center against cyber attacks i don't
really understand what you do
i always thought that you the head of
the jsoc
the drukov is the head of the jsoc so
you're the second guy
well let's see situation is much more
complicated
previously in solar has been working as
analytic and pre-sale
then i've collected the department and
at a certain moment of time
volva has offered me a topic related
with the business development and
this area is being headed by me but of
course pre-sale
i couldn't live
here especially in such difficult days
like today
well right now we're going to speak
about those days
and if you are in a borderline between
technical
diving and these business vessels
then let's speak about what has changed
in informational security in the market
what has changed in recent six months
and how do you feel yourself what do you
feel in the market
okay
let's begin by saying that from the
point of view of informational security
there are changes which are noticeable
by everybody the growth of the number of
dose attacks
violations of different sites uh other
things
there are less noticeable things which
to my point of view will show themselves
more and more
and this is activity of advanced
criminals whose main objective is not to
break something very quickly and to
announce about their position but to
penetrate into the infrastructure of the
company
stay there for a certain period of time
and after this
do
big damage
today we don't see that for a certain
company from the real sector of economy
in the industry or the energy they are
non-acceptable risks but i wouldn't
avoid and i wouldn't disclose this
vector of attacks so you're saying that
serious guys will be targeting to stop
or to seriously influence organizations
of industry
fuel
energy etc etc yes
i think that after a certain period of
time all these mass ddos attacks will
come to nothing they will get tired of
it
and things which are happening
constantly within a long period of time
it's not
interesting to people
that's why yes i think this mass trend
of ddos will
uh disappear
it will still stand high position coming
to the previous year but targeted
attacks with a serious stoppage of
business processes and god forbid
technological processes this is
something that we can expect in the
nearest future near future when when
when we should
faint
well according to our experience and
according to the experience of your
company as well
is not developing within a week it takes
months
so i think right now we can speak about
months so the first signs might appear
in the beginning of the summer
maybe in the middle of the summer
something will
show up a little bit later
so i think that in the summer we have
the independence day so we will have
some gifts during that well speaking
about connection to certain dates on one
side it would be very logical
many people were expecting
this
mass things by 9th of may but
a lot of public things that we know
roots you have suffered also i have seen
and by the way
yes it was a story within cyrus it's
something else i wanted to remember the
case with lenta.u which on 9th of may
had other headers but it was not
insiders well according to the official
position these were actions of insiders
uh so this is something else
i wouldn't get connected to certain
dates but i think that us soon
as uh
criminals will find something they will
realize that they will do it and
for example today
database of leakages were updated for
yandex food yes we've been speaking
about yandex food today
and i want to google and see what's
happening with this database what's
happening what's happening about me
there's information there's a passport
data
registrations and everything else did
you look at it have you seen all the
names not of course of course not
today i'm here with you the whole day
that's why it's doubtful that criminals
will dedicate it to phds
i think these are just uh adjacent dates
yeah by accident
we've been speaking a lot about import
substitution
by the end of the day i'm losing my
words and we've been speaking about uh
the part of vendors who previously have
been closing big pieces of informational
security and they stopped doing that
well i would like to ask you how you as
a supply of services how do you live in
the conditions of import substitution
when you form
the same jsoc you have the full set of
different tools so what do you do with
them well according to our mass services
like mss and jsoc we did have components
related to foreign vendors in different
industries for example we had suppliers
of feeds uh compromising indicators from
the western companies which
as it is well known as the first
community they just stopped updating
they stopped sending us updates we
in the condition of mss we had computy
anti-spam solutions from western vendors
and it's understandable as soon as the
special operation has started we have
understood that earlier later this might
happen that's why we did have a certain
plan because always
the choice was
done from the position that there should
be a domestic solution and there should
be a good and mature solution so in some
directions we have only domestic
solutions because they are really mature
and like application firewalls
in
the brand models uh input substitution
should happen but of course it was
understandable we did have some clients
that worked on western solutions of
those brand models so we've been putting
them in a certain queue well of course
we've tried to minimize downtime when we
did it in the planned order but
everybody started running in this
direction because the time was going
away and we had a lot of clients
speaking about socks situation is very
simple and it's not only for us but for
the whole community of mssp providers
many
of them in the basis of their services
had
western cms but we had two vendors you
had double-headed double-headed dragon
two twin brothers sitting inside
yeah that's what was happening
and that's why all the clients
what is the main advantage of cm cms
have not been discontinued uh
simultaneously that's why it's
understandable some have been
discontinuing the activities it's not
like we are getting leaving russia and
we're disconnecting you know these were
official letters uh like we are stopping
our activity we cannot provide technical
support to you but no worried about the
product
therefore
continuation of contracts is the painful
stage so when we deny an old contract
well this question can be equalized uh
so that not everybody will migrate to
local solutions but after the migration
of the clients we had to legitimize our
activity
by using another cm some have been
transferred to cm
that was a domestic one
some clients came to us with a request
that there is another domestic cm which
they want to switch to
and therefore this technological
possibility was also developed with
another large supplier so you will have
it
basically yes
mssp providers should
be
the only partner there always should be
a choice because there are different
situations i understand you
can you tell me please about business
about business part
how do clients live in condition of
import substitution well except for the
fact whether they offer you another cm
well clients they all live differently
and honestly speaking i would like to
tell you that out of our clients working
with the sock
there were no serious
hacks of the infrastructure yes of
course we did have some phishing
necklace some people were attacked
through the web scanning some being
attached to ddos attacks they did those
their services but they had another
telecom operator and we could not
provide them protection from ddos
attacks
but speaking about big
hugs and leakages nothing like that
happened from the point of view of new
clients and their arrival to us right
now we
are observing the situation when people
at the last moment of time they are
searching for solutions some people are
waiting
in hope that
the explosion is not going to happen
over their head so
some already have suffered
some people are expecting some are
trying to find fast solutions and of
course service related solutions are
really fast the stage of connection like
five to ten days and right now we have
reduced these uh especially for warmth
and auntie d doors because people need
it they need it immediately they are
under attack so sometimes it takes 24
hours and maybe even less when people
really need it
there was there were a lot of attempts
to make provocations during may 9th
related with certain drinks
by attacking a system which wouldn't
allow yeah this case was mentioned today
so we had to protect it so that whole
country would have a good may ninth
holiday good job good job
listen okay let's speak about cases if
you started speaking about that can you
share with me
your opinion
top three
most impressing events
in recent six months
in the area of i.t security well that's
understandable that's understandable
my final vacation have impressed me
sincerely good positive yeah let's speak
about work
don't make me jealous
no i was able to rest before this
happened
well i believe that
there was an interesting attack against
ross monitor related with dfa's side
because
it was a proper
strategically proper vector
to make
bring people to panic the second
announcement of the anonymous company
from the point of view of the cyber
attack
what do you think was it a serious
announcement uh these apt serious apts
or
[Music]
why not
well these are people who are playing
i will take everything and let everybody
know about me
i think that it can be both ways but i
still think why not why not i think yes
and topic number three is
out of those events which have
astonished me it's readiness of the
domestic vendors to help everybody both
clients directly and
mssp partners
a bright example is when the company
while contracting the process and it
takes a certain period of time and
therefore we have to look at this in a
moment we need licenses we need
something else so we need some
consulting
uh purchase updates if something is not
working because the client is very
specific for some very specific website
and vendor
should reply to this very fast they
should go for the dialogue vendors who
represent developing cm systems
in the roles of catching up also
actively ready to go for the dialogue so
everybody understand the situation on
the active market instead of behaving as
kings okay please come to us we're going
to be happy about you
they do actively participate in the life
of communists and in the attempt of
protecting them and this is very good
this is a right and proper statement and
we behave in the same way
thank you very
much think that you is
you're one of the most positive speakers
from the point of view of today's
realities
because because today
we've heard a lot of horror stories but
from you i hear good stories the peace
the life optimism everything's moving to
the future okay my friends i had alexi
pavlov in my studio ross telecom solar
if it's interesting for you to
hear optimistic
approach to defense you should come to
this guy thank you very much julia