so my name is eros von Toder I'm working
in product management at BitDefender and
for the past two years we've been
building and launching the BitDefender
box project which is cybersecurity for
IOT for your smart homes basically and
this presentation is about the lessons
that I learned in this in these two
years okay so to start with the
beginning and with the actual sign
options of the presentation how do you
navigate the line between form and
functionality and how can you maximize
both without becoming an extremist in
either side and of course as the man is
asking is it too much to ask for both I
think not I think you can have both but
I think it's important that we are aware
of both and we try to intentionally aim
for both and I'm saying this because I
think that mainly in our industry we do
have this tendency of focusing on the
functionality and trying to build the
best product there is the most valuable
product very techie very savvy and
everything and we also pride ourselves
with the fact that we're not here to win
any beauty contests but in in the world
of reviews comments stars ratings
feedback posted everywhere by everyone
not only professional reviewers you
gotta ask yourself what's a bigger
disappointment is it ugly or stupid now
just to start the presentation on the
right note I'm gonna be talking about
products that are built for the consumer
area not Enterprise and why while both
do share some common ground they're
really not the same and they should not
be addressed the same and also I'm going
to be talking about product management
not project management so I'm not gonna
not gonna be saying okay here's how one
should build a very organised product
but rather about what kind of product
you should build so that it brings value
in the eyes of your users alright the
and I'm starting with the vision because
it is probably the most important thing
that the product manager should have you
actually should know where you want to
get because let's face it at some point
you know that you have to build
something it's either because you
actually fill it yourself you want to
build something or in most cases you got
to justify your existence in the company
so you're the boss says okay you got to
build something now you gotta dig deep
and understand what it is that you want
to build you have to set this like a
North Star and you know you want to get
there you have no idea how you want to
get there or you don't know exactly all
the details about what there is but you
have to build this vision this image of
what it is that you want to build and to
do this I would advise to look into
three areas the reality the surrounding
world your labs and your competition and
you look in the world and see what
threats are arising what's happening
lately what's very hip like DDoS attacks
or brute forcing or whatever what areas
are rapidly changing but also look at
the at what areas doesn't seem to don't
seem to change what hasn't been changing
in a long time and now it has just a
slightest hint of change and I think
that's one of the most interesting areas
to look at and then look in the labs see
what they brag with what they show you
what they come up with and then try to
understand how you can use this in the
real world because the labs do have a
tendency to to bring you quite a raw
technology so you have to pack a little
bit a little bit to make sense in the
real world and then look at the
competition
what are they failing with what are they
gaining market with what were the
winning I advise you to read if possible
the financial statements because that
will give you a pretty good idea how
they see the market and where they see
themselves in the next few years and
that will give you more of a strategic
look of things and now that you you know
what you want to build and what it is
that you want to protect against and how
your
do it and how will that position you
against the competition
you really should change focus
completely and look at this whole thing
from the user perspective it's very
early in the game and it's exactly the
point where you should think about the
user does this exist in the real world I
mean for sure it exists because you saw
it but do your users did it exist for it
does it exist for them do they perceive
this as a threat as a worry do they have
this problem does your technology solve
a problem for them can you at this early
stage match every major feature in your
vision to a perceived value or an
existing perceived problem in the
reality can you do this match because
not you've got to go back to thinking
about the vision and now that just a
second please now that you kind of know
what you want to build it's time to go
back into your organization and get
people on board and build this product
and just as you're preaching your vision
inside your teams you will soon realize
that the site they do group into two
sides you will have your techies here
with R&D and development and analysis
and quality assurance and architects and
everything here and then you will have
that say the marketing people marketing
sales the c-level the guys with the
money I don't know conversion analysts
UX designers everything here and really
there will be fine people in both sides
no question about it but they will also
be very very vocal and they will not be
shy of telling you exactly what your
production look like exactly what it
needs to do or how it needs to do it and
things like this and of course they will
also not be shy telling you that if you
don't do like they say your product will
be a major failure it has no value and
so on now this is a very good position
to be in because it means that both
sides are
we care about this and they're very
involved and they really want to build
something that they trust in so what you
can do now is listen to them and become
more of an idea filter rather than an
idea creator because I will explain what
I mean if you're an idea creator I'm
going to product manager and this is my
vision this is how I build my product
you only use your own mind and your own
experience and you build something and
you bring it to the world but if you're
an ideal filter you can actually harvest
everyone around you all the developers
all the analysts the R&D and everybody
that has something to say will be able
to come say what they have to say and
you will get to decide whether it makes
sense whether you want your product to
take it and in that way or not and the
only way you can do this is if you're
asking all the questions and I'm gonna
stress the subject because it's it's an
important strength that you have and for
me it was quite hard in the beginning
because asking questions made me feel
like I didn't get it like I was the
stupid one in the room and it was it was
a bit difficult to overpass that and
really ask all the questions and until I
really got it and as a friend one told
as a friend once told me I was about to
take a really bad decision because I
just asked why I got an answer and I was
like ok let's go I wasn't really happy
with you answer I didn't really
understand the answer but I was about to
get on with it so no you should actually
ask all the questions until you're
really happy with the answer and you
really understand why it takes 3 months
or not 2 days or even worse why it takes
two days and not three months and what
is the impact on your infrastructure how
the users are going to use it or how is
that going to position your guest that
gets the competition and everything just
ask all the questions all the time
because next to the vision everything
that happens in this product is really a
responsibility every decision taken it
will really come down to your
responsibility so we really have to
understand everything and harvest
everyone around you now that you build
your product and you launched it into
the market and you're quite happy and
proud of what you did
the perfect MVP it really proves your
technology and everything people will
start talking about it it will get
reviewed and everything and it's the
perfect moment to ask yourself what will
make your user speak is it gonna be
frustration or excitement and make no
mistake other than professional
reviewers that do this for a living or
your very close relatives nobody will
speak about it unless it's really
frustrated or really excited
nobody mildly content with your with
your product will bother the writer if
you think oh I'm mildly content with
this product so here three stars
this is why the majority of ratings that
you get on platforms like like Amazon on
any product is either one or five stars
because people will speak out of
frustration or excitement
so I was looking at the reviews we were
getting and we saw some reviews saying
oh your product is completely useless
it's really hard to install it affects
my internet speed the interaction with
the customer support was really bad
everything was bad and then we see a lot
of really good reviews saying oh it was
really really easy to install your
product and it really didn't affect my
internet speed and it's really great
value for money and people that the guys
at customer support they're really great
guys and had they helped me a lot and as
I was reading these reviews and looking
at them I got a I started asking myself
really what's missing here because
something was clearly missing and it was
protection nobody said anything about
protection they didn't say anything that
okay I got hacked or I got infected or
you let me access the phishing page or
you really protected me it was about to
get hacked or anything about protection
nothing so it was really time we talk to
our users about security and here you
will see two comments written on the
same product by two different people one
of them complains that we don't give
them the detail logs and they cannot
analyze everything that's going on and
they cannot understand what we're doing
so they cannot troubleshoot their own
problems whereas the other one is
complaining that he doesn't know what an
IP is so really our product makes
so basically bad both of them but at the
really opposite ends of the same
spectrum so what can you do how can you
answer to both because if you take
either one you can answer it's easy you
can solve any problem but what if you
have only one answer how do you modify
your product so that you make them both
happy and in the end should you actually
aim at the aim to make them both happy
because I'm really going back to the MVP
product the the mythical way to launch a
product in the in the market these days
but that's just a proof of concept it
proves that your technology works I
think we should really be talking about
the minimum lovable product and it's not
my term there are some people at the
company called leverage that coined this
term but I really think they're onto
something because they define the
minimum lovable product as the product
that brings you the maximum amount of
love from your earliest adopters or as
some guy at Y Combinator said some
Altman is far better to build something
that a small amount of people love
rather than something that everybody
likes because remember they will speak
out of frustration or excitement so this
time we started thinking about feature
versus feeling and at this point I
should really be talking to you about
the cake mix you see back in the 50s
there was a company that brought to the
market the cake mix and it was a really
cool deal it was everything you needed
to do you just added water bake it and
it was boom fresh cake on the table they
were doing user research back in the
days as well and everybody agreed that
it's it tastes great it smells great it
looks great it's a great cake it's
awesome the only problem was that sales
were really bad and nobody knew why
so they started thinking about it and at
some point they realized that well
people didn't feel like they were doing
anything so what they did was they
removed the dehydrated eggs
from from the mix and now you'll you had
to go to the market by X come home put
the eggs in the mix put water mix
everything bake it boop the same cake
same to his team look but now everybody
loved it because they started feeling
that they were doing something they
started feeling that okay here's I put a
cake on the table for you so they relate
it to that product now the thing is how
can you make your users feel the good
things about your product
what are your fresh eggs in this in this
situation I think at this point really
you should be able to look at the code
and of course you're in this in this
industry so you can look at a code and
go like okay this is a beautiful piece
of code but you have to understand that
a beautiful piece of code means
absolutely nothing in the world it's
completely it has no value you have to
understand that the most important
features of your product the ones that
really keep your user safe are
completely invisible to the user and
what they see is completely something
else so put it simply nobody wants an
intrusion the text detection system or
an algorithm that detects anomalies in
their users behavior and things like
this what they want is really to to feel
that their kids are safe and they're
online that their payments are secure
and their photos remain private
hopefully but at least you can try so
that their photos remain private and
shared with with only with who they
choose to share them with so at this
point we started thinking what is
security for our users what does it mean
is it blocking malicious urls preventing
them from accessing phishing is it
blocking attacks closing ports or
whatever and it hardly is that for our
users is usually in in our product is
this idea that their home is not an
invisible mumbo-jumbo of devices that
they don't even know how many or what
device is in an invisible Wi-Fi and
everything floats around it's actually
everything organized in a little neat
list they can interact with they see
exactly who's connected to their home
they push a button they see if they have
any vulnerability they push a button
they cut the internet connection and so
on they actually feel that they are
interacting with with with the product
so we realize that really that is the
point nobody really wants to rationally
reach the conclusion that they are
protected nobody really wants to analyse
logs nobody really wants to especially
they don't want to trust the company
that they protect them do what they need
is they need to feel protected so let me
emphasize that they need to feel
protected not know that they are
protected all right now that you build
your product and you've taken into
consideration all the ins and outs and
the outside and the inside of your
product and everything and you build
your product and it's technically viable
and emotionally appealing and everything
is great let me ask you again what's
next what now now a few years ago in a
cornfield Kevin Costner in a movie heard
a voice saying build it and they will
come and what this was about it was
actually about build your product build
your vision do a great job while doing
it and people will find out about it and
they will show up and they would use it
and everything will be great now my
grandfather had the same idea by the way
he always dreamt about owning his
groceries to his own grocery shop and he
will sell the freshest food the best
food there is people will find out about
it and it'll be a great success they
were lining up in front of his store and
whoa sadly this was somewhat true back
in the days when my grandfather's brain
was not attacked every second by mental
stimuli fighting for for his focus in
the meantime science has actually proved
that a goldfish can actually focus a
second longer than our highly evolved
but very stressed brain what this means
for your users is that they will folk
whose focused incredibly fast this means
that the
chances that they will take time and
discover your wonderful features are
quite slim if really non-existent so
what can you do in this situation well
you have to hold their hands the minute
they install the product the second they
install the product hold their hands
teach the metric showed them how to do
something and they will actually start
having a relation with your product they
would have done something and they feel
that the product is doing something for
them I'm going to share with you another
story of a friend of mine who joined the
gym recently and she paid for a personal
trainer and one-on-one sessions and
everything and they got really sciency
on her they measured her measured body
fat percentage most of mass everything
so she started showing up did everything
right for the for the first few weeks
and then she got measured again and what
do you know body fat percentage hasn't
moved muscle mass has actually gone down
so it was really kind of a failure but
while this is normal and skin sometimes
happen in the beginning where did the
instructor go wrong you see she didn't
focus on proving to her client
immediately that they spent money on
something valuable
she didn't focus on helping the client
reach this conclusion that okay I bought
something valuable and it does something
for me in return she just expected for
her client to get on with the program
and to to wait for the results to show
up in the in the normal way yeah we're
all go fish so that's the point for us
once you install the product it
immediately scans your network it tells
you okay you have this many devices in
your home some of them that you don't
even know about it with scanner for
vulnerabilities and me tell you look all
of these 12 devices that you have three
of them are vulnerable so you should
really change your default passwords on
this one and about that Chinese IP
camera maybe you should really throw it
away because it has a backdoor in it and
it's really bad news so we're teaching
them to do something this is our tower
trick with them in in your product I
don't know but remember that we're all
goldfish
I am a goldfish so teach me a trick in
the first eight seconds four preferably
and I would absolutely like your product
all right now just in case in the
meantime lunch took over and you're kind
of sitting there wondering who am i and
what I am doing here if you're not
because they have the really compressed
version of this code of this
presentation also known as five things
to take home with you first remember to
ask all the questions all the time until
you really understand everything that
goes on around you because especially in
our industry things tend to be very
complex very deep they go very deep and
you will not be able to control all the
details all the time so it's important
to understand everything that that goes
on around you second when it comes to
R&D and UX very loud voices hear them
both don't favor any and like in
politics keeping keeping them equally
unhappy is actually a good compromise
keeping them equally happy I don't know
I haven't seen that but you're welcome
to try when it comes to your users do
the exact opposite choose a niche choose
a group and make them love you and don't
try to make everybody like you and you
will be great on the long run remember
that your products biggest strengths are
usually invisible for the user so don't
expect your users to value a product for
this try to always match with something
up front that is visible and they
understand and we're all goldfish
remember that remember that in the first
few seconds few minutes you really have
to teach me a trick and make me feel
that I understand your product and that
your product does something for me and
the main idea of this presentation of
this gap between R&D and UX is to be
actually aware that there is a gap there
is a gap between what we're building our
products to do and what the users see
our product is doing
so I'm done thank you and if you have
any questions and we'll be taking six
questions in so it's also be fast
he's always fast
that's 95 so you're building this box
thing that protects homes would you say
that what would you say is the target
audience for your product somebody
smarter than me yeah I'm good
[Applause]
the target audience is audience or the
target audiences and actually follow-up
question why why did you select those
target audience what do we expect them
to perceive in your product what do you
expect them to see in your product well
it clearly is not for the very advanced
and I think we actually followed the
trend and we saw that the market is
going towards smart homes as my goal
that too because you have to look at
your competition so we see that the
market is going toward smart homes
the adoption rate of smart devices is
actually incredibly fast or high however
you ought to say so we actually targeted
normal people normal houses living
normal lives because the IOT devices are
spreading at an incredible incredible
rate so not only the tech here's the
savviest or the earlier adopters are
getting them anymore it's something on
the mass-market and this is what makes
it more more dangerous thank you
in first row to the right you notice one
I had this thought of testing the Cree
second one I tested them for you it's
okay should I try them all one by one
for each question one rate the smart
phone the Smart Hub adoption is much
more wider y'avait yeah however there's
a portion of people that are still
paranoid about all this and are you do
you have any tactic to convince these
people that these devices are safe or
something so you're talking about the
the people that are really paranoid and
they will not adopt them it really get
into well the quick answer is no I will
not will not because then I will give
you the let's say the business answer
there's this the distribution of your
user it's like a bell of course like
everything in life and here you have a
small person which are the early
adopters a small number of people which
will jump into the into the new
technology and then after a while you
get all these people and they're like
let's say the normal people okay they
will adopt this technology in due time
some earlier some later and and then
you're talking about this end of the
spectrum and they will almost never
adopt this so from a business point of
view it makes no sense to target them
because it will be really really
difficult to get it or if you ever get
it okay plus we're not trying to
convince people to adopt this we're just
trying to protect people who have
already adopted this thank you thank you
people in the first row are amazingly
active I just love you guys so we're
gonna say in the first row here raise
your hands was there anyone in the back
there
was a very nice presentation my question
is regarding the cultural knowledge so
the concepts which are hyped by the
media and by the marketing departments
and how do you take into consideration
if the new products what the marketing
messages are on a specific market or not
or a specific user base well I think
that the problem is or the answer is the
other way around because you're not
really taking into consideration the
messages you build your messages to hit
something that exists in the market so
you try to to find what are the triggers
that exist in the market and what kind
of messaging can you do to hit those
triggers
[Laughter]
[Music]
so is your box secure RF communication
attacks like over the ZigBee or other
Wi-Fi or something so this is something
that we it was one of the arguments with
the tech side so probably in the future
it will be right now no it doesn't cover
any alternative protocols like cig be
z-wave or Bluetooth or whatever thank
you he wanted it I said no and the
reason why I said no was that those are
really proximity attacks so we went for
the wider range of attacks the one that
can be like mass attacks for a ZigBee
attacker more or less targeted for
example anyone else
there okay so you're saying you should
focus no sir please don't mic okay so
you're saying you should focus on a few
number of users loving your product as
opposed to lots of people being merely
content with it yeah I do do people
actually love security products that
doesn't really translate the physical
world like think of pipe locks yeah
that's that's actually a really good
question and I think the answer to that
question can be an entire book because I
think cyber security is one of the most
difficult areas in which you can
actually produce something like love or
excitement but it's it's more like
insurance people don't really are don't
really excited about your product they
just want it to be there to protect you
if something goes wrong so this is why
I'm saying that there is a gap and that
we should really be aware of the UX part
and try to come up with things that will
make people interact with your product
and understand it because let's face it
the fact that you're creating a guest
network it's only marginal for
protection but it gives the user the
chance to interact with your product the
fact that you give them a chance to scan
their product for their devices for
vulnerabilities is again marginal
because you can do that automatically
and just tell them but you give them a
chance to interact so exactly having
this in mind that it's very difficult to
create some sort of interest in the
cybersecurity from your users you should
find ways to interact with them that
don't really have to do with them
understanding what intrusion detection
is
[Music]
to the right
hello well you said that basically the
the product scans everything that you
have in your house everything smart
let's say and by doing this you're going
to have a lot of enemies because there
can you repeat the first part of the
question so the product scans everything
smart let's say in your house your TV or
whatever and you're going to say okay
this XYZ brand has an issue has a
backdoor and we've seen things like this
or also for big brands for TVs just take
a random example how are we going to
cope from the let's say the business
side of things from from the business
side of things the enemies let's say
that you're going to get well I think
there are two different answers to this
what box does is it scans for non
venerability so if I find a CV in your
LG TV it's already there it's already
documented you can fight on matriarch
for example so just a second so you're
really not breaking anything it's it's
known information you're actually doing
your user a favor
look it's documented they're all
somebody like Jay has to do is just you
can look it up and then they can hack
you but the other part and I will let
Jay speak immediately the other part is
there such thing as ethical disclosure
or something you find something you let
them know and then you start to talk
about it unfortunately we have to close
you're less common and your comment will
be the last one really shortly it's very
brief
they don't care dude really really they
don't in in 90% of all of our findings
and because we also do vulnerability
research anion IITs 90 percent more than
ninety percent don't care thank you for
being here thank you guys thank you
[Applause]