so hello my name is Adrian this
presentation is entitled when we write
two more narrow one year's worth of
honeypot data and I walk you through
some of the things we see running our
own honeypot Network and I will try to
explain to you some of the exploits
techniques and attack that we see and
I'm some of the insights we gain into
what attackers are and do oh there it
goes so who are we
that's me and my colleague me hi we're
the two authors of this presentation
we're both senior security researchers
with xes application and threat
intelligence team will have exploits
malware honeypot tinkering and stuff
like that but we're good guys so we only
do the part where it comes to detection
simulation emulation and stuff like that
and we hope to finally become unemployed
because at some point security is solved
we'll manage somehow and if you like us
please feel free to follow us on Twitter
of course you must plug now you might be
wondering about the Royal we in this
presentation the reason for that is that
that's me hi right now he's somewhere
nice and warm and that means I'm the
only one who's going to be entertaining
you for 30 minutes and on to the good
stuff there goes so this is a view of
our honeypot Network like I said we have
a Jew graphically this should be a
network that's not a one-to-one mapping
that's just the fact that I have very
good four skills with clustering and
graphing and I would like you to first
think about these questions what do you
think attackers are like if you have an
image in your head please think about it
and I'll walk you through some of the
stuff that we generally see some
assumptions being made some people
imagine them as simple script kiddies so
you know this guy he just thinks he's a
hack store because he grabs a script off
the internet runs it against the website
and that's
I'm an almighty hacker the media you
know talk to us about these bad guys you
know criminals toiling behind the laptop
somewhere and then just going somewhere
to enjoy a vacation from their heart
stolen money and if you work in a
position of power you probably have an
idea that's more like this and just an
interesting assignment here if you think
machine learning is at that point where
it's finally solved security the machine
learning generated out text for that
image is screenshot of a cell phone so I
don't see a cell phone in there and we
should wait before figuring that out so
this is what I'd like you to tell you I
think attackers are I think they're
persistent I think they're not very
fashionable I think they are resourceful
I think they're opportunistic I think
they're a combination of all of the
above and I think they're driven by
something right they want to accomplish
something otherwise they wouldn't be
hacking systems and I also think they
have a preference for targets in the US
so I don't think it's some gradual
geopolitical stuff probably has to do
with the fact that a lot of great
services are hosted in the US and please
do not take this as an idea to secure
your network by moving out of the u.s.
that's not that's not gonna solve
anything
so I said attackers are persistent and
when you think about persistence what
can you think of in security better than
brute force what's more persistent than
trying millions upon millions of
username and password combinations right
we monitor a lot of different protocols
and services some examples telnet SSH of
course web-based protocols and
applications and the long list of that
and we see a good number of attacks
coming from these so this is a graph
showing you stats from January to
September of this year and the constant
salt might not appear that high and the
reason for that is we tend to bucket the
events we see so just one user name
password combination
not an event we bucket them by the hour
if 1 million come in one hour that's one
event so to get a better idea there are
700 hours of time in one month so every
700 hours of time you get 200,000 hours
worth of gridforce attacks that's the
scale of brute force as you should
imagine it we also see quite a large
number of IP addresses different IP
addresses being used some of them
recycled from time to time some of them
just continuously appear there as being
used proxies and other stuff of course
and there's a decrease that seems to
appear for some reason is praying I
don't know there might be vacations or
something
most of the brute force attacks we see
tend to target telnet and ssh and that's
most likely because they're connected to
a botnet which i shall not yet name you
probably have an idea which one it is we
also see a lot of attacks against
database servers so we monitor attacks
against my sequel and MS sequel and one
other candidate I'd like to point out as
being important is VNC the reason for
that is right here it's at position
number 9 in our top 10 but this is a per
year statistic and we've been monitoring
it for one month so one month the VNC
brute-force suddenly takes it in top 10
so these are the stats for October and
in October suddenly it rises to position
number 4 so if you feel safe because you
don't have telnet SSH and database
servers you might consider if you have a
VNC server somewhere listening on the
Internet
one other example of percent assistance
I'd like to talk about is connected to
something called Cisco smart installed
so this is a feature a boutique configs
feature for Cisco devices and at some
point is here a vulnerability came out
saying that you can achieve code
execution by downloading uploading
configuration files by unauthenticated
key FTP already sounds like a bad idea
we don't see an enormous amount of hits
like
do for other things but still impressive
considering that we're running simple
VMs Linux VMs and not Cisco devices
they're just v8 Linux machines with
Python scripts on them so another bad
idea to secure network and map doesn't
says there's something over there well
if they find out an open port and if
they can't can communicate with it in
the way that a vulnerable device would
someone will definitely try to attack it
and exploit it now you might be
wondering what is fashion brought into
the discussion and any point
what do you mean the attackers are not
very fashionable well in security we
tend to talk a lot about what the newest
and latest tool or exploit is what the
newest technique is and attackers don't
necessarily care about that an attacker
doesn't care he cares what words he
cares what's easy to use and what's
readily available and what can target a
large number of devices case in hand
this is a five-year-old CVE targeting da
hua DVR devices and we've been
monitoring it since August already seen
hits on it there's a constant number of
hits on it from different IP addresses
and an interesting point here is that
with implemented communication messages
for its protocol from all public PLC's
we could find as a result 97 percent of
the message are unknown so either there
is something shady going on out there or
there are too many TVs that don't have
any sort of public description
whatsoever work in progress this is
something that seemed interesting to
present also from the I would probably
expect this whole thing to have died out
eternal blue if you have any idea about
it you probably recognize it as the
exploit behind the wanna cry malware
infection from last year so wanna cry
leveraged eternal blue and given the
size of the wanna cry attack I would
have definitely expected this to die out
okay I would have expected the graph to
go in the other direction and not this
one truth of the fact is in October of
last year we had saw 100,000 attack
at one akhirat eternal blue-based
exploitation and a September of this
year we passed 3 million 30 times more
than last year and the only reason why
someone would continue doing that is
because they can actually profit so this
means there are a lot of devices out
there still vulnerable to the same
exploitation method that was used by one
a cry that's kind of sad news to tell
you the truth also in the oldies but
Goldie's front ntp and dns which a lot
of people probably don't consider to be
attacks anymore because like oh they're
all those protocols that used to get
abused a long time ago they stoled you
we have two months worth of monitoring
and 321 million attempts to exploit this
so these are used for reflected
distributed denial of service attacks
okay so you'd expect a large number of
attempts because you have to do a lot of
requests to be able to do a DDoS attack
still if you think that you want to
expose a dns server out on the internet
and make an open relay you will probably
want to allocate a lot of CPU and
bandwidth because people are just going
to require all that power now attackers
are resourceful like I said they will
use anything at their disposal any tool
any public QC that appears can be and
will probably be leveraged by someone
case in hand last year in November I was
looking at our honey pot data found some
interesting requests exploit attempts
mentioning something called X attacker
okay so I googled it found a project
uploaded on github just one month prior
to that and thought hey this might not
be something it's one tool has a lot of
old exploits inside it just something in
a corner of the internet well it just
went on from that point so right now
it's a nice project it's got a good
number of Forks nice word cloud they
added the word cloud so you know what it
does you know pentesting targets and
whatnot
it's got technical support so there
should be an issue tracker over
3:7 closed issues containing requests
for new exploits support for people not
being able to run the tool and all of
that updated readme file updated change
a lot of stuff that some some software
projects don't have it actually and
recent commits and this is just one tool
from github github is that place where
you have millions of projects you
probably don't expect people to actually
access some of the stuff there from time
to time the truth is it does happen we
do see in this tool exactly being used
because it's got a trademark string
inside it not millions of attempts but a
couple of hundred attempts and the truth
is the number of attempts itself doesn't
matter because what Integra needs is one
successful attempt just one is good
enough if he gets the right one I also
claim that attackers are opportunistic
given a window of opportunity they will
probably try to take it this example
comes with Drupal Gaiden two and three
two remote code execution
vulnerabilities and the Drupal framework
that came out this year
a couple of weeks after the public POC
appeared for the first one spike in
attacks then it tends to die out then
the public POC comes for the second one
another spike in the number of attacks
now rupaul itself is a framework that is
pretty secure and administrators
probably patched it
so this died out most likely because
there were no more targets of
opportunity but it just comes to show
you that if you have a small window
between the time when the public QC is
available and the time when patches are
finally made attackers will try to
exploit it and like I said you can find
things there are combinations of all of
them so we've been tracking multiple
vulnerabilities for d-link devices that
long tail that you can see on your left
side as a bunch of older vulnerabilities
that still get hits every day and from
time to time and then at some point you
see the spike the spike itself is a
remote code execution vulnerability a
new one that
here this year for some dealing devices
when that happens the next thing we can
see a whole lot of interesting traffic
all of it for that new key OC and this
one because dealing devices don't get
updated as often is Drupal website to do
this one just continues on and on and on
and on and again I will not name the
customer for this one and one more
example of attacks in the world and
techniques so like I said we monitor a
mile scale we have a fake server so it's
it gets attempted brute force a lot
sometimes we tell them okay you're
successful EURion what are you going to
do now so the first thing you generally
want to do is gain privileges grab as
many privileges as possible and someone
took that very literally I think they
just copy faces all possible permissions
in there I actually learned about a
couple of them that I didn't even know
existed replication slave and client
definitely seems yes you need that and
then you want to be able to execute code
on the server so to execute the code you
don't necessarily have the easiest tools
available but there is a technique and
it's connected to that select long hex
string statement that you see that one
continues with into dump file so my
scale being the database server allows
you to select data and save it to an
output file in this case the output file
is PowerShell not the exact type of data
you would expect to see decoding that
hex string its PowerShell code that
should get executed it would access a
website download date something and then
execute it but how do you go about
executing the PowerShell code itself you
still have to call PowerShell so MySQL
has a feature called creating
user-defined functions what it allows
you to do is compile a DLL file or an
ISO file under Linux where you define a
function that you will then call from
MySQL itself so all you have to do is
compile system of string inside a DLL
send it to the server using that magic
statement after you've gained access and
then you can just create a function
alias and then call it just like those
select says eval CDs slash temp W get
statements up above there so this is not
a new technique this has been around for
a good number of years now you can find
blog posts you can find references to it
you can find a lot of info on how to use
it but I thought it would be nice to
show you just one of the tools and
techniques out there there goes okay so
I said attackers are driven now I won't
talk you about psychological drive and
stuff like that because I'm not a
psychologist I'm an engineer so I can
talk to you about the tools they use the
malware they use and what they can use
and can use it for and first purpose of
course DDoS attacks and now you know the
major bots that I was talking about
because you didn't miss you probably
missed it in the title so that is Mariah
we rise this large botnet for Linux
based IOT devices that appear the last
year it managed to generate what some
people say are six hundred gigabyte per
second and over one terabit per second
attacks so very large scale attacks very
hard to stop something like that and
then the author said hey we don't want
to do this anymore we're just gonna give
up which they did after open sourcing
the code because that is always a good
idea open source something that powerful
to for everyone to use and use it people
did stop we saw clones coming out a lot
of different clones of Moriah or just
simply reusing the same code we saw an
increase in the number of events and I'm
not sure you can see those counts over
there so I'll just zoom in a bit 128
thousand events in October of last year
and we've gone with past 20 million last
month so Mirai was one botnet capable of
generating 600 gigabytes per second now
people are advertising Mirai based
botnets that they claim are capable of
400 500
and we actually have a lot of these
right now we have a lot of different
botnets which maybe individually they
have less power firepower than what I
had but if we put them all together I
don't even want to do anything
the to imagine the rabbit that they
should be able to do now you may have
been wondering how hard is it to grow a
Mariah Network well last month 14th
published a blog post about a ddos for
hire service that at some point said hey
let's use Mirai for our to power a
botnet these talked about it growing
from sometime in mid-september so we
looked at our honeypot data try to
identify the botnet found it and this is
the number of infection attempts we get
from it in two days they went from zero
to 30,000 different attempts per day
that's how easy it is to grow Mirai base
botnet there are so many vulnerable
devices it's actually very easy to grow
it and if you're thinking i OT is
insecure by definition because that's
the state of things desktops are safe
well we have a nice windows-based but we
see it mostly by mysql and eternal blue
it's called an atoll it's been around
for quite a while now pretty old just
stays on your machine does some
fingerprinting send some data then waits
for target and then starts bombarding it
with the do s request and if you're
thinking wait but Windows is insecure we
know Windows has its issues right now
right we have a lot of different Linux
based families going out there multiple
documented families I'll just walk you
through two of them one is called DDoS
Kiev first time I've seen it was in 2016
I guess the other one do flu DDoS trojan
and you might be wondering wait but
you're saying this is old malware how
can you be sure this well we do some
validation for example DDoS DF has a
giveaway string inside it the other one
you can simply decrypt a couple of cnc
websites so it's easy to see old malware
being reused by people all over
place and you can have a presentation
called me right in one area without some
reference from when I were right
so coin mining is something that once we
get image back ok coal mining is
something that you know it's a lot
harder to track attackers for so I think
it's a lot harder to prosecute a lot of
people have switched to that we see a
lot of it going around one arrow is the
go-to currency they reuse open mining
tools so they will download XM rig or
something and start mining on your box
one example from the eternal do honeypot
so it receives a command script that is
going to execute the first thing you can
do when you get on a machine is to kill
off the competition while you mining on
my machine this is my machine now kill
the competition fingerprint determine
what capabilities the box has and then
you will download the necessary binary
and execute it with nice enough
configuration so you send everything to
the right wallet of course and I want to
ask if you notice anything strange in
there so this is the download string
this is the part that does the actual
download and I'll zoom it up so you can
see it so circuital is a legitimate
windows binary it's normally used for
certificate management if you give it
the right parameters you can actually
turn it into W get or curl for Windows
so pen testers no longer need to send
VBS scripts PowerShell scripts and what
not to download your malware files from
now on you can just use cert util for
this purpose this is not a new technique
per se its recent but it's been
described before one example from one of
severe mertens ISE diaries just another
nice tool and technique that you can see
used in the wild and we've talked
malware no discussion of malware would
be complete with what without some sort
of espionage and backdoor tool so this
is an older Trojan again
known as easy ghosts main source we've
seen it coming through is the eternal
bill honeypot it's an allegedly Chinese
backdoor as origin some people say it
might or might not be connected to the
older ghost rat if you are familiar with
eternal blue the pale of that comes
after the exploit comes by I DLL file
but these dll files just contain a URL
in this case the URL will get fetched
and then the binary download from there
gets executed and as a Trojan itself
again validation by a payload
configuration description you can find a
lot of references to it online and we're
looking into one of these samples I know
that something's something strange how
would a URL inside so I fetched it and
it downloaded 8.5 megabytes of data now
malware tries to keep invisible you know
keep sizes low 819 5 megabytes is huge
that seems interesting I looked into it
static analysis said ok this is a
malware binary packed with the meda ok
good packing there so i sandboxed it and
what do you think I found what do you
think the most prevalent malware in 2018
would be no ideas no mining that's it
someone finally said it so once you get
on the man's machine you can spy on him
you can do whatever you want might as
well make a buck out of it ok so that's
about it from the data part I guess I
should probably be telling you this as a
forecast you know the Internet is still
and will be a dangerous place for the
foreseeable future but I thought hey
this is kinda you know depressing gets
pessimistic and most of my days in
InfoSec reading the news I feel kind of
like this so I wanted to say something
more uplifting and thinking of all the
things I said about attackers that
they're resourceful that they're persist
and I said okay most of that stuff
probably applies to the people in
InfoSec as well so I'll leave you with a
better ending quote I think we should
stop demeaning attackers and just
imagine the fact that they are a lot of
like us and I'm sure that if they can
break a lot of the things we've built
there then we should probably be able to
protect them as well so thank you and if
you have any questions for me thank you
very much now we will be taking
questions and then going to our favorite
time of the day lunch so raise the hands
we have goodies for you have a question
here
hello
get your microphone closer to your and
[Music]
yes
exactly so you've brute-force it then
you send the dll file that allows you to
actually call system code which man
skill doesn't have by default so you
just do a call to system or eval or
whatnot
compile it into the DLL send it over
there and then you can call the function
from the DLL so that it's going to call
that for you thank you we have a
question in the first row and then going
back here please make sure to speak
directly into the microphone so that we
can all hear you
did you have specific games with
so to catch the malware coming in we
have specific honey pots multiple types
of honey pots then we do some analysis
of the malware also ourselves sometimes
we sandbox them execute them in PMS and
see what they do most of the time we try
to do all of them if possible
if we will be able to identify Oh so
basically you're asking if some a piece
of malware just uses an exploit or can
you speak please closer to the mic or or
it's not working or no it's not work
okay
so the question is if I understand
correctly if I'm able to identify them
well we're just by the packets that get
sent and received well we do some of
that we do try to create our own
signatures for some of that work to
identify them it's not always entirely
possible because a lot of the malware
nowadays uses different types of
encryption for the payload or some sort
of custom binary protocols you look at
it and it's a blob of gibberish
sometimes you might identify some parts
for example with I can't remember
exactly what it was it was one of the
windows-based BOTS it would send in the
beginning an isolator a little header
and then a hex digest and then an
encryption key
but the encryption key was encrypted as
symmetrically so I have no chance of
breaking that I actually have a chance
of breaking that if he uses plain old
windows encryption services because we
can do memory dumps otherwise you have
to do you know live debugging and trying
to identify stuff like that but that
means that you don't have any chance of
automation in the future you would have
to have too much inspection into the
system to be able to do that okay be
sorry before I'd like to take a question
from this here somewhere yes and then
we'll go back to the front row
my main question is how do you call is
attack
how how do identify I'm sorry I can hear
you can you hear me now yes
how do we counter the attacks well it
depends on the type of attack for brute
force like I said we tried to compact
them because otherwise there are too
many otherwise if it's just one request
that he would have to do in the case of
the d-link RC I think you just send a
request to a CGI script with a parameter
we just count those each request is a
different attack they're against us so
we have we host our own seemingly
vulnerable services which then receive
these attacks thank you we have a
question here in the front actually two
questions one of them is so let's say
you have a simple VM which you forget
which you leave the SSH port open what
kind of let's say ultimately scans and
brute force you can expect from me let's
say let's say we have it's just a simple
VM on on AWS and then you forget one
port open okay like for an average let's
say user what kind of automatic scans
and remembered for some types you will
expect you'll see loads of brute force
attacks they generally use past password
lists from what I've seen so they do you
don't just go about completely brute
forcing and doing password generation
they use password list some of them go
as little as 100 passwords some of them
use maybe like 1,000 passwords we
actually had to count the number of
passwords because one of the protocols
used encryption and we couldn't decrypt
it so we just created some sort of
intermediary Jive digest things so we
had to generate our own password list
and see how they overlap so for example
mirror I only use this like a couple of
hundred passwords I think it was where
this will this other one used 2000
honeypot sandboxes that you're having
are you regularly changing them is there
like maybe a chance that this malware
will detect your sandbox
well sandbox detection yes it does
happen so we have taken some steps to
cloak them from malware being from
malware detection a lot of stuff
involving CPU customization creating
fake files the general stuff as for the
honey pots the best thing you generally
can do is just move them around because
at one point you can see the number of
attacks against and decrease that's more
difficult to do we do it but it's not
something that you can easily do with a
lot of providers because - they don't
have support for automation you have to
go and manually click Launch instance
launch instance launch instance we were
taking one last question there and then
we will be heading to lunch meet me
halfway
but my question the attackers the
attackers use Bitcoin and if so did you
try to drag down the transactions no I
never seen them use Bitcoin in my
experience I know if anyone else did all
I've seen is Manero the reason for that
is someone connected a lot of the
devices they hack into our intel or AMD
devices and Manero is hashing algorithm
is optimized for these so there's some
point in using that there was all those
ecash that i've seen at some point but
most of that stuff i've seen recently is
strictly Manero about the wallet
tracking you also asked you asked about
wallet tracking if we do any sort of
tracking yes we did look into some of
these wallets now with mono it depends
on their pools that you connect to some
of them for example allow you to see
someone else's balance we've seen some
guy make somewhere around eight or ten
thousand dollars in one month
pretty good payday others don't allow
you to track and we've also seen some
sort of proxy service where they do not
have to specify inside the protocol
inside the communication program called
the wallet because the wallet is then
hosted on a VM somewhere on a on a
server somewhere they just connect to
that send the data and that one as the
wallet and those guys we can track in
any way okay thank you thank you very
much once again thank you let's have a
final round of applause thank you