thank you very much encourages everyone
I'm going to talk a little about modern
transport problems quickly about myself
I work at Kaspersky Lab at security
assessment department we are responsible
for all pen testing and auditing
projects that are done by Kaspersky and
I'm a reverse engineer in this
department
my job is strongly strongly connected
with industrial control systems Internet
of Things and and some other things and
occasionally I have a chance to look
through different areas of modern
electronics in search of something new
and interesting and sometimes these
results and the things I am going to
discuss in the next 40 minutes well all
of you may heard that all good
combustion engines are not in the best
shape in the in people Minds this is
caused by such events as dieselgate you
may heard about it and some as a
negative information in the mass media
and the authority of the market is
offering now electric vehicles or EVs in
shortened form and that is making them
interesting for security researchers we
are not the exception
so things that can be researched include
as v's themselves as various
infrastructure devices and you know when
we started to look what can we research
I really had my eye on this BMW i8 but
you know it wasn't acceptable so we
started to looking for something small
and maybe cheaper and now I will present
you a personal charging station research
and when I'm saying personnel I mean
that this station is going to be
developed for installations at private
homes so there won't be any payment
system
so there are a lot of vendors in that
area now and every vendor has its own
piece of market there is no well
recognizable Eden we were looking for
something interesting so at least when
in the station with some kind of network
interface or something like that and we
found out that some vendors are trying
to attract more customers attention by
implementing remoting monitoring and
controlling feature that means that you
with that station you will be able to
start and stop charging cuca with the
mobile application with you smartphone
and that is why we started to look in
that direction and so finally here is
our hero charge point home station by
charge going to operated and you can see
from that the diagram that they have a
really good ambitious for growth and the
reason why we chose exactly as that
vendor so that is the marketing style so
we believed that guys who created this
picture are not able to make anything
boring by the way this is a picture of
different socket types so those sockets
that connects you vehicle and your
charging station there is some
functional scheme of charging station it
is always based on some kind of a smart
relay which is responsible for
accommodating as a charging current on
and off turning the charging carrot on
and off depending on external conditions
for that station several communication
channels channel exists the first I'm
going to talk about is we go
communication channel it can be
implemented in several ways starting
from a simple one pin interface which
represent in and ending with dedicated
canvas which can offer great abilities
to talk with these vehicles in the
vehicle internal systems
there is always some beckon connection
exists which usually takes place over
Wi-Fi or wired connection and several
protocols exist now for that purpose and
the most well-known is called OSI BPO
open ChargePoint protocol for stations
that I installed in public places
as a reservist and see present so for
this virus interface for payment system
of limitation but as I said before we
made we did our research on a personal
station so these interfaces out of our
scope now and of course several more
interfaces may exists depending on the
device design and in our case this is
Bluetooth interface and it is used at
the at certain moments for communication
with the smartphone first let's have a
look at those mobile ads awesome this
mobile application which is used for
controlling the charging process first I
need to mention that charging stage our
charging station can be in two different
states first state is inactivated state
and during that state only the ability
to interface is available and this
bridge was interface is used for Wi-Fi
connection settings and establishment
the connection to the back-end for
further controlling and after connecting
to the backend the device is entering
the activated state and at this state
the Bluetooth is disabled and the device
the device receiving call commands over
Wi-Fi the first state is more
interesting for us this time because it
invokes direct communications between
the app and the device so let's see what
we can find and learn about that
Bluetooth channel we are using Android
smartphone and enduring channel is
allowing us to to make a dump of all
traffic that is passed over
Bluetooth it can be done with our cedam
tool and collected collected logs
collected data can be analyzed
Wireshark because it supports our setup
format we activated our stations and
made a dump of all communications that
took place between the device in the
phone so we realized that there is a
simple refcon protocol implemented which
means that it's just a single UART line
that accommodates always a wire
Bluetooth and all commands have text
format here is the list of all commands
and the most interesting for us started
with number three so this two commands
number three and number four I used for
connection to the Wi-Fi network so with
these comments you are passing your
Wi-Fi network parameters the fifth
command is used for establishing those
connection to the backend server so
after processing that command your
device will be will be online and will
be able to receive all remote commands
from from the vendor side and last
command here is shutdown Bluetooth this
command as no surprise disables the
Bluetooth service and that's finishing
transaction to the activated state now
let's have a little closer look at the
device source code it is written in the
hour so we can be compile it and we
found those activity which is called set
to factory defaults activity and what is
interesting here and you can see those
lines like flash sequence and request
chimera pay permissions so this code is
probably appeals to the camera's flash
so that sounds interesting that we can
you can also see this the screen picture
which shows how to possess your device
in front of euros how to possess your
spec phone in front of the device so now
I'm going to show you a very small video
that will show how this function works
so here you can see the smartphone and
the device here are two two small
windows in that in those place we can
activate this activity by stating the
start button and so that is how they
implement this function you can see is
all blinking and you can see that the
device accepted our blinking by those
red light so by the way this is really
just a factory reset function so this is
the same function functions that is
usually implemented in your home road
why is this small it says button but the
way how it is implemented here shows
that developers use their fantasy not
only for drawing those funny pictures of
sockets now we're switching our focus
we're finishing with mobile app and
we're switching our focus to the charger
charging station itself first let's look
which services are available to us from
the Wi-Fi network and here is a small
table of these services not not so much
only three of them the first test telnet
and then the third port and also there
are two SSL services one of them is
probably HTTPS it's no surprise on for
free port and the second at this point
we don't know because it can be anything
none of so we try to use some default
credentials but none of them none of
them that we were able to think about
was accepted by the device and what
about SSL it is set up for mutual
authentication so we we need to
certificate the community to talk with
it at now we don't have one so let's
have a look inside the device and may be
able to find something interesting here
here is how the device looks like if you
and if you want to unscrew this front
panel
it consists of two boards two separate
boards one of them is power board and
there are a lot of elements s coils and
relays that I hear for commentating big
big charging currents and the second
part is called panda board and it is
called so by the developers they wrote
this small string on top in the top side
of the board now let's have a little bit
closer look at both boards on the power
board as I said before there are a lot
of components that are responsible for
big current commutations like those
those strips for connecting the charging
station to the we go and to the
electrical grid also also there is that
mechanical relay for accommodating bkc
currents
this board is controlled by separate MCU
which has here IDs
it has msp430 architecture this is a
proprietary conjecture by Texas
Instruments but anyway all specs on it
available online and finally there is a
small socket proprietary socket that
connects two boards together we didn't
spend much time on this board because
you know we were more interested in not
all communications and it is a
responsibility of the pandal board so I
will continue i'm going to continue to
the panda board here it is at the closer
look it is based on Atmel cpu with with
an ARM architecture mmm number one also
there is some additional chips for this
for this controller to work to work like
non chip and ran chip in the difference
is those extension board which is
developed by is M which implements all
wireless interfaces it can operate in
which Wi-Fi with Bluetooth and
with annecy so the vendor is probably
using the same hardware design for
different stations even for public
stations and finally there is a small
debug socket on a morpheme and we we
were able to fight the g'tok interface
on the socket and geoduck interface is
always a good start for hardware
research a couple of words about tools
that we were using first this little
pink board is called reticulate and it
is used for for determining G tack
pinout it works rather simple so you
just connecting it to the socket you you
suspect that have a DTAC and if you are
right it will show you the exactly pins
that I used by these protocols and
that's small red board is our program
meter we're using it in pair with open a
CD open OCD is well known and widely
used from framework that is responsible
for setting breakpoints edge attack
reading and writing memory all of that
debugging stuff so to understand how the
device parades we now need to get from
where from from the non memory and of
course there is an option to chip out an
end but it can be very harmful to the
device and we now don't want to break
anything because before all the fun
begins so to read it in some other way
is a great idea and it can be done with
JTAC non data lines are not connected to
the CPU core together so they cannot be
read simply by setting by setting
address and reading the data from that
address
there are some special scripts that's
included in the openness to distribute
effects that that are responsible for
reading an aunt named with different
controllers but unfortunately none of
them was acceptable to our controller
even even even some of them were
developed for admin everyone failed but
we did another way so here you can see
the sequence of orders that our charging
station passes through during the boot
process and we found a function that
read mint in the lowest level boot
loader which is called ROM and by means
of jtac we are able to to invoke it in
cycle so that we can read all non
content first to the buffer in the
memory and then in the operating memory
and then to read it to the host here is
the table that shows us the structure of
those non non content the most notable
here we can see two lineage this tooling
is distributed to Linux images so if one
of these image images will be corrupted
the device will be able to boot from
another one every image contains of the
bootloader kernel arguments section
kernel root of s and the parameter
section the parameter section is among
the most interesting here it is a
section with a proprietary format and it
contains you know it's no surprise
several device parameters like MAC
address and serial number and among
chasm as there are several certificates
so that's look interesting for us and
maybe we'll
[Music]
sometimes later and in addition to those
linux images there is a section that is
called ssh key recovery partition and i
will describe and discuss it a little
bit later too by the way there is one
other thing that can make our our life
easier and that can be done by means of
JTAC so this is the unlit access and
with it we will be able to debug
separate separate processes and not
whole system as it is done now by JTAC
as soon as now we have all non content
we also have this shadow file but the
shadow file contains strong crashes it
they use md5 result so we want is this a
security or a secure algorithm and we
wasn't we weren't able to brute it by we
weren't able to break it by Mindel but
forcing but from the other hand now we
can analyze those binaries that is
responsible for for validating user
login and password and after that we can
find it by means of jtech again in
memory and patch those instruction
originally this is conditional branch
and dissipated and if we change it to an
additional branch every pass what will
become correct so that's how we did it
now we have G tag access and now I'm
going to continue with the network
interface and I'm going to start with
those two SSL services ok
we realized that up SSL service which is
in those ports which started with five
five five five it is the net encrypted
online service but this is exactly the
same thing that as we already have
access to so this is not interesting for
us at this point
and the second board number for free is
as no surprise HTTP it is it is used for
invoked for for common gateway interface
so we can invoke some binaries with it
and SSL there for both these two
services is implemented via SSL with
mutual authentication so to be able as I
said before to be able to establish the
connection we need a certificate so
let's start our search from those
certificates we've we found in the
parameter sections there are two
certificates okay one of them is see a
dot certificate which was certificate
authority Authority and is used for
client certificate validation and second
is system dot certificate it is zero SSL
certificate so it is stored with a
private key but private key is encrypted
but all the data that is needed for that
decryption is available at the parameter
section so when are able to look to get
it in the clear form that is one of the
way how it can be done and the way how
we did it actually so there is no source
code in this tunnel which which derives
as a price phrase for the key decryption
from several exactly three three files
from parameter section one of them is
system Mikado's and two seconds like
special additional data we can so we
have JTAC so we can put the breakpoint
at the end at the end of source code
fragment and download the decryption key
after this code execute executed so when
I learned about react and I became
you know little lazy with this kind of
tasks because I don't want even to know
the algorithms that is used it is
something that is based on exclusive for
but so it is not really secure but not
really interesting so now we're having
as a certificate with its private key
and we know that it it was created
somewhere on the vendor side so why
shouldn't we try to use it to establish
a connection to the ssl service so we
try it and bingo it works so don't be
afraid of those red red screen of course
because there is no actual web content
on the device and now we are already
able to access a common gateway
interface now let's try to figure out
why this is possible so why was possible
to establish those connection was or
certificate in this connection with this
certificate here are two certificates at
the closer look
several field fields of those
certificates and what is notable here is
that system dot certificate is signed
with with that CA certificate you can
see that from these serial numbers that
written involved here and you know in
this signature is checked during
certificate validation but in in web
world you know not only the signature is
checked but of course the subject field
so those fields that is that is short
whose certificate it was issued for but
in the embedded world syncs working in a
very specific way sometimes so that is
that case and that is why why these
certificates
works now we can proceed to the HTTP
part and there are free elf files that
can be invoked with it
this is some some form of in the back
interface and running forward I can say
that the under removed those HTTP server
from the device at the latest
you know where first by there are three
binaries the first binary is called
upload the same and it is used for
uploading different configuration files
like payment system configuration the
second is download log assem it is used
for downloading different types of logs
from the device like server log or
system log and the last one is gets or
and it is used for issuing different
debug commands so we we didn't find any
you know charging control commands in
this binary but for example there is a
boot command available so it is still
can be interesting to play with it as
for input format of the input parameters
for upload the same just it is just the
filenames that is passed to the HTTP
server and for two other there is a
specific command format it is it looks
like a simple text line which contains
of consists of tokens that are separated
by the pipe symbol as the first token is
always same detect in those in this
example this is our BT and other tokens
represents represent different command
parameters like charger serial number
time step some commands specific
parameters and so on one of our purposes
was to find vulnerabilities so here our
findings in this CGI interface the there
is there are some loopholes in the input
verification in upload the same binary
then that leads to a betray file write
vulnerability you can see from that
little code snippet that they just pass
the sub was a substring from the input
to the open function without proper
verification of that dot dot slash well
known sick sample sequence so we can
overwrite not only files with settings
but any file in the system by the way
for example including shadow file binary
files library files so that can be
dangerous
also as input is not verified in this
upload the same binary there is also a
ways command injection vulnerability
exists but I need to know that all s
commands here will be executed to use
very low level privileges and the system
is designed in that way so that only
mostly objects require root access so we
won't be able to do anything with that
with the commands finally there are two
series of stack Buber of stack buffer
overflow vulnerabilities at the last two
binaries which is download log SM and
gets over they called this vulnerability
could lead to remote code execution and
it is called by it is caused by by using
of that type scanf function for parsing
as this specific um those specific
comments and you can see that it is just
reading tokens to the different buffers
and if the buffer is buffer is on the
stack and no when no lens verification
is performed they can be an overflow a
couple of notes about exploitation of
that stack buffer overflows here the
kernel this address space randomization
is used so that position is randomized
from the one hand but from the other
hand a stack is executable so we still
can be able to execute our payload code
from it
in this case we can call a vulnerable
binary that is part of CGI interface
multiple times and when binary fails due
to and it always of course will fail due
to payload with due to payload is wrong
state colleges it won't affect the other
parts of the system and even if sent the
payload that is complete for the exact
stack colleges they always be a
probability that the exploitation will
succeed spa probability by the way but
there is a big number law and which
states that with much rice the success
probability becomes much greater so here
are some dealer for our particular case
stake here can be placed in 512
different positions and bit number law
says that in we will need 315 tries to
guess position with 15% probability we
found that the observer appears
correctly when we issue Inc when we are
issuing two seconds one request per two
seconds so we need one two seconds per
one exploitation try and that leads that
after 15 minutes from the beginning of
the attack we in average we will take
control over the device and this time
still can be practical now I'm going to
tell what we learned about not Rock
servers
that is responsible for communications
with the back end it is the protocols
that is implemented here is implemented
over HTTP and WebSockets and it is
called OC PP 2.0 during the connection
establishment this protocol is actually
exist now but the problem here that it
was published on the rails April this
year and this film is investigated film
was released several months earlier and
in addition our vendor ChargePoint
Incorporated is not the participant of
the organization which is called OCA and
which is responsible for those protocol
development
so those name is looking strange for us
at this point and further investigations
shows that what vendor did is they took
previous version of that o CPP protocol
which is OC PP 1.6 and they they created
their own protocol on its base so our CP
t1 does this protocol is often
criticized by information security
community due to lack of attention for
security problems for example this
protocol doesn't provide any encryption
for data transmission and here as this
new version of protocol was implemented
over HTTPS so it uses TLS and so it is
encrypted and this is a really good and
big step forward from the previous
version let's have a closer look at the
vulnerabilities again
so in this protocol implementation
implementation it is always the same
this is always the same vulnerability as
was in
common gateway interface it is cost it
is there this is Stack Overflow and it
is caused by using cons of the same type
of sscanf function but now the process
that is responsible for those this
protocol is not a part of CGI so it may
seems that we are not able to you know
to to try to exploit our pair to execute
our plot multiple times but the problem
here is that there is a very specific
approach that I always that I usually
see in different industrial control
systems and it lays in the fact that
every critical process is tracked for
fails and it is restate restarted after
fails so it can improve the system
resilience against different kinds of
denial of service attacks but it is a
terrible and anti patent from many other
points of view and our examples shows
shows is perfectly so we still able to
to make this repeated exploitation
attack and here are some details so this
time much bigger time delays must must
be made so now average attack time is 6
hours which is you know much bigger but
still acceptable but the problem here is
that there will be Station reboot every
4 process restarting and during this
stationery booth there will be
daya blinking in the front panel of the
device so this can attract a lot of
undesirable attention to the attack and
this vulnerability in CGI is still more
practical for your attack now I'm
actually going back to the presentation
tail title I promised you to show as a
way to the Windows Network and so here
is that now it is the time there is a
process that is called SSH
we have tunnel dot Asajj it is actually
a bash script and you can see some code
snippet from there and what this code
does it is it tried it tries to
establish remote SSH connection to the
servers that is located somewhere at the
vendors in the vendor side and
authentication is done with SSH key
which is stored in the device is a sage
recovery section in the Lea form so this
is probably some kind of a specific
debug backdoor this remote back back-end
server is called mothership in one of
these script comments so developers may
be big fans of Star Wars or Star Trek
but anyway this is the reason
opportunity to connect to this back end
to this mothership and you know to test
all this swarm control features of
course we didn't do that but that can
cause some hero problems you know if the
researcher will be more greedy and less
responsible now I am going to talk a
little about Bluetooth interface but
very little by the way because the usage
of this interface is very limited as I
said before there is a scheme of
implemented Bluetooth stack and I think
the most notable here we did we didn't
find anything inter
think in those upper layers but what is
interesting here is that they implement
bluetooth a share level over UART so
that is very you know very unusual for
modern electronic devices now this host
controller interface or so ash the
interface is usually implemented over
USB which is done in your laptops or it
also can be a part of system-on-chip
which is done in smartphones and the
only device we were able to Google
during our research with the same
actually interface of your art was some
very old Sony smart TV and these facts I
think making this type of interface some
kind of guest from the previous era at
which IOT devices event attract didn't
attract so much attention from the
security community and this is while
this interface may have some you know
childhood diseases may be in it
unfortunately we didn't have enough time
to look so close in one particular
interface but that can be an area for
further research couple of words about
vehicle interface in our station there
is a specific socket type it was drawn
on those fine on these funny pictures it
is called J one seven seven two and we
go interface is implemented with only
one pin which is called control pilot
and we call reports it states to the
charger by changing the resistance
between as this pin and the ground as
they can be three available states for
the vehicle
ready for charging a charge and charged
and ready for charging with ventilation
so as I said we we didn't instill don't
have electric vehicle vehicle in our lab
so we immolated those different states
by means of registers how this shown on
those on this little picture couple of
words about communications with the
vendor so at the end of our research we
send all of annex to charge port
incorporated it it was on sounds of
August this year and we understood his
commitment to securing his devices and
coordinate with security community as
they reacted we can ask so first so
after we discussed or vulnerabilities in
more details they made a mitigation plan
on 21st August and finally as a team
we're with all bugs fixed all fixes was
released at 14th of September it's just
a slide which charge port operated sent
to us it's so they they wrote it by
themselves and you can read that it was
by the way the first the first time they
they received some security issues from
the south side so and that's I think
that that is making the reaction speed
even more respectable couple of forts in
conclusion mmm ok so as I said before
all vulnerabilities were patched and
what is I think the most awesome in this
charging station is the film very
upgrade system so every station that is
connected to the back end will receive
of the update automatically without any
user interaction so we can be quite sure
that all devices are already patched and
about future plans you know Eevee
industry opens a great area for further
research and this includes transaction
protocols and what is the most
interesting I think for me is are those
protocols that I used for communication
between the charging station and the
vehicle because as I mentioned that that
can be a can bus and can bus can open a
really wide road to the we call internal
to the vehicle Network let us all for
today thank you very much for your
attention and your questions are
welcomed thank you ok well I think this
man was first ok so did a vendor ask you
to find the vulnerabilities or did you
start to find them ourselves
oh by the way who started that by
ourselves but we as I said before we
were in there we were really cooperative
to the vendor so we sent our first time
email awake quick okay mmm
we'll go to the back and welcome okay
we're trying to take it in the order of
thank you for your presentation
you showed buffer overflow coat so it
was very exact see code how did you get
it you made white box testing or you
mean the first or the second second
where the length was not specified but
it was rather well formatted the second
was found with some form of vendor help
because they they wasn't able to
communicate with so as I said there is
an SSL implementation but they helped us
to connect to imitate their server yes
it was a white box okay thank you okay
so you mentioned that the Panda boards
are reused in charge points commercial
so my question would have been if you
found any of these charge points
publicly exposed on the internet now and
we haven't even try so this wasn't our
target at this time but maybe we will do
it in future yeah you mention about
Bluetooth Bluetooth right so is it works
on 2.0 or 4.0 ple or what exactly it is
can you please repeat the question you
mentioned about the Bluetooth
communication with Lewis yes between
mobile and your the herbals 4.0 4.0 yes
and you sniff with the bt smooth which
is in android mobile right with our say
damn we made our Salem is not Bill bitty
bitty snuff okay thank you we'll take
the question from you raise your hand
please
we're all types of charges affected or
just some particular cases
mmm it was not loud enough please repeat
we're all types of chargers affected by
this by those disabilities
you mean all charges all charged foreign
stations nations yes yes they were
because
these are vulnerabilities in one
particular conversion so but only we can
be sure only about you know this model
so there are some other models that are
made by a church point and I can't say
anything about them I understood you
right yes all right thank you thank you
and then we have there are two questions
and you'll be the last one okay you
specified that after having the
certificate you could communicate with
it with a device and exploit it
it's in - with its wireless interface
yes so having the certificate can you
exploit it over the internet or only in
its own local network so it doesn't so
we we are not able to do it over
Internet because as I said we made only
one we were focused only on the on the
station on the on the local one okay I
see thank you thank you just one short
question did the vendor pay no no no
thank you and our last question for this
session will be right here please raise
your hand and for any other questions I
will invite you to have a talk after
with Dimitri hello just want to ask how
do you solve the vulnerability related
with the JTAG you say that
most of the wood nobility they're
starting from the jtag connector so as
far as having the interface one JTAG so
you can still connect how can we solved
this I don't know if you understand no I
didn't say the question about the jtag
connector a kg that connector well is
the the start of many vulnerabilities
because you through this port you can
access the the device yes how could you
solve it
physically remove it yes but after that
you can still connect to the pins on the
micro processor you know what you know
the JTAG is internally connected it was
more difficult what is still possible so
how can you protect against JTAG okay I
understand the question now and thank
you yes it is possible to protect
against d'etat can be blocked so it is
there is a possibility to block the JTAG
in some chips but in fact I I think I
haven't ever seen the exact the exact
device where this possibility was
implemented so now it is used it is not
used in fact okay thank you everyone
thank you for your amazing questions
Dmitry thank you for your presentation