can you hear me okay perfect okay so
there's a lot of you here I wasn't
expecting this big of an audience at
this time but we're really glad that
you're here we're going to talk today
about some unique behaviors that we
found exhibited by malware a little bit
so first of all my name is Mattias
he's your notes and a little bit about
myself I'm a threat hunter at
CrowdStrike I've been in the IT industry
for over seven years now with the last
four years focused on security at Kraus
record at a veera I'm a food and travel
enthusiast I like food a lot I know you
can't tell but still I like it I'm going
with my colleague introduce himself
hello my name is Ronnie apple also known
as your notes for my friends I'm afraid
I'm a lizard CrowdStrike
I'm working in the right to secure
industry for five years now previously
with a Europe
I consider myself or in person here and
it's don't forget to assess and i'd like
to 'participate density of challenges
speaking of city city of challenges I
invite you to participate on our
challenge named down the rabbit hole you
can go and talk to our colleague chippy
on about that and we our prize me so I'm
gonna let Marva sue the first half of
the presentation please yeah so we
divided this presentation into four big
topics it's what we do on a daily basis
we're gonna show you three what we found
to be odd infection techniques we can
also show you some quirky but still
legitimate behavior that we've seen and
we have 15 minutes at the end for
questions and answers so if you have any
questions just write them down and we'll
have a 15 minute sessions at the end and
we can discuss about those okay so let's
dive into what we do so we do our
hunting with the reverse engineering and
we write detection
we're actually two groups the one I'm in
focused on malware hunting and on
writing detections and your notes over
here is the one that does reverse
engineering so let's go into malware
hunting what does mallory hunting mean
well for me it's finding the unknown
basically you have to find something
that you've never seen before something
unique in behavior something unique in
the weight the way it behaves on a
computer so how we do it well we have
multiple techniques that we use
techniques workflows first of all we
used yara rules in Mal query Mallory is
a commercial product which is all by
CrowdStrike
and it's basically a search engine for
binary files right it indexes all of the
files and then you can run right here
our rules against it and find samples of
interest if you want to analyze or find
similar samples of something we do use
some overwatch patterns also in Harrier
this is an internal system that we use
so these are very very generic patterns
we're gonna speak about them a little
bit later in the presentation of course
we use virustotal who uses virustotal
here ok so a big chunk of users virus so
this is our open source in feed if I can
put like that so we do VT queries to
find interesting stuff in there we also
look for infection vectors really
important why because we need to find
the kill chain as higher up in the tree
as possible and we also search for
infections if we in our met customers
right now hunting would be are our rules
in mark query this is basically a simple
yarra rule that I use to catch like
interesting stuff so for example this
one it's a possible LNK link download
area I'm looking for link files I'm
basically looking at
the magic of the the link file and then
I use the HTTP white token why use link
file is because lately I've seen a peak
in the wild with linked files that you
do all kinds of crazy stuff from crazy
powershell one-liners abusing mists
abusing WMI and a lot of nasty things
that are used with link files and the
funny thing about Lincoln's it's not
funny the best thing about link files is
you cannot give it a context right so if
you think about the process tree that
follows the execution of a link file you
will see Explorer that spawns whatever
is on that link file right so you can
give it context you can give it context
like when you have a powershell
downloader in a windward right
you see powershell on the windward
that's easy right but when you have link
files the context to give context to to
do that execution is it's it's pretty
hard so again a possible link download
or a simple yara rule which returns like
in the last two weeks 66 malware link
files five clean and two one okay so
this is like mal query as i told you
it's an internal to overwatch patterns
we use this also a lot but they're
mostly used for hunting targeted
activity and sophisticated attacks
they're very generic so for example you
can use a pattern that's just not use
right nate use is like a legitimate
command that is used by system
administrator right but we've seen it
used a lot by attackers in like if you
want to move laterally or or stuff like
that another thing another one could be
wmic and HTTP we have an example
actually with wmic
you I'm just gonna speak about it this
could be another pattern it could I mean
it's very generic again
and you can just block everything that
uses wmic and HTTP right what we found
interesting though is that by
correlating three or more of these
patterns together it gives us a good
indicator that something's happening on
that end point on that machine right and
somebody should take a look and
investigate what's going on right so
three or more patterns it's that's
basically that means that something's
wrong there I was telling you also about
virustotal right
a lot of you use it a lot of you I don't
know how you use it I use it mostly to
find if you find new things that are
running in the wild so for example in
this query I'm looking for emails
luckily I know if I could put it luckily
or not but it's luckily for us we still
see emails on virus though for some
reason which is good for us so you have
emails positive three or more why use
three it's arbitrary it's just a number
I choose to like exclude a lot of false
positives right so if it's three or more
positives for the email then it's
probably something wrong with that email
and I should probably take a look at it
I'm excluding some I don't know some CV
some vulnerabilities or not that I'm not
interested in and I get a little fascist
right with this list of hashes I'm gonna
tell you at the end what I'm gonna do
with all of those hashes another example
is this one the query for zip files I
found again very interesting stuff using
querying VT for zip files that contain
this these extensions it's these file
extensions
these are javascript jscript jscript
encoded vbscript I also use windows
script host windows script file I also
use a nankai files over here to look to
search and I just download them all and
make a small collection daily out of
everything that I showed you so
virustotal mercury and also from the
overwatch patterns I take all of those
hashes and detonate them how I detonate
them I have a VM
that has our product installed on it and
I get all of the information back I get
telemetry back from from that via oh so
after I get I find something interesting
like the needle in the haystack
I basically hand it over to my colleague
over here who does the who does the
reverse engineering part and at the end
he's gonna give me he's gonna provide me
with a report of what happened what does
that file to you and she's gonna show
you more but that makes me feel like I'm
his boss sometimes because you know I
give you something and you give me
something back as a report what if some
day yeah okay so I'm gonna hand it over
to him for the reversing part Thank You
Martha for the introduction so when my
response new collections of files that
you want to analyze he handles them to
me or other guys from the team so we
start to during policing process on it
I'm not necessarily interested in what
that mother does whether it's a but
whether it's around somewhere
I just people I just care what it does
in the system like if it's injecting
processes for example that's projecting
code in other processes sorry basically
for events that are not seen in
conventional tools so one of them as I
showed as I said previously is process
injection another thing that we like to
look for is malicious call stabs remove
procedure calls via my I'm going to talk
about via my later for those that are
not familiar familiar
this technology privileged escalation
credential dumping the rot of tools out
there and mallar that want to do
credential without dumping and do
lateral movement also we look for some
exploitation techniques we have quite a
few but these are some of them deb SLR i
pass
keep spraying excetera another step that
can be done before or after the analysis
i look for other similar samples or
other binaries other PE files that are
from the same family so that i can be
sure that my findings are correct and
accurate as possible so i'm going to
work with you through three different
model samples i'm gonna talk about their
infection how the infection works so the
first one is a malicious document that
abuses am excite sec to drop Delphic
compiled Mulder onto the victim machine
also this binary is digitally signed and
that signature is still valid by today
which is interesting
i'm going to talk about emi and how it
can be abused to inject a dotnet binary
into a legitimate windows process this
technique over here is also known as
people e to you can google that if you
want to learn more about about this and
then if i know the example and the most
interesting from my point of view it's
an excel spreadsheet that uses a
steganography to infect its victim so
let's dive into the first one the
malicious document that uses
I'm excited this document was found in
the wild you can see a prince Prince
piano in the right corner it has by now
a industry standard social engineering
message trying to convince the user that
he has to enable the contents even
though it's under a security warning but
who won't click that button everybody
does so let's see what it does this is a
screenshot from Falcon UI we can see
here the Windward process which opened
that document and we see that it created
another process under it from update a
local temp and it has an interesting
common line the file name is stable dot
exe and has a common line with a URL at
the end so what's with this URL over
here if you go and download the sample
calculate the hashing search it on
reverse total for example you'll see
that it's a Windows installer next so
Windows installer and has three
detections on one virustotal
which makes me think that it's smaller
so let's look a bit into it a little bit
more looking into process Explorer the
one from sysinternals you'll see that
after Windows starts this table dot exe
another two processes appear within the
operating system the first one is mxi
exec from the Windows operating system
under services and that one starts
and si host file if you remember this
MSI file at the top previously it has
another P file embedded within it so if
you unpack the code and drop the second
stage sample you'll end up with that
Delfy binary that I said at its sign and
our signature is still valid and the
detection ratio virustotal increases
each day so let's put a bit at the
interesting part of this infection
scenario I think I should go over here
so that you can see the code better if
you open the word document and extract
the PPA script you'll end up with this
from my point of view it's a pretty
small piece of code don't think that
it's interesting over here even though
it's pretty small it has also some junk
code in it you can see some variables
over here some objects being declared
but they're never used anywhere so
looking through the code I see this
table dot exe further down I see file
copy and this file copy receives two
arguments the first one is frm that
label on the tag which it's a variable
that I don't know what it where it's
being declared as let's know we're over
here and the second one that calls the
path to table dot exe the second
instruction that catches my attention is
[Music]
is this one down so this basically
concatenates to two variables using that
app and then creates a new process this
creates a process with that command line
and we're gonna see how that's being
achieved looking more into the into the
VBA script of the word document
see that it has an embedded win form in
it which has never been displayed for
the for the user it has multiple objects
in it so the main window and some labels
over here so if you start debugging this
script and go to here at this file copy
you will see that frm that label 1 dot
tech contains this path over here the
path to MSI offset which is a windows
binary legit 100% clean code from the
operating system and it's being used to
copy it to cable not easy and of course
we need to devote table dot exe so where
do these variables where are these
variables declared these objects over
here from we forms have some controls so
if you look at the controls for each of
these objects down at the bottom you'll
see a small property named tag so that
tag over there has the path to that URL
that I am told one from the command line
so if you have security products on your
machine where you want to do some
forensics where you have some cool
script that autumn eise's the analysis
of word document of work of Office
documents most of them dumped the VBA
script do some analysis over it they can
apply some error rules they can look for
strings occur for PowerShell encoded
commands like base64 but apply some ml
on it maybe I don't know where any other
interesting technology that they may
have but you don't find anything here
because all of the malicious part it's
being hidden in the in the controls of
the
before so I don't want to keep your
ideas because I know you have something
you are some test pen testers over here
but instead of using MSI exec you can
use PowerShell and instead of having
that URL over there you can use an
encoded command and you don't see
PowerShell being started by Windward
you'll see a little table not easy or
whatever not easy with very long string
at the end not many red flags are raised
because of that but they should so this
was the first example I'm going to go
down to the next one
I'm going to talk about VMI and how it
can be used to inject it into other
binaries the technique that I said that
it's called feebly to also some people
like to talk about this technique and
say that it's file is smaller but it's
not really fast and we're gonna see why
this is a spring spring from Falcon ey
again on the left here we see VMI for
those that don't know what VMI is it's a
technology embedded within the operating
system Windows operating system since
Windows 95
it enables you to create sql-like
queries to the operating system you can
create files you can create processes
you can delete registries you can do
whatever you want it's a tool that it
was and still is very popular among IT
administrators among network
administrators to be able to deploy
different kind of scripts within their
their networks but recently modern
developers started to understand this
technology and to leverage its powers so
why is this am i important if you look
over here on the right side we have a
common line which is being highlighted
here we see that VMI has a very
interesting command line printer get
device ID format then again a URL to
some form / H forms so what about this
this URL over here
VMI will go to this address will
download the content and if the contents
are according to a standard the standard
is called extensible stylesheet language
it will execute those those instructions
where a what whatever it finds over here
so let's see what's happening in that
extensible stylesheet sorry so if you
don't know the contents you'll end up
with this file over here well think
about extensible stylesheet has a
wrapper for jscript
or VPS in this case the code the
programming language that is being used
is VBS
so let's comment a bit about on the code
the first thing that catches my
attention it's this function over here
which is being collapsed not to buy a
lot of space on the on the screen this I
think you already know does some base64
decoding down we see some declarations
of some variables and there you have
assigned some different strings like
xcms build a path to an interesting file
name see versions dot 0 dot DP and
microsoft.net framework before and other
numbers over here looking down into the
code we'll see that this function over
here is being used to decode it this
very long string and assign it to the
variable named frog the contents of this
very variable are then dumped into a
file on disk using Create file and write
line into this sea variable subversions
over here so this is the first file that
that touches the disk right now and if
you decode the the long basic step or
the string you will end up with some
c-sharp code so what does this script do
its completes creating a very long
comment line over here by concatenating
these strings up top and it's using
msbuild to compile dynamically some
c-sharp code that's the main reason why
msbuild is over here to compile C sharp
and then of course it's being ran next
yeah this is the common line catenate
the see windows microsoft.net framework
before name is Bill and the path to that
[Music]
file over there
okay this is the c-sharp code this is
the main function but you can't see it
very well it's pretty short function
this is the code that will be compiled
and executed by msbuild
so up top we see again another base64
encoded string decoding the string will
end up with P binary we can see the
first two bytes over here I am set and
then the P here which are which is being
highlighted and then several api's are
used to create a new process out of C
windows system32 ICS and at theta dot
exe which is a legitimate file between
the operating system it creates the
process with a suspended flag allocate
some memory write some code into that
newly created process gets a handle to
the fret creates on a synchronous
procedure call and then resumes the
friend's execution by ten days it's
starting a new process it empties it out
and then inject malicious code into it
so this is the entire functionality of
this c-sharp over here but as I said
this is considered far less but it's not
actually the case because when M is
built over here starts the compilation
it will write a DLL want to the disk
into the temp directory with random name
slash the dot DLL and this DLL will be
loaded and executed by msbuild so this
is why I'm saying that it's not true
fallas file true fallacy infection story
because by now every forensic tool out
there will be able to get this far over
here you can compute the hash can
download it save it to cloud apply again
some
Maloney do some static analysis or
whatever so it's not very good I see you
had to use ms building this scenario
because you're not using the true file
this infection technique so by now since
M is built compiled that c-sharp and ran
it the previous file over here which is
which can be some back door apart it can
be a ransomware is now running within
your operating system as ICS unattended
so if you open up task manager you don't
find anything over there you'll just see
a file residing in system 40 to go
process with the file path residing in
system 42 if you compute the half of
this file you'll see that it's clean
what in fact it has running Mahler in it
so let's move on to the third and last
example please work the one recording
steganography again typical social
engineering message with the macro on it
this one over here has a message in
italian convincing you to click that to
a bottom where there and we'll see why
the message is in italian and not
or other language in this case I'm not
interested in the VBA script
I'm just interesting how it's being used
to to infect a machine in this Fred
graph over here how we like to call this
nice picture over here we see that Excel
creates CMD dot exe process which spawns
other processes one CMP you another CMD
a clipper exe clip let's the windows
tool that copies whatever you put on the
command line and it will be copied to
the clipboard of the operating system
then we see PowerShell being being
started and we should have seen another
process over here but we're gonna get in
that details a bit later so let's look
at the command line over there next this
is it it's pretty office kata Tjuta you
can't read a lot of things out of this
but if you look closely right in the
middle you'll see URL string pointing to
a randomly named image randomly named
file which has a PNG extension so at
this point I said that so why bothering
to rename your executable as as a PNG
file of course it's not executable let's
download it and see what it does and
look at at the file now I can fall and
look I'm looking at the head header
you'll see the magic Vice over here for
for the PNG file so this is a 100% image
file and if you open it you'll see a
cute little green team over here
free sorry okay so what's the point of
this why is it using a PNG file in
the mother infection process going back
to the code this common line over here
is being composed of two two parts the
first one just echoes a very big string
to click on txz
using this pipe over here this cop is
the code to the clipboard and then
another partial commercial command is
being around let's look at this second
part over here right now
this is the code again a little bit off
escape it but if you use the magic and
the obfuscated we will see that it
creates a win form object and using the
clipboard class it will involve the get
text method to get a Content to get the
content out of that clipboard of the
operating system and by doing that it
wipes out the content of of the
clipboard to invoke expression revoke
expression for though the dot for those
that don't know PowerShell it's like if
L from JavaScript you just give it a
string and it will execute it happily
and the last line over here just to
remove the traces clears up the clip
were not not for you to find any
interesting garbage in it for whatever
reason so let's go to the first part
back again this is the office fitted
code if we add some new lines the code
will look something like this it now
starts to make some sense you can see
some strings now we can see some coding
over here new object you can see bitmap
you can see those
that we previously talked about we can
see a furlough we can see even invoke
expression over here the shorthand
notation but it's pretty messed up you
can't understand the logic of this code
[Music]
if you do office Kate it's a bit more
you'll end up with a pretty nice
powershell script over here and you can
now understand what what it's doing
under the hood so it's downloading the
contents of this PNG file into an object
of type bitmap it then creates a buffer
over here of 428 bytes
using the for for loop it iterates
through the first column of that PNG
file applies a mathematical operation on
them and decode some data out of those
pixels so this is basically second
ography by abetting information into an
image so the map of this example is
quite simple I would say you take the
blue pixel and it with 15 the result of
this is being multiplied with 16 the
green pixel it ended with 15 and result
of this it's being worked with the
previous with the previous mathematical
operation and then all of this is being
assigned to to this output buffer over
here after that this buffer is being
converted to a string and then is being
executed by invoking expression so if I
now expect that I'll have another power
source code that will be executed by by
our mother so let's look at that as well
this is the last power shell that
was in this infection routine or chain
call it what you may like we see up top
URL to IP for that I useless JSON
downloading the contents of that file
we'll end up with the JSON that splits
out spits out information about your IP
address including your country over here
so we see an if statement and it checks
whether it if you are from Italy if
you're not from Italy you're safe so
it's good if you're from Italy then
downloads another field over here using
the download file method saves it depend
on app ain't got your exe and there
starts process at this point I see okay
someone went through the hassle of doing
steganography and hiding its code as
much as he can and doing some
interesting things over here but in the
end it downs of downloads a PE file and
write to the disk why do you do that I
don't know but I think this is a this is
some sort of mosquito mistake that they
that they didn't realize about that and
that's it I'm gonna handle the rest of
the presentation back to Mario's oh I
forgot about this slide yeah this is the
results of Devi engines on virustotal
regarding that paint
PFL over here it had six detections when
it was first seen and then it rose to
almost 40
so please Marcus thank you man
yeah so about this last example funny
it's not funny
the thing is that when we first thought
is about two months ago it was targeting
Italy we've seen it like a month ago
there was another wave that was
targeting Japan and then like a week ago
we found another wave that was targeting
China so they target countries I don't
know one at a time probably so yeah
that's interesting okay so after I get
the report from from my colleague over
here we basically have to write
detection rules we need to as I told you
the beginning I know if you remember we
need to find the kill chain as soon as
possible in the in the life of an
infection right so even if we kill it
like at the last stage it's okay but it
would be a lot better if you could kill
it later on in the life of the life of
the infection so what I do is I
basically write some detections some
detection rules by using multiple
technologies that we have available and
the product these are strictly related
to the product I'm not gonna go into
details I'm just enumerated some like
caustic analysis process injection
remote procedure calls process freeze
control there's a lot of them that we
can use to to write detection so what I
did is I got a report from my colleague
over here and I using some of those
technologies we wrote like three
detections for each and one of them so
for the first two use for example one
and three we used Iowa s Iowa is we call
them indicators of attack
they're basically indicators of some
things that happened during that
infection didn't into that process it
could be a command line it could be a
process injection it could be multiple
things right for the second example we
only use inflection in injection Flags
process injection flags and we got
actually pretty good results with those
those detection so we saw malware but
we're also gonna see like legitimate
stuff that shouldn't happen right so I
have a saying just because you can
doesn't mean you should just because you
can use crazy powershell one-liner
encoded downloading stuff using crazy
api is crazy functions doesn't mean you
actually should because it creates
basically a door to your breach to your
security right and there's a lot of
people who do I mean this is their way
of doing things it's pretty hard to
change this mentality but as an industry
standard is the best practice you
shouldn't do write a custom win logon
into program data and then run it under
SVC host and then spawn another win log
on from there right so but again this
was something custom-made for them it
worked in their environment we were
looking and said okay it's good that you
do this but maybe you shouldn't but
after all it's clean right this is
another one that was actually really
interesting if you take a look over here
this is your typical this is again of
screenshot from Falcon UI this is your
typical fishing tree right so you
receive an email right it's some
attachment win document that has some VB
a script with it that launches some
PowerShell command line right so this is
your typical fishing tree that you see
on a daily basis if you download an
email from VT today now you'll find this
fishing tree but this was also a
legitimate thing they did this in their
network in their environment this is the
way that they did things so we can't
just go ahead and block everything and
hope for the best
that's not the solution we need to
distinguish the bad from the good the
thing the good thing is that we managed
to distinguish the bat from the good so
we were able to fix this another one
that I like very much is this one over
here again your typical fishing tree you
receive an email have an URL there you
link or you click on your URL chrome
opens up you download the file that has
this
extension right here PDF dot zip Tod exe
which is yeah which is PDF that zip dot
exe but again this was something
legitimate they I mean they were doing
they were using some kind of encryption
software that they used on files so they
send files encrypted over the network
via email to each other so they when
they typed in the password they could
decrypt the file and look at the content
of it right so again I have to mention
we can't go and block everything right
because there are people who do this
like this is normal business business as
usual for them even if it's abused my
attackers even if it's used by Malory it
not doesn't necessarily mean it's it's
malicious in certain scenarios ok so as
some closing remarks we've seen that I
mean at least I've seen that
productivity is still a big thing in the
wild and their uses initial infection
vectors why because it's really easy to
to bypass a spam email solution by just
attaching a document right and then that
document does some crazy stuff and to
come some crazy stuff and then you get
access to or to someone's network quirky
infection techniques are seen more and
more often attackers use Windows
legitimate binaries as you've seen they
use msi exact they renamed it they use
WM i which is again legitimate and used
by a lot of a lot of system
administrators again we can't just
blacklist and hope for the best right
and as my colleague said adversaries do
try to migrate to fireless infections
but at some point in this infection they
they do drop some files on disk so
that's it for us I think we have five
minutes more for questions I think we're
out of time
[Music]
just
anyone here in the earth until that
there's yep and then the second row
there right
first of all thank you for the
presentation it was great
I was just wondering because of the many
bad pieces of code that are written for
legitimate purposes how do you decide
how soon they decide that you're on a
false-positive track and that you should
give up or you just keep on
investigating until you're 100% is just
bad code or bad practice well it's kind
of hard because our product that doesn't
send data into the cloud it only sends
metadata so when you have a file like
the last one that I showed you like this
one over here it's pretty hard to decide
but this one was actually kind of easy
because we saw it was lying there on a
shared drive you know in some network on
the network and we said okay this might
be this might be legitimate but you need
more information yes yes yes
usually they contact us when they see
something like this like a false
positive and then they say okay this is
false positive so you have to fix it
okay thank you so I have two questions
the first one is do you do any file
based detection soar just behavior based
I mean just like an anti-virus or just
based on behavior oh the sensor has two
components it has the AV component which
is only machine learning based and looks
at P files and then there is the
behavioral component so we also look at
static statically at files okay and the
second question is when you see all the
t's like these in your customer
environment it's actually two questions
do you do you do you make suggestions
that they shouldn't be using these types
of yes I mean I mean I assume they
trigger a lot of alarms in your yes we
do that there are actually some sales
engineers that take care of those
customers and we form that hey they got
this maybe you should talk them into
changing this
they don't always do it but with we try
the second thing is I wanted to know if
you get any pushback on this this yes I
do this my own way and I don't care
suggest yes thank you okay
in the first few slides you specifically
discussed about detection I wonder if he
made some profiling in order to figure
out whether your model could be could be
applied to real-time detection of larger
throughput data we do that we do that in
the cloud there are some plans of doing
that for behaviors but right now we
don't so we're planning on doing it but
it's not this model does not this ml
model it's a different one this one only
I mean ml model I think I got your
question right if not stop me and see
Europe so it seems that it has a very
good potential for application to
real-time detection of it is this is all
real time yeah this is all detection and
prevention real time yeah yeah okay
thanks you're welcome
[Music]
the middle and will be after that one
more question so one final question
after this one here in the front row
okay thank you
hi did you saw any campaign or fishing
for example with legitimate the files
only to get you into the wrong direction
or something like this not sure I
understand so legitimate files that yes
like to send you a fishing to your
clients fishing emails but actually the
files inside to be legitimate well there
is a funny thing and maybe next
following an attack or something like
this a funny thing when I worked out of
your funny thing happened there was a
phishing campaign that was running in a
while and somebody hacked the Packers
situ and instead of delivering malware
there was a jscript the jscript actually
delivered the AV antivirus they have
your antivirus and we were like what
okay that's good and that at that point
that was a pretty good thing first it
was free marketing free free commercial
hello yes Alec and what do you want and
for the non P files for example for
Android and Mac do you have also
behavioral machines to watch over the
for Mac applications and Android also
for men we also have a ml model for Mac
and we also do behavior for for Mac also
enter Android not yet it's probably in
the working something's gonna be
something real soon okay thank you
you're welcome
you are and Marcus from CrowdStrike
thank you very much yes thank you guys
[Applause]