so in this talk we will be talking about
reverse engineering malware and
introduction to it as a very much the
introduction to the tooling the sandbox
saying the environment that you need to
set up this might this is not an
intermediate talk not advanced talk this
is actually a very much a beginner talk
for starting security analysts and we're
gonna go through the basic steps on how
to reverse engineer a Windows malware
very potent Windows malware that
actually hit a large company we will
talk about it about ten months ago it
was very alive very potent it's the
servers are still alive so if you want
to go ahead and pen test it that's your
decision okay
so hi everybody my name is Abdullah as
the introducer already said I work as a
security analyst and mobile attribution
provider company and if that is too
confusing it's basically we allow mobile
marketers to authenticate installs that
are coming from their advertisements and
I work as a security analyst and the
fraud team sre anti-fraud team of the
company and previously I worked as a
software engineer and here's my twitter
handle so if you want to follow us
alright so first of all what is malware
and this definition is not made by me
this one is made by a mr. Jake Williams
from SANS Institute is a his handles
malware Jake from Twitter he's one of
the most smartest people that I know of
malware handling he's very dedicated
person malware is a binary that does
something someone wouldn't like I hope
I'm paraphrasing him right so it's not
about I will get to the demo in a minute
it's not about an exploit that's a
misconception
not all the time malware will actually
contain an exploit that's only the
really powerful very fancy ones most of
the time is actually just abusing the in
the windows case that 132 api in android
case it's the Android ecosystem the
permission system if you were in the my
first talk you would see me give a talk
about how the Android ecosystem was
exploited in order to attack the content
provider that Google Play uses it's not
an
a technical exploit and the security
nomenclature it's actually just an abuse
of the already existing system so more
or less it's technically legal so we're
going to go through a small demo right
now about this you know the case about
the demo gods right you know if the demo
works or not here's a virtual machine
I'm running Windows 10 and you see a
small little exe that's called open me
dot exe alright so a free hat goes to
whoever can tell me what should I do
with this thing
thank you all right so this is gonna
take around I think 60 seconds or so so
I will just go over here and get back to
it and in the next 60 seconds so while
this is actually working why bother with
analysis why do we need malware analysis
in my opinion malware analysis is
necessary not antivirus I'm not I'm not
here to trash talk about any antivirus
I'm more or less uh opinionated about it
but it's necessary to know that there is
a difference between malware analysis
and letting the antivirus people do
their job it's very different a very big
difference most malware is targeted to a
specific organization to specific people
the specific infrastructure and a
specific target it's actually has a
unique signature and if the molar writer
knows what he's doing
he's not going to be he's going to be
avoiding anti viruses if any of you has
done o SCP I think one of the main tasks
is that you have to design an exploit
that avoids that of AIT's antivirus
programs so this is why we mother with
analysis because most automated tools
can't really catch it it's something
very targeted at something very unique
so simple hygiene I believe its proper
world is a very good good way of
protecting against such a thing number
one rule don't click on exe that says
open mean dot exe all right let's get
back to a little virtual machine lovely
all right
important information all of your files
are encrypted with RSA 2000
48 and aes-128 ciphers right so that
sounds bad decrypting of your file is
only possible with the private key and
decrypt program this is my unique
personal identification ID and if I go
to here my wallpaper has been replaced
and if you look in here
what is the extension of this file
Osiris wow that's not a file I created
that's actually a txt file that I had
flying around it had some input in there
and all my files are right now encrypted
this is what's called ransomware it will
encrypt all your files all day necessary
very crucial text files that you have
budgeting anything that you anything
that you and your boss talked about all
encrypted with a dot or in this case dot
Osiris extension and you can't do
anything about it this is unreadable if
you go into notepad this was a txt file
it didn't even have a magic number it
had nothing it's just a pure txt file
right now it's encrypted this is what
ransomware does and if we can revert
back to my virtual machine I will get
back to it right right at the end we
will do a small experimentation
afterwards so we're gonna deal today
with a small ransomware before I go and
into this into the analysis there is
something about AV vendors by I think
the the name of the person is Brian
Welton from blank Black Hills
information security yes I remember they
made this thing this event and they keep
doing it every RSA and it's amazing and
they actually have it as a webinar so
what they do is that they have a small
booth they set it up using usual an RSA
conferences or a black hat and they
literally attack and the virus vendors
live they say download the latest
version of the antivirus whether it's I
don't know I'm not gonna name names but
they have a list of AV vendors they go
through it every year and they basically
attack it they have a small malware they
keep changing the signature of it and
the a pipe ass every single antivirus
program out there and I as I said I'm
very on
been United about antiviruses but the
thing is they are not made for
protection against directed attacks you
can't protect against us
there is no antivirus that could have
protected against Stuxnet that's that
wouldn't have existed and moving on so
analyzing a ransomware the name of this
the codename that hybrid analysis gave
is open me dot exe that's the name that
it was that the large organization that
in fact that was infected by this
ransomware that's the name of the X part
of the exe file open me dot exe if you
go to the top right corner you can see
threat score of hundred and that's
something from not automated analysis
tool so we can see that there is a lot
of fun geeky where it's happening and
the e AV detection rate is 76% but not
hundred percent nothing can be caught 1%
so this one was it has a lot of
interesting signatures that do resemble
Antivirus Pro do resemble malware like
crypt encrypt the use of crypt encrypt
function for 132 API for ransom wires
which we're gonna go over later and the
steps that were going to follow right
now with the analysis is very much a
surgical approach we're not here to do
an entire analysis or a dissection of
the malware I don't care about what sort
of SQLite database libraries that they
imported I don't care about the
versioning I only care about a very
specific thing I need to know if this
exe is safe or not and assuming that the
person actually doesn't open it before
he send it to me so we're going to
follow a small methodology of analyzing
this ransomware the first one is that
we're going to go with static analysis
not reverse engineering that's a
different step that's static code
analysis right now we're just going to
see what the properties of exe is
afterwards we're going to go with
behavioral analysis some people call it
dynamic analysis we're going to run it
see what's the inputs and the outputs
and afterwards we're going to open it up
with either pro or radare or pick your
own disassembler the thing is a lot of
since this talk is aimed very much at
the uninitiated and the malware analysis
never ever open a malware or an exe file
directly into either without knowing
what you're doing you're gonna be
bombarded by a libraries that you're not
that you don't know about and you don't
need to know about you need to have a
theory before you actually go on to an
analysis that's what the job of a
malware analyst is and either stands for
interactive disassembler so the
interactive part is you static analysis
the format of this presentation will be
that I'm using small sandbox environment
of two virtual machines UNIX system and
a Windows system which is the victim
system and one is the analysis system
for the windows for the both systems
you're going to see the either UNIX or
Windows : and then the command that I'm
executing if it's a Windows GUI program
you're going to see the name of the
program I'm doing this so that later on
if you actually want to do this thing by
yourself you can download open me dot
exe it's and I github repo which I have
the link to at the end it's called the
zoo it has a pretty big diverse range of
malware's for you to analyze and have
fun with and you can execute these
commands to follow exactly what I just
did and you can reach your own
conclusions afterwards so in here we're
running strings it's basic UNIX command
that actually just dumps all the strings
that are there in the exe file and as we
can see in here to me none of this makes
sense
none of this is relevant by the way the
cover story of the exe file that the
infrastructure of the company found was
that it's a paint replacement program ok
so that's what if you're a male or
analyst this is the cover story that
you're going to receive it's like hey I
would just receive this email and it had
an exe file that says this is a better
paint program so how about you go ahead
and tell me if it's real or not so what
we're looking for right now are
signatures for drawing GUI drawings so
to me none of this makes sense
what is constructions strike Banner
Chinese medium somebody can explain to
me this he gets a free hat so
yeah strings didn't give me any useful
input right now this is the next page of
string I like this one Astro burn light
is not installed do you want to download
Astro burn light I actually search for
Astro burn light on Google I have no
idea what this is it's it's it's not a
real software so when you receive a
software like this and it has a it says
it's a paint program just run strings on
it and see if it actually is trying to
do what it says it's doing okay next
step is that we're still on the static
analysis part we need to know what the
CXC looks like Wow what's the imports
what's the exports but what's the
libraries it's using what's the DLL
stuff like that so we run it through a
small program called P studio I really
can't believe this program is free it's
amazing if you have five minutes and you
just your boss tells you it's like ok I
need to know what this malware does like
now just throw it into PE studio it's
beautiful it gives you all the imports
that you need gives you all the
blacklisted keywords and highlights them
on the left side what you're gonna see
in a minute and tells you basically a
small summary of what it thinks this
program does now that's a summary of an
automated tool so just be aware what
you're trying to do so it's actually
from what we can see in here it actually
has some paint properties set pixel I
can see in here Phil rgn I'm guessing
that's some sort of something relating
to paint programs rectangle set brush or
GX create pen there's some interesting
signatures that do actually resemble
paint programs so it could fool the eyes
so but let's keep going let's let's keep
asking questions I said about the PE
stood here the strings the blacklisted
strings it's right here highlighted in
red and there is the indicators above it
will tell you a small summary of what's
what it thinks it could be doing and in
here I do see some interesting stuff if
you're if you may close attention you're
gonna see two very important things in
here TLS okay anybody knows what TLS
stands for in 132 API
thread-local storage not transport layer
security it's it's a weird thing in
win32 api it's basically a very niche
weird little thing that Microsoft did
which is basically having the ability to
store variables that is on the threat
itself and you can transport it for
multi-threaded applications for malware
analysis there is a side effect for it
for a malware author excuse me you can
execute a program before the entry
before the actual entry point the one
main function you can execute whatever
it is that you want before it when you
see something as that says TLS 99% of
the time it will be doing something
malicious why would you if you're a real
program or an actual binary why would
you want to execute something before the
execution of the program to fool the
analyst so if you see something with TLS
that's already a red flag all right so
we have an here terminate process why
would a paint program want to terminate
the process of another programs we have
is debugger present why is the paint
program trying to detect if a debugger
is present you see this is only some
like gang signs in here that you can
detect for malware when you see
something like this just to keep doing
some analysis you're gonna find some
interesting stuff right now we're gonna
go for dynamic analysis what I'm gonna
do is that basically have the Windows
victim machine which is the virtual
machine that you just saw it will be
running it's connected through it's
connected through an IP ipv4 proxy to my
analysis machine the Ubuntu machine and
the Boonta machine is running some just
basically some traffic analysis to see
what's going in what's going out what's
the DNS requests what's happening when
when I click the button
what's the requests that are being made
and there's a small Python script called
fake DNS the pie it's uh has a big hub
big github repository basically what it
does is that it captures all the DNS
requests and show it to you in here it's
kind of like running Wireshark or burp
or whatever it is that you want but this
is just for DNS it's
little bit easier if you want to just
know what you're exactly something
specific what you need and I seen here
some when 10 API went to an FBI request
and I see something in here BRB the 3d
touch that'd be why
what does which be why domain name
country which country code does it stand
for
anybody it's not so far away from here
Belarus thank you so and there is a
paint program that is connecting that
has trying to connect Belarusians server
it's not from Belarus the paint program
so let's continue on so we running
another tool right now we're gonna have
a list of tools at the end of the slide
so don't worry if you miss one of them
this tool is called I need sim
it's basically what it does is that when
you are throwing PHP requests it will
reply back with a small PHP header with
a small PHP page add fake made PHP page
when you're asking if the victim machine
is asking for a jpeg it will reply back
with a JPEG it's basically there just to
continue the analysis it's like okay
we're throwing a request the victim
machine is still waiting trying to get
something back it will throw it
something back it's it's just throwing
back a dummy request but it's nice to
just continue the analysis just to see
how the execution of the ransomware just
goes how far will it go and it actually
got fooled the the BRB the 3d touch dot
py had a slash ads but PHP request and
the victim machine through a payload all
of this payload through it with to the
host BRB the 3d totes and I received it
in my analysis machine and at the end of
the presentation we're gonna know what
the hell is happening in here the first
one is I think pretty easy it's an IP
address
it's my IP address it's my local I'm
using VirtualBox so it's my local
internal torques IP address static IP I
see in here C equals desktop whatever
that's my computer name and then we see
P equals
huge payload looks encrypted we're gonna
get to it later and we're gonna know
what's happening right now right now we
have we have an more or less
confirmation that whatever it is that's
happening in here it's not a paint
program okay we still didn't see any
gooeys we're still gonna see anything
it's connected to a pollution server so
at this point you can more or less stop
the analysis until the person who sent
you this file don't open it so an
encrypted post request this is what we
note is the summary of what's happening
we have an encrypted post request we
have a reference to PR bit of 3d totes
that be wine there is an interesting
quote is that I I can't remember who
said it but in communication it's not
what is being said it's what's not being
said what did I not see in the list of
imports in here I see a lot of function
names what am I not saying there is the
internet functions the HTTP requests
that made this where is it it has to be
made through an import through a when I
net dot dll import to be specific
that's the DLL library for win32 api
that's responsible for handling network
requests I didn't see it it's not there
so there is no cryptography imports none
actually I just got infected by
ransomware
so I'm expecting that the library that
if every binary that infected me could
have some cryptographic functions like
crept encrypt that's the number one
cryptographic functions that you need to
actually encrypt stuff in 132 API
krypton crap it's not there it's not
done a list of imports so moving on with
the analysis we're done with the dynamic
analysis by the way we know that it's
doing something funky we know that we
need to go further let's actually start
having a preparation for the static code
analysis for actually attaching a
debugger or disassembler for radar or
either pro or whatever it is that you
want and we can start getting prepared
for that part to do that we need to
check for Packers as in a small
one-liner a packer is usually a program
that is
encrypting the program it's a V a Packer
is a wrapper around the program that is
encrypting the real program the child
binary the one that's actually doing the
work
it's encrypting it and once you click
the executable and actual try to execute
it it will unpack it and you will have
the real binary why does it put a small
binary into a box close it and gives it
to the client why is it doing it this
application it's basically trying to
hide itself from the analysis either an
automated mail and a scanner or an
anti-virus or me the analyst it's right
it's trying to hide itself and we have
some tools in here to actually check for
Packers at some online tools we can
check it out in here exe m4 detects it
easy none of them actually detected a
packet as you can see in here it says
not packed the this tool which is the
CLI version of this tool it's different
ports that's actually doing something
different
it says not packet has anti debug so
it's definitely doing something funny we
didn't detect the packer but we didn't
detect any Internet functionality we
didn't affect any cryptographic methods
so we still need to go through with the
analysis theory we have two theories now
the binary is protected with a packet
it's it's a protected with a packer the
second one is that crypt encrypt is used
somewhere crypt encrypt as I said before
is the cryptographic function that is
necessary for encrypting a section of
plaintext that's if you're writing
around somewhere you will have to use
this function or you have to make your
own cryptographic methods so I'm gonna
go with the Occam's razor with the
easiest path is a straight forward path
so I'm just gonna go to assume as a
theory that crypt encrypt will be used
so I need to know where is it being used
how and the first theory is that this
binary is encrypted somewhere somehow I
don't know why I don't know how but I'm
just assuming virtual protect is the
method that is being used to actually
change the protection of a region of
memory into writable or readable or
executable so if I'm a packer and I want
to unpack my child binary
we'll have to use this function to map
out a section of memory that I can
unpack it in and you can do this in
different methods of course there's ten
ways to do this thing but this is just
one of the most famous ones and I'm
going with the theory in here I'm gonna
see how this theory holds up so I'm
attaching a small debugger in here it's
I'm using x32 debug it's one of the
variations of x64 debug project and in
my opinion it's a great open source
project if you're using community or
something I use immunity it's amazing
but this one I really like it it's very
good it has all the features that you
need and the GUI is actually
nice-looking so so I'm attaching this
binary into a debugger and I'm running
virtual protect on it by the way how am
i doing in time so basically we're
attaching a debugger in here attaching a
breakpoint on virtual protect and
running the executable and it hit
virtual protect was not in the imports
list but it hit I see it how is this
happening we check that will answer how
is it happening later right now we
actually know that virtual protect is
doing is reserving a section of memory
with er w ER w means execute read write
a paint program has just used virtual
protect on an import that's not listed
it's hidden and it's mapped out a
section of memory with er W execute
read/write so if you ask me this is
happening because it's trying to unpack
the binary theory number one was correct
we know how it's working right now we
know the debugger is actually present
and it's we know that the virtual
protect is present and it is mapping a
section of memory with execute
read/write we can go on we may be
available to actually get the decryption
keys which this might be helpful for
anybody who fell for this
so we attach another breakpoint set BBX
crypt encrypt and decrypt encrypted
scription and it hits again the binary
is being unpacked
through a custom Packer not listed not
known not upx not something that any of
the three tools that I ran were able to
figure it out and it just hit two
imports not listed and I just hit script
encrypt we will be able to if we
actually see what's the section of
memory that's being decrypted right and
not decrypted the section of memory
that's being used that is coming from
Krypton crypt it's here all four two
three eight the entire oh four two three
zero memory section is the section that
was unpacked
it's the erw section and I see right
here MZ what does MZ mean folks exactly
executable M G stands for mr. marks
Barsky if I'm saying his name right he's
the creator of PE he's the creator of
the executable file just kudos to him
because he actually from what I heard
that a lot of lawsuits because every
time somebody say sees an MZ they call
him and they say oh my god you just
created a malware all right so we just
proved the two Theory's correct and we
were able to extract after we took this
executable read write section of memory
we were able to go ahead and see the
entire real binary the unpacked binary
which does have and this is the name of
the unpacked binary dumped bin this
executable readwrite section of memory
it's actually a small PE file it's a
small executable and we unpacked it and
we did see cryptographic imports right
here and strings we didn't even have to
go through PE studio crypt encrypt crypt
acquire context script derive key
everything in here destroy key which is
not so good for the people who actually
just cut their files encrypted so you're
kind of like locking the key and then
just destroying it so that's not funny
but it's doing a request and it is
sending a small payload that I'm just
assuming here contains the encryption
keys or not you know the attacker could
be just sending encrypted blob of data
that doesn't have anything you send
money to him and then he's like help
I don't have a case oh you have the kid
so and this is more or less the entire
analysis that we need to continue that's
the a full-circle
static analysis dynamic analysis we know
the properties we know everything what's
happening right now and further analysis
if you continue going through this thing
with ida pro or rad re or something
which by the way if you notice i still
haven't used i did more or less
everything with just using a debugger
you don't need to know assembly to do
malware analysis that's something
important it's good that you know it's
necessary that you know it but it's not
hundred-percent required you can still
know what you need to do if you know how
to use the tooling and you know how to
use the methodology behind it as we said
before surgical approach i think i'm
closing in on time so um more or less
done that's the conclusion and what i
want to take out of this is that if
you're a starting malware analyst or you
just are interested with this thing go
and take a small malware from the zoo
maybe the github repo that i mention or
from anywhere you want from your friends
honeypot and try to analyze it try to
see how it goes this one was a little
bit complex actually this one will has a
custom Packer not every binaries has a
custom Packer that's pretty unique thing
actually pretty hard process to write
your own alpha scalar and a packer you
can go ahead and do it put it on a
virtual machine connected through an
analysis machine run the tools that we
just saw fake DNS and I netsim see the
requests that are going in and out and
maybe you can actually know what is
happening the entire walk through the
entire cycle and you'll be able to at
least write a report and say oh this
malware does one two three because of
this imports because of that packer
because of this and that and you will be
able if you're working for an IP as
you'll be able to extract signatures
maybe you can put it into your networks
IPS so that it can detect such a thing
and thank you so much for listening
thank you so much of loss oh I bet we
have some questions here's the first one
please the third you know left it so
thank you for first of all for the
wonderful presentation and very
interesting so when the malware no you
caught it you missed it and it encrypted
all your files yes
so they exist also the descriptors of
the old one CS of the old malware's I
didn't understand I'm sorry so when your
information is encrypted yes and you
cannot decrypt it without a key but as I
know they exist some descriptors for
malware that were used before yes
they're good people to think is what
this malware does is that it's
encrypting it with RSA and a yes with
that from what I understand are not a
cryptographer but you need the
decryption key for that yes for such a
thing there are the right equation is
the Decrypter that exists so probably
they have the key yes
depends on the malware if the malware
generates a random key because of it I
asked so it generates a random key yes
further analysis could show you that
there is a hard-coded encryption key and
there then there will be a decryption
key that's also static and constant
across all but it could be random I
actually didn't do enough analysis on
this one to know if it's random or just
a static one mm-hm okay thank you very
much
so we have a mic there okay so you
alright so yes in your opinion what
makes a malware almost impossible or
actually impossible to reverse
impossible to reverse yes I don't when
you're attaching a debugger to um any
binary you're entering God mode right
now
you're basically can do anything that
you want you can have the binary execute
a Swiss that never even existed in the
codebase I think the only limitation is
your knowledge you should be able to
understand the enough imports and the
libraries and you will you will be able
without question to do much of anything
that you want that's why a lot of real
malware's follow multiple layers of
obfuscation it will give sometimes a
fake sense of conclusion it's like oh
this is the end of the malware no no
keep looking for there maybe there is an
encrypted binary that's actually doing
the real work so in my opinion no there
isn't any limitation that anybody can
come up with that could stop an analyst
from concluding the analysis so thank
you for you know first if you want let's
go ahead okay so you spoke about how you
importing the encrypt decrypt function
could be generally custom-made as
opposed to actually doing it where it
would be blatant have you ever had cases
where it would be so custom that it
would generally bypass most analysts
analysis and it would be really hard to
detect because it would seem like a
genuine I will tell you that I haven't
caught something that is just bypassing
any analyst because usually if you're
following the proper pathways of the
execution of the binary you will be able
to know something the thing is this is
more like a road stop the crypt encrypt
we know the name of the road stop if
you're like going from I don't know like
through Europe you're going to stop
through a city or one city or something
you can just go into a null space and
you will have to you will have to stop
into some road signs and if somebody is
trying to
tract you he will follow those road
signs there is a possibility that it
could be a custom function I am one time
wrote a CTF just for a small meter that
used an XOR basically and it's XOR in
width
I believe it was Oh X and not dead beef
it was like something something cute
with hexadecimal characters and it was
just horrible made by me it was in win
main and in that CTF only like five
people out of 30 were able to get it
they really could not understand that it
was as simple as an XOR there is nothing
to it it's not Krypton crib there is
nothing in there and they finished the
entire thing but three different ways
but nobody got the decryption keys they
were able to decrypt everything else but
they didn't get the decryption key just
because it was so simple so you can make
your own custom functions and it is very
much possible it's very much out there
but in my way if you're just going
through a theory out there alright okay
so it's a good tool light from so either
is disassembler it's one of the most
famous disassemblers it's one of the
most expensive this assemblers - so it
is what it does is static code analysis
that it's basically dekum disassembling
your code your binary code into assembly
language into machine language and
that's something very ok but the thing
is all over I did right now I try to
avoid using that because the assembly if
you've ever read it it's very very hard
to understand and it's usually for
everybody who wants to start out you can
see it like a programmer what is
happening in the
that's very good but so you can see the
function that I imported you can run it
with a do different kind of attach
extended I hear you
so radar a is another disassembler it
also has pseudocode generation
hopper another this assembler it also
has it it's very good that you can read
C code but in my opinion if you want to
throw if you want to follow a mess
Adamas article approach it's better not
to look at code it's better to see her
eyes what the app is doing what the
binary is doing and try to follow the
tracing and thereby executing the code
not by trying to look at the analysis if
I was writing an office cater to deter
an analyst from doing their job I will
throw flashes in the middle of the code
flash is basically trying to do getting
some factorization for for whatever for
no purpose just to throw away the
analyst so in my opinion don't look at
the assembly don't look at the source
code even if you have something like I
don't follow something like this dynamic
analysis execute it and see what's the
input and output and then maybe after
that you can run it for a debugger and
afterwards if you really want to know
what's happening go for either do the
pseudocode summary which in my opinion
is amazing it's really good and it's not
all the time accurate but it's very good
and then afterwards you can have a more
conclusive opinion but the first
approach is to always follow a dynamic
analysis approach that's my opinion okay
thank you of course okay thank you so
much think he'll do us so if you have
other questions please approach of the
login break right apples
[Applause]