well hello my name is John Constantine
and from born in Romania I think it's my
third time here at deaf camp but my
first time on stage so I might get a bit
nervous
maybe my jokes won't won't appear as
funny as they should be but now that I
have my pointer I'm going to hopefully
not bore you for the next 45 minutes
talking about advanced persistent
threats complex threats and machine
learning I'm going to do my best not to
pronounce the words artificial and
intelligence in the same phrase during
the next 45 minutes I'm going to answer
three important questions the real
questions the first one which James Bond
movie is the best the second one how
long does it take for for mankind to get
from Earth to Mars just a one-way trip
and the third question is a bit
technical we're gonna get there all
joking aside my presentation starts with
the big question how do you go about
finding a needle in the haystack this is
actually a funny quote from a superhero
movie and the answer is pretty basic you
bring a magnet and what are what are our
haystacks a huge amount of data this is
our current haystack we are generating
large large amounts of data we are
generating large metrics logs bits and
stuff like that we are trying to process
that we are trying to process them we
are trying to find threats that might be
dormant hidden somewhere in that huge
data set and we are kind of having a
hard time doing this on today's agenda
I'm going to go through what are complex
threats I'm not going to stress this
point necessarily I'm assuming that most
of you guys are already familiar with a
PT's I'm going to talk about context and
the post hash
context the post signature context what
do our machines or technology need to go
beyond detecting threats detecting you
know signature signature events and of
course one answer might be machine
learning I'm going to give you a sneak
peek just a sneak peek a very high-level
overview what we're doing back at orange
in using some advanced algorithms to
detect some very advanced threat and
hopefully maybe next year at that DEFCON
10 I'm going to also present you a demo
and of course I'm going to answer that
last question I was saving for for the
for the final slide are we trying to
replace our CMS are we trying to build
another open-source iam well spoiler no
we're not so let's go ahead with complex
threats advanced and complex threats you
all know them y'all heard about them
they use sophisticated zero-days they
use cloaking and stealth and stealthy
mechanism together in order to gain a
foothold a stronghold in your network
and to spread to move laterally they are
persistent as the name implies they do a
low and slow approach to attacks they
gather ground they gather information
they move laterally they actually trade
data sometimes they even break things as
in some recent cases with VPN filter and
such and very important they are task
specific rather than opportunistic keep
in mind that these strats are designed
from the get-go from the Ground Zero
from the from the zero point to be as
complex to detect and as complex you
operate as they can be they are not your
simple your average malware that you
know one antivirus anti-malware solution
just opens up a beacon like red bulb
somewhere here you get a virus no these
are threats these are complex software
that are built with in some cases they
are backed by state nations you know by
intelligence agencies by companies with
which can
you know put forward a huge effort in
designing software and they are highly
dependent on social engineering on
surveillance and supply chain
compromised what can we do to at least
have a chance in detecting this kind of
threats other than you know building a
huge wall of IPs and firewalls and
things like that well in order to in
order to detect an apt you gotta know
what are the stages of the inner
workings and this warm thing here which
reminds me of the game snake on the
Nokia all Nokia phones it's actually
self-explanatory
you have six or maybe seven stages that
one such advanced threat may act may use
in order to in order to complete their
mission and you have your initial
compromise using either social media or
phishing emails which is very common or
in some cases infected storage devices
you have your foothold establishment you
know where the the malware the software
creates a controllable tunnel stealthy
tunnel to your control server to a c2
server you have some form of
reconnaissance the thing looks around
finds other vulnerable systems you know
just Maps out the surroundings and then
it moves laterally and this is the bad
this is the really bad thing it does you
know it uses privilege escalation it
uses uses some form of exploits in some
cases zero-days exploits things that
cannot be detected as easily with
traditional methods it does keep a low
profile we're going to see in a couple
of slides that in some cases you have a
PT's that are laying dormant for years
on end in networks like very high
profile cases or they keep doing the bad
thing that they are supposed to do for
two or three years
and in final they complete their me dump
their mission the extra state data they
break stuff and sometimes they do keep a
back door open maybe they want to you
know return to the scene of the crime
according to a Trend Micro survey which
was if I remember correctly based on
maybe 2000 or something answers from
small medium and large companies alike
these are some of the technical controls
that most companies are using to protect
against a PT's specifically I mean I
entered this slide here in my
presentation just to give you an
overview on the wide spectrum of
technical measures that companies are
trying to use in order to prevent such
infections such threats nobody knows for
sure what to do nobody has an catch-all
answer like you know you should use this
this solution this technology from this
vendor or you should use this method in
order to be safe or at least be at a
reasonable level of safety against such
complex complex threats some are using
antivirus and anti-malware specifically
to protect against apts others are
looking at their mobile endpoints with
mobile device management and mobile
security gateways and some of them most
of them actually are relying on that
traditional you know border where
enforced firewalls new generation
firewalls IPS is ideas hoping that maybe
they could catch a break if you know
somebody try to try to sneak in their
networks and 64 percent of them are
trying to use some form of log
correlation log aggregation or cm tool
to detect something more than just your
average run-of-the-mill malware
there's challenges in mitigation and
this is the probably the main reason
that people are kind of holding back on
investing in in cutting-edge solutions
because the you know they're possibly
waiting for the for the for the
playfield level you have your malware
variety there are literally hundreds of
millions I'm aware of malware species
and Marvel marvel value variations that
were actually let loose in the wild just
back in 2017 that's hundreds of millions
you know you have traditional security
that can be ineffective in this cases
you you you don't necessarily have to
expect you rely on your firewall to
detect
something that was cooked up in a
Chinese laboratory just two weeks ago
using a zero-day that is net from I
don't know network chips that producer
back in Taiwan you simply cannot rely on
your fire off a debt and Loganlea
analysis and low correlation has its
limits because if you don't provide
enough context to log files or to log
data well log data remains just that a
huge index a huge data database of
events that you can browse to and maybe
you can build a couple of correlations
back and forward but you don't get the
big picture you're not seeing the trail
maybe you're just seeing the breadcrumbs
and there's of course a lot of noise is
extremely hard to separate legitimate
traffic from bad traffic in our complex
large networks nowadays you are a
telecommunications operator we are if
I'm not mistaken we are boasting maybe
11 million customers you can imagine the
the level the the sheer volume of
traffic that we might want to inspect
for malware for threats using
traditional security that is simply not
going to work
and this this gets us to my first
question if I'm not mistaking how long
does it take for men to fly from Earth
to Mars it's 160 to 180 days and that's
exactly how much it takes for an average
company to detect an apt maybe you can
go back and look at your activity for
the past six months things you work you
work at at your job documents you you
know you redacted you you create it code
your rhythm and think that somewhere in
your network there's this thing staying
there like lying dormant that
exfiltrated every bit of information
that you created on your workstation on
your file servers and you simply don't
even have a clue that this is happening
because it takes up to 39 days to
mitigate such trade as such such threats
and 43 days to recover to remediate this
is bad I know it looks bad because it is
bad and this is just a statistic the
statistic done by the the Ponemon
Institute for the first six months of
2018 and there you have it your
obligatory time line slide and this
answers to my first question actually my
second question about the James Bond
movie I know most of you are familiar
with this most of you have seen this
most of you some of you have even worked
with this you have your moonlight maze
the first apt that I for one know about
you have some guys in Russia breaks in
the system from Pentagon and NASA and
the US Department of Defense and they
actually trade thousands of documents
for nearly two years two years in a row
then you have title reign with various
Chinese sources attacking some large
defense contractors you know the people
that build rockets and stuff
and you have your ghost net your stuxnet
you know with the Iranians and the nukes
your RSA attack where you know Adobe
Flash and phishing email equals love
and then in 2018 you have your
garden-variety VPN filter the things
that actually the thing that actually
infects your router and god knows what
it can do with it because it's modular
you can update it on the fly if you
control it what this slide and what this
timeline is about well it's about the
best spy movie that I've ever have ever
seen
you got everything from Chinese hackers
and Russian hackers breaking into the
Pentagon you have nukes and you have
state of the art technology and malware
there you have it
a PT's so solutions you can go about and
do pretty much everything and you should
do everything in well left side of the
slide you can do proactive security can
do bug bounty programs you can do trade
hunting and I encourage it you can do of
course threat intelligence with open
source intelligence human intelligence
and social media intelligence but the
thing that you gotta take from these
activities is that you gotta provide
context you have to provide context to
your machines to your traditional
security in order to detect a stealthy
presence
so maybe machine learning is the
solution I don't know we'll see stands
for the University and the University of
Washington have two definitions for
machine learning I personally like them
because they are kind of complete there
they run full circle Stanford University
says that machine learning is the
science of getting computers to act
without being explicitly programmed
while the University of Washington says
that machine learning is our algorithms
that can figure out how to perform
important tasks by generalizing from
examples this is the two definitions and
this is the two strong points that we
are building our platform that we are
going to preview in a sneaky
in the several future slides
what does machine learning for
cybersecurity what does it do what is it
good for well it allows you to learn
from available data by using
representation evaluation optimization
you know it allows you to train your
machines to act by creating a baseline
and seeing observing in time in a
timeline how specific input go beyond
above or below that baseline it allows
you to find anomalies and by identifying
anomalies you actually stand a chance
stand a chance of finding stealthy
hidden things in your networks in your
data in your information and of course
if you want to go the full route though
full Skynet Robocop you can let it act
upon finding you can automate your
detection and mitigation what is the
available data that you can work with
and we are actually working working with
in in our test machine learning
cybersecurity threat detection threat
intelligence platform well you have an
active network equipment noisy things
you know like route or switches printers
everything ap is AP controllers they all
generate tons of data you have your
endpoints you have your fixed end points
you have your laptops you have your
mobile devices you can get metrics like
Oh s logs Hardware lock security logs
and everything in between and you have
your applications you have your
applications that can run both the
client and server you have your email
clients you have web browsers your VPN
clients there are they come in all
shapes and sizes they run on anything
from ms windows to iOS they all generate
information they all generate logs they
all can tell you something about what's
going on inside them
you have your security products and you
have some other you might just have some
other cool stuff in your networks as we
do because we are a large telco and we
generate huge huge amount of data from
very specific very business specific
equipment and this brings us to our
sneak peak which is going to be very
brief and very high-level at this
platform that we are currently
developing with leverage which leverages
every data source that I've mentioned in
the previous slide and add something to
the mix we can add our info regarding
cellular data don't worry this is highly
on on mice we really don't need to know
which of your cell phones did what and
who are you but we need to we are maybe
interested in finding out in figuring
out some trends you have your Wi-Fi data
because we operate a large Wi-Fi network
both for consumers and business
customers we have some security data
that we can generate from business
internet security which is our which is
our managed security service with
sensors deployed all over the country
and in the in the opening presentation
earlier this morning
Kristy showed you threatening one of our
front ends to that platform and we added
some fields some threat Intel feeds we
are interesting and ingesting everything
from critical stack to apt nodes
children bandulus apt nodes which is a
terrific repository I recommend you go
ahead and use it a sec species domains
thread mine and thread crowd Carol
virustotal vx7 we even we even try to
ingest further reports from our pen
tests we run both internally and
externally we use sacra parent senses
and rapid7 open data for vulnerability
scans
and we put all these data together in
this in this infrastructure in this
complex infrastructure that uses some
algorithms to tell us in its current
form and actually to to learn to train
our algorithms to detect you know your
next big apt we of course love the
Alexus at the elastic stack and we are
using it we love cough cough we love
logstash
of course elastic and keep on it
provides us with great flexibility it
provides us with great scalability and
we are actually thinking of and doing it
we are writing our own filters around
modules for it this is a very quick
overview over architecture we have
everything from the data collection to
one end to one under the pipeline to
event viewing and custom dashboard
reporting which is the elastic servers
for elastic search servers for our ml
algorithms and analytics and analytics
algorithms and we do offer some form of
long terms a long term storage
you know Hadoop service just to you know
trace back in case we missed something
but right there in your lower left side
of the screen we have someone we have
some int things that are happening and
that that's of course our open source
intelligence and human intelligence and
social media intelligence we are
ingesting tons tons of data in this
pipeline and in other pipelines from the
sources I've mentioned earlier in the
previous slide
we are going about machine learning in
both in two ways on the supervised size
with supervised the algorithms that
allows you to train your machines with
training data with with data sets that
you know teach the algorithms how to
actually act upon a finding and on the
unsupervised size when we have to where
we have to rely on some more advanced
methods of you know complexity the
reduction and clustering in order to
teach our machines what to do in case
things happen right there in the middle
that's our sweet spot because we are
trying to use both techniques some in
some cases we are using supervised ml
for things like Marvel detection because
it works out great you just show you
just throw some sample data some some
data sets at it and it just shows that
way and we are using unsupervised
machine learning for things that are
more you know subtle like text mining
and data mining from Twitter and forums
and even dark web things this is a very
quick overview and representation of the
algorithms as we as we are currently
implementing them
you have your run-of-the-mill use cases
for the supervised machine learning and
that is spam detection and moriah
malware ID and of course going above or
below the baseline all our algorithms
can help us detect some anomalies that
we can act upon and you know investigate
further on the unsupervised size we are
using clustering and Association rule
learning and as I said before as I
mentioned before dimensionality
reduction in order to classify entities
in order to detect anomalies and in
order to explore it to learn from
available data and one thing that this
architecture allows us is to use the
output of one a chain of
algorithms as an input for the other if
if we go about entity classification
from our unsupervised ml algorithms we
can use in some cases of course that
output in order to feed the input of our
supervised ml algorithm we are of course
relying on text mining this is not new
this has been done before and you have
great commercial solutions like
synthetics and B text that are doing it
for sentiment sentiment analysis we are
trying to read tweets and interpret them
in the context that they been written
for both for both alerting because you
know that is supposed to be the main
reason you agreed to it and you are on
Twitter just know things like rapidly in
your face and in order to detect more
subtle connections between some mentions
some verbs and nouns and some action
that we are we are already seeing in our
networks it's a bit obfuscated for me to
try to explain how this works because we
are actually in the process of building
it but our expected outcome the expected
results we are actually looking forward
to to gain is that our machine can get a
bit of a contextual timeline about what
has happened in our network relative to
what people are talking about nowadays
today and circling back to a PT's well
I mentioned that there are maybe six or
seven stages that complex threats a
complex threat uses in order to complete
admissions its mission and two of them
are establishing the foothold in your
network in your infrastructure and
lateral movement and I've just picked
the two because they are of course the
most important to show you how we are
designing our pipeline the pipeline in
our ad stack to gain some new knowledge
gained some new information about the
activity going on there
we are gathering logs of course in
traffic dams if does necessarily we are
working with noise removal to exclude
legitimate traffic this is supervised
machine learning for one part so we
actually thought our machines what is
good traffic we already labeled get
traffic like business legitimate traffic
that we know to a certain degree that it
is secured we are interrogating of
course your run-of-the-mill IOC I OC
repositories and we ingest data about
non malware and known malware domains
because in establishing a foothold the
few main entry points in a network are
phishing emails and social media so we
are keen on looking very very very in
detail in that and we are looking for
anomalies like large amounts of requests
single request requests during the
nineteen night I'm where most of our
colleagues are not working you know
large DNS queries why not because Marvel
can be noisy and of course the output of
this pipeline is an alert a report maybe
and a very very nice you know red bulb
opening up in a cube on a dashboard on
lateral movement
this is the this is actually a longer
story because we are using we are using
supervised machine learning in to some
extent here
and we actually got to the part where we
had to train our algorithms algorithms
to detect some kind of activity
regarding the tools that most of your
attackers might use to move laterally in
a Microsoft domain because most of our
security domains are actually Microsoft
and we use Windows like most of your
companies do for business for business
uses of course and you have your you
know everybody knows them your PSX IQR
DP or Mimi cats with silver bullets and
gold bullets your BW Tampax your time
stamp these tools they all create some
form of some form of footprint they live
some form of crumbs you know be it in in
the windows logs bit in the application
folder that they are running in we got
the point that we analyze the logs and
attribute and actually stitch together
specific event IDs and specific
attribute changes to some kind of
activity that we decided that it can be
it can consider a constitutive lateral
movement we literally just you know
start ApS exact we watch the output and
we said ok I want to move from this that
this so I gotta escalate the privileges
like this and if I was successful if if
I was successful in doing that I just
collected the output throw it to the ml
algorithm and let it decide for itself
if my next try is going to be was
actually successful or not we got to
some pretty nice success rates maybe in
the 95 percentile by doing this and we
are kind of certain that if we continue
to improve our algorithms and our data
sets the data sets that were using to
train the machines we can go up to 99%
in detecting specifically detecting
lateral movement
with the use of some of the tools in my
slide and we have some output it's a
stack and on top of the stack you have
keep on keep on is pretty nice right you
have your browser and you have your pie
charts and everything I mean it's very
manual friendly we can configure
dashboards to show both live data and
statistic data analytics you have some
very very nice alerting capabilities
that can both alert operators and can
interface via api's with other machines
such as firewalls if we want to go the
full circle and automate detection
information and of course you have the
reporting capabilities this is what we
are working with this is actually what
we some of the things we wanted from the
get-go when we began working on this -
this kind of stack this usage for a
large stack and we are kind of pleased
with it and this brings us to our final
question I told you there are three
questions and this is the final one are
we building yet another open source cm
no we are not we are very satisfied with
what we have as I'm sure you guys are
with your CMS we are not looking into
mitigation we are not mostly looking
into compliance we don't want to build a
machine that tells us see for network is
I don't know some percent iso 2027 one
compliant we are not into that we're
just trying to teach our machines some
new tricks we are trying to go beyond
just seeing the breadcrumbs but we are
trying to see the entire trail and maybe
this machine learn anything with will
help us we had some we had some
references in the past with other with
some researchers in academia especially
building things like this but
unfortunately they didn't had the
require share volume of data to train
there
algorithms I mean they're the success of
the rate of detection and the success of
their stacks of their machines well was
limited by the lack of data of real
valuable data not just that statistical
data not dummy data not generated
traffic from a traffic generator and we
have that and in closing some nice stats
again from upon Iman survey conducted in
the first half of this year it says that
companies using machine learning to
detect threats can save up to 2.5
million dollars in operating costs and
that 60% of them in 60% of those
companies using such mechanism can
improve the productivity or their
security their security people because
the security people actually have the
time and to you know to dedicate to
other projects and of course in nearly
70% of cases you get more speed you get
a quicker response time those 170 days
that an average company needs to detect
an apt actually gets down and sixty
percent of them have the respondents
stated that machine learning identified
their application security
vulnerabilities well this was it for my
presentation if you have any question
please I'm here
thank you for the great presentation
anyone we're going to take questions now
so as you know please raise your hand
and yeah let's go for it
I thank you for a great presentation I
was wondering if this platform that
you're developing are you developing for
a custom use or do you plan to provide
it as a service and we would be
dependent on your infrastructure that
you have right now for now we are just
developing it internally we are going to
test it internally because some of the
data we are going to ingest in the
platform is internal data from our
internal networks not the client network
but you know our business offices
networks what maybe maybe I don't know
in the future we can see if this is an
option yet thank you we have a question
there in the back please no because our
security guys do a great job at securing
our networks and another question was
you are are you using a Dimitra attract
matrix in footprinting or are you
simulating specific attacks in order to
learn to - we are simulating specific
okay next one get back to how does your
machine learning algorithm
work with zero days well you know we
didn't have a chance to work with a zero
day per se we worked with some things
that were already classified and labeled
that you know things that were zero days
a couple of days back
so we already knew the expected output
as I said before we didn't get to
actually catch something new we just
landed on we just you know spread our
nets but we didn't catch anything new
that's a you know a honeypot job but
with high profile a PT's that use zero
days if that's your question
well actually the detecting rate as I
mentioned in a slide before was
somewhere around 95 percent one question
from my side yeah
the time
are you using the machine learning
capability within elasticsearch or are
using something custom-built and if you
are using bility within elasticsearch
how are you handling labeling of non
numerical data we are actually using
both the the capabilities of electives
elasticsearch and some custom-built
solution from one of our partners well
about numeric data I'm going to get back
to you on that I don't have the answer
right now but I'm definitely going to
exchange some cards and I'm going to get
back to you on that
ok we have time for a few more questions
so please okay right over there please
wait for the mic so we can all hear you
okay about machine learning are you
using statistical models or DNS that's
one and did you try to computer your f1
score your you know you know what a
score is yeah we are actually using some
statistical models because we we have to
you know start from somewhere and we are
kind of new to this of course it's
something that we are working on we are
we are not at the point where we get
our own models but maybe in time okay
time for two more questions hello
and that's the secret sauce but I'm sure
that you use some public actually a
partial disclosure is that we are
working very close with some
collaborators collaborators of ours that
are helping us develop developing such
algorithms they are built for us for us
from scratch because as I've mentioned
before what we are trying to train our
machines using our real-life data thank
you last question
hello thank you for the presentation I
wanted to ask you when you built your
machine learning models do you see use a
specific technology such as Python or
Scala or do you have a specific software
to build your models they are built in a
specific custom software
okay can you tell the name no no okay
I'm not trying I'm not trying to be
secretive on purpose it's just that this
is the thing that we are actually
developing we are very invested in
seeing this get from you know a hobby
for a couple of guys in a innovation
department back at orange is something
that we can rely on upon finding a PT's
and we can we can I can maybe tell you
more about about it without going into
the specific after this presentation
awesome thank you so much you're on it
was great having you on stage
[Applause]