my talk is going to be super packed
about like a topic that I think it is
relevant in today's news and I'll try to
go as fast as possible through all of
this stuff hopefully it's gonna be
interesting for you and I really really
hope I'm not gonna be that late so I'm
really sorry for the organizers about
that so let's go you might have you
might have you might know that this
Monday there was like an interesting
interesting day it was Guy Fawkes night
and what makes this um Guy Fawkes night
event really interesting is that they
tried to blow up the parliamentary well
it was a there was a gang of guys and
the most famous one was Guy Fawkes and
his the third is the one the third to
the right and basically he he tried to
bring up the Parliament and watch it not
so known about this guy is that he
almost has he almost he also said a
famous quote and he said that who owns
the information owns the world and we're
gonna get back to this one a little bit
later so my name is Dan Demeter I
graduated from Imperial College almost
four years ago since then I'm a security
researcher at Kaspersky Lab and you
might know as the guy who developed the
open source distributed the yarra
scanner Clara which my company Kaspersky
Lab we open sourced it this year so
that's a little bit about myself a
little bit about a lot of my team we are
called global research and analysis team
and basically we are focused on highly
advanced attacks we have been founded
like almost 10 years ago this year we
celebrated our tenth anniversary and
since then we are tasked with finding
and fighting against advanced attacks
for again like for advanced like finding
the advanced attacks against banks
governments power plants and everything
that is like critical infrastructure and
so on but
you know I would like to start asking a
question like if if we Google search war
and we'll search for images of war on
Google you might actually find out this
kind of stuff or this stuff you might
find like which is looks pretty normal
you know it seems pretty normal for like
word images and this is what we we know
and this is what we expect to find when
we were searching for war on Google what
about if we searching for the info war
so you might have heard a bit about in
for but Google definitely didn't hear
about info war or at least this is the
this is Google's definition of info war
and it's kind of like a silly silly
stuff like for example this grenade with
some keyboard keys and there's like this
plane dropping some course or I don't
know like my own some cursors here right
you know it's not that the relevant and
it actually doesn't make sense you know
for for all of us but then actually
instead in for might look like this so
it might happen around us it might
happen right now and it's all around us
it could possibly all around us it can
be like actually it might be happening
at the Deaf game right now and people
don't realize it it's like really close
to us and I think this is very important
because in for it's not something that
people are actually taking care of or
like carrying that much about this one
so okay you might ask yourself fine
if the in for is here what's next well
we defined we defined in for within
Kaspersky Lab having three components
and those three components are the cyber
espionage cyber sabotage and must
subpoena manipulation where two
components are using malware the cyber
espionage and sabotage whereas those two
components are using malware the third
one is actually mass opinion
manipulation and we are pretty good in
those two items but on the third one
actually we're not so good we're not
doing so good
I said okay fine I would like to
research this topic and I like to I like
to present you my findings but before we
do that before we go to the present we
have to go a little bit in the past we
have to understand why and way when why
and how some of the things happened so
I'm not gonna go like super in-depth
like from the ancient Rome or like from
the ancient ancient Syria or whatever
but instead we're gonna go a little bit
and we're going to focus on the Cold War
period and I would like to ask if you
know who this guy is and I'm not talking
about the dead guy on the left
I'm talking about the guy in the middle
anybody knows who this guy is
okay what about this one
like he's the same guy cool so you only
hype a choppa and I think it wasn't
there wasn't any better introduction to
my presentation here in Bucharest rather
than talking about you only hyper
chopper which is was one of the Romanian
spies who defected to America and he
still alive and basically he wrote a lot
of information about he wrote some books
about disinformation and his other book
is called the red horizons so if you
haven't read his books
I actually recommend you reading those
ones I didn't read read horizons yet so
I would like to read it as well I just
skimmed it a bit but he basically said
something and he scratched the surface
of what we nowadays call desi format so
does he for Mattia by defined by this
fine gentleman here who was the director
of Department X Department X of the
Department of this information from the
East German on foreign intelligence so
this guy said that our friends in Moscow
they call it the same format yeah the
Americans are calling it active measures
and it's my favorite activity so Eastern
Germans were like very good at this
disinformation and we know it at all but
cheaper also said in his book that if
you're good at with this inform
you're good with anything you can get
away with anything I think this check
this is actually pretty pretty cool in
his book he also says that Stalin
himself coined this term of
disinformation which is actually itself
a disinformation and this is why because
he says that Stalin wanted to give it
like a more Latin root digital format
said this information which basically
comes from a French instead of giving it
giving it a Slavic root so the term
itself it's actually called this in form
it's actually this informing that the
term itself well honestly I'm not so
sold on this theory mostly because Papa
in his read horizons book he kind of
like didn't write like Allah all of
things were true for example he said
that the Ceausescu was everyday
Ceausescu was using a new suit suit and
then at the end of the day he was born
in that suit well historic sources tell
us that it that wasn't true so you know
i would i would take with a grain of
salt what was said in his book and of
course like put put yourself in his
shoes like he went the americans he he
like he should he must have written
something bad about about the Russians
okay so i would like to ask you some
some questions and you have to tell me
which of them you think are true so
first of all is like aids was created in
a lab the earth is flat
napoleon was like short who eat banana
clones and Einstein failed at maths who
believes that all of this all of these
statements are true ok who believes that
four of the statements are true what
what 3 what all three have like some
okay what about to have some more one
statement is true okay if some other no
none of these statements are true okay
so I'm sorry to dissapoint only one
statement is true and this one is that
we eat banana with cloned bananas
so actually it's a funny trivia is that
if there was a new bacteria new new
fungus that would affect the actual
banner at the actual strain of bananas
right now all of all of our banana
population population would be dead so
be careful with bananas well why did you
consider that the other statements were
also true well first of all there was
this myth of Napoleon was short but
actually when him his height was
measured it was measured in five feet
two inches which is indeed short but it
was French French feet it wasn't British
feet actually he was 1.7 so there's like
this slight difference between British
feet and French feet and he was like 1.7
like quite a tall I would I would say so
Einstein failed at maths also this one
this was debunked by Einstein himself
when they asked him like hey you know
did you fail at math because like people
are saying that then he was like no what
the heck like I knew I was like pretty
good when I was like 15 years old then I
was like I master different differential
and integral calculus back then and this
makes sense now because he was like a
genius he was ingenious genius in
physics and it doesn't make sense that
he failed math because math you need
maths for physics so all of this kind of
stuff are the core components of an
activity a mirror and if you don't know
Russian this means active active
measures and let's say let's see what
active measures actually mean and we see
here from from the Wikipedia source
active measures is a Soviet term for the
actual political warfare actually
collecting intelligence and producing
politically correct assessments and also
active measures range from media
manipulations to special actions
involving various degrees of violence so
basically this is this is one of the
definitions so if you if we look in our
research that was published last year by
the London School of Economics they also
define the fact that active measures can
include a combination of white gray and
black propaganda and then you might ask
mice you might ask me like hey Dan you
know what what is like white gray and
black propaganda well why propaganda
it's
it's information that comes from known
known sources so for example we might
have like a news outlet that is
spreading propaganda or we might have
like leaflets that are being dropped on
the battlefield this is like white
propaganda great black propaganda crumbs
comes from unknown sources and this is
more interesting you know because for
example you might have like for example
a radio stations that are supporting the
anti Soviet movement but actually those
radio stations are spreading propaganda
or spreading propaganda against against
Soviets but actually those those
stations are controlled by by Moscow I
controlled by the Russians and basically
what they do they tried to subvert they
try to delay the people they try to
force them to not have not be so
organized so basically it's a way to
dismantle groups it's a way to block
people to achieve their goal and of
course great propaganda it's like it's
more interesting because you know you
know the source
but you you're not you know you don't
know for a fact that it's working for a
government or a state direct so for
example when the Korean War happened
Russians
Russians started his talks or
conferences about world peace and those
conferences were actually looking good
at the beginning and they attracted a
lot of attention they attracted the
attention of like high high profile
persons like Pablo Picasso for example
he joined this movement but literally
they know that actually the main the
main purpose of those conferences was to
actually put the blame on the Americans
to make them look bad so basically you
present a good cause but actually you're
your motive is is bad intention so let's
see the cookbook of active measures and
again in their in their research we see
that you have like front organizations
agents of you
infiltrating media use fake stories and
use forgeries in order to promote your
hidden agenda and in order to be able to
make people act or believe as you want
so but this is pretty good this is
pretty good and then like let's have
some examples and I mentioned before
aids and then this this is actually a
controversy even now that aids was
human-made and I spoke with a lot of
medics and all of them told me that it's
current currently like they don't
believe that it's possible to produce
Aidid aids you know in a lab but rather
it was a mutation it was like the
another mutations that we actually we've
seen in our country as well so it that
was kind of a mutation and um there was
this document secret document that was
that was released and basically this
operation was called the Americans are
saying that this operation was called
the infection operation and basically
you can check you can check this report
by this guy Thomas and basically they're
saying when does this campaign start
when did this campaign start and we have
we have it here on the 17th of July 1983
there was a there was a paper published
in Pakistan saying aids may invade India
mystery disease caused by us experiments
they also continued insane I'm sorry
sorry I'm I'm not sure if you can see it
well they say AIDS is believed to be
result of the Pentagon experiments and
deposit then from that paper from
Pakistan it was then referenced by other
news media in the world and this
information spread along what's also
interesting is that by the 1980s this
new this new syndrome the AIDS syndrome
was not well known it didn't even have a
name it had a name two years later and
the Americans didn't actually know how
to handle that one it was pretty in
pretty new for for them at that time and
the Soviets actually managed to
find this moment and to take advantage
of this moment so this is pretty okay
nobody died from these fake news but
then you might actually have fake fatter
consequences so this is another this is
this is another example and basically in
1968 there was a paper that was a paper
that was called who's who in the CIA and
this paper was distributed in the East
German and basically what this paper
said in a nutshell this is the list of
CIA CIA agents and half of the half of
the names were were real half of the
names were fake well what happened two
years later a guy whose name was
identical similar to the list of the new
fake names that appeared in that list
was killed mostly because his name
appeared in that fake list so basically
here there was a terrorist who killed
him
furthermore there is another example of
an event that happened at Mecca
basically there was an explosion and a
lot of people were like killed and
basically the the Soviets said okay this
sounds like a good idea let's spread the
rumor a rumor they spread a rumor saying
that this plot was this explosion was
plotted by the Americans and Israelis
what happened next
I don't I'm sorry I don't think you can
see it the rumor sparked an attack by
this new Union the US Embassy was a
tectum a one American was kidnapped two
Pakistani employees died a marine corps
was shot and an American contractor has
been left to burn to death from a rumor
that was it like you went to somebody
and say okay that's a rumor and that's
it and then like all these people died
cool so of course in order to deploy
these techniques you need a lot of money
so how much money actually
well again the the publicly released
released paper on the one about AIDS
also says that I'm sorry also says that
in 98 is a conservative CIA estimates
puts the annual cost of Soviet active
measures at three billion dollars not
back in the 1980s per year which is
actually nine billion dollars in our
money right now due to inflation
every year so this is how much the
Russians were actually spending in order
to promote their agenda and to use these
active measures that's pretty impressive
but you know they were not the only ones
you know they were the more prep most
prominent but not the only ones the
Americans were actually doing the same
so this is like a stamp from the from
the second world war propaganda where
they were depicting Hitler as like this
monster and like you should fight with
your life the Nazi the Nazi threat and
basically it ISM this is the American
Way of doing active measures this is
like um an airborne leaflet propaganda
so basically it's a bomb you load it up
with propaganda and you drop it so it
doesn't do any damage but it just
spreads a lot of leaflet so this is this
is actually product like this was used
by the Americans but I think you might
actually know a better example of active
measures used by the Americans and I've
seen a lot of people who are like I
think old enough to have heard of Radio
Free Europe and we can see that from
again from from a CIA document that was
like released to the public this they
say here that this radio was actually
pretty pretty annoying the people people
like the authorities from the Eastern
Bloc so it's because of that they used
1500 jam jamming stations in order to
try to block it was a successful no
because actually this radio was still
broadcasting but it's actually an
interesting another interesting fact is
that in this in this document that was
sent from the American attache at the
western embassy to the sacred deputy
secretary of state and you consider link
here he basically says that it is
regretable that Radio Free Europe is
still entirely financed by the USA and
that the Europeans have failed to show
financial interest so basically he's
saying we're pulling all the money and
nobody else is putting the giving and
putting their money into this
project which is okay pretty which was
pretty okay but later he also says that
you know apart from the fact that the
German government grants the license for
the European broadcasting station there
is no reason why Radio Free Europe
should fail fall under German control so
basically in other words he's saying
that you know we want people to give us
money to put money into this project but
we don't want to give out control over
it we want to control it ourselves but
it would be better if other people other
states would actually put their money in
the bust in the in the basket as well if
you want to read more about the CI
operation and the Radio Free Europe this
is the book you want you should read and
it's pretty interesting okay so we
talked about Russia we talked about
American I'm really sorry like I there
was like there's a lot tens of other
states that we can talk about but I
think I shouldn't miss the opportunity
of talking about Romania so you know in
Romania
I wasn't born in the communist period so
I've heard so I've read also in the news
that they were like foo durations so
people were actually kind of starving it
was a kind of a hard period and
dehydration
you had like limited amount of food that
you can get you could get every month so
a food ration looks like this basically
it sells your name it's like how many
family members you have and how much
food did you buy every month the
interesting fact is that people were
actually trusting sign the scientific
community so everything that was like
science everything that was like
researchers they were trusted so
basically the Romanian government asks
some scientists to write this report
saying that it's healthy for grown up
men to only eat one kilogram of chicken
every month and this was actually
convenient because it was actually the
amount of of chicken that they received
during the every month so basically they
used scientific facts which of course
like you could eat a lot more chicken
than one kilogram they used the
scientific coming
to produce some facts that people
actually believed in order to justify
their own actions they own their own
government actions so you know this was
in the past so in the present it's a bit
different but not so much so let's look
at from this guy North Dublin he has
like an interesting YouTube video and he
basically discuss is the idea that
currently in the present we have access
to a lot of information and this is good
and bad at the same time we have access
to like tons of applications we have
instant notifications form on on our
mobile phones we receive our parking
ticket instantly we can download
everything almost instantly we want
everything that really fast fast fast
immediately I wanted I want to get
something I I want to I should get it
right now and he also said that because
of that our desire for quick answers may
overpower this the desire to be certain
of their validity in other words if
you're looking for something and it's
right there at an arm's length and you
get the result as fast as possible then
you might not be tempted to you might
not be tempted to actually fact check
that thing you might not willing to go
over the process of checking if that
fact is true or not to see if actually
that makes sense one or it doesn't make
sense and this is what fake news is all
about people not fact-checking their
other sources of course there are more
other subtle types of fake news like
remember grape about grape propaganda he
also presents in his video which is like
3 minute video so please do please watch
it it's it's amazing circular reporting
circular reporting you might have heard
about it basically says that we have a
publication a b c d and e publication a
a does like an original content
publishes something and then b b
references ACB and then d and c and so
on
well this is all ok or it's not ok min
from my point of view but
is all okay except when publication a
publish is something that is fake
if this publication a publishes the fake
news then the entire chain will actually
publish and reference fake news and the
problem is that if this chain is long
enough the actually news might become
true and this is the this is the problem
this is another problem because people
nowadays they actually tend to act
predictably if I can say so so for
example what are the three main reasons
why fake news are actually happening
well first of all because of tribalism
or partisanship and this is when this is
happens when you have a view and
somebody else comes with somebody else
with the same view as yours comes along
and you're more willing to accept his
his answers you're more willing to
accept his proposals if that person if
that person is similar to you and you're
more willing to reject or to not be
involved in a debate with a person that
has different views that you have and
this is very important basically it's
like I call it the laziness of people
you have to have debate with people with
different views than you have else
you're gonna be in a bubble and we're
actually there's like a lot of talks
about these bubbles nowadays
confirmation bias if you are if you are
sure or you are you know like if you're
sure of something and somebody else
comes and reinforces that confirms that
thing you're more you're more actually
more likely to have your own
confirmation reinforced so basically
this means that you're not willing to
talk to other people that have different
views you're actually gonna be accepting
people you're not gonna make friends
with people with the same views that you
have and of course the dangerous of the
banked ideas is another issue an idea
a fake news that stays long enough it
might become true so we have this we
have this example with the we have this
example with the vaccines there was one
paper 1998 that said vaccines cause
autism
it wasn't debunked at that specific
moment so it stayed on and on it caught
on and now we have this entire
anti-vaccine movement and you know the
rest so just from that paper which was
later proven to be false so it that
people is like totally bullocks but it
doesn't matter it's true because a lot
of time passed so you know another
approach of active measures and I find
it really interesting to look at the
Eurobarometer survey and this service
says that most of the citizens are happy
with their country being part of you and
then if you look at the percentage of
how many citizens are unhappy with their
country being part of you we can see
like UK which is the first twenty ten
twenty two percent of people in UK are
not happy about being part of you and
the second country is Romania actually
it is twenty first percent the third
country is Greece so you know this is
quite shocking but then this barometer
says that the threat of fake news and
disinformation in latvia sweden in
romania are highest so I think those two
factors are actually correlated with
each other also a study that was
developed by and was paid by Soros
foundation so basically they said that
may immediately teachers literacy
rankings are in a balconies are very low
and they said that the bulk the
balconies are most acceptable for fake
news and if if we look at the rankings
we can see like Romania Serbia Bulgaria
Montenegro Albania Turkey Macedonia all
of them are like super super low and I
think this is the correlation between
the fact that in Romania at least a lot
of fake news have gained traction and
the fact that we've seen movements of
raw exit
meena exit like also grease exit and
brakes it but the problem is that in
Romania the threat of fake news is more
it's like more real than ever and how do
we do like how do we combat this with
this facts well there's like this
tonight some night science journalism
program at MIT and basically they said
we conducted an overall one overall
survey of multiple publications asking
them do you fact check your your
publications or not and basically they
found out that a lot of them they don't
have they don't have a quality control
public person and furthermore only 1/3
of them actually had fact checkers and
researchers to do the fact-checking
before publishing other publications all
of them had like editors who were in
charge of doing that and 50% copy
editors for the people who actually
doing fact checks furthermore they were
paid like thirteen fifteen dollars
nineteen dollars and the average was
thirteen dollars per hour this is really
important because you know fact-checking
nowadays is the most important part of
journalistic investigation and not all
investigational journal a journalistic
process and if you don't have capable
people doing fact checks then you're
doing something wrong so lastly if we
add in this mix about active measures
fake news if we add bots and nowadays
occur in principles we have like we're
gonna get like a pretty good image and
you might have heard about the troll
factory it was all about in the news
like two weeks ago
Twitter published all the treats from
this troll Factory read read all the
article is pretty interesting this this
lady here Kate starboard basically his
she said in her research that there I
paid trolls sitting side by side someone
in st. Petersburg because that troll
factories inside Petersburg Heat were
courting each other so basically there's
this guy who infiltrated both opposition
groups that were like this is like it
this could be like Democrats and like
all other groups
or like it doesn't matter you basically
the idea is you have two groups of
people who are clashing a debating girl
with each other you infiltrate people in
both groups and then you start promoting
your agenda why because of tribalism and
confirmation bias people in this group
they see that you are actually doing the
same stuff there are they have to have
the same views and they're gonna
actually trust you same happens with the
people in this group but you're the same
person in both groups and then what
happens you might actually have accounts
that alike have like huge amounts of
followers like 100,000 I know you don't
you can see it here but it's like
100,000 followers who are actually been
proven to be part of this disinformation
campaign and you know this happens again
we also another way to do active
measures is to silence people so how can
you do that basically you block their
views if somebody is saying something
wrong about you you just block their
views so basically if you can't read
Romanian he says like the Facebook
account for this famous guy in Romania I
don't know if he's famous anymore was
blocked and you know it's pretty simple
if somebody's saying but something bad
about you you just block him you
silenced him and then he's gone no and
then this is pretty interesting let's
let's let's play a game
you know if I were to come to you on on
Street and say like I'll give you some
money would you go with your Facebook
account and report the page whatever
page I'm telling you would you do it so
raise your hand if you do it if you
report the Facebook pay for one euro
okay to yours for I go to you and say
like I give you four euros just report
it it doesn't affect you at all it takes
20 seconds ten euros would you report it
for 10 euros nobody yep 20 euros go if
you have a winner nice nice thank you
thank you let's round of applause let's
get round of applause for the way so 20
euros you go to the people and then you
actually get like you know report this
place your positive pay report this page
and then if you want to have like 100
people or 1000 people the costs are
$20,000 you know it's it's nothing
compared to the active measures course
of nine billion dollars
so that's it internet balkanization
please go my friend my dear friend
Stefan tenacity he's presenting about
internet balkanization today don't miss
his talk basically the idea is instead
of having like a global network where
proper checks can be implemented you you
create your own internet local local
networks for for example in Iran they
blocked the blocked telegram and they
created a new application called Sirach
in Russia instead of Facebook you have
Vkontakte have Google you have Yandex in
China you have other search engines and
so on so on so this relates to the fact
that if we don't consider these facts
and if we'd not taking this facts into
considerations more and more countries
will turn black and this is the
reporters without borders the freedom
press index for 2018 and I'm afraid that
more and more countries will turn turn
black and then lastly the last thing is
about privacy and then there's right
there are some definitions of privacy
but from my point of view privacy is the
state of being free from unwanted or
undue intrusion the freedom to be left
alone and this is very important you
might have the illusion of privacy you
might say oh my life is private but then
you're being you're being monitored all
your communication is being monitored so
that's something that you have to
protect against but then there are other
people who say nothing to hide argument
basically they say my life is not
important okay I don't have anything to
hide I'm giving out everything on a
clear plate here here take it then this
is a very very dangerous slope and then
you should actually be careful about
this because if you're willing to hand
out your data on a like a free platter
then we have like companies like
Cambridge analytical who are saying sure
I'll take this data I'll take as much
data as I want and then what do they do
with it
they process the data and they try to
target you with specific information in
order to manipulate you so don't give
out your data try to be as a sixties as
possible else these two events that I
never thought would happen happen and
completion rate guys kind of dead or
they change the name but there
other companies so advancing bollocks
I've never heard about this one before
my research and basically they say they
they disrupt the industry and set new
standards in behavioral research yeah
sure behavioral research I know what
this means you know it's like basically
Cambridge analytical so check out this
guy this AI they correctly predicted the
vote in America or yesterday so they
know their stuff
so it's privacy that is there anything
we can do I think there is there is hope
so I think the first thing we let me to
do user education the second thing we
need to do quality journalism so media
outlets they have to have fact checks
and I have to provide quality journalism
secondly user education because it all
starts from the users there was a report
that said that fake news was most spread
by people and not by BOTS so people
spread the most fake news and not bots
and you know there are other ways we
trained Ian's also create an interface
artificial intelligence but in Romania
it's not like we can actually start
creating this stuff so basic what you
can do you can donate to people who do
actually good quality journalism so if
you don't if you want to do it something
good if you want to combat fake news if
you want to fight it donate to these
guys these are like some really quality
guys that are doing amazing stuff and in
the end the information war is here and
the problem is that there was this ask
me anything reddit and then some which
is the roaming and search team and one
guy asked what are you gonna do if
Russia or somebody else will start a
campaign for to influence our elections
and they said it's not within our
capabilities and then my question is
whose capability within whose capability
is this one is it government is it
public institutions who should protect
against the threat of fake news and
maybe private companies like a spear ski
I don't know this is a question that I
should answer my my job is here to like
give you more info and maybe you can
decide for yourself but up until then
I'd like to take all the people to thank
all the people who helped me with this
research and by the way the
quote at the beginning was actually fake
news because the guy who said the
information this code is actually Nathan
Rothschild so take everything with a
grain of salt and try to combat fake
news sorry for being late
Thank You Tories that was so intense
thank you so much Dan