okay anyway we can start so today's
topic of interest is timing attacks
whether or not they're still practical
in regards to web applications and we're
seeing web modifications because timing
attacks are usually a methodologist art
in cryptography in the field of
cryptography and that's not pretty
common in web applications nowadays the
main reason for that or reasons will be
speaking about later on but for now this
is the topic and the things that we'll
be discussing here just doesn't work
obviously
so the topics that we're going to
discuss today is what is dumbing tab
because there are different types of
timing attacks but in the field of
cryptography it's quite different so in
this particular case we're going to go
over a specific case of timing attacks
we'll go over what our plan was for the
presentation what we did differently to
our researches because there's been a
lot of research in this field but
obviously most of them haven't been
carried out on web applications at all
they have been solely focused on
cryptography and this is because the
timing side channel is famous in that
field and it's not pretty common web
applications
there's too many jitter and a lot of
network latency that is pretty difficult
to figure out so this is not something
that is usually done on daily basis so
we'll talk about what we did differently
doing our researches what we achieve
because first of all we have a different
goal for the target but we ended up with
a total different scenario we'll be
generalizing timing attacks and we were
talking about how practical they are
which is the true meaning of the
presentation because as it seems as of
2018 they haven't been any exploits in
the wild for timing attacks and finally
we will be talking about a bit of misc
stuff about core subjects to attack what
is an acceptable solution because a lot
of people don't think that trading off
memory for execution time is a good idea
while this may be true to some extent
it's not entirely true so we'll be
discussing that as well so this is a
basic string comparison in PHP we've
taken PHP is an example but this pretty
much applies to almost any language out
there so the first thing we have here is
a pretty exaggerated example and blitzen
fight so you can just get the idea is
that we have a variable key as the only
5 checksum of any string actually
doesn't matter as long as it's an md5
it's 32 characters and what we have next
is an if check and if course we're
checking whether the gap parameter code
key is equal to the value of the
variable key which is essentially saying
that if
not different it is not equal then it
echoes out for better next case it
echoes us welcome so this is pretty
similar to any authentication with the
own exception that authentications tend
to be a lot more complex than this so
the problem here is that we have a
comparison and the comparison is not a
constant time algorithm which means that
depending on what we input it takes
different amount of time to process it
essentially this is giving out a lot of
information that shouldn't be exposed
otherwise for example imagine that you
are inputting your password in any form
of their authentication form and once
you've mistaken that imagine if the form
says well we have an error and that's on
position five your password is not wrong
it's not correct so this is the source
code for the is identical function
because PHP as we know is written in C
there's a source code of C of HP that's
in C and we have a simple switch case
which match up if the input string is a
string type first thing that we do on
one - is that we compare whether the
variables are the same this is different
from comparing values just about
variables as types and what is a
particular interest is the else clause
which is the thing that we're going to
exploit in this presentation we also
have a demo included at the end the
first thing that it does is it compares
the length of the strings if they are
different doesn't matter I mean we won't
continue further obviously if the length
is not the same strings are not the same
so next thing we do is that we compare
the bytes one byte at a time this is
done by passing three arguments to mem
CP the mem compare function and the
first part asks for the first variable
the second variable and their length
so this is what the source code of
memory camp areas actually it takes two
unsigned cars u1 and YouTube and indeed
rates over the entire string so it
counts it one byte at a time and it
basically says that if you're comparing
one byte at a time you want to index
that as an array and what you have right
now is you take each and every single
character and you compare it with its
corresponding from the following string
from the second string if they don't
match up an error is it don't or
otherwise says return false so this
exposes a lot of information but if we
can time it properly if we can extract
information from that it would be great
but unfortunately over the network is
pretty difficult to filter out jitter
and that's not something a lot of people
are eager to accomplish nowadays so this
is a pretty trivial example
those are nanoseconds but it's a pretty
exaggerated example has nothing to do
actually with real data it's just to
exemplify what timing attacks are and in
particular timing attacks that we're
going to discuss now so as we said we
have one key this year that is a
checksum an md5 that's hexadecimal and
32 characters of length and the first
thing we do is that we input any string
literally if we find let's say the first
four matches of the string and we get
different times but when you attempt to
uncover the fifth one and it's wrong yes
it does process it it does take some
time but it doesn't attempt to process
the sixth character because the fifth
one is wrong so it doesn't matter
whether the sixth seventh or eighth
s-sarah are correct even if one's wrong
the whole string is not equal to itself
and you can see from this example that
the 18 nanoseconds we compared three
letters three symbols two five and six
de the fourth one is incorrect it takes
time to process it but it doesn't
attempt to process the fifth one so this
means less time less execution time
which we can assume that the next
character is not correct the main idea
of this is to just try all possible
characters until we find one that it
takes the most time the one who takes
the most time means that is it the
correct character
how does another example that would show
what timing tacks are and particularly
ones we're going to discuss as you can
see again the times are different but
they are still in a particular range of
each other so it's there's no spikes
here because obviously we have what
could a dancer that that's just a
trivial example so the times are pretty
much the same I mean the difference of
four nanoseconds doesn't really feel
like much and we have 59 five
nanoseconds for the first string we have
guessed four characters and 91 seconds
for the second case again with four
characters then we have the third
example which is accounted in 15
nanoseconds but in this case we have a
total of five characters that we have
guessed and it attempted to check the
sixth one whether it's correct or not
doesn't matter it takes more time and
clearly 91 91 95 and 115 is very
different from each other so our main
idea for timing attacks the other side
it's a particular it's being studying a
particular field of the cryptography
field and it's not something that is
generally used in web applications so we
had to make sure that we time each and
every segment properly so the first
thing we had to do is done the
round-trip time RTT which is basically
how many hops it takes to reach the
destination and how long it takes for
each cup to be processed we also have to
time the webserver its response time and
the response time of the application and
we should also consider that those times
are pretty equal to each other they are
self-contained I mean the application
time the time it takes for the
application to cross the data we input
is pretty much contained to the server's
response time so we have to figure that
out we have to know what the server
response time is essentially we know all
these measurements and take measurement
of both
categories in order to just execute a
normal timing attack otherwise if we
work on it with the service response
time without the application without
round-trip time it's pretty much a
failure and we won't be getting any
reliable data at all so the thing that
we should mention before we can continue
is a cup of pre requisite because you
need to know what we've had access to
what we've done different and what our
test cases was so first of all we had
access the source code it's a PHP system
that is vulnerable timing attacks and it
also has grown ability that as a pass
the hash is present again not so common
in web applications but apparently this
case the developers consider that
performing hashing on the front end was
better so they had the password just to
save some execution time with their
back-end forcing the user to compute his
own hash using javascript and then they
were comparing the hash at the backend
so whatever was generated on the
front-end was compared on the backend
eventually we also didn't have any
hindrance with web application firewalls
intrusion detection systems prevention
systems we had no Sirians but no Koffler
no caching no reverse proxies no nginx
and this is vital because in most cases
when you have any kind of a reverse
proxy it will just fill out the data you
won't have any reliable source
whatsoever
imagine the reverse proxy just standing
in front of your web server and it just
routes packets
we're actually timing its response time
not the actual web server so this was a
problem and in this case we had no
reverse proxies in front of us obviously
a web application firewall or an IDs
near because timing attacks tend to
require a large amount of requests and
if we were to send out let's say a
thousand requests per second clearly
most web application firewalls or IDs
will stop us and we'll be able to
continue
so the thing that we started off with
was first of all study application
source coding details just so we can
find a particular module particular
functionality to exploit usual that
revolves around security critical
operations like authentication
cryptography and we know that also
operations don't take time because they
process a lot more data and it's pretty
different to any other really
implementation of modules and mechanisms
and essentially it's one that exposes
data I mean if we have one ability the
fication system that's not a good idea
so we have to pinpoint a particular
function source code that handles this
data to exploit it we conduct the basic
data collection so we can just know what
we're working with
as in information about timing
differences and we had to work on
improving the noise filtration because
the noise situation is if not the most
important part of the entire timing
attack if we have a lot of noise no
matter how much requests we send it
doesn't matter it's just a fair attempt
whatsoever so we have to figure out
noise and we applied several techniques
most of which were derived from another
conference in blackhat that we kind of
copied there and eventually we had to
reduce the search space for a timing
attack yes unfortunately we have to test
each in every character which is 16
characters in total for 32 positions
this amounts to millions of requests
that have to be sent in a reasonable
time let's say within an hour or two
otherwise we get a watch CPU spike from
the remote server or there could be some
other noise that is induced by our
network and that general isn't a good
idea so we had to think of a way to
reduce the search space as a matter of
fact in this particular case we had an
idea what to do but it isn't really
applicable in most cases out there
so those are things that we've attempted
first of all this is part of what we did
differently than our researchers out
there what we attempted to do and we
thought initially it was a good idea was
to profile the application using AXA
buck or ACH prof. it's a PHP application
again but as it turned out this didn't
work out well because the application
itself isn't really a viable means of
data and we had to resort to other
techniques essentially timing it woke
early without the usage of the bugger we
have a lot less noise we also have to
measure the round-trip time we've
attempted to do that via TCP timestamps
but they don't keep that much data and
there was gravity is one millisecond to
a hundred seconds and we're working with
microseconds so milliseconds are no good
for us and TCP timestamps go as well as
one millisecond so this wasn't something
that could help us at least not at first
sight and we also didn't get to make
observations from user space because
they didn't use a lot of noise as well
working from user space implies that you
have to handle a lot of things for
example system calls when you send a
request and when you receive it goes
through the kernel the interface card
and of those operations take a large
amount of time I mean what amount of
time is in microseconds something that
we really don't need at the time
difference and we had to fill that out
so doing that from user space for
example using curl burp or anything like
that didn't work out we had to dress
system codes with a stress for example
but that was pretty tricky because
estrous is not as handle and we also had
to automate the process in the end but
what we did differently and what
actually worked is timing each
individual PHP function by itself we've
copied from source code we've done some
unit testing and eventually we just
attempted to time it using the micro
time function in PHP we collected data
from
samples for example in this particular
case the samples we took were a hundred
thousand and we also have rich talc
Webster's performance perversion because
different versions of PHP for example or
Apache because we've done PHP as well as
an interpreter tend to have different
execution times for example PHP five six
is totally different from PHP cell b7
has huge boost in performance and that
can pretty much grip our attack to a
large extent so we have to handle that
as well and timing different PHP
functions was our main aspect of this
act because once we have a reasonable
idea how long it takes for a function to
get executed we could essentially just
subtract that time from the total time
and we can have some reasonable data to
work with so those are the few things we
did differently from others because I
say others as in the parentheses
presented at blackhat in 2015
they've only attempted to calculate a
round-trip time they've calculated the
noise Delta and they worked with a lot
of statistical analysis where I guessed
iOS tomaters nothing that they used was
a common furor we use a common filler as
well but it turned out in our case
comfiest the only thing we needed in
addition to the timing of different PHP
functions so regarding the round-trip
time what we actually don't to calculate
it is that we didn't do it from user
space we clarify that because user space
is not reliable especially for
networking but what was pretty robber
was packet capturing we captured cup of
packets we estimated a time based on the
synchronized and acknowledgment requests
and yeah as I said history timestamps
don't work that well was drawn right is
one millisecond a stress can be tricky
and different protocols came through out
differently for example if you were
attempting to get the round-trip time
using pink ICMP traffic you won't be
getting as much Robo data as using TCP
stack so we had to work with Pakistani
thing and
that was pretty much something that we
had to automate as well so packet
capturing and extracting information
from it and that's about round-trip time
here you can see basic statistics of how
a round-trip time differs this is the
basic ping request those are the four
criterias the medium deviation the
maximum value the average value and the
minimum value as you can see it's quite
a lot of noise here we can't really
figure out what wobble data is hidden
within it and if we just leave out an
average value it doesn't work out as
well because one little spike and we're
all charts and using this beeping which
is not utility but instead of using ICMP
requests uses TCP once was also not a
great idea because as you can see it's
pretty different from a smooth graph
that would otherwise represent wobble
data so we couldn't use any of those we
had reserved something else and packet
capturing was that we had to capture
packets using wireshark let's say or TCP
dump and we calculated time depending on
the differences and this is how the syn
and a scape packets look like when we
applied a common furor the graph is a
lot smaller and this is pretty much data
we could work with in addition to the
timing with PHP functions and averaging
out Webster's response time because yeah
I mean Apache 2.2 is taking a bit more
time than Apache 2.4 of the scale of
nanoseconds microseconds but this does
matter to us because we're aiming to
time this as perfect as possible we
can't afford to lose any microsecond at
all and as you can guess this induces a
lot of noise which is otherwise not
preferable
so this is what a basic packet capturing
looks like we've filter out most of the
data so we can represent in a sensible
way the xxx IP is ours this is the hosts
the target yoy
the first thing we do is send an HTTP
request with sighs the protocol version
request method and this is the current
timestamp that is on our walking
computer this is the first response the
acknowledgment packet and in the end we
have essentially the status code there's
actually response from the web server so
as you can see there's quite a lot of
difference here as in time differences
and if we were to measure from time it
took the time it took from the first
request hours response time of the
server that's totally different the
response time is actually the
acknowledgment packet and we have to use
this data to work with and get some
reliable statistics so we can later on
work with our timing attack in order to
derive noise that's centrally the
biggest part of the entire attack feel
right noise so we can have revival data
and then basically for the server with a
lot of requests so you can just get a
lot of metrics and figure out which
character is the next one
so spikes were another case which gonna
bug out our statistics you can't always
predict you can almost never predict
whether a spike can occur and how it can
differ from time to time so imagine that
a process with a higher priority than
peach peace process is running it can
simply affect it up the scale of
nanoseconds or microseconds and this
would pretty much bug our data and we
won't be able to get anything out of it
so ever so what we did to reduce that
and actually calculate how long it took
on average was by mirroring the target
environment we've essentially done some
reconnaissance on the target site and we
figure out it's using a certain version
of patch after the minor version 2.4 29
I think so we timed how much on average
it takes for a patch 2.4 point 29 takes
to execute certain requests we did the
same with PHP and pretty much anything
that we knew we had information about so
we could just subtract that from total
time and that's just averaging out stuff
so the application profiling the
function timing is the most important
thing we've done and I think that pretty
much made our attack successful in this
particular case this is not usually the
case in most web applications because
what they do is they hash a value they
store it and when you input a string it
has to be compares it so this is totally
different we're not working with string
comparison there and I'd say they're not
skeptical timing attacks but in our case
we had a pass the hash vulnerability
which essentially allowed us to provide
a hash instead of a password and this
pretty much means that we can
authenticate without having the plain
text of the password we can just provide
a hash couple of developers consider
that a good practice but in general
that's pretty bad idea because yeah I
threw that you transmitting the password
encrypted in this case hashed over the
network in case somebody sniffs it he'll
be intercepting the hash but at the same
time he'll be walking with the hash you
wouldn't need to crack it because our
authentication mechanism is using the
hash
instead of its plaintext value so yeah
we've calculated a session time for
different environments and we also
calculate the medium absolute deviation
this is just something I would refer to
as time differences or variance and it
turned out to be a pretty useful
statistic in our attack because it
helped us improve the analysis by I
think it was 15 30 percent which was
pretty huge of disco
so the target more specifically what we
had is we've extracted some of the
functions here so you can visualize that
easier we have the is valid hash
function which just checks where the
hash is valid or not so we can know
whether we should even process it and
what is basically does is it just
compares the length if the length is not
equal to 40 basically not a sh-1 a shave
on hash and if it's not hexadecimal it's
not a hash eater so if none of those
both these not confirmed it returns
false otherwise that's true so once we
use that down here in the verify
password function we can then proceed
with the string comparison we compare
the user password hash with the one that
is stored on our a on database in this
case and this is again using a known
constant time algorithm as we would be a
is identical function in the earlier
slides it's comparing one byte at a time
which is not a good idea it induces some
vulnerability that is essentially a
timing channel so this was not a good
idea at all from developers but you know
they've they haven't figured that pass
the hash vulnerabilities are that much
of a concern and they were more like
relying on performance rather than
security like saying you can't obtain a
hash so basically you can't walk in so
it doesn't matter if I've implemented
the past cache vulnerability or not but
anyway in this case all we had was we
needed to time among how long it takes
for a hash process one character at a
time so we can essentially guess the
next character etc so this is how the
execution time of the is valid hash
function works like it is up the scale
of microseconds this time 5,000
microseconds in this particular case and
yeah there is not a lot of noise but
still we would like to smooth that and
have more reliable data to work with
because what we've done is done this
particular function how long it takes
under different PHP versions and in
particular the point was using let's say
B to be 546
so we had at execution time subtracted
but at the same time we were calculating
during the runtime as well and this is
the verified password function how it
resembled you know a similar graph but
different time this time is 19,000
microseconds or different and takes a
lot more time to do that comparison
that's because it does the string
comparison here in addition to the
verification of the hash so this is
something that we're focusing right now
this is the vulnerability in the system
that we're trying to expose and trying
to bypass the mechanism by trying one
character at a time but unfortunately in
this case some rough statistics means
that on average we have sent 14,000
requests and this is pretty much I'd say
not a huge number for now usually takes
a lot more like 50,000 400,000 but this
was like two hops away from us we had
reliable statistics and we also worked
with the server itself we had accident
server as well so we had you know the
possibility time it's particular
response time locally in this case so
the example is pretty much exaggerated
just demonstrate the attack but the main
idea is the hashes 40 characters we have
to guess it one character at a time it's
hexadecimal you know that hexadecimal
contains 16 elements it is based on a to
F 0 to 9 16 characters that we have to
try this session means that for every
element we have to send out 14,000
requests and as per every position as
well which means that on average we have
to send out 224 thousand requests for
each position to guess a single
character and that's on average this
could range up to billions of requests
minutes of requests nobody would
naturally allow us to do that and in
total for a full hash recovery in this
gauge in this case is the secure hashing
algorithm one
sha1 it would take all about nearly nine
million requests for a foolish recovery
and as I said this is again greatly
exaggerated because otherwise we would
have billions of requests sending out
and we are also expecting a response
from the server so this is not a thing
to look up to we have consider like a
window of two hours and in those two
hours we have to send out 9 million
requests usually we won't be allowed to
do that so what if people were wondering
when you did our research online we
prepped a lot of topics and forums a lot
of opinions expressed by other searches
they were wondering what is the
difference to brute-forcing is there any
actual usage of timing attacks well
there is and yeah it is really quite
simple
because it works for any password no
matter the complexity in this case we're
not cracking the hash we were covering
the hash not the plain text behind it so
in this case let's say that our password
is totally random 20 characters of
length using wide variety of characters
say our character set is 64 of length
that would take a large amount of time
if you were to attempt and brute force
it because essentially this roundabouts
you I know
trillions of requests trillions of
combinations you have to try each and
every one
so brute forcing is preferable in some
cases this is if the password is
predictable consume the password is
whatever or test or test one two three
yeah brute forcing would be better
because it would simply contain this in
a couple of iterations or it would be in
a word list one of the top passwords so
to say otherwise we would be trying a
timing attack get something that is
fairly simple to to guess so yeah I mean
the basic idea is if someone attempts to
target a system like that he should
first perform any wordlist attack mask
attack brute force and only then if
nothing is recovered resorted timing
attacks timing attacks are not practical
at all in web applications and
the only difference is that it works on
any user support input in this
particular case the pass the hash
vulnerability so reducing the search
space essentially means that we have to
reduce the number of attempts we're
making because 9 million requests are a
lot and as I said it's exaggerated so
they're billions actually and this is
not a good idea to usually go out we
have to do something about this and in
this case as we said before this is a
pretty weak authentication mechanism it
was like intentionally vulnerable so to
say because not a lot of developers are
using such mechanisms for tenth occasion
for example in this case we had a simple
message dysfunction I think it was 75
but we later on test with h1 worked as
well and the length is 32 characters we
know that we know how an md5 is bill to
know what it consists of and if we were
to attempt each and every possible
element it would take a total of nine
million requests it's not a good idea so
what we do differently is that it wasn't
necessary to recover the fou hash you
know search space is incredibly big and
we wouldn't need to recover the fou hash
because if we have let's say the first
four five six or ten characters doesn't
matter we could just look them up in
rainbow table of precomputed hashes and
store plaintext corresponding to them
and say like 50 or 40 pop out to be
certain matches we could just try those
passwords manually or automated doesn't
matter but the main idea is that we can
just identify hash by the first several
symbols so that kind of reduce the
search space a bit but considering that
the hash is in a rainbow table and
rainbow tables tend to be quite huge in
terms of storage we needed like two
terabytes of data for just basic rainbow
tables was basically alpha numeric
numeric of the length of nine and that's
assuming the user uses a password one of
those but the main idea here is that
we've taken this from an online attack
to an offline attack once we have the
hash we can work with it it doesn't mean
that we should brute force and expect an
answer from the server once we retrieve
the hash we can just do an offline
attack where we have no limitations and
this bit of Statistics well first for
first 10 characters I expect to be
recovered with 2 million requests based
off of this the elements would pick
multiplied by the number of requests per
element multiplied by the length because
we need to apply this for each and every
position after the full length so if
words say recover the first 5 for 6
characters this would take a reasonably
wall amount of requests in comparison to
a fou hash recovery and 13 characters
take up to 3 million as 4.5 million so
it's still better a lot better than 9
million requests and we can work with
this methodology for other
vulnerabilities not only the past hash
so we can switch to demo now
so we produced pretty simple and
simplified to for this particular case
and I exaggerate and I focus on this
particular case because we've written
this tool for one specific case and that
case is the pastor has vulnerability
that is present and that we've exploited
what is to actually does is you filled
in some data that there is essentially
the URL to target the page request where
it goes you also have to specify the
data that accepts otherwise it won't
know what to send what to expect and it
does some statistics it estimates the
transfer rate so we can know therapod
and how much how many requests we can
process it also checks for caching
because like caching would be a huge
problem if we have any sort of hashing
it would not be a good idea at all
because caching just cache our requests
won't be able to get a reliable data we
won't be communicating with the server
will just be receiving a cache copy and
in this case they detected model flight
but mother flight is not a problem
it's caching statical resources and it's
not something that can borrow us what
we're working for is dynamic requests
and dynamic requests only and next is
checking for that's the timing check
yeah it's pretty corded first thing is a
caching it checks for any rate limiting
which is essentially a web application
firewall on IDs and IPS and after it
filters that out after refines whether
there's an application firewall in front
it continues on obviously if there is
one it wouldn't continue because
there'll be a huge problem with data
we're working it it also does automated
calculation the round-trip time using
the difference between the synchronized
and acknowledgment packets and wasn't
calculates that as well only then can we
have the timing attack executed because
we need to have some data to figure out
we need to subtract that data so you can
get a rough estimate of what is going on
at my tech tip of seconds the 3/4 view
because a real-time attack will take a
lot more resources and we won't be able
to execute it here on stage especially
over the Wi-Fi and considering that
we've done this over three hops away
here it might have been depending on the
routers but could have been seven this
matter so calculated round-trip time its
error data is Robert's table so the
round-trip time it does several
measurements of round-trip time using
different methods not only the
synchronous and acknowledgment packet
differences it is also ICMP traffic as
we mentioned earlier and all of our
information that is retrieved from
different sources so it calculated
round-trip time it said how many hops
away we are and what is the Webster's
response time it says all of this
information in his memory so it knows
what to subtract when subtracted and
what we are doing now is just it prompts
you to you know whether you want to use
statistics from this particular version
of Apache 2.4 29 because we had walk of
statistics loaded prior to this attack
that is the average time it takes for
this particular version of patch to
process requests and yeah we've decided
to use the statistics to reduce the
noise does some basic request statistics
how many requests on average it would
take for us to execute the attack in
this case it's 47,000 requests which is
you know per element it's not it's not a
whole number
it's pretty huge number and we have to
multiply that by the character set
length which is 60 in this case and then
multiply all of this by 32 if we were to
check and amplify for example first
check on sha-1 it would be 40 and
imagine if there was a South it would
pretty much rendered attack useless so
in this particular case it already
started so there's a couple of
statistics before that
as well it said that on average attack
might take about 37 minutes depending on
transfer rate but this is not much
accurate I mean it's just roundabout
time it would take because we can't
really calculate I want you to take and
what it does now is sense samples of
data forty-seven thousand requests and
this is done usually in a time frame of
say a minute or so so it checks each and
every single character to see how long
it takes it does some statistics based
on that and we're essentially checking
each and every character we're
calculating the medium absolute
deviation here we're also using that to
subtract it to know how far from the
Walker difference that is the deviation
and we have variance this is something
that we've been using to to how variable
is this result from the different ones
from the previous ones so the first few
ones are not really Robbo as an
information source obviously if we
retrieve more information it would be
pretty clear that the tolerance that the
variance is storable and this is the
confidence level something that we have
invented again something that says how
confident is the two about this data
we've also worked for identifying spikes
between the two but that was a bit
tricky so we couldn't implement it
eventually and right now is checking up
to the length of five because we might
have a full hash recovery but we've
talked about that it takes a lot more
time to process and a lot more requests
so in this case we were prompted and we
chose to use five positions two time
five positions and then woke up those
first five characters in any rainbow
table so we can just find hashes that
start with this particular pattern and
we could basically make an assumption
that maybe one of those hashes that are
contained in rainbow table that matched
or our users hash essentially the
password adventure
so this goes long times actually 47
minutes won't be watching The Hobbit
because there is pretty much the same
you've seen the same over and over again
eventually it ends up calculating the
first five characters and I said we can
look them up in a rainbow table
essentially find hash so this case we
can just skip the video and see if I can
do it from here we're colleagues from
deaf camp can just switch the video back
to Pradesh can we go back to
presentation please
so first thing to talk about after demo
is what the consequences can be because
a lot of people overlook this type of
tax but it's not that unusual to see
them in the wild especially if the
attack is targeted against a specific
system and we've also done that we've
attempted that to WordPress but
WordPress doesn't use the same
methodology it doesn't do pass the hash
you inputted a password and it hashes it
on the back end but this isn't a pie
only to pass the hash when abilities
it's also applies to a wide range of
vulnerabilities that could induce a
timing channel because most developers
are concerned about performance more
than the security aspect and essentially
they don't even don't even consider
timing attacks practical at all to a
certain extent they're not practical but
in specific cases they could turn out to
be quite more practical than a simple
brute-force attack and the consequences
can range from a complete take over the
server this is something that could be
the final goal it could be achieved
although in rare cases and consider that
that kit has been running for a long
time this also induces a lot of resource
exhaustion on the server if cost the
operations are performed an example the
identification system might do some
crypto on the back end in addition to
the comparison and this takes some cpu
time essentially for sending out
thousands of requests it would just sum
up and it would exhaust a lot of
resource if you're even a lot of that
code Linux protects against this for
example and quadrants available in
almost every cPanel there are almost any
shared hosting environment and it's
basically something that says you're
limited to those resources you can't use
any more CPU times than this so this
would pretty much you know wouldn't be a
problem in this case but in general it
could to not be a problem over an
extended period of time
if there is no limitation at all
regarding the number of requests we send
this could turn out to be a problem
and the basic solution timing attacks
we've read a lot of papers online
something that a lot of people express
an opinion is that you should just
compare each character doesn't matter if
it's right or wrong you compare the next
one as well so it's a constant time
function and it's pretty much applies
mostly to security critical operations
go on such example is the authentication
again as I say because this is something
that handles our data this is something
that handles the authentication of a
user which is essentially almost
everything in today's systems and of
course if you have a rate limiting
policy if you have caching if you have a
reverse proxy pretty much renders our
attack useless so even the smallest
things can hinder the attack consider
that the user is using up cash and PHP
that would might as well just ruin the
attack totally and we will be working
with quite useless data from then on
which is not a good idea at all but yeah
we would be wasting just on yeah so
enforcing a very limiting policy saying
that this IP address is allowed a couple
of requests per second and requests per
second would be a good idea and the
usage of constant time algorithms is
really the key aspect if we rely on just
third factors like caching and rate
limiting yeah this would most probably
limit the attacks but it would they
would still be possible no matter how
small and yeah a lot of developers who
are also relying on network jitter we
thought up a couple of github
repositories when there were issues I
have been submitted from the community
they were saying that you know there's
time attack here and developer was
simply replying that there is a lot of
noise so they won't be able to export it
eventually this was a case of the system
Pyrrhic the statistics system it was
actually exploited in the wild and it
turned out that this is not something
that you should generate a Y on national
jitter yes it does stop you but as we
saw earlier on we can figure that out as
well and come up with a rate limiting
policy a caching server something that
you not sure naturally have anyway this
was pretty much rendered
the attacks totally useless we won't be
able to utilize in any way possible
last but not least what give some kudos
to these two researches the second one
of Patrick Brady is spirit technical and
it's something that sparked the idea of
timing attacks back in 2010 when it was
possible to time it up to nanoseconds we
couldn't time it up to nanoseconds we
managed only to microseconds but it
would be a more or more accurate if we
could you know go down to nanoseconds
unfortunately Dallas we didn't find it
possible in our case and the first one
the opportunities and limits of remote
timing attacks is something that also
had a lot of news about it a lot of
people were talking about this of course
the mail down and spectra exploits we're
essentially using a side channel is a
bit different from this I should rather
say totally different this one but again
it was a timing attack and we all know
what a consequence of meltdown inspector
were they weren't patched immediately
and yeah this was a pretty different
story so that's about it if anyone has
any questions I'm guessing there will be
a lot of questions asked now's the time
to thank you just a quick question
some people suggest to use delays
randomly days what's your opinion on
them no run the place are not a good
idea because you can still average out
the noise you can still have ajar how
long it takes for example you can send
out let's say 12 requests when you
request 100 requests depends on the data
and how much noise induced and you can
still average that out you can just you
can also predict the output into entropy
as to wall but that depends on the
source if you're using deff few random
for example Linux that won't be possible
it will still hinder the attack to a
great deal but it would still be
possible from ability will still be
there thank you
second question hi how can you find the
best the best timing do we mean by the
best time so you will set the request
and delay up for a few seconds or maybe
a few minutes but do you have a method
to find the dupe the one that took the
longest yes yeah that essentially the
character that is considered to be valid
in other words but what we've done is
that we've sent a 47 thousand requests
for each in every position each and
every character which position and on
average depending on how long it took
for each and every single we managed to
just establish the basic disco analysis
when you could say that this one took
say 100 nanosecond 100 microseconds more
than the previous ones was basically the
one that has the most execution time but
we do that by sending a ton of requests
in this case for 7,000 per position and
maybe make you vulnerable we didn't
create some noise when you do that when
we send out 7,000 requests or 47,000 no
well that would depend as I said the
statistics is greatly affected by almost
any factor out there so we can't really
work with rapid at all the time as a
matter of fact this particular recording
of the test script was done after the
fourth or sixth attempt I don't know
until we could get this working
especially so yeah it is possible quite
possibly yes thank you we have our next
question
you you have done here okay okay so most
of the CMS actually we using to reset
the password using linked with Heche and
there is no limit on how many requests
you can do on the reset password link so
isn't the best way not to attack the
password but the reset password Heche
yeah but in this case we wouldn't know
which hash we're selling in order to do
that we need to have a dependent system
but what they usually do is they
whenever pass request is being sent they
generate a hash for the specific user
and you have to guess the hash for this
user but consider that a system is more
scale website is widely used consider
that a couple of users have requested a
forgotten past at the same time similar
time frame we would recover a different
hash possibly we wouldn't know which
hash would be for this particular user
so it's kind of a logical issue here
because we wouldn't know how to match up
this hash to the specific user you might
as well reset the password to another
user in this case next question was
somewhere here hello as far as I know in
these days web applications sold
password hashes before storing them in
databases so isn't that actually the
best solution about around the timing
attacks well it it wouldn't make this
possible certainly but in this example
the developers had no understanding of
security at all and the idea was to just
present a simplified version of tech but
if you using bcrypt for example if using
argon to does matter as long as it has a
hash as well as long as it has a pepper
or salt that's pretty much run or attack
useless whatsoever yeah okay now this is
also if you have a past hashman ability
which is not something you have in
almost any application out there so it's
not very practical at all atomic attack
yes a South would totally render it
useless unless the Souda static I mean
if we have one single statics out for
each and every hash
thank you thank you and is there anyone
else or will this be our last question
hi actually I have two questions if you
may how often do you use timing attacks
in your fantastic engagements and
secondly what's the best result that you
could get well we don't naturally use
timing attacks not penetration tests
because we kind of focused on more rabo
vulnerabilities
timing attacks are something that is
something of wasps resort so to say if
we haven't found any other vulnerability
or if there's something specific to the
application that could be explained and
we have in mind that it could be
exploited we will attempt that but it
just requires a lot of research what of
resources we spend all about let's say a
month and a half on this specific case
and it's not practical at all as we also
so they're pretty much not practical and
this isn't something that we do on
natural base as penetration testers
obviously if a client asks for white box
testing and if he asks us to test for
timing attacks in particular we will do
that yeah but not in general case no not
in general case the best result month
timing attacks is just to make string
comparison constant time in critical
operations
I'm not saying make the entire code you
know constant time because that would be
totally nonsense but the idea is for
security critical operations for
identification in cryptography make it a
constant time algorithm so it takes the
same amount of time for each and every
input that would be the best thing to do
of course you could also bypass that but
this is something totally from the
theoretical field depending on how much
CPU it takes you could still time it but
I was totally off the charts I don't
think that is even possible nowadays
cool thank you
thank you if we have any other questions
otherwise we will be finishing here
thank you so much Vaughn thank you
[Applause]