have you ever been in this situation
that you want to perform a certain
action that you want to execute a file
or change a setting and you just got the
error message you're not allowed to do
this action you're not authorized to
execute execute this file or you are not
you don't have the permission to change
this configuration yes did you get angry
and this is exactly the talk for you
welcome to well that escalated quickly a
penetration testers approach to
privilege escalation but before diving
into the topic I would like to know a
little bit more about you guys who of
you is a penetration tester please raise
their hand okay some not that many do we
have security researchers all right do
we have system or network
administrator's some of you great
another question how many of you guys
use a disk encryption tool like
BitLocker not all okay and a few guys
how many have to enter their password
every time they put their PC ok that's
good because it's going to be
interesting later on so as a penetration
tester sometimes during our assessments
we get access to a system however only
with a low privileged user but we want
to do everything that we want we want to
execute any file we want to change any
configuration file you want to intercept
the network traffic but we cannot do
this with our low privileged user and
that's exactly why we need to escalate
our privileges we want to escalate our
privileges to be fully operative so it
is a very important task in a in an
assessment within a penetration test
but sometimes it gets really complex and
complicated it's not always an easy task
sometimes it might be but it does not
necessarily have to be so that's why we
want to know more about privilege
escalation and if you search in the
internet for privilege escalation
articles and tutorials you will find
some things you will find some very
specific tutorials or articles and some
that are written in a more general way
however there is not really a
comprehensive and profound literature
that deals with this topic and that's
why I chose to research this topic so
what do we want to achieve we want to
learn the theory and the practice of
privilege escalation attack attacks so
that we can use it in our daily life
whether we are a penetration tester and
attack we are attacking a system or
whether we are on the other side and
trying to defend our systems and at the
end of the talk we want to have a
practical and systematic approach for
every one of us who wants to escalate
his privileges in this talk I am going
to focus on Windows systems but the
concepts that you're going to learn our
are can be used for other operating
systems or even other systems or
applications so we have to talk a little
bit about Windows and its basic
components Windows is the de facto
standard in the company networks most
companies most big companies most banks
use Windows as a operating system for
their employees computers laptops and
workstations it holds a market value of
over 80% so it's the dominant operating
system and also in company networks we
find
more and more Windows servers windows
itself is complex
so it's opera an operating system that's
old that's long on the market many
vulnerabilities have been found and what
many vulnerabilities have been patched
and this altogether adds into the
complexity of Windows systems and
obviously what we always want to achieve
on a Windows system is to get
administrator or system privileges which
are the highest privileges in Windows
systems the equivalent to the root
account in Linux so one of the most
important components of Windows is the
registry the registry is built in a tree
structure where you have a root key at
the top the highest level keys are
called root keys and it consists of keys
and values and every key that has
another key or every key that is under
another key is called sub key so as you
can see on the right side of the slide
we have the different the five root keys
of a Windows system what does the
registry store amongst other things it's
lost system-wide software settings
it contains the security database so all
the users passwords all the user
passwords are stored in the registry not
everyone can access it you can only
exist it with system privileges but this
is where it is dot and also it contains
per user configuration settings so if
you have more than one user or even if
you have only one user the settings that
are specific to this user are also
stored in the registry the registry
itself is protected by an access control
list so for every key you can have a
different ACL another important aspect
of Windows systems are processes a
process in simple terms consists of a
process ID
an executable program and the security
context so a security security context
are mainly security tokens also called
access tokens and it contains
information about the user the security
group and the privileges of the process
now that we know more about processes
what our jobs and threats to them job
jobs are simply groups of processes so
as you can see on the screen you have
the process CMD dot X ax and this
process again contains two other
processes Khan hosted X and notepad or
Tex and threads are entities within a
process that are computed by the CPU
services is another very important
component of Windows what our services
services are processes that are that
start at system startup so every time
you boot your PC different services are
started and these against that load
processes which again container
executable file so every service also
has a executable file and these services
run under us in the context of a certain
user meaning that every service can have
a certain user in which the this with
the privileges of a certain user which
the service can use most of the accounts
that are used for services are non
interactive accounts so-called service
accounts which we'll talk about shortly
and normally or most services only just
run in the in the context of a system
user so with the highest privileges in
the system Windows offers three
different service accounts first of all
the local system account which is the
which is also called
the system account as we said it has the
highest privileges on the system and you
can do everything with this account
although some privileges are not enabled
by default for the system account or the
local system account you have the
privilege to enable other privileges so
eventually you can have every privilege
out there and yeah most core windows
components run under the system account
so if you would find a vulnerability in
such a Windows component then you will
directly have system privileges the
second account is the network service
account this also contains high
privileges less than the system account
but still high privileges and what the
network service account is used for is
to authenticate against other network
services and then last but not least we
have the local service account which has
the same privileges as the network
service account except that you cannot
use it for network for authenticating to
other network services and the last two
things that are important are startup
programs and scheduler tasks so that our
programs and scheduled tasks are very
similar to services the difference
between sada programs and services is
that services are managed by the service
manager whereas other programs are not
and scheduler tasks are processes that
run at a certain time or after a certain
period of time yeah and both of these
run under again in the context of a
certain user so what we want to do in
the later stages we will find out more
we want to attack those SATA programs
and those scheduled tasks that run in
the context of a high privileged user
that's it about the windows components
let's dive into the different
privilege escalation methods and
techniques so just as an overview there
as we said there are things in Windows
that are similar to other things there
are components that are similar to other
components and that's why some attacks
and some methods may be used not only
for one component but for several and
what I did is to create attack trees
these it attack trees can give an
overview to you on which attacks you can
perform and which different conditions
have to be met so the first big attack
tree and you have to imagine this is the
part of a very big attack tree is
unsecure services so in this part of the
attack tree we want to attack insecure
or miss configurated services and as you
can see in the second row we have five
five different techniques the first one
is weak service executable or
configuration file permissions unquoted
service paths weak service permissions
the ad l hijacking and weak registry key
permissions as you can see in the third
row for instance for uncoated services
path service paths we have again two
conditions and we will talk about it in
the next slides so the first method or
technique is the weak executable file
permissions so as we said every service
has executable file that it runs what we
could try to search for is to find a
executable file that runs in a high
privileged service that we can modify so
as you can see in the blue figure we the
the service is called waves waves this
SVC which is a soundmanager tool for
their laptops and it it runs under the
local system account so the highest
privilege
I don't really know why a sound manager
to need system privileges but hey it's
good for us and in the fourth row you
can see we have the right attributes and
every user of the group built-in users
can modify the file so we with our low
privilege user can go ahead and just
modify or replace the file and put in
our malicious code the next time this
service is started the our malicious
payload will be executed with system
privileges how do we restart a service
we could either reboot the system or we
could if we have the privileges use the
SC tool to restart the service another
interesting method the unquoted service
path method for the uncoated service
path method what you need our services
that have that user file path which does
not contain a double quote so now no
double quotes at the beginning and at
the end and that contain a white space
somewhere in the file path so as an
example we have C backslash program
white space files backslash waves etc so
both conditions are met in this example
what does Windows do and this is
something very weird I don't really know
why it does it but it is how it works it
tries to execute the file C backslash
program dot Excel what does this mean
for us
it means if we have write permissions to
the C directory we could just create our
own program dot excel file and then the
next time the file is the services
loaded our malicious file will be
executed instead of the file that is
defined in the file path and I was kind
of shocked when I noticed that my
previous Dell laptop that I got
had exactly this vulnerability in it so
this is how I got it from Dell and it
contains a service for this wave Syst
SVC service which is also a sound which
is a sound manager tool and it didn't
contain any quote any any quotes at the
beginning and at the end and the same
applies for Lenovo and think that some
years ago there they had this
vulnerability another very interesting
but a little bit complex attack and
technique is called DLL hijacking so
applications that are started normally
try to run DLL files at runtime or load
DLL files at runtime if the DLL file is
missing meaning it tries to load the DFA
that does not exist and it uses a
relative path and not an absolute path
then we might have a vulnerability so
what does Windows do if a dll file is
missing it tries to search for the DLL
in certain folders it starts with the
Applications folder then goes to see
windows system32 see windows system see
windows and then the current working
directory and after that it searches for
the DLL file in all the directories that
are in the system path variable so and
this is exactly where we could try to
find a bypass or where we could try to
find and exploit if we go through all
the directories that that are defined in
the system path variable and we find the
directory where we have right access to
then we can just write our own file name
our own DLL file into the directory and
the next time the program is started it
will it will load our malicious DLL file
that's it about services just a quick
glimpse into start-up programs
Sutter programs as we said are similar
to services and that's why we have three
techniques that also apply for unsecure
services and the same applies for
scheduler tasks for scheduler tasks as
we all know a certain time period has to
pass by or a certain time our scheduler
tasks are executed at a certain time
what can we do if this do we have to
wait until this time really and until
this time happens or until this until
this time comes no we probably don't
have to do which you could try is to
just change the system time if you have
the privilege to do that so you would
change the system time to the time the
scheduler task will be executed and then
it will be executed immediately one very
obvious but probably very successful
method is to exploit outdated software
so we you have to kind of software that
you would want to exploit first of all
you want to exploit software or
vulnerable software that runs with high
privileges and you want to execute and
you want to exploit would not the
windows kernel if possible why the
windows kernel because if you exploit
the windows kernel you will have system
privileges right away why is this very
successful because companies mostly are
very slow in deploying patches maybe
because they have many different systems
or maybe they have very critical systems
that need many that need to be tested or
where the patches have to be tested
before they are deployed into production
and that this opens the gap for us
attackers
also very obvious weak passwords but I
will tell you a story shortly so which
you could have you could find the act
you would you will gain access to a
system which has a web server and this
web server connects to a database so
what you will do is to search in the web
server directories for the password of
the database for the user password and
some administrators use the same
password for everything they do so this
would be a very simple technique to just
try this - just take the password and
try it for the login of the
administrator account other specific
admit yes specific administrator account
also you could try wordless attacks or
brute force attacks as we all know what
sometimes happens is that besides the
database configuration file that you
will find plaintext password passwords
in Windows configuration files or in
Windows XML files
so these are some paths where you would
probably make where you might might find
a password and once I was in a
assessment for a big German bank and I
had the test
I got an employee laptop and I had the
test to find a way to escalate my
privileges so I tried all the hard stuff
I tried it with this the DLL hijacking
unquote the services pass and I tried
many different things but I didn't
really find a way to escalate my
privileges so what I thought is maybe
I'll try just the easy things and I
searched for a plaintext passwords and
tada
I found a password and this password was
not only used for a local user or local
administrator it was used for the domain
admin that means with this password that
every employee of the bank has on his
laptop he could directly access the CEOs
laptop you could access the
administrator laptops until it is a very
very low hanging fruit so yeah such
stuff happens so don't only only go for
the complex things also go for the low
hanging fruits and besides files you
could also find passwords in the
registry so for instance if auto log-in
is enabled in Windows you might find
passwords there also another possibility
is if we have physical access to a
machine be it a laptop computer or a
server then we could try other attacks
so first of all all those of you who do
not use disk encryption use this
encryption why because if I get access
to your laptop I can just put my own
Windows CD replace some files in your
file system and the next time I'll boot
up your machine I will have system
privileges and have access to your
machine so it's a very easy thing and
it's widely known however if you use
this encryption but you do not have
pre-boot authentication
what is pre-boot authentication pre-boot
authentication means that whenever you
start your laptop that you have to enter
your password - which is used for the
decryption of the volume if you do not
use this meaning that the decryption key
is thought somewhere on the motherboard
and is loaded into the memory when
starting the machine this means that an
attacker could try to extract the
decryption key from the memory and there
are many attacks that were performed
within in in some research in some
research universities and they were able
to successfully dump the memory and
extract the decryption key and then
access your machine and if you have the
decryption key I can again do the same
technique I can just replace some files
on your machine and then have system
privileges another thing a possibility
would be attacks against CPU
microcontrollers we all heard of Specter
we all heard
meltdown and although no proof of
concept was published it might be
possible that out there in the wild
someone has some exploit which which
which executes some malicious code on
your Intel or AMD microcontroller so in
the beginning I asked you how a few uses
disk encryption hope uses a password if
you use a password that's already very
good but nevertheless if you use disk
encryption three days ago there was a
new research published by a Dutch
university which showed that many
hardware encrypted devices are
vulnerable that's why if you go home try
this command with administrator rights
and check whether you have a software
encryption or whether you have a
hardware encryption if you have a
hardware encryption it might be possible
that you are vulnerable
so we learnt a little bit some
techniques and methods there are many
more out there if you're interested come
to me after the talk and we can talk but
one very important thing is I know there
are so many different methods and so
many techniques how do I apply them how
can I have a structured and practical
way to use them in an assessment for
instance and that's why we need a
practical and systematic approach this
is how the approach looks like we have
three different phases the first phase
is the general information gathering
phase the second phase is the method and
technique iteration where we again have
four different steps and as you can see
we stay in the in Phase two because we
iterate through the different methods
we'll talk about it shortly and then
phase 3 we have the reporting phase so
in phase one what we really want to
achieve is to get a good overview of the
system we want to know which we know sir
which Windows version
is it we want to know which cpu
architecture is used we want to know
which service pack is used we want to
know about network devices and
interfaces and so on and so forth so we
want to learn more about the system in
general after that we will go into phase
2 in phase 2 as I just said we will
iterate through the different techniques
and methods and you can choose the
techniques and methods according to your
goal for instance if you have an
assessment where the goal is to find as
many privilege escalation possibilities
as possible then you could start with
more complex ones if you have the goal
to just get to escalate your privileges
and then attack other systems you could
choose the most easiest one of the most
probably the most successful ones and
yeah as we said every iteration consists
of four different step in step one we
have again a small information gathering
phase or as information gathering step
what we want to achieve here is to find
out is the system vulnerable against the
technique that I want to use for
instance if you want to check for
uncoated service paths then we will
check every service for our uncoated
service path if the system is vulnerable
we will go to step two in step two we
will conduct our research and we will
develop our exploit so we want for
instance if there is an outdated
software we want to gather everything
about the system we want to know more
about the exploit understand the exploit
and then maybe customize our exploits
according to our a system so we have to
know which architecture is used and
which service pack and so on and so
forth sometimes it is necessary to set
up a test environment why because some
services can be exploited only once and
if they exploit fails the system
fresh so you want to be sure that you
exploit works and that's why it would be
good to set up a test environment that
is very like this is very similar to the
target system that you're attacking also
you should consider possible security
mechanisms so let's say is there an
antivirus software and the PC if there
is an anti-virus software then we have
to apply different evasion techniques
and modify I hope our payload so that
the antivirus system does not detect it
also if we want to then if we use a
payload that builds a reverse TCP shell
do they use a firewall and if they use a
firewall which pots are most likely to
be open what four four three
so these things are part eighty so these
things are dependent on the environment
so these things are should be considered
when you develop your exploit in step
three we want to exploit our we want to
test our exploit so we use our exploit
sometimes it works right it works right
away but in most cases you will have to
go back and see what failed check again
rebuild your exploit and then explode
test again to exploit until eventually
it will hopefully work and in the post
exploitation phase of every technique
you should document every step and every
result and also you could check with
system administrators or network
administrator's hey I just escalated my
privileges did you notice anything
because this is very valuable for
companies sometimes companies pay
millions for different yeah
security software systems and in the end
they don't even work and this is
valuable information for them so yeah we
go through every technique and every
method that there is and in step in
Phase three the reporting phase as in
every
penetration test any vulnerability
should be reported independently on
whether it worked or it didn't work
sometimes you have a vulnerable service
but you cannot exploit it because you
don't have the time or because of other
things nevertheless you should report it
you could should document it so that the
customer can patch or fix the
vulnerability also passwords and
sensitive later should always be
censored so you don't know who will get
access to the report so and you don't
want the domain admin password to be
known to everyone right
also sometimes what could happen is that
you get access to a system and notice
hey someone else was already on this
system like there was another exploit
already in the in some folder or
something like that
and if this is the case you should
immediately contact the customer and
then discuss how to go with it and also
always document all the exploits that
you used and the users that you edit
because they should be removed and if
you can remove them yourself then this
would be the best case so this is the
approach there are some tools which we
can use to simplify the approach so we
have I have men I mentioned for tools
there are many more out there but you
could conduct your own research and try
them out I found these four very useful
in my from my experience but yeah just
try them out and check whether they are
good for you or not so the first one is
obviously Metasploit Metasploit comes
with a lot of enumeration tools and yeah
methods which you could use in a Windows
environment also another very powerful
tool is power sploit so let's say
unquoted services path or the week
service executable file permissions
there are scripts which do the research
for you so you don't have to do it
yourself
also there is a tool called B root which
is similar to power sploit not that
powerful but also fulfills its purpose
and you have the Windows exploit
suggester which you can use to you you
will first dump the last applied patches
on the system and then use the Windows
exploit suggester to find out whether
the latest patches have been applied or
whether there are patches missing on the
target system
so to conclude what we have just learned
can not only be used by penetration
testers but also by network or system
administrators by architects who build
Windows systems and generally speaking
about Windows Windows offers a great
number of security mechanisms so we have
different many different security tools
that you can use you have a very
granular configuration of accesses and
privileges as we just saw you could
apply an ACL for every different for
every single registry key and also in
most cases patches are deployed in a
fast manner so it doesn't take windows
too long to publish exploits I know
there are exceptions but this is the
normal case so hopefully we have learned
things about Windows about privilege
escalation methods and techniques about
an approach that we can use during our
assessments and tools that we can then
use and the next time I'm sure this will
be you well that escalated quickly
thank you everyone
all right thank you so much Khalil so we
have our first question here's the first
ask two questions
sure so and exploit regarding the
unquoted
path you said that Windows first looks
for seed double dot slash slash program
taxi is that generally true or does it
look for any kind of program after this
before the first space like if we had C
dot dot slash slash Facebook stuff does
it look for Facebook exit if there is a
white space after it it does look for
Facebook totally cool and the second
question would be Windows comes with
some pre-loaded and predefined services
you can't really stop if they don't
patch that service what do you do I mean
there's gonna be an exploit in your
system that you're gonna know about can
you mitigate that oh that's a tough
question so from a defender point of
view you would have to hope for Windows
to patch the system that's if you cannot
change the service you cannot disable it
then very hard what you could try to do
is to find other security tools or like
antivirus software or something like
that which explicitly it looks whether
this file is replace or whatever the
attack is so this is maybe something
that you could do on another layer so
you just like virtually patch this
vulnerability but to have a really to
really fix the root cause you would have
to wait for Windows Update but one very
interesting thing is that attackers
normally not penetration testers but
they could just do if they have access
to a Windows system and they are not
able to escalate their privileges just
build a backdoor connection and wait
some months because
from time to time colonel exploits our
Explorer are published and companies
most companies will not notice a
backdoor into their system so you just
wait until the next exploit comes out
and then you can escalate your
privileges thank you thank you sir
there's another one yeah there so he was
the second sorry sir please this is the
easy one you can answer with yes or no
did you find any way to exploit the
specter of vulnerability no thanks I'd
like to know in real life how long does
it take to go to the whole process of
scanning the computer and including
extending your exploits and customizing
them for the target machine because in
real life once an attacker has physical
or remote access to a computer well he
kind of won already
I don't really know where you are but ah
there are great great service how long
does it take depends sometimes it can
take minutes hours or even weeks
so those there of you that did the OS CP
certificate or want to do it you will
get to know what I mean sometimes you'll
find it right away and sometimes you
have to enumerate and enumerate you
don't find anything and then you have to
take a step back and again search
through the system gather information
and then hopefully eventually we'll find
it thank you
so how common is the unquoted service
path vulnerability because developers
I guess if they put uncoated paths they
should be able to notice that their
service won't start when testing now it
should start
I mean unported service paths the only
means that windows additionally to the
file you have defined tries to load
other files where the white space is
located so if there is not such a file
windows continues to go through the path
every white space it finds it will try
to fight to execute the file but if
there are no more white spaces it will
execute the file that you want to use ok
so first it tries till the first white
space it doesn't find anything then it
exact museum exactly yes alright thank
you so you might find not you might find
the direct you might find the white
space or you might find two white spaces
where you at the first white space
cannot write a file but at the second
white space so this is also possible
okay thanks
we have another one here one question
about the inception when you think that
Windows who saw this problem and not
only Windows that can use to escalate
privileges in Windows Mac OS Unix
everyone and I even saw that lately
adopted also one module from Metasploit
instead of the inception for can create
reverse vectors for connect thank you
sorry I didn't get the question what was
the story when you think will be solved
this problem or because it's four years
small yeah I think it will be never
solved so it will be always a race
between hackers and defenders I mean you
have to imagine an operating system is
not a small program it contains of
millions of lines of code
even much much more and you cannot
ensure that every developer knows what
he does and does not and does everything
in the correct way and sometimes it's
not even the windows developers but it's
also software that you as a company
install on your employees laptops or a
Mis configuration so in my opinion it
will never stop thank you yeah so I got
a question regarding the password should
we use better passwords or is there a
recipe for how we can secure our
networks or our computers yeah by which
I mean you say is there a clear recipe
that we can apply on all machines that
we can ensure that there's kind of not
never gonna be a privilege of escalation
or a possibility of exploit you object
so from a defender perspective there are
tools there is a tool I don't really
remember the name but what it does it it
sets the local administrator passwords
on the laptops and it changes it every
90 days or something like that and
generally speaking you should always use
a password manager and use complex
passwords which you and only use one
password for only one user and not for
several users there are many guides out
there which you could apply or ya
implement in your group policies also as
Windows administrator so to say yeah
this way you can ensure generally good
OPSEC operational security for the
computers yeah thank you do we have
others was there at a certain point time
default service vulnerability in Windows
that could've been exploited to take
control of the computers on the whole
domain not just the local PC you mean a
service in a local PC yeah you could use
to exploit good question so I'm sure
they were
services 100% I mean what you what you
could have is you have a service that
that you can exploit and then you get
system privileges and with the system
privileges you could use tools like mini
cuts to get all the password hashes of
users that log in to your machine and if
there is a domain admin connects to your
machine you can then extract his
password and use the pass the hash
attack to connect to the domain
controller or other machines so this is
a way that I could imagine you could
exploit your escalate your privileges to
a domain admin but directly from the
service itself I do not know any case
regarding the missing dll exploit yes
since the DLL file is missing should in
the app be able to start anyway so would
a user keep still keep an app on its
laptop or desktop that is not able to
start and if the DLL is erased by you as
a hacker shouldn't you already have
privileges to exploit or directly modify
the earlier five okay good question so
regarding programs so windows all the
windows applications load dll files at
runtime and if they don't find that the
ll file it does not necessarily mean
that the application crashes sometimes
it does but not every DLL is necessary
for the application to run so you might
have have an app you might have an
application or there are many
applications that try to load missing
the other alphas but are not able to
from a security perspective it would be
great if you could remove such tools but
it will not always be possible and your
second question
if you are able to place your own
malicious DLL file does that this does
this not mean that you don't already
have high privileges not necessarily so
in the first folders that I showed
earlier on I'll just open it again
so in the first four or in the first
five folders you will probably not have
write access where where you could have
write access is in a directory that is
defined in the system path environment
so in the system path environment
sometimes you have tools like C
backslash Python and in Python you I
think by default you have write access
and if you can write to the Python
directory the DLL if I will be loaded
from there that's how to exploit works
all right thank you
thank you or any other questions no all
right so if you have further questions
you can always contact me via my email
or call me directly and also after the
talk I'm going to be here and answer
your questions thank you again for your
great questions and the discussion Thank
You Callie