okay happens every 191
I haven't been reading here heard
several years
on and beating advances my home
hundreds is the word remain I
not another good things like would not
have happened right now on
published on their I and the board of
directors
to build a new National Museum 100 be I
hang out with their with them around
actually be cared for after being one is
alleles
I and that all had respect every day
pregnant hosea up how many people here
herds
in before there everything wherever
somewhere else
okay am so I
on Jul a little bit that story Jonah Hex
organizing here had created a
code it is was way before
all the other stuff but he had created
which had not been cracked and I heard
about it
actor and time where I was speaking on
electronics and games at my day job as
any computer games
and a Andrea 33 her dad ran her hand
with other Flyers didn't Homer there was
a prize arm
and handcrafted and yeah i won the prize
which was
free trip to have your country hotel
train station silencer
and I'm gonna happen to mention other
goods magazine
I've actually been banned from
competition at this point yeah
Atlanta not mention and then release the
good the bad and the papers and no
past has a crackers are ineligible
prices as he was on the lam
give someone else a chance longer
yeah and then and
and then actor September 11 happened
and I was using some my good time skills
not that the war on terrorism and I was
I giving talks about her ankles not hide
it was using
readings taken 100 be her the rumors
that ok I'm using steganography
I don't believe the reasons they cannot
be again and 333 could ascertain that is
hoped you'd see a country yes
hun which is a challenging ways CIA to
support both on it reinforcements are
was not been solved yes when the world's
most famous unsold goods
and I became they're knowledgeable
after yes and so that started I getting
drawn attention and AM brown the other
dimension another
was had criticism even want his novels
hand in the capital his novels and so he
would call upon me
and asking questions and answers me with
no ready answers in
right now and he was gonna be alright on
them
and then you know anybody in here and me
in
his novels and so does all kinds a lot
and made really dance and everything
so I didn't know I was getting stay here
we you know
a just ended came in last minute
and I said you won't have any money to
speak and they said yes
Mason here's a list in everything that I
can see them out
and no and well they said okay she is
gay
okay so a hug me in this is no one like
her
passions right now as a day job is any
computer games
and most interest in new jobs games they
can quickly looking to gain even break
down did
the basics and what kind of game is it
is a first-person shooters a real time
strategy is to
I Nash three classic game and and
this this job location is changed his
fascinating
because yeah I years ago mean really
didn't
Ansley have the technology to do this
naked really didn't have the technology
is that fifteen years ago
and their workers and what's going
around that would be making
location to location is prepared for
military targets
and there yeah civilians were allowed to
get the signals bed
things are going to be offset by and
large amount within an oil change
major house and president clinton a
same quarter ending was called selective
availability
had when that ended and the demons
millions with our
with GPS series we did Gary accurate
location as well
accurate reading snow liane 2340
and and in bed that much more angry than
it was before within about 24 hours
selected then
leading turned up again it started
something when do words in Oregon
with a box things actually back a
as enable her and it had some
sideways and editing a video Kb he would
have guaranteed
get the latching on June in any way back
and post
these ordinance on mines and can you
find it and
very rapidly the US they have really
blame him he was very pleasing
cash is all well and since May 2001
started there's now over two million
geocache is him
and there's over five million people
playing the game geocache
has other location-based games it better
around as well
you cash was not hers on that but I'm
going overseas
many different games going from big ones
and you cashing
letterboxing do something more modern
ones
Google inggris has very popular here
right now
and how many people here playing dress
is hassidic okay
how many people here are geocache is
okay
are an awesome either that letter boxes
UK
I'm it does anyone else like really
identifying with what it is and I played
a game that this is
this is partly why Sam if a lot is on
the front sounds rather be interested in
your head feel free to jack you know
what happened that sounds and
anybody else I have never been there
okay thank and
yeah I was a Indiana something cell
other all the same how location-based
games which means
you where you are physically matters
in the game that's not like
by AP playing nintendo ds I really
doesn't matter if you're playing
and why or playing in Arizona use the
planes ingame
these independent where you are not done
and said
that means and how fast you were moving
at the time sammy's and
and exact location doesn't matter
selections that you're moving
at the time you yes I doing things that
restrains the game
it tells the story and you can put it on
your smartphone and it has a new music
and it's almost like and DJ in place on
them to you linden story in place on
feel the story and the story in the
world was overrun by zombies in every so
often that we start chasing its own
incentivize you to run a little faster
because
is an easy casing and he'll be here it
is like be
CRB E BB be even an addy ran
is the saudis catching that you lose
gear and other things
is there and bring and there's different
chapters in the chapters and our line
you can get the main part of the story
or just landed and just doesn't work and
gym in 30 with people really a mother in
zombies and
and but I'll be going no more that
so the earliest location is im really
does create satellites now be
letterboxing
and Afghanistan in England in the
eighteen hundreds
%uh obviously they didn't have the exact
managing large teams lol
into lose and he would say something
wrong %uh
you starred at this table prissy
I want my along the stream look for the
tree
the Three Sisters tree which would mean
a tree that had maybe three trucks that
were trying to get it
and awesome letterboxing is
they would normally be some are working
class citizen rubber-stamp
so when you have a litter box and a
reason
every a reason I like this but in the
united states now
letterboxing in partnership you get
their news
parts and used to stamp your book to
prove that you been to that letter box
and you have your own personal stamp you
can car
some people find answers it you then is
the sample it's in letterbox
through you were there and west by Max
you and stamps and then with the back
stack wherever it was
you go on I know the boxes thank you
yeah a geocache
generally very similar you go somewhere
you imagine logic warranty crime
minus cash other never dared they rose
above ground but sometimes they can be
camouflaged
and once you find it inside this box
will usually be a logbook you sign would
you name
uses him me but the dayton down in and
then
global back cash with that usually
Austin
always mom in the larger caches
and children loved you hashing the rule
is they're lacking a two-way
Ranjan dash as long as they put
something back and this indeed was
greater value
tree surgery as the general rooms
passions
are generally going to be and now she's
back size and can size
and Amy very small they can be the size
and %uh the line
they're often alanis on they'd be pain
he didn't like sizes available
and we can and I think the check to
advance person
somewhere be all all
home were hidden meaning
it to him seems
so-called virtual one for you only
the first
a little virtual yeah she's room here
injury will millions from Hulu
you know the usual version 11 you home
do you know him signs
European mine yeah
it seven tonight and letterbox should
mention often include some sorta
a message when it was in England he
would leave a letter in these boxes and
periodically someone would come and
collect all
letters than actually send them to their
designated targets Indian
England the letterbox in a bit
differently than they are in the United
States
so this idea reading a letter doesn't
really happen this nation states in the
same
weekend still down to just having that
rubber-stamp but
geocaches yeah have rituals I use %um
and you cashing earlier today and I was
trying to buy as many different types
the geocache
that but I'll into their and
lying in wait my right hand you cash in
fact really doubt that he's run
was a Kickstarter project yes and make
it happen
open-ended about half a million
downloads so far
and their motto yes States Army is the
coming here
and hey it's it's a it's fun I I
surrender then I find it I'll play well
in my car
that we are
snowy mountains can be easier than going
to the demands an hour
them but it is a fun story they get some
real
yeah she'd rather
it but it's a fun story and i guess im
really good ways actors
packing their what's going on and
there's this I'm going to serious story
you don't quite know what's going on in
the world so you want to talk a little
bit now
NYU I hear how did you hear about her
them
like yeah I think you covered mostly
it's just
it more interesting than running along
and
not received any yen the other
activities
on so that how did you
you play it using not often I i Moses
was an audio book so once or twice a
week
mom yeah I'm enjoying it I
that when a lawyer I did it's guys like
podcast I
in some reason and that will make them
okay well
being run you know and then gather some
way kind
visualizing the zombie energy
as this on engines that were necessary
them
added him on Foursquare
anyone I know these people have
repeatedly were square
I is a young people and to check in at
different locations and you check and
more than anyone else
and become mayors a very very basically
placed might have even quality many
buttons and everything
and sentencing decision hackers in me
has
people are very pricey oriented and you
don't want the government watching you
you don't want anybody to know where you
are what you doing
location-based you want people to know
exactly where you are
by the location to be as precise as
possible said
it and then engines and I am were
scrapped millions and objectives every
day there's a lot of people
my head and baseball game and also
is really getting on Sun is now the name
pair when you check in on Facebook you
you can say where you are what you doing
so people like the world in general in
like the world know where they are just
something
very humid air hrs so this is a
Yahoo behind it it's as simple as they
had
less I heard and that many it started
May 2012 massive back story going on but
Internet
shell an action that augmented reality
all around this includes taxes energy
there's a link I'll exam exotic matter
that you don't see them
if you have your phone with you it him I
know but it's an angry
gains a you need your Android device see
where these
its energy are as you the seasoning your
you can walk towards it
with the phone and you collect that
energy and your help
are certain ago that and as your energy
and help goes out you can also email
your areas where this energy is
emanating from Jekyll morals and he's
wheels and then you get into this combat
kind of game is important to me
run claim or lunch 12 actions
Louis resistance or green being in line
your
you I'm him I'm
said rock it
and I was gonna ask what color beams
people around them because there's a
yeah its is a very dynamic game people
who really really enjoy this
this is an example screenshot as reading
as you can see the various portals in a
little bit synergy that are floating
around
yeah when you get a portal even
basic basic happen to you
and intelligence agencies that adds that
maybe depends I am
on this is Ryan's easy in Lakeport
together
if you can't leave reports together your
are you make me feel
and people all over the world that is a
No million downloaded
downs people competing to see how they
you need me and is making his reports
like a blue resistance has been healed
over Italy
you know it really is everybody who or
others interested in the end it came out
in the middle east that was leaning
lebanon
and Israel which was especially
interesting because the border was close
people didn't get across the border slap
he is an ambitious
he is a native created this video %uh nm
in Canada and aidid's measures aimed
artwork heels are they may endanger the
make-believe
a many Kenz were happened the lines will
hamper greets the gym bag metallic
across action prop Friday they work
together
yen it yet really impressive
he had as you you attack poorly jailbird
and sometimes yeah
is going on people isley that were alone
in its your color
Taliban degrades after that a week or so
and sometimes at the rules
lead I am in minutes it has
on people were playing a game that
particular area
I was playing in southern New York say
at one point and I i was just traveling
as you can see the area and I checked
into a hotel
owners Borel near to go home
you know flew over my color and for the
defense I went out there and I at low
levels on my
hang and and head
as an attacking he realizes it going
down energy is
happen energy and I okay there's
something else around here
and happy fairly close usually it is
replacing resonate
it was his return so I didn't return
and in there and he'll be there is no
been standing in london keyes and she is
these moving their location in like okay
and that a hard drive by Hannah no cases
and he's in a drive-by is defending the
portland is a wrap okay
a it there any that yeah
Cincinnati gains and I had my car and I
don't wear any follow-on
yeah so they were so
engine protecting their territory yeah
yeah than 1,300 group realization
I was homes about three months ago
under plans this conference and that we
miss our movie after
about 1 o'clock in the morning and I
love the rumors room
and I stopped the local cemetery move
which
has a lot of girls and as a bonus some
driving around
very very slow blue lights mine and
officer wasn't asking what I'm doing did
say the word
blowing up for all yeah it is a
I'm playing a game on my phone needs
using historical landmarks
miss no freedom and he said %uh only
geocache
I as I was surprised that apparently law
enforcement is aware
as well yeah Barcelona yes do you have a
car and by the New Jersey USA
no no you're fine you doing what you're
doing not be alone after that
it was a they can get you into trouble
Fisher
in weird places so it doesn't recessions
yeah I was up in people here in
different ways
world unity something that's in person
at this culture or something historical
though people gas in it orals in areas
others named world's
Asian be morals like is an idiot are
known as our knees
or else they have something he get
happen for miscarriage
yeah Yahoo generally Indians were here
is my live in safe houses are you excuse
it happens everywhere
her missionaries happened yes him and is
there's a lot historic buildings all
around the area
and my favorite let's play and is
married but
I like it was why I magnin there's no
oppositions
might like to reply morning going out
usually means there's no opposition I
did you tell people that have set their
phones
that wanted their orders is being
attacked alliance
and the people that you find in the
morning if they're gonna stay with me
and a
in the car and more
yeah I did
yeah that's right away I sure
notification I
attack girls are ready ethyl acetate at
that time
then is regarded morning I think driving
yes
charles Murray friend and 11 at
borderline
God more now than at it he said
circle yeah I guess more exam live
through an IV yeah I know what are you
doing
I you know I'm being jazz/nu Julia
having and here's
and I'm is your rights certain Lynn
my looks like and yeah
one yeah old virgin
%uh anyone else having yeah interest
story did
one yeah yeah
there I haven't played much for the
first time I ever went down
play kinda the same experience here with
a drive by there are like two of us and
we just finish placing
or however many resonator is your place
around a
moral capturing and also this car drives
by about thirty miles an hour and
destroys all
yeah it was just someone who was like
level a after the game
been out for two weeks %uh yeah
it and as you say that is interesting
clapper tasaday each porn has a
resonators and real has level level will
be depended I N
level people places resonators so at
level 1
he was at work what resonators it was
you yeah
made the higher loan originator you re
was %uh
world so when you're a level a where you
can only place
one resonator a little a and others will
not sit here
were usually needs a lightly resonators
he
eight players Egypt home is is 10
jeanette world where they have a
resident here
%uh let players in really powerful your
happens yeah attack are they can't get
harder
and the people and people who is right
by smeared on his other hand at
a whole said in their car and it has
your name on it and now
own yeah
problem that is right here and I
or accidents your neighbors players and
its xxx alright rally yeah
but it's the way the game is designed to
constantly
arson unit Jerry Martin world your house
moving very vigorously
happen said in a yeltsin
any other in resources my
are dang yet
okay Mac sorry yes very
that brings up word for
hah daycare across the street
yeah my your
was a dangerous more across the street
from the
here toward him
yeah I was a child
yeah yeah
for this word over yeah right to sleep
years here really
more hands yeah you know said
people with your senators might be one
yeah
who here's a place for copters
like undertrained lasting
there his the right way
word yeah
third-degree called yeah
break does that whole book
jobs there worst members
all I and II my fingers in multiple
cities have my heart
said playing at little rock band playing
at was a
where state was course Atlanta
and he I see the same happens over and
over
I it does yeah you have some really
aggressive behavior
and and the his hand at the
personalisation
the other side I see this happening over
and over blue and green
and reminds me a lot the Serna as I
think it's a a
for university relations and are they
said okay
workers are your cards and live in a
very rapidly
these inserted internalizing when they
were and its right hand there naked
ramifications on hand c.net over and
over again yes
that down yeah did and
with eight years I see it really happens
on the street and talk to people that
run
lucci and is charging all greens are bad
I don't trust the whole screen
players rocks and requires a ok luaus
where doctors and nurses yeah its did
little yeah
tried you can't have people had a nice
and cool wet yet
you have to work together her son on
goal and
so you're absolutely yet to bring
there's work with in with she said goal
and i said im
I would one work with him and it's
difficult really good
a game that has brought out back and
then
I hate all yeah capital G
those people there's booze
who and that %um cross actually does
and dinners classes here
yes me and I know the last person
the heart my business streamers and
another cross ash risen get help break
down side throughout the country
reasonable some other personality when
Jack
years user mother's eyes and
as well I i'm I see that as a yes
and it again in Canada I Lacasse
actually work together really well
enemy hapless absolutely no all the time
so much energy it was sincere in saint
louis
you know I don't see as a hacer process
your day Anderson and
these no I don't hang around those
people
yeah and which is yeah him play
your yeah home and you don't take it out
on someone personally
where is it yeah this is the sort is
actually at high
who switch fashion's elite NJ
a girl any other action yeah it is
really important message action
estrategia
Living Color Enhancer and he had
and him home either
interests stores mine
an had anyone wants to play it is still
there
mothers day yeah yene says here is
acecomm slashing right I got five yeah
everybody and a few hours
it this way a ii-a meet Bedi's
you read in the company handles and a
former and because in the industry and
unit and we had long talks community
slayings the sash man's really hungry
heart about this
antagonism between action as a medium of
something
that is he gonna happen all because
otherwise
it you're only saying he was the enemy
is Erin change
a hassle my ok maybe his present
missiles
I in searching secular and they're
getting this report
at settlers are on that cross actually
yes yeah I hope they had it
began its understanding they're they're
doing software
it's pretty much yeah wetlands makers he
has an answer
its it said
sack yes there
higher something that week notice or
problem
girl
where
makers their Thursday way your hackers
hardcore with technology you're playing
race
no she UK game given what it was
him parade yeah yes
mae tao house his eyes it's a good thing
go ruin everyone's by gene equipment
your body one thing but agrees that use
the euro people using
remark either him no year
while lot yeah gnocchi will ruin the
game
it does I I was a morning
it and just to be been reporting and I
was talking about how
trying to encourage people specially
hackers are playing in your head
not she has a million times the game and
I i've seen that hinders add be
ruin I got my
for all national room definitely yeah
there is there marci injured yeah
all day will room with me here yeah
Russia there was a German hackers I
think in the sediments
and they said that the botnet which was
basically a
I'll players they're going to remove 101
men just
attack portal take it over to the next
world taken over taking over the entire
city turn
the Hoodoo it natcher but The Sims
control any
the other players on the other side
likes red I am why bother playing
and I i love you dad alright I have
another games the evening on the couch
I guess I wanna gave his team of the
couch
going down walking around CNN's anything
with energy like what you can do you
think that on the couch UGG program now
that they've been cuttin
and beans the whole point so I just
thought I'd mention it
president
an xkcd oh well you know i will review
the whole thing but it's basically said
some people inviting themselves over to
a guys house and watching this is not
because it happens very much
or less yeah and
cell here's another day ahead and I just
heard about this
drag that someone came in and told me
that after my time
didn't mention it I like it and let you
know that I'm construct and what it is
is it keeps track of where he knows
start up with that
everything's dark in the city and as you
walk the street at City
like our that area and so did her
religious
more all these little nooks and crannies
in the city it's great when I'm driving
one of the interstates are all that he
has a trip down the interstate
but I can see this is going to get bike
trails
and going at it into different areas min
anyone here abstract player high score
list
him okay thing this is another
location-based game that this tends to
be associated you
yeah she noted 100 mg specifically its
monthly
and they doing this QR codes so they
will hang
a tag like this somewhere and you user
well yeah you scan it and then you get a
point for it
I places you can print out a bench fewer
goods and hide them in different places
and activated again
you can see this QR code is in this
location see your point
placing one season and point and points
for buying Menzies
on and offers ranch in which you cash
because people were mass players usually
also geocache is and it can help
by any looking for cash I
Lindsay and now the cash scattered glass
yes
are are you familiar with the
OpenStreetMap Roger OpenStreetMap I
heard it
%uh again just me never your
to worldwide remain
room improve my house open source maps
the numbers or the new loopholes or
don't know the mayor
with but date back here which is you
neighbor
usual home tourism and it
Tollway you all white people dressing
room
down people
GTO is about this
good shop doing
helpline things like that yeah
p.m. and nothing about a million small
is
but if you go to a website called GPS
finally dot com
and people are mapping trails which I
find raining here in this
like really big park area and you're not
mention the trails are
someone who love God really don't like
to wait wait stamps
and some trail and then they uploaded
then you can download these trail maps
to your GPS
second your last yr same I can use caps
they all look is it gonna be a trap that
he
that way %uh and that I don't have been
so my taxes all I need is
time to get some sort of a satellite
lock and used it many many times
so yeah that people are going open
sourcing all these locations
is awesome casting so a
going and you cashing in a little more
detail there's very different sites
that will that they have cash is there's
old and caching
and and these can be changed their own
database
bed the really the big one on the block
is your cash
the house so that's that's rather be
spending was my time talking about it I
is run by have become perhaps the
at a Seattle I there are I'm here
National Capital Region on geocache is
around the world right now
only 2.2 million geocache in over five
million people playing the game
and you can look energy yeah I mean you
can pull up
a manner that is murphysboro here and
each one of these
up like us here is a cash you can see
someone gets home goor
really is there they actually made a
little picture in the car
by placing caches
is to draw the outline and the school VW
bug out there
see go to anyone in those caches say
goodbye niskayuna solve this puzzle
noted this location
so the only way to see this thing is I
can't match
not have the people that are good Eagle
there's one in Idaho or they just an
area
desert this many many miles across the
whole picture the trainers like checking
on
and another thing that really good
locations in
to so this is an example the cash pages
the cash I placed in her own way
%uh me yeah so cash will have a name
this case I it was their detention
centers I call a meeting of the minds
in having difficulty in ensuring
difficulty will be on a scale 1-10 by
and the jury will be on a scale 1-5 give
me an idea of how much
effort is going to be required to get
you cash so I sure AM one
means very simple wheelchair-accessible
literally
with someone in a wheelchair to get to
this cash change to
in people who candidate exactly what
change in his bed
generally means not wheelchair
accessible but say someone was small
children
a stronger really good chance your mom
get to this cash
stranger I jury 3 you're trying to be
like push
leaves after the way the doing some push
back in
a jury in four him you need to be
prepared for being outdoorsy
hassle supplies probably one don't wanna
be making little kids on a train
or 35 you need special equipment
I it's you're getting a scuba gear
you're gonna be
rebel I'm here and you get a kayak I'm
there's a a cash advance the station
that was placed by Richard Garriott were
British
so that securing I
especially to rock a rather here
I'll difficulty what you're buying the
same thing in the building when he needs
the cash
its in pretty much plain sight change
you
means experience cash it by ear within
half hour I'm searching half hours
actually a lot in
releasing harry groaned but that didn't
happen three and that they got
the difficulty by something serious
mental effort
and and there's some really interesting
because it caches are coming up in the
geocache
senior sidebars homes you have to sell
I we have time I'm gonna show you what I
was created by someone
murphysboro and it's a very techie
at he's obviously a computer hacker as
needed
people to go and tell that somewhere and
he be able to go in and look at age you
know stores
I and organic corn its unaudited to find
the cash
her but when I'm gonna marry at well
generally viewed as I get listed the
cash is better in the area and I'm
soared
I what's called favorite place and
over here this little blue ribbon is
your you can sort on any these comes
with a blue ribbon
someone who's a a paying member geocache
how most people are she's a creeper
35 us here I'll bet your premium member
you can
you get for every $10 cash minute a
point and you can sign that a point to a
cash
bpm and then it's very useful to have
sort by all the cash is an area by which
have the most favored
points and cash is there are rocket
are going to have hundreds a favor
points usually word seems earlier today
and geo caching
and I did the same thing I said what's
the highest Avery Point cash
in Murphysboro I'm
an instance and a cashier the library
he started ornaments minutes isn't a
church in ninety degrees and 36 faces an
interview this in turn
whom were cases going through this door
and what it's dragging you
into the library it your town square and
it directs you to
as a civic shell and whether the books
on the shelf is a big book
and then you open it up and inside
there's a lot happening inside my body
but you put the book back on the job
now they have information on the library
in all this and what I want to do it
they recommend him he was laughing and
he doesn't look that is not letting
signage is like 10 years on people that
in mind that these caches
sign your name and contact now %uh
you may have noticed people for cash
because a certain amount of snow
is a good idea you don't wanna am saying
is many kids in the area they see you
like pulling a box
mother tree inside buddy banks getting
an industry
what is that they're not gonna know
they're supposedly they're gonna take it
home
session there's two ways and us there's
a word for this
the geocache yeah geocache starting
popular around the same time that Harry
Potter started becoming popular is the
word much you cash
is don't blink moguls see so get the
cash
disappears where it is it's been bundled
and sell it
it happens gathering all the time but I
am yeah im down did 88 cops I didn't
know it was
80 K begin at maybe an animal dragged
off because they sell to you never want
to put food in cash
against sloppy angela is something I
wouldn't be sick and here's something
don't have food in a cash is that
there's a box out there who didn't
animals are gonna come to that box and
again in June after their contract
anyway
a also anything you wouldn't cash you
wear
that your cash his family activity don't
put anything yet you wouldn't wanna
three-year-old see and so nothing
W your pledge yeah interview nobly and I
said yeah
required step with yeah adults
explosives and I'll
your and yes it will then I have in my
hand and i own a cash
c7 their specially here and I'll within
those cards you know that the industry
I'm I think but I'm 13 year old thinking
isn't helpful
yeah cash in hand you can just take a
look at
object to that thing at times and think
you know looter
cash am Sam now
and passion maybe many different types
gashes goes back to what you were saying
earlier that virtual cash
the most miss stanton yeah a tradition
in cash
which means the boxes catalog
incitements its size shoe box and Hannah
bill while all these are traditional
caches
even if it's really makers passion
delaware call there he hatched
which is am you go to the court in San
you find a small James had his eyes to
the park and that's a chain link fence
you open it up in again isn't he in says
little chances use the side door and
your
parking lot and there's one of these big
fan heating ventilation
air conditioning there and yet he over
the side to work
light comes on and it's like a little
other in
there the entire they have is the cash
they didn't like it
morial someone's there's that little
writing yes log book
and there's a little boxes the moment
but slack to trade and its
is maybe so as big as that yes though
it's still a traditional cache
its its object no more the hash is one
where
when you go to the corn is ready cash
page you're only getting
who to where the cashiers for your next
who's going to be
these can have as many as ten different
hops firm on the cash
virtual cash as he described it might
there may be a physical object that many
information sometimes again in a virtual
cash earlier today
a chance where upward everything was
there they
was very partial going on with you
vintage cars but
had to walk around I'm certain
historical plaques
and finds a way answer questions what
was here
from 1816 1823
as I'm oh this is the state capital yea
in so you learn more about Mary virtual
cash hugely important sir
puzzling mystery caches i knows I have
ciphers codes
trivia questions to answer a jigsaw
puzzle sorrow
a the sky's the limit any in place
cash anybody because others yeah ash
owner
there is a certain review process there
is no you really shouldn't be saying
that will check the cache to make sure
there's nothing really stupid and like
when you put it on a railroad track
renewal an interstate highway
in or in the middle and elementary
school his last thing you want is a
French people and while you're at an
elementary school
and looking for something yeah %um
and they don't as long as you follow
certain days
rules about wear casually and he did you
post another cash tacit least
agenda my heart 520 eighty
part and usually is the problem %uh
sometimes a
help our trails are those that it when
roadwork ashes like every 10
mile and he will raise have any cash is
a combined using
really time yeah a gathering
for cash inside a virtual cash but its
your learning something that geology
again 100 cash today in his brain
is there cash let you know they're
treated blacks get information
usually some sort consummate and the
geology here
I had to learn a little bit about
limestone and limestones and restrain
I'll where no and I can john told me
that we're gonna easier companies were
geocaches in a sec
computer games and I written Hill
at like RPG is that you're going from
here
queen bee and where you are changes the
rules
changes happening in his place and route
100 whereas on the
is going to gym where it says
starting the engine is location you go
to that location
and it is OK looks like a hotel parking
lot actually
this is a hospital in San overrun by
zombies and your goal
is defying Asian 0 satins on the play
defined mission 0 Elin
an actor's own so who was last seen 730
that way yes yeah
when you get there then the horror and
this is your day well as on the way here
then he have been signing any taxes on
the area anyway and so you know they're
play the game and eventually in by an
axiom in Stop The
suddenly and he's very good with it
purges
game I have to conquer his they're
they're all over the place again I did
what it is today that was yeah
available and I think you've been
reading customer again
and go to a place January but yeah I
need to figure out where the photograph
was misinformation
lies them meet included an extra and
then later boxes I i rehabbed
iraq's me so this is an example of a
puzzle cache
I is eaten was and I know this guy has
awesome
his cash murphysboro is that everyone is
in cinemas
need the cash is just 25 and
you guys is gearing them okay
am so this is the only who in the cache
page
and he did that and then the cash 25
well
some you be ready sends a very famous
yeah a
yeah airplane though if you look at the
on the right
is the actual cm the one on the left is
the one cache page
so exited the
now is different the actual samples 24
cents
and yeah is prices again the ashes name
25 so this way I was going as a
mediation human sources
and and see what was going on and I
don't you can see is what you need
no agency that URL instead it was not be
most Gretzky who is being hosted at show
me I G
SMPP Ashanti idea com slash
ale yellow slash where you find that GE
so anyone that has no protocol SMTP is
mail protocol yellow is also mail
protocol
and evasion and yeah it was awesome very
interesting in
he cashed a check ordinance also would
it yeah
90 square has been where do those
cornice points and when I did Google
Maps
and these are the Hornets pointed to
mailbox
so again this is being male to male so
it long story short mention n
and he and see that it wouldn't help
lead you
yeah show yahoo.com board
25 and I got this really interesting
long
spots during their those unit recognizes
asking me realize that this is not
a normal part a response stream in this
case
this was a boner yeah with an extension
so
I could call here any way they can call
it and you get a recording and reporting
congratulations now leaving the senate
emailed to you
Yahoo address
after right here yes 25 min is your
passion
and then gives the actual at lunch
important then
you go to record its R&D in Syria
Penn yeah its in the basement as ours
and
signs near Highway lose a chain link
fence well you know that poster those
chain link fences
sometimes it can certainly not and has
not send this case
to the camp office how to cash in on
those
there's little street nearby seen here
market bill
water from the stream pour the water
into the fence post
cash to blow to the top anything in mind
sign a lot
oh my god them
so he said here yesterday bright
overhead since then other caches like
this that require
I'm web page impressions certain time
is that enhances where his hidden things
and who is director in
the dairy industry they handed
just a lot and really he doesn't yeah
icon that him have there been any
changes that there's a
geocache ham radio something that would
be
yes at I don't have any specific caches
that intersect you're getting every
night on a geocache is or ham radio
operators now be there handle
there's like 10 a.m. in Missouri where
his hands and 0 WN he jizzes
Sam call sign in as the energy and ashes
with you get the license plates for
million it needs to be
if somebody's making a puzzle cache it
generally
needs to be even in the realm 'em
an amateur Salt Lake really great
high school student been solved this one
that I should be with you
raymond et les really high level is
marinating it was little
are there is one thing wouldn't have no
clue how did telling me that they knew
they needed to tell him when it happened
walls were you able to do it you know as
the ones made you cash
yes ago from
on simulations and he's proud of his
puzzle cache is
there and subcategory as cash a
challenge cash
enchanted anything like mine
29 catches a single day before you can
lock the slim or
line seven different heights and cash
san Diego has cash he has turned his
name hates caches
one day I a virtual cash a happy puzzle
cache
and where to go my guy and earn cash and
I'm happy
initial cash in Atlanta and excessive a
nice catches in one game
which would qualify hebrew challenge
somewhere and we shall
that I thought was cool did those
different on
so you may be familiar with his hands
mass of the Delorme mass
in these usually what he said is what
he's very say some
one is other to form a challenge in my
heart every city has it
is defined in cash I every page at the
Lorena
age 25 page 26 th 7 and
its yet people it is nearly should be
more energy
challenge yesterday I think the has
anyone ever Geneseo radio
you know where the job him and thinking
that its owner
he said not sell but fashion 'em
is also something on the Jasper
challenge
is to buy any cash that has been lays
in every month since you cash in hand
you cash
started May gymnasts and binding caches
place
in a gym pass find it cass is placed in
June 2000 July
yes I'm yes is considered one
the premier challenges in geocaches
complete Jasper Johns katherine is the
name
cash it it came up with it California on
ending his loans cash so much for every
day they get my goal
E-cash and resides in my region cash
anymore
another thing and are already missions
with bronze medal and a cash in an area
anymore
summers others arms there is no more
than a half a dozen caches
place in yeah I think I'm still doesn't
work
in the world so you really have to
travel he might be just
no its not that busy challenges and
wounded
from your challenges that member John
netted
ok injury Wnt I'm sure he wanted by CNN
with a bridge is especially I you 1 1.5
2 jeep-like nice you have
81 walks integrated and Ashley want my
reaction to her for an hour
all these am shall only is she invited a
slight cash
for every block in grid with his the the
is in charge
I is home busy being has been joking
started it was a cashier
and in busy magic who was writing he
usually is
infielder cashes in by and binding will
be foundation difficulty during happens
a busy man eileen is in the business and
vision
so busy that you can add yeah the shower
has a deputy
not busy with a well-rounded challenge
on
is there's a lotta sad as completing his
yeah
currently a leading the Jasper and she
walks away from completing his ened by
any cash isn't the only one train for
Hannah
and it'll be july hatchery
four-and-a-half and whatever reasons and
here in Genesee right now is the second
by both these yassin
as the very essence pouring rain so many
girls learn
edition is I'm and cash across america
is another day challenge we have to find
cash in shape but not just
a hash NBC as simply
in every state there's hidden caches us
I'm cash his Washington DC and it has
the cash
-ism said one lesson here I think
there's a parts out was a national
caches
absurd passions and whose area the where
Walt Disney
that childhood home is Anna instance
again is a challenge to here him are you
sure dashing any challenges
these three challenges Yasmin busy in
cash
Rossoneri good as mine yeah is a girly
sacks like visit Maryland and then
go away all I was right next to the you
can trust me anything wrong
yeah sure I was right next to a June
2000 cash
yeah she don't wanna miss get a chance
that Laurean
I County I not just fighting cash I
every page
the 290 cash every pound see
which is really good years Wednesday
trading go gary told you know and their
at home UK go into more detail about
most people are smart phone cash these
days I resorted to customers even all
school hasher
smartphone I henry's by GPS in
and it is being with my hands you can do
is pay abstinence
okay argue that he's good I a general
strike people are
more more undead Slayer cash in which
were securing an urban environment
because you have that so axis or yeah I
still have a GPS chip bill
yes even if you're not within cellphone
range wifi range
is a figure out where you are I
generally
have both usually is a smart bomb but is
there a second hand lol
on way no service so did have an actual
GPS is
ACA general rule is you always want to
have mobile homes navigation never have
just one
or navigation as he needs a great is thy
on the world you drop it the battery to
die
hmmm yeah River I'm
yes yes always right he removed the
worst
be also I'm house in cash is and isn't
is there are different ways represent my
country my kitchen
I A B Duodecim yes what you can do it
will use yeah it is
the differences in so is on ESPN where
did you work as a cashier
just what heinz werner's they may have
represented
the general rule is is I is Andy like
more
38 degrees worry point and then
something
yeah in with your cash in a I G stack
handed I good nugg
classes when he sent this is a very
powerful database program called you
ashes I'm wishes you can download
thousands
caches brown beer and seek sanctuary
from him
filled with only radiates queries and
are messengers in raising it really is
region especially school unit cap
challenge might be
fine and cash it started every letter in
the alphabet
as it might wanna under sunlight hahaa
me to start with the letter M
you know that ended miles there W lower
than three hands he writes known
really losing worries that way am and
if you're looking for cash and is a you
go shoot in the area
your words like huge any Jeezy Ground
Zero
and that we put away GPS as even SUVs
is Zack its 10 vacation any funny
and then you hywell at air here are your
GPS the air and we'll replace it
the day after or death in a place the
cash so
even if you say 0 the way you should
then search in Berlin
thirty-year worldly day
your area I'll and it looks and and the
ordinary most Holland
he an area where there's a certain sure
reason trees
is one for ILCs yeah usually added six
this decision is high and 6 30 Rock's on
they don't look at the ground %uh ashes
are often injuries
passion for his medicine can parse I
I'm lots to do is a highly cash
and sense a gash a little and accuracy
other LPC the lamppost really a Walmart
shouldn't have posts there's a certain I
lappam's science name so few
lift that skirt usually basically
cash andrew de a is a easy ways I
yeah I'm haiti is it doesn't like the
Islamic percent I
you can you can do that LTZ a truly
morning
and shares the same day are real cash he
will but I had
and Andrea is not legal rehash
guardrail I knew she know if you like
are
lot behind Walmart it's it's legal but
yeah
can should always have permission
a they should always have me don't i
wasnt he should always have a mission
from the property owner
and he rarely pay cash advances
I yeah chalet
his chair there let madala
like 11 yeah and like
here mock
that rock country watch out
like the awful likes that rock
yeah yeah and there's danger people die
geocache I he has a degree in and around
at all the time
is a fellow that happens a lot it is
their location yeah
further I am ages what Rambler I'll
or a heart attack home your have
lower so is is good know where you're
going with him
as though these numbers and contact here
your PC well cycle i SAT SEP
he thinks yes generally that mark
fuhrman
you cash a more experience caches
place the cash will know that
the proper etiquette is merely posted in
blog he has along
is your way thanking the cash in their
replacing the cash
begins feedback it continues the story
so
I in when he's the nice to new hampshire
is right
guidelines sometimes you need to hurry
but GN TC
you can always go back later in his
right arm or stand in line
tiananmen to nothing left nothing
s
else I'm on and yeah did not find
a some people I'm there's would be an
abscisic
yeah if you don't mind in cash
postlets.com yeah
did not I'm like it it serves many
purposes it tells the cash only
cashmere the model on perhaps they have
the difficult he said she loved it
there's a lot of good reasons to post
Vienna at sea gel
is a Titan Medical cash in trash out and
cash we get together and I don't mean to
be there
hildebrand trash bags in Australia trash
bags
and no one can mine trash when did you
get she
his you know who it is and you're
looking at anything they have a a
museum and it feels really good style
since the cash is easier to buy into
beer cans are gone
I'm path yeah phone brand you have any
cash
is perfectly fine dining hall bring your
society and the cash and say you know
yeah where is it them ever plays the
game in a different way
ads as another important takeaway that
geocache is nobody plays in the same way
some people want to be very strict they
they never wanna ask for a hint
am the very strict about logging
and other people it's much more casual a
one controversy might be. if there's a
high jury
cash say their son David other clan
something like say you're gonna have to
live in cash huber's
sleep I know that with my net cash
people say look how was it
group 10 people we got this Friday yeah
I hear you would have to get a cab ride
down we all signed a bit socket
I love the room route cache is OK %um
categoria mindless from no unifying
and yeah this is a whole nother level a
place on the way with a dress for people
get really into buying
people there helium geocache are often
very much in the first by 20 cash
publish their foundations as my way
enable race
you can be the first person by name cash
others people who will say I've got a
hundred yes and that you
yes there's they were great speed limits
table rendering private property
they want them yeah at me I got a few
yes usually crashes that is no one else
down in four days and I have resolved
must not win any cash
that some people really aggressive that
and get comfy in FB account to um
was passionately I won't go into a home
but
they're all over the place E the
designers heat sensor
classic has listed the hustle I could be
the check it doesn't like Asian Tribune
a mathematics he could be images am
and it's like here there's a serious
cash
agents as the club was here and I don't
you dance
yeah yeah here we have here they momma
like the image the Redbirds
my he will sixty-something
in Jersey there's a little whom there
and there's another
go down here am and this one's a
mathematical puzzle
yet gets there numbers and with that we
will figure
this is a this this person on the cash
will be able to cash a check with this
view on him
great I'm and it was a it was
hundreds lines apps where ways and and I
looked at and I knew what it was
is that it was my hand and and the news
they with the ones the residence where
there is no those three thousand since
there was no way I was gonna sit down
and
by have transcribed 3,000 that
I was telling everyone else the geocache
nearly done something else whose line is
it a chance for a bit
hand and it was instead in as I think
a bit ASCII am and ask you to love them
by investigators
9 a.m. yeah I heard this is why
indianapolis
I'm and it's not gonna show up their bed
the corner to hear what you need to do
you pull this new an image program and
then change the hue
on one and there's any evidence they
cannot be the cords are actually there
crystal ball it's just in a color this
one off from the rest
the colors there now there's also gadget
caches and west virginia has a lot again
cashes where I want yes it is you will
not be able to solve this cachelocking
you will not be able to find cash you
are riding a bicycle
or motorcycle you need home and you too
will the most people have been here
and what it is he didn't pull up to the
cash you need to get your jumper cables
out
can connect your battery and connected
to the posts on the cash
which denotes last name get like that
there's a catch yes underwater
with and just as a whole is coming at me
to bring a bicycle bomb
any deposit its blue which brings the
catcher
yeah little stumbling into the
groundwater others are kinda little
birdhouse cash
you're having a big year at sidebar
relaxin yeah I'll
the birdhouse it all kinds of things
also
with diana is an NFC talked earlier
today is there any cash showing up with
a busy day
now so all your mind is this the little
in in the little guy he had my head I
want do it by hand written down in June
in a way that she did quartets there
then being here tonight
tell you where the actual cash is yes
you like a musical talent a handsome
and trackballs and on line 109 have that
these are items
toys began to have a number on them the
measure that number
see no online you can see all the places
that particular item is gone Strathclyde
he will train travel items and their
yeah
yeah I won't go into great detail on
itself
want to get involved and you can join
the community
getting hacer room if you want to become
a premium member did she
there's also hundreds on Facebook is
probably in Tennessee
you cash group and April 01 Google+
I'm make friends with the hasher's have
your own cash name
also for long drives wonderful
lighthouse
for geocaches are the most popular well
as well I'm passionate and San Diego
has been white units and the insanity
and once a week they think it is great
but has a
any places you can choose and use it was
a bomb scare somewhere something I did
you catch is a bomb or
I'm just going up and down sit and talk
about the good news stories and its
unless you when you're driving 150 miles
to get here
Bryn Mawr check check and years
republicans found your heads
it's happened at an impasse that are
showing up on phones now
I'm heading for GPS technology in
various progress I was gonna mention it
again
players you want an external battery
because it eats
your phone hacking like nothing
there's even I'm and there's awesome
passable best season ends
geocache they bring in hundreds of
people have been this
brings in some people's and that brings
ever 500 people is what other may get
there
you get an extra eye time for that and
and that is actually a naked man
in my can say charles is our next year
goin shot
am settle the debate in the attention
and these are the controversies in geo
caching
I was other ATL ours additional logging
requirements like if someone places
passions as
in order to block this cash there's a
camera in cash you take pictures I'll
I and you don't take pictures on the
camera into your life and then
people were were yeah arguing about this
one is a leading all
cash in on grounds he actually a ruling
saying is let's call it a large
additional I'm
requirement it is not require only thing
you need to get credit for cash is
needed by now but we need to sign in
with the exception to the challenge cash
is how I like to do more
but they can take picture yourself they
they can't make you mine
you go out in your move a rock in a
certain way those those are our allies
and those are all illegal
virtual caches they no longer allow
people to place them in stock several
years ago
because be more cynical I really don't
ritual caches
had like yeah drawing attention to the
words and say no
I and the generation tell me what brand
is the 10 ish yes it was a virtual cash
it was very
using virtual cash so because it was
causing so much
angst is that okay number rituals album
and other countries is
NRK cash and cash for the cash in his is
OK
I no longer maintain his cash and
archiving is that it doesn't show up one
day they say more
but sometimes you even
NJ you're still out there might be like
way out miles
hike in ages don't like to compare well
some people still don't know
going to find the cash in a sign a lot
in the go ahead and and a lot of mine
may be getting one
or some people say yet has the cash
there are other people say no it's not
jet is the cash rx7
is a controversy I am I mentioned I'm as
part of a group
because everyone happy high above the
clouds are not go by net cash
some people say yes some say no I'll bet
is like owners GPS
and Granger in difficulty there'll be a
lot of arguments that isn't changing his
legendary
idea jim is very millions designs
were close a.m. said am
placing a cash handy only down
you recommend a good place here find at
least
a hundred passions for your place in
cash
humour ill for your house has some
is don'ts and again if you take
something leave something illegal or
greater value
posting a lot on line these may get more
than just the FTC
also 300 cash as well or better
it was when you found it %uh and the
cash is in there
this is another controversy some people
say they have they're they're sure it
was Michael
use pollen from them sale don't put in
new cash
Jan
well I sure hope was not able here are I
hope that nobody knew contained
jeanette do that unless you have the
cash owner
and said I think it was not was an OK UK
may yet its controversial cell summary
location-based games religion usual
right but
as smartphones get better and better and
as location techniques GPS it like that
girls are getting more and more accurate
were more names are showing at this
really opening things up to the public
hun
letterboxing geo caching resolve it's
usually for you
no way to have fun and I
that thank you %ah