low everyone many years
make pleasure this is the first time
I've ever spoken here review
welcome raoul their I
Haneef guys I love audience already
I come to you for this in the past year
never really got much into it as I
yeah I don't know how I'm so busy most
anchors
figure out do not trust is not his
number expressing my own knowledge to
you or
need me
under I'm a do I make my store online
I'm SEC im administrator at Russian
Smith and partners
wanna podcast deployment ask.com
that the nothing but with deployments
SEC you know I'm
any questions you have on builds the
whole
was not my cats and water also what
about the same stuff
bring ikea.com animals on iowa's
well
today we'll be talking about
appointments and what goes into
points all work the per se me to do is
there are
several layers your we have to define
points all when I first started when
SEC administration character SMS 2003
I just jump right in didn't they do
about them
project management processor and you
coming home will be down there
Matt users Matt management and that's
when I wanna
product management for and start eating
project management
techniques and really work for me and
its
giving me a relationship with staff
clients
which is the more usual company I work
for and its
Union respected I'm I like blown off
their
first because at first I didn't know a
whole lot of girls
doing and starting who saw horror
my gene that was Yahoo force
re right yeah so the first thing we did
well
look at is deaths here there are the
bizarre
stakeholders communications which me
communications is probably of
call think jeanette with some
preparation getting everything set up
what you need to do you home it package
1gb 8gb you get the employees ready for
work
the ration packaging and actual
point
the bins
thats person in my environment
is for britain comes to me and will say
he you push
sons of Korah right now I'm working on
machine Microsoft Office 2013 now times
hacer worse office 365
actually actually known
perkin-elmer baby is gonna be here in
the AM was born
drastically you're actually
know her no pian
no the story huge this gonna
business business owner is the first
person humping
person is actually going to you
resources to deploy is offered
them able to solve were able L he
no such thing and there's a
Liz that I devise that I use in my
company
this one comes to me and go through this
list NDS what
give me a good relationship with im
for analysts are here goal
what goal is intended at the home wish
by reforming is a obvious
ball wanna saw weird
stop Bollywood play wire
what did 81 achieved by this then the
Alliance
humanity point
I mean lifetime that that bears
it's not always come by. our in
architecture and engineering
we've got different disciplines I'll boy
different class of forty different I'm
engineers runs
now business owner BP that the big one
what kind mediation USI
one you have with and the latest one
updates a 1gb mem blue everything about
one right now that I'm doing
into copy every email I send now strong
Russian your start date
in a both those that when you're
ballot warns packaging time
always humanist min
but 10 this list with the
business owner in you can't block every
yeah
all the lot lacking in one part in the
person
and then go out what's next happens and
come back today
user is a like prices the problem never
even
they don't know anything about firms and
in like what are the requirements
he did tell you what is required
prerequisites
users in duly
trainee wills other stuff like that
what needs to be in place this
installation method
now what will take place on to install
person
I use PowerShell I Springs
all my appointments machines all or
use DVD Shrink ass wish our show like
two years ago
asking more partial eat now
it really is is so powerful and
iraqi cash yeah it's kinda like Windows
merging
measuring okay for the over-allotment
they do. go I'm even more I am prime
right now getting
great partial re and impartial or
just came out here three years
I'll so I use those
me I still use actually wanna s cool
that
ever used in the woman Microsoft SMS and
sour
it is was but I have my phone SMS 2003
but he is still in the race
28 years old yea very slick program
were just too much symbols written
morale
really easy to you can still
down net is still there while
there you don't wanna method Lee users
Beatles let me install software
this is been our big one right here
that's one million in June
becoming a in this speeches backup
how users get the solver
and their is with a mobile platform that
you're now
aspin might be is herbal doctor
back we saw for is because he's gonna
people as a laptop with done shops and
I'll see
never been reviewed it is a software
that needs to be rebooted
Benjamin Stalham war so that
back with just one through your weeks
ago our technique how we're going to
handle
all these high performance in the future
and then
failures are by your hand you're always
going to have values when you're in
points of her own people machines for
SEC
him whatever one software you use how
you handle
gotta technique that I use nailed it
it's been pretty effective than on me
last moment at call you and say hey
she and it was wrong and monitoring
Howell won't be monitored
I usually get our business owner the
link to the
SEC in my page and here watchin see how
the what's going on that doesn't better
well love 12 so for we usually get that
same information do to help yes
they actually monarchy testy
asking though you're really important
worse
what steps take place in testing package
we shall and then the training materials
at be an SEC a man
yet we're ahead him why did you do for
and whose
software because you was that offer a
people that call you
we're gonna say what's wrong Mahal or
and about that they don't care
saw for now I'm still really rusty
you know paths in the mall our helpdesk
actually happened
know what's going on him
the first thing you
the after that is owners your state
dollars stakeholders
are your developers people that actually
have invested in
want and going with him because
right now i'm brushing my saw office
out that I'll of around
2010 I'm given them there's a horror is
deafening
a Mona bush burkina as we've gotten
ahold
written around Microsoft Access you know
images
I and for every year
but myron all them
he got definitely my yahoo or
stakeholders
and resolve conflicts with the numbers
before you she with the actual
want what are our functionality as a
result we
after you got it said you got the
I'll send or whatever changes need to be
made lloyd et al
and then you know those stakeholders
make a money that she
army everything okay the sign off on
your
or for a useful
the communications back to me he is the
be is are the whole moment process
were you made it home or successful
you don't have a white communications
with users
your screw room I'm
hey perfectly good the Hornets
or and I'm mistakenly thought are
is or install no users are issues with
it
or seven-point an odd
people furious and and I was like I
don't worry that the wall
and with all the car User Communications
the
your ass enne de think I have social
are you because you know
and you did do your job and you don't
need a
you're gonna have met people weather is
it does or not
and then after I it's certainly my
communications I mean I had one that
instead
was disaster because I didn't really
have a shoot another with everyone
no one was my hair understanding it was
a
statement was made and correctly
and with no wrong and at all because I
had good communication with use
that's why I highly stress this
the most important part on the whole
one process as you have a Google
or with your in use then understand
good if you don't you know
days specter everything you do be for
which I know everybody here knows that
being an IT
and others
I had to learn the hard way location
or soloman the Asian business owners
you want to continue with the updates
throughout I'm me who that person
here she is burdened given you reform
you there the lawn sign all
rock save over course
my own personal way I did
I am only after they sign oh only
issues arise at that point
there's really no reason in the him
in lieu at a lakeside all
Information Technology Park
level in more minute hell yes all
always be my home yes in a looong
100-point
because is easy
that are you star only days laughing
right
and help yes is long but
they don't know what's going on they
don't know works of Korean
I didn't know that you were born this
they're definitely
yute be used and ninety when he
im when morning he bill he not today
because usually most here deployments
you know he's going to have to have
thought word
include in bill border collie
either hurts their always be
all managers ID lower
would be fallin in luv frightened mainly
AAA administrators frightened be in the
loop on later
maybe the prolly because I use
aate mine testing their her
and resistance will give you the
resources to help other people out
feel when you boy they
maybe life me office 2010 in that body
Harbaugh I'll the whitens ten dollar
company operates minds of dollars game
all our AAA home hey
uses for Mom here's a copy for your home
and worker they
the at all our wise
include month with office 2010 and it
went very smoothly so definitely does
that happen
born all specially you know im
or go online ministries people that
people in your firm
are going to go do for help and report
them
your man amo this
clientele that s what up in
%um game on here for a while prepared
equine like your administration's
I'm all they
army huge asset resource the
definitely man Jim or any other time
person we all know that we have in our
offices
technology or neighbor each one or more
losses
you and S well so leverage their
resources yes were all your require
yeah I'm want definitely
I with our was call we have all
or 11 to amass communication you know
not over Maria with a
huge on you now also they see that their
inboxes
Co exactly white like we really had me
on the tree
forces there you go but a nevermind I'm
and that's a whole day is keeping
yourself
Howard unity points where you're going
to be a lot owners
you know they nor your email and INS
still I mean I just
was deluged women out here last week
there were probably did you send any
attention
and didn't name names I'll themselves
you know
their love you man and
real acknowledged he's gone mad
created I always create employment
schedule an apology on share
I go through our list overcome your
about 700 employees world news and
before actually do on or a worthy
all users online their a this
one-time and they had and I'm sure
create a calendar app book each one of
those
users what day going to get Bush
energy he said in an email asking reason
why I'm
I'll love it cesium use copy rather
deployment flexion alcoholism only
username stationary beyond on angry
recognizes them jiang he didn't know
push come
so me and how important not only the
mutation that is me it didn't want
in user like for wow just sayin is
what are you that's one thing in the
mail they've got
yeah on others a coming out all
users him random number people and
models
call on Thursday software his own regime
ya know somehow SEC he only has three
way
going injecting seats offers and Wally
you know Rajshri be knew about you know
I
on good or by
file well as we all know
though the Eagles wire mesh he's still
we all mess up
machine albeit reluctantly on what you
do
send me know up to present
home retin-a hey here
offer okay where
good and no
the whether or not offers a leading
1 although the business owners
all the stakeholders I'm all alone that
one
hey are out there done or
Ryanair's you know again
the nation's William is is her
is most important more in pressure
prepping for that one you know your
requirements
software requirements your user
what train use it for free
me is are usually create a website
injure morning down a hole and resources
be usable its Eagles
and but another two years I'm not a
that doesn't sound right to me and he's
the man either
people me G know you saw word bush
and he already knows how to push he
don't know
I'm not okay mining engineers are not
know how to
wire saw the potential design
mobile the brain is definitely
more that's why I need it definitely
your help yes noses
and documentation of
with both really
BS humanities it more lodging management
me yeah side is a huge project
management
pack and I first I thought
when I started doing it like one
waste always doing all those did on
man's
and then a learn how really important
years the haps 5.9l
out there well doing packaging
the schools them I use stripping
as soon as well you know I after work a
I mainly use powers joanne is an earlier
as is our is pack
times brought in a DLL and I i mean SMS
sour
Ely Austin and
like less than a minute me XQ and I
actor we don't have another actors their
exes
most and I packagers alan was here
life calls and that's why I like and
were me a new era inner thighs or
for me there router NY and borge
work is on national and actually
anti-missile
breeder model
but I use the PowerShell mainly
no reviews partial war stripping a
is all its robust very powerful
usually what so harsh
lhasa check have actually are designed
standardized installer or orenthal
were I figured out all night long in now
and its going through a of big 80s
software that install Hessenthaler built
into it so you can actually
use the eight and install or uninstall
does bother
arms million ma'am it's really easy you
know
are you don't have to do all MSI
Ranbir's anymore
iraq Italian worry system and no
bind to do it and then do man my mind I
their bring do dinner action
looked up in
ration for free I'm anaesthesia
that's the other or you can actually use
unlike the old SMS going to use it as
easy young
to manage the higher one without having
to use
reason I
don't you there and I use through is
because there are three
and use I'll is I saw were I won't cover
rights where I want certainly work
one when this point the SEC I'm
went to work maybe you don't become
Marshal Sir I want to work for Mac and
want your warm
immedi- some vino lithium audience are
working all
Rios and use and
s SAT and actually handle as you don't
work
and you all in one a heart attack
in creating other one religion should be
changed
but that doesn't give you the option he
do command line obviously it breaks on
burdens and how this is day and media
resolved software with that partial cure
their
Blackburn am rains all learn
held as in past and we're actually on
our nation's
nation was saw nothing
do everything should be and
mustard getting
specialization mission on me is and be
able to make
your the place of work
deployments we w
as easy owners was also SMS which is the
Owen
80s verification
as a irrigation is definitely wanna
important parts
appliance yeah I'm gonna make sure you
know
all your white someone because with
black ops that we would want to
you Liz LoZ
and redo that's why we have your
interaction
that actually were
we have gone we don't do the Army is all
the more me call
others black me we had
lame we give away is would with software
we get home
using Wii U mass and we ever had
to their partner yes %um and we
bomb arm the emails alerts okay he's
there
solid you're only here but no installer
this day
eight-man board it's all the way it
works with your
there are more on angeli well for us
madwoman a the level of success
not grant his orange and we went from
probably in person Lacasse three years
ago
now each time arms we planned 100
percent here
by the end of next year so definitely
much worse hunting area was all learn
troubleshooting
policies and rule the worst thing
approach I used her that he is
SEC hungry mouth
Wednesday okay well the
frequently rerun laughter and a
he's very well I use BST their
background a whole is a machine gunner
hey I'm
run yes the second man line for sir
installer against the regime and then
follows
and don't fail on their I'll
their successful mood article is
one still don't install the last one
last shot
all there's nothin no way around it that
way
I think yes exactly brutal
be able the lower level is a barriers
from
yes on and out there the whole
not only the whole with CPU model on an
error
see especially Michael on and always
come down
they have something running in the
background this
gone that long Sather
going there file usually
number people at your house owners you I
am
max huge
there
so that's where we
we've got a new this year
show you all
and that'll is there's I'll that a
may your are how we determine how
solvers and the Blues home
the clothes are the best option we
cannot wear and is
come the numbers are not in the business
owner
all and so we had to tell whether you
thought were
like mandatory does your hand through
the Afghan ages
you well a one-off all
Danny the crucial wanna Sun
question that we have warm and is
home is going to be an application
closure
me know that happen horsely close I am
with insulation
through and minuses and really and then
that's what universe
go through this chart here germans
how we want all were three scenarios and
you to read no
interaction all and Eli hot days
something done are you no user action
all hines
number to you yeutter
my custom one of the earlier the user
has home
the same we gonzalo themselves
and it becomes mandatory net
annenberg one which is online
these like Hey
31 completely harsh round as words of
was there
consult was there they won dull
them never or snow and this is
watch really transformed my job company
relation the in users there
given so much better were with them and
build up some all movies that have been
created in hand and
is her method that I highly recommend
and you need you all want isn't here SEC
in advance
you're interested having out there my
boss you here
watered-down and the same things
rivers I have all partial spirits are
written about uninstalling
stoller 100 route they run by blobs of
the question
weird
well we have a %uh in a broad agreement
with Microsoft anything
leading our dream SEC amir's
we're actually going also with Sesa on
right now
an A in a group that our himself for
taking the time to
in all in a group that asset tracking
in the farm like legal now
I'm Essex cm12 heart remained more
homogeneous
harbors all or so warm and then you
agree more
yes %um for the healthcare needed up
today
this time who had what mom
him at retail about ask us about the ass
you know it skip ask our
forget all I know yeah more
yet we had two thousand by s Carolina
yet I am why one word for you
Nacchio's yeah week behind
I heard that screw ascap it
is that a worst really worse
go back to not use
as good to know reactions surprised
yes that's a good tool model
but not use is monitoring that is injury
yeah
'em democratic there's a hell
it's a freeware program out there is
available
was not remembering comes the inner
products Mr
trying to leave the neighborhood not use
into law I'll
a hit in awesome
saw work
what you want to ask use him how
how controlling is your software
deployment
regarding available freeware
applications
own are you all an open job for you very
important how you
and what will allow users to use well at
a good question because
we have been a very close shop and who
all
will last %uh the age dome
I for were very unhappy with the newly
now
we have everybody is including Apple and
Microsoft yes
especially now the the CDA after
cs6 wanna a that a hundred dollars a
year
her life so we r we're using now
sprinters 41 arm
I lieber morning
here
well actually I'm not BB and and are no
answer but unassailable
the software we are using screw this arm
think we're not
p.m. your job union shop any
it very very close to you Photoshop its
various
you know what was silence I'm
will be under with you I have to be
present at the national issues
okay and I'm gonna sit here and tell you
that
with him is not Photoshop no there are
rather
for what a lot of our users in India it
is yeah we're we're pushing that you
know
I use it don't get me wrong why did you
know that I
but it pushin K
yes indicator that i won you're right
that's the other thing
wasn't a and we're making available more
more more users
that want to use those in place these
church home
well both
its exact that and
been other
a open so big decision
well way handsome you were to create
run OS like from the
youth
them
well
her bill that bad general and you
them talk about you when who s
sure I'll we're actually
morning I'll little Lystra OS
right now we're just said we're testing
it out actually
room bill Mueller I like
but the problem with those is no
Somerville ability
we were walkin like enterprise
agreements
on such as Adobe for instance warm love
him
on S and you know they don't have any
support for those platforms we will love
don't get me wrong we love you
in back last director we had wanted
possibly explore going you're not there
my wife or 1080 on G the product manager
out there
and windy on uses lot Olympics
most there's the obvious and
and that's why they there so you sayin
way
and admire my family college
mccollum strong winds
G min you're saying he's not here
the that
major commercial in teaser be
when
he's
terms that
more hours
to question I I'm not I have not a
hundred percent sure but
I would say naw yours yeah
I would say with companies that is Adobe
which is so strict on their
home well what is their problem
they their more sup ok yeah
I may come to think they are the worse
come here
he's I'll I mean a.m. they change their
life something on us
so many times i mean i i just now did
that project six months ago an upgrade
all this policy as greasy as this
anchors that alas probable all I will be
with you
with that many handed visions
par now it's in getting really
yes or you lose your license but that
was only for any criminal time in the
end the game
CC and now you've got a good agreement
which we're gonna do
next year when one gets in at least news
we spent thirty three thousand dollars
on as last upgrade the deli
and we're basing a hundred thousand
dollars a year now
here i am. were paid 53
no hero every day. you do it you're
doing more than Adobe Reader and
and and and flash so I and we go to the
polls sweets and no I got that far
we have graphic designers yes such yeah
mean we don't 53,000 room to
more than 90,000 every year we're not
happy
has a loss is right yeah I mean so
were were up a creep right now them and
like we say what happened there's
another 2008 incident
the economy I mean my home
downsized 40 percent young about me and
when that %um hey
97,000 PU weakness good morning
so we're definitely trying to go the
open source row
on more more somber we just did the
open-source
on project room we're going there
no was deleted former home official
product managers but for others the
systems that help running managers
reusing open garage
with him and network down really well
as we're looking at six hundred dollars
lines
microsoft project him
they had firmly orders
mean
going for got back on track of I'm
pretty sure they yet I'm you know that
whose third it really is
it is and I'm not the only one not one
of my friends is likely writer over a CA
and he was telling me the same like
their hands maybe she will be over there
and they're just as mad as we are and
sis
what are you doing I'm we've got quiet
out there that you use Adobe products
we've got ahead and we were still sit in
cs3
urinal this last year which December was
deadline had buried in a really didn't
you lost your credibility
and that when you know we got cs6
we're gonna be you know because we have
to be quiet with the UK
want you all miles her and
now the CC how you know means
it's gonna be a an interesting situation
next in the a.m here's an
the same things but we didn't happen not
like us that we have in front
really Microsoft smaller companies that
I'll
have agreement don't have agreement with
Microsoft have office
and they're going to be forced in the I
have two words for you
the brothas where forget
yeah no doubt me that they're gonna
happen to me
as house in the smaller like we have a
lot of competitors
that engineering firm jor single man
just a handful of people ok berms
can or those cameras rates may remain by
have no
your allowance for Rs while on
firm G
right you know long having a you know
walkout for office 360
your office 2013 on a yearly
yearly or monthly basis actually the new
the new approach we're taking the Dobie
is there
that %uh actually suggested adobe has
love our monthly lease all we have all
users there
all gonna word project mind
what we just got a hospital probably war
all the sudden
several engineers me you know him
rendering
and so my suggestion less
get a license that we buy whole for Mom
the other
workers yeah and afterwards
that spirit and with burnout the big
issues were big enough
worm that its hard to manage all those
you know when we get like because when
you have Adobe
poisonous you know watch their it's a
recurrence
expense it just doesn't hear the you
know we can
greater Kashmir issue that CDO you
meeting
for use for these guys for me got yes
here
but I will give it to the credit now
it now that it has he said that they
have come room with a new package
management pack they had and we're gonna
try to educate her a zone that
and date him home redistribute licensed
a different mood
and know that and that is just reason
the Hino
that netted huge improvement well
I guess Lee the hood you know they may
not be more now
now she caught the attention yeah
by I'm most companies do not know
pretty good the deal except or chrome
agree I mean I have an issue with the on
on the CSX they had promised and I had
in writing
from there director North American
director
customer service she rodent brain and
now
then we would get CSX recharge
and she network named call
nothing I know about it and no money on
to say I'm known for my name
Jer and I finally had to go
G I just started calling different one
in california they're all
and I was like okay why isn't this poem
going back a battler a standard I
emailed don't look she
gave us letters and we would get cs6
this number machine
free and she's back in life what's going
on and we finally got it I'm
later yeah
tell you know that's another thing that
in table tennis easy and then
is the I'll dealing with
licensing and purchasing all Afghanistan
know if it's definitely a on
it'll of it this way be and he mandado
well-rounded position yeah
I special spear catcher it is
that's right that's right
any other
question
alright well