(light, airy music)
(echoing note)
(swish)
(applause)
- Thank you for having me.
I'm sorry my co-worker
couldn't make it.
So, I'm going to try
to go through it.
We had it all separated
so we'll see how it goes.
Just a quick About Us.
Andrea, she's the one who
can't be here, obviously,
she's been working
at Cisco for about
two or three years, and
a lot of her research is
in this presentation, of course.
And there's me, as
mentioned, I worked with NASA
about five years; I took a
year off, and went to Mandiant,
went back; and was
their threat researcher.
One of two threat
researchers for
the whole agency,
which is crazy.
I've done consulting for
nonprofits in San Francisco,
where I'm currently
based, and I worked
for Cisco Umbrella,
so previously OpenDNS,
and get to play with a
lot of DNS data every day.
I'll give a quick summary of
what I'll be talking about.
We're gonna talk about the
kind of research that we do,
and how we find maliciousness,
why we build visualizations,
and I'll show some
visualizations
and some findings.
So, we research
a lot of criminal
activity, like ransomware, spam,
Remote Access Trojans,
infected websites.
When you get spam, you
might get something like
this email, where you have
Collete87 really wants
you to click on this
Russian website,
so you can meet her, and if
you do, you get ransomware.
We look at website compromises
where iframes are injected
into a website, and it sends
you off to other locations
to install malware, do
all sorts of things.
Look at Remote Access Trojans,
so malware on a system
that allows an
attacker to connect in
and control the system,
exfiltrate data,
drop new malware,
things like that.
There's a lot of
data to visualize.
So, we can put, look
right at an IP or a domain
or a registrant, it
builds up quickly.
It depends on the
kind of attack,
when you're looking at
what you want to visualize.
So, compromised domains, it
depends on the scope of it.
Maybe it's just a command
shell, it's doing something
bigger, or maybe it's just
a simple compromised domain.
Maybe it's just
phishing, so it's domain
that's set up specifically
for malicious activity,
or it's a compromised
website with phishing
deep in the directory structure.
Or DGAs, so you may have
one complex domain name,
and that doesn't give
you much information,
but the more you have, the
better information you have.
It depends on the
infection method.
So, you know, if it's
the spam infecting users
that's one thing
we're looking at.
If it's just a simple
compromise of a website.
Maybe you've got one
indicator of compromise
that doesn't give
you a lot to go on.
And exploit kits, maybe
what you're looking at sites
that are compromised
via exploit kits.
So, this is a service where
you can pay to compromise
sites, and try to
compromise users, depending
on their vulnerabilities in
their browser and their system.
It also depends on
the size and scale.
So if, like I said, if
it's just a defacement
of a website, you
don't have a lot,
or if it's one DGA domain, one
dynamically generated
algorithm domain,
it's not a lot to go with,
but you can build off that.
There's a lot of features you
can get from even one IOC,
one domain, in this
case magicpharmacyinc.su
See, there's this
big spike in traffic?
Compared to another domain,
when you have domain queries
like this, where you
see a regular traffic
pattern that doesn't
look suspicious.
So, finding maliciousness,
you have to find
all this stuff, and
then do stuff to it.
But, it's kinda
difficult to find.
But, if you have a lot
of DGAs, you can analyze
a whole bunch of them; a
lot of them won't be going
anywhere, they won't be
registered, they're NX domains,
but you might be able to
find one that is pointed
to the command and
control server,
and then get additional
information on that;
and the more DGAs you
have, the more likely
you can find out what it's
attributed to, as well.
Here's an example of
an infection where you
might have a command
and control contact,
and what you can get from that.
So, at Layer 1 at the top,
it's a system's infected,
and then it contacts
the C&C server;
and if you have
visibility into this,
you get the C&C server,
and you have the victim,
and occasionally on
obfuscation, there will be
multiple proxy nodes
that it will contact,
so you can get
those nodes as well,
and then you can build
a dataset on that,
and you can keep on
going, as you'll see.
So, you need a large amount
of these changing DGA domains.
You can get nonexistent domains;
they're not all
registered, as I mentioned.
One of these domains,
maybe a few of them,
will be pointed
to an IP address.
So, a lot of this is
using passive DNS,
a lot of the stuff I do.
So, I'm looking, like I
said, at domain names,
I'm looking at IP addresses,
name servers, which is,
we can get historical name
server and WHOIS information,
which is important; which
EDPR, so you can see changes
in that, and if you tie in
other things, as I'll show,
like VirusTotal or
ThreatGrid, you can get add-in
malicious binaries,
and the relationships
between IPs and
domains and stuff.
So, using one example, is
just tracking Hailstorm spam.
Hailstorm spam is just
a lot of spam sent out,
a spam campaign done really
fast before spam, anti-spam
mechanisms can catch up to it.
Just looking at
this one IP address,
what can you get from
this, this one thing?
Using passive DNS, you
can see that there are
a lot of domains
hosted at this IP: 857.
There's also Level Two
domains, there's 422,
that's subdomain, .domain.com,
and you can keep on going
down the chain of subdomains;
and then you can get
basically a list of that,
and do something with it.
Just looking at a
select example of that,
you can see that
there's a lot of domains
that look like medical,
luckypillmall, firstdrugmall,
so they're usually, they're
probably pharma-spam,
which is attributed to one kind
of ransomware that
we've seen a bunch.
Pivoting off that, you
can take that IP address,
which is on the lower
right, and you could see
that there's another domain that
has been pointed to other IPs.
So, you can go,
look at those IPs,
and see where they've
been pointing to.
Basically, you're
adding to your dataset,
and it's getting probably
pretty overwhelming.
You keep on going,
you find more domains,
more domains, more.
Just to go on what you can
get with one specific domain,
the kind of things you can,
before I get into the big stuff.
You can see query
volume, if you have this
kind of visibility; so
you could do this in
your environment, looking
at your DNS queries,
or if you have access
logs; you could also
do it if you have something
bigger, like where I work.
If you could see the spike
in traffic, all of sudden
when there was very little,
almost zero to one queries
per day, and then it drops down.
You can get other things,
like the WHOIS data
I was talking
about, IP addresses.
The TTLs, so you can see if
it's changing IP addresses
often, or if it's
set for a while.
You can pick up the
popularity based on requester
geolocation; so how
many people are visiting
from this country
versus that country.
And what's really interesting,
which is something
you could also do inside
your own environment,
without third-party tools,
but is more powerful
with third-party tools,
is co-occurring domains.
So, these are domains that,
when our DNS query was made,
right, at the time
time, or just before,
or after the domain was queried.
So, then you can use
that to branch out.
Of course, this adds to your
overall data that you're
looking at, still so,
there's still a problem here.
Collecting all that
stuff, you still have to,
I mean, when you have
one domain, you still
have to get this data somewhere.
So, we use a lot of Open
Source Intelligence.
Things like
MALWARE-TRAFFIC-ANALYSIS.net
A blog by a security
researcher who publishes
PCAPs, live malware,
and a quick blog post
on what he's seeing; and you can
download this and play with it.
It has things like,
there's a PCAP right there,
and I'll get into this shortly.
We actually, well,
actually I guess
I'm getting into this now.
You can download those
PCAPs, you can run them,
and you can look at the
domains; but it's a lot easier
if you program this in Python.
You can process, batch process,
through tons of
them at one time.
So, you end up with
a list of domains,
which is problematic in itself,
because it's a list of domains
and lot of third parties
will send you lists of domains,
and there's legitimate
things in there,
and there's
non-legitimate things,
so you still have to weed out
things and clean your data.
There are other sources, like
My Online Security is one.
I mean, there's a million
sources out there,
but you can scrape these, or
you can go download things.
If you're, as a security
researcher you get access
to places like
this, DGA Archive,
which are closed-off
to the public,
so that attackers can't
see what you're working on.
And of course, there's
VirusTotal, which is a really
great repository for
malware and other viruses.
If you are doing it for
free, you can use an API,
you can call it four
times a minute, I believe.
But if you're paying,
you can do a lot more.
So, you can set
up your RI rolls,
and hunt for specific
kind of activity,
and then download all that stuff
programatically,
which is what we do.
We download hundreds
of samples a day,
and maybe run them
in a Cuckoo Sandbox,
or run them through
various systems to get
additional information
to look at.
We also look at feeds.
So, there are some
feeds that are
providing constantly
changing viruses.
They're usually a little
bit more up-to-date
than the historical
data that we're finding
on VirusTotal and
Malware Traffic Analysis.
One example of a really
great feed is John Bambenek.
He runs a security
company; I'm sure
some of you have heard of him.
He just runs all these
malware samples, every day.
I think he actually might be
stopping the feed pretty soon.
I heard, but I'm
not sure about that.
But, he publishes them
as the malware families
that they belong to; so, you can
quickly ingest that
and work with it.
So, why visuals?
I feel dumb asking
this question.
I mean, I know why
visuals, I feel like
it's extremely
important to be able
to see what you're looking at.
But, as you can see,
just to go over it again,
it's a lot of data
that you're looking at.
A ton of data, and
it's really hard
to keep it in your
mind, what you're
looking at; and you
wanna work fast.
Threat hunting is,
it moves really fast.
You can't just sit and wait
for something to change.
'Cause, as you can see, a domain
spikes up in a
campaign, and it's gone.
So, you need to
turn that messy data
into meaningful
information that you can
work with really fast, and
move on to the next thing,
and also go home
and have a life.
It also helps us quickly
analyze threat data.
This is a quote
from Edward Tufte.
It's basically kind
of long-winded.
He's a data
visualization expert;
a professor at Yale, I think.
But, he's basically saying
assessing the change,
and the dynamics, and
the cause of something,
helps you really understand it.
So, some visuals we like
to use as we, like I said,
we program in Python,
we've had some coworkers
that work with R,
but we convert them.
I mean, R is fine,
but we use Python.
We throw it in PANDAs
for data analysis.
Sometimes, use other
tools, and then
we have been playing
a lot with D3,
which is a JavaScript library,
and it's a pain for
me to work with.
I'm always struggling
with it, but the things
I've gotten working have
been satisfying, at least.
So, we will do some specific
kinds of graphs, like
force-directed graph; this
is really great for networks.
We'll do timelines of first seen
queries versus domain queries.
So, this is the first time
a system in your network
contacts a domain versus
the time it was registered,
also versus other things,
other components of the domain.
Timelines of domain queries,
this is just the volume
that you've seen before in
some of the previous slides.
Timelines of queries just from
network captures,
and log files too.
And then, signature
patterns built from queries
in network capture files;
so I'm gonna get into that,
that's a little bit
different, it's something
I'm exploring, I've been
exploring for about two weeks.
An example of force-directed
graphs, how you can
take a list of domains and IPs,
and get something maybe useful?
I mean, this is a
mess to look at,
but it gives you an idea
of maybe where to go next.
You have this IP
address, and it's got
a whole bunch of domains on it.
So, if this is something
bad you saw happening,
maybe you know where to go next.
You have all these one
offs on the left side
that maybe aren't
as pressing, so...
And while I'm talking about
force-directed graphs,
this isn't about this,
this is a fantastic product
that's actually a free
thing called OpenGraphiti,
made by one of my coworkers
that used to work at NVIDIA.
So, he's made this
beautiful thing.
This is an example of
what Zeus, Game Over Zeus,
looks like in one environment.
So, obviously you
can really visualize
things, and just
look at it all day.
Here's a video of
what Mirai looks like,
like a section of Mirai botnet.
So, you can do some
really beautiful things.
I'm sorry to show you
that, 'cause we're
gonna go back to really
boring-looking visuals, but...
We can do, as I mentioned,
on the query timeline,
so if you look at Google you
can see there's a pattern
here, there's a Monday
through Friday pattern.
It's kinda normalized for
North America, in this graph,
but it goes high up
in the day, and down
in the evening, and
the weekend is lower.
So, you can see there's
nothing, basically nothing
malicious here, I mean,
you know it's Google.com
But, you can see this kinda
pattern, or other patterns
that you recognize as not
bad, then you can move on.
And in doing pattern
matching, so I'm gonna
talk about this towards the end,
but I'm looking at
PCAPs with specific
kinds of activity and
counting the times in-between,
trying to find if this
pattern is involved.
A different way of
building signatures.
So, what makes a visual useful?
We have some questions
that we ask ourselves.
What will make it clear?
This is pretty obvious,
it has a count, if it's
a timeline, you know, how
many, and when did it happen.
So, in this case we've
got this graph here.
The line, the blue line,
is the query volume.
So, we can see that this
domain, humoronoff.top
had a big spike kind of,
a relatively big spike,
and then it went down,
it's still being used,
but so, if it was in a
malware campaign, or something
then it's probably
something to look at.
Am I putting it in
the right context?
So, force-directed
graphs, those are great
for networks, terrible
for timelines.
So, you gotta make sure you
put it in the right place.
I was gonna put some
really ugly graphs here,
but there wasn't a lot of time.
Also, how can we reduce
the visual clutter?
So, maybe we can
combine domain names.
So, here we're looking at
Google and the humoronoff.top
domain, in comparison
can be useful.
And looking at, we can
assess change by looking
at spikes, and changes,
and traffic volume.
So, some visual examples
of attack campaigns.
Just to give you an idea
of where we're going.
I'm going to talk about three
different malware variations.
EMOTET, Hancitor, and TrickBot.
EMOTET is a mal-spam malware.
Spam is sent to victims
and it usually includes
an attachment, like
a Word document, or
something like that,
or a link to a Word
document; and if you run it,
and have macros enabled,
it'll do all sorts of stuff.
So, grabbing just from
Malware Traffic Analysis,
just from a bunch of PCAPs,
for a selected time period,
we ended up with
what you're commonly,
probably see, in your daily job.
Domain lists and IPs,
and it's the job of some
poor analyst, which I've
been before, to look at these
IPs and domains, and
figure out which is bad.
Someone higher up
says, "Block this."
And you're like, I don't know
if I should block all this,
but you should
definitely look at it.
But there are domains in here
that shouldn't be blocked,
obviously, like ipinfo.io;
these are just IP checks
from the malware, maybe,
trying to find out
if it should infect you,
or find out where you are.
So, you need to do
something else with this.
If you put all these
IPs and these domains
that you just saw into
a force-directed graph,
you get this cool-looking graph
that looks kinda like candy.
I don't know.
You can see that there's not
a lot that sparks interest,
except for, there's one
section where there's a few
more connections, so maybe
you could start there.
You can check out what's
there, and you could,
in the stuff that we've written,
that we use, we can
highlight the nodes.
The red is is the IP;
the blue is the domains.
And we can get some more
information on that.
We can click on that and go to
further resources that we use.
If we run those same
domains through to create
that kind of messy
graph, and we enrich
it with passive DNS
data, so we include
a whole bunch more stuff that
wasn't in the initial file,
and we turn the labels
on, we can see that there
are a couple IP addresses that
are hosting domains
associated with this,
or have hosted domains; so,
there are some more places
that are more
interesting to look at.
This mykeeptake.xyz,
we'll see that again in
a few moments, but
just keep that in mind.
We can do some timelines
on this kinda thing.
So, if I take just the PCAPs
from one EMOTET infection,
just these two files
right here, and I pull out
their domains; I've got
those akademia, I'm not gonna
try to say the
names, this one here.
I pull them out with my
Python script, and I've
got these four domains
here that are interesting.
I didn't pull the DNS queries,
just the GETs in the post.
I can put these on
a timeline, which is
a different way to
look at a timeline.
I put the dates the
emails were received
by victims, according
to this blog post.
So, there's probably a
lot more emails than this.
But, put those on a
timeline, I put the domains,
and you can see that
there's three domains
on the far left,
back in October,
and then there's this
one domain right there.
So, this gives me
a quick image of
psychedelicsociety.org.au
is probably really
associated with this, and
the other ones, I mean,
it's probably compromised
or it's been setup
just for this
campaign, right here.
Those old ones are probably
compromised, or, I mean,
they're not as important,
but they are important.
Looking at that
psychedelicsociety page,
you can see there's
a spike in traffic,
all of a sudden,
where as before,
around it there's
pretty much nothing.
I can see the First Seen date is
the date that was on my graph.
Looking at those other
domains, you can see
that there's kind of consistent
traffic, it's not as big.
I can look using other
tools, like VirusTotal,
I can find that there's
some interesting URLs,
and I can scrape these or pull
them programmatically,
which I do.
Looking at, just at the site,
sometimes I do this a lot
in threat analysis,
I see what's up.
It's a site, whatever, but it's
WordPress, which I
am suspicious of.
I could tell by those
previous domain names
there's a word, WP
Admin Directory,
but I didn't take
screenshot of it;
but going into one
of those directories,
you can see there's some
spam inside those sites.
So, the site's
compromised, and it's
being used in this
campaign; as you can see,
'cause of the PCAP,
I mean, that's proof.
But looking at all
the EMOTET domains,
I pulled like all of them
for a huge amount of time,
I can't remember the exact time,
but you can see that
there's a pattern here.
And it's a mess, but you don't
have to read all the domains,
but you can see October
had a huge spike in domains
being used, kinda dipped
down and then up again.
So, this isn't relative
of the entire internet,
this is some PCAP files,
but it's place to start
if you're hunting for something.
So, there's some
patterns we can look at,
and I've been talking
about this a little bit,
this is stuff I'm
doing that's brand new.
I'm just trying to play
around a little bit,
which is a big part of my job,
and that's my favorite
part, to play around.
So, I can get those
PCAPs and I can see
that there's GET requests,
and there's posts,
and there's all sorts of
cool data to play with.
This is, right here,
that you're seeing...
There's GET posting to different
IPs, different domains.
I thought about maybe, if I look
at the time between events.
So, Malware Traffic
Analysis is real great,
because he provides these
PCAPs that it's just
a specific moment in time
where EMOTET, or Hancitor,
or something is, or
some other malware,
is infecting a system; so,
it's pretty consistent.
So, I was thinking, if you can
count the times in-between,
maybe there's a way
to look at patterns,
and then research further
on will be more interesting,
'cause I hope to be able
to run it on live traffic,
and maybe catch
something interesting.
But, I'll keep working on that.
But, looking at it, just,
I put it on a graph with
with MatPLotLib, just to
see what it looks like.
These dots are just
the, they represent...
Well, what I did,
was I took the times
and I took away the
time information,
and I made it a unique number,
not to get too weird with it.
But, just to try to
do a constant thing.
So, as I did that, I would
plot it on this line.
So, the numbers don't
really mean anything;
it's just a visual for me
to kind of to start with.
I'm looking to see if
there are patterns.
So, if I run a bunch
of EMOTET PCAPs,
you can see that there's,
there's sort of a pattern.
I mean, maybe, I
haven't yet compared it
to what's it like when
you're viewing YouTube,
or viewing news
websites, but you'll see
when I get to TrickBot, there's
a little bit more
of a unique pattern.
And I'm at TrickBot.
So, TrickBot is like
a mal-banking Trojan.
Sent usually phishing
links, or phishing emails
are sent to people to
login to their fake bank.
They think it's the real bank.
And it's changed a little
bit to have kind of a
ransomware component too,
but I won't go into that.
So, let's look at
some graphs with this.
So, putting it in a
force-directed graph,
we can see there are a
few interesting things.
These are the same kind
of, we took a list,
just like we did
for EMOTET; we can
look at the nodes of this,
we can expand upon that.
This is really pretty,
it doesn't tell you a lot
of information, if you don't
know the context, but you
can see that there's something
interesting to look at.
So, we turn the labels on
and we enrich it even more.
Actually, that last graph
we enriched already,
but with additional
passive DNS information,
but you enrich it even
further and add the labels.
You can get a lot more
useful information.
You can see that there's
something; there are a couple
probably bad hosting
providers that are hosting
a lot of these domains, so
you can take action on that.
Whatever that action may be.
Looking at timelines
of this, just
to give you what it looks like.
Same thing, October, big,
huge thing, comparatively.
And then some smaller bits.
And then patterns, of course,
I wanna look at patterns.
So, this is running
through a bunch.
This is actually a
video, it's showing
a bunch of different TrickBots.
You got these two, two
times that things happened.
So, it's pretty unique.
As I work on it, maybe I'll be
able to catch TrickBot live.
I mean, I'm not building
the next Snort, or anything,
but, you know, I'm
just playing around.
Hancitor, which is
another kind of mal-spam.
Look at this and see
what we can find.
We've got timelines,
that kind of have
the same pattern again, so I
don't know what's going on.
Maybe this is a
general, a larger trend.
Maybe if I look back at
what I've been doing,
for the last year, if
I can even remember,
'cause you're always
on a million things,
I would maybe be able to
see that there's, like,
maybe I would assume that
October was a hard month.
So, putting this in a
force-directed graph.
Same kinda thing, you get
a lot more connections.
This is a lot more
interesting, right here.
And if we enrich
that with extra data,
the past domains and whatnot,
we get some more stuff.
And as we were researching
this, we found that there
were a lot of relationships,
as you can probably guess,
based on those
timelines I showed you.
A lot of relationships between
the different campaigns.
But, we can see things
like this IP is hosting
a whole bunch of these iffy,
or bad, or known bad domains.
There's that mykeeptake.xyz,
which was in EMOTET,
which is also being used
in this Hancitor campaign.
So, now that's been
raised up a little bit
as something important
that we need to focus on.
Looking at patterns, just
to kinda give you an idea,
it's definitely, definitely
different than EMOTET,
definitely different than
TrickBot, the PCAP pattern,
but it's kind of
interesting to see.
And then the relationships
between attack
and infrastructure, I
just mentioned this,
but this is everything
all tied together.
All the static domains and
IPs from TrickBot, EMOTET,
and Hancitor that we looked at.
You got these
outliers on the side,
and then those are
interesting, for sure,
but you've got this huge amount
of just working together,
the domains are
working together,
and IPs are working together,
it's the same infrastructure.
And as, when you're
trying to find attribution
for something, generally
you find it based on
the sharing of infrastructure
and the reusing
of domains and
registration information.
But, it's just nice to see that.
If you enrich that further,
you can find a place to attack.
And this is historical
data, but there are ways to
be up to speed with
the present moment.
And then I put these on,
or just relayed them,
this is not a programmatic
thing, but it will be,
when I'm continuing to work
on this, and so is Andrea.
So, if you put the Hancitor
over EMOTET, you can see
there's a definite
relationship between them.
On TrickBot, it's
not as much the same,
but it's, I mean, EMOTET
and Hancitor are mal-spam,
and TrickBot behaves
a little differently.
So, you expect some
different results with it.
This probably should have been
in back a little bit further,
but you can, when I was
talking about bringing data
together, to give you better
visuals, but you could,
I didn't want to put
all those domains on
one big, huge timeline,
but I bet I would see some
query volume patterns, which
would be very useful to see.
Cool, thank you.
(applause)
(piano music)
(deep, booming piano chord)
(metallic echo)