(applause)
- So I'm Ryan Nolette,
I've been doing
IR forensic-ey fun stuff
for about 15 years now.
There's my GitHub page
if you're interested
in any of the public
stuff I've done.
As part of this
talk I'm actually
giving away an Amazon
detonation lab.
So that URL at the bottom is
a quick easy way to set up
a fully configured
detonation lab in AWS
takes about five minutes,
builds a cool topology,
I'll expand on that
a little bit more.
And of course, Time Person
of the year 2006, come on.
(person cheering)
Three people got the
reference, and I like you.
All right, so the things
that we're gonna go over
are pretty much the overview of
why cloud really isn't
that scary, right.
If you guys are all used
to trying to protect
a perimeter that's on
your on-prem network,
it's really the same thing
just different words now.
So I'm gonna go through
some of the logging examples
that you guys can do, and
then go over an example
showing how you could
actually do the exact same
investigation that you're doing
or the same kind
of hunts right now.
The who did what and when.
These are the questions that
I like to try and go through
for every single time
I have to work through
in any kind of
threat, hunt, right.
I want to bucket
things into two groups,
visibility and accountability.
Because if you can't see it
you can't account for it.
Therefore, I need to keep
increasing my visibility
until I can account
for everything.
Which is a nice end state.
So to get to that end state,
we do the same
typical things, right.
Use OS hardening, you guys
subscribe to NIST or BIS,
or any of those
benchmarks, right.
You're still gonna apply those
to your templates in AWS.
Config management, you
can run Ansible, Chef,
you could use CloudFormation.
There's a ton of tools that
you can use to maintain that.
Identity management
and process monitoring,
those are a little
bit more interesting.
And that's because of things
like server-less computing.
So bucketing those back
into the visibility
and accountability buckets,
what you're really trying to do
is answer those three questions
of who did what and
when they did it, right.
Because if you can answer
any of those questions
you can cycle through and
answer the other two, right.
That's where you want to be.
I want to be able to say
I know when this happened,
now who did what.
And until you're able to
answer those questions
you haven't added
enough visibility
to have that accountability.
What are some common
tools that we all use?
We use IDSes, we have EDR tools,
we do different things for
Netflow or Identity Management.
Well these are the
equivalents that are there.
All right, instead of
Netflow it's called VPCFlow.
Do we know why?
Because it's the
Netflow in your VPC,
which is your Virtual
Private Cloud.
When you set things up
inside your Amazon account
you're putting them in
either one or a zillion
different VPCs that you create.
It's your own little virtual
private space to play.
So increasing that visibility,
what we want to do
is we want to use these
different groupings of controls.
Up here I've broken into
about six different groups,
there's more of course,
you guys have all seen
different compliance charts.
So, this is going through
more of what are the tools
that are either native
to the AWS realm,
or are able to be
used either free
or just open source in general.
So, authentication launcher
using tools like IAM,
which allows you to
control the identities
that log into your account
and your different
Amazon resources.
But that doesn't say who logs in
on the actual instance, right.
So you still need
to collect the logs
off the instances
that you spin up,
to see did the person
sign in as root,
did they sign in as
Apache for some reason.
And those kinds of
normal system configs.
But, the end to end example,
this is going to be kind of fun,
because this is my
detonation lab that I set up
with these scripts
that I'm giving away,
and what's kind of cool is
this is the typical instance
for people that have extensions
to their on-prem networks.
So, right now show of hands
whose boss has told them
that they're going
to the cloud, right.
All right.
Who actually wants
to do that? (laughs)
Right?
It sounds scary, it
has a whole lot of
different controls and things,
but what I kinda
want to bring out is
cloud's not gonna rain
on your parade. (laughs)
Yes, cloud reference,
dad joke, thank you.
The thing is, a lot of people
are just looking at things
as can I bring my current
technologies up with me.
And that's often no
because those products
were designed for
static systems,
in traditional networks.
Well, that doesn't always work.
So, what I've done
here is I've built this
CloudFormation template
which I'll talk more about
CloudFormation in
the lightning talk,
to give you an idea
of what it does.
But you basically
run this script
and it goes in and configures
your entire topology for you.
This is the topology
that it builds.
It has a private VPC that
I stuck four systems in,
and that's guarded
by a Bastion host.
So I can do all kinds
of fun stuff in there,
but nothing really leaks out.
Inside I have a red team server,
which is where I'm gonna
be doing my attacks from
for this demonstration.
I have a Windows victim,
and I have a Linux victim,
and then I have a Wazuh server.
Has anyone here ever heard
of Wazuh or ever used it?
No?
All right, how about OSSEC.
Do people know what that is?
All right.
Oh, Wazuh is a more
commercial version of that.
It's basically an elastic
stack with a app that does
OSSEC stuff on top of a
lot of other new features.
But the reason
why I'm using them
is because I worked
with their team
over the last three
months to build in
ways to ingest logs from AWS.
All the different logs
that I normally use
to do detections they
now can all ingest.
So super big shout out
to the developer, Marta,
because she's the one that
actually developed all of this
(laughs) for the Wazuh side.
The pipelines that
this template builds
look kind of complicated,
and that's because
there's a different
methodology with things
in AWS and other
cloud providers.
They're no longer talking
about your application,
your instance, or
terms like that.
Now things are being
called workloads
because people
are moving off of,
I'm gonna stand up
an instance of E2,
I'm gonna install
Apache, NGX, whatever,
and run my application
off that instance.
Well that's pretty expensive
because there's
a lot of overhead
that's unnecessary
to do your end goal
which is run that
one application
or your one workload.
That's where people start
moving into things like Lambda
or Kubernetes, I never
can pronounce it. (laughs)
You know, docker style
virtualization systems.
That's why people are
moving their stuff there
'cause it's significantly
cheaper to run the
same workloads.
So the first tool that we
went over is CloudFormation.
This is what I use
for automation.
If I want to stand up a
stack to quickly poke at
some new attacks
that I just learned,
I'll run this script
and somewhere around
five minutes from there I have
that full detonation lab set up.
Right, the same kind of idea.
It's quick, it's
repeatable, it's free.
Big, big fan.
S3, that's just where I
dump all my logs, that's it.
It's this giant bucket,
and they're actually
called buckets. (laughs)
That allows me to store
the data that I'm pulling
from all these different
logging sources.
VPC we quickly went over,
that's just the virtual network
that all my instances are
gonna be installed into.
VPC Flow is what
monitors inter-instance
and extra-instance
network traffic.
That allows me to
monitor any connections
between the systems in the VPC
as well as external to the VPC.
Lambda, this is a piece
of code that I'm using
to add in enrichment
metadata to my VPC flow.
Firehose, this is what
collects those logs.
So I'm sending all
my logs to Firehose
which can actually handle
that kind of volume.
Because Firehose
scales natively.
So, if today I only
have 20,000 logs,
sorry 20,000 traffic events,
but tomorrow I have 20 million,
it will still scale for that.
IAM, this is that
identity management
that we've been
messing around with.
This is how I
create all the users
that are allowed to
access my S3 buckets,
as well as are allowed to run
different privileged items
from inside my network.
CloudTrail, CloudTrail
monitors API calls.
So anytime you interact
with the AWS console,
or use AWSCLI, or any
of those native tools,
you're interacting
with the AWS APIs.
Every single time you do that
you are generating
events in CloudTrail.
So we use CloudTrail for all
kinds of fun detection stuff.
Did somebody just XFIL
your temporary credentials
from your instance
and are now using them
to access your S3 buckets?
There's CloudTrail
events for that,
and we can use them to simply
say this bad thing happened.
Really, really useful
for correlation.
Macie, this is an actual
security tool that people use.
This monitors and categorizes
data in your S3 buckets,
so if Bill from accounting
uploaded one of his spreadsheets
and it has Social
Security numbers in it,
and stuff, that gets flagged.
So it does cool stuff like that.
And you can create your
own different triggers
if you want something to flag
on if the name Ben is in there
you can write
something like that.
Kind of think of it like, it's
based on, what it's called,
but the data, it's not DEP,
it's a compliance one that
I can't think of right now.
So Inspector, this is my
vulnerability scanner.
This allows me to scan
against my instances
for things like CIS compliance,
common vulnerabilities,
Oauths, Pop10, stuff like that.
And CloudWatch Event
Rules and Logs.
This is the main thing
that I use to capture
events from these services,
so I can forward those logs
and write them to my S3 bucket.
Without CloudWatch monitoring
all those different services
nothing's actually
grabbing the logs
out of the service
when they happen.
So you can log everything but
the only way you'll see it
is in the console of that tool.
This allows me to take
it out of that tool
and drop it into S3 so
then I can ingest it
into an elastic
stack kind of setup.
And then GuardDuty.
This is another tool
that works kind of like,
it's kind of like an
IDS/behavioral analysis tool.
And it has a bunch of
pre-configured stuff
that it looks for.
This one is just looking
for a cryptocurrency.
This is traffic going
from one of my instances
to a known destination
that's been categorized
as cryptocurrency.
And then this is Wazuh.
Once again big shout
out to them for all
of the stuff that they did
for me, huge, huge help.
This is what I'm using
for an EDR tool in here.
This basically installs OSSEC
on the different instances,
as well as it's gonna pull
stuff into my log stash
and eventually feed
my Kibana dashboards,
which is extremely,
extremely helpful
'cause now I can do
full stack analysis.
I have an EDR tool,
I have a tool to look
at my network traffic,
I have a tool to look at
my identity management,
my config,
vulnerability scanning,
and categorization
of compliance stuff,
and it all gets dropped
into one place for me.
This is what the detonation
lab CloudFormation script does.
So you guys can go in
there and play around,
and it'll tell you
what breaks and where.
To give you an idea of
some of the mapping stuff
that I've done, this is
just for CloudTrail events.
I wanted to give an idea
of how many things overlap
between these logs that
allow you to map between them
in order to do further
kinds of detection, right.
If you're hunting through data
and none of the data
is communicating or
connected together,
how do you end up connecting
those relationships
between the data?
Well, what I ended
up doing is I took
common overlapping things, for
instance for the AWS account
we have something called
an ARN which is an ID.
You have a principal ID,
you have an access key ID,
those are overlapping fields
under account management.
So those are what
identify accounts.
By using that I can
now connect every event
from every AWS service I have
that uses one of those
four identifiers,
and I can map it to
the same account now.
So that's huge for the attack
that I'm gonna be showing.
So an example of a
couple of the dashboards.
Here's some simple,
easy, pretty pictures.
Management loves these.
These are not that helpful,
but management loves them,
so keep them in mind.
These idea for these are top
external destination IPs.
Now, not always helpful.
I have the accounts
for GuardDuty alerts.
So these are the accounts
that set up GuardDuty alerts.
I already have one
account in the test lab
that gets destroyed so I
only have one account there.
But in a real
production environment
you could have a
couple hundred IDs.
And this tells you
which one of your users
is constantly doing
things that are weird.
Next up are talkative, the
most talkative instances
based on their
interface ID, right.
When you have these
virtual instances
you can put as many nicks
in them as you want,
so how do we know if a
instance is being talkative
or if their attacker
is moving the nick
to different systems
so they can run traffic
outside of your monitoring,
cool attacks like that.
This ends up capturing
things like that.
So, finding what matters.
This is what I did
with the Kibana boards,
that come in this,
I feel like the voice of god
just happened there. (laughs)
The Kibana boards, these are
gonna use all these dashboards
and they're gonna show
you what's happening.
So this is the threat hunt
that I had a junior
analyst do, right.
They went in and they
started looking at
places where there's
a ton of traffic.
Now this is a test
at Nation Lab,
this is not production data,
so it looks an awful
lot like China (laughs)
has a lot of
traffic going to it.
Maybe they're
outsourcing their math,
but most likely what's happening
is something is sending
out and talking.
So I dig into that country.
From there I can see a
massive spike of traffic
that happened yesterday, but
all the other days before it,
for 30 days, nothing
has happened.
I can dig into that and
see that the top IP address
is this 58.218 address.
Well, from there I can go and
see if any alerts happened
for that destination.
And lo and behold, I have
some alerts from this IP,
magically for this demo,
everything worked out perfectly.
So, this now allows me to
find what internal instance
has this fun traffic to
it, and now I want to see
why this thinks that I
have something talking out
to a cryptocurrency exchange,
and I can use those
logs for the EDR tool
to find out that my
netstat table changed,
and it shows a
binary called pip3.7,
that is using that
destination IP address.
And when I go into that I
can see that it was installed
by the user Apache, and then
I can look at the hashes
for that binary and VirusTotal
happens to have that as
a known crypto miner.
Yes, there's a lot
of conspiracies
about how well this worked out,
but the overall idea is
all of this information
was able to be related together,
and we're able to do
a full stack (laughs)
investigation of something
that happened, right.
All this was visual, I didn't
have to go and dig through
a couple million lines of text.
I was able to pull these
together very quickly
and easily, to show
this full picture.
This is something I
would end up presenting
to management of a great
example of this junior analyst
who's ready to take on
more responsibility.
Right, they were able
to go start to finish
without any issues and
were able to connect
all the different
disparate data sets
that they ended up
having to work with
all within free and
open source products.
So, how did they get in?
Now, this one I actually have
a feature request out for
because it's not
currently baked in,
but I went ahead and I used
inspector to do some scanning
of my instances, and I
found that my web server
on the Linux victim
has not been patched.
So, (laughs and
imitates sad trombone)
I wonder if it was a web shell,
but most likely it was just
a really bad web server
that ran Netcat to an attacker.
Now, to do kind
of a recap, right.
Does cloud seem as scary now?
I hope not because every
tool that I just used
is available on
prem, and most likely
if you have a sock, hell if
you have something simple
like free and open
source Security Onion
running with OSSEC.
That's all free, yes the
cost is really an effort
for setting stuff up, but
you could do everything
that I just did without
spending any money
outside of hardware, right.
So I wanted to go through
that stuff showing,
these are common tools,
they just have a
different name right now,
and we're working on
naming conventions
to make things a little
clearer for people.
But, with the last couple
minutes that I have
I want to get to the
most serious question,
the attacker lifestyle.
Now, this is in
honor of squirrel,
because if anybody knows my
corgi attacker life cycle,
this is quite similar,
though this is from the idea
of the cryptocurrency miner.
We have script kiddie
scanning around the internet
looking for open addresses,
they end up popping one and
run a cryptocurrency miner,
all of a sudden
they have some cash,
so they buy a fancy car.
They own the only Lamborghini
in Eastern Europe.
Somehow that stands
out for some reason.
They get investigated
for tax evasion,
they get arrested,
they flip on people,
and now they're in the
witness protection agency,
and they want to start
it all over again.
I'd watch that movie. (laughs)
So kind of my motto
that I like to have
coming from a blue
team perspective
is Flag it, Tag it, and
Bag it, AKA the double tap.
If you find something,
flag it, right.
It's either the user
manually looking for things
in the threat hunt,
your static defenses
that are looking for
common signatures
or anything else, right.
Show what happened
and then tag it.
Even if it doesn't
look malicious,
if it looks anomalous, tag it.
And eventually you build
enough information to it
to bag it and get that
out of your network.
So, I ended up right
on time for minutes,
do we want to do questions
or push them to the end,
so that way we can
keep on schedule?
(laughs)
Play Free Bird!
All right, and while
they're talking.
That's just so
much fun. (laughs)
- All right.
- It makes me happy.
- You good?
- Oh yeah.
- All right, round
of applause. (cheers)
(applause)
(light piano music)