okay it looks like you restarted the
stream are we are we ready
ready to go great so um
yeah well we're starting a session on
formal analysis this session is about uh
is about quality over quantity we got
two excellent uh talks ready for you um
as usual ask your questions here on on
zoom chat or in zulip
and if you ask in zulip maybe prefix
your question with
the target of your question but the
first talk will be
systematization of knowledge uh on
computer aided cryptography
and kevin yeah will be giving the talk
go ahead kevin
awesome thanks for the introduction so
today i'll be telling you about how we
can use computer-aided tools
to develop cryptography and this talk is
based on a systemization
knowledge paper which was written with
the many wonderful co-authors listed
here
so i think we're all familiar with how
difficult it is to get cryptography
right
widely deployed protocols often have
high profile design flaws
heavily scrutinized libraries regularly
have bugs and
otherwise secure and correct code can
still leak secrets through side channels
so clearly the current way we do
cryptography just isn't delivering
the high level of assurance that we
expect
and this brings us to computer-aided
cryptography which is an active area of
research that aims to address these
challenges
but what exactly do we mean by computer
aided you know we've long used
computers to develop cryptography so by
computer aided
we're referring to formal machine
checkable approaches
to help in the design analysis and
implementation of cryptography
and one of the main goals of computer
aided crypto is to improve security
without sacrificing the things we care
about such as
interoperability and performance
and so how exactly can computer aided
crypto help
well there are a variety of tools that
address different parts of the problem
space
we've broken it down to the following
three layers design level security
functional correctness and
implementation level security
so for design level security today
security analysis is primarily done on
pen and paper
which is highly error prone and makes
double checking security analysis
extremely tedious
with computer aided tools we can
formally specify designs
and automatically check that they enjoy
important invariants
or otherwise discover new attacks
so using tls as an example before
version 1.3
the protocols design phases didn't
involve computer aided analysis
and the process was highly reactive
leading to an endless cycle
of attacks and patches and given the
complexity of the protocol
early analyses considered only highly
simplified cryptographic cores
but once the academic community started
considering more
detailed aspects of the protocol many
many new attacks were discovered
and this dynamic really changed during
the proactive design process
of tls 1.3 the academic community
provided analysis throughout
developing multiple drafts and in
studies using symbolic analysis tools
such as
provera and tamarind the process of
verifying tls and actually even just
formally specifying it
revealed flaws led to protocol
improvements and otherwise
clarify the documentation of security
guarantees
for correctness today's solutions for
avoiding implementation bugs include
code testing and auditing
but unfortunately code testing is
incomplete and is pretty unlikely to
catch the kinds of correctness issues we
deal with today
but with computer aided tools we can
formally verify
that code is free from memory errors and
that it behaves according to some design
specification
on all possible inputs
for example openssl has had a long
history of bugs which
probably isn't surprising given the
demand for highly optimized code
for performance developers are required
to multiplex implementations by hand
for each combination of algorithm
parameter choices and hardware platform
which increases the risk of introducing
bugs
fortunately things are starting to look
different today for example
recent work from the project evers team
on hako m
presents a new methodology in which
developers can
write generic code in a verification
friendly language
check that it enjoys properties such as
memory safety correctness
and constant time and then compile the
code down to different platforms that
support vector instructions
and this significantly reduces the
manual effort
needed to add new implementations and
also minimizes
room for error
and then finally for implementation
level security today in order to protect
against say timing side channels
developers need to apply tricky constant
time coding recipes
and just hope that they haven't missed
any vulnerable pieces of code
and with computer aided tools developers
can automatically check
whether or not their code is constant
time
and it turns out that writing constant
time code really is pretty
unnatural and difficult to do a botched
patch for a timely vulnerability in tls
led to the lucky 13 timing vulnerability
and open ssl
and in turn the lucky 13 patch led to
yet another timing vulnerability
but fortunately today there are many
tools that let developers
annotate program inputs as either public
or secret and then automatically check
that the program has constant time and
these have already been applied
to many real world libraries including
openssl
at this point i think it's important to
emphasize that computer aided crypto is
not just
academic crypto it really is real world
crypto and i've already touched on tls
1.3
but aws's key management service also
has machine checked proof of security
and approvally secure and correct code
is also being deployed at scale
in firefox google's boring sound library
and more recently in the linux kernel
and even though these success stories
are great in order to fully appreciate
the benefits of computer-aided crypto
it's also important to acknowledge that
formal guarantees
do come with limitations namely that to
make formal analysis tractable
formal models are almost always a
simplification of the real world
so for design level security this means
that protocol models are often
simplified
into a cryptographic core that ignores
many details about
designs and attacker capabilities
for correctness there may be gaps
between what's being verified and the
output machine code
for example verification might be
carried out on a verification friendly
representation of the source code rather
than on the source code itself
or if verification is performed on c
code we have to trust mainstream c
compilers which
frequently have bugs and even if the
code that they produce is functionally
correct
they might introduce side channels that
weren't present in the original source
code
and for implementation level security
formal models just can't capture all the
physically observable effects of
hardware
which leaves room for unaccounted side
channels and even further side channel
attacks such as spectre
reveal gaps between what we think is
being leaked and what's actually being
leaked out in the real world
on top of it all in order to carry
formal guarantees all the way down the
stack
we have to make sure that we haven't
left any gaps in our modeling between
layers
closing these gaps though does leave
many exciting future research challenges
this first one is more of a suggestion
but an important lesson we learned
from tls is that standardization
processes
can embrace design changes that simplify
security arguments and help
modular reasoning the tls 1.3 design
incorporated many
suggestions from the academic community
from
security fixes to fixes that simplified
automated analysis
to carry guarantees correctness
guarantees down to machine code
they can be established at source code
level and then compiled using a verified
compiler such as compsert
but the problem is that today's verified
compilers produce pretty slow code
so important future work is to
incorporate more optimizations including
support for
say cmd instructions alternatively
there's a lot to be gained if we could
focus more efforts on
scalable verifying assembly code
directly which currently requires quite
a bit more work than verifying c
code
to achieve a sound formal treatment of
protecting against side channel attacks
guru jerome and heiser have argued the
need for a new security oriented
hardware software contract
today's isas describe what a developer
needs to know to write a functionally
correct program
but they're an insufficient
specification when it comes to writing
secure programs
and so in order to carry sidechain
countermeasures at the software level
down to hardware we need isas that
capture for example
the temporal behavior of programs
and finally to bridge any gaps between
layers we encourage efforts on
consolidating all of these guarantees
so the holy grail of computer aided
crypto would be to deliver
guarantees on machine code that match
the strength and elegance of guarantees
on cryptographic designs
so now that you're all a little bit more
familiar with computer aided crypto
let's think about what computer aided
tools might change
in the grand scheme of things so even
though we've made some great strides i
think the answer is that it's not
totally clear yet you know will computer
80 crypto fulfill its promises
and put graphic designers out of work
well it's only recently been deployed in
the wild so i think it remains to be
seen how well these formal guarantees
actually hold up
but it's important to remember that
security isn't about
being perfect but rather raising the bar
for attackers
so maybe we shouldn't expect a world
without high profile crypto
vulnerabilities but maybe just a few per
year instead of like 10 per year
what i do know for sure is that this
will be a very exciting research area
for many many years to come
so with that i hope i piqued your
interest in computer aided cryptography
if you want to learn more i hope that
you'll check out our slk paper
and i'll be happy to take any of your
questions thanks
thanks for that talk kevin we're
starting to get some questions
on zulip thanks for that so the first
question i'll ask is from watson
um it's about open ssl
um and specifically x509 verification is
there any research on formalizing and
verifying
implementations of x509 verification
um off the top of my head and from our
literature search not that i'm aware of
okay another question from paul grubbs
do you think it's especially important
to use formal methods for crypto or
should all systems be designed and
implemented using formal methods
yeah that's a great question um i mean
in an ideal world we would have you know
formally verified system codes
and all the way down the stack but i
think for crypto
i think we definitely should i think
crypto is kind of the sweet spot where
the volume of crypto code is not as
large as say like an operating system or
a compiler
and so it really is possible to achieve
best in class performance
for the schemes we care about and so i
think
even though verification is quite
expensive we're not losing much in terms
of things we care about
such as performance so i think there is
um
a huge motivation to have uh verified
crypto code out there
great wow the questions are really
pouring in i'm gonna i'm gonna triage
the question according to the number of
thumbs up they're getting so the next
question i'll ask is from uh frank davis
um i don't know if this is an easy
question
to answer but um frank is wondering
about the tools available
um the current set of tools available
and he's listing some that he's seen
like kryptol
and cpsa um
i guess i guess you shouldn't just list
all the tools you know but is there
they're a good place to go to understand
all the tools that are out there
yes so definitely check out the so paper
so the essay paper paper has um a
comparative analysis of all the
state-of-the-art tools that you would
ever hear about i haven't talked about
that much in this talk but you should
definitely check out the slk paper for
those
okay great
how much of uh so i assume this is a
question from richard outer bridge
um how much of this entire picture
depends on invisible compiler
optimizations
invisible compiler optimizations um
in terms of you know gaining assurance i
suppose about the
the result of the compiler relating the
compiler's output to the
to the source code right so i can speak
to sort of like
two strands of like verification method
for this so obviously
if you want to verify c code then you
either trust the compiler or you use a
verified one
and there are verified compilers that do
preserve side-channel kind of measures
there's recent work from jill bartholo
that does this
and so i guess if you don't want to
trust the compiler then you would have
to go this route
alternately there's a lot of work now on
verifying
um assembly code directly and so all the
counter measures you would want such as
correctness and side channel
protections directly are established on
the target level code
okay great i think we maybe do one or
two more questions depending on how long
your answer is
a question from ayla lee um how suitable
are the current
design level verification tools for
lesser known crypto primitives
i assume lesser known as anything other
than encryption and signing maybe
yeah i mean so so she asked about the
symbolic tools was that right
uh design level formal tools yeah i
suppose symbolic
yeah so so at the design level they're
sort of like two camps there's either
symbolic tools such as like pro verified
tamarind which are
better suited for um verifying protocols
and then there's also tools like uh
ezcrypt which are better suited to
verifying uh primitives and
at least as far as i know there
shouldn't be any barriers when using
like ezcrypt to verify
any primitive that you would want to
verify
okay good uh we certainly have
uh orders of magnitude more questions
than can be answered live here um looks
like people are pretty interested in
this topic kevin so hopefully
uh you and your co-authors can uh help
answering these questions
on zoolip afterwards but uh thanks again
for your talk and for answering all the
questions i think we'll move on though
to the next
talk in the session looks like it's the
last talk of the day
um this is a talk by nadim kobesie
on verifpal cryptographic protocol
analysis
for the real world so nadeem go ahead
all right one moment please
is this working yes thank you
hello everyone it's a pleasure to be
giving this talk at real world crypto
this is joint research between myself
and george on ulla and mukesh tiwari
this is verified cryptographic protocol
analysis for the real world
so the preceding talk gave an excellent
overview of the state of formal
verification today
we have programming languages like
f-star that tie an ml-like programming
language with
um set three theory improvers to get a
state where types are proofs
and there we can produce um functionally
correct side-channel-resistant
primitives such as
the ones included in hackl n and also
fully functionally correct protocol
implementation such as
the signal star implementation of the
signal protocol and then if we look at
modeling protocols we have
tools such as proveref and tamarin and
cryptoveriff that take
models of protocols and then try to find
contradictions to queries
or in the case of cryptoverif produce
full game-based proofs
because you know tamarin and provereaf
work in something called the symbolic
model
and then crypto vera forks in the
computational model
and the computational model is indeed
more detailed allows for the production
of proofs that can stand
by themselves right whereas the symbolic
model the proof is usually on the way
that the tool works
and the tool produces analysis results
so
we are going to be focusing on the
symbolic model here because this talk
and the whole
point of this research is to focus on a
simple and intuitive
uh formal analysis of protocols and how
simple can we go how big of a compromise
can we make
in terms of um soundness and
completeness and still get results that
actually mean something
so an overview of symbolic verification
you know the the big tools in the field
right now are pro verifying tamarind and
indeed they are being used more and more
uh in these tools you write a model of
the protocol so if you're modeling
signal you just model a key exchange
between alice and bob
if you're doing tls you'd model a
session between a server and a bunch of
clients
and then you ask questions essentially
can someone impersonate the server
what happens if my phone is hacked and
my keys are stolen temporarily my state
is hijacked temporarily do i get forward
secrecy
and then provera from tamara and try to
find contradictions to these queries so
if you look at the paper that was
discussed in the previous talk the sok
there was a list of these compara of
these tools being compared and the hope
here is to add a new uh tool called
verve pal and to i hope to justify in
this talk
verify's novel novelties or
contributions to the domain
so i really believe in symbolic
verification if you look at the research
some of the research published recently
it's quite uh inspiring how you can have
things like small subgroup attacks and
invalid curve attacks
on protocols that use diffie-hellman
that are able to be modeled in the
symbolic model quite expressively and in
an interesting way that can catch new
attacks
also attacks on signature schemes and
protocols uh that use signature schemes
uh research by cass crummers dennis
jackson catriol cone gordon and
is really showing that the symbolic
model is far from
boring and also um you have many papers
published in the past four years that
are just
analyzing signal tls noise protocol
frameworks cut about bluetooth 5g and so
much more
so this is a great way to work i really
like the symbolic model because it's
intuitive and it allows me to reason
about protocols
uh in a way that doesn't uh the return
on investment i feel is quite good
and so really the big elephant in the
room so why
isn't it used more if it's so great it's
being used more a little bit these days
but why is the progress so slow
well so here is a
quick example of tamarind and i have to
admit when i first designed the slide
i think i was being quite intellectually
lazy here is a
also proveref and the naive thing to do
here would be to just look at these
languages and say well haha they're so
hard to learn and understand
certainly we can do better as it turns
out when you actually do due diligence
and
and try to understand things properly
you realize that there is a good reason
why these languages look like this and
that there is a level of expressiveness
and
and sort of like the profundity of the
analysis that you can actually get
and the profundity of the queries that
you can ask isn't does indeed benefit
from this syntax so the reason why
tamarind is like this and the reason why
proverbs is like this
there are very good legitimate reasons
that benefit from
some cases decades of research and i i
want to make that very clear i want to
state that clearly however
that being said it's they still are hard
to use right from the
from the perspective of a student or a
first-year perhaps student or an
engineer
and so um perhaps we can still
try to cater to that space as well while
respecting that
these design decisions were not perhaps
as misled as one might believe at the
beginning
so verifial is new protocol analysis
software it has four main goals
and one an intuitive language for
modeling protocols
two modeling that avoids user error
three
analysis output that's easy to
understand and four
it essentially tries to combine itself
with the surrounding ecosystem
you know integration into visual studio
code translations to proveriff and
and other stuff
these are the four main goals that i
just discussed you can see here on the
left
they provide a user-focused approach
however hopefully without losing too
much strength
we can still reason about advanced
protocols such as signal or dp3t
out of the box we can analyze for post
compromised security
and so on out of the box we can model
for
fresh values and unbounded sessions and
other cool symbolic model features
i need to specify i think proveraf
probably has a better grasp of unbounded
sessions than we do at the moment but we
are targeting these
um these goals and so really
this is not something that produces full
game based proofs like crypto verif
doesn't either
but also it is not formally proven to
not miss attacks
uh the way that proverf is uh our work
on um
uh formalizing uh verve palincock really
is pushing us towards getting more and
more formalization on the soundness of
the analysis logic but we are not quite
there yet
uh we are working on obtaining this
higher confidence but we
are conscious of the trade-offs that
we're making
to get this simple language and this
analysis that allows you to really
prototype and draft and like whiteboard
protocols and immediately get feedback
with little investment
into what you're trying to say and i
think this allows a lot of creativity
and a lot of learning a lot of
understanding to happen
with students and engineers that i think
is truly valuable
so long as you understand and are sort
of intellectually honest with what
you're doing and the trade-offs and the
responsibility and so on
so here if you look on the left you'll
see an example of a simple protocol
model using verve pal
and i really like how you can just say
you know alice is sending a message to
bob and bob is doing this and he's
generating b
and diffie-hellman looks very intuitive
right and we can capture all of this
uh and also give an intuitive experience
and
as you may recall the second priority
was eliminating user error so in verb
file you can't define new primitives
and that's not because of you know of
anything other than
we don't want users to define new
primitives we ship with
hashing primitives mac hkdf password
hashing such as script
encryption authenticated encryption
public key encryption
uh signings ring signatures blind
signatures
shamir secret sharing and so on and so
we
want to give you primitives we know
we've specified them according to a
universal
specification built into verve pal that
is called primitive spec that is used to
model any primitive
and then we know that you're basically
going to be able to understand what to
expect from these primitives
and we're not targeting users that want
more if you want to specify your own
primitive
um pro verify and tamaran really do
provide
you you shouldn't be using verified you
should be using tools that are more
advanced really
and so um a verifiable syntax is also
fairly expressive for example if you add
little
uh brackets around the around the value
as it's being sent on the network as you
can see here in orange
you'll see that this becomes a guarded
constant and so it's basically
not mutatable by the active attacker and
this can be used for example to model
pre-shared keys
and also if you had a little question
mark this makes it such that
a primitive is a checked primitive so if
signature verification fails
the client here will abort their
execution of this particular execution
of the protocol in which
signature verification fails this is a
giant thing that i shouldn't have
included but basically
uh there is a sort of formalism as to
how verve pile works
here's the primitive spec on the left i
should use my time to talk about things
that are more relevant since i only have
10 minutes
so we have advanced features we have
protocol phases that allow for temporal
logic and this allows you to model
uh things that happen in different
periods of time and this is necessary
for modeling for poor secrecy post
compromised security you can also leak
values to an attacker
recently we introduced unlinkability
queries and freshness queries and these
are quite
important for modeling something like
the dp3t contact tracing protocol
and we also have password uh values that
are crackable
unless you first hash them i thought
this was a fairly unique feature turns
out
proverev has a similar feature and also
query preconditions uh which allow you
to basically relate queries together
and uh of course this is a feature that
other this is a very common feature
and so uh we also have verified for
visual studio code it's a shame i can't
talk more about this because it's really
good
you know like the integration into
visual studio code you can run verified
analysis from inside visual studio code
generate graphs
uh format your models upload them to
verify
oh we have a thing called verify i don't
have a slide on it but there's like this
like like github for verified models and
you can upload your verify model there
and share it more easily
uh the translation to and proverf
is really good it
forced us to basically have a better
understanding of the formal semantics
uh and have lemmas and proofs on how
everything works and also
we're translating pro verified models
automatically to provide models
both of these things are need more work
this stuff is really hard
but it works kind of and we're getting
it better uh it's it's under active
development
uh with my uh co-authors uh the
analysis output is easier to read here
on the left you can see
what provera analysis output looks like
on the right
there's a verve pal attack trace and the
vert pilot attack trace is colored also
if you look at the terminal output
which i'm sure is very important oh
there you go there's one
we've analyzed signals cuddle bud
protonmail telegram dp3t using verve pal
and we haven't found new attacks but
every time the analysis has matched what
we've expected and also other formal
analyses using
similar tools in the field uh people are
using verifials so
uh assa abloy makes uh locks and smart
locks they've used verfpal
uh i know some engineers at google have
used verve pal but
they just like sent bug fixes on the
mailing list i don't know if you such as
google is more important than that
it most likely is not quarks lab uses
verve pal a lot
zoom has used verve pal in order to like
just early sketching and prototyping
of the zoom uh of ideas for the zoom
protocol but it also led
to finding an early flaw in one of those
prototypes and i'm very proud of that i
think verve pal
so what's really interesting to keep in
mind is that the zoom team
you know like they they could have
invested a lot of time in learning for
example pro verify and tamarind getting
better results more
sort of elaborate and profound results
but is that really a priority for an
engineering team
early in the design phase i don't think
it even should be really
i think in the early design phase you
want to quickly sketch and whiteboard
and get meaningful feedback but with
little investment and verifial is
excellent at that i'm really proud of
that it was
able to be used in these contexts uh the
verve pile
user manual also means that verified has
been a huge success
in uh teaching so uh i taught a class at
nyu
and verify was able to actually get 20
year old undergraduate students with no
background whatsoever in security these
are first year second year students
and they're modeling protocols and
understanding security goals i also
think this is a great success
and so now we're working on something
called verve pal heroes which is going
to be a
very long and elaborate hopefully
illustrated guide to protocol
verification
and it uses verified as an introduction
into the field but then from there it
goes into
proveref and tamarin and cryptoverif and
easycrypt and f star and
and as you can see we're sort of uh
expanding the uh
sort of almost uh ridiculously
uh approachable uh uh sort of like uh
style that verified has with the sort of
illustrations and so on
to cover all of these tools because we
really want to focus on pedagogy as well
as being something that is useful
and sort of makes sense for engineers
and students
so good i was just getting so
interrupted to
to conclude uh my co-authors giorgio
ulla and mukesh tewari i believe
are at this conference giorgio is just
finishing
his undergraduate is going to start his
masters he has done incredible work for
an undergraduate student he
worked so much on the aspect on
formal semantics of verve pal i strongly
encourage you to hire giorgio
really he really deserves it i'm so
grateful for uh the way
georgio and mukesh have been able to
help me out and contribute to this
project so i just wanted to
shout out that's it thank you so much
great uh thank you nadeem for that
uh exciting talk uh we have a couple
questions
on uh on zulip uh the first question
i'll take is from nigel smart
um you listed uh secret sharing very
quickly and it
looked like it might have just been uh
one out of three shmear do you allow
um you know arbitrary threshold secret
sharing and also do you
model the fact that secret sharing is
linear like that's a common
property used in npc protocols for
example
so for the first question we do not
allow for
more than three and uh this is for no
good reason we could allow it i just i
guess i haven't
worked that in yet we could easily
expand that for the second
thing i don't think that really can be
captured i might be wrong
but uh as far as i understand i don't
think that can be captured in the
symbolic model
okay well there was a there was an aside
in nigel's question which i didn't read
but he said
similar to how you modeled biffy helman
you have a group operation so there's
some
algebraic reasoning presumably in the
model well
the way that you model something like
diffie-hellman so tools like tamarind
have a more profound understanding of
diffie-hellman but
in verve pal is just a equation where
you basically say
and some uh sort of basic proverbial
models you know g to the b to the a is
equal to g to the a to the b
and you're basically just satisfied with
that and you could expand that
but uh so far this is what we've stuck
with
great uh a question from jonathan
hoyland
what is the performance of verifial on
massive protocols like tls
you have to split it into pieces or can
you analyze it monolithically oh man
so right before real world crypto we did
so much work on improving performance
it's written in go and so we're able to
like use multi-threading and
we're kind of uh improving also the
inner uh
we did like a lot of graphing of the
performance uh
something like tls takes a very long
time even something like signal
takes a long time but at the same time i
recall that when i modeled ikpsk2
in uh proverif and this was with also
assistance from
people who were very expert in proverb
and like giving me pointers on how to
make the model go faster
it still took 30 days to get the result
it took 30 days to get that result in
proverb
and we it was in the winter which is
great because i had free heating in my
house
and that was quite excellent really but
tamarind also
uh can take a very long time on certain
protocols and this is just a thing that
we have to deal with but we are working
on making it fast and i think currently
it is
reasonably fast uh okay i think i'll
i think i'll pass along one last
question thanks everyone for staying a
few minutes
late um a question from sebastian very
sure
um given that verifpal might miss
attacks are you not afraid that protocol
designers might mistake
the output for a proof of security
you can miss attacks so easily by
modeling the protocol
so i have looked at many uh protocols
written using tools that are decades old
that have been under development for a
long time
and attacks are very frequently missed
just because the model is not
comprehensive enough and it's quite
difficult to have a comprehensive model
when you're working in the symbolic
model and even in the computational
model because you're always restricting
yourself
to a sort of like uh elegant
representation
uh model really of the protocol uh we
are
i think very clear about verifia's
capabilities
and i think that especially in the last
little while
it has become quite adept at finding the
attacks that uh
one could reasonably expect it to find
and a lot of times attacks that are
a bit surprising and unexpected uh
none of this stuff is perfect and i
think that ultimately whether even
you're using something that is
really truly quite impressive uh an
impressive feat of theory and
engineering like f-star
you know you still find bugs in f-star
that are quite uh simple sometimes
great well uh on behalf of all the
audience members i just want to thank
nadeem and kevin for their really
interesting talks
there's lots of lots of questions for
both
sets of authors on zoo i hope you'll
have a chance to to look through those