good to go enjoy your session
thank you and thanks everyone for
joining the the group messaging session
at real world crypto 2021 we have an
interesting session today covering
some pretty diverse aspects of uh group
messaging and group
encryption and authentication ranging
from very ad hoc distribute
decentralized groups
um how we handle concurrency and how we
do some real-time stuff as well
uh so with that i will pass it over to
our first speaker um
lenka marikova to talk about
mesh messaging and large-scale protests
uh looking at breaking this bridge dry
app
thank you thank you for the introduction
um so i will present a work that titles
mesh messaging and large-scale protests
breaking bridge phi
that was done in collaboration with
martin albrecht jorge blasko and ricky b
against
the story begins with the hong kong
anti-extraction law amendment bill
protests that started in 2019.
organization of these large-scale
protests has been described as mostly
leaderless
and it made heavy use of various online
platforms
given this there are fears that the
government would use its emergency
powers and block these platforms in
order to prevent the protesters from
communicating
in this setting a number of articles
reported on the apparent rise of
messaging apps that enable communication
in the face of such a potential internet
shutdown by the government
and these reports focused on one app in
particular and that was
bridge file it allows people to
communicate without internet using a
mesh network that is composed of mobile
devices that are connected
to each other via bluetooth now
bridge file was first conceived as an
app for music concerts and sports
stadiums
where mobile networks may become
congested but which is still miles away
from the potentially highly adversarial
setting of a protest
however even then it was being marketed
as secure and
end-to-end encrypted and once it started
gaining traction in hong kong and other
places experiencing
protests the developers also began
promoting it for this use case
now an actual internet shutdown never
materialized in hong kong but
mobile networks did get congested which
could have also contributed to the app's
downloads
however hong kong's role was to serve as
inspiration for protesters in many other
countries and
indeed in vastly different contexts
bridgeway started appearing as part of
so-called hong kong tactics that were
being adopted elsewhere
and now just to name a few examples this
included the citizenship amendment act
protests in india that happened during
december 2019
when government mandated internet
shutdowns actually did take place
it was being promoted during the
resurgence of the black lives matter
protests in the u.s
then fear of a government shutdown
during protests in zimbabwe also urged
protesters to install bridgeify
during the presidential election in
belarus and the days of protests that
followed
internet was again partially blocked
which led some protesters to bridge fire
and the latest country to join the list
is thailand
that moved to block certain independent
media and also the messaging application
telegram
now of course given all these examples
judging adoption on the ground purely
from press reports and social media
posts
one could get an overblown picture of
its actual use
especially since for the mesh to work as
advertised
the app requires a certain critical
number of users
however there is sufficient evidence to
suggest
that whenever there was a new flareup of
protest activity
or a government move to limit internet
access people downloaded and
tried to use bridgevie in response
so we took an interest and decided to
investigate how secure this app was in
reality
since the source code was not available
we reverse engineered
the android app and this includes both
the app
and the software development kit that it
ships with
which is also available for other
developers to build their mesh apps with
so in short we focused on the case when
internet is unavailable and so bluetooth
is used
and in particular focus just on
bluetooth low energy
the mesh that is composed of all devices
with bridge fire installed
is a managed flood-based network that
uses time to lift counters that decrease
on every hope and receipts that indicate
that the mesh message has
reached its destination
the messages sent on this network are
first compressed with gzip
and then encrypted block by block using
rsa
using the deprecated pkcs1 version 1.5
padding standard
and without internet all devices that
come into bluetooth range of each other
automatically perform a handshake during
which they exchange their
public keys now
in the setup we discovered a number of
vulnerabilities
so first an attacker with a physical
presence can easily track bridge file
users and reveal their social graphs
just by passively observing the network
further the handshake was not
cryptographically authenticated it was
only relying on
user ids and bluetooth addresses to
establish identity
and as a result there was nothing
stopping an attacker from
impersonating any user as well as from
performing
a full attacker in the middle between
any two users who
are currently in range
further while the use of pkcs1 version
1.5 didn't immediately provide a padding
oracle
one could still be built thanks to the
composition with gzip
and so a new variant of blackenbacker's
attack could be instantiated
that could decrypt a message using on
average to the 17 chosen ciphertext
and finally it was possible to perform
denial of service on the network
by using a zip bomb which is just a
small file that decompresses to a very
large payload
and we verified all these attacks in
practice on android devices using
frida which is a dynamic instrumentation
toolkit that allows
injecting scripts into running processes
essentially in a
blackbox manner
i will now go through a short timeline
of the disclosure process with bridgefy
the company
we first contacted them privately in
april 2020
initially offering the standard 90 days
before public disclosure
but after some back and forth this was
moved to end of august
however before the agreed date the
company started partially informing its
users about the existing issues
in a somewhat non-standard manner
they tweeted that they removed the
encryption from the app
so while this was not actually the case
but the company said that this was their
attempt
to explain to users in a simple way that
there
are serious issues without having to say
what exactly went wrong
and they further announced that they
were redoing their protocol from scratch
however the app or its description on
the app store didn't mention the issues
and the app continued to be promoted in
protest context
now by the agreed date in august it
wasn't clear what the timeline for the
new protocols would be
we considered moving the disclosure date
forward but there was no assurance that
this wouldn't happen again
and also given the partial disclosures
that already happened
we decided to disclose as planned
so we released an abridged version of
our paper
that came out alongside a media article
informing about the dangers of
using the app as it was then without
actually giving away details of their
implemented architecture
and then bridge fire also published a
statement of their own
in which they confirmed the issues
finally at the end of october the app
was updated
supposedly integrating the signal
protocol
however we have not reviewed these
changes and so we cannot comment on
whether the
implementation is adequate and we
recommend it to bridge file that they
employ an independent audit
if they can finally i would like to end
with a couple of doubts
so first of all you would be right to
note that there was nothing particularly
surprising about the attacks we found
once the specification was extracted
from the reverse engineered
implementation it was kind of clear
where it was going to go
and one reason for that is of course
that the app was not intended for the
protest setting
however we are kind of on thin ground
here because once the trend picked up
even the developers of bridge fight
didn't shy away from explicitly
promoting
it as a protest app this brings me to
another point
and that is underscoring the need for
applications to be evaluated under the
conditions they are used in
even if their designers have not
imagined such use cases when they began
and why do users turn to apps that are
not really fit for purpose
now here the simple answer is when
nothing better can be found
in the space of mobile mesh networking
and that is without the need for
additional hardware there are
essentially no alternatives
breyer gets mentioned here sometimes but
it only allows direct connections
without relaying private messages in the
mesh
so it's not really in the same category
and so with this work we would also like
to highlight the existing gap for
technology designers
and lastly we would also like to raise
two open questions for security research
first what security can even be achieved
in the mesh setting in the first place
well there is a lot of common ground
with messaging protocols in general
there are some features of this setting
which mean that we may need to
re-examine the notions that we deem to
be ideal
and second bringing back the focus to
the users of these apps
what security needs do protesters in
these settings actually have
we have somewhat glided over this in our
analysis imagining scenarios and
assuming that some
basic properties are actually shared
among many users
whether or not they participate in a
protest and whether or not that's in
hong kong or one of the many other
countries which included a vast range of
regimes and potential threat models
so therefore more fundamental research
into this question is needed
so that designers can avoid creating
solutions that do not fit their users
needs
and thank you for listening and i'm
happy to answer any questions
great thank you for the presentation
there's a question
in the chat from james muir asking is
there a place for pks cs1 v1.5 padding
in modern crypto
well it is a question to ask but i think
that
work like this shows that perhaps there
isn't
because i mean that would assume that
there was
there are attempts to make sure that it
works fine but it shows that in general
sometimes people may not be aware of
these so as long as it's considered as
an
okay thing to use then people will
probably keep using it and then we end
up
with attacks like these yeah i agree i
think this
is a good argument for removing these
sort of things from the kind of code
ecosystem that exists as a way to really
explicitly deprecate them
another question from watson lab are
there physical or link layer issues that
need to be considered in this context
for anonymity
um certainly there are
but i am not an expert on the subject so
i mean when we did this work we we
weren't working on this
layer at all so this is what this was
all about um
bluetooth but yes and in general
there would be i don't know if that
answers the question
yeah i think it does um a question from
jeff
burgess um can you give an example of
what you think the security goals for
any particular mesh protocol should be
um i think that's an open
i mean we listed this as an open
question for a reason so
i think off the top of my head i would
rather not speculate
okay from kenny patterson um is there a
big difference between
ad hoc networks and mesh networks and
security terms
there's some literature on security and
ad-hoc networks that could be drawn on
from building better solutions
i'm not entirely sure which part this is
referring to
whether this is ad hoc networks that are
made up of
still routers that serve users or is
those networks that are
um
because usually even even when mesh
comes up it's usually
about not not really the users are not
really part of the
network as such they are only receivers
still
but this is a mesh network that is
directly only between the mobile devices
if that makes sense yeah i suppose the
one way you
might be able to read this is uh in
terms of how much setup is done in
advance for example with bridgewater i
think
the phones just show up in a context
with no prior association and form a
network entirely in their own whereas
you can imagine a mesh network as
say some more introductions among the
nodes so you can have some more
assurances between them
yes finally one last question
uh from cass cramer's do you have an
intuition for how much the mesh network
model differs from a more standard
security model for signal
i think the the biggest difference is
just that
in the signal model you can kind of
forget where the participants are
but here this is very much a part of the
security model like are they
physically together are they within you
know four or five hops with it with
of each other so um yeah i guess the
the location is the part that's missing
all right well thanks again for the
presentation link this was
interesting thank you
next up i'd like to pass it over to um
antonio martinez uh to talk about the
work that his team at zoom has done uh
on
ends and encryption and identity there
can you hear me yes please okay awesome
hello everyone thanks for the
introduction i am antonio mercedes
a photography engineer working on
end-to-end encryption at zoom
so in may of last year our team
published a white paper detailing
a new design for end-to-end encryption
or e2e
and a strengthened notion of identity
for zoom users
we know that we opened our design up for
public review and i've received a lot of
useful feedback from the community
since october just a few months after we
started offering
end-to-end encrypted meetings to all of
our users
in this quick talk i'll cover two main
points first
i'll describe a simplified version of
the protocol which currently powers our
e2e meetings
then i'll give you a sneak peek at what
we are currently working on
i will argue that a strong notion of
identity complements and improved the
security provided by e2e
and discuss how zoom is planning to
build this identity
note that for the sake of gravity i will
be omitting some important details
so please refer to our white paper to
learn more
let's start by looking at how we built
e2e
in a standard zoom meeting which uses
what we call enhanced encryption
the tomb server generates a symmetric
meeting key and sends it to all the
meeting participants
this key is used to encrypt all the
meeting streams
and this ensures that any third parties
and network attackers such as
internet providers cannot eavesdrop on
zoom meetings
while allowing for features such as
phone dialing and cloud recording
which require the server to be able to
decrypt the meeting streams
on the other hand an end-to-end
encryption meeting is one where only the
communicating parties are able to
decrypt the meeting streams
this is really important as it protects
the meeting against server compromise
our protocol already supports meetings
with up to a thousand participants
and showcases an interesting trade-off
between security performance and
simplicity
in our design since the server cannot
generate generate the meeting here
anymore we have
one of the clients take that role we
call such client the leader
this is typically the meeting host which
already has control of several
administrative functions
such as the ability to mute and kick
participants out of the meeting
before we get to how the meeting key is
communicated to meeting participants we
have to introduce a few more details
first
each zoom device keeps a long-term
sign-in keeper
the public key is advertised to all
other participants during the meeting
while the private key never leaves the
device this key
identifies the devices across meetings
and will be the basis of the notion of
user identity which we are currently
working on
so in addition to the long term signing
key for each meeting each participant
also generates an ephemeral defiant
encryption keeper
then it signs the public defeatment key
with its device signing key
and broadcasts it to the meeting through
the server
the leader can then compute a shared
ephemeral defilement cigarette with each
participant
and use it to send them an authenticated
encryption of the current meeting key
when users join and leave the meeting
they meet the meeting leader also
rotates the midi key
so that each participant can only
decrypt the sections of a meeting in
which they participated
if there is too much churn key rotations
are throttled for efficiency
if the leader changes for example
because the original leader
lost connection or left the new leader
picks a new key
and sends it to other participants
the leader also periodically broadcasts
signed heartbeats
which include the current key generation
as well as the list
of the meeting participants which have
the current meeting key
this list is used to render the ui and
ensures that
other participants know who else is in
the meeting
since participants expect these periodic
heartbeats
the server cannot withhold key rotation
messages
also note that in this phase the display
names which are shown in the ui
can be picked and changed arbitrarily
and so they cannot be used for
identification purposes
the problem that we described so far
provides security against ease droppers
who monitor the communication
without tampering with the messages
however
without a way to confidently associate
each user with their own long term keys
it is hard to prevent active meddler in
the middle attacks and to know who
really is in the meeting
to prevent these attacks we currently
offer the meeting leader security code
a hash of the current leader's long-term
public key
which all the participants should verify
on their screens either out of band
or by reading it during the meeting
checking this code is a really if port
operation and it needs to be repeated
for every new participant
or when the leader changes it also does
not offer protection against people
posing as your colleagues to infiltrate
your meetings
this motivates our ongoing work to build
an ocean of identity
the identity that we're building will
consist of two components
first is a set of human friendly user
identifiers which we can display
during the meetings in the participant
list we use
a domain name to identify the account
which a user is part of
such as a company or school identifying
the organization one works for
is often the most important piece of a
user's identity
to identify individual users within an
account we use the email address
the second component of each identity is
a list of names
and signing public keys for all the
user's devices
some identities are mutable users can
move between accounts can change their
email
and change their set of devices we store
an identity as an append-only list of
statements that describe these changes
this makes the changes it is easily
auditable and clients can show the user
notifications
when their own identity changes this
notion of identity
will enable several important features
first clients will remember the
identities of their meeting participants
this way if one of the regular meeting
partners is suddenly
using a different device or public key a
user can be shown a warning that invites
them to check the security code
this creates a trust on first use
guarantee which is similar to what users
get in signal or whatsapp
when their conversation partners
reinstall their app or switch phones
however in our case these warnings take
into account the multi-device nature of
doom identities
older devices can sign statements at
proving newer ones
so that clients who add meetings with
their old device will not show warnings
with
when interacting with the newer devices
moreover
devices from the same user can share
information about the identity of the
users they met with
which further minimizes unnecessary
warnings
we just described how clients keep track
of their meeting partners identities
we also want to ensure that the server
cannot give different clients
a different view of any user's identity
to solve this problem zoom will deploy a
transparency tree an authenticated data
structure
backed by a merkle tree which allows the
server to commit to the identities of
all the zoom users
through a short digest two will open
source code which will allow external
auditors
in a privacy preserving way to guarantee
that identity statements cannot be
removed from the tree
clients will contact the auditors to
efficiently check that their view of the
data structure is consistent
in practice that means that if zoom
squares to add an extra device to
alice's identity
for example in order to impersonate them
in a meeting evidence of this device
cannot be erased and this action will be
detected by alice
a consistent notion of identity and the
ability to detect impersonation attacks
after fact
reduces the need to check security codes
but we want to go farther
in particular many businesses already
delegate their authentication and
identity needs
to external external identity providers
which offer
a centralized service to manage access
control to several company resources
and allow users to use a single set of
credentials to access these
resources we will partner with identity
providers
which would issue signed cryptographic
attestations
validating that a user belongs to a
company's account
this prevents a compromised boom server
from impersonating any users in that
account
to generate this attestation we extend
the open id connect
connect protocol with a new attribute
so first alice will authenticate to the
identity provider using
auth then alice can
ask for a signed open id connect
identity token which includes the hash
of r2 identity
and here we need to take special care so
that the zoom server cannot request
these tokens
then the token can be presented can be
presented to alice's meeting partners
along with the rest of their identity so
recipients can check that the identity
provider is
authorized for alice's account by
retrieving a simple json file
from the company's website over tls then
they can validate the identity and the
token signed by the identity provider
in short rather than relying on the
users to detect them
identity provider attestations prevent
impersonations from happening in the
first place
in conclusion zoom is pushing the
boundary for secure end-to-end encrypted
meanings
we currently support up to a thousand
participants and we believe that the
novel identity notion we're building
will provide the first italy meeting
experience which is secure against
active
tax without relying on security codes
that's all i had for you today thanks
for your attention if you are interested
please read our
white paper we would love to hear your
feedback and i take any questions
thanks antonio we have a few questions
queued up in the chat
i'm going to take the the privilege of
the session share and take the first
question
your description of the idp based
identity has
one participant sending an a token
to another participant um which
i find is a little surprising to me
because those are often used as bearer
tokens on so there's a risk of
token replay is is there a way you're
addressing that risk in this system
yes so we're so the details of the
um of the of this part of the world are
still
like you know being uh sorted out but
essentially
we we plan to use a different type of
token
uh to differentiate these kinds of um
tokens that are supposed to uh convey
the
link between a user's identity uh and
their public keys
from like the other better tokens
um okay great thank you let me get some
some of the chat questions
um question from kevin mccurley we don't
require users right now to provide an
email address to zoom in order to join a
room
does this mean that a user that doesn't
provide an identity can't benefit from
ede
that's a great question so we we still
offer
we we plan to still offer the users the
opportunity to
join as guests um which will mean that
they don't have to share neither an
identity nor an account
um and so in that case we will have
people will have to rely more on
security codes and the
contact sync feature to to see if this
is like the new
the first time you're meeting like a
specific with a specific device
and it's the first time you see the
public key or you know in case of uh
of a guest that uses like a like a brand
new
device or a brand new key you would have
to like check the security code in order
to be sure that there are no
man-in-the-middle attacks but of course
there's like a trade-off there and
you know even if you even if you um
plan to disclose that you are part of a
specific account we offer the option to
hide your email um there as well so you
can
say i'm i can work for bank of america
but i'm not disclosing what my email
address is
next question from nigel smart um if the
streams are encrypted end to end
how is audio merging done i'll add into
that things like video
layer selection or transcoding how is
the video merged with the audio
is that the question yeah so uh how is
he says how's audio merging
which i think he means um taking
multiple audio streams and putting them
into one for for a receiver
so the the way that the zoom works is
that the streams are not there's no
processing by the server
so the streams are all conveyed to the
client like independently
um and so that's of the solve the issue
each participant
uploads like different streams at
different resolutions and there is some
logic
in the server that can deliver to each
participant the streams that they're
interested in
but you know there's no merging done by
the server
next from watson lad um is this
something that could be used for mls in
a more open way
so the our setting is different from the
secting
of mls mainly because uh our setting
is uh synchronous so we assume that
everybody's online at that time and the
sessions are short-lived so we we we
worry less about forward secrecy
so we use ephemeral keys which means
that that are generated at the beginning
of
a meeting um but for example
uh we don't provide forward secrecy
within the meeting we only provide
forward secrecy
like after the meeting is over which
means that like essentially after the
meeting is over every participant will
delete their small secret keys um and so
this product would not be like a good
replacement for affecting
like mls okay thank you
um next from renee marhoffer how often
do you expect
device specific keys bound to the same
user identity to change
uh practical experience with things like
wire shows that people are easily
overloaded by tracking other people's
device changes
so
we we are planning to offer uh
people the opportunity to rotate their
keys the their device keys
uh but in practice we don't expect them
to change very often
and of course there is like a trade-off
between like uh
privacy and like
compromise recovery essentially um
but we don't expect these uh these
changes to happen
to us very often okay
and finally one question from about
omara
how does zoom ede integrate with srtp
um does it expose media metadata for the
media server to route streams properly
uh i'm not sure about the
details of like the
how the metadata for the streams is
communicated but
i can tell you that uh um as far as they
know they
they can't they call the messages that
are like on the on the control channel
so everything that's not actual streams
travels over an encrypted tcp
tls connection to the to the doom
servers and then
the the actual encrypted packets um
that go over udp those are sent directly
um on the network but
so i imagine most of the metadata uh
goes over there
over tls but to be honest i haven't
looked at the details of how
that part is
implemented okay thank you um
and i think that's that's the end of the
question time we had so thanks again for
your presentation today
and now we'll go for our last
presentation of paul rosler
talking about uh resolving concurrency
issues and group graduating protocols
so paul please yeah thank you very much
uh richard uh this is joint work
together with alexander beanstalk and
you have guinea doris
and we will start directly with the
motivation so we are looking at group
messaging
and the motivating example that we look
at is an activist group so we heard a
lot about
such protesting organizations and the
threat that these
users are faced with is potentially that
some of the group members
may be arrested by the police and the
police then may
obtain a copy of the key material if the
users or
the group members the activists have
their phone with them when they are
arrested
and so the key material when being
leaked to the adversary
which is in this case the police leads
to
the breach of the confidentiality of the
group messages so this is not good
a trivial solution for bypassing this
issue would be that the remaining
group members just reopen another group
and just starting there again without
those who have been
arrested but the problem is that
sometimes such a
exposure of the key material is not
directly obvious
to the users either because in this case
they they've
just mentioned far too late that he has
been arrested as well
but otherwise for example if the
exposure of the key material is not a
result of
physical excess of an adversary
adversary but rather
for example a virus has been installed
on one of the user's devices
so in these cases the the group members
cannot really
protect against such an adversary but uh
as what we want to have and this is what
modern protocols do and what mls for
example i will mention this in a couple
of slides again
what these protocols implement is a
recovery mechanism that helps them to
reach so-called post-compromise security
so this property requires and
the the technique that is implemented
there gives these group members the
ability
to generate fresh new secrets after the
adversary had access to their devices
and then from these fresh secrets they
derive public values that they then
share and as soon as each member in the
group
has shared a new information to the
then they can communicate securely again
so what you see here is however that if
these users have to coordinate in a way
that
gives them the ability to recover
sequentially
this takes a very long time for them to
have secure conversations again
and also it's possibly inevitable that
some users try to recover
concurrently and this is what the issue
here is so um what what we want to have
on the one hand to help these users to
recover
quickly and also what is sometimes
technic technically
about inevitable is that we want that a
protocol
can handle concurrently initiated
recovery attempts
so an ideal protocol would help these
users to quickly recover
would require them that the shares that
or the information that they share
in the group is relatively small
or small as possible and that these
protocols can handle
concurrently initiated recovery such
that post-compromised security is
reached and the most promising idea to
realize this uh
this type of protocols is a tree based
uh key structure and this key structure
works as follows the group members are
technically arranged in the leaves of a
tree
and within that tree these users just
arrange all the key material that they
use for
encrypting their messages by storing
in the individual storage of each user
just those secrets that are linked to
the
direct notes on the path from each
user's
leaf to the root so in this case here
charlie
would for example just store on
his device the the secrets on the path
from the leaf to the room now since all
users with their paths
share uh the joint route in their
storage they can use the
secret that is attached to this root as
the group key
now in order to recover and reach
post-compromised security
charlie would just update the secrets
that are stored on his own device and
therefore
after charlie updated those secrets he
can securely communicate with the other
users again and we can reach
post-compromise security
this basic principle is the basic idea
behind almost all
papers and also all practical protocols
that have been deployed based on this
three-based structure
and as a result these all these
protocols share
similar properties namely they all do
reach post-compromise security
and they reach this with a relatively
little communication overhead namely
each user just has for a recovery
to send the secrets for their paths
which is information in the size
logarithmic of the number of group
members
but the issue is that if two users at
the same point in time try to recover
the paths that they propose cannot
really be merged and so concurrently
cannot be really handled by these ideas
there are some sidestepping ideas uh so
i will just list them all
directly on that slide i will talk about
the mls idea later in my talk but
you see here that that all these
protocols
share the same trade-off so either they
do reach post-compromise security
but then they can't handle concurrency
or
they have a large overhead in
communication for reaching
post-compromise security under
concurrency
and the question that we asked ourselves
was is this trade-off inherent
and we must specify this question even
further by asking
whether we can find a theoretical
fundamental minimum
of communication overhead if t users at
the same point in
time try to recover concurrently
on the other hand if there is a
foundational minimum
that we can find out is there a protocol
that we can come up with that solves the
issue of
concurrent recovery attempts with
a matching overhead and we answered this
question in a paper that we
published on a rather theoretic
conference last year
but i will show you that the results are
also
practical so we begin with a theoretic
minimum
that we found out and for analyzing this
we designed a model so an abstraction
and an idealization of the real world
that is both round based and symbolic so
round based means that users in that
model are fixed
to just send once in a round and receive
once in a round
but they can do so concurrently so
multiple senders can send at the
within the same round but this shows
that
if we have an overhead found out in that
round-based model of course the the
overhead will be at least as high
uh in a setting where we have full
asynchronicity
the symbolic model means that we define
fixed computation rules so there is no
real free mathematic algebraic
structures
that all the entities in that model can
use but rather a fixed set of
computation rules and these computation
rules
model all the building blocks that we
think are useful
for realizing group ratcheting and
essentially all the building blocks that
we define cover the tools that have been
used in previous protocols
we have to restrict the the set of
building blocks in order to
not allow exotic tools like multi-party
non-interactive key exchange for which
we don't know any efficient
implementations
but that would solve the idea or the
problem of
concurrent ratcheting group ratcheting
trivially
now what we prove is the following for
any protocol that can
use those building blocks that we define
in an arbitrary combination
and that tries to help its users to
handle
t concurrent recoveries so t users try
to
recover at the same time for every such
protocol
it the following holds every user when
trying to recover has to contain in
its message when it tries to recover
asymptotically t distinct shares at
least
so this means that the the overhead is
linear
in the number of concurrency the simple
proof idea behind this
is that if we have for example four
rounds and then the second round two
users send something
then in the third round each user has to
send at least
two bits of information and this shows
that preparing
something for a later recovery attempt
is useless and this makes our proof a
little bit
tricky or harder we
then give a protocol that
helps us to to realize concurrent
recovery attempts
by the following technique instead of
updating the entire path
when uh bob and charlie try to recover
they just
update their single leaves and then in
the next round the the other users when
they are sending help them
to update the remaining secrets in the
tree and this indeed
reaches concurrent recovery i just
want to mention that the yes this
trade-off is indeed inherent but it is
probably not as
as bad as we thought it would be some
final remarks on mls
i think it is a really great success
that we soon have a standardized group
ratcheting protocol and i think it's uh
really performant and reasonably secure
and
there are many other good aspects of it
but just
a few shortcomings for example the
current idea how recoveries are
implemented in mls are the
leaked metadata for example if i try to
recover
then the server knows in which group i
try to recover and also
um the the recovery process
requires that the central server kind of
coordinates who is
sending what i won't go into details and
this is not a real huge problem
but with our protocol on the one hand we
reduce the metadata that can
be seen by a server because all our
recovery messages look the same except
for the size
and also we reduce the assumptions that
we need to make
on the central server from a
coordinating server to just a clock
synchronization
open questions are of course how can we
get rid of the clock synchronization and
just have a normal
message delivery service and also equip
our protocol with practical features
that shuts
such that for example the next uh
version of mls can make use of our ideas
and finally i think there are many other
fundamental limits that we need to
analyze
for group ratcheting in the future so
what we show in our work is essentially
that this tradeoff exists
but it's not bad as i mentioned before
you can find the full details
on eprint and you can contact me here
via twitter or
in the chat or whatever thank you very
much for your attention
thank you paul um and people feel free
to drop any questions in the chat
i'll start with one um so i i agree that
um
your uh your your observations about mls
are correct i think there are some
opportunities
to um you know mls exposing certain
metadata right now then
there's some opportunities for some
further work to reduce that
um so it seems like
when i've um and maybe i'm
misunderstanding the details here but it
seems like this
protocol you described requires uh the
group to kind of maintain some coherence
for at least a couple steps
um which seems kind of at odds with the
idea of concurrency am i
misunderstanding that or
how did this country mesh uh i think
this was just a simplification in my
talk
in fact our protocol but though a good
question
to uh to make it clearer um
our protocol just reacts in the next
round on what happens before in our
proof indeed
we show uh that uh this
that this that this overhead is
necessary
even specific for each round and not for
the entire
uh for the entire conversation fix but
we can
do it specified for each round and also
our protocol can
adaptively react on what happened before
so the concurrency
is uh so far just uh for individual
rounds and not for the entire setting
but nevertheless i think there so if you
know
uh the the uh the concurrency that is
uh assumed in your network i think so we
didn't uh
specify this through our things with
through but we had some ideas
that you can arrange the tree a little
bit more efficient if you know
what the concurrency in your setting is
yeah
a question from kenny patterson if you
hide metadata do you need lots of trial
decryption do you run into efficiency
issues in large groups
uh which kind of encryption sorry i'm
sorry if if you're hiding metadata
do you have to do trial encryption to
figure out
um oh i know so still so
what i was referring there to is signal
for example
encrypts every message independent of
whether it's a group message to which
group it goes and
to whom you should send it the same way
yet you sh
you reveal to the server to whom this
message should be delivered
but in mls as far as i understood this
proposed and commit approach
the server has to know in which group
you want to propose something and in
which group you want to commit something
and this is some metadata that reveals
in which grupo you are sending something
to
but in our protocol all the recoveries
look the same and you can say okay this
message is meant for this
user and this is for this user
nevertheless of course
we reveal uh by uh when you observe the
patterns
in which groups we are you are
communicating but if you look at the
static
database in which messages are saved
then these messages can
do not reveal this information
immediately
all right thanks and there's a couple
more questions in the chat if you could
take a look and
follow up there um i think we're out of
time for this session um so
thanks to the presenters again and
thanks to everyone for uh participating