and you can go ahead have a good session
welcome everybody to the hardware
session so we have four
exciting talks um i'll be watching the
zulip chat for questions for the
speakers so put your questions there and
make sure that you
say who they are intended for um so our
first talk is going to be
on rosita towards automatic elimination
of power analysis which will be given by
madura and yuval
hey uh good morning everyone yes i
didn't
um i'm yuval and i'm here with the
madura
and this is work that was done with the
neighbor samwell layla battina francesco
roguetzoni and marcus wagner
and uh let's go ahead madura please
okay so in 1996 paul kocher
told us that uh if we have devices that
run
cryptography then the device
interacts with the environment and may
leak information about what's going on
which we can pick up
by uh
using a maduro
and then we analyze the signal and we
can recover the key
and to fight side channels we
use a common technique we just mask up
and we take a value that we want to hide
and we choose a random mask
and when we apply the the mask to the
value
um we hide the value and now we can
process the value and the mask
together oh sorry the value of the mask
separately
and uh as long as only one of them leaks
we don't have any information leaked and
they
and we are secure and that works nice
theoretically but
if we go to the real hardware we have
an issue of unintended interaction so if
we have the computer pipeline and we
have a value going through the pipeline
then this value may be stored in one of
the pipeline registered
and it stays there
and if we later process a related value
for example the mask then
uh when it is stored in the register
uh there is a it to basically remove the
uh
the old value and that leaks uh the uh
originally unmasked value and that's not
good because we don't have any
information from software side
that will tell us that this happens so
the standard
way practitioners use
to work with that is we have our
programmer and she writes
the uh cryptographic software applied to
the device under test
run some tests on that
and analyze the test to apply fixes to
the
software and then the process repeats
and repeats
until there are knowing no more leaks
so uh this is an expensive process
because uh
we need skill tech programmers to do the
work and they need to have a
large number of skills to enable them to
do this process
and it just takes a long time to run and
they iterate between
programming and testing so what we want
to do
in this work is basically to take the
programmer out of the loop
and
automate the process and with that i'll
hand over to
my colleague madura
so basically we need to uh turn
all this into an automated process so to
do that
we use a leakage emu data called elmo
which was presented at usenix security
uh by mccann or at all and
secondly we use rosita which is a tool
that we
wrote that can apply as
patches for the softwares uh
but there's a problem with elmo that we
can't use it as it is
we need to do some changes because uh
original elmo is uh it's only capable of
emulating leakage of neighboring
instructions
any instructions that are far away uh to
the target instruction
uh are not immediate so because of this
uh we we added some modifications to
elmo to make it more realistic
ah so we
uh so this is a this is an example where
we
already found some leakage uh so let's
look at how we set up the experiment
for this experiment we loaded up two
instructions with related shares and
we added some noise in instructions in
the middle
so that these two instructions do not
interact in the cpu pipeline
let's look at the results that we got
from those
that previous experiment so in this
experiment uh what we did was
uh so here uh in the
horizontal axis uh it's the time
and and the vertical axis it's a t
value uh so the t value it shows the
significance of the leakage
and we use the 4.5
the absolute value of 4.5 as the
threshold t value for our
analysis so here you can see that
uh the real
leakage is significant at the second
instruction
and that the original version of elmo
is incapable of uh emulating it
correctly so that
we can see significant leakage and our
modification which is shown in green
uh gives us closer to realistic
uh evaluation
so now that we have a realistic
emulation of the decage
let's look at how we can find the root
causes for this
leakage so we
use the nmos power model
uh which is a combination of variables
that
emulates the differential voltage uh of
a
cpu so the elmo's
analysis generates the t test values for
the differential voltage and what we
additionally do
is that we introduce t test values for
each of
these individual variables so that
whenever these individual variables also
become significant
we know that the cost for the leakage is
coming
through uh this value
let's look at the fix on how we
use this root cause detection to apply
figs
so here we from prior detection we know
that
our the value of r4 and the memory
that's pointed to by
the value of r1 is leaking so to fix
this
uh so actually this is the this leakage
leakage is happening because these two
instructions are neighbors and that's
why they are leaking as we need to break
the
interaction between these two
instructions
to do that we add a dummy instruction
that
processes random information
so that the leakage that we saw before
is cleared out this is just a
single example for more examples like
this
that we use in rosita please read our
paper
so let's look at some results so
we started out with the mask
implementation of
aes so the this is a this should be
theoretically
leakage free but in hardware we see that
there's unintended interactions and
because of those
interactions we see significant leakage
at a
cycle around 500 so
we ran this through rosita and fixed
all leakage we did the same for
a masked version of cha-cha and we did
the same also for
sudo please
refer to our paper for more information
and because we are adding
new uh instructions for these fixes we
are
uh slowing down the uh
implementation so we have to add here
to uh 15 for aes and 64
for charger
in summary we started out by
explaining unintended instructions in
hardware
and why mask implementation stay leak
and then we we explained
how the how tedious the manual process
is and that we need
an automatic fix for this uh we improved
airmo
and then uh explained how root code
detection
uh and how rosita applies fixes
and finally we showed some results
uh uh so please
visit these two links uh to our paper
and uh uh open source version of source
rosita
thank you and i move into four questions
now
so we have several questions in the chat
already
so the first question is from anders
nilsson who asks
is the masking compiler dependent and
will switching compiler optimization
levels matter
ah so for masking it is compiling
independent because you are
the implementation itself is masked so
by switching the compiler optimizations
what you are doing
is basically changing the code
generation
so that is that is not a problem here
because what
we we apply our fixes to the
assembly so it doesn't do any change
so the um the next question is from
jurgen pulkus
who says assuming you're using your
tools on real hardware
when you're porting code from a platform
to a similar new one how do you get the
leakage model of the new platform
do you have some special test code that
you want yes so
this is this is dependent on elmo so you
need to uh
profile elmo before using it so we we
have already profiled it for uh
cortex m0 for uh stm32f030
evaluation board so even when you when
the
when the devices change you have you
have to do a profiling and
it is it doesn't it doesn't take days to
provide it so
also it's amazing
and uh so the next question is from ben
marshall who asked can you identify
patches
where you only need to reorder
instructions rather than add new ones
to save impacting performances etc
that's a good question we haven't uh
find out
ways that we can reorder the
instructions and keep the functionality
the same so
that's uh that's a bit hard thing to
guarantee but what we
do right now is to insert instructions
that do
do nothing but what they do is they
they change the uh
the execution uh to uh one that
doesn't have any unlimited interactions
because these are
uh usually uh happening at the
microarchitecture level and
we do we don't need to change the actual
values of registers
because we assume that the masking is
correct and the implementation is
correct but
what we are erasing off is unintended
ones
so our last question is from tanya langa
who asks can your tool take an unmasked
implementation as input and produce a
masked one
if so how much is the overhead compared
to starting with a manually masked one
on which you then run your tool on
yes so what we what we have to run on
our tool is uh on uh on on a pre-mask
implementation
we don't do any masking automatically so
we
it's a it's a requirement of the system
to
have a mass implementation as input
and okay i guess we have time for one
more question so watsonlad
asks what happens when the cpu gets
smarter and starts reordering the
instruction stream
uh hi so so this is
uh this is uh we we recall this as uh
pipeline instruction so pipelining is
not uh yet
uh baked into rosita so that uh so
this is actually a part of the emulation
so uh for this is uh
that's uh that's regarding so our
specific processor that we are
using right now is the cortex m0 and
it's it's on uh it only has a pipeline
of about three and uh
for that uh that the processor
the the model that's used by elmore
matches perfectly because they
uh use instruction street triplets to uh
model the case but for
anything that's more complex i think we
would need to reevaluate the model
building
and change the model to suit those
processes
thank you i guess um
oh and uh i'm being instructed to
advertise that maduro is soon on the
market
so everybody go talk to him and talk to
him and um there are more questions in
the chat
but we should move on to the next uh
talk in this session
so thank you
so i welcome everybody to um keep
discussing
this in the chat
hello there everything fine
you're seeing my slides yes so our next
talk is
risk v a risk five scalar crypto uh and
will be given by marco and ben
yeah hello there i'm uh marcus aaron um
i'm giving this talk with ben marshall
um
right so this is uh we are basically
representing
risk five which is of course a huge
consortium we have about
more than 200 members these these logos
i put together
in november and this there's already a
few missing
missing in there um basically everyone
except you know
intel and arm are members of of the risk
five consortium it's easy to be a member
because it's
it's free and even if you're not a
member you can you can use this
intellectual property to build
cpus which is of course good fun
um so anyone can create these extensions
but
of course we like to have standard
extensions so so these are the things
that we can
put in a compiler upstream to gcc
uh built into a linux kernel and
and so forth so and actually that sort
of uh standard middleware is is what we
are working on
so there are basically three kinds of
risk five so we have the
32-bit sort of microcontroller thing
here
i've got some some actual silicon off
from uh it's a low five chip which is
basically intended to be
um like replacing these low-end arm cpus
and and actually
like uh um espresso has uh has a version
of esp32
with that the second second version is
uh the 64-bit
general sort of application cpu which is
also available
um on silicon and and that has a
different kind of uh
of course it's a different instruction
set different uh register file so
so it has its own crypto extension and
then there's the
the vector architecture uh
rbv k so it can be 32 or 64 bit
and that's actually how the crypto dash
group started so they uh
basically because intel and arm has sim
d
as extensions and such it was it just
thought that yeah
let's uh let's do a similar thing with
the with the vector
registers but in 2019
um i think it was ben who first showed
that
yeah you can do things with uh with the
microcontroller things as well so you
can you can actually
have 32-bit uh crypto instructions which
are really helpful for
for speed and for contracting attacks
so uh scalar crypto means not vector it
means that you don't have a vector f
register file you are just using the the
uh general purpose which is that risk
five has
that's actually quite a quite a good you
know you can you can put secret keys and
things into 32
uh register so so um so that that's a
scalar crypto
so uh i'll advertise this
the repo here uh v actually open source
full open source cores are available
that implement this um
extension and and beef car formal uh
verification
things and and and industry
participation a as well with
that so you can find everything under
that repo
so the test group is pretty happy with
the the current status of
of this thing um and we are currently in
in we've handed it over to opcode and
consistency review so so that means that
uh the other parts of the risk five um
other risks by working groups are
checking that there's no conflicts with
any other instructions extensions and
and such but
the dash group uh has been very active
in in 2020 and
and we are pretty pretty happy with that
of course currently
most implementations of these are on on
fpga but they they exist right
um so so a little bit about the the
whole
whole uh instruction set extension bit
so this is of course a risk instruction
uh set so we don't want to just invent
the instructions
just for fun basically we we studied
uh especially the bitmap extension which
has uh
very helpful things for crypto like
rotations the the base
uh risk five instruction set doesn't
have that on or and
of course uh those make uh chart three
and char charco
go a lot faster and they are essential
for the lightweight crypto competition
candidates that are
are coming up also uh luckily enough
in in bitmap we have carrierless
multiplier that can do
gcm so we did the like evaluation of how
to do gcm on various architectures
on 32-bit 64-bit
and of course it's helpful for for like
code based crypto and some other things
as well
so we took those and made them part of
the
of the crypto extension so if you have
crypto extension
you're using the same op codes and
things same instructions by just a
subset of bit money
so we mandate that for example you'll
always have rotations if
if you you have the crypto extension but
then there's specific things that really
benefit uh from having special purpose
instructions like aes so that you know
your
timing out x and such are are can be
encountered that way
so that that was basically the approach
um
minimal set uh for standard things that
that you can use it at the most
so aes there's two kinds of areas the
the
microcontroller the very lightweight
aes is basically doing t
tables in hardware so
d table of course in assembly would be
five instructions you would have to mask
the
by you would have to do address
calculations do a table look up and sort
that together
so all of that is rolled into this a
single
cycle instruction which is very small so
that
it's about like 1 000 uh gate
equivalents
which means that aes all of the sudden
becomes like a lightweight crypto
this can be implemented on a on a on a
32 bit core that has very little
else than than any other extent this
extension alone this instruction
uh or these instructions here are
sufficient to implement aes
so so that's fun um
for 64 bit there's a little bit
different extension of course the
biggest registers are double the size so
so you can in two
instructions process the 128-bit
bit state you need six instructions per
round
uh that's that's again faster
i mean that was five times faster and
compared to if it's less inflation
required for constant time it's
that was more than ten times faster this
is faster again
but it's a little bit larger because but
you can do these trade-offs
we have a paper uh already on on on
teaches or coming up in chess
later this year about these sort of uh
considerations we did consider quite a
lot of different types of instructions
right there's also a lightweight shot to
support
that that um well it's not so needed for
for uh timing attack countermeasures but
it does uh it's a very simple
instruction it's just
a bunch of constant rotations and uh
source basically
implementing these sum and sigma
functions uh
and similarly for sm3 with the chinese
equivalent
we have uh we have support for that
and well the approach random
is a little bit different so so this is
an um entropy source interface uh
it's it matches basically with the sb
890b
and and an aes31 approach
we already have as4 drbg generation so
so this is simply an entropy source
interface defining the minimum entropy
coming coming in there it's an
it's it's not a user mode uh instruction
intel had had some problems with that um
some um yeah anyway it's a it's a uh
it's a very simple instruction we've
already been in in touch with bsi and
nice you know
hoping that this will actually meet the
certification requirements for
common criteria and uh and and vip spawn
40-3
so um so
10 minutes is up so we got a bunch of
stuff here that
that i collected so how do i do rsa so
um risk 5 is famous for not having a
carry flag
that one would need of course to do
large additions but actually if you look
at common implementations they use this
redundant
representation where you have a
basically carry accumulation within
those
like a small bit of each bird uh this
generic instructions that help with all
kinds of uh things like side channel
countermeasures
table lookups constant time we also have
a
constant time multiplication requirement
there's like an encoding
for so that your rsa will be constant
time
um and uh of course we've um we've run
all the post quantum algorithms on this
just you know they are no surprises they
are really
behavior is like but uh they're similar
similar class cpus
um uh lots of questions about
non-invasive which is the fibs
for side channel uh yeah
we don't have any this is an isa
instruction set architecture
proposal so so it's all up to the
implementation and anyway
if you certify something like that you
are basically certified
a cryptographic module which consists of
um
of um of the hardware and software for
so for very specific hardware
implementation you can probably certify
uh some some such channel resistant
things up to the highest
like common criteria levels
so yes coming to that i have been also
able to answer questions so
um so thank you
so we have uh one question so far in the
chat but i think this came earlier in
the talk so it might need more context
uh richard outer bridge asked what about
apple's arm m1 yeah that's that's
probably related to uh
rosita which is called xm0 thing uh by
the way
we are uh definitely doing emulators on
on
leakage emulators also for risk five but
that's that's that's
you know yeah
um so i have a question about the random
number generation so
um is there any um specification about
the entropy source
um yes there's this paper
that kind of gives the idea about
what the entropy output should be about
so we don't opinionate about the noise
source itself we just
required to have certain amount of
entropy and have the
sort of uh health phase required by for
certification
there's this couple of uh things like
for virtual machines it can be a sort of
virtual
entropy source but in that case we
require
uh it to be secure at least two five six
bit secure
this uh this yeah that paper gives a
pretty big
pretty good outline of the whole thing
and there's also an awful lot of design
rationale
in the spec itself it's it it is
recommendations to implement as
sort of hereby dragons is how everyone
else has gone wrong in the past
implementing their
their random number generator source of
their energy source here's how we're
learning from it
so there's a lot of that yeah our
rational for entropy source is
this big chunk of of the specification
so there's i guess um i failed to scroll
down so now there's uh
lots of discussion and questions in the
chat so um
let's see there's already some answers
so uh jurgen focus
asks uh when designing the crypto
extensions did you also consider
instructions that might be helpful to
implement side channel countermeasures
yes right there have been
several proposals for that well
ben and you yeah so it depends which
kind of side channel countermeasures are
talking about so for timing
the most important one is things like
table lookups in aes and
that problem goes away if you wrap up
that in an instruction so that's sort of
done and out of the way
um there are some general purpose
instructions included in the
proposals that make it really easy to do
constant time s boxes
um for other algorithms like camellia
for example
um for things like power and em um
that's an open research question how do
you give iso level guarantees
about microarchitectural behavior and
the same thing is true for sort of
general purpose
um timing attacks there's an interesting
paper called the
aisa or augmented iso that talks about
it a lot of the timing
but quite early on in the standards
process we decided to sort of put
power and em side channel considerations
to one side
yeah so when isa is a contract between
the hardware and the programmer and
and having having side channel things in
there that would make it a lot
you know a lot completely different
looking thing than an isa specification
the the point of the spec is to make
sure that as
long as you implement it functionally
under the hood you can do all kinds of
crazy clever things to make it
whatever side channel secure that you
care about um
so if you're a specialist shop that
builds risk five cores you know
this should make your life a bit easier
from a supporting software point of view
um and then we also have a question from
watsonlad who asks what
sort of big number assistance is there i
love to have a simple way to do carry
chains and multiply
accumulates with the full width and the
hardware like uml from arm
so risk five or maybe you want to go
marcu
yeah so the recommendation is is to use
this uh
redundant bit representation and
and it works for vector two so so it's
basically where you have
eight bits out of 64 bits as a carry and
then you do a laser reduction on that
and it's it works on the on the scalar
instruction set and also on vector
vectorize
multiplication and big integer but yeah
general recommendation is rbr
[Music]
there are more questions in the chat but
we are at 15 minutes so i guess we
should
get to the next talk so thank you very
much and everybody keep
keep uh keep conversing in the chat but
make sure that you label your questions
for for who they're aimed for so i can i
can tell what's going on
um so our next talk everything
everything works
so our next cut talk is cash out in sga
axe how sgx fails in practice
and it'll be given by stefan and andrew
hello everyone um i'm stefan and
together with andrew we'll be talking
about cash out and his checks today
but first a quick recap so back in 2018
you might remember these logos
back in 2018 we've got a new class of
speculative and transient execution
attacks and we basically saw a text like
meltdown foreshadow inspector
and to
stop working so
how these attacks work basically we have
a basic cache hierarchy here and we have
our execution core
and we have like our l1d cache and
meltdown and ford shadow basically
are able to leak data from the l1d cache
and of course this is very bad so this
prompted the right mitigation efforts
and if you buy it like the cpu you see
here the i9 9900k
it's basically no longer possible to
leak from the caches as you're no longer
able to
use small down unfortunately um
then in 2019 it actually turns out that
there are many more interesting buffers
to use
so if you look closer at the diagram you
see like a field buffer the subwoofer
and the loadport
and in 2019 we actually saw a new clause
of attacks called
mds or microsexual data sampling and
these are basically able to sample data
from
from these buffers as data passes
through so what mds does
it basically targets these internal cpu
buffers
um so basically nds allows you to
use faulting or assisting loads
basically for instance through
speculation
and that way you can access other
people's data and this works across
processes
vms and even intel sgx and basically
what this meant means is that if you
looked at the news
it basically had the same implication as
meltdown and it was also sometimes
dubbed second meltdown
so what nds does is like if we have like
a malicious user
as data passes through the field buffer
and this is basically able to sample it
but as only as long as it passes through
the filter
so what this means is that mds attacks
are basically like drinking from fire
hose
you just get whatever data is in flight
at the time um
and the hands also the name
microstructural data sampling because
you're just sampling data from these
microstructural buffers
but it also means that at the same time
you have no control of what you're
getting as you're just
leaking whatever data is in flight at
the time in those buffers
so how to dental mitigate this well
intel just um
update release a microcode update that
patches the 4w instruction
and the w instruction is used to flash
these internal cpu buffers up on every
context which for instance
when switching between processes and
this actually brings us to part two of
the talk so cash out
so if you look a bit closer at these
mitigations they just flushed internal
cpu buffers
um but this was actually not fixed it
would cause behind mds it just ensures
that the data is no longer present there
but it it doesn't really fix the fact
that you can still leak data from those
buffers so if you somehow can get data
inside of those buffers
you should be able to leak it so this
brings us to
an important question so is flushing
buffer sufficient as a mitigation and
as a bonus um as with nds you get like
whatever data's in flight like you you
see
you saw this girl can we actually be
like this cat and get some more control
over um over the leakage
so if we look at the at the mds works
for instance the real paper
um this code basically mentions that um
if you evac data from the
from the cache it's basically forced
into the fill buffer
and the zombie layer paper also reports
a 0.1 bytes per second leakage despite
the mitigation
um and this residual leakage is actually
worse
so what we found with cash out is that
there is exactly a data pad
um from the l1d cache to the l2 cache
that
gets triggered through eviction so
whenever you evict something from the
l1d cache
it actually passes through the field
buffer before reaching the level two
cache
um but remember that the line field
buffers are still leaking so if
we can actually manage to get data
through the field buffer
we should be able to sample it so how do
we exploit
um evictions so we have a cache which is
fast we have a fill buffer next to it
and we have a dram which is slow
and as the program runs and the victim's
data ends up in the field buffer and the
cache
and now as the operating system switches
to the attacker the 4w instruction
basically ensures that the fill buffer
no longer contains the victim's data
so can we somehow get the data from the
cache into the field buffer
so the cache is divided into different
sets and if you have like the address of
your data determines into which cassette
the data is going to be
so what the attacker does the attacker
just reads addresses that all map to the
same cache set
to basically fill the cache set with its
own data and because there's no room
left for the for the victims data
it has to be evicted so it ends up in
the field buffer
and in the meanwhile the cpu just writes
it back to the dram
and this basically allows the attacker
to perform as an attack simulator mds
where it just performs a faulty load
samples the data from the fill buffer
and then extracts the data
back to the attack so what we found with
cachet is that you're actually able to
link at 2.85 kilobytes per second rather
than the 0.1 bytes per second that
zombielog mentions
and cash out actually targets data at
rest rather than in flight so with mds
you just have to rely on the victim
accessing the data continuously to
ensure that it's in the lightful buffer
and then while the victim is running you
can basically sample the data from the
line folder
with cache out we actually have control
over when the data ends up into the lfb
we just effect like the particular cache
that we want
and we can actually do this long after
the victim access the data
and because we have control over the
particular cache set we can actually
structure data like as and rsa keys
we can leak neural network rates we can
even break hazel
and the kernel data and this works
across vms
as well as including hypervise
so to put it even more to the test we
put the picture of the mona lisa
inside an asgex enclave and we basically
managed to restrict it
using cache and with that andrew is
going to talk to you about
the exact implications of cash out for
sgx
all right thanks stefan so uh intel's
sgx is a set of cpu features that allows
developers to
run code and store secrets inside of
enclaves such that nothing uh
neither the os nor the hypervisor nor
anything but the enclave
can read the enclave's contents sgx also
provides remote antistation
which allows the enclave to prove to a
remote client that the enclave has been
initialized properly
and on genuine sjx hardware to do this
sgx stores a key called the epic key
enhanced privacy id
inside each cpu the epic key is used to
sign the contents of the enclave
along with a diffie-hellman key exchange
this produces a quote
which can be forwarded to the remote
client as proof
and the takeaway of all this is that all
the trust is based on the assumption
that the fbkey
cannot be used by an adversary to forge
arbitrary quotes
with cash out however we broke this
assumption by extracting the epic
private key
as proof of this we deployed the sgi
spot on twitter which will attest
anything tweeted at it using that key
and back when we first released it in
june it actually signed over 100 quotes
within two hours after which it was
blocked by github
and after the public release of the
paper and the bot
the key that was used by the bot was
actually still trusted for an entire
month
and this is because updating the sjx tcp
requires users to uh
install bios updates and not all users
are tech savvy enough to do that quickly
and so intel can't invalidate them too
quickly
to address this we and to be responsible
we hard-coded mri signer
to prevent abuse of the uh of the bot
so now let's look at a case study uh uh
using signal as an example to see how
cash out's extraction of the epic key
can impact a real world
application so so back in may sigma
started prompting users to add pins to
their account
and this was to deploy a new technology
called secure value recovery svr
and the idea behind that is that it can
be used to backup contacts in the cloud
and enable non-phone number based
addressing
you may be thinking however isn't the
selling point of signal that they don't
store info about users
well to address this the data is
encrypted under a key that is derived
from both the user's pin
and a random seed and done in such a way
that signal themselves cannot decrypt
the data
the only problem is that the system
relies on sgx
so let's look at a simplified overview
of how sbr works
the user will first select their pin
that will get hashed
and expanded into a value called c2
which is stored on signal servers
then c2 will be combined with a 256-bit
random seed
to generate an encryption key when the
user wants to
store their data it will get encrypted
under that key
and finally stored on signal servers
and so the encryption key is derived
from both the user's secret pin and a
random seed
however the user's pin is likely just a
four digit number
which can easily be brute force so to
solve this
c2 and the random seed are stored in an
enclave and the enclave
rate limits the guessing attempts
against c2
so this works properly the user's data
is still secure even when the user's pin
is short and memorable
however uh using cash out
an attacker with access to the signal
server storing c2
can just use cash out to recover c2 from
the l1 cache
uh this however requires some side
channel knowledge alternatively we can
exploit the trust placed in the epic
keys that we did that we extracted
so we just take a closer look at how c2
and the random seed are stored
they're actually stored as a distributed
log using raft where each of the sgx
replicas is storing c2 and the random
seed
however if the cluster's network is
compromised whether by a subpoena or
coercion or a hack machine
an attacker can use the stolen epic keys
to forge a quote
proving that the malicious replica is
running on sgx
even though it's not then if this quote
is given to the network it can
it can um request that the raf network
replicate the entire log to the fake
then since it's not running sgx c2 and
the random seed can be read
in plain text and and then the user's
pin can be brought forth from there
uh so in summary cash out breaches xbx's
confidentiality
allowing an attacker to masquerade as a
legitimate sgx enclave even if it's not
and and while it's good that signal is
thinking about side channels against sgx
by inserting l fences before each branch
and using red pallenes
these don't actually mitigate cash out
and so stx cannot be relied upon to
limit guessing attempts
this means that signal should still
require strong passwords for svr
and uh and so while we did extract the
epid key using cash out
we didn't concretely demonstrate the
signal attack because it requires
it assumes a malicious signal server
with access to the cluster
so you can't do this at home however
this is also
the threat model that signal was built
with in mind
so as a counter measure until uh deploy
a dedicated microcode updates on june
20th
and with that i am happy to take
questions
so i'll start with one question which is
um what
so for the for the signing bot what were
the counter measures that you took
against
abuse yeah um so
the there's a field that is signed in
the quote
that is the mr uh signer
mr enclave and so you can see that those
values are hard to sgx how sgx feels in
practice
and mron played when good on facebook
bad so it could only masquerade as
an enclave that happen to use those same
fields
which is um yeah it's unlikely anyone's
using those
so did you have any uh evidence of
people trying to
misuse this for actual attacks not
uh no um
yeah no
and why why did it get blocked on github
and not on twitter
um it was actually it's taken down from
both
um yeah
are there other um threat scenarios
beyond the
the signal case that um you could see
this being
applied in um
yeah so so we should signal the case
study because that's actually um
a widely deployed application that's
using sdx
uh there are a few others that we
discussed in the paper
um more sort of experimental sjx use
cases
there are some academic works using sgx
combined with ethereum um such as um
uh oasis
um
yeah then
uh we have a question i think i think
this is aimed at at this talk so uh
richard otterbridge asks which
mainstream architecture is eg intel amd
apple have been microcode patched
you want to take that questions down
um so basically as it uses uh like
as skyshark relies heavily on ental tsx
and sjx which are like intel only
technologies edges
until that's basically affected by these
by these issues
and we haven't heard from any of the
other companies if they actually have
similar issues
so only intel really world arts
microcode updates
back in june basically
um i guess we are at time so thank you
very much and and further questions can
be posted in the zulu chat
so i guess we should move on to our next
speakers
thank you
so our last talk of the session um is
going to be
my car my other car is your car
compromising the tesla model x keyless
entry system
and will be given by linux
thank you um so this talk is about
compromising the tesla multi-skills
entry system
as this is a very brief talk i will
mainly cover the issues that we found
and how we exploited them but not how we
found these issues exactly
now this is the hardware attack so we're
going to start by looking at some
hardware
if you want to unlock a car you usually
use a key fob
that's not different in the case of the
tesla model x so if we open up this
keyfob it looks like this and there's a
few interesting components we can
identify
so first of all we see a texas
instrument's bluetooth low energy
microcontroller
that is packed with a two 2.4 gigahertz
range extender
on the other side we see a maximum
integrated 22 kilohertz
transponder chip that is not used to do
any cryptographic operations in this
case
it's only used to establish a low
frequency communication link
then on the far left we see an
accelerometer that is likely used to
prevent relay attacks
and then finally we see an infineon
slm-97 secure element
that is common criteria certified so you
can likely imagine that this
secure element is performing all of the
cryptographic operations
and would probably be the toughest nut
to crack
so from an attacker's point of view it
makes sense to try and compromise the
bluetooth energy chip
because if you're able to do this you
can send commands directly to the secure
elements
now if we take one of these key fobs
take out the battery and put it back
in it will actually start advertising
itself as a bluetooth low energy
peripheral
which means we can connect to it and we
can observe all of these services and
characteristics that are exposed on the
device
now one of the most interesting services
is related to over air download
which is basically a way for us to push
new firmware to the key fob
and as it turns out tesla modified the
implementation from the example but
there was a bug in how they
validated the signature so this means
that we can override the firmware on the
key fob
a second interesting service related to
application protocol data units
which is basically a format of sending
commands to secure elements
so this means that to this service you
could send commands to the secure
element
over bluetooth now this is likely a
security
issue and so tesla realized this and
implemented
some blocks basically on the server so
that wouldn't allow you to send all of
the
possible apd commands and of course they
blocked the apdu commands that we as an
attacker would like to use
now of course if we can override the
firmware inside of the bluetooth low
energy chip we can remove these
instructions
now at the beginning of this slide i
told you that i would have to remove the
battery from the keyfob which of course
makes the attack quite lame
and it turns out that we can actually
circumvent this issue by using a body
control module
so this is one of the ecu's that is
normally located inside the vehicle
and in this case is responsible for
among other things unlocking the vehicle
now as it turns out this body control
module can
actually send a wake up command over low
frequency to the key fob
which forces the key fob to advertise
itself as connectable over bluetooth
energy
and this is done based on an identifier
that is derived from the vin
so the fin is a unique number associated
to the vehicle
does in this case also stored in a
secure element inside of the body
control module
now of course if we replace a secure
element we could take this body control
module into believing it belongs to a
different car
and then use it to wake up a target
keyfob
so for now our plan of attack looks
something like this
we send a command using a modified bcm
to the keyfob
that wakes up the keyfob we now connect
to it over bluetooth
we push our own modified firmware to the
key fob which removes all of these
restrictions
on the apdu interface then we can
request a valid rollout code to this
interface from the secure element
and we can then go back to the vehicle
and use it to unlock the car
now it's important to realize that we
can only unlock the car using one of
these rolling codes and that we would
not be able to start the vehicle
and of course it's more fun if we can
also drive off with the car
so at this point we have established
physical
access to the interior of the vehicle
and it now makes sense for us to look at
how tesla would spare a new key fob to
the car
and as it turns out tesla uses something
that's called the tesla toolbox for this
which is used to service model s and
model x vehicles by uh
service technicians basically so the
tool is not publicly available on the
internet
but as with most things leaked versions
do exist
on the internet and tesla even briefly
released
the tool themselves unintentionally a
few weeks ago
now once you install the tool you will
realize that most of the interesting
stuff is actually stored encrypted
but as you can imagine the tool itself
has to actually decrypt
these modules before it can use them and
of course these modules contain a lot of
interesting information for us
so normally what would happen is you
have a service technician with a laptop
that's running the tesla toolbox
software
he has valid tesla credentials and so
also gets access to a back-end hsm
or hardware security module the laptop
also has a usb to com interface
that allows the toolbox software
basically to send apdu commands to the
secure element
inside of the body control module and on
the other side it also has a usb to
bluetooth adapter
that allows the software to send apdu
commands to the secure element inside of
the keyfob
and in this way the toolbox software can
communicate with both secure elements
and basically perform
the pairing procedure now the actual
pairing can be split up into
two parts namely provisioning and then
actual pairing so as it turns out
every secure element will have 5 rsa
slots
slots 0 and 1 are reserved to store
tesla specific certificates
and then the secure elements will
generate 3 rsa key pairs
and the idea here now is that the
backend hsm will
create certificates for these slots and
then the certificates get stored inside
of the secure element
so presumably here the idea is that if
you pair this keyfob now to a vehicle
the vehicle would be able to ensure that
it's pairing to a legitimate key fob
that has valid
certificates signed by tesla
so at this point we can continue to the
actual pairing process
and we could play a little game so if
someone is able to find these
certificates back
in this pairing protocol then i will buy
them a virtual beer
later on in the conference so now you
can see that the properties involved are
basically
the card body control module the toolbox
and the keyfob
but the keyfob will actually never send
its certificates to the car
so the car is not able to verify that
it's pairing to legitimate keyfob
so for us from the attacker's point of
view we can basically modify a keyfob
and have it skip all of these
provisioning related steps and
immediately go for the pairing protocol
and that's how we basically complete our
attack
so we've already established physical
access to the vehicle
we now connect to the diagnostic
interface and start pairing a key fob
that we have modified
i'll show you in a bit more detail how
we modified it
so to show you how we do this this
attack in practice we've built a proof
concept tool that is
completely battery powered so it's
mobile and it fits in a backpack
it consists of a raspberry pi that
basically controls all of the
electronics
and on top of the raspberry pi we have a
gan shield that
can send can bus commands basically to
the body control module that's
on the other side of this device but you
can also connect the second interface of
this module to the diagnostic interface
inside of the vehicle
and then finally on top you can see the
model x key fob that we use
so this is a standard model x key fob we
didn't modify any of the firmware
but what we did is we removed the secure
element from the board
and replaced it with a usb to sale
converter
and this basically allows us to
implement our own version of the secure
element
in the python script that runs on the
raspberry pi
now a similar modification was made to
the body control module
so again we remove the secure element we
replace it with a usb to serial adapter
and then emulate the secure element in
python
and basically what this allows us to do
is to take this body control module into
believing it belongs to a specific
phenomena
and that then in turn allows us to wake
up the key folk
now of course when we found these issues
we reported them to tesla this was back
in august of 2020.
they released a patch by the end of
november 2020
basically together with a with making
this research public
and they gave us a five thousand dollar
bounty
now to end the stock i want to show you
a video of how we would carry out this
attack in practice
i'm gonna switch to vlc i hope this will
work smoothly
over zoom but basically the idea is that
we have someone that
parked their vehicle and in this case
they parked it in front of our
university building
which was probably not the best decision
ever
so now they're maybe going for a walk or
waiting for the car to charge
and at this point we can approach the
vehicle with our tool
we can reach the vin number from the
vehicle from the windshield enter this
into our tool
and now our modified body control module
thinks it belongs to that exact same
vehicle
and it allows us basically to wake up
kefobs and force them to advertise
themselves over bluetooth low energy
so this initial step has to be done over
a distance
of up to about five meters but once
we're connected
to bluetooth we can of course extend
this range so now we're pushing our
modified
firmware to the key fob which opens up
the apdu interface
and now we can start asking the secure
elements to provide us with codes to
unlock the car
so these codes are rolling codes they're
one time valid and we have to use them
in the same order as we receive them
from the secure element now we can of
course go back
to the car and use these rolling codes
to
unlock the door and as this is a model x
we also of course have to open the
falcon doors
now as i've explained earlier at this
point we were able to get inside of the
car
and that's basically where the second
phase of our attack starts because now
we can start
pairing our modified key fob
so we get inside of the vehicle and we
attach the tool to the diagnostic
interface which is located
underneath of the center display in the
vehicle
once connected we can start pairing our
modified keyfob
and as i explained before we basically
skip all of the parts of the protocol
that we don't want to perform
now the car in a few seconds believes
that we have a valid key for paired to
the car
we start emulating again what a normal
key fob would do inside of the secure
element
the car will send us a challenge we
compute a valid response
the car verifies this response and then
allows us to drive off
so with that i want to end my
presentation
and if there's any questions i would be
happy to answer them now or later on in
one of the
social rooms
so can you
um just because i'm slow and i don't see
questions yet in the in the chat
everybody post your your questions in
the uh
um in the zooloop chat uh which parts of
the
the protocol is it able to skip um like
if there's some
signature validation that it just
normally would um normally when you get
a new key fob
so you buy a brand new one from from
tesla basically
it will it will be in in this state
where tesla certificates have been
loaded
but these slots are locked so you can no
longer override them
and then basically what the service
technician will do is to
instruct the secure element to generate
these rsa key pairs
and then um get the back-end hsm
basically to create certificates now
because i'm not a
service technician okay i'm not that
yeah i don't have a
valid credentials to this toolbox
software i cannot use the backend hsm
and i wouldn't be able to create
certificates so i wouldn't be able to
log the slots
and i wouldn't be able to go to the to
the next step which is basically a
pairing protocol
and then by basically replacing the
secure element i can
basically start at this point in the
protocol and it's also important to note
here that in the provisioning the the
car is not part of the protocol
so it doesn't realize that something is
is going wrong
so we have a couple questions from the
chat now so uh
lorenzo martinico asks um once you have
physical access to the can bus what
other attacks are possible
there's all kinds of stuff that's
possible um
i think on the diagnostic connector so
inside of a vehicle there are usually
multiple can networks
on the diagnostic connector you can
access all of them so the one we're
connecting to specifically is the
bodycon
so one other thing that would be
interesting look to look at for example
is
tesla has a second factor of
authentication where you enter a pin
before you can actually start the
vehicle
now there's only so many ways they can
implement this and my feeling is that
the center display would have to
communicate with the body control module
and or the um the driving first inside
of the vehicle and this has to happen
overcome
so there's some potential for attack
there as well
um so basically bypassing second factor
the second factor
but there's all kinds of malicious thing
someone could do with access to the
canvas of course
so cyrus manuela asks in the video why
does the attack work without power
cycling the key fob
so that's basically um what i explained
here
so they they have basically um
maybe i can better show it here so on
this
tool i'm not sure if it's visible on
your end but basically this tool says
um that it's waking up keefops with a
specific car identifier
and that's it's basically to make the
life of the service technician easier
so it can they can basically instruct
the vehicle to do
the wake up of the key fob instead of
having the service technician
having to open the key fob and take out
the battery and i'm basically using
a component that's inside of the vehicle
to to emulate this
uh your muted mother there are a bunch
of super interesting questions going on
in the chat but i feel like we should
move on to the next session on formal
analysis since
we're at time but i encourage everybody
to go to zulip and
talk about how to properly design a car
security system without these um