all right
we are live so hi everyone my name is
martin i'm the chair of this session and
the next
um and the uh first so the next session
is an invited talk uh to be given by
dustin moody from nist and he's going to
give us an update
on the post quantum process
um by uh nist thank you dustin
thank you martin let me uh
share the slides hopefully that's
working and everybody can see that
so on behalf of nist and the post
quantum team
like to thank real world crypto for
inviting us to give an update on our
competition um i'll rewind back two
years ago
uh real world crypto similarly invited
us
it was at the end of our first round and
we were going to announce the candidates
for the second round of our nist
um post quantum competition
and we were invited to come do that at
real world crypto
uh you may or may not remember but
shortly before that happened uh the u.s
government went into a shutdown
so being a government employee we were
not allowed to come
and give that presentation so i'm glad
here two years later i'm i'm able to
participate even though there's a
pandemic and it's virtual
it's uh good to be here
so of course everyone is probably aware
of the the threat that quantum computers
pose it nist we're most worried about it
in regards to our our three public key
crypto standards that we have
we have two of them that deal with
public key encryption
or key establishment those are sp 800
56a and 56b
and then we also have a public key
digital signature standard
in fips 186. and these would be the ones
that would be most
vulnerable to attacks from a quantum
computer namely schwarz
algorithm which would break all the
algorithms that we use today
for public key name the rsa dsa ecdsa
diffie-hellman olympic curve
diffie-hellman
and so forth and so we need to
completely replace
the algorithms in these standards we
have many other crypto standards and
there would be impacts from a quantum
computer but the impact is
less dramatic we would be able to use
longer keys use longer hash function
output
etc which is easier to manage than
having to select a
a whole new algorithm
so that's what this project is this post
quantum cryptography project
we want to ensure that the crypto we are
using today will be
secure from both classical computing
technology as well as future quantum
computers
and even though we don't yet have a
large scale working quantum computer
uh we know that we need to begin working
on this problem well in advance of that
and that's best explained by uh this
theorem from dr michele mosca that
has been widely seen as well that helps
us
understand that even without a quantum
computer here
somebody could take your data which is
encrypted and just hold on to it
and wait until z years later when you
when they a quantum computer comes out
and then they'll be able to
get access to your data well before the
you know you want your information to be
revealed
and so it's displayed here in forms
where you could put in numbers for
x y and z for your organization
and see you know do you have a problem
now and
if you want to protect your information
for any length of time
yeah we need to worry about this now
now the big question is what is z how
long until we
have a quantum computer it's not exactly
my field i'm not a physicist or in
quantum mechanics or anything
um so for that we have to turn to what
the experts say
and i'm copying here a chart from the
publication of dr mosca and one of his
co-authors
peony from a little over a year ago
they surveyed 22 experts in the field
and asked them what what would be the
their opinion
of when we would have a quantum computer
that's large enough
that would threaten public key crypto
and so if you look at this chart for a
little bit the first row
is they put odds on would we have one in
five years
and you can see that most of them
thought it would be
less than a one percent chance but as we
go down a couple rows to 10 years 15
years we see
more of these experts believe that
there's you know there's there's a
there's a chance we could have a
large-scale quantum computer
that would be breaking cryptography of
course nobody knows for sure this is all
just speculation
but it just goes to uh give you some
estimates on a possible time frame of
10 to 15 years is you know a rough time
frame
when this could could be something uh
where we'd have a quantum computer
around that time
at nist we've been worried about this
for quite some time well before
2016 we held a workshop back in 2015 and
had a survey paper we put put out back
in i think 2010
but in terms of our competition it
really started five years ago in 2016.
that's where we
we first announced at uh pq crypto in
japan that we would be doing this post
quantum
competition and we put out the
requirements and the evaluation criteria
we would be using
since then we've had uh two rounds
we received a large number of
submissions and all in the
slides coming up here i'll quickly
summarize those first two rounds
but right now where we are is we're in
the the middle of the the third round
where we have uh 15 algorithms that
we're still considering
um for each of the previous two rounds
we've issued reports um
the you can see them highlighted here if
you just google mr 8240 or 8309
you can see our report on each round and
how we selected the algorithms to move
on
and and so forth
so the evaluation criteria that we are
using
the the two main criteria are security
and performance
and again security we need to be secure
against both classical and quantum
attacks
and for some algorithms setting your
parameters to classical attacks are
actually the ones that
are most relevant we defined five
security categories so that when
submitters were creating their parameter
sets and wanting to uh
show how much security they offered that
they would have a uniform framework to
compare them against each other and we
would
have that as well level one means you're
at least as hard to break as aes using
an exhaustive key search and the other
levels are similarly tied to
some of the symmetric key crypto that we
have standardized at nist already
we think that levels one two and three
will be enough for the next several
decades
and we also have levels four and five
for applications that need very high
security
and to see how key sizes and so forth
scale as you increase your parameters
so security is always top priority for
cryptography
after security there's performance and
that would be measured on a variety of
of classical platforms both low-end and
high-end
software and hardware this includes both
the efficiency like how fast you can
encrypt and decrypt
um as well as the size like what's the
public key size what's the signature
size cyber text size
etc and then beyond these two main
criteria there's a number of other
properties that it would be nice to have
you know as much as possible a drop in
replacement
provide perfect word secrecy beside
channel resistant
and so on and so forth so there's kind
of a laundry list of
desirable properties knowing that it's
probably not possible to have you know
absolutely everything here
there's no silver bullet that solves all
the problems
so in the first round we had 82 schemes
that were submitted to us
69 of them met our requirements um five
withdrew pretty quickly after they were
broken so for
most of the first round we were left
with 64 algorithms in play
you can see in the table in the bottom
right for the most part they followed
the established lines of research that
the community was well aware of
so there was a lot of lattice-based
submissions a lot of code-based
submissions
and several multivariate signatures as
well as some other uh
ideas out there such as stateless hash
isogenies
and and so on i think it was a lot of
fun for cryptographers right after we
published this
you know here's 60 some schemes to it to
attack so cryptographers quickly went to
work
and just in the first i'd say a month or
so you know they've broken
probably about 20 of the the 69 that
were out there
so that was a lot of fun to see we held
a workshop where we invited all
the round one participants to come and
to
explain their their strengths of their
algorithm so that had a large number of
presentations
it was held in florida very nice venue
we established the the pqc forum and
had a lot of discussion a lot of
questions a lot of posting a lot of
official comments on there
and that's still very active today and
you can look up those archives and see
what people were talking about
a lot of research a lot of performance
numbers in the first round
and after about a year um once our
government shutdown ended
we selected 26 of the most promising
schemes to move on into the
the second round that included
four submissions that were mergers from
the first round
there had been a lot of very similar
submissions particularly in the lattice
chems
so it was good to see that we had some
mergers going on
for the most part we maintain the
diversity of the algorithms from the
first round
but we needed to choose smaller numbers
so that people could focus on
we held a workshop co-located with
crypto out in california and that was a
good workshop
a lot of people attended that and as
could be expected cryptanalysis
continued even in the second round
these were the 26 of the the more
promising schemes but even
even then seven of them were broken or
significantly attacked
in the second round and
we're also glad to see even more bench
work benchmarking more performance
numbers
um and and experiments that were being
done where they were taking some of
these algorithms
and putting them into real world
experiments into protocols and testing
them out to see how would they perform
after 18 months we selected 15
submissions to move on
into the third round and that was a
really difficult
decision process it took us a while to
to settle on that
so looking back at the first round
candidates here are
they all listed if you're involved in
attacking some of them may see some
familiar names among them
it's kind of fun to see the names
everybody chooses
for the second round i crossed out the
ones
that did not make it the ones in orange
were mergers they merged together
to make it into the second round so i
wanted to highlight that they did
survive
and the ones in green are the ones that
made it into the the second round
[Music]
so some of those names hopefully look uh
familiar as we've been
studying them over the past while
as i said it was a very difficult
decision selecting the schemes to move
on into the third round
we we kept in mind our our evaluation
criteria
criteria in terms of security and
performance
as well as other issues as well
implementation characteristics
and so forth uh each round
teams were allowed to make changes so we
looked at what those changes were and
were they improving the submission
as well as again the discussion on the
pqc forum
and the research and performance numbers
that were published
and for the third round we decided to do
something different than we've done in
the past
we just decided to use two different
tracks
of of algorithms moving on
um and that was a
not an easy decision even just doing
that there there's tradeoffs to doing it
this way
but ultimately we needed to narrow down
the number
so that we could focus on the most
promising algorithms
but we also felt that there were a
number of algorithms that still could
potentially
be standardized pqc
is still a very much an active research
area the science is not yet settled and
we don't want to to rule anything out
yet
so we thought this was the best way to
kind of balance those interests
the first track we called finalists we
thought that
they were the algorithms that would be
most likely to be ready at the end of
the third round for standardization
and that they would be the most
promising ones to fit the majority of
the use cases
the algorithms that were not finalists
we called alternates
and the crucial point for us there was
we didn't want to keep an algorithm
around just because we thought it was
interesting
and we thought people should keep
researching it we only wanted to keep it
around if we saw a potential
avenue for standardization that wasn't a
promise that it would be standardized
but just
um we saw a path where where
it could be
so for the third round the seven
finalists and eight alternates that
we're
still have in there the chem finalists
are kyber and true and saber
in classic mcleese the signature
finalists are dilithium falcon and
rainbow
the chem alternets are bike frodo hqc
entry prime and spike
and the signature alternates are gems
picnic and sphinx plus
and again we we tried to maintain the
diversity of the algorithms
as well as reducing the number down
but they were some some very difficult
decisions and we had to eliminate some
some good schemes
in order to narrow things down
just to kind of give a quick summary on
these schemes these are the five
lattice-based chems that are still
around in the third round
the finalists kyber saber and entro are
all based on structured lattices
as such they have pretty good all-around
performance
key sizes aren't too large they're
pretty efficient
entrus a little different than kyber and
saber and that it's a little bit older
has a clear ip situation is
based on a different security problem so
we do have some diversity among
these three but uh as they're all
structured lattice ones we expect to
choose at most one of those three
at the end of round three for
standardization um
we also had as alternates we had intro
prime it is a structured lattice scheme
that made kind of different design
choices
and it is interesting um but we did not
put it as a finalist
and then frodo chose uh some security
performance trade-offs that
perhaps is uh more conservative but it
took a little bit of a hit in
performance
so we see it as a more conservative
solution or is a backup
which is available to us if we need
the other cams three of them are code
based
classic mclease which we selected as a
finalist it's been around a long time
has very large public keys but the
ciphertext are the smallest out of all
cams
so for some applications you know you
might be able to manage the
the keys and take advantage of the small
ciphertexts
um we really like bike and hqc but we've
we thought they needed a little bit more
time to iron out some of their
the details that they're still working
on so they're they're two good
code-based uh
schemes that will likely uh continue to
be worked on and improved
and then there's also psych we heard uh
about it
during luca's talk um it's based on
isogeny's which is a newer problem
it's a little bit slower in performance
but it has the advantage of having small
keys so you know for some applications
that that could be a win
and we have it there is an alternate to
continue being looked at
for our signatures we have six
signatures still in
dilithium and falcon are both uh
lattice based based on structured
lattices so similar to the chem
situation
their key sizes look pretty good they're
both pretty efficient
and we will select at most one of them
to be uh standardized at the end of the
third round
uh we also have sphinx plus and picnic
they're based on kind of different ideas
sphynx plus
is based on uh hash based signatures
it's a very stable conservative design
we understand the security well
it's a bit larger and slower than some
of its competitors
so for that reason it was chosen as an
alternate
a picnic has a lot of potential but
there's still a lot of work that needs
to be done on it so we selected it as an
alternate
and then we had two multivariate schemes
rainbow and gems
based on different problems in
multivariate but they have a similar
profile and they have very large public
keys
and very small signatures in comparing
the two we thought rainbow was a little
bit better
and that it's small signatures
for some applications that could be
useful and in order to have some
diversity and not depend entirely on
lattices we selected rainbow
as a finalist
now even in round three cryptanalysis is
continuing uh particularly for uh the
two multivariate signature schemes
rainbow and gems
uh they both have had some attacks from
some new min ring style attacks
due to uh buoyance and tau petzl and
ding
this all came after our end of the
second round decision making
but we're very much aware of what's
going on now
a rainbow seems to lose a little bit
less security than jams
and just last week the rainbow team
responded with the new security analysis
where they go into some more details
about memory costs
and explain that they still feel that
they are still at their same security
levels despite the
the attack which which they did confirm
is correct
so that needs to be looked at and
evaluated um
but when we look at the the state of the
signature schemes
we have six signature schemes and uh two
of them multivariate have had some
attacks
that gives us some concern at nest and
probably to the crypto community as well
you know we don't want to have all our
eggs in just one basket
so we want diversity for security
problems as well as for for application
reasons as well and we wanted to
highlight
two quotes from our second round report
we're thinking a lot about this
situation internally and we hope other
people as well
the first paragraph points out that
sphinx is an extremely conservative
choice
and um if confidence in better
performing signature algorithms is
shaken you know sphinx potentially could
be ready at the end of the third round
as well even though
it's an alternate so that's
that's not saying we're necessarily
going to do that we just wanted to point
out that
um that is a possibility and the second
paragraph where we
talked about um we may adopt in the
future a mechanism to accept new
proposals at a later date
in particular we might be interested in
general purpose digital signatures which
are not based on structured lattices
and again we're not promising or
committing that we will
be accepting more uh more signature
schemes
but this is something we're thinking
about and we would appreciate getting
input from the cryptographic community
on the state of the signature schemes
like i've talked about here
so our timeline we've been going for uh
almost six months
in the third round and it's expected
that it'll last a year to 18 months
after which we'll select some of the
algorithms to standardize
we do expect to have a fourth round
where we will continue to study some of
the alternates
and maybe after the fourth round they
will be ready for standardization
it would similarly be like the first
three rounds it would be a 12 to 18
months
we are working on a workshop planning
the logistics of it right now it'll be
virtual and
it's looking like it will be late may or
early june
and we hope pretty soon to have concrete
dates for you
overall our timeline we still expect to
be what we've been saying from the
beginning
we expect to have the first draft
standards ready for public comments
in 2022 to 2023 it does take a little
bit of time to write them
and to get public feedback on it and to
get it through the bureaucratic process
which we need to go through
but we we expect that the final standard
should hopefully be
or not the final the finalized standard
would be ready by about 2024.
so there's there are plenty of research
challenges still open
um i'm not going to go through these in
detail or anything
there's there's more general topics as
well as
questions specific for for certain of
the round three
algorithms um i'll uh
let people just work on those as they
will without going into detail right now
as well there's other challenges besides
research
ip's a concern we share the the feeling
which most of the
community does as well that we want
anything we standardize to be able to be
freely used so we're actively working on
that
we want benchmarking to continue both in
hardware and software
we want people working on side channel
resistant implementations
of the algorithms and we like the real
world experiments that we've seen so far
so that we
can see if they work our key size is too
large are they too slow
things like that we also want to
continue to encourage as people are
already doing to think about the
transition and what they can do to
prepare ahead of time
one idea that is frequently mentioned is
using hybrid solutions and that's the
idea of
combining a classical algorithm with a
post quantum algorithm
in such a way that you have to break
both of them
in order to break the hybrid a few
months back we
allowed this in one of our standards
basically you can concatenate the shared
secret that you obtain
from a nist algorithm and
a quantum resistant algorithm and then
you run it through a kdf
and we explain how to do that in such a
way and and then the result can still be
fixed validated
um it's only validating the classical
part because that's the only thing
currently standardized but nonetheless
uh
you know it would allow input from a
quantum resistant algorithm as well
and of course we'll have more to say
about the transition
in in future years is as we start
selecting algorithms
and we've published transition
guidelines in the past you know we've
done this with triple q des for sha-1
and so forth and we will of course do so
for post-quantum standards in the next
few years i want to point out
the national cyber security of
excellence
recently hosted a workshop in october
about some of these issues regarding the
transition and hybrid and what we can be
doing to better prepare
and they're still actively working on
this project so if you're interested
um they're leading that we're working
with them as well
but i'd invite you to get involved with
that project as well
stateful hash based signatures were
outside of the scope of our competition
they have been standardized in the ietf
with two rfcs which standardized xmss
and lms signatures
this recently also standardized the same
two algorithms
in sp 800 208 so there are
stateful hash based signatures that are
standardized and can be used
we want to caution they are not general
purpose
digital signature algorithms and should
only be used in applications where you
can carefully manage the state
otherwise you can have some pretty
disastrous results
so in the standard we point out some
warnings on that but
they are available there are some things
that organizations can start to do now
to prepare even though we have not yet
selected the algorithms
primarily you want to just start looking
at what crypto
you know you're actually using which
which algorithms are your public key
ones
can you start doing things to prepare
for a transition knowing that it's going
to occur
make sure the products you're using the
you know that your vendors are aware
of the coming transition and just be
tracking what's going on with our
project as well as
in other areas with other standards
organizations as well as
developments of quantum computers to
know how they're advancing and so on
with the main goal being that the sooner
you're aware and start
doing your homework and preparing you
know you're less likely to have mistakes
in the future
so with that i'll uh conclude we're not
at the end of this but we can start to
see some of the light at the end of the
tunnel
it's going to be a long tunnel but the
third round is you know not too far off
from ending
nist is grateful for the efforts of
everybody we certainly could not do this
on our own
and we appreciate all the the hard work
and research that everybody does
that includes other standards
organizations who are working on this
and collaborating and cooperating with
us so that we have a great unified
effort
and i've got the info there for uh you
know where to get more information
and i'd recommend you sign up for the
pqc form if you haven't to stay aware of
announcements and discussion on that
topic
with that i'd be happy to take any
questions in the time remaining
all right thank you so much dustin for a
fascinating talk uh there are indeed
a bunch of questions uh in the chat and
we have a whooping three minutes
uh so in light of this i will prioritize
those questions
for just a moment i wanted to launch
this poll that dustin had put up
while you take the questions let's try
to take that
poll that dustin had put up at the
beginning go ahead with the questions
okay
cool uh so i will i will prioritize the
questions that
uh daniel hasn't already uh uh engaged
with on zulu
kenny asks to what extent will this use
secondary security criteria such as pke
robustness
to decide between the finalists
um we try and consider everything when
we
weigh these factors so uh it's hard to
put a
you know concrete way as to how we weigh
everything but yeah all these other
secondary issues
we're aware of them it's good if people
talk to us and remind us of them but we
do try and weigh
everything yes
then cass is asking uh so
is you're requiring existential
unforgeability
well we've known for years that we can
do better stronger watchability
exclusive ownership and so on
we know how this requirement came about
historically was an explicit choice to
require only a weekly
graphic definition or just an accident
um remembering back we made this
requirement
back in 2016 so it was five years ago
and we debated
which security models to use and then we
put that out for public comment and we
tried to uh
respond to the public comments we
received i don't remember a lot of the
exact discussion
but of course teams have been able to
update their security proofs and provide
the best
security proofs and models that they can
you know those were kind of the minimum
definitions that we required in order to
be accepted
all right let me do one more question uh
by fray but let me remind everyone
there's more questions uh in the chat
uh so does this provide a service to the
community
uh the advice of real patent lawyers to
evaluate the potential problems ip
issues for lattice paid schemes
um all vip stuff i'm not a lawyer but
we're working kind of behind the scenes
to get some of these concerns
um that we're aware of taken care of and
we're confident that by the end of the
third round
anything we select we will have cleared
up
by that time
all right um so i think at this point uh
we should uh
thank uh dustin again for a great talk
and everybody please head to the chat to
see kind of the other questions that i
unfortunately had to skip over
and i believe we are moving directly
into
uh the post quantum session so
the first talk of which so we have three
talks they're all
focused on implementation in the broader
sense
um of course quantum cryptography
exciting talks first talk is jointly
given by daniel and james on the tax on
the nist
around three candidates
okay great thank you um james are you
here just checking in
yep yep great all right um
i'm gonna get started then thank you
martin um this is a talk
uh attacks on nist pqc third round
candidates
um i am daniel apon at nist on the pqc
team
um i'm the loudest guy i guess on the
um this is a joint talk with my
colleague james howe at pq shield
um so just as an introduction here
you know first of all of course why do
we care about attacks on pqc
um so this is a talk primarily and in
fact entirely about
side channel attacks against nist post
quantum crypto
uh candidates um so you know we at nist
have
stated many times before you know going
back to the initial call for proposals
in 2016.
and as recently as the uh second-round
report nisteir 8309
um that we're looking for more
information more research more
data on side channel attacks um so you
know
just just a quote here um we're looking
for more performance data on
implementations that protect against
side channel attacks such as timing tax
power monitoring attacks fault tax this
type of thing
and i should point out just for context
on this talk
why are we giving a talk about side
channel attacks before there have been
you know large scale implementations of
post quantum crypto primarily we want to
highlight this issue
and point out for future implementers uh
kind of the category
of different issues they're going to be
you know coming up when you're thinking
about
you know deploying this for your
business um so with that
uh we'll talk about a survey on
uh attacks on mrs speaker c third on
candidates
yeah so this part of the talk is is sort
of the main contribution really
before we do that we just want to give a
brief prelude
firstly a quick overview of the attack
types we consider
these include classical cryptanalysis
and fault attacks
and then the typical side channel
attacks that vary from
timing analysis simple differential and
correlation power analysis
an electromagnetic template and called
boot attacks
we also provide any counter measures we
found these can vary from masking
techniques to hiding techniques
for brevity we won't state the details
of these but you can look at our slides
or pause the video offline for this
um and also a quick disclaimer
we tried to be as unbiased and neutral
as possible here
and we only show attacks that target a
specific candidate so that would be
a key encapsulation mechanism or a
signature scheme
so this means attacks on a public key
encryption or a key exchange version
is out of scope and we don't speculate
about whether
an historical attack or a potential
attack supply either
we try to focus less on implementation
foot guns as well
trying to show more on novel
vulnerabilities
um so we assume um as we can tr we
try to assume that uh secure code
practices have been used
so we don't really consider key reuse
attacks or memory use attacks or
anything like that
so without further ado here is our main
contribution
we did a complete and comprehensive
survey of the current state of the art
on this pqc third round candidates
summarized here on the table
you can see the attacks um we mentioned
earlier in the columns
the rows make up the third round
candidates a check
mark in the row will refer to the
corresponding attack
and then ordered references are provided
in the final column of the table
any gaps we have any gaps we have here
we we
we haven't found an attack on a
candidate
in general most if not all of these
attacks are academic
mainly because we've yet to see
real-world deployments of these schemes
some vulnerabilities may have been fixed
but we keep the attacks
in the table for completeness and and so
that known weaknesses are remembered and
mistakes are not made again
most if not all of these attacks are
also single targets and we've yet to
really see the impact of multi-target
attacks
this is something you might see in for
example staple hash based signatures
lattices make up more than 50 of these
attacks
this is unsurprising since it's been the
case since the beginning of the project
for everything from software to hardware
implementations
although power analysis is the most
common attack there remains a lot of
gaps here
this could be due to some schemes being
infeasible to run on the typical
embedded devices used to evaluate these
side channel attacks
one of one example of this is classic
michaelis
also some schemes such as cycle sphinx
plus may also suffer from being
significantly slower or larger
in comparison to others which makes side
channel analysis significantly more
difficult
lattice based schemes generally don't
suffer in this regard
even though even the largest and slowest
of these um freddie kemp
actually has the the most attack focus
of all
and as is generally the case counter
measures are lacking
for chems saber is really the only
candidate that has shown a
full masking scheme although this was
first order masking
um and would not be enough to protect
against more advanced
uh power analysis it will be interesting
to see how this masking scheme scales
for higher orders
and for signatures the same is true for
dilithium
being the only mask candidates and this
mastery scheme covers higher order
masking levels
um so yeah now we go on to some recent
highlights all right so i'm going to
discuss
just a couple uh recent attack issues
and some analysis
just from the past few months um so the
first thing that i want to highlight
here is this
work lwb site information from crypto
20. um there was a
talk actually by uh ludicas on this i
think at the simons institute
it says when a side channel attack fails
what can you still do with it right
um so the point is that for a large
number of the especially the finalists
in this third round
we're looking at lattice schemes the
canonical attack here is a lattice
reduction attack
um this work proposes a new tool
with uh some kind of like script you can
run to estimate things
uh to integrate hints from side channels
to use
in the lattice reduction algorithm so
for example maybe you learn some partial
information
you know as on the slide here um about
some coordinate of the secret key
um they consider four types of uh of
hints perfect tense modular hints
approximate and short vector hints
um and the idea here uh really want to
you know have people look at this is
that these hints can reduce the bkc
block size
for your lattice reduction algorithm
making the attacks easier um
in terms of impacts in the future that
this work may have
um i want to highlight this can affect
certifications of cryptographic modules
um especially for certificate processes
such as common criteria
perhaps even fips related you know
material um some certifiers at least
historically for symmetrical crypto
require that you know some
number of remaining key candidates exist
to the 80 to 100
after a side channel attack is performed
and if you can't
show that as the case for all known side
channel attacks
you can't be certified so this work will
provide you with some mechanism
at least uh you know a framework for
a lattice you know kim or even a
signature scheme
for analyzing that kind of information
you can set your cryptographic
parameters
with those side channels in mind and
that's something we're thinking about at
nist
a separate issue is the difference
between
ntt based multiplication and
non-entity-based multiplication
in particular the cost of masking such
multiplication operations are for
polynomials
for lattice kim's here's the example the
one thing i really want to highlight if
you take nothing else from this talk
right
is that we want to highlight that the
the uh the
individual pairing choice between qyburn
sabre okay this is not like a
broad scale thing but just between kyber
and sabre they're so similar
that it may come down all else equal to
side channel attacks and masking
efficiency
and security um so in particular
you know there is a masked version of
saber at first order there's
not yet a masked version of kyber
and also i'm going to point out as well
that there was this recent nice work
that showed that sabre and intro
which do not use ntts can actually been
benefit from kind of embedding the uh
their algebra in a higher order ring and
then
they can perform an entity operation
this actually gives a performance speed
up
in the reference implementation however
you then have to specifically consider
at least you know i would suggest uh the
cost
of side channels um this is also the
case for signatures i won't talk too
much about this just for time's sake
i'll just move on and say specifically
that for falcon
masking floating point arithmetic is a
major open problem
um and finally in terms of recent
highlights uh just considering active
side channels there's this work
quantum hammer uh against luvio at ccs
2020 this didn't have
a major impact on our process because
there was uh kind of a concurrent
computational attack against celluv but
you might ask
whether uh such active side chill
attacks are more broadly applicable
against the nist pkc third round
finalists um and i will point out
there's an upcoming work uh
joint team with uh nist pkc members
along with the university of arkansas
that is going to attempt to do this
against lwe chems
um and finally we're just going to
conclude with some takeaways for the
future
yeah i think one thing we can say for
certain um in the future is that
implementation complexity of these
standards will significantly increase
compared to rsa and elliptic curves this
will in turn make simple
implementation bugs more likely near the
beginning of the project
nist asks for the focus of
implementations to be about to be around
the arm cortex and
for microcontroller and the xilinx
artix7fpga
just to make comparisons uh easier
however for side channels
all these attacks or counter measures
we've seen and these devices be as
effective on other platforms
will there be more attack vectors and
will we need more countermeasures this
is
an open question this complexity is also
highlighted
heightened by um the increase in these
fragile or sensitive operations that
have led
to a large proportion of these attacks
post quantum also makes it more apparent
how even simple
isochronous or constant random time
complexity increases
this is um this can be seen in a recent
timing attack on random oracles
um in photochem but of course some of
these attacks will only be relevant if
they fall into your use case
so be cautious of this tailor the real
the relevance
of these attacks for your use case and
obviously use secure coding practices
and to conclude our main objective was
to really motivate more attacks and
analysis of these candidates
this decision may be decided by attacks
or the performances of countermeasures
if your business is considering
transitioning to post-quantum it's
definitely prudent to start this process
now considering the difficulties it
brings the complexities of
the and the new attack vectors they may
include
uh thank you for listening we're happy
to take
any questions now and offline via email
right so there are a few questions uh on
the chat
so um the first one
is by daniel bernstein asking
i think it's more of a complaint or
critique of like equating attacks on
implementations with attacks on schemes
because it assumes that the reference
implementations were meant to be side
channels secure
i'm trying to find the the question of
the chat uh
james you can answer it while i look for
it if you want
uh yeah i'm trying to find this isn't
the post quantum crypto chat or indeed
yeah so let me read it out verbatim in
all seriousness i'm bothered by the way
the overview slide a moment ago it
created attacks against software x with
against against
primitive y of course follow chem could
be implemented better
right yeah
yeah right um go ahead okay
yeah i think that's a fair point um
they've obviously not been designed to
withstand certain attacks but
also a lot of these attacks we've found
are quite um
novel and sort of um they weren't
expected such as the
the timing attack on the on the random
oracle i think not many people are
expecting that so i think
it's yeah it's also like it's an easy
target but also
um i think some new vulnerabilities can
easily be found
then let me just do one more question
before we move on
uh so dmitry asks whether fault attacks
uh
the existence of a fault attack signals
anything uh
since he expects while attacks are so
powerful or they apply to almost
anything
right let me let me actually answer this
one here uh just to kind of wrap up
um so in terms of side channel attacks
um this has been kind of an issue that's
come up here and there and we've
highlighted it before it missed
um now if there's a category of attack
that is only
you know defensible in some completely
generic manner like you know
make sure your implementation's correct
you know add noise to your hardware
you know vary your clock speed that kind
of thing well that's that's really
outside the preview of nist however
it could still be the case that there
are
categories of side channel attacks that
exploit a particular property of the
algorithm
such that implementations of algorithm
x1
and implementations of algorithm x2 um
you you end up in a situation where uh
the implementation is
is it's more convenient to have side
channel resistant friendly
implementations
of the first rather than the latter
that's the most interesting thing i mean
of course research is going to continue
inside chill attacks and defenses
for you know days and years and decades
um
but that's particularly probably the
most important stuff
so that's what we wanted to highlight i
think from this is that if there is a
particular type of attack
that distinguishes between candidates
that are very similar
um that would be useful during this next
year uh
to provide you know that information
that research knowledge to nist
that could factor into our decisions all
right
so um at this point uh let's uh thank uh
daniel and james using virtual applause
of your choosing
and let's move on to the next talk and i
actually don't know who's giving the
next talk of the
authors me here hannah felix that would
be me hannah
hi hi hannah okay so hannah is going to
talk to us
about how to instantiate your random
oracles
securely or at least how to not do it
insecurely so thank you
all right
hi my name is hannah davis and i'm here
today to talk about my joint work with
me here bellari and felix gunther
on separating your domains miss pqc
chems and pitfalls in implementing
random oracles
in the face of growing fears about the
advent of quantum computing
nist in 2017 put forward a call for post
quantum
secure key encapsulation mechanisms or
chems
um a pem is a cryptographic protocol
used to establish a secret session key
between two parties
and this key will be used uh for with
some symmetric key crypto like aes
so it should be completely hidden
one or more of these chems will be the
basis of the next public key
encryption standards they've been the
subject of a lot of attention
and analysis by the cryptographic
community as we just heard
the process is now in round three but
even the round one candidates were
heavily studied for over a year
in our own study on one of on the nist
pqc chems
we noticed something strange about
a reference implementation of dags
we were looking at the ciphertext and
session key
and we noticed that they looked
surprisingly similar
as you can see with the highlighted bits
there's a lot of repeated information
and indeed this chem is actually leaking
over half of its session
key directly through the ciphertext
worse than that this wasn't just one
fluke in one
cam uh we found two other
chems that had vulnerabilities that were
extremely similar to this
and all of them were based on the same
problem with implementing
hash functions um the fact that
none of these are round three cams
they're all round one cams and none of
them made it to round two without being
updated
but uh none of these attacks were caught
during the entire year-long round one
scrutinization process
and we think that reflects a systematic
oversight
in the way that we're studying these
chems um we're not looking at the way
that they implement hash functions
and that's letting these attacks slip by
um so the reason that these attacks are
arising
is that many of the nist chems call for
multiple hash functions say
h1 h2 and h3 in practice it's
much easier for developers to use just
one hash function
everywhere this seems like it should be
fine
but it's actually a very common and
serious mistake
the security proofs for almost all of
the nist cams
assume that h1 h2 and h3 are distinct
hash functions
with outputs that are both random
looking and independent of one another
these assumptions are normal and we can
satisfy the random looking requirement
easily by using a cryptographic hash
function like sha-3
but when we use sha-3 one hash function
to implement
um three hash functions like h1 h2 and
h3 this clearly isn't independent
um the outputs are correlated and this
is what causes
attacks like the one on dx um in dags
the ciphertext and the session key were
supposed to be the outputs of two
distinct hash functions
whose outputs would be independent and
uncorrelated
instead the implementation used the same
hash function
in both places so the outputs were
highly related and information was
leaked
this surfaces a problem that we call
oracle cloning
we'd still like to use one hash function
everywhere
but since we can't substitute a hash
function directly
we need some more careful way to build
multiple hash functions that truly are
or at least
look independent
an immediate reaction to oracle cloning
is well we already know how to do that
um and indeed there are methods that
work well the most
well-known one is domain separation
where we assign
each hash function that we want to build
a unique label and then we use that
label
to prefix all of the inputs to the hash
function
this is simple it's efficient and it's
effective
but even though we theoretically know
how to do oracle cloning
in practice we still frequently
encounter both schemes that don't use
domain separation
and as we saw attacks that are arising
from poor oracle cloning choices
furthermore these attacks aren't being
caught during the evaluation process
because they violate this assumption in
our security model
that our hash functions are independent
of one another
all this says to us is that there needs
to be a bit more attention
paid to oracle cloning at this point we
have a number of questions about oracle
cloning
we know domain separation works but we
don't know what other methods are being
used in practice or how well those
methods work
we don't even have a rigorous definition
of what it means for an
oracle cloning method to work we'd like
to provide a toolbox of good methods
that we can be confident in
for use in any scheme and we'd like to
prove that schemes
using good methods are secure even after
the oracle cloning step takes place
this would extend our evaluation process
to cover oracle cloning and stop these
attacks from being missed
our work attempts to achieve this goal
in two steps
the first step is a catalog of the nist
cams
where we looked through both their
specifications and their
reference implementations and we
classified them into three groups
the schemes that we attacked the schemes
that use good
secure oracle cloning methods and an
in-between group that we call brittle
schemes
from this classification we extracted a
list of oracle cloning methods
that appear in practice in the second
part
of our paper we developed a theory of
what a secure oracle cloning method
should be
and we use this definition to validate
the oracle cloning methods in our list
by doing this we can prove security for
all of the nist pqc chems
except the ones that we attacked all of
the ones in the latter two groups
and we can build up a library of proven
safe oracle cloning methods that will
work for any scheme not just
chems any crypto protocol it may need to
use multiple hash functions
where we would like to use only one
we'll start by going through our
classification
the first group are those we attacked
bags big quake
and round two um i want to reiterate
once more
these aren't round three schemes they
were eliminated after round one or
updated after round one so none of them
are candidates for standardization
but all of the attacks that weren't
picked up during the process
are extremely fast the latter two
achieve full key recovery
and they go much further than breaking
the stated goal of
quantum indcca security
and furthermore all of these attacks are
easy to fix just by using a good oracle
cloning method
and that's what we want to provide
our second group of schemes are those
that use good oracle cloning
methods in their reference
implementations and we can prove their
security
we call them brittle though because
their specifications give ambiguous or
flawed oracle cloning methods
whichever algorithm becomes standardized
will likely be implemented
many times in various cryptographic
libraries sometimes by developers with
very little cryptographic experience
when the specification is unclear on
oracle cloning
we fear that such future implementations
may perform oracle cloning incorrectly
to improve clarity and prevent bugs in
future implementations
we recommend that these schemes update
their specifications to reflect their
own reference implementations
oracle cloning methods our last group of
schemes
are those that did well with regard to
oracle cloning i highlight the need for
good oracle cloning and discuss
in their specifications how developers
can accomplish it
from these submissions we identify three
good oracle cloning techniques and those
will
form our toolbox the first method in our
catalog
is output splitting output splitting
works by partitioning the output
of a hash function h into shorter
segments then each segment becomes the
output of one of the constructed hash
functions
to use this method the constructed hash
functions must have fixed output
in our example 32 bytes
we've already discussed the second
method in our toolbox prefixing
or classical domain separation this
works well in almost all situations
we highly recommend it the final method
is the identity method or just using the
same hash function
in all places it may seem odd to include
this in our toolbox
since this is the exact method we argued
earlier was insecure
we present it here because identity can
be used safely
if the constructed hash functions will
never
be called on the same input the most
common way to
ensure this is by restricting the
lengths of inputs to each of the
constructed hash functions
this is one to be careful with and it's
not one we recommend but it is used
appropriately by some of the nist chems
when we say these are good oracle
cloning methods what we really mean is
that they're read
only indifferentiable this is a security
definition that captures the ability of
the oracle cloning method to maintain
the security of a scheme
if an oracle cloning method is read only
indifferentiable
then the construction the constructed
hash functions can be used
anywhere that truly independent
hash functions could be used we use our
own definition
rather than the classical definition of
indifferentiability
in order to provide in order to apply
to a wider range of applications
including multi-stage games
i know one minute so
last slide the takeaway here is that the
main separation
is easy to get right it can be
catastrophic to get wrong
um but it's easy to fix
uh all we have to do is use a good
oracle cloning method
uh from our toolbox make it part of your
specification
if you don't see an oracle cloning
method use one from the toolbox that is
appropriate for your hash function usage
um we've already seen one scheme do this
the round two
chem new hope which you previously used
and not
a oracle cloning method that was not
read only and differentiable
um after we pointed out that we our
framework was not able to prove security
for a new hope after the oracle cloning
step
they changed to use classical domain
separation or prefixing
and we were now able to prove security
of their scheme without any additional
analysis necessary
thank you i'm happy to take questions
now or over email
right uh so thank you very much hannah
uh fascinating talk so first there was
some confusion on the chat about the
term oracle cloning on whether it's a
defense mechanism or an attack but i
think that has been cleared up
um can you say something about
uh how amenable you're kind of like
so if i want to do static analysis of
say a code base and see if i have this
problem in there like how easy would it
be to find it do i just need to grab for
all the calls to sha too
or like what's my approach to find out
um
if my code base on a higher level than a
primitive has the same problem
that's a really interesting question um
certainly searching for all of the
places where a hash function is used
um would help but
it isn't the problem
arises when a hash function is used in
two places
where the specification or the security
proof
expects to different hash functions to
be used
um so for example um
if you have as in dags three you have
a portion of the ciphertext that is the
output of say hash function h1
and the session key is the output of
hash function h2
you don't want h1 and h2 to be the same
function
or to be related in any way i don't
think that static analysis would
necessarily be able to catch
it would catch the first case where
they're the same function
but there are more complicated versions
where the output is
related in some predictable way but not
necessarily
equal
so i would say keep different
names for your different hash functions
and make sure you're implementing them
with proper domain separation
and then static analysis isn't necessary
carolyn asks is there any good reason to
leave the oracle cloning
to the implementer instead of just
mandating a specific scheme
it's common practice to leave it up to
the implementer but i don't think
there's a good reason to do it
i think our our hope is that people will
start putting
oracle cloning methods into
specifications and just making them a
part of the scheme
okay great so uh for more questions uh
kind of um please kind of ask them on
zulip
because we are now moving on to the
final talk of the session
thank you hannah so the final talk will
be
uh given by gopher um on the embedded
challenge
for post quantum crypto thank you
hi guys can you hear me yes
awesome yeah so thanks a lot my name is
uh yoko boss
and it's my really my pleasure to talk
at real world crypto and i hope
we can actually do this uh in real life
soon again
so the last two talks were more about
attacks on post quantum crypto and with
this talk i would really like to
highlight yeah a different view and and
what kind of work we have done in this
area
namely related to a embedded perspective
of post quantum crypto
so maybe let me try to um kick off
um yeah we saw from the very interesting
talk uh by nist and the poll which was
run
uh yeah when do we believe if there will
be a quantum computer or not
i think yeah from our perspective it's
really not that interesting um
when or if you believe that a quantum
computer will become a reality
because the post content crypto
standards are simply coming and if your
customers are asking for this
um yeah then you have to you have to
comply
um so you need to prepare yourself to
actually migrate
towards these new public key crypto
standards
and and that is the big motivation here
so when i say embedded devices what do i
exactly mean
um so for us at nxp we mainly look at
these four pillars
um which you can see on the screen here
so first of all there's automotive
so modern cars have a
hundred or even up to a thousand
different chips in them
and some of these chips need to securely
communicate to each other
then you even have vehicle-to-vehicle
communication where cars need to
communicate
between themselves and of course you
want to do this in a secure manner
then there's industrial iot many
embedded devices live there and of
course
they need public key crypto as well
there are mobile applications
so i think electronic payment or transit
applications
which need to be secured and then of
course there's our communication
infrastructure
and with all these embedded devices they
already
struggle to actually implement in a
timely manner
our current public key algorithms like
ecc and rsa
and now they need to migrate away to
more expensive
in for some definition of expensive
publicly crypto
so yeah the big question is what is the
impact and is this even
feasible in practice
so yeah i wanted to highlight two use
cases but since this talk
because it's virtual uh was a bit
shortened i will only talk
mainly about one about the second use
case but the first use case
i wanted to highlight digital signatures
and where this is used
um so for instance in the industrial iot
and in automotive
the first thing you might or makes a lot
of sense
to make this post quantum secure are
your secure boot
and your over the air update because if
these two components
are post quantum secure you can use this
as a vehicle to actually
uh upgrade the the remaining part of
your of your product
to post content security
and we actually looked into this and we
uh
yeah advanced on a time memory trade-off
technique which allowed on better
devices to actually make the signature
verification
which you need to compute on the
embedded device significantly faster
while still being compliant with these
stateful hashtag signature schemes
and what i want to highlight a bit more
is related to key exchange so
think again use cases related to
industrial and iot
in these end or edge devices you have a
secure element which might need to
communicate
with your regular core so your
unprotected core or
different iot devices need to talk to
each other and for this you need to uh
perform a key exchange and the big
question here is is this even possible
in practice and what exactly uh
yeah is the impact
so if we look at the yeah the nist
finalist i think they've been mentioned
in the last couple talks as well
for key exchange and you look at the
academic literature
about implementations on what's often
called an embedded platform of cortex m4
uploaded some numbers here in blue so
for saber and true and kyber
um and then in red i uh plotted the
numbers for an elliptic curve for
popular elliptic curve crypto scheme so
x 255
19 and you can see here that the
performance numbers
so there are two things to notice here
so first of all
the the fourth uh finalist classic
mcaleese
is not plotted here simply because yeah
i couldn't find any performance numbers
on the cortex and four
this is probably something to do with
that their public key
is massive as was already mentioned by
the talk by nist so it
for the larger parameter sets it's over
a megabyte which will simply not fit on
the device
um and the second thing to mention is
that from the remaining three letters
based
schemes you see here in blue the
performance is actually not that bad so
they're really in the same ballpark
as elliptic curve crypto which is kind
of good news
on the other hand it should really be
highlighted that
a cortex m4 although it's often
considered an embedded device
yeah for many of the applications which
i showed
in these four pillars a couple slides
back is really
considered high end and therefore the
main problem is not really related
per se with the performance but it's
really with the
with the memory or the stack consumption
so here you can see
so these same implementations which were
were
really fast i mean that's why they
advanced to the final
and again but now for not in performance
but for their memory and we see for
elliptic curve crypto
this is really convenient and that is
why elliptic curve cryptography is so
popular in embedded devices
if we look at these other
implementations they're much much bigger
so for instance you can see
one of these goes over 20 kilobytes of
stack
and here i also want to highlight this
is even without considering the storage
of the cryptographic keys which are also
much much bigger
than our current public key crypto
and of course there are many ways that
you can try to remedy this
you can make implementations which look
use much less
stack but then of course this comes at a
cost of performance
so in practice for these embedded
devices what are we considering so
often of course depending on your
product uh on your product line and your
use case
think about one two four kilobytes of
stack
and that includes the storage of your
keys uh
maybe eight if you're lucky but 20 and
is definitely a real stretch and uh will
be a massive problem
so now if we would find some sort of
trade-off that you can trade some of
your
uh consumed memory for performance we
again have the problem with how can we
get
faster uh in this in this case let's
base crypto
so of course this is a well-studied
problem for our
public key crypto deployed nowadays and
that's why lots of these embedded
devices have co-processors
and they compute the core of the public
key crypto as we know it
so for rsa and ecc this all boils down
to modular multiplications
so for rsa the modulus is a couple
thousand bit for
elliptic curve crypto this is a couple
hundred bit but for lettuce biscuit this
is completely different
so now we the core operation is
working with polynomials with integer
coefficients
where the coefficients are small they're
only 16 bits
so if we now want to use the power of
these arithmetic code processors how can
we proceed
so one idea of course and this has been
studied in 2019
is to use these large registers uh pack
multiple
of these 16 bit coefficients in there do
one
big large multiplications ensure that
the result doesn't overflow that
everything stays correct and then you
get a constant time speed up
by processing in a in a bit like a cmd
type fashion and if you do this
um actually when you think about it this
is just chronic or substitution so this
is
a way how you can convert polynomial
multiplication into integer
multiplication it's well known it's from
the 19th century
and with the team with nxp we had a
closer look at this
and we actually looked at it not from a
from a point of view that is any
polynomial multiplication but we
specifically looked at the rings
used in crypto so and the question was
can we do better
and the answer is yes so the idea here
is that
you would use the roots of unity in this
ring
and you build a symbolic numbered
theoretic transform similar
to bomber but different
and although this method is slower when
you would do it on polynomial
multiplication
if you combine it with this kronecker
substitution by converting it into
integers
you actually get a much faster method so
just to highlight
for kyber if you convert your polynomial
multiplication
in an integer multiplication it would
turn into one 8000 bit multiplication
and now assume you have an aromatic
co-processor which works on 128 bit
words you need roughly 4 000 calls to
your co-processor
now when you use this method
we proposed using the roots of unity and
the symbolic entity
it boils down to 16 512-bit
multiplications
which you can compute only with 256
calls to your co-processor so that's
already a very nice speed up in practice
so to conclude um yeah it doesn't really
matter if you think
quantum computers will be here soon or
not the post quantum crypto standards
which will replace
our pki infrastructure will come
and um yeah as industry we are already
preparing for this
um so we have this the short-term
standard as you saw stateful
has been signature schemes and then of
course the new standard
and then this standard will make it even
a bit more difficult because they will
select multiple winners
per category so it means lots of extra
work
and we didn't even talk about hardened
implementations but it's good
that daniel and james did this in two
talks
back that will be i think a major
challenge for these
embedded implementations where you need
to actually protect against these types
of attacks
and indeed there the table they showed
was very interesting
it showed what is done in academia but
of course it didn't show what can be
done per scheme so in that sense i think
any scheme can probably make secure in
this model the question is at what cost
so i think we have very interesting
times ahead um especially for the
yeah from this embedded perspective
thanks a lot and i will take any
questions
thanks for a great talk chris asks what
makes andrew sabre use so much stack
compared to kyber yeah that's a good
question so um this was not an
implementation
i i made so this was from the one of the
implementations submitted to pqm4
so you yeah you would want to ask um the
implementers of these schemes the big
question of course is
uh is this inherent to the scheme or was
this more memory used to achieve this
this high performance and and to me
that's not clear
and then uh thomas is pointing out that
uh
upon the x 2 5 5 19
uh listed as 0.9 cycles on the cortex m4
it can be done in 0.55
but this makes your point uh and it
doesn't change your point
and then james points out that classic
megalis was
indeed implementing the cortex and iv
uh i don't see any more questions at the
moment
so people want to jump in real quick in
the last minute that we have here
okay i don't see um
oh let me ask one one of the problems
that we had when we're kind of doing
just chronic
substitution was that schemes mandated
the use of the ntt
do you see that this is a long-term
problem and would you kind of ask
schemes to be neutral to the
implementation like
you know that yeah we actually it's a
very good remark so we encountered
the same uh issue yeah like we also
remarked in our paper
so some schemes they sample from the
entity domain
um so the entity domain so
typically that's a shown a strata
approach used um
on these polynomials directly and of
course then if you would
use kronecker substitution you need to
first invert this
uh in order to proceed so computing in
a backwards transformation and that
indeed gives a yeah significant overhead
so
indeed so in some sense for the embedded
devices which want to use this approach
that is a very in the
unfortunate design decision um and it
might have been better to just
sample uh yeah not in the entity domain
and make the high-end implementations
uh slightly slower but help them better
devices a bit more that's definitely
true
yes okay so then kevin asked the
question
given their ppc is looking perhaps many
years in the future do you think
this should change the economics of
embedded systems to choose a higher
capability core to handle the future
this is also consistent with auto
companies who want to make their cars
have
subscription servers for future revenue
so i'm not sure if i completely got the
question but yeah you're absolutely
right so
of course one one direction you should
go into is design new hardware
specifically
for uh yeah the winner of the nist
competition the downside is we don't
know
uh who will win we don't even know or it
might be a letterbase scheme might make
might be codebed scheme and they need
completely different hardware
accelerators so
on the and designing the water takes
time um
so for now to ensure that we have a
seamless transition
and that actually the currently deployed
embedded devices can run
post quantum crypto i think it's
important to look into
the existing yeah hardware we have and
how that can be utilized
all right thanks this brings us to the
end of the session so thank you yopa and
all speakers of the session
at this point i'm handing over