yeah I might have Sam I'm a security
engineer they're gonna be and I've been
thinking for a long time just in the
back of my head if I were gonna write
some malware like what would I want to
do with it and what we might focus on so
I'm not a tip what security researcher
I'm I came up as an admin and now I'm
screwed engineer so we go to little
different focus a background with other
people here but I kind of thought that
the most interesting things that you
could do today with malware with it
thank you agree so like a little
basically rerun occupies like in the
beginning there was a root and there was
nothing more powerful than there is
anything they wanted to on the Mac and
that was just it for like the first 10
11 years of its time and into Mac OS but
apples kind of figured out that route
has been more powerful than it probably
should have been and a few years ago
that came out of system integrity
protection this is a few other features
like requiring code panic or texts but
really the implications for malware
aren't that much all set really does in
my mind is just like keeps you from
deleting chess and this might matter to
you if you're like a huge organization
that doesn't trust your employees that
never do you work because they're just
going to play chess all day but I don't
think they're Malik's it really matters
that much so in Mojave
Apple came out with CCC transfer consent
and control and this was really about
protecting these are data from
applications at Chinon access to its
sure and I think that which does have
real implications from out where but not
the kind of matter that I would want to
write so what is TCC there
it really protects files on the disk on
in directories so that applications
aren't authorized to be done can't read
them so in this case Peru you can't read
the Highnesses database other user
that's kind of unfortunate you can't
believe it anymore but whatever we'll
write our malware to do something so
what I've really just thought about is
is it rootless or route less like what
is what is the less really means and at
this point we're in group that can do
less so it really is so it so if you do
a lot of interesting things and like on
many systems it's just words for the
taking so let's talk about that look
like looking still do that's interesting
in a case of not work so they're gonna
fall launch demons to persist you know
it's pretty simple on I think
modifying instead trusted routes so that
we can intercept software you can block
communication or if they're in DM either
by removing the profile if it's not dep
or just on blocking it through the PF
firewall or just modifying a host live
you can still do that we can unload all
those security tools that are protect
you from malware so whether that's the
launch humans or unloading the text we
can't load any new pets that are
wait-listed
but you can unload them so that's nice
we can spell authorization plugins to
get the users password and then grab
their keychain upload them somewhere and
they don't like passwords I really don't
understand why authorization plugins are
still permitted maybe that will change
tomorrow Mike Lissy
we can enable file ball to like this is
great for if we wanted to write a
cricket locker and there's like so much
more
and it's not really hard from how are
you here on something else like you can
really just ask for it and most users
are probably just gonna give it to you
but what we didn't have to ask for it um
it's like we're out use every way that
can now be really great in the case of
malware because you know these pop-ups
they're a little sketchy and people
forget their passwords or maybe our
admin and you know probably some user if
you're in a large organization and you
target it that's kind of where someone's
going to notice that I would say
something but let's do without that my
green escalations
have been in Mac OS for a long time and
people still focus on them here's the
vulnerability earlier this year in
feedback assistant where it would calm
we would run as cables that were that
may have been writable by other users
and the simple reverse collation and
that's cool because it's it's building
sort of Mac unless and and like this is
what a man looks like at a box but I
don't know anybody's market actually
works like that most people's max trying
to look like this and they have like all
this stuff on them they've got
applications and applications and more
applications and it just goes on and on
and this third-party software is just
like bad
you probably shouldn't trust third-party
software with root because you don't
really know what they're gonna do with
it it's like you shouldn't you shouldn't
trust those rights off with that with
root without fully analyzing what it's
doing so
let's talk about some examples where
that's really fond of these might be so
here's an application on which I
discovered was vulnerable to you know
vulnerable to root escalations by having
functions being bad so this is an
application which you drag and drop your
Applications folder and as we know for
the last few releases of Mac OS users
have the ability to install it the
victims the Applications folder without
authors that you may have access to they
can do that we're gonna drag and drop it
and then no authorization dialogue is
ever gonna pop up so we do that they
follow instructions and they right click
it and click open because this is not
code signing because that's really hard
to do and you open it up and you get
this dialog and after you type the
password name and it installs and
launching so the launch team that
installs looks like this and it points
to an executable that's inside of that
inside an application bundle and it's
fine except on modern versions of Mac OS
that file is going to be writable by the
user so malware could just come along
and change that file and the next time
launch team initializes it's been run
that as root so pretty simple through
escalation these are the extremely
common in drag and drop on kind of
applications so if you ever drag and
drop an application or your Applications
folder and pops up over any
authorization dialogue and should
probably question what it's actually
doing but maybe we should talk about
something that's more common than this
non cosign application and that does
this
you know I hope that most people in this
room would kind of question you know the
salon coats like half that on but then
pops with an authorization like you know
that something is kind of sketchy
they've had a sketchy looking disk image
so something more common than that so
I'm gonna guess that most people here
whose phone number is a great tool if
you want to install
you know Python 3 or other programs that
don't comment and I'm sure the homebrew
sells a lot of maths to a lot of
developers but it couldn't really treat
on tree truth with the respect that it
so a lot of formulas in lumber is time
but your install require you to do
pseudo to start the service for the
program that its installed
so in this case the NS master needs to
bind a lower number port so it needs to
monitor a normally you don't run over on
the pseudo we do each it meets a elevate
during its installation but not really
even if you if you run through as we
it'll warn me like hey don't do this
but sometimes it needs to be better so
in this case we can solve the announced
mask and conserve the service and it's
running and that's great but if we look
here that um that DNS mask file is owned
by my user and not by reach now Humber
have attempted to solve for this problem
by making DNS mess not writable so if we
look at the Doudna
file we only have read and execute
permissions on it and not on right so
like that's an attempt and you can't
break through that file without changing
anything but we still own the directory
we can still change that file so
in this example I just wanted to use
that too I made a simple script and
simple gmail script that we just create
a file in blackberry which all new group
and thank you so we can't change the
file but we can repaint it and so I
renamed it and move my Eagle executable
into the same place this is all just
running it's my user and then the next
time you reboot harden goal script cool
one so on I reported this to hungry a
few weeks ago and it's been fixed since
then for homebrew services and now it's
now whenever you start their service
they it's through homebrew it's it's
owned by group and that's take you like
it set so long with users cannot change
or modify them but like what else is
vulnerable this kind of attack there's a
lot of things now I can't say what is
vulnerable to this first lock is I don't
know everything that's vulnerable this
there's so many things but also this is
the number what is this 9 9 to 8 popular
applications including Mac management
tools like enterprise communication
tools even some Mac security tools are
vulnerable to these types of attacks
because they don't they don't place the
right permissions long sure they're on
to the i-x peoples that they whether
through launch humans directly or
through processes like things that we
can't handle it but I'll ship so I can't
tell you everything that is one of those
it's the first I don't know but also a
lot of them have been fixed in I've
reported to a lot of vendors about this
some are taking months to fix it
others dispute that this is actually
problem and other things are only happen
when you have combinations of different
software so I just wanted to show demo
of what this looks like I put my demo so
I've got a VM what we're here this is
the hard part so I've gotta be in here
and I developed this cilium work that I
called root canal and I already
downloaded it here and you can see that
I have a motorized because I don't know
what no ization actually checks for but
I wasn't able to get it to reject
anything I wrote so here's here's a nice
little application I spent about five
minutes in interface builder you can
like blender up all these things
whatever those buttons you can play mmm
but when you click this button here you
end up with this like objective by the
seat root CA trusted in your system
teacher and like what actually happens
when I click that button
so it's scanning the filesystem for
launch demon name well loads on watch
demons in the memory to figure out what
they want
it's and all ex pupils that those run
and it will prioritize anything that has
a watch path that can be written to so
watch path so probably my favorite
feature to launch these is you can make
things one just right now on them so if
it finds one that has a watch path
I can touch it will touch that and run
immediately now if there are times there
aren't any of watch paths they will
still do you will still do this but you
have to wait for the service do you want
whether that's to reboot I'm probably
thankfully found one that you so much
path we've done this MOA faster because
we're eating angry and more fix right
but that's really it I did give it a
nice feature where you can click it
again it will remove the route but
there's and I don't know why and key can
access it we will live show it in there
but when it disappears you have to
relive the half of it so that's that's
like the example never get it right and
I can obviously have it be way more than
that but I didn't want to like check the
lock micromachine back
so that's the demo of this like it
really stands for everything that I
can't tell you what is installed in that
VM there's a lot of third-party software
installed on that we an they're very
easily at these way but really this is
like about your descriptions and you
know Apple remove this repair disk
permissions thing but you've got to
repair your dis permissions if you're
going to use a third-party software
applications have their creditors
connections and it's not just
drag-and-drop applications or like
homebrew services applications that
install through packages can be very
vulnerable to this kind of thing as well
whether that's because in the ROM they
specify things being owned by the center
everybody is in instead of real or they
have crazy person install scripts that
change everything that got installed in
the right way so what I would strongly
recommend is if you're gonna install
things from packages but have any post
install scripts install it on another
machine and then analyze what it
actually ended up that's because I've
seen installers that like hundreds of
post install script and you don't really
know particular but how can we tell what
it's actually horribleness and how did I
find it and how do I find out things for
me so I they're going to be leaves it to
focus query which is originated at
Facebook and it's a great way to look at
what's actually on your system and and
like okay
because it's equal interface you can
join against different tables and look
at different conditions of different
things so I like to write somewhat
complex sequel queries on that we use in
history and don't worry I'll share these
out later on but what this one does
so all the launch demons in your system
[Music]
although this one looks for requests is
there scrambled so this look this looks
like all the processes that are running
every and all the and the files that are
backing them and whether or not they're
actually owned by we or owned by we're
like can they be written by the elected
and the mining we owned by regional but
they might be writable by finally use it
so this helps us find vulnerable on
applications and executables and it's
not just the things that are directly
referenced by launch demons but it's
things that they may invoke now the one
of the hard things about demons is that
it's very hard to tell it's actually
executed so this is this is a example of
watching them from okay it's not
vulnerable to this type of attack look
could be if someone like schmatta these
are local for curses if you like seven
seconds seven that would obviously be
vulnerable but here we have user local
monkey supervisor look it's easy to tell
it that thing that stupid but later you
have a parameter of this manage software
update executable but it's like it's
just a string and you don't really know
like when you're looking at thousands of
our students like what's actually been
executed so that's why it's really
important to look at the actual
processes it's not exploited well this
is the same exact query I need that I
will share out the good directories but
the point here is that oh scream it's
really easy to find three sections or
abilities and when you look at the
launch demon ones and processes to you
on this is a sizable story so here's an
example of something that would get
returned from postcards from Carbon Copy
corner and we can see that this
ex-people is owned by my user and same
run by root I mean I attempted to
replace X cables here but it's not
actually vulnerable to this type of
attack because Carbon Copy corner
um verifies the pets cables that it's
going to execute as before action once
them so just because something gets
returned on some of these queries
doesn't mean that back you can level so
how do you minimize us your companies or
your direct exposure the same thing as
well as if your developers I'm obviously
evaluate as David thanks after your keep
usually local they might have you path
like it's really um it's really popular
to you know you sound brewing
I think Humber effectively on so it's
path these days but it's easy to swamp I
use anything um if you're developer and
you want your program to end up in in
users hats so they can easily limit use
this feature
Dracula's flexi fast lucky you can
create a file in this folder and it will
hand out and the contents of that bottle
end up in users paths without you having
could dump your executables maybe use
your local bin or somewhere else tools
like monkeying puppet use this and it
works out pretty well if you're if you
have management tools that that call out
on their excuse mother that's like that
you're using factor with puppet or you
use it like extension attributes in camp
or whatever you're doing useful paths to
executables the ones that ship on the
system instead of just saying for all or
we like user control on use the things
and apple chips that Apple gives you so
you're less susceptible to having
something on you and follow up with I
was Prairie on you can use classes
events even to know kind of works
following the tips but the real winning
move here is just assume that any non
sandbox process for the one
on a real on as much as you can do to
guard against this kind of thing without
doing crazy full static analysis of
everything that's been relying on the
computer it's it's harder than that is
something like we conditionally executed
or something like that so yeah there's
just seeing that and like what could
Apple and you to help us with this um
the things that we found most common
were directly volatile processes to
watch II so it would be great if watch
II wouldn't execute directly programs
that don't have safe permissions I don't
think this will change because it's been
the behavior forever but it would be or
go along way to change this if there was
a method that walk all mount say about
so down the Mac it would be great to
guard against a second malware even
after your installations were still
there but I think what's really gonna
happen is that routes abilities are
going to be reduced even more over time
on so that we even lost interest in
during the backers and with that does
anybody have any questions and I will
tweet out the queries to for the North
Korea that's the homework that I want
everyone to have is let go of all these
queries and see what's all about your
system because I'm betting that at least
half the vaccinations are vulnerable to
these types of attacks
questions I have a question um you could
be a good idea for an hour author or two
perhaps once they get on a system run
this query and then dynamically
basically find yes so that's just yes so
that's exactly what my sample does um
when I was first writing it I was like I
just had five quoted paths but yeah then
I was like well why don't I just seen
everything wasn't that all right I wrote
it in Swift there's my first Swift app
so it's super fast but if if you're
malware wants route and you can do this
then you should do it
well you shouldn't right now look like
one if you're going to and your malware
needs route like just to make it easier
for your users instead of asking them
talk about like if you can't find
anything vulnerable then it's still pop
it up like yeah
and we also surprised by the fact that
Kazak busy if we literally um yes like
so really all it does so the app it's as
simple so if that it has the program um
but actually does the militia so sure as
a string and then it just works without
the file system yeah and I mean I don't
know what the authorization does at this
point but I submitted it maybe Apple
will make it so that this one thing it's
rejected in the feature but hope that
leg yet yes I think like apps looking at
your file system like that's a little
big enough thing to do have some idea
things to the file system that's
legitimate
so it's hard it I think it would be hard
to vote that they contain numbers
automatically but it's certainly
something that I would expect should not
be notarized in the future