welcome to my talk called here mapping
out there's a new virtual memory so
compared to some other taunts today this
is going to be more like an operating
system internals with a bit of fun today
a few research and maybe some
exploitation at the end it says time but
most of the focus of this talk is going
to be as if a virtual memory internals
and xnu so hopefully if there's like me
from like a forensics background either
this is all very much old news or wait
the interesting there's certainly a lot
of interesting vulnerability research
that can be done in this area and also
just the sort of high-level terrifying
view of the legacy craft that we are
underneath all of my shiny phone so you
can't have any X in you talk without
bigotry slide what is xn you you have on
the left hand side here marks and on the
right hand side
BSD why do these exist next to each
other well they wanted to have it's very
nice old microkernel but this
microkernel can't do things like I can
fire or have a network sack ma just
doesn't have those things
so what Darwin did was take BSD on one
side and not on the other side and sort
of glue them together so actually this
is structure talks which is the
abstraction boy talks for precepts any
module got bullet passed down in the PSD
world it's called a process and
literally they just point to each other
so a mark class has this VSD pig poo
it's a just avoid saga is much doesn't
know anything about nathie and that
points to the striped
croc in the PSP you are vice versa the
PSD bootstrap tasks the start frat
brother as a tar field which points to
the map well this is all irrelevant for
what we ended up rather so they both
have to eat they both have separate
responsibilities in terms of the area of
the system that they manage
so on a much side we had Venus's talked
earlier about the ports and about how
much what names can be difficult to use
and that all lives under this itk states
which is the task per person per cart
way of imagining port names to rights so
it's what goes means is 41 for to do or
whatever important name to struct a
decent port and then here similar
attraction in the ESD world for
thousands ripping others weren't seeing
a transcription numbers which Derek long
a number which is it's an index in your
process table do a file cool subject
which is similar this is a client
attraction level to I can support but
once after you know mark that there's a
threads ESD versus groups and
credentials are ladies want to start and
ma is responsible for me and Matt say
alright Mike Ovitz the virtual memory
manager is done on the much sighs it's
not be exceeds memory interface memory
impaired although you can use the BSD
memory user space memory management
interface to to manage users that use of
memory and its really all implemented on
the market side and if you look at the
bsd Siskel's that you would use to
allocate memory we will just end up
there just quite sure subs which call
over into the ma side of the code
and what's the fundamental thing that
i'm going to talk about message passing
this is this fundamental
microkernel idea and it's important to
point out i OS news
likewise this is not a microkernel in
any way but nevertheless it has the
legacy
background of some of it used to be a
microkernel
so it's drank all this stuff with it
even though whether they actually gained
much benefit from it now
I'm deal with message passing is that
you split out all your functionality and
a different user space processes was the
idea bone and these are all have just
mineral level of courage that they
require and they will talk to each other
by sending you know little over works
with messages lemon and the idea well it
was thought it's probably true that the
media sort of reason that no one ever
took these microkernel architectures
that fire that's there are systems that
do use them but your iPhone it's not a
real micro camera and this is not really
a major performance bottleneck the fact
that you have to copy memories all the
time to make anything happen and so this
talk is about how much use uses virtual
memory tricks to make being able to pass
these mock messages fast and how
actually how it works and it was quite
very cool so we must already mentioned
mock messages I think everyone in the
audience is 43 familiar for enough
messages so we're gonna go very quickly
look at this the fundamental unit of
message in userspace at least is this 24
by structure this is the smallest
possible mock message you can find and
you don't think that we am interested in
here is this single there this is
the complex bit the most significant bit
occurs the b-word and this is gonna tell
us is this message complex so there's
one or simple it's not one if it's
complex then following this heavy
structure in memory because panel is
going to look for another D word called
confusingly body so this is not the body
of the message this is actually a count
of how many structures similar this will
follow before you get to the body so I
guess it's called body for some reason
and then after these these structures
from the actual in line message body
we'll come back to what mark message
house applying descriptor actually is
well we really need to know that in this
message we tell it how big your messages
that's how big the this action entire
butter is you want to talk me into the
camera and then the car like a copy to
the recipient you said where you want to
send the message to in terms of this is
a mock name that you have some kind of
right over and then people take other
ports in there and by convention you can
use the local port to transfer a receive
a very send able writes the morning to a
reply port and there's also about report
which the last time I gave a talk this
was this was undefined what was in there
and a few Mac OS releases ago they about
report in this field so important thing
here is when you send a message this
entire structure and this inline message
body
you basically hundreds of megabytes
that's very unlikely the fine example
there could be hundreds of megabytes but
the system completely supports our and
every time you want to send one of these
messages only to want to use a space
process or cubic are not there's a lot
of memory company that goes on so there
will be a kernel heap allocation made
that's the same size but slightly larger
than this message back that the message
buffer will be copied in from user space
to the kernel processed and then copied
out into user space or recipient and so
yeah there's a lot a lot of memory
copying going on here and back in the
early 80s when this is being written
um memory copying was even slower than
it is now only very slow and so if you
want to make your thing fast you want to
avoid copying these large amount of data
and so how do you avoid copying large
amounts of data you can use virtual
memory magic so to look at this message
here rather than having an enormous
inline message body what you can instead
do is tell the system actually is just
my
virtual memory address of the region of
memory I want to send here's how big it
is here's some flags don't make this
happen for free and specifically what
you want to do is if you set these are
flags here if you set the copy flag to
zero
are you saying I don't want you to make
a copy of this memory for the recipient
in fact what I also want you to do is
not make a copy and deallocate it from
my address space and make sure that the
FGX is page aligned then size and page
align then what the map from the M
subsystem is able to do is actually take
that entire virtual memory region pull
it out of your process and push it
directly into the recipient completely
avoiding you need to actually copy the
contents of all of the pages yeah it's
nothing these bits implies move
semantics
she's apply it to the underlying virtual
memory and the idea is this will be
boxed so that was this look so we need
to look at a little bit of my virtual
memory internals and the kernel managed
data structures that make this work so
as we looked at before this starts task
is the high-level perception of a task
and the time has a virtual memory map
which is a struct VM that you start p.m.
match then contains pointers into a
process linked list of virtual memory
map entries I see you in here sir
these can be either in a linked list or
a red-black tree and essentially the
linked list version is easier to think
about but the red black tree is the one
that's actually used in practice and
really this is just an entry which
covers everything well while it's
virtual memory working memory region in
your task
so for each address that could be
dereferenced okay if the new records
don't as a deep it's covered by one of
the virtual memory map entries in this
mix we're actually read back through
those me and my entries themselves first
contained they're done didn't respond to
see who they're going backwards if you
wanted for example grab all of the
veterinary map entries covering a region
that's spanned by multiples of these you
can start at the first one and
particular in this until you've cracked
all the things that cover the entire
region the heat map that entry then
tells you here's the verb to the dresser
that I represent the start out and I
represent the end on so I'm responsible
for everything in between start and end
and then finally at the end you actually
have the pointers into the object that
actually tells you how to get contents
or the pages and finally what offset in
that object do I start getting my memory
from and then the last of our attraction
we'll look at is what do those objects
themselves look like so it starts off
with this many cue pointer and this then
finally need to point it in to the
linked list of yes of DM pages and there
is one VM page for each physical page of
physical memory that can be allocated
like that so these are then the pages
that are currently resident are you
actually their contents is in RAM for
that object and it's very likely that
the object that's Bob represents far
more memory or has far more contents
then is actually occurring in physical
memory but this is the stuff that's in
physical memory and then these other
three fields here this pager aging
offset pager control are then the way
that you can get to BM object to either
give physical page
back or going request more contents to
put we need their physical pages and
then finally you can also nest these
structures so rather than having a
virtual memory map entry pointing
directly into an object which could be
for example the Earth file you can
instead point into another map and this
way you can nest between processes
different virtual memory max so now that
we've looked at accurately structures
let's look at actually the
implementation of how this optimized new
operation is supposed to work so on the
Left we have a sender task and on the
right we have a receiver task so sender
wants to send a mock message to receiver
and it wants to in that message move
some portion of its subjects face to the
receiver so the way this works and
Selina's already mentioned earlier these
messages in most cases are actually
being infused into the kernel and then
only when we receiver actually tries to
DQ the message will they be copied into
the receiver so actually they cut this
limbo state where they the message is
live in the kernel and so the structure
that's going to contain the near map
entries which we are putting in this
limbo state is called a DM map copy
which is like a VM wrap but it's just
there for containing stuff which is
being copied like be a map entries which
have been spotted around so this is how
it's supposed to work you take your
source in fact object States which is
this big list like that three of virtual
memory map entries we find the start and
end of the region that you want to move
then you move them into the copy and
then later on when the receiver receives
this it walks through their BMI entry
it's where my entry list finds a place
to put them and then copies those
entries one copy the contents of those
VM entry structures into new VM map data
structures in there and so notice that
that's taken some of the collector Jeff
space but this presets on the left the
thing that moved it is the receiver and
at no point anyone have to amend copy
the contents of that memory we get moved
you know one obstruction or a few
abstraction layers higher you just move
the data structures around and magically
you've done the equivalent of my look
and then copy in their target so what's
wrong here well what you have to first
appreciate is that this works or this is
supposed to work because what you're
trying to do is move the merit yeah I'm
not trying to make a copy of the memory
there's this things like copy on writes
which this bug has got nothing to do but
would be a different way of achieving
the same effect or a similar effect ie
no overhead way to copy memory around
but this is not a copy on write style
thing this is so it's important then
that the operation of finding the
correctly and map entries and copying
them into the VM map copy and then
removing them from the cars all needs to
be atomic and we'll see exactly why it
needs to be atomic later on but
hopefully it should be relatively clear
that things are going to go very badly
life it's not atomic so in order to
understand how that might be enforced
you need to understand the ownership
semantics or the lifetime semantics of
all of these objects so these here map
entries are owned by their VN map and
this is enforced by the VM rack lock
field so you can only do everything that
you do with a VM map entry
you must hold the corresponding the M
max luck at all times if you don't hold
that lock then something else to come in
and destroy the VMF entry that you are
currently using yeah and it's almost
certainly very very long is a very bad
way if that doesn't happen and I think
that twice a bug was actually audited by
someone someone audited for that gasify
okay there are many many many places
where it's almost there it's not quite
there they well done the Apple to report
it for that bug Wow it's more subtle
than that
so let's look that's that
how that look is actually used so yeah
on the side I'm locking in the VM
subsystem avoiding kept up to the hard
problem it sort of sit there and it's a
problem so this is their Mac very for
taking the Mian record they're actually
buying BM Mac Mac Mac it's a very long
function what read/write lot of specific
look it doesn't matter what this
actually does but that looks like really
sounded way to take a lock yeah cool
funny thing would lock in it so let's
look at me and Mac unlock yeah Mac I'm
not a slightly more curious looking for
doing the unlock it bumps up this time
stamp counter and then drop the lock and
this is a human executi not really
relevant for the backing and talked
about but very relevant for why none of
this is really fixed so why do we even
have that time stamp counter there and
what's it being useful remember avoiding
dead box is a hard problem
so let's look at an example okay so the
usage of me and map dot when Sam so what
am I do what they hold the lock is make
a local copy of my time travel without
Molotov then drop the lock on the map go
do some stuff a lot on the map again
and then check whether last time stamp
plus one is equal to the current time
stamp and if it's you know reason sir
otherwise continue so what is actually
going on there well really what they're
saying is I'm about to do something here
for which I am NOT for which there may
be deadlocks
or even worse things if I hold the lock
on this map therefore I'm just gonna
drop the lock do some stuff and then I'm
gonna try and check if anyone raced me
and if anyone raised me when they would
have taken the lock and drop the lock
and on dropping a lot they would have
bumped the max time stamp up at which
point I'm going to now have to try to
recover because everything I thought I
knew I can till this point about the
structure of the PM map may no longer be
true so find the edger again it could
have been Kip doctor we unlocked the map
yes you have to go reset everything and
you can think about why this might be so
pervasive well this is the virtual
memory time system and it turns out with
a virtual memory subsystem sometimes
faster allocate virtual memory and it
can't really hold a global lock on
itself while it's trying to put more
memory into it so yeah it's it's not
real without some severe thinking how to
like generically fix this correctly and
this is this construct is everywhere and
so it should be kind of clear where the
bug is gonna be the bug is going to be
well in this window do some stuff will
surprise them back to be unlocked then
did someone race us well okay we
detected that someone raised us so we
need to reset our expectations about the
state of the world and try again and
it's something in this let's reset what
no I don't think we know about the world
the box exactly so we'll look more
accurately don't
a case where they are failing to
accurately reset what they believe the
state of the world should be in regards
to in this case a virtual memory
operation which is supposed to have new
semantics so let's take this task on the
left and we want to send this shaded
region in a VM a copy to another task we
want to send it in so we start with the
being unlocked and we're RBM a copy
object we allocate one VM map entry
hanging off of the copy these me and my
twin trees come from a lock so the
generic kernel zone locator which we
cannot hold me and that lock because we
may well be smoothing this task could
leave the color fast or it could be the
VM map from which that stuff comes so we
can't hold a lot so but we upfront
allocate one VM map entry then we take a
lock on the and we copy the contents
of this first VM map entry into our copy
of the beer map actually and so now we
can't distill there in here and there's
a little present in the VM Maps link
list of near my entries but the lot is
healthy then no one can come in mess
with this then with the locks are
matched we iterate through to the next
being map entry then we watch copy and
if there was one I if we haven't yet
reached the end of the virtual memory
regions we want to copy well we only
allocated upfront on one of these things
and what you're going to need some more
i remember if you need more we need to
drop that look because we can't hold a
lot when we make our talent allocation
so what are you here needs we're going
to call the
we're going to drop the lock we're going
to allocate a new VM map entry onto our
list in the VM map copy then we're going
to click the lock again and then we're
going to see does y 0 2 plus 1 by r
minus there when we drop the lot plus 1
equal the current myanmar times that
did anyone racist only this is not
clearly detecting did anyone like
maliciously
race against us this just means we did
anything else happen which modified the
state of the map and don't think about
what might have happened if it modified
the state of the map for billion times
and the tag that explode that's not the
bug but that is about simply it doesn't
actually at the time if it appears that
either no unlocks happened or all
billion and whatever on what's happened
then we will not reached therefore we
can continue back up to the head of the
loop here we hold the lock we've got a
new VM map entry and we can copy the
contents and move on so the question is
what is the type that doesn't match and
this is the point where we need to reset
our expectations about the state of the
world
well linear map pretty changed and it
could be the case that the me and map
entry for which we had a pointer is has
been freed and that pointer is no longer
valid so we need to go and look up the
VM entry which now covers the remainder
of the budget X region that we have
tried to copy so we do a fresh look up
of the next we're mapping through to
copy and then we continue along the loop
so we take the contents of now this
second purple one here and we copy the
contents of it in to the near map a tree
and repeat all the way down until we've
covered the whole region
and then finally once we've copied all
of the contents over into the Nano map
copy we remove looking at my entries
from the source task and say this is
really than this point into the next
field this one now point a to this one
and this pops back there there's similar
thing in the red black tree that make
them all wake up correctly so what's
wrong yet the problem is this is
supposed to be a completely atomic move
operating if you are an observer of the
VM map you should only ever be able to
see two states we should either see the
whole virtual memory region is in there
in the source or the whole the promoter
region is gone
and if you can ever interact with the
map in intermediate states between those
two when this is no longer an atomic
operation and we will see what is going
to go wrong if it's not a real atomic
operation so let's look at what might
happen because it should be clear that
this is key not so much on the
operations because at some points that
lot goes red and the lock is dropped so
the content doesn't match then it's not
enough to just invalidate this pointer
which points to the next VM at entry to
copy we also have to go back and reset
everything that we've done previously
here so there is someone because we
never removed this where map entry from
the source we only remove that entries
right at the end of the operation so
when we reset the state of the world we
need to reset everything we've done now
that basically what the you can also see
this in the source but it's kind of
clearer here but really it's all us it's
like you need to go back one loop one
nested loop higher so you can't just go
back and fetch this current entry you're
working on
you have to go back and researched all
the entries so what
concretely bad could happen well let's
imagine that while the map is unlocked
so while the market unlocked and one
copy has already been made and we are
busy making a Kellogg zone allocation
for the next near map entry someone else
another thread with access to the VM map
comes along and decides well how about I
also perform and optimize the move
operation at the same time so then
there's going to be this second VM a
copy which again has a VM that entry and
then this second one it's going to start
at the beginning of the virtual address
space see that this great out here map
entry the contents are still intact
because the contents were just copied
into our original being map entry copy
so it's going to copy the contents of
this ones into this second we are map
copy and now they're going to like both
contend on this lock and kind of thrash
around but what you're at to gonna end
up with or to VM map copies that if the
locking works out and actually the
locking pretty much all those lights out
if you correctly for ask the VM map set
up you're going to have to VM map copies
which both believe they are atomic moves
of virtual memory regions where they
both have the same underlying their map
entries which a map to the same yeah map
objects and offsets and we'll see
exactly what there are consequences of
that are in a little bit so how to
actually set something like this up to
do something interesting
so this diagonal set of boxes again is
the virtual address space of your
Christmas this being our lower dress up
to a higher regress and what we're going
to create our active line descriptors
so those are these descriptors which
enable you to take I think with a
virtual memory and put it in a message
and move that and we're going to create
two of them and send them in two
different messages and what the first
one is going to contain this first dark
shaded region and this blue one in the
middle here while I sit there and the
second one it's in an overlap just one
being map entry and continue on like
this so you can see you're going to
create descriptors which overlap by one
being map country and then in two
threads at the same time we're going to
send these messages so in parallel we're
going to get one VMware copy which
contains all of these dark purple ones
and the shaded blue near map poppy and
in the second parallel thread because
the lock keeps getting dropped and we
can do this because they don't correctly
reset the state of the world we are
going to have a VM a copy which starts
with the overlapping region and then
contains a bunch of other game at
entries yeah depends about the actual
structure that I used for the exploit on
my team's bug tracker you have to be a
bit more speedy about I'm certain these
things up but this is ending in the area
and so what it's actually gonna happen
when these two messages get worse needs
well you click the end map and some
contents implies in this case it's an
anonymous object so this is just a way
that you get empty pages of memory that
you can do stuff with that aren't backed
by a file or anything else that you can
in map in geography and so the
consequence of them both pointing to the
same offset is that you're actually
ending up with shared memory I
when this firm might copy gets mapped
into one process then this it's wrapped
into a different process we ended up
both having the same with having a
tree which in the end will
the same physical pages so they
accidentally created shared memory and
we will find a way to turn accidentally
created shared memory for something more
useful so then that's as quickly look at
what is going to happen when these two
messages are received
so first message here will be received
by the task on the list so again all of
these me and my entries go away all of
these here my entries will get swatted
somewhere into this virtual address
space and then of the task on the left
and the tasks on the right will receive
will match this VM a copy into their
address space and they will go in there
and now these parts have a VMware entry
with the same contents which is fine
what means is you have said Mary what
does the shared memory really mean it
means that in this task if I write to
this page which I believe is in an out
of line which is in memory sent to me in
an out of lying descriptor in the mock
message that meant that those change is
going to be visible to the task on the
right whereas the tasks on the right
also believe that it's just received as
well it has received us in now to find
descriptor and it believes that that
memory is immutable because that is what
the doctors say about watching mark
messages so the trick to do something
interesting with this is when we can
send messages to ourself so we create a
crafted out of line descriptor
overlapping region and then we have the
target that we're going to look back in
second and we send one bit of this to
the target then back to ourselves and
what this doughnut is evil is to do is
to read and write to these pages in that
event descriptor while the target is
processing and that's what's there
enable us to do something interesting so
yeah how do we exploit unexpectedly
shared memory
against the client premises that you end
up with there so this breaks the
semantics that well myself just like an
envelope ie
unique a letter in the post you taking
out the envelope and you expect to just
be able to if you read it twice you read
the same thing you don't expect the
contents of it to ever change it's
immutable and this is the guarantee that
mock messages make as well
you are deafening given this as if it
were copied into your address base and
it's supposed to be eating from you that
it wasn't really copied because all this
went to stuff going on behind scene so
we're not learning it there is we need
to find somewhere we're breaking those
semantics by breaking the fact that this
is meant to be immutable actually leads
to something happening that has security
impact in air quotes we'll go quickly
through this is gonna dive into serious
aside what is security in fact quickly
some think about it it's very difficult
to define what security integrity means
memory corruption is the most boring yet
white except the thing with security
impact that's in there is a great deal
of research over decades which in
hopefully have to convince you that if
you can call us we're in this in a very
likely way it is almost always possible
to turn memory corruption in each target
context into the ability to perform
other consistent interactions with the
trust level of the target context are
you memory corruption is always bad but
there are all interesting things you can
do with a primitive like I can suddenly
make memory there's not socially shared
when I we shared memory so you can
imagine things like time of kept time
abuse in signature campaign which exists
everywhere there have been many places
on iOS there any mac OS of things like
that you would then have to find some
place where that's happening on a
deadline on
that sent as an applet line just like
that I didn't find any that interesting
things out you can think of other things
like more time effect I would use in for
example select the validation so NSX PC
I don't reckon over here has ever gone
into the details of NSX PT works this is
a way where you can do kind of very cool
objective-c magical object remoting you
can just call a selector or an object in
your exacts and it actually occurs in
some other versions on the other name
and this really involves like sending a
string like a serialized string
representing to select that to the other
side and saying yeah please call the
selector I have actually look quite deep
this of whether that could be a time
check my keys there and I don't think
there is what 2220 some bytecode
verification and we could the quirky is
not here it's gonna play right that was
for him because that happened pieces of
for example is playstation for exploit
with time technologies in the EP a quite
code on playstation 4 ESD to our color
mac OS via PDF it's far simpler than the
other well you know that could be a
weird alligator that releases the pages
or really still don't but yes I'm boring
I'm lazy
we'll just call for intersection
specifically I also really wants to bog
which we can play more with point
authentication point authentication is
very interesting and that's not really
what the story's about and I think I
will run out of time before we get to
discuss that at all
but if you're interested there's a
public blog post about how you can play
with one aspect of whatever the security
model of point authentication is
supposed to be you can defeat some of it
with so if you did memory demand
reduction so they're doing bugs
similar to the one I've just described
we've been done by other people before
so in 2017
he on our team at Google also found this
Punk Cee presently in 24:56 which led to
a similar style similar kind of contract
well you can end up with unexpected
shared memory the colors in that case
rather than it was a different kind of
trick and you could send out the blind
descriptor where the pages were fact by
a mock memory entry object and then
there was just on fire where you could
actually then bring aid back from the
mock memory entry object but suddenly
you had shared memory again and so he
targeted that construct in Linux PC so
here is the live XP T time I checked and
gives the game great so I just copied
his technique with its exploit so
serialize XP T West bodies xvc I
mentioned NS excuses NSX BC it built on
top of exbc XP T itself is a new ish
kind of its serialization format and
with about 10 or 12 basic types that you
can serialize into my binary message
send it in him
send it everybody into a binding but
first send that a mock message and then
deserialize it on the other side the
idea being to read out key value pairs
of extremist dictionaries different
things so it turns out that when you
read the steriliser if you try to send a
large serialized ecstasy message it will
actually take the bulk of the data and
send it in one of those out of line
descriptors so this means that any of
the XP CDC realization code could be a
target to find an unexpected time of
check time of use because remember these
things aren't bugs these are just
constructs that if you had a bug that
enabled you to make shed memory where it
shouldn't be the new all of these things
become bugs but don't worry there and
that's why none of them have been fixed
because there's nothing to fix if you
think that your
we're going to create one of these
situations again what's going on here
but it's essentially our twelve is
pointing into the descriptor into the
amount of language is now shared what
doing is drilling finding the X 29 to
that value my lock and then getting some
offset in gear and strike up in yeah
that offset X 20 it's stripped copies
from that buffer now this should be and
so basically we only speak our here's
that iOS version and you enjoy the x86
version while it's still relevant
because there this will die sweet
yeah learn entity box and it's all here
so we can also just use x-rays that's
good I mean look at where the fields are
mr. couple so here there's a double
affection and since that if the memory
quantity by this changes then stir copy
is going to strike up the more than we
my logs because this points in so now
unexpectedly shared memory next second
we have a few more in 30 seconds
remaining so I can do maybe two minute
30 second review of how that excellent
actually works so we did crash serialize
ecstasy dictionary that we're going to
send to a tag our target and at the end
of this we have this overlapping being
that country so this first region thing
gets into our target as a serialize the
object in this region it's gonna
get sent to ourselves so we are going to
end up being able to read and write the
end of the series ecstasy dictionary
while the target is positive
so in the shared memory the structure
very simply we have one byte which is
the posting in null because in actually
see dictionaries the keys which is what
we are targeting for our overflow from
tip that's extra Len malach Circle T are
specially null-terminated so we have
this flipper bite which in a loop we
just really quickly flip between zero
and nonzero the idea being that we're
hoping that think about this right this
strollin will see them null milah and
then the strip copy will not see the
null and so we'll copy after it so we
hope that it gets mapped to be big
enough to contain just this size have
been the copy will have this whole size
and so before that there is some kind of
deep cream the idea being that we can
make something interesting happen over
there at 10 10 10 overview of the heat
grew we're going to set up a structure
on the heap such that the malloc for the
short string fits inside this deck we're
gonna create an heap which has before it
well anywhere before it or after it an
ecstacy array structure it's just after
I undersized buffer it's in a big actual
backing store for that array so that
when we have our bad strip copy mr.
copies but here into the first pointer
in the ecstasy arrays the package movies
that don't post afford the exploit the
next thing isn't a lot more detail so
then what we're going to do in the
senator is just as fast as we can flip
this between 0 1 0 and in the receiver
we hope this is going to happen and if
we're successful
these are XB c object pointers and we're
going to be able to correct the next pc
object pointer and make something
I think I will just skip over the 40
authentication defeat essentially the
high-level overview of the point of
authentication defeat and I hesitate to
call it a defeat because I don't think
this is an intended attacker scenario
for the for authentication you have to
move sets of keys three sets of three
versus two sets of keys we keep them
used to tag pointers and you can tag
whatever pointers you want using these
key keys you have keys in this family
like easing the be family even the be
family are derived from the same traffic
material for piecing in any families
which are insane for graphical terror
for all processes so I can create an
authentication code in my low privileged
user space process for a pointer that
will be valid in a hive for different
privileges for the eighties for the VP I
can't do that because the keys are not
shared so local pretty desolation pact
defeat essentially really just means
like you have to play the part but only
uses pointers which are I can use this
point at which are not educated or only
uses functions which are authenticated
with any family keys which in this
little example here is this pack fires
n/a uses instruction a key with zero
contact family so that doesn't have a
theory backed by a rather than something
that uses beep and it turns out that
it's not too difficult to find some
concepts about them the only mine is a
partner to see object pointer control to
PC control without the BP and a whole
other dog disarray of that server let's
get rid of that I'm
and for some final thoughts about what
just happened so xnu virtual memory code
is very old very very old
I can't generate that I tried to show
very little code but if you did look at
some of the page when you scroll back to
the copyright this is like 1985 so I
discussed publicly many times before
that Paris these are seriously legacy
devices not because this is a 5x but
even like the newer ones extreme legacy
fundamental underlie all of the
shininess
well to me is very old it's really
horrific Lee complex this might just be
a necessary construct for a virtual
memory code but it's really really
really complicated and hard to read very
hard to read very hard to reason about
extremely keen on multi-thousand buying
functions with like 8 levels of nested
nests that halfway through just like to
call themselves again with other flags
like it's really hard to read and
critical than every security boundary
swing decades if anyone understood it ok
this isn't well is it the kind of folks
would have almost certainly in bed this
is definitely low hanging fruit ie it's
quite easy to come up with here is some
security guarantee I this move must be
atomic let's break it find someplace
that they unlock the map and then try
and do that well that's unlocked yes so
you feel free to prove me wrong if you
understand the whole thing or if you're
watching the live stream and like are
the dev wrote this in 1985
like do you have some things I'd like
you to explain I'm finding finding the
remaining or finding the better bugs
it requires understanding okay now I'm
gonna other small branch yes you can
still make a million dollars grepping
from n copy in iOS and you definitely
can but virtual memory bugs are more
complicated than just correcting for
knowing bad functions okay if it wasn't
men copy it was a memory
so maybe they're like apples and grep
mr. the wrong thing
yes who refused to be that these suckled
memory box
I like you to make for a very long time
trust your mom luxury 999 all the
devices going here that was some quick
well every budget equation confirm that
quake agree three weeks ago second we
don't know and luxury devices so I'm
assistant thank you to Objective C for
this awesome conference and especially
to Jonathan Levin and Amit Singh who
without they're very helpful books they
sort of walk impossible yeah thank you