sir whatever okay thank you everybody
for attending this is a passion that I
had started to develop that year or more
ago simply put I realize a whole bunch
of things were happening and I realized
that we needed to do something different
I'm not sure how much you myself
I can impact it better I cannot sit down
tonight and write a better antivirus
program not gonna happen
personalized code second of all I
probably would have to learn a heck of a
lot about a virus so there's a lot of
controls that we have that are just
failing and I wanted to figure out a
different way to approach I'm what is 10
tests of red team's something that would
actually return more value when it was
completely so that when you have no HDMI
button on for her up there is it red
because I have nothing up here well I'm
on PGA okay see they told me VGA that
may be a problem I specifically got my
VGA ready which was like what do you
have HDMI I know because I have the
small HDMI which you guys know okay Kibo
that's why so this won't be broadcast
sorry it's not your mine that's what I'm
sorry what
oh so anyway so I started to think about
this and I started to come up with this
whole framework and and that's what this
talk is about so one of the precepts I
almost went to walk out and crazy here
that's pretty long ago in information
security years yes sir
oh there are two types of companies
those who have been
and those who think they haven't I'm
sorry no it's a same exact feeling and
that's in my notes that you can't see it
actually says those that are aware they
have been happy and those who are
unaware there really is and he actually
my positive statements
I want more recently to say every major
organization in the nation has been
hacked which I thought was a little
aggressive because some are new and they
haven't act yet given their - but but
seriously this is what really got to put
the controls in place successfully to
stop them so there's a whole bunch so
this is the next slide really details a
lot of those reasons a little bit I'm
not even gonna hit every single one of
them but I'm in delivering this talk I
decided I wanted to do a lot of research
so I went through each one of these
points and then I contacted some
confessions I did some research I read
online and the first thing I did was I
contacted Brian Krebs he's one of the
first articles I've read he published in
2012 they really scathing critique of
antivirus and his research said that
about 25% of all 0-9 malware was not was
caught so 75% of the new samples of
malware that you've been running through
systems was just going right by the
signature base antivirus at the time
which is now changed some so we're
improving but at the time it was
horrendous I would actually argue the 25
percent while fairly pathetic still
gives you a layer of security
you're still reducing your risk it may
not be tremendously but it's something
so we depend to death I'm not exactly
going to throw away any virus I'm not
gonna Harold it this is the solution so
I asked Brian Krebs after reading his
article if he had anything more recent
2012 so he said no we
- again I went to walk out deported me
out to a University researcher I
contacted him he said you can use
whatever I say as long as you don't
mention who I am so I won't but he
pointed me to an interesting study from
a company called last line and they did
a very cool study if you go on hit me up
on LinkedIn or big blemishes really
interesting studies year law they found
new antivirus new viruses as they're
released malar every single that they
use virus called and ran the brand-new
samples through the next day they ran
the samples from the day before and the
new stuff o'clock and they kept doing
this throughout the year so they were
getting a tremendous amount of fur but
on all of the antivirus engines that
were out there so their their research
said 50% 51 percent of the zero devices
were getting caught that's a really good
game from 25 percent in 2012 but is it
still you know now I'm still just
calling it a lair but here's the
interesting thing
a year later the day one viruses cuz
they only run through a year ten percent
of the engines still didn't catch him a
year later so they were no longer than
anywhere years they were any what the
wild for an entire year so and the other
thing that they pointed out because they
wanted to be fair about this they were
hoping too many vendors really hard they
were being this is the whole industry
this is a city interested but one of the
things that they pointed out was every
single antivirus engine at one point or
another failed so there was no silver
bullet out there there was no company
that did really well someone than others
but like I said they were trying to be
fair so they didn't want to pump one up
or knock one down so they they didn't do
that so that exploit is really I want to
get on this in two different
perspectives what is in the quarry
and the other one is just the state of
our industry so the first is I like to
do things interactively and there's one
ground rule and security MBA session is
a great chapter I reckon it's a few
phases
I'm sorry to have to put you through
meat speaking again but we do something
there called Chatham House Rules Chatham
House Rules is very very easy you can
say something that happened in an event
that you can't attribute it to a company
so you can say I heard this company
today there are problem with virus
cannot say which company you have to be
generic about so I'm going to ask a
question and some of your gonna be like
to raise my hand well Chatham House
Rules
so if you raise your hand nobody's gonna
say ninja everybody agree okay we're
here after Julie do we know about
whatever you're about to ask no I'm
going to ask you a question but I have
to preface it with that because
otherwise everybody's going to look at
me like I'm right so who in here has an
accurate inventory of their hardware and
software oh you're very small company
still if I had a price I would throw it
to you one hand there we go so that's
that's even better of sample size thank
you for the record yes sir and most
people agree that 80% or better is
accurate you're striving for um yes
maybe if your Center better is a peer so
a couple more hands go out when you when
you loosen the constraints a little bit
okay so that's true right I mean we're
all we're all fighting this struggle
okay so and and of course patch cadence
the company comes out with flow other
patch comes out when sometimes it's
right away sometimes it's sometimes the
malware writers they'll figure out the
flaw right away something out hours
later and that's actually happen where
somebody releases a flaw they don't even
release details and these groups that do
this malware they'll reverse engineer
figure out exactly what the flaws and
released malware eight hours later
there's no way a company she's gonna
patch that fast so we're really behind
the times we're not a factor in any work
so we can't have you maybe want to here
and the patches aren't available so we
have to do something a little different
so very very briefly because I think I
mean I can ask the question - how many
people here field as they do in friction
preps and in motion
well you have to have control of your
certificates some sort of certificate
management system you have to be
confident that your data address is
actually encrypted yes we constantly you
did it in motion is actually encrypted
the stuff that you're worried about is
never unencrypted there's companies that
do that actually my own company that is
pre gamed into that
so what interesting point when my
research on your question gemalto 2017
it was really one survey of breach data
they found only 1% of the breaches
involve encrypted data that's cute
someone because legally a lot of
companies don't have it and report you
quickly paid for each so yeah
so I skip ahead lavance imagine things
were great that's kind of funny I like
this one
how many of you have a position where
you talk to your CEO good amount
probably would you say your CEO is
engaged yes I got a couple of months a
couple of guesses that's good
so 68 percent of CEOs think that their
organization is a leader in information
security 95 percent of boards their
company is better than the field in
information security
conversely 38 percent of CEOs say they
are engaged and 28 percent of boards
that say they're engaged I don't know
where the hell are get now but that's an
interesting stat right if you have a
board that's engaged if you have a CEO
that's engaged that's fantastic stage
that's great so I'm going to get down
again human element I don't want to go
into that's just people it's social
engineering that's the nature if you can
find to be nice to people somebody
caused a problem you want help them out
or even I mean if people want to fix
that I don't know we should fix that
that's a whole nother talk but lack of
qualified very professionals really one
point here Isis squared had a 2018 study
they found it 2.9 million security
positions were open in the world right
now and not able to be filled so if
anybody hears looking for a job what
you're doing wrong so is there any pen
testers here any red teamers now I know
why just one two three four five anybody
up so Tiffany Chatham House Rules you
have to maybe your company or anything
has rep at a time so so a hundred
percent success rate if that's pretty
much the industry standard by the way so
if you engage by these firms and they
get in one of the things that you get is
a nice little report a lot of companies
take these awards and do they're
supposed to this they'll take the
control valve or they'll take an area
inhabit role they'll apply control maybe
just Apache maybe it's a new policy
procedure maybe it's a complete upgrade
overhaul new security clients whatever
it's gonna be a lot of companies totally
ignore them sure these guys competitive
and then the next year when you're
engaged you get on the same exact wire
which is always fun you're done on you
too easy but one of the things I found
in this whole trying to flesh out this
thought that I had was I went to the
PETA standard which is the pen testers
reporting standards the engagement
standards it's really their Bible of how
to do stuff very well written it's
missing something very very big job when
you get to the end of engagement it
doesn't tell you how failed to catch
them tells you what they did how they
got in what flaw they preach what
protocol they took advantage of but it
doesn't say you would have caught us if
and that was one of the big things that
I was trying to figure out when I was
going through this whole process of
coming up with this thing this really
interesting I you know there's stories
of pen testing these guys could probably
tell stories are much better than mine
but
stories about just all sorts of
creativity on how the heck people get in
and do it did you
anybody familiar with oh my god and
drawing a blank on it's great babe yes
go run friend of mine really great guy
and I just blank his name so I and it's
reported so he's never get he once told
me a story where he did a physical test
and he walked into a building with a
clipboard and he piggyback somebody
walked in he's got an empty office at
the office himself in here and he worked
all day he met people he left he came
back the next day the same exact thing
it might and their way people were
thinking he was new company and that he
was like a VP in the office there's
another Rob Hamlet he's a spider laughs
he told a couple stories if they're
online to see quantum where credit's
theories get a two different pen test
one was really funny though
I'll just share that one they could not
find a way in this company to lock down
everything they found no flaws they
found nothing
social engineering did large they
couldn't get in they finally found a
unprotected network that was barricaded
off from everything else they got the
video camera they couldn't do anything
with them but they got the video Paris
and then they realized that one of them
was actually in a work area I know it's
a pan tilt zoom into a keyboard and they
caught user name and password and reach
the whole network they got in and
credentials fantastic so it's just
interesting and red team wins the next
thing that really influenced my going
into this whole thing and I'm not going
to go into these but this is exactly
this it's well time it boggles my mind I
understand our adversaries are trying
not to be discovered
but it's just mind-blowing that they can
stay in our networks for hundreds of
days and you don't see them they don't
trip any alarms and the thing that
bothered me about this and the thing
that furthered my thinking along these
through breach testing is we must not be
collecting the data properly
we're not alerting on the right thing
this is kind of funny I gotta walk a
little bit hopefully I won't go to the
Arnage flight recorder that's an
airplane flight recorder and series
isn't not I was really shocked they
track everything a plane goes down you
pull that sucker first of all you can
locate it by you can look at the plane
by that thing well plane goes down it
has all the data you need all the
forensics you need to figure out why
that plane went down
was it mechanical error was it a
Highlands paramore they've got
everything on there they know every move
that was made that no titles me it's
fantastic and that was something that
just struck me we do something like that
in security so we can't give up that's
not really what we do first of all we
like the challenge I like you challenge
I mean they're stacked against those
odds right but we can still beat them we
can still come together and find better
ways to do things so this is something
that I took an inordinate amount of time
on probably way too long
that little paragraph right there
because I'm trying to hope that when you
walk out of here today you will think to
yourself this is actually good idea and
I think I would like to push this
forward and you can help because right
now
roll the clock back 20 years somebody
came up with the idea of pen testing and
everybody thought wow this is crazy
attacker own network now it's in
compliance in it's all over the world
and everybody this pen testing and
there's the pen testers room right now
we do it for a living
who would have thought so my goal is few
years from now the series testing will
become part of our environments maybe
it'll be a supplement to the red team
maybe it'll be either-or I don't really
know I think the value propositions are
different but this is essentially what
it is so going into it a little bit more
giving you a little bit more detail
pre-engagement
this is a lot like prepping for pen test
prepping for a red TV the first step and
this is a step that's in a lot of
compliance guidelines it's a step that
we've all should already have done we
have to know what is important to our
companies we also should not be the ones
to make that call we very often sit in
our rooms with education for management
I've been there and we try to figure out
our own what's the most important thing
and sometimes members of the team will
actually kind of laugh when somebody
brings up the idea of hey we should go
talk to management you talk to upper
management find out what they think it's
the most important imagine I teach you
get to a meeting with the CFO the CEO
couple vice presidents and just sitting
down and saying I want to go over
everything bold and I want you to tell
me what the three most valuable things
are they could be like we have to let
them know how important is we have to
let them know that this is gonna drive
our budgets this is going to drive our
initiatives this is gonna drive what we
protect and how much emphasis we placed
on that protection and we really
shouldn't make a decision I go over that
because well not only is it obvious but
very recently I had a really cool
discovery in my own company
I spoke to our CTL and there was a
couple of other executives in the room
and we were talking about this very
thing route insurance does a really cool
thing and I'm not plugging the just the
dynamics of the company we actually do a
whole bunch of stuff with telematics so
we have a whole bunch of data and that
data drives the decision about whether
we want to insure something or not it's
not driven by weird models like are you
married are you over 25 it's actually
models that based on your private what
we do that data scientists the beryllium
lines who are much harder than me who
figured out all of these data points and
how to interact with each other and what
is a safe driver I assume was our
biggest priority to protect executive
management totally blew me out of the
water and I was so grateful to hear they
totally disagree they thought our number
one responsibility was the key to our
clients data secure because we don't own
it we're just custodians of it and I was
so blown away to hear that because that
is what I would have prioritized but I
just assumed the business would have
prioritized differently so the lesson
there's really don't try to do this
don't try to be the one in terms of
priority I was dead long I'm good but I
was dead wrong if I would have built my
program around my assumptions my number
one goal would not have been the
businesses number one goal not a good
thing this is a weird one and I keep
that used to this information Security's
not used to this but if you have a legal
team if your company's big enough to
have more if you have an outside counsel
trying to talk to the CFO about getting
an hour of the outside counsel time or
try to make a meeting with somebody on
the legal team and get to know them I've
become their friends because you're
going to need their help this is very
very important and what I put up there
instead of the work doctrine that's how
the legal thing which means most of our
eyes will glaze over but it's very very
important
you have an incident what do we do like
I like a big like you legitimately
something just went really really wrong
and you need some serious expertise to
come in you hire somebody if the legal
team does not make that hire everything
they do is discoverable one more law
so I usually give this talk with Matt
Curtin
anybody know one person he's a much
better speaker than I am so I apologize
ahead of time but he has these great
stories about and he know what's the
personal identifiable information
outside of it
generic stories about a couple of
companies that he's been engaged with
where they get it right
and everything went according to plan
and whether you do is wrong so your
legal team get them on board let them
know if an incident happens you're gonna
call this number and engage this perm if
you get really chummy with the legal
team that's fantastic because then you
can tell them you're gonna call it
engage you and flip it to me you don't
have to be involved really but you have
to be believed that's one of the most
key things I think you probably be here
with now this is obvious and it's an
extension of the previous one incident
response any responses so I'm sorry
about that these four points are if
you're in a company right now and you
don't have a full-fledged insert
response plan get this done and then you
can do in a super each test and the
reason why I say that is because part of
them is huge test is actually working on
this so if you have a framework even a
poorly developed framework it's going to
help you tremendously when you get to
the end of this testing
and there's a very important reason why
you want to do this and I will go about
in a moment or two so now here got your
data you've got this is relationships
you've got legal relationships you have
gone through and government response
plan we're ready to get you runs in turn
don't take this lightly you really have
to get your term that knows what they're
doing
try to get a firm that has a history of
presenting in court trying to get a firm
that has expert witnesses who are really
qualified expert witnesses getting a
firm that knows what they're doing if
you are a cloud first company don't get
a forensics firm that's been around for
twenty years and doesn't know what the
cloud is quite yet try to get one that
has a few people on their team who
specialize in pulling whatever they can
from AWS is you're out whatever flavor
you're in the reverse is true as well if
you're on friend get a firm that has
done the datacenter work on friend and
that's their bread and butter now the
reason why for this slide and the
previous slide the reason why you want
to do this and the reason why this is so
important this has a side effect
potentially if you do and soon reach
pest I'm sure you know figure out that
is you may find a breach so that's not
really the goal here but it is it
possible side tech you're going to
identify the goods that you're looking
to protect then you're gonna hire teamm
and they're gonna go and look at this is
an outline I swear this is I'm just
gonna tell you all right now it is
really hard for me to stay still I want
to walk around okay so what is done as
you might expect you are assuming you
have a breach you're calling in the
cavalry only there's no red lights
flashing you're gonna have a forensics
team come in and they're gonna say
how makes your company how many branches
how many locations
okay what's your data where is your data
okay what is your primary objective to
protect let's go look at that now if
there was a breach what can we find out
maybe it's on a server and they'll look
at that log on that log and they'll look
at whole bunches of different
Commission's and artifacts and whatever
they can maybe you're streaming to a
seam and they'll look at that data from
based on what you told them is the
important thing they're going to
actually conduct the exercise as if you
really had a breach and that's really
really important because the last thing
you want to do is do this if you've had
a breach and have no idea what's going
to turn out so this is kind of jokey
slice the last one but it is actually he
detected alert in this bond that's what
they want to find out and they want to
find out before our region curves they
want to make sure that you can actually
find the things that they look for which
are not the things that we are looking
for as the red teamers here attest to
we're obviously not looking at the right
thing so we need to get somebody who
knows somebody who comes in after it
cleans these messes up get them to look
at this stuff beforehand work with you
your ability to detect their ability to
alert and then go over you into the
response plan and yes there is a
possibility actually do this they are
going to empower evidence this is why
you want to be friends with your lawyers
beforehand this is why this whole assume
breach testing should be engaged from
legal team and this is why you want
really qualified forensic sperm because
if they find a breach and labs coming to
this car I had and I'm not trying to
offend any red teamers here I had a red
teamers end up kind of aggressively you
said red teams do this too now
why don't you just say you can get your
red team in turn that's a very good
question however there's a slight
difference in how the data is handled to
preserve evidence and it's very key if
you stumble across a real breach you
don't want a red team who doesn't know
forensics inside and out to discover
that reach because they may have already
run tools they may have already mistakes
and handling you want forensics firm
that's going to go in there with the
mindset this is a breach we're looking
for evidence very big difference and I'm
not insulting refugees they're fantastic
they would find so many different things
and the value of that is incredible this
is just a different approach we're
trying to stop the breach from ever
happening by doing this work ahead of
time preparing ourselves to tackle earn
response so the deliverable I see that
somewhat as the about the Penguins
you're gonna get a normal document
you're gonna work with this team this
team is gonna come back and the curtain
or present the findings they're gonna
present your gaps
they're gonna find out so they're gonna
say hey we went in we found some good
evidence surrounding this one box and
then we want to check to see who we
found out that you're not logging this
box there's finding number one get your
crown jewels to be locking through the
scene if that might be as simple finding
it could be anything it could be the
triggers that you have aren't really
relevant they're good at some things but
right here he's gonna blow right by them
and they know how they're gonna trip
alarms because they're the ones you
clean up after the fact they are the
ones who find the little teeny in the
artifacts that red teamers can leave
behind because they know nobody's gonna
find them so we work with a firm that
knows this stuff we can know what
triggers to look for we can alert on
those triggers and of course we're gonna
go over it into the response plan which
is why I mentioned in the beginning have
one make sure it's someone flushed out
make sure especially the communication
part this is one that almost everybody
leaves out the tepee I can do a whole
second deployments or response but one
of the things that often gets left out
is communication there's one thing that
I always says and not might be coming up
is that it's something that I found a
long time going to be very wise advice
it's nobody better to call the FBI and
you don't want them not going to endorse
it you have a breach and you have no
idea that is like a career-ending thing
resume updating a bank so if you can do
this homework if you can make sure that
we're actually seeing the right things
you're supposed to see we're actually
learning on them properly and we've
actually done our homework minutes in
response I think we will be much better
off to stop the attacks they're actually
getting curved so this doesn't have a
bearing on the controls we've put in
place so far it doesn't affect any
viruses as an effect your idea as your
firewalls this is simply a practice that
I believe will be better suited to let
let us find the things that are
obviously getting through the red
teamers here of all tested for that we
all know it so this is pretty much it
this is cool I saw this from a site that
I really should have breakfast because
you know you're not supposed to do that
so I'm sorry whatever site that is thank
you so Britt and really I'm hoping that
this actually gained some traction and
become something that people in the
industry really consider as a really
viable option to help them elevate the
majority of their information security
programs and this would have been a much
better talk so I apologize
but and that's pretty much the end I
mean I will take any questions anybody
has but there's my contact