all right you're gonna go ahead and get
started here see my name is kaya
Westhouse I'm a student at the Ohio
State University and I couldn't discuss
what a dedicated 19 year old with about
60 bucks and some free time and a
passion for cybersecurity to do
specifically EasyPass transponder before
I begin just in general when you're
there you can see signals especially the
device that I'll be using the output in
our lives just make sure if you're
playing out the stop no output spectrum
that's legal because we'll get in
trouble with the communications I'm
going to talk about Hospital cloning on
the tubes transponders and so that's
illegal do that attempting to circumvent
okay it's also illegal I think on
eventually I can talk a bit more about
methods you might get caught the future
if you are going to topple the devices
you can you're not sure they're going to
do these Faraday cage to make sure you
not break down their devices around you
which basically just put everything in a
insulated box wrapped and completely
metal you don't want to break the Vice
in to have you alright so something
goals in this presentation so first
engineering started the scale of our
discipline maybe and so I'm gonna apply
that to radio frequency communications
walking the process of reverse
engineering OneNote device show some
tools have been developed recent years
and I can be applied and then try some
backgrounds to me about how that applies
to toll booth where I'll be just
background how all that process works
and these are the things I'm going to
cover in this presentation assuming that
time so I'll start background of easy
pass get into some athletes that's been
done by other people and I'm going to go
through the process that I went through
this device so there's gonna be a bunch
of engineering this company to
understand all of that to understand the
implications in the importance of it but
I think it's useful to show the reverse
engineering process
I'll show though dissecting the packet
the protocol that EasyPass uses I'll
talk about transmitting interacting with
the system attacks things like that and
I'll take questions at the end so what
is easy fast
it's a tollbooth group that covers most
of the eastern United States so there's
it was formed in 1990 starting oenophile
lots of smaller groups that were forming
in the eastern United States make sure
that the states were interoperable is
you can drive to different states that
use the same device sort of that
infographic on the right shows that
essentially it's a bison windshield in
your car you driving the meter reader
and it is scammed in order to determine
your account and charts probably a total
mountain so specifically for the e-zpass
system they use transponders that look
like in the left picture and I have one
here for Ohio and that's what the
currently in Ohio the gantries as you
drive through they still have human zoom
and but the fast lane all have those you
can sort of see condition about the
trunk on the right appears that
rectangle that's the actual leader so
the total Tollbooth world is sort of
about changing protocols right now
because in 2012 President Obama signed
the moving ahead Congress acted like
basically the last paragraph 11 will act
said that it's wanted that for a
tollbooth companies to move towards like
a natural droesbal or at least national
interoperability this
they want some point all the parts of
the nation to support each transponder
device so that's what all the supportive
protocols looked like that was
introduced 2012
they've narrowed it down to three
protocols since they've sort of been
there that further easy passes largest
of those protocols taking up the purple
if you have a right which 2018 there's
35 million transponders the e-zpass
system certainly lots of activity and
date of the process these so I mentioned
that they are paying down the protocols
that they want come you see the future
this is a comparison between two of the
ones that have become most prevalent
most notable difference on the left side
is protocol the easy pass uses the right
side is a protocol that some the other
states I'm going to use most of the
thermal differences that easy pass
system uses active transponders which is
actually a badly enough they do their
own transmission the other devices are
passive which means sort of sticker tags
they're smaller and they work based on
modulating it'll start reflecting back
there with the reader signal a lot
smaller something else that's important
in that screen is two protocols the EZ
Pass protocol doesn't support encryption
at the protocol level has to be the
application level but succeed at
protocol right it does support stategies
that's nothing so since then things have
been sort of changing sort of condensed
down before like regional groups and the
goal of that interactive
Act was to have my 2016 which did not
occur like many of the companies but
they're working on so things might
change in the future but this is where
things are at right man who's been some
cast research in this area
Nate Lawson give speech in the past in
the conference about basically reverse
engineering a different protocol fast
track which is which was the system used
in California they're now updating to a
60 protocol it was on the right in the
last slide so he did some analysis of
radio frequency but also went deep into
the actual device itself microcontroller
like if JTAG chip reading that's a
really in-depth great reason Tatian if
you're curious about this stuff
he also basically found that not only
are these are these devices scan that's
whole loose but also just generally
along the highway these devices are
scanned in order to blow things like
that and that basically what he said is
that lawyers know that that's that
information available so fast activist
subpoenaed occasionally to get
information about his whereabouts using
the highway transportation and then that
second presentation was given at DEFCON
by guy because his pukey monkey we
talked about privacy implications of
having all these different frequency
devices in the vehicle so stole devices
as well as many other devices output RF
in your vehicle is vacuum so he
basically modified his e-zpass
transponder motive in circuit to it so
that whenever the scanned it was
actually output noise so not only was
the being on the highway but also like
you driving to
I was going off at a bunch of different
intersections and he actually mapped out
where that was occurring so his argument
was that it's a privacy violation and so
NY CLU took attention of that so that's
some of those passages that's been done
in this area so originally this sort of
challenge was given to me as part of the
interview process for an internship
given the first two phases which is to
modulate the RF communication EZ Pass
which basically means turns radio
frequency communications into ones and
zeros and then phase t was to take those
ones and zeros and servers engineering
write scripts sort of output maybe more
human readable protocol phase three
wasn't given to me but I sort of went
afterwards because I was curious and out
of my own research so the whole time I
started thinking all right when we can
listen in on this conversation but can
we take an active role in discuss how we
can do that later
so this great in frequency reverse
engineering is important because our
vices are everywhere they're not always
given most important focus chapter
security sort of like IOT devices that
aren't always most well known or biggest
systems they might not be receiving the
most security attention totus are a bit
more interesting here a bit interesting
a little device to analyze it because
they're associated with money and but
you want to attack if you could save
some money it's not large scale maybe
money operation cuts there's money
associated with it so that's Prince
interest first step of reverse
engineering basically any radio
frequency device is all using devices
have to be registered with the SEC
if they're gonna transmit and so in a
lot of the information that they
registered it's public and to go to the
SEC website and type in like
registration ID so all that informations
post up there is sort of listed
generally it's probably the most
important that information is about
relation time which basically has going
to describe precisely how the binary
data is converted to this radio signal
how you're gonna take that radio signal
work back to the binary data EZ Pass
specifically News transponders so here
are manufactured by a company called
cash so fun reverse engineering in
general is doing a research a lot of the
time so I went to manufacture a website
and browse down and so I founded the
marketing different information for this
specific type of transponder the e-zpass
news is resolved and there's a bit more
information there one hits includes you
know I was on the FCC ID page including
maybe a package size and the data
formats of how binary data types and the
process even before the signal and then
some more information about the
signaling day of a Bronagh beam and we
can look at so protocol I began
searching for that because that looks
interesting and this is on the e-zpass
group they have a page or they work with
each other told with companies and
they're trying to integrate with on that
pagers and helpful information and you
can see there's a link TV on
specification and comes to the cast page
so you name it a story but the protocol
is actually open so registered your
company or an individual some people
looking for licensed licenses
Jews register with them and also the
company that I was doing sprouted for by
the way that means I spend time waiting
to respond so specification is lots of
helpful information so if you're gonna
be reverse engineering other devices
might not always have the specification
but this was a good place to start and
now that I've gone through all this
process it would be it would be possible
to reverse engineer devices without
specification this sort of just helped
with the timeline and moving quickly
lots of important information in a
specification basically just sort of
refines those other hints and clues that
we saw in CID page and maybe Bachelor
information so I'll go through sort of
all these explain oh it's so cool
listen before I talk basically means
that like I said this is an active
transponder so that was its own signal
but it doesn't just end up a beeping at
us while it waits until it's near and
actually EasyPass be here this is a
specification communication sequences
like I said it's before talk you can see
there's a there's a trigger pulse by the
rear there's an optional speaking with a
bit of information and then basically
transponder sends one packet reader
sends one packet and that's it so it's
very simple very quick
we just important when vehicles are
moving fast by to make sure that
everything happens in the tiny vehicle
what is that what's the basic range of
that it ain't no well I mean terms
distance yeah so about a hundred years
so that's when it starts reading a lot
here's how you think yeah so when I was
at when I was like to tension captures
you can see us with a suspected girls
drinking transponder was talking to
spawn spawn through a little bit of all
those involves in the range also
mentioned is the frequencies which is
what the readers of transponder which is
helpful because it
information about where to search for
with our listening device generally dust
within the radio pan for location
monitoring services range of the arts
mail STR which is the SDR stands for
software-defined radio device you can
tune to listen to many different
frequencies is 24 to 17 66 megahertz so
915 megahertz is your smack in the
middle back range so yesterday our
rtl-sdr that we will be able to listen
modulation type has also been shown in
Vedas pieces of information if you're
not familiar of modulation in terms of
radio frequency information there's come
with a type shot there and amplitude
modulation is basically based on
information wave at the top that's how
you're gonna basically have the upload
what's called the carrier wave so you
can see as the top wave rises and falls
so does sort of outline of the bottom
wave the middle one is frequency
modulation so the frequency of the
signal changes based on it away and the
digital modulation is shown on the right
because you don't always want to show
you don't you're not always wanting to
transfer your information it's an analog
if you you binary data unless you want
to get the right then that's gonna be
different so that's frequency modulation
basically to two values for that top
wave the on-off keying which is
specifically what ye transponder uses or
EZ Pass is either signal it's on the one
or it's off or zero so it's quite simple
which again sped things up in terms of
making appropriate tools demodulation
Manchester encoding it was specified
with the data format and what that
essentially is it instead of just
outputting a 1 for a while in a 0-0
you're gonna combine the data with sort
of constantly changing the signal and
acts as a clock signal so that the
responder transponder the reader of the
transponder stay in sync so every bit
periods can have a transition which
makes it easy to tectum that bit period
is one start I goes love zero starts low
and goes high that's how that's if we
see one of the zero work that's active
we have to decode that person to one
before we can so tools I mentioned the
RTL SDR that's shown on the left eye of
the Raspberry Pi and I have mine right
here she's a small USB device that you
plug your computer hook up an antenna
and there are open source programs that
you can use to listen to very
frequencies a new radio that programs on
the right it's the open source software
I'd really worked with anything related
to radio frequencies in terms of
processing in data and thinking through
data
I'll show those chains later gqr X is
the program that I use that works with
the RTL SCR captured the bra green radio
frequencies that are going on so that
colored data in there that yellow and
red is the actual green frequency
spectrum from left to right is the
frequency domain so left is lower
frequencies right and higher frequencies
as it moves up it's increasing in time
that are going forward in time and
transitioning to red college means that
the signal stronger there and this
particular image is captured around 90
megahertz which
that's basically FM radio - might listen
to in your car being transmitted which
is frequency modulation here q go back
that's like for a second yes see the
sense of Berlin radios does that mean
you're capturing real radio traffic from
out station that was in Berlin no this
is this is not asking job that
information that's actually being
recorded when you're running that
utility and saving things to a file is
called IQ data and so essentially you're
recording of value for the
electromagnetic spectrum at that point
in time so I and Q is a way to express
the amplitude and also like the angle of
the spectrum at that point so signal
signals that you're actually gonna
receive signals as they are transmitted
are real like are a real number but they
can be expressed you know as combination
of complex signals and so a lot of a lot
of the processing it's gonna make use of
complex numbers and a lot of math using
complex numbers in order to process a
good thing for what you want before when
you transmit in order to process it back
to data so basically that picture the
upper right shows a projection of the
bottom line which is the bottom right
the complex signal showing it's got both
amplitude and phase angle going through
time above when projected as it would be
transmitted my device near reveal that
was very confusing for me to try and
understand at home there's no like I
said there's a lot of electrical
engineering that goes into
they're trying to search for stuff
online sometimes resulted in a lot of
advanced math confuse me for a bit but
certainly just after being relentless
and trying to understand it there's a
lot of simple explanation pages that
help so this is that information that
was captured to a file this is a utility
you can open up a bottle in in order to
check it out so time is going from left
to right and then frequency is starting
to glow at the bottom we're going to
hide the top basically this is and you
see that's actually okay so if you
remember going back to this line that
had the communication sequence there to
the finger falls he's fast responded and
then the reader responded with a few
information that Paul said the upper
left that Paul never left there is the
trigger Falls and then this little line
here that's surrounded by data on the
side is the transponder responding and
all this information that occurs on the
side that is basically a byproduct of an
amplitude modulation that's occurring
but definitely the center line is we're
expected in the frequency domain based
on the information in the specifications
we know that's the transponder
responding and then this section here is
reader responding in the same fashion
with lots of information on the side
because of amplitude modulation and then
something interesting that occurs here
is that we see you something that looks
like the transponder speaking up again
so this is the detailed in the
specification hall or
that EasyPass basically responds again
to show that it understood the
information properly to the beater and
if it's not correct them in the reader
will there's something if the device
itself so has some errors he's not happy
that basically wasn't before I get back
get yes
now that view is reversed from GQ RS yes
yes is the DQ axis requests time has
left or right so I mentioned humane do
earlier as utility that I've used to
process this information there's lots of
tutorials online on how to work with
this and I probably the biggest time it
took me for the first project was here
in terms of trying to figure out how to
get that in places like play we see was
these paths communicating and trying to
get to binary data lots of different
steps here Chum this chart
detail to go into but there's plain
tutorials online there you cannot
actually to learn more about this
there's couple different steps in here
including if you're familiar with some
are awkward centering the correct
frequency and then low-pass filter
basically finding that outline of the
wave that we showed earlier okay a few
modulation there's a special ways to do
that which is made easier by the fact
that like I said this device I'm not
keys since either on transmitting or
less per second and then there's so each
of these blocks performs a different
function in shorter chain and you chain
them together to and then output data at
the end and so there's a ground at the
end and also out to file this is sort of
something graphs that I produce when you
process this data so up at the top is a
fast border
yeah it's basically frequency expands
from left to right and strength of the
signal 10 decibels is shown the bottom
to the top so we can see there's a that
green is that's like what the maximum
value was over the over the length of
the files you can see there was a big
spike all right very expected to be in
the middle that ran communication occurs
and then at the bottom that's basically
a signal strength over time you can see
the first little blip it occurs and from
above those like sequences the
interrogation pulse of the reader and
the second longer and wider thickness
the actual communication carrying so FFT
basically there's a processing to get to
that ground the reason we tell is
because that graphic on the Left shown
up there is MC modulation with noise and
you're just looking at the signal itself
it looks really random but if you take
the fast Fourier transform you can see
that there's noise going on the bottom
row but still the actual signal itself
the amplitude modulation really this is
a bit more processing basically this is
showing the reader and the transponder
super-violent graph so up at the top
there that blue is the reader and then
the red is the transponder and that
matches the communication sequence that
we've seen in all the other events as
expected so I got to a point where I was
stuck at almost the data that I wanted
which would be basically clearly showing
the Manchester encoding as shown earlier
and so this is looking at the top of one
of those write wider rises that was
showing earlier I can see like this
alternating like ones and zeros that I
was stuck there for a while that was
tantalizing
but eventually after looking
through it and there we go so that's
basically binary data in terms of the
radio signal police shown after some
processing so that was a very exciting
to us at that point this is that this is
B radio this new craft produced by the
radio that open-source program mentioned
earlier so there's lots of processing
and outlet even more so next step after
chain at least getting at this point is
recovering from the clock how if here is
a ground which we already know based off
of the FCC information and the protocol
but basically getting a program to
detect when when each bit period is
basically how it works what these two
graphs show is that it performs takes
the derivative of the signal and it
tries to find the derivative to zero
because that is where every signal is at
a peak and then it's gonna it's rising
up to that before and dropping
afterwards so that's the peak period so
that this is facially all performed at
one walk that you just have to pass some
parameters and put it into link and then
pass the information on come so an issue
that I ran into is that the reader the
antenna that is basically placed over in
the lanes is very powerful and strong to
show up clearly but the transponder
comparatively can be pretty weak so at
first I thought based off of us and the
graphs I was seeing earlier that the
reader was going to be too strong
there's overpowering things some
captured it's sort of a lower gain
setting my STR the usually not in
complaining it but because of that
transpire I wasn't strong enough so a
stylus and captures well the nearest
Tolman's to us are on the Ohio Turnpike
which is sort of it goes across
the stage my Mason captures one day
while going up for Thanksgiving back to
see family and that stayed up north and
then figured out some of this and then
way back down captured again this time
if more information as you can see just
that like very small little rise next to
the peak is the transponder
communication middle and it's barely
above noise levels so that's that's
we're not gonna get much out but this is
much better so this is this is actually
one of the the captures that was
originally given to me though I
basically using my own or Menard
captured my own make sure I was
understand things correctly that could
be done but in the middle is the meter
on the size is the transponder you see
the transponders definite little noisier
because that's it's scaled up to fit
that size but it's definitely a lot
better after capturing that
identification we actually have
something run through there so at this
point after dr. Bellamy radio work got
everything to be modulated so we have
binary data unpacked into Manchester
encoded Manchester encoding and there's
basically I only happen it provide but
we have the file that the information
that we need to be processed so at this
point sending away from new radio this
is more about a process from the Packard
which I did with some c-plus velocities
that's what I'm most familiar with so
the rotor script basically to cut
transmission down to the specifically
the actual communication sequence can
convert that Manchester encoding bikes
all the way down to bits so it's just
256 bits or two bytes is one packet and
then they stop that information that's I
said point to the protocol so in that
specification that I mentioned earlier
it specifies a couple different sections
like you can see there's a factory fixed
agency picks there so then there's the
act sections and actually change each
and there's a air-pressure code at the
end on the branch to picture the file I
made is underneath you specification
sort of clearly mapped out in my mind
way to expect everything numbers
milliseconds on the left the top here oh
yeah those are that's it like Oh
actually so part of the specification is
that the manufacturer sort of set some
fields as fixed but some of the sections
are it's up to the agency on the side
now can be used so that's listed there
so that's one sections with variable
length because of that so basically easy
passage group has decided what some of
the sections are going to need and all
the sudden there's all the states have
been and have to use the spec according
to that so I was trying so side the
specification was some information but
there's those reader programmable
sections as well right
specified so I was searching through
again that research aspect trying to
comb through everything I can to find
more so search through the sitemap
there's an easy pass again the document
that's posted or to help with combining
other
Oh agencies that lists basically for
every like time entry and exit point
along all the Turnpike's there's there's
like an agency code for basically each
state that it's in and then there's a
closet code for that point and then it
lists a lot of the magnitude but the
most important thing there's a plasma
code that we can start searching for in
the data when they actually have strings
in there the 31 character oh this is uh
this is describing just like in this
file itself
but this is just this is a father that
used to understands the information this
is an extra specified McCracken there's
plastic codes which we know that based
on my needs to pass enters and exits it
automatic attention council we assume
that somewhere that my information was
going to be a genetic code other places
to look for up information is there's a
file descriptions that EasyPass chairs
or basically sharing files in there out
of its daily yes her shank buyouts in
between the states so there's
information in there like the skin type
time things like that that we know must
come from the transaction if they can
look at start searching for a bit fields
in the transaction so the current state
of the nigh sectors that augmented mine
packets within like a caption file split
the packet of data fields output of the
human readable forms there's an error
code and the protocols and then check
that make sure everything matches up
it's a correlate some fields to
interpreted meaning like one things that
I found was there's others codes we
could be able to type search more in
common with a packet so but I have
captures from Virginia and Ohio that I
confirmed that the show like the vehicle
type but certainly other agencies you
know other information in there and then
this utility to happen with has bad news
there we go
there's about reading in all of the
files that it cost us music radio visit
we can eat Sierra's searching through
file on time to find ones and zeros and
the proper pattern and none of the
specific pack bank finds it checks the
error code everything is correct the
different sections so we can show this
easy pass this is a toll collection
using unit as opposed to test units
standard relationship now as opposed to
simply different types of transponders
for like trucks comes from Ohio she was
a serial number which astronomical is
listed just on the barcode of the device
so we usually is now that's listen to
the document what that means
blocks this sort of ran out of time to
sort through all the binary data that's
shown in there I'll talk more later
about how I know that there is at least
Plaza you know like with the entry and
exit point in there also transaction
time you have the sort of anywhere hurt
I I didn't
all right so at this point I sort of
completed first two phases that was
ready give it to me but something that
sort of popped up that might mean
basically what I was talking about
possibility is that same guy that at
least this rtl-sdr versus the schooling
sheep listening lights found the USB VGA
adapter that you might be driving for
and you basically make an output since
you're right into a screen whatever you
want or whatever tiny screen if you can
doesn't properly filter the digital to
analog converter inside then it sort of
leaks radio frequency spectrum that you
can completely control so this stuff
that thing interesting to me is about
fifteen to twenty dollar my city to buy
this is the transmit side between the
SDR so when I hit in order one of those
so I could play with it so when I
picture the right is showing that the
Creator you didn't imitate GSM which is
phone towers GPS just like that well
it's not my research yeah ironically not
I was so they told us if you're gonna
present with featured a year and we have
HDMI my laptop and I was I really that
have the VGA adapter but music cuz I'm
using it for the demo of the
presentation that's what this is signed
by another adapter but cuz I think my
pls the R times utilizes the sound card
because of the frequency so I think the
high frequency of each it you know
bandwidth the VGA and y-yeah
part of that will chew uh oh yes
something else to mention a stop that is
so use the USB 3 which on it's usually
round it only goes up to around one
hundred fifty megahertz er samples the
second but this device is properly
filtered so you can rely on harmonics
and their frequency spectrum the output
all the way up to with at least where
job where GSM is that cell signal that
the Creator was transmitting was also
with 900 megahertz range you know but I
could also use it so that's a picture of
the range in their minds across the
spectrum so again this is going back to
that amplitude modulation that's shown
that's usually protocol and what we see
is that basically how we get from I
would take the two signals and get to
the model signal Bob modulated signal
bottoms and that found the processing
basically this multiplication of the two
singles together then you multiply that
top carrier wave basically it's just
height its amplitude by the variance of
the middle weighted so thankfully that
means that implementing this in the
radio it seemed a fairly simple but
further basically going the opposite
direction developed data signals this is
the original meters that are used by the
e-zpass on the left is like the big
devices in some entries but also we've
just been searching on their website and
found that the Bison right which is like
a pocket reader I guess that they
utilize for field work sometimes so
essentially we're gonna we can create
that device in the right to cheap low
adapters dollars plus measure this is
the new radio code for basically going
from the verse from data to greater
frequency so the process was I take the
data or the packet that I want to
broadcast and then put it through this
processing set of blocks and then
outputs to file samples that are going
to go into yo the awesome that I felt
okay it's all of this must be the BGN
after this you create a single radio
frequency it up come on believe desire
so I adopted the uh
provider code just a little bit not the
major is that make it except signed or
unsigned data and then hatchets period
already had you've only done output on
the red the red the green Channel blue
channel only red was enabled and I just
patched it trying to increase output
strength I have putting out all three so
this is a result this gqr X again
capturing rtl-sdr
showing as you can see there's some
information showing up right in the area
we want not here 15.75
so this is just this is just a simple
interrogation pulse is showing up but
successful so every wanted to be it's
the interrogation positive and this is
the actual packet being Robbie has one
of those pictures is from yeah so I felt
okay one of them is from the actual easy
pass reading I asked to see the
difference because we can clearly see
that it's modulating information
correctly if you're doing one but in DIF
that I know that you can't see believe
those two pictures is that one of those
is captured a different game setting
than the other so the actual helpless
Frank Oh yes--of NFL 2k is very weak so
that's basically like scale to the same
level that was earlier like much wider
from the easy patch meter so that's a
big week and because of that that's a
myth basically I make sure can't end on
the publish a picture just showing a
jumper wire before
and and like I said modifying into the
blast on all three channels at once and
still only that's drawing but thankfully
I can solve that so I didn't actually uh
bought these devices yet or testing them
but left is a filter or the specific
frequency we want a picture of the right
is a amplifier so the filter necessary
because we can amplify the signal this
harmonica if you have even stronger
really artists are transmitting an area
they don't transmit in hit some
attention it you don't want so both of
these devices around $20
so I mentioned forty lakhs cost a bit
more you combine three spices somewhere
in that your dog really completely yeah
so now we can really make system one of
the result of that the protocol itself
doesn't protect against any replay it's
officially capturing I captured liked
you know to communication sicknesses in
a row and the data that was on the
transponder the end in the first one is
what it out boil in communique second
one so there's no time collation going
on anything so it's trivial to clone
these devices Lawson I mentioned at the
beginning investigated California toll
system basically said that this is a
maybe interesting because like we said
lawyer so that sometimes subpoena
that's all information to search for
where people work so if you want to tend
to be the place of our app you can start
writing your information to maybe a car
drive by and say you're at this totally
this time you can do been committing
this crime it's not one that was his
interpretation of a clubber possible
attack vector and it's something else
you could do not even completely a drive
exact this is you want then your
transponder
test exactly how much data is verified
by the reader
you can maybe try using using
not easy to use there's one for a lot of
tests and many new factories you know
just not charge for that you can see the
different transponder types are cheaper
I can pretend to be other vehicle class
maybe the charts glass also I mentioned
there's a lot of code entry and exit
point and start changing those and see
the pair Heisman was originally scanned
or could just trust what's on the device
to make it seem like you're only
traveling no one told moved in instead
of six along the Turnpike to save money
that way so before I presented this
presentation though this is I would make
sure I was going to get developers
sharing all this information so that's
my problem
slide alternatively the benefits of
becoming your ass because I call EZ Pass
and they're sort of hard to express just
college in the research that I was doing
and trying to find something what's
going on but after four or five times
being forwarded I got to head tech
manager at EZ Pass one of the executives
that's charging basically all the tech
is very inaudible and also time very
understanding and very open having
conversation which is very relieving
it's me make sure trouble had a very
knowledgeable conversation it's
basically EZ Pass is aware of basically
establish this protocol in the current
world so the protocol was you know
enable of sometimes ninety six of the
big development in Hades so back then
they were that's this wasn't necessarily
yeah the almost interested them in
security but since then they have turned
focus to it they are aware that it's a
very simple protocol basically something
else we discussed is I mention that I
ran out of time when I was working on
the project as part of the internship to
find some of the air tests completely
searched through the data fields but
like I said there's an entry and exit
points and the time basically confirmed
those are both present in those program
full sections there's two reader
programmable sections one of them is
used by specifically just like the for
total information
entering the next thing that the other
the other section is for there's other
devices they're going to be scanning
like you can just drive along the
highway or out you have traffic
information things like that they might
change their also so it was just
interesting to hear basically an awesome
some of the protocol decisions made from
from easy passes of viewpoint why it
shows things essentially they understand
the protocol simple to sort of then keep
it that way because keeping it simple
and having an active transponder makes
it really easy then actually scan the
device and make sure that a person it's
time for you that it takes for car to
drive by simply some of the other
transponders that are passive are less
reliable scanning or more difficult scam
you install more expensive equipment to
be able to read them properly and you
know stall to gantry's and overhead
passes to make sure that places are read
properly but when you have a simple
protocol and and I can transponder
that's a self battery very easy to make
sure it scans properly you don't have to
rely on the other Vesta that they use
when this fails to sort of background
which is licensing so encompassing
network like discussion of possible
tackling them is they rely on that even
though these devices work a lot of the
time they don't work on a percent of the
time so occasionally when you go through
its neck I've scan properly this
happened to us when you're driving for
you hasn't yet I think because we like
moved around the transponder didn't
leave its own basically we just have the
attendance again the intendant's again
at that point but if you go through and
it doesn't scan properly then they rely
on the license plate scan so even if
you're using a clone one one they're
relying on that while the person goes to
become if charges are going to there
there's two eventually your devices and
scan broccoli at some point and then
they're gonna go up license plate find
out the vehicles wrong and start
searching it out from there so it is
possible to clone and use these attacks
but they're still important too
it shows that the osmotic a is
transmitted by sources very recent
release 2018 can work for protocols
beyond just what the creators shown
really be applied to basically any
protocol that you want and then just
lowers the barn an interview or that's
really the most please take away Chris
presentation is that for if you utilize
these two point on devices and it just
makes it even easier investigate any
part of the RF spectrum both in terms of
knowledge and the money required to
attack the system investigators CSI time
can you step out I understand this is
okay what i was submitting with east
basket zack beast i found also this
someone else who had done concurrent
research basically around the same time
as me i'm and released
use USRP which is a type of SDR
equipment which is more expensive
viciously wrote code to do some similar
stuff but the USR be what makes it
different is because it's more of a
dedicated device I put MSRP up there
because it's more expensive drastic
spending dollars for that doesn't
necessarily bar my troop lower than
getting an actual EZ Pass reader itself
but I still think what I've done is
important because again it's much
cheaper but something interesting music
would do that device is basically you
didn't have to capture go file and then
process the USRP you can go off when it
receives a burst transponder so we sort
of responded meetings to venues the file
and also he went through that
specification that I did but I went into
a bit of further analysis than packing
fields and I'm going to keep doing that
until I make sure that I've got
everything just curious so like I said
further announcement packing data by the
important in the future maybe combining
all the functionality into one program
instead of having GRC portions in
portions to let it's more contained on
one thing and that would allow combine
receive the transfer at the same time so
that it's not two separate functions
it's a transceiver one of course now
that we've confirmed that these devices
can work in tandem to the first your
other devices to protocols I'm gonna be
interesting to see whether the Optima
pulsing K which is much more recent it's
going to catch on like the RTL SDR has
which is there's lots of tutorials
online so be interesting to see what
happens with total interoperability in
the future because it's shorten flux
right now protocols they are something
that some that I thought was curious
when looking at future
might use theirs there now they have
been a sort of a call for Casa Vista
security considerations so I think
they've seen some of the houses and I'm
sort of like goofy monkey was
circulating the light the privacy
considerations
there's thinking about what I thought
that did some change in the future so
the things I've learned from this if you
do not research easily other parts of
Health existing lurch that anything I
think it was very interesting the ways
that he's that's why I'm gonna give you
the data not necessarily like like
approach also yeah I would you have any
questions feel free to come back leave
or talking in one during this conference
I'll be around
yeah there's any questions yes is this
vulnerable to the replay attack but we
should be able to actively put in active
signal get the idea of another easy pass
reader and then like bonuses yes you can
you can trigger the other the other be
there and capture the information that's
not it put that on your reader and then
go to the toll booth before they do you
sort of like stolen their information
and it's gonna fail for that yes so
there's that 2015 is when the packets
turning 56 bits that's what's kinda
dated every time and so the reader just
transmits exactly that sort of 56 bit
section of the store so whatever that
156 midsection the output that's in
store yes
do you think the easy pass system cares
so that their transponders can be cloned
at this point I resist the cost of a
variant of mitigate
basically my understanding of while
talking with the insect is that they're
aware of it and they they haven't done
research into like whether or not it's a
concern I don't think it's been
prevalent at all or it's not enough an
issue that it's causing any issues for
that so the discussion of the cost of
may be up
the readers and the infrastructure would
brought up in turn and during the
conversation like what's gonna happen in
the future as the protocols trying
becoming interoperable so I just
something to consider that updating is
considerable price but I don't think
that's preventing from trying to
reasonable odds to this they seem very
well aware likely to detect any
microcontroller programming and what
platform you prefer I've gotten again I
got time all right check out the esp8266
it's about three four dollars it's a
full Wi-Fi capable chip and it you can
program it using Arduino code and
favorite seat blah blah and it's good to
see a young guy who's into C++ is
everywhere