good to go my name is Brian I'm here to
talk about a ship hacking data on the
open seas
it's the description side this is kind
of a primer for the ICS is in systems
that you find on and most boats being in
cargo ships cruise ships and private
yachts that kind of encompasses
everything it's kind of standard across
no matter where you go the idea is the
same the networks are kind of similar
they just have different functions for
what they do
so disclaimer not so much for this
weather I mean there are some things in
here that I'll show you
no one authorized access to ships or
ship systems was done for this
presentation no ships are harmed or put
in distress and public sources were used
to perform all the ascent as well as you
know the as well as all of the
fingerprinting and everything else
needed to be done for the for those
systems I'm an overview entered
introductions obligatory Who am I
we're going to talk about the maritime
industry it's kind of let you know you
know why this is kind of so important
and hasn't really been talked before so
I'm going to touch on that we're gonna
hit the networks that you find on this
on the ships as well as the conclusions
and questions at the end Who am I
Brian Olson I'm a volunteer for project
gun sway engineer past work for the
Marines I've done some cool stuff for
them as my hobby kind of brings me into
the maritime industry I like sailing I'm
an amateur tactician and I do a lot of
the regattas and what have you and it
just kind of encompasses i'ma die like
churning through data messin with all
the systems onboard and kind of you know
it introduces me to certain people and
it you know it just kind of rolls from
there
volunteer organizations I'm the Calvary
if you're not familiar with them they're
there to kinda you know put a check on
our trust in certain technologies
they've done a lot of work in the
medical and automotive field and then
project gun sway is kind of a branch of
that we're kind of focusing on maritime
that sector we are a grassroots
organization our home is Nova labs in
the DC area we share the Calvary's goals
we're like I said we're kind of a fork
of what they do some of us are members
of the Calvary again we have day jobs an
IT but we focused on the maritime domain
and we follow their disclosure standards
so if there's a bug or something that
comes out or vulnerability again we
followed their standards and pop it
through to the vendor and what have you
before disclosure so part of the reason
why I'm also going through this is kind
of a primer this is going to be our
first year at DEFCON with a heck to see
maritime village so if you're looking to
get hands-on in any of these networks or
these tools and you're at Def Con stop
by and we'll be you know there to help
you out thanks to you know fathom five
cyber Marinette with the maritime
security ports the calvary knows a big
help and getting everything together so
we're actually bringing you know
networks a ship network you're gonna
have all the you know set a is GPS
sensors what-have-you we're trying to
roll in a capture the flag game with it
so we're coming up with a point system
and how we're gonna do that with the
separate teams based on how that network
is set up and like I said if I get hands
on with any of these tools and poke
around stop by and be happy to do that
so what's at stake if you're not too
familiar with the shipping industry
about roughly the size of the u.s. GDP a
19 trillion dollars and goods are
shipped annually it's ten point three
billion tons of cargo
so everything is going through cargo
ships the environments at the sake you
know if these cargo ships you know hit
rough waters there's something wrong
with their systems oil spills can happen
you know
cruise ships again tipping over losing
individuals human human life is at stake
I give the PII with all the systems
onboard credit card transactions
what-have-you all that data is stored
locally on that ship private yachts and
that sector again you have people on
board celebrities that they basically
use that as their home right or they run
out those ships all their information as
well is at stake as far as guidelines
for what's being done with these as they
travel through there really aren't any
which is kind of shocking so there's
people trying to lead the charge and
carnet develop standards but as you move
from one country to another there really
isn't anything that you can have as far
from a security practice to be held
accountable for a lot of the systems
they're just thrown out there because of
ease-of-use if it ain't broke don't fix
it it's kind of the mentality whether it
be on the ship or at the port and you
know if as far as security guidelines
training people that really had it just
started to kind of come about and we're
hoping to kind of raise awareness for
that just to get an idea of how big
these ships are what impact they have
just a scale model again a lot of these
ships are carrying a 11,000 teus find
that is one of the bigger bigger ships
that are out there
it's twenty-foot equivalent units are
the big trailers that you'd find
floating around on the back of trucks
and what-have-you so with that movement
that they have right now again we're
trying to bring awareness because that
everyone's trying to go to autonomous
right they don't want to have people on
board they don't want to pay people
security what
have you fuel costs everything that can
be done remotely is you know it's the
movement that they're trying to have
whether it be you know steering the boat
robotics autonomous operation health
monitoring remote support maintenance
robots I'm not sure really sure how that
would tie in but the idea is to have
someone sitting on shore basically
remote controlling a boat or having the
boat kind of take care of itself when
it's out in the open ocean
it seems smart but the same time with
the security posture the way it is
there's a lot of checks that have the go
into place and a lot of you know we're
revamping that needs to be done to a lot
of the systems that are on board so to
go through some of the networks that are
on we're going to start with the
commercial ships this also applies to
cruise ships I know the containers there
it's kind of our forte but then again
you know container ships are also in
this realm communications you have your
satlink radio a is ship to shore basic
communications to where all your links
are going over for internet GSM and
everything else that needs to be done to
communicate with the outside world your
navigation again that's gonna be your
radar whether GPS information it's going
to tell you where you're going
who else is out there or you want a
collision course all of that info the
ship network this can be if it's a cargo
ship your timekeeping customs
integration email cruise ship it might
be you know your POS systems credit card
transactions or what have you the crew
network is generally they like to say
it's separated but we find out in most
of our talks that it really isn't where
you have you know the crew has their own
email Wi-Fi wired and get out through
other communications the network
backbone a segmentation of devices from
your sensors to your tcp/ip
infrastructure
your ICS HMIS PLC's where all your
sensors lay with the cargo ships in
particularly if you're loading
instability there's gonna be your head
effect basically where the containers
lie where they're going to be placed
what's tracking inside the containers
weight of the ship
balancing it so it can safely make it to
its destination a lot of the updates and
remote access to is on a separate
network and it's it's kind of surprising
the way that works in a way where those
systems are generally always pinging out
to home that being the manufacturer so
if there is an issue you simply call
them up you give them a PIN number and
they could log in remote push updates
whatever they need to do and a lot of
time they do that without anyone on
board knowing private yachts are a
little bit different it's again geared
towards you know the luxuries that you
have at home ideas kind of the same the
smaller boats generally don't have a
whole lot is the bigger boats too but
you know it's it's starting to get there
because everyone wants the once the
latest and greatest crew network so
generally they try and be separated but
again we find that's generally not the
case you still have the you know the ICS
with the HMI the PLC's the sensors your
navigation is generally the same
communication again ship-to-shore radio
AIS and your ship network it's a little
bit different like I said or this you're
gonna have you know your entertainment
systems or cameras or cloud services you
know you I want to open my blinds from a
tablet I want to steer the boat from my
tablet there's a bunch of systems on
board like that which you know you will
be able to kind of interact with that
these guys like having around so the
maritime protocols Nemea
183 is kind of the old standard it's
released in 1983 it's a one-way talking
right so it's it's not bi-directional
very slow
updates infrequently and it's just the
way the past there are systems that
still use 183 it is still accepted it
has to be because like I said if it
ain't broke you know they're not they're
not going to fix it to me a 2000 or n2k
is the newer standard it's faster you
can daisy chains that systems together
so it's all in one giant network as a
sensor spitting out information
these tools are pulling everything out
pulling what they need and so basically
they're giant you know sharing
everything across one network you'll see
at the top right hand corner that's
basically how then the connections are a
bunch of T bars with the sensors coming
up to whether it needs to go to you know
chart system or down to your GPS antenna
in the middle right there you'll see all
the sensors sitting below that yellow
line CPU in the middle and then of
course you know all your you know charts
your screens and all that data for you
to read sitting right up front
below that is basically just the the
formatting and the message it's all kind
of standardized and I actually tell you
what system it's coming from how its R
it's read for each device time arrival
so there's checksums and checks that are
taking place has a can identify errs
basically what the Vice what sensor it's
coming from the length of code and then
the field data right so if you're
getting one from a GPS system we'll have
courts sometimes I'll have coordinates
and what-have-you in there which will
interpret and pop that through your
actus or your chart display so as we're
talking about that to kind of put that
in the picture form I'm a visual person
so I like pictures and describing things
that way you have your HMIS you know
your windows and our windows and linux
embedded shoreside networks network to
ship-to-shore third parties and your
serial conversions you'll see here again
your sensors right they want to know
no the engine monitors the battery's
transducer
transducers how fast you're going
temperature of the water barometers what
have you all the way up you know linking
that into the tcp/ip bus if I want to
have it on my laptop
pull it on an iPad take my display with
me around the boat see what's going on
pull the Wi-Fi from the you know satlink
that's coming down and all that jazz
email music whatever you need to do so
taking all that in account if you're
sitting in front of a system like this
and you're trying to get in you're
trying to manipulate what's going on
you know what attack vectors are out
there well your points of interest again
are gonna be the wireless right it's
going to be you know cell phones or just
the wireless link in general the Wi-Fi
on the ship if you're there it's gonna
be if you're on board you know the
server farm our servers rec reco or rec
servers that are on there the SATCOM GSM
links that are coming down heading in
through the network through that there's
also the laptops on board a lot of them
are Wi-Fi I'll show you later this
morning I had something set up where
basically I'm pumping all that data
through a wireless link and picking up
picking it up on my laptop to kind of
manipulate and have and go through it
you can do that on both the TCP I tcp/ip
network as well as the Nemea network
with the sensors themselves the GPS
again jamming spoofing what have you
with that as well as the sensors down
below as well if you want to take
control of you know the fuel sensor let
them know you know you have to refuel
you have to keep refueling or an engine
you know it takes steerage of an engine
give that false information as it's
reported up into the ectis those are all
things that you can
and you know disrupt on a normal day so
methodology when taking this on I mean
just basic basic basic is the way to do
it there's a lot of low-hanging fruit on
these networks you'd be amazed when you
go through if you poke around on a few
of them you know network scans brute
force web scans then manual scans and a
lot of it also it's just you know
fingerprinting taking a look at it and
then just open it up the manual online a
lot of default credentials are out there
outdated operating systems they'll tell
you a lot what goes on basically I just
open up the manual and the installation
guide and whatnot OSINT so if we have a
ship right and we want to take control
or we want to see what's out there
rule number one easiest way to do it is
see what I mean browse the web and see
what's out there so this side my ship
comm is basically Facebook for sailors I
don't know if anyone's familiar with
that it basically it's if you want crew
people out on cruise ships people on
working on cargo ships people working on
private yachts a lot of times they'll
you know you'll free account the log in
there I'll tell you who they are where
they are where they're gonna be the name
of the boat they're on where they were
last all that information is you know up
there again this attack vector is gonna
be you know a lot of you know phishing
emails you pull their information some
some of these guys are again you know
the technicians on board usernames
passwords what-have-you as well the ED
effects system so this is the system
that's used when ship comes into port
right it's gonna be kind of tied to port
security
what containers go where
what containers get offloaded where
where they're placed on the boat right
so I just want to I want to say
last year late last year this system was
hit when someone decided to load all of
the lighter cargo below and put all the
heavier cargo on top just to mess around
right they ended up you know figuring
that out halfway through it took a lot
of time and money I kind of get that
fixed but then again you know this is
kind of the stuff that's if you play
your cards right and it's just fairly
easy to you know physical security and
the port side head in there manipulate
that data and have them load it
offloaded the containers where you well
there's actually another instance of
this where they were quote-unquote
shipping bananas but really they were
just you know loading drugs into the
into the containers the cartel would
basically have them offloaded container
certain port they'd roll up with a truck
and just roll off right just because
they were messing around at the artifact
messages within the ship this one I like
to call sip and smile this is actually I
did this last week I was down in Antigua
doing the Caribbean 600 just kind of
sitting on the patio looking all these
boats come through talking to the crew
and social social engineering was you
know a big part of it drinking beers
having having some Romans some guys next
thing you know you're sitting next to a
captain of a ship telling them you do
some mighty work and you're taking
pictures of a server farm alright I mean
it happens it's it's easier than you
think
down there everyone's on island time so
they're all relaxed not really don't
have really have their guard up yeah the
shoreside internet and marina Wi-Fi is
also a place to go a lot of these crew
that are coming off you want you know
with their personal devices the key down
there is Wi-Fi right there on a separate
network there
coming down here they want data they
want to connect to their Instagram
connect to their Facebook make Facebook
friends they're gonna be on the Wi-Fi
networks down there again which are not
secured at all if you need Wi-Fi you
just look at the chalkboard behind the
bar and that's your access to the Wi-Fi
the ship Wi-Fi now the bigger yachts
might have their own they might still be
using their GSM networks but a lot of
smaller mid-ranged vessels down there
they'll actually piggyback off the Wi-Fi
of the marina the yacht club the bar
that's sitting right there as well so if
you're on that one network and you want
to throw a scan out there more than
likely you're gonna hit one of those
mid-range shots that are out there
trying to piggyback off that Wi-Fi and
the last one is a pick any door any door
so if you look at the top photo you see
that line of boats on the left a little
white line that little brown spot is
actually at the guard shack and I want
to say 80% of the time he was just so
sleep so if you want to go walk around
and check these boats out no you're more
than welcome to if you want to take one
of the Dinks floating around with the
keys in it and just kind of head around
to the other side I'm sure no one would
really mind cuz its island time alright
so one of the other systems is gonna be
the vessel tracking system we kind of
talked about this it was the AIS and the
radar that's on there this is what
you're basically going to use to track a
system it's course it's heading the name
of the ship they look the location as
well as you know who else's are who
else's around that ship and and yes this
is done through not only with the radio
towers local to shore but also through
the Sat links when they get farther out
so that's what this kind of picture
describes you'll see here that when the
ships are closer to shore that AIS is
bounced
around between the ships themselves
again letting them know if they're on a
collision course what their direction
where they're heading what have you as
we go farther out ashore it's done
through the Sat links satellite a is
where that information is then brought
back to a you know software of site on
land where that is then productive
prayer projected online for people to
view there are sites out there free
sites Marine tracker AIS tracker there's
a bunch of sites out there if you want
to open it up now click on a red
triangle you'll be able to bring up a
description of the ship again where it's
going where its words been sometimes the
cargo that's onboard information on you
know its home port all of that will be
on there for you again openly and free
available for everyone again this is a
so if we take that in account of what a
is does and how we're gonna kind of take
a look at that so a is data is exchanged
in two forms right it's your RF VHF
protocol and your online providers and
software so what you are able to do if
you want to you can spoof one of the
online providers and basically change
the routes if you want to you know have
a ship you know pop up on your marine
traffic net and send it to you know
through Texas you can do that right it's
just a simple RF this is widely known
it's been published before just sending
a you know radio frequency out there
telling them you know what's going on so
that information is relayed back to the
online provider you can hijack the
Gateway again and move ships around
again all done through radio RF VHF
signals so the global marine and
distress this is going to be also
communicated through VHF this is
actually a separate system
that you can interact with as well this
is basically used for in emergency
situations it is required to have this
on board based on the size of your ship
it'll bring in all the safety
information weather reports that's all
done through this system right here
radio beacons if you're in distress
again easily manipulated through the VHF
and radio signals with your you know if
you have a system that can put out data
like that so now I get into the GPS
system or a global navigation satellite
again this is going to tell you you know
kind of where you are on the map the
United States has their own against GPS
is kind of widely known Russia they call
theirs GLONASS European Union came out
their own Galileo and then China of
course has their own system that they
use for you know GPS or tracking the
graph underneath kind of shows where
that is at what frequency is it's done
we're generally on the all the private
stuff is on the l1 band or on the lower
level it's on the right-hand side in
that frequency frequency range the l2
band you'll see that the l2 g2 is
basically reserved for government only a
lot of that stuff is supposedly
encrypted but you know I hear that
sometimes depending on at least in the
past they've had some possibly not again
and then the other one is going to be
the l5 band which I don't really know
not really used I haven't really done
any research on that so I'm not really
sure exactly what that is used for so
with the GPS and the Sat system that's
out there again there's a communication
with a fleet to land
it's an always-on connection again this
is going to be one of those attack
vectors that we talked about
position conditions it's going to be
your instant access with your internet
emails calls whether telemedicine remote
operation of hardware again vendors
pushing out updates without anyone
knowing calling up with a pin if you're
out at sea and saying I have an issue
with the system this is the pin number
guys sitting behind a desk go look for
that you know ping coming in
consistently pick that system and then
be able to log in remotely and take care
of it so that communications always
going back and forth again we talked
about the the safety system with the
search-and-rescue transponders and
location beacons so all that is done so
it's an open connection generally always
on always available for you to take a
look at so if we're trying to kind of
manipulate the GPS there's a few ways to
do it
jamming is probably the easiest way you
can spew RF at the same frequency used
by the satellite on that L one-on-one
band that we were taking a look at
earlier generally not that hard
depending on how big your antenna is to
kind of determine how close how far you
have to be for that you can spoof GPS
it's a little bit harder probably a
little bit more costly if you want to go
that route out of the box you can always
develop your own it has been done
believe Texas Texas engineering lab was
able to do that spoof GPS for automotive
and GPS with the cars and driving this
system right here such a simulator just
basically over on the network if you're
not familiar with GPS the way it works
is it's triangulation so there's three
separate signals coming down to the unit
or the device what-have-you
what they generally do is just throw in
like a fourth signal and by doing that
you know let you know that you're 100
feet over here 200 feet this way you
know basically manipulate you know where
you are with those
systems on board and if you're caught
sleep and then you're gonna be in for a
rude awakening combining this again with
like some of that AIS stuff is you can
start to see the whole picture you kind
of understand how all these ships are
starting to you know collide run aground
those reports that you see in the news
whether it be possibly someone's
sleeping I don't know or someone you
know messing with the data that's coming
in on those bands in those frequencies
so this is what I was talking about
earlier so if we don't have excess so
let me slide back one and the third
option again is injection into Nemea
Network so if you have access to the
network and you can inject your own data
this is kind of what I was hinting to or
earlier I kind of set this up this
morning in the hotel with the GPS
antenna you'll see the Nemea network
sitting behind the laptop basically
where it is I'm sitting in Columbus but
I'm putting putting in packets into that
Network because it's to weight talk I'm
letting you know that I hey I want to
make my way all the way to Greenland and
that's basically what what you see on
that chart on the left over there if you
zoom in you'll see a line going from
Columbus all the way up to Greenland and
it's just the track of where we are they
see the heading over there 26 degrees
magnetic it's kind of the direct path to
Greenland
then Nemea messages over in the middle
and then the Nemea generator you'll see
that in the middle the Nemea generator
is a open source tool I believe it's a
German tool it's available on the
Internet the charting software is called
Expedition
it's a paid-for software that I use for
some other things but a good
alternatives open source freely
available is open CP n you kind of get
the same same results from that there's
also some back-end foo some kind of
encapsulation that's going on there the
way that this worked basically what I
had to do is I have a USB connection to
the name
and then that little device sticking out
just to the left of the monitor is
basically the Wi-Fi access point so I'm
spitting data in through my laptop back
into the Nemea Network and I'm reading
everything via wireless basically
encapsulating everything manipulating in
a little bit just so it's easily
readable and then at that charting
software is picking it back up based on
whatever whether it be the comm court
not in this case let the wireless access
point I'm just sending it to a to the
system itself the actus display so with
everything that we talked about before
with the AIS the GPS the radar all that
is brought together on actists so this
is the system that when you're standing
on the bridge that you're taking a look
at your autopilot all that configuration
is done on the ectis your charts your
RNC's your en sees your digital chart
displays as you're moving into app or
you can zoom in I tell you how deep it
is on there if you want it and you know
fathoms what-have-you it'll change it
based on your settings that you do have
you'll see on there on the bottom
left-hand side of the screen track
triangles or other ships the names are
popping up you'll see on the right-hand
side that all the information on
whatever ship is selected is up there as
well as the radar overlay where's those
circles flown above so this is another
system again if you're on the network
and you have access to the network
that's worth taking a look at worth
taking a scan simply because of what's
running behind the scenes a lot of this
stuff is running on a separate server
it's not proprietary
I'm you'll see the requirements for some
of these are wind a lot of them are
windows nt-based if you run a scan again
it's just things that pop up that are
this mentality that they have ain't
broke don't fix that it's you know
throughout the industry you'll see the
one of the systems right here on the
right-hand side uh
linux-based I don't want to say a
company name but the Colonel's you know
was has been supported was it since 2020
a few years now 2014 something like that
and this is again just open source
taking a look at what systems are out
there pulling down the manuals from the
website and they're just kind of doing
all my open-source research on what
needs to be what what systems are out
there what's running behind the scenes
and what's required for some of this
some of these insults moving on to the
one to last attack vector is going to be
that sensor control units that are down
there there's gonna be a hill seized
this is one that we did in a
presentation a few months ago
[Music]
this is actually an engine control unit
that we were able to manipulate that
we're gain access to and manipulate and
control the this information coming in
and out of gained access to you'll see
here that you know everything is
passwords are easily readable am route
again just basic basic information an
undocumented version of drop air
outdated just low-hanging fruit so again
with those sensors all of these sensors
also have a web server
I generally attached to them a remote
panel you can log in take a look at
[Music]
walking through this panel with the
admin credentials
everything is unencrypted it's over HTTP
you are able to upload without logging
in you're able to upload and that config
files on firmware updates the default
pin
I just by taking a look at the code the
firmware on the system itself came out
to be one two three four left is the
default a failed login again
it's that five digit pin you got to call
them up they'll take a look at you know
what's pinging out what system it is and
they'll call you back with you know that
credentials or unlock it for you but
it's so if you're not on the ship if
you're not on board and you need access
to this network cue show then again
google searching what are the primary
satellite providers Sat systems for this
just a quick search in there brought up
the ship sitting in the middle of Paris
I don't know if it's one of those river
cruises or if it's that restaurant that
kind of sits over there
I don't know but without even logging in
without even touching anything I'm
picking up all of those of the
information as far as the satellite
profiles where it is their frequency the
antenna what it's listening on the modem
there's a version number port name if
you look at the right-hand side all of
that information is viewable without
logging into the system which is going
to be your network if I don't know what
the internal LAN looks like I just click
on network information that will give me
you know what what's going on outside as
well as you know all the IP space on the
inside if I want to mess with this ship
and kind of change some values with the
antennas and take a completely offline I
can potentially do that I'm pretty sure
also that these guys didn't change the
default password it's just a guess
all right yep so there's a few other
ones out there as well this is just one
of the providers in Merced as well as
few other systems out there kind of the
same thing with some manipulation
viewing the information the page itself
and just browsing through documentation
you'd be surprised to see how many
systems are a outdated and B just have
weak passwords and
we credential verification so looking
forward what we'd like to do is examine
the related products the Wi-Fi router
accessories the HMI software some
rebranded devices that are out there
because like I said everyone's kind of
coming out with everything else you see
a lot of these controllers are put under
separate systems right so if there's a
rebranded controller Auto mask in which
is one of the sensors that we worked
with you actually find that in you know
your Cummings engines Yanmar engines
what-have-you so it's across the board
just doesn't affect that brand in
particular I need to clean up the neat
Nemedia injection
I had it working it is a bit finicky I'm
hoping to do that with some of the other
sensors that are out there as well not
just the GPS injection theoretically it
should work for all of them but then
again it's you know the manipulation
getting that to work with stopping that
information from being processed and put
on the network from the actual device
itself
explore the VTS and the a is kind of get
that working kind of bring the whole
picture together explore the GPS that is
a whole nother realm of hard work and
then the other controllers that are out
there different sensors fuel sensors
battery sensors sensors that rely on the
bottom of the boat for cleaning right
that put out you know because there's
that will clean the bottom of the boat
keep it running smoothly so there isn't
any resistance in the water as it goes
through there's a you know a plethora of
sensors that are out there that you can
manipulate take a look at and then
potentially that's worth so conclusions
what kind of what we went over I mean
it's the number one story man everyone
that tells us it's not it's not on the
same network it's not an isolated
Network all the documentation says that
but when you go out there and you're
actually you know taking a look at all
this stuff
the way that people work they just throw
it all together it's just I mean it's
just how it is
and there's like I said that attitude of
you know it's not gonna happen to me all
right
I'm out in the middle of the ocean it's
not gonna happen to me I mean what we
just saw that you know I can view all
your information just from doing a show
in you know query I can log potentially
log into your terminal if I wanted to
you know do that and then gain access
and then poke around your ship SATCOM
turn normal terminals
you know patching again and
double-checking for the week in blank
admin passwords blank admin passwords
are a thing network isolation
you know actually separate the night
networks you know bridge your engine
room the crew the Wi-Fi air gapping
would be a huge plus
highly unlikely it's gonna happen
relatively soon but again you know if
you're going down that route of
automation stuff like that and policies
like that need to be set in place the
wireless access week or blank passwords
again not only for the ship but also
with all the Nemea connections that are
coming out taking a look at that data
that's on board and gaining access to
those devices spin out that Wireless
information and crew accountability you
know these guys walking around their
cell phones on the Wi-Fi network taking
care there's you know kind of men and
milling compromising their cell phones
and having that talk out to the south or
through the satlink as well is one of
the biggest concerns of a few people
that I know of and we've actually wrote
a proof of concept to control parts of a
ship based on that talking through a
cell phone again the Calvary we're
always looking for people with interest
in the shipping industry if you have any
ideas or input or just want to be part
of what's going on feel free to shoot us
a email check out the blog
and contact us so we also like to thank
Brian cetera who couldn't be here he's
kind of our leader in a project gun sway
I could follow him at at readout Steven
curling at ob1 666 just gave a talk at
HEC Lu he kind of focuses on the private
yachts I know he's trying to do a lot
with the auto pilots right now another
good person to follow if this interests
you again Nate Adam and few of the other
people I'm the Calvary and again the
b-side staff and the companies fathom
five Sabra marinara kind of help us get
getting that stuff ready for the for Def
Con coming up to bring to you guys to
kind of mess around with our questions
yep I'm sorry no not yet
yeah I mean like yeah I believe it I
believe it but no we haven't done
anything with that yet like I said we
all have jobs like an IT this is kind of
like a hobby for us we have you know
people a group of people I think just
like we're like five to ten strong ish
across the country a lot of our guys
work in socks so it's all kind of
after-hours type of stuff that we're
doing this this type of work but you
know that's why you know if you help us
out shoot us an email more than happy to
hear from you
any other questions yep well sometimes
again so a lot of times like when I'm
when I'm going down through Norfolk a
lot of that stuff is turned off you know
they're coming up they use that again
they have that a their own frequency for
the GPS what have you but a is a lot of
times if it's on they'll I mean they
could communicate if it's turned off and
it's you know a lot of times you'll be
driving out and you just see a boat pop
up out of nowhere you know it's kind of
at their discretion of what they want to
do but yes if they do use it then yeah
they some of them they would have to yep
I'm sorry there was so I don't know what
the cost is associated with that I'm not
sure how widely used it is which would
be my first question trucking ships
based on satellite where in you know the
VHF is kind of you know the standard and
running the ground I guess I just have
to see what the market is you know it's
at the end of the day it's a business
decision right like if these guys got to
pay extra money to do that then you know
it's probably not going to happen but if
it comes to a point where a unit can
make them you know understand where in
the long term it will save you money
after a while I'm sure you'll start to
see a shift over to that any other
questions