all right we're going again so do we
need to use both mics one mic okay okay
hey let me see that this one okay so we
don't need to hit them all right yeah I
have it on right here okay all right
sorry about that so yeah so um we're
going on when you're going on from the
Morris worm let me turn that off that's
a little loud so going on from the
Morris worm there's a lot of good
write-ups out there go read it it's a
good history lesson so gonna talk about
UNIX passwords a little bit here the
myths of the makeup of your password the
full name the home directory and then
the shell good alright miss I'd get this
wire way here okay yeah so the Etsy
password follows where they store
historically the passwords are they and
the user list of the system in there as
he says David said it's broken into
various categories the one that we're
interested in is that encrypted password
field there and you'd also be interested
in the UID field because that tells you
what privilege level in windows world
that'd be your red like red 500 or 1000
something here
UID 0 is route and all your single digit
or load ones are your system commands or
your system which is on that and usually
you're like five hundred or a thousand
whatever and above are your users but
for the passwords this file is read to
the world almost universal across unique
systems well that's fine because
services need to know who the users are
what the encrypted password it is all
that's great exactly and that's okay the
password is hashed and stored in there
so you it uses the crip function it uses
DES which is fine everybody loves DES
all right but now that honestly
originally it was using des they did use
a saw so that everything that get hash
to the same string every time but that
hash was based on the time of day
converted into digit converted into two
characters and then it was appended to
the string okay but because people could
read it they could then dump it down
crack it blah blah blah well was that so
solution to that was they actually took
all the hashes move them out into a
separate area secondary file most UNIX
systems use Etsy shadow that's where
it's stored only very slick privileged
accounts can read that file and edit
that file so standard users can't read
anymore
great they didn't move crip to md5 sha-1
sha-256 and so forth to make it a little
more robust down the road file
permissions not going to jump into this
too much but just to let you know that
the following Siskin or a falling
directory access control lists are very
robust ish on unix you can restrict
stuff down to the owner the group and
the everybody else in the world if they
have privilege or not to the files or
directories
do they have read run a read access
write access execute access not going to
go into a lot of education on this just
understand you have all these different
layers in there but the ones that we are
concerned about our set UID and set G ID
then there at the bottom ilk the set UID
bit is set on a file on a binary or a
shell script something like that in
particular that means when you run it
you're actually running it with the
privilege of the person who owns the
file not of yourself but who owns that
so if it's a route owned binary and you
run it you're running it with the
privilege of root so if there's a buffer
overflow committing that execution
something like that in there you can
make advantage of that and gain a root
shell run a root command something like
that and oftentimes these planners are
set incorrectly with the city ID bit set
because of lazy sysadmin or you know not
knowing you know things like that so
you'll often times be you'll get a shell
on a UNIX system and you'll see you'll
do a
you'll see a demoed here in a few
minutes but you'll run a string that
looks for files that have that set UID
binary set or flag said I should say on
the binary and then you go oh okay I can
run this as route cool so let me modify
it a little bit we're in this route and
that we've escalated privileges so
exactly we'll show you guys what that
looks like here in just a minute
absolutely and by the same token and set
GID means that if that's set on the
binary you run it you run it as the
privilege of that group not the user but
for most cases that are ISA ficient as
well depending on what the privilege
level of that group is sticky bid is a
very odd one not all UNIX ease UNIX
systems use it but it basically means
that if that said on a file or binary or
directory only the owner has the ability
to modify that no matter what the other
permissions are only the owner can
modify it
it's a weird scenario and you'll see
you'll see sticky bits more and like
CTFs and stuff I don't I don't ever see
that in the real world but if you're
doing a CTF that's nothing I actually do
you see it in like trusted Solaris back
in the day some very strict versions of
selinux and things like that you'll see
it set file permissions go through this
quick some interesting files out there
if you get onto a system search and see
if you have read access to these files
it's the password if nothing else just
to get a user list off the system
anything under var log or var mail those
are great var log on the UNIX system
pretty much every single service that is
running on their log set directory and
they tend to be fairly open on
permissions in a lot of cases you can
see their Pesce logging see their some
of them are gonna be locked down like
your auth log and stuff like that but
you're gonna get a lot of information
out there farm mail if it isn't lockdown
you can read their email if they're
using a mail server on the UNIX system
that is look in the home directories for
dot history files dot bash history files
dot forward files where you can forward
emails around dot our host file which
we're gonna talk about that one are very
good I mean actually any dot file on a
home very useful if you want to search
for sent UID files or set GID files
there's a command up there it's very
short it's just fine space the directory
on a start and space - per
space slash than 4-thousand that is the
bit flag for set GI set UID then that's
print or - LS there's other options on
the end now to list them all out we'll
take a quick look at a demo showing that
later during us some stuff trust
relationships I think this is the last
history slide really here so bear with
me
you have heart commands which are very
useful think of them as really old
versions of SSH honestly you can connect
into remote systems with our HR exec you
can log into the system you can of
there's a very steep Isles you can you
can maneuver around things like that
it's it's an old dinosaur version
essentially of connecting to the system
right so the nice thing about it is
there's a feature in there called the
dot or host file or host ID quit file
both serves similar purposes think of
those as your authorized keys on a SSH
server you set up an SSH server you set
up your authorized keys you can connect
into it as your user without providing a
password anymore well at the same thing
here if in your our host our hosts file
or a host of equip you put in the IP of
the system and you put in the username
that you want to allow access from that
IP that person can then log in without
providing credentials well there's also
a nice little feature in there if you
have the ability to create this or it's
already created if you do a plus space
plus that means any system any user has
access to log in with that password if
you find a way to write to a remote
system through some sort of exploit and
you can write the dot our host file with
a plus space plus in there then you can
if they're running ssars HR tech you can
log in as them without a password
anymore yeah they don't need a password
you just
NFS is that their version of shares UNIX
system shares network file system the
main thing here is that a lot of older
versions and some modern versions I've
seen as well have the ability that when
you mount a remote filesystem and
it allows you to write to that
filesystem as whatever user access you
have on your own system so if your user
Adam it tries to write it as whatever
your UID is over there if it can some
try to restrict this try to do various
things but the big one comes in is if
your root on your own system and you try
to write into that file system it didn't
used to mind and it wouldn't let you
write as root they came out with a
concept called root squash which then
took if somebody's trying to write in
here as root okay you now have privilege
of 1000 or something you dummy user
account and okay we're going to go ahead
and see some demos on that let's go
ahead and see through the are command
one here we're gonna that is a little
small
alright okay so we're so he's
essentially which is which is a network
mapper and essentially opens but you
know what what ports protocols and
services around so he runs on map pcs
that are exact and different things are
open on this box so he's gonna run our
PC info to turn to see okay well we know
that some of this is open let's see what
information will you pull down so our PC
info the name of the host that we just
scan we see uh we've got absolutely so
we have we see our users are set the in
offense all these different services on
there one thing we're gonna do is just
run our sis info it tells you a little
bit of information about the remote
system if it's there great there's not a
lot of information even pull from that
but sometimes you get up time you can
get a ferry so that all information
gathering then we run our users that let
you know what users are logged into that
remote system at this time the nice
thing about that is you can possibly use
that to get a user list off the remote
system in this case it just shows a root
is logged in over there so I'm just
gonna try to see if by chance they have
a our host file setup Hydra an rsh space
dash L the user that I want to log in as
which in this case is gonna be root let
it catch up there I think good thing
about a new Bernie users to is
oftentimes you can spray weak passwords
you know winter twenty nine same
passwords like that using that usually
with a pool so so I just did the R SH -
L
and then I pee it let me in no password
I run I D it shows our UID root and GID
root groups root and if you look at the
not our host file there it has a plus
space plus in there granted this was a
little you might not see this very often
out there you very well might depending
on what level security minded the
developers are stuff like that one thing
I will call out here is UID that is a
user identifier it's what level
privilege you are it is that UID I said
up front whenever you're running a
command or logged in on UNIX system
you're running as well whoever your UID
is there's another concept called EU ID
which is effective your UID it's sort of
saying all Windows system when you run a
command as I saw you can't do this
things they run as administrator' sort
of that concept it's like okay I know
I'm really Joe Blow but I really want
you to run it as this other person so
give me an effective ID effective UID
that will come into play a little later
on a different demo a quick little in FS
demo here same sort of thing we run in
map upfront just to see what services
there are ok Wow I was almost smoked but
I ran it with the NFS script or the show
mount script for in a fast it showed
that there were exactly we then we run a
show mount - e against the system that
tells us what are the in offense mount
points that are exported in this case
it's slash so they're exporting the root
filesystem
star means to everyone so it's not
restricted to a particular IP address
something like that so let's go ahead
and mount it you will notice that due to
the prompt I am rude on my local system
here so go ahead and mount it a CD into
that directory so MNT remote I see the
remote filesystem I CD into the root
home directory to show that I can I echo
something into a file so he's
essentially writing to disk and writing
to this host that he's now gain
unauthorized access to that he has no
business being on somebody because they
had an open manifest here yep and if you
actually look at the very bottom
you see test txt that I wrote to and
it's owned by route route at this point
so yeah so I wrote as that user great so
ok other kind of application flaw is out
there historically there was some really
nice ones like telnet D sad Mandy which
is system administrator daemon for
Solaris Morris worm took care of took
advantage of some of the sin male ones
there's lots of other ones out there
actually in map and the report scanning
tool has a code variety there's not
other version that has essentially an
interactive mode and it was installed on
on some versions of Linux and if if you
found that nmap was owned and run by
root and the interactive mode was
enabled you could essentially get a
privileged collation shell on that box
because again they installed it anything
anybody would mess with it and we've
learned better since then there's other
things such as PHP my admin or tomcat
urge a boss or Jenkins you know these
are all old software versions and web
apps that we see out in the wild even to
this day that are very easy to take
advantage of to escalate your privileges
my personal favorite exploit from this
era of unix is the telnet D or F user
attack which targeted certain versions
of Solaris 10 or open Solaris up into a
certain release point which was very
common very widely used across
Department of Defense a lot of telecoms
a lot of is just out there a lot the
amazing thing here is that you tell a
telnet space - L space and then in
quotes - f BN or - alpha root or some
user account on that system and then the
IP and hit enter and it says thank you
here you are with a shell of that user
now I don't understand fully the
background and understanding of how it
actually does that in there is it just
is a sort of like a heap overflow ish
thing I believe but either way you could
do this on any old Solaris 10 box up to
Brown
a big level a torso and you're gonna get
shell if you uh and as old as that
sounds I've actually seen this in the
wild I actually just saw this in the
well two weeks ago at a customer site so
this is this is still very real this is
still very valid this is still being
seen out in the wild and this comes back
from the days of again lazy sysadmin and
or trying to make it easier to do things
to do tasks and stuff so if you think
it's hard to get your Windows
administrators to update your Windows
servers up to the latest Windows 2016 or
whatever try to get a eunuch segment
update their server it's near impossible
especially once that you have a version
of Slayers on there they tend to keep it
on there they don't want to reinstall
that if it works yeah you leave it so if
you find a node version of Solaris odds
are it's not gonna be patched to that so
all right handing off to you for a
little bit okay so let's look at some
you know so we've gone over some history
of goners from historical issues and
things so let's look at some real world
privilege escalation okay so I've got a
quick note for y'all this is gonna sound
a little cheesy but just bear with me
occasionally throughout this part of the
talk you guys are gonna hear me say oh
so we've got a shell so when you hear me
say that I need y'all if you could just
just yell out turtle power as long as
you can can y'all do that for me it's
easy this edge it's very we'll see we'll
see if you do it okay so let's test it
so so we've got a shell all right
and the reason we do that is because
it's pen testers we do a shell dance
right when we get a shell in a box
oftentimes you know we've been working
on it for several hours or sometimes
we're really excited so a lot of us get
up and like you or you know I'll play
some good some good you know rockin
music and stuff because you finally
gotten somewhere I finally got a
foothold in the network so it's across
that's true so it shouldn't be dancing
that's why I rock okay so you've got a
box we've got a shell all right what's
the first thing we need to do right if
we if we get unauthorized access to a
box first thing we need to do is get
away the land we need to do enumeration
right you need to figure out things like
well Who am I
who's this Activision I was able to get
on ass who else is logged in who are the
super users what kind of info do I have
access to what can I do you know from
where I'm sitting and where can I go you
know can i navigate throughout the the
file system things like that
and to do that we've got several
different commands from Quran you get on
a box you can run things like you named
Ave it suppose use a kernel version and
there are little bits of kernel exploits
out there that are one click and done
you can run env that gives you the
environment variable PWD is the working
directory that tells you the current
directory you're sitting in who am ia
user history you can check the history
for the current user cat bash history
tells you the past history that's been
on my box and we recently discovered but
your text Prudential Zama gig and our
customer site for from checking bash
history and because of that we were able
to find another password we were your
plans by privileges and gain full root
access on the on the machine
couple of commands through - L I'm
Kennedy sudoers that tells using the
suitors file and then Kennedy password
like we've talked about that tells you
additional users so you can have and
build a user list that you can then
passwords to pray I'm in charge of
things history or CH history depending
on who the shell is that you're running
under so and Who am I is common on
almost every Linux based operating
system but most UNIX I don't remember it
being on all of them but ID yeah so as
with everything we like scripting right
we've got we can do that manually or if
we have a way to upload a script to a
box we can often script a lot of this
for us right and then give us some more
information system great enumeration
scripts that are that are really popular
that we like using as like linen um and
scripted local Linux and enumeration and
privileged escalation checks we've got a
Linux proof checker it's intended to be
executed locally on the Linux box and
tells your basic system info search of
common through that
vectors world writable files things like
that and then UNIX professor check it
this one's from pens nests monkey he
does a lot of a lot of great stuff on
this blog writes a lot of scripts and
things and it's essentially shell script
is do the same thing it checks for
simple privilege escalation factors all
these kind of do very similar things use
them all check them all out you know
somebody give you more information than
the other school of scripting ones did
very similar things for UNIX back in the
day have since been deprecated long ago
but if you've been around long enough
you've probably seen those yeah right
Tiger stuff like that so so what is what
is one of the scripts look like right so
we've got a shell all right so we're on
the show and I run Who am I and I see
I'm just easier sack right I'm in the
sec directory and I can't see it either
route okay so I'm a little preview sir
can't really get anywhere so we're going
to move to see dev sh m right and we
worked out of Devon SH M because when
the box contributed anything in that
file gets wiped and it's pentesters
relates to be very clean and how we work
we don't wanna leave artifacts on
customer systems so we're gonna sit in
Devon SH and do our work checking that
we're actually in that file and then we
need to check to see if we've got W yet
and what that essentially does is lets
us the files from a web server you can't
see it here very well but there in the
lower right hand corner right there we
have a web server set up on another
screen so we W get our privilege
escalation script and pull it down on to
this box in dev SH M we make an
executable CH bond and then we run it
and dash T for this particular one is
thorough so it runs all sorts of
thorough tests and everything you see is
scrolling by is all sorts of pertinent
information that's on this box and then
there'll be a few moments of awkward
silence as it finishes but as you can
see just kind of looking at something
from you know some important information
there you
got things like software versions and
I'm scrolling up here to kind of give
you guys some more information here how
do you do to do to do to do to do to do
okay so cron jobs there environment
variables current users on there okay
there goes school to bus yeah so Laura
scroll so throat tester enabled that
tells us the current kernel that's on
the system which version of Linux is
being used right the name of the system
you know can sometimes I can come handy
other users that might be privileged our
current user that's on there right now
it dumps group memberships CPU info
dumps that's a password for you
let's you know if there's other users
that have admin access because it may
not just be root right there may be
other users let you know like right down
there it says possible sudo pwnage user
pin VI it also lets you things unless
you know things like user sec may run
the following commands on shrek which is
the name of the box
mark wat can run a user bin VI with no
password so that's you know handy any
information and now again this is all
information that we shouldn't have right
we shouldn't be on this box we should be
able to get this information but this
will help us you know further move up in
the in the chain of command as it were
and escalate our privileges so that we
can ultimately get full access and full
and authorized control over this box so
I'm going to move on to the next slide
here
I think one other thing there that I
mentioned earlier about running commands
cleaning up after yourself on UNIX
systems a nice little trick if you're on
the command line put a space in front of
your command if there's a space if the
first character of the command is a
space it doesn't get logged to the
history file yeah it's good yeah so if
you're if you're trying to do things
like that that's a good yeah it's a good
tip why but it works so another simple
we use the search point right as you get
all that information from from one of
these scripts you can oftentimes feed
these software versions the kernel
versions and things you have into this
database that the final defense and
security of paraded called the exploit
database and what search point is is
it's essentially a local version of the
exploitative base save your machine so
it's a command line tool you can run it
it queries the DB and says ok here's
some common exploits or common passive
attack that you can use to try to
further type machine as claim proves
these things like that and then I
screenshot there we're gonna talk about
dirty calendars talks here in a minute
but if you search Boyd's makes it dirty
with you all the different kernel
versions and privilege escalation
factors they're just with the name dirty
in them and then on the right it tells
you the you know where the the exploit
is being held so then you can just
search boy - and mirror it onto your
machine review the code and execute it
that way we've already talked about a
user ID a little bit they're really in
simple words it's just users we're gonna
file permissions as well as owner UID
and GID when executing a file program or
command one of the dangers of running
set UID like we talked about with nmap
so we have a shell so we have a shell in
the box and I've already run some basic
commands kind of figure out where we're
at
we know it's ubuntu box we notice 1404
trusty
maybe we know that I'm the user daemon
you can go into route so we're not super
at you know an upper super high level
can't really do much so we're gonna run
a command to look for files that have
the set UID flag enabled and that's that
perm - 4000 have no all there and I
really need to learn to type faster in
these videos and so that tells us all of
the binaries and files that have the
state UID flag enabled we say there was
a Zen map things like that so nmap
probably gonna be our best route of
attack there so as soon as that finishes
propagating and again this it's kind of
a slow command so it's gonna be slowing
on pretty much any box you're running on
because it's it's got to go through the
entire file system and look for things
so knowing that end map has that state
UID flag we're going to go ahead and see
you know if we can play with it so we're
gonna use some full path and give us a
version number to make sure it is
vulnerable and it is an old version is
straight one so pretty good chance that
we'll be able to use this to escalate
our privileges to somebody that's not
Damon to make us you know route and then
that's a miss type there we can figure
it out earlier that we have to use the
full ask to run it so we'd use the full
path of a user local bin in map give it
interactive mode now we have the end map
prompt you can't do much of the in map
prompt though as you can see it will do
Who am I you know it doesn't know that
command so we'll just go ahead and go
straight and see if we can get a bash
prompt we do bash - P and we are ripped
and it's literally that simple two
commands on a box that has this old
version of a map on it and I'm now route
my Yi into the root folder I can get the
SD shadow I can dump the users I could
dump the password to crack them offline
I full access to the box with two
commands yeah forever it was in it was
in several versions links forever
side really can't cool in place I
believe it said do not run this as route
right change this and finally people
kept exploit so he's like fine fine I
just remove the feature well just say
that so tying in to what we talked about
at the very beginning with all this
history of UNIX and everything else
because of how you know how bolted
together the software is there are
literally thousands of kernel exploits
out there I mean thousands thousands of
it the screenshot just shows a small
portion of the ones from the
exploitative base if you just type in
kernel you can you know just this list
of all these different Carmel exploits
right so the more popular ones that have
seen media attention in the past been
mem flow dipper dirty cow which was a
few years ago send page and then one
that was released about two weeks ago
called dirty sock dirty cow is a very
popular one it's essentially a race
condition that handled on the
copy-on-write or breakage of private
read-only memory mapping such as mice
calls cow so it's copy-on-write the guy
decided to go with it and and he logoed
it and and and made t-shirts and stuff
because he thought it was really cold
any versions of unix linux prior to
these are probably vulnerable and iike
model versions part of these are
probably vulnerable and what it looks
like in action is this right here so
we've got a shell i think this one was
from he said turtle power so we got a
shell i think this one was from a local
file inclusion on a web app so we do our
basic enumeration you know we go okay
let's check you know let's check the
kernel version and ID and all sorts of
stuff here and we see that it's Ubuntu
1604 but it's got a kernel version of
403 one so it's you know it's probably
dirty cowboy based on the information
that we've got so we double check to
make sure that W get is on there so and
GCC which is a compiler
both Florence it's all along the box so
again being clean testers we go into
deficit hm we've got a webserver already
set up so we're W
getting the exploit from our web server
which we're essentially pulling it down
and placing it on the box and there's
many versions when you go to dirty
cotton engine you'll see there's several
different versions that he wrote we're
just using the canal route dot C version
other ones will change the the route
name and things like that so GCC coyote
will compile it for us and on many of
these exploits you'll see compiling
instructions written within the exploit
code so be on the lookout for that it's
been compiled successfully we've run it
and we are now route literally with
again three commands because they have
an old kernel version we've now
escalated privileges from a low-level
user that had access to nowhere so now
we are ripped
dirty stock is one that just came out
let's save a two to three weeks ago this
gentleman found a bug in the step ad API
and he seems to infect all snap ad
versions prior to two to three seven one
essentially you can use this with this
Python script that he wrote there's two
different versions to again gain
unauthorized root access to a machine
that's essentially what the code looks
like he finds the R in a socket file he
binds to it connects to snap Abe snap D
API
he sends the payload and then you've got
access to the host
there's each video there of a different
group showing that and they you know
change the name of it or whatever we're
going to be released in our own kind of
version over here soon
video I should say a video that demo of
in here soon just gonna give you guys a
better better idea of it version one
requires that you have internet access
version 2 does not version two just you
can do it locally so take a look at that
google it and you'll find it and you can
see the differences between them it's
probably gonna be really really
me for the next few months because not
everybody updates their snap D version
right it's just none of those things
lacy sysadmin or you know busy or
whatever however when he went to the
team behind that instead half on this
vulnerability they were really really
quick to patch it and release an update
and push that out so so good job on that
so go do some final thoughts talking
about the walls being around for a while
unique sentiments love their up times so
software that nice passion okay
her level then he's upgraded yeah I got
a three-year DUP time I don't want to
get rid of that right so its mentality
thing I know I used to be one so some
additional resources got mill wrote a
blog and that's kind of the the King
macdaddy back in 2011 on basic finished
for losers collation it goes to the much
more depth than what we talked about
here so I lay belad first because that's
the first thing you should absolutely if
you're interested in links frivolous
escalation read that block Jake Williams
didn't talk besides the Gustus a few
years ago and then tradecraft security
weekly also did a brief talk about it
and now hopefully somebody can add us on
it if you need practice out there
there's all kind of resources out there
phone hub is the one I used to recommend
to a lot of people because you could go
download various for a boy exam os's
burn horrible VMs almost always the
Linux or UNIX base there's different
capture and capture the flag style
competition things CTL some great ones
as well
Metasploit abou is one that's been
around for a long time as roadable
mister over to Matt is playable three
which is actually windows-based I think
it but um these are these are
intentionally vulnerable yes that you
can put on your machine and you can
practice these attacks and these
enumeration takes a dance safely and
then when you break the Machine you can
just revert it in front all right so if
you want to something a little more
aggressive a little more challenging
heck the box is definitely the path
you'd want to go
some people have equated it closer to
like the
Oh ACP level beat himself with that
systems going again so it's a really
good practice for practicing pen testing
or capture the flag in general but also
testing out your unique skills learning
from mistakes learning from the way that
they are intentionally messing up on
their because these are things that
people see in the wild at a lot of times
now they're yeah sure these are these
are boxes that are made in fact one was
made about a year ago that showed the
the most recent credit card breach oh
they basically recreated that in a VM
and said here probably something so you
can recreate you know how that curb
intercept so so yeah it's really good
environment you have to have to get
access to it so you have to actually
hack your way in but it's pretty it's
pretty easy for your low levels so once
you're in there you know they've got
free and paid tiers and you can just
practice on it it's absolutely worth it
I do it I do it at least once a week I
get on hack the Box you know to keep my
skills sharp and stuff so one other
thing you can do is just go download the
old versions of Ubuntu download ode
versions of Red Hat whatever if you have
access to it apply code versions at work
something set up a lab and run something
with that because the thing is here
you're not trying to if you really get
into these like heck the box phone huh
but although those are intentionally
vulnerable now you're looking at the
ones that are provided by the vendor to
hear it this is it can you steal hacking
what version what is the old kernel
version there that you can still exploit
what shares are in place stuff like that
and then finally if you buy has any
questions for us we'll be up here let me
go ahead and click through to the
contact slide that's our contact
information so feel free to reach out to
us you know hit us up on Twitter YouTube
we both have channels and the email and
stuff so feel free if you have any
questions comments concerns Pat hey we
sincerely appreciate you guys coming out
and hearing us ramble for awhile and
thank you guys for playing along and
definitely sitting through the technical
difficulties there late