[Music]
a
you
[Applause]
hello people hello so this thing here is
called Game of Thrones does anyone
watches this skin Wiccans yeah okay so
there are some people I I don't really
watch it and they made me watch
summaries of seven seasons for this talk
because we're going to make a comparison
with the EU political landscape and Game
of Thrones families today no no spoilers
spoiler free you shall worry not so the
reason why we thought that this is a
good idea is because EU topics are not
so popular to listen to and we really
think of 2019 as the beginning of a
perhaps a period in which Europeans can
get more hooked on to these topics stay
more engaged and follow a bit more
episodes of this real-life version of
Game of Thrones so today we have a
little plan for the next 20 minutes or
so we will speculate a lot about the
shifts in power balance in the EU
influenced by a new European Parliament
a new Commission obviously breaks it and
the impact we will talk a bit what is
the impact that this have on the way we
do advocacy in Brussels for digital
rights then we'll give a small overview
on the topics that we are planning on
focusing on in the next period yes but
before we dive into the details I just
want to give you a quick overview of the
main events this year so the next thing
to happen is on 15th of May where the
lead candidates have livestream debate
then of course very important the
European elections taking place between
23rd and 27th of May in July beginning
of July the European Parliament will
have its very first session
and we'll then later in July elect the
next Commission president so decide who
is going to sit on the Iron Throne
then in September October there will be
hearings of the appointed commissioners
and in October there's going to be the
vote by the European Parliament on the
next Commission scheduled for end of
October for now at least this brexit and
then first of November the new
Commission is going to take office so
but why are we actually here standing on
the stage talking to you about the
European Union well Andrea and I we both
work for European digital rights
Adri and short and you can call us the
small folk of Westeros if you wish
because we represent civil society
organizations from across Europe right
now there's 42 human rights groups from
20 countries that are member of a tree
and that defend rights and freedoms
online so in Germany you have for
example the CCC or the utilization of
the attack oh gosh v Wikimedia and also
fsfe that are members of a tree and yeah
and we work in Brussels I forgot to say
I'm I can repeat that so we work in
Brussels and we were funded in 2002 with
a mission to protect promote and uphold
civil and human rights in the digital
sphere in 2001 we got this Brussels
office and we sorta say increased our
cooperation with the European
institutions needless to say we work in
European level and the last years we've
been focusing a lot on monitoring
legislative initiatives and assessing
the risks that they pose for freedoms
online and then intervening discussing
with policy makers about how we can
give those initiatives of better shapes
for a right so obviously 2019 is a very
special year for us because the new
European Parliament will impact who we
talk to when we want to talk to the
Commission will obviously affect also
the legislative initiatives that are
being proposed and breaks it will have
an impact too on the way we discuss on
[Music]
now yes a year with a lot of changes
overall we will see a lot of plot twists
betrayal murders revenge mainly because
the families the political families are
changing a lot Kirsten will get a bit
more into detail about that but they
will change names they will change
constituencies there will be a
battlefield of shifting alliances pretty
much breaks it will come with 75 MEP is
leaving the Parliament the British ones
but some of those remaining seats will
be reallocated to other member states
and in the end we will have 46 less
seats with seven hundred and five
members in the parliament standing
regardless of brexit happening the
right-wing political spectrum will see
an increase in seats bit more of the
overall aspect to this we will have 40%
or it is speculated that only 40% of the
members of the Parliament will keep
their seats the current ones which
states like France seeing even a higher
turnover only 25% of French MEP is
maintaining seeds finally we were having
our digitalized champions leaving the
Parliament such as Yulia red emeritus
arcane young Philipp Albrecht so we will
have to create new alliances with
perhaps
more and more of the pirates joining the
Czechs and the German ones we're
expecting four or five new people in so
as a disclaimer it's important to
mention that all of our speculations
today are based on knowledge that we got
from our personal contact with the
institutions but also reports as the one
shown here from the European Council on
Foreign Relations and public polls and
so on take it away yes so basically we
thought it would be easier and more fun
to well we would find a new way to
present European politics and the
upcoming changes to you by comparing the
biggest houses the biggest groups in the
European Parliament with the big houses
of Westeros of Game of Thrones that are
currently fighting for the Iron Throne
aka the Commission presidency so if you
are not following Game of Thrones then I
think it will still be understandable so
please don't leave and for those who are
following or who are trying to catch up
with a series
there will be no spoilers we promise so
in the European Parliament until very
recently you had two big groups that
formed some sort of big coalition the
EPP and the snd so the Conservative
Party and the Socialists and Democrats
that held a majority and well you could
compare them to the previous alliance
between the Lannisters and the
Baratheon's and then you also have a
couple of smaller houses the Starks the
tag Aryans the Bolton's and the
Greyjoy's but yeah let's go first to
King's Landing the seat of the EPP so
the EPP is the Conservative Center
rights groups and the German city would
say us
politicians they are part of this
political group they have held the Iron
Throne for the past 15 years so they had
the Commission presidency for a quite
long while and the EPP much like the
Lannisters they good at political games
and they do anything to protect their
family so they want to show unity even
though there might be yea disputes
cooking below the surface and yes many
polls indicate that the this grand
coalition with the s and D will no
longer have a majority in the next
European Parliament so that's a big
change and the EPP is well they might
lose seats currently they have 217 and
they might be down to approximately 189
or even down to 182 if the Brits exit
and then also what was more recently in
the press the Hungarian party fetus is
suspended only for the time of the
elections and they might be back
afterwards because well the EPP cannot
afford to lose more seats right now
let's jump to storms and home to the
great house of the snd so the S&T
reunites the Socialists and the
Democrats and is center-left in
orientation and well in Germany the SPD
members are part of this group and like
the Baratheon's they once held great
political power but they are slowly
disappearing now so most polls project a
loss of seats of 40 40 seats less is
quite a quite huge they could even lose
54 seats of the British members exit so
it's basically the group that suffers
most from from brexit now let's move
Dragonstone yes where the house of the
Liberals is located so either which is
short for the Alliance of liberals and
Democrats as a centrist liberal group
and it has been a strong force a long
time ago and while the german ftp
members are part of this and in the past
months there were rumors that this
centre liberal group would fuse with
McColl's lovely public Amash so the
center might actually be back as the
third biggest force in the European
Parliament at least then it has also
been announced already that the name
Alda will disappear so this whole
central liberal group will be called
something else and macomb just like
Daenerys Targaryen they look like nice
people and they want to bring peace and
unity to to the world but actually well
below the surface it's they can be
pretty scary and but are a bit edgy and
they both want to fight the populace as
hell the polls show that while they
might be increasing seats then if my
Khan teams up with them from currently
72 up to 95 400 seats so the EP the
European Parliament will be finely
balanced between the three biggest
groups the Conservative Party the the
Social Democrats and the central liberal
yeah so let's move up to the north to
Winterfell home of the green group
so yeah the Greens EF a they unite the
ecological and left-wing groups and the
German business 960 Quinn and the German
pirate Giulia Veda they were they are
part of this this group so they were
really the first ones to alert us about
climate change and that winter is coming
and just as the Greens teamed up with
the
snd before well in the past the Starks
had an alliance with the Baratheon's now
that the Baratheon's are disappearing
they the greens are trying to well they
are growing and they try to defend their
own space with the rise of the
right-wing and extremist groups in the
parliament it's much more unclear how
the alliances will play out and well for
our topics for digital rights it could
be possible that there will be more
cooperation with the centre liberals but
it also depends which ones I guess in
terms of seats they might increase just
a tiny bit the polls indicate five seats
more or well they would say the same
basically with the Brits exit right in
the Iron Islands the Nordic Green left
is situated and just like the Greyjoy is
they're quite split internally they have
members they're quite fond of the
European Union some there are not so
much the left-wing party group
represented by the German d-link
from from the National German context
currently they have 52 seats and with
the UK standing during the parliamentary
elections they're expected to have 55 so
a small increase after brexit we're
looking at perhaps than having 56 spots
these small your skeptics groups are a
very interesting thing to look at for
the next period we have compared them
with the Bolton's
because they have a tendency to do the
dirty jobs of the EPP s being a bit more
cruel a bit more populous than a bit
less diplomatic even in their discourses
individually they might seem
insignificant but
together their star is rising so this is
something to look very closely at the
ecrt conservative reference the FDD
the ENF some GUI members some unassigned
members and EAP n something I will get
back to all of these that I mentioned
are expected to be the second largest
ideological bloc in the European
Parliament over 35% of the seats will be
held by them and this will play an
important role now EAP n what I
mentioned earlier the European Alliance
for peoples and nations Springs from enf
it is expected to form as a group with
representatives from over 10 countries
including Liga Salvi knees Italian
deputies Sal Sal Venus Leah now if this
would indeed become reality EFT has high
chances to be dissolved and ECR will
most likely lose a lot of members who
will join this right-wing extremist
alliance as a group they're expected to
be fourth largest in the parliament and
even perhaps compete for the third spot
with Aldi now when it comes to the way
decision-making is happening in the
parliament in this new context Kirsten
mentioned that des indes and the EP bees
even if they agree on something they no
longer held majority which means that
they need to invite others on the table
to reach consensus
this means that consensus will be more
difficult to reach this also has an
impact on international agreements to be
signed it is predicted that lot less
agreements will be signed because
Europeans position use position will be
more less likely to become concrete now
the group with the majority
with the power to get majorities in the
Parliament will also most likely have
the power in the European Commission and
will determine the president and Kirsten
also mentioned all of them having a very
important unique position in securing
majorities this is why it is perhaps not
too far stretch to speculate that the
power they get in the Parliament could
be traded for a president position in
the European Commission the presidency
has been EPP in the past 15 years and of
course EPP is still a strong candidate
for the European Commission with Webber
if he would be voted down after the U
council proposes him for the European
Parliament there is another strong
candidate the French Barnea coming from
the same ip P so EPP has very strong
first option and second option of course
there's the Social Democrats timmermans
who has been quite popular in the public
debate so far but politically speaking
he doesn't really have any chances for
presidency now yeah right
so what are the impacts of all this of
all these changes on digital rights and
freedoms and on the way that we do
digital rights advocacy so all these
developments definitely make room for
new ways to influence a policymaking in
Brussels and this means that we also
need to find new ways and allies to win
political fights going to brexit shortly
in the short term nothing much will
change because the decisions of the
European Court of Justice still need to
be implemented there and the UK also has
a couple of national implementations of
new legislation such as the privacy
rules in the form of GDP our net
neutrality and so on and they will stay
in place
but with a full brexit in the long-term
the future of all these national
implementations is much more unclear on
top of this there is pressure to
deregulate IT companies because well the
UK needs to find a way to compensate for
the loss of access to the digital single
market and this of course might be very
bad for digital for our rights and
freedoms in terms of the changes in the
European Parliament so what do we do
when winter has come to the to the
institutions so some might think that
now we might need to start talking to
all these right-wing extremists and
populist and your skeptics and
what-have-you but we think that that's
not necessarily the only or the the best
solution first of all as Andrea said as
many old digital rights champions
parliamentarians that were fighting for
our topics leaving the Parliament it
will be very important for us to find
new people there and new allies and then
of course the center liberal group that
will have a king-making role in the next
parliament will also be an opportunity
to create majorities for for our dosas
and the changing political landscape
yeah you can go to the next one no I am
sorry about the National landscapes so
because the majorities in the Parliament
are not so easy to secure nowadays as
talking to people in Brussels will not
be enough this is why advocacy at
national level is crucial pressure needs
to come from the national level to
Brussels also and we know we have seen
from the copyright defeat that young
people care about a free internet we
have seen that they can be active and we
have seen that they quite lost some
trust in the EU
so this means that we need to work
together at a national level to foster
pro-european messages to foster
communication between people and their
representatives and work together to
secure digital rights this is also a
quick shout out that if you do want to
get involved either come to our meeting
tomorrow our workshop on digital rights
or and or get in touch with your every
members in your countries the map is
also on our site that you've seen yeah
so now in terms of substance the
changing political landscape doesn't
only have an impact on how we do digital
rights advocacy but also on the
substance and on the files that will be
coming up so three main areas are first
of all platforms regulations secondly
security and thirdly privacy for the
first topic platform regulation it's
going to be an immensely important and
huge topic of the next term and it's
basically well the question is how
platforms can take down illegal content
and how they might be held liable for
what users upload to the to to their
networks to their well services it
started a bit in the past years with the
copyright and the terrorist content
debates but in the next term this is
going to be a much broader discussion
yeah and the thing is that the
centre-right doesn't really like the big
US tech and so it might it's possible
that there will be more efforts to focus
on the big players which doesn't sound
like a bad idea per se but if the
legislation is badly drafted and if
smaller players and media for within the
scopes and there could potentially be
huge collateral damage for our rights
and freedoms so the main file that we
will be seeing in this area is the
reform of the so-called equal mess
directive which will be renamed I think
as we heard into the digital Services
Act and then part of this whole platform
regulación discussion of course is the
question of algorithms how they are used
by platforms and how transparent or how
discriminatory they are when it comes to
security we already know by now that
terrorism and cyber security are
prioritized on the EU councils policy
cycle for 2018 2021 with the rise of
right-wing political ideologies in the
European Parliament it's not again far
stretch to guess anti-immigration and
surveillance law will be quite hot in
the next period again we're also looking
at data retention being reborn a file
that every members have killed in the
past in the EU Court of Justice the
third thing Kirstin already mentioned
the regulation on online terrorist
content currently this has been upheld
in the European Parliament after a guess
what content filter on on line terrorist
content has been proposed so far it's it
hasn't gone further but the risks is
still there so it needs further
monitoring final thing is a evidence
that refers to law enforcement agencies
accessing data cross-border and this is
a ongoing file that will also be
monitoring in the future yes now privacy
so there will be still of course some
major privacy fights to win currently
there's a reform going on that's called
a privacy privacy reform and that
defines basically how
well the confidentiality and the privacy
of your electronic communications and
then there's also going to be a need
again to defend encryption if we've seen
in Germany recently that law enforcement
pushed for prohibition of Tor and the
German bonus had also discussed the
proposal to criminalize tor hidden
services so that this might be coming up
at you level as well especially since
France and Germany tried to push for
encryption backdoors back in 2017
already so yes so we're nearly at the
end of this talk yes final slide it
doesn't look so good for European
democracy and our digital rights in the
next term but then again I mean we
thought many times before that the end
was near for digital rights but we still
kept on fighting and looking back the
you actually did also some good things
for our rights and freedoms so and then
since the last legislative term we have
stronger privacy rules in the form of
gdpr we have you wide net neutrality
protections and more recently also
whistleblower protections so it's not
all doom and gloom so we've been we kept
telling you how winter might be coming
and now we're telling you that actually
the EU is really great and it's been
doing good things for digital rights and
really the truth is that the EU is what
you make out of it so even if right
wing's right-winger ideologies are on
the rise and even if winter might be
coming it just happens that we are quite
fond of winter sports and just like any
other winter sports
it requires the sports require good gear
and good practice and we've got the
practice so we're asking you to give us
that good gear go out and vote competent
candidates for the European Parliament
so we have good people that we can work
with
and we believe that with our practice
and the good gear that you're giving us
is really we can survive any winter
thank you
one more thing one more thing we have a
digital rights meet up tomorrow at 12:30
at meet up space 1 and there if you have
more questions you can ask us all about
it because well the 30 minutes were not
enough time of course to go into details
so yeah thank you guys thank you
Hey