[Music]
a
you
it's lovely to see you all here this
morning I hope you enjoyed the first day
and I can enjoy the next two days with
us as well a couple of quick
housekeeping remarks or reminders we
have a bookshelf set up in the viaduct
the long read which is what this
república is about so if you have books
at home that you would like to share or
you would like to go browse for a new
book to take home and read the viaduct
is the place to go and of course we also
have our Moby Dick reading which is
going on throughout república and you're
welcome to join the ideas for you to
read a section from Moby Dick and
whenever a person makes a mistake the
next person continues reading and I
think a lot of people had fun doing that
so be sure to check out those two model
related things anyhow my name is
Geraldine de Bastian and I'm part of the
Republic a program team and it's my
honor not just to open the stage this
morning but also to moderate the
upcoming panel with a title or the
digital identity revolution grape hopes
or deep concerns now identity is a
concept that the majority of us here in
the West or in so-called developed
countries take for granted but according
to the World Bank 15% of the world
population more than 1 billion people
lack a valid form of identification a
figure not even accounting for the 60
million displaced 21 million refugees or
10 million stateless persons so with the
rise of different digital identities the
solutions new ethical questions are
rising as well and different
possibilities and those are what we'd
like to talk about today those ethical
questions around identity around self
sovereign identity and different
technologies in use and the concerns
around them I would like to first of all
welcome the host of the session to the
stage for you yeah the man from the
bonus material from which after
shih-tzus am a veteran victim a Federal
Ministry of Economic Development and
corporation Julia Lehman is currently
heading the division for Human Rights
gender and inclusion of persons with
disabilities at the Ministry and we're
very happy to welcome here at her a
republic her today
[Music]
good morning everyone very early hour
this this morning but on behalf of the
German Federal Ministry for development
cooperation and the gaz which is our
implementing agency which implements our
projects all over the world and all the
different partner countries we have at
warm welcome I'm a bit blinded by the
light but I hope we can still interact
with the audience later on even if it's
hard to see you thank you very much for
joining us this morning as this
generally has already said we all take
identity for granted we all think we
don't even think about this anymore
we all wouldn't be here if we hadn't
been able to register with república
this morning we all had to take out some
form of identity card this morning to
register here to actually get entrance
but as geraldine said already in her
including remarks 1 billion people in
this world do not have any form of
identification they can produce this
particularly relevant to contexts of
migration of flight of refugees and a
lot of them then in especially in
refugee camp camps can't find a
satisfiable answer to the question of
who are you I mean we often regard the
question Who am I as sort of you know a
metaphysical question but fill a lot of
people it is actually a very factual
matter the question and Who am I in
terms of how can I identify myself and
how can I lead a life that is based on
some form of identity digital identities
have opened up new avenues and we will
hear later on especially from Andrew
Harper from UNHCR and how that has
helped to register refugees but of
course with any kind of digital new
revolution there's always a question of
human rights concerns in the sense of
the right to privacy and the right to
your digital identity and of course you
can imagine it's it's not
it's not hard and you don't really have
to engage in any kind of conspiracy
theory but you can easily imagine that
identity data in the context of refugees
and in the context of migration that
gets into the wrong hands you can easily
imagine what what that amounts to also
of course to to other government
agencies who seek surveillance or even
imagine you you've deserted from war or
you're part of a persecuted minority
then of course you but those data in the
wrong hands can can have a very very
very detrimental effect in in all of our
development cooperation we do as the
German government we pay when one of the
fundamental principles is the respect
and regard for human rights and that's
not only offline but also increasingly
online and a lot of you have heard of
agenda 2030 that includes the
sustainable development goals which have
been agreed with in the United Nations
in 2015 one fundamental principle there
is leave no one behind leave no man
behind means human rights Accord to
everyone every single one especially
very what vulnerable groups and in the
context of migration and refugee and
flight of course those groups are very
vulnerable and their human rights
especially also their right to privacy
privacy and digital identity have to be
respected part of that we're trying to
do through something that has been very
much debated and has gone through the
media over the last few months and
that's the Global Compact on migration
the Global Compact on migration has the
great advantage to actually comply with
human rights standards and actually
explicitly state that any action taken
under this Global Compact has to be
under a human rights-based approach and
also the Global Compact for Refugees
which is the lesser debated but second
compact that that
fits into that that area in in those all
governments are obliged to respect human
rights and those of course include that
the right to privacy and digital privacy
but today we've got many speakers here
who know much more about this than I
actually do so I'll limit my
introductory remarks to simply now try
welcoming the others and thanking you
very much for for having us and thank
you for being here and I'm very much
looking forward myself to learning a lot
more about digital identity and where
that balance is between the great
benefits of identifying people but also
protecting their human rights thank you
very much
thank you very much Julia for the
introduction as well as for bringing
this panel and this topic to república
this year so I would like to now welcome
the three panelists that we have invited
to discuss this topic with you I would
like to bring on stage and please give
them all a big round of applause Andrew
Harper Zahra Rahman and polish image
I'd like to give them all a bit more of
a detailed introduction so that you know
who's on stage with me today
Andrew Harper's the director of the
division of program support and
management with the office of the UNHCR
in Geneva and prior to this current task
he led the innovation service at UNHCR
and was leading and coordinating the
international response to the Syrian
crisis in Jordan and of course we'll be
speaking more about your experiences
there and you'll work in this panel
Zahra is the deputy director of the
engine-room
an international nonprofit organization
that supports civil society to use tech
and data more effectively so researchers
responsible uses of data and technology
in advocacy and social justice and the
relationship of power and technology she
has written about identity and
technology for outlets such as Daily Dot
and the real life and to my right
Vanessa Messi is an expert for the
Economic Forum on digital identity a
part of the digital identity task force
good ID he has been a core contributor
to the driving of topic and the
decentralized identity globally so
bringing forth a discussion with the
World Economic Forum and other fora and
his company Taquan o Taquan is focusing
on creating solutions and decentralized
identity that can deliver privacy by
design for systems for the developing
and the developed world thank you very
much for being here together the three
of you as you can see we have kind of a
distribution of expertise on the panel
andrew has a wealth of expertise
actually working in refugee context and
managing so-called refugee crisis Zahra
with her expertise on digital ethics and
you as sort of the practical implementer
of digital identity solutions and that's
very much so the focus of the discussion
we want to bring in for the format I'd
like to start off by asking each of our
panelists make a mini interview set of
questions before engaging together in a
discussion and also bringing all of you
in it is kind of hard to see you but we
know you're out there so if you want
please don't be shy and we're looking
forward to joining you joining this
discussion
Andrew I'd like to cut it off with you
because I think it's important to give
everybody the right kind of context
exactly what we are speaking about in
the midst of one of the world's largest
refugee crisis or perhaps the largest
refugee crisis you established Satar II
and as rack to refugee camps I'd like to
begin with a question how identity
matters in exactly these contexts of
your work perhaps you can give us a
little bit of an insight what appoints
the right identity has in those spaces
and for people living there it's on um
so thank you very much okay and and
thank you everyone for coming this
morning the there's a massive effort in
regards to the Syrian operation and it
wasn't just obviously one organization
or individuals alone and we were there
in order to support the government of
Jordan the population of Jordan who were
having their borders kept open for tens
of thousands of people coming across
there's actually we're getting about
5,000 people per day coming across in
order for Jordan to control the
situation because you must you must
remember that Jordan is in a pretty
rough neighborhood they've had to deal
with Iraq they've had to deal with the
situation in Syria they had a Palestine
Israel next door so security and the
credibility of the operations were there
their foremost concern and so for them
they had to they put in place a
registration system even before we came
in play and so we worked with the
Jordanian government to ensure that the
registration system that the government
put in play and they already walking at
biometrics talking to account the needs
of the populations and we're done as
effectively and efficiently as possible
so in many aspects this is where the
world is also going that governments are
taking more and more responsibility for
registration and UNHCR and other
agencies are just trying to ensure that
the best practices are put into play and
so in relation to the digital
registration there we found that one
providing people for digital identity
provided an access to territory which
was the most important element so they
were not being bounced back into Syria
but to when they had a digital identity
that allowed them to leave the what was
basically closed camps so they were able
to leave the triandos Rock because no
matter what people say about refugee
camps they still refugee camps and no
one wants to be in a refugee camp so
this allowed gave the confidence to the
government to allow refugees to leave
the camps and to relocate to urban
centers were then able to use just to be
very quick we're obviously then used the
digital identity the biometrics that we
we captured from the refugees with their
concurrence to be able to access
everything from cache through a TMS and
then link that up to assistance which
has been provided by a host of other
organizations and agencies so what will
probably be discussing here at great
length is how secure is the data and
what was the willingness of the refugees
to come forward and be registered if
you're dealing with refugees who've been
suffered so much in Syria for the
previous four some substantial time the
feeling was that no one would come to
UNHCR and register because they the
refugees themselves would be concerned
about what would happen with the data
they would they didn't trust anyone
they'd been they'd suffered a great deal
from the previous regime and so to come
forward and register and share their
experiences and their details people say
this wasn't going to happen
but very soon after we started we had
thousands of people come through and so
that was a demonstration that people
wanted to be registered and they wanted
to avail themselves of protection that's
a very important point to make because
as I said in the opening remarks we take
these things for granted and the sort of
apprehensions that we feel people might
have to give the data as you said upon
registration
sort of in the practicalities if one
finds themselves in the situation of
course the benefits of doing so
completely outweigh and and there is
yeah probably not much choice that
people have so the fact that you had
people queuing up to do this with all
the things that you listed that they
would get access to if they did so of
course it's clear that people would want
to write but I'd like to well I just
reek how quickly access to territory
freedom of movement access to resources
some of the points that you outlined
that of course you need to prove
yourself anyway and show some form of
identity for now you introduce biometric
registration systems in these refugee
camps and I'd like to ask you the
difference between sort of analog
registration systems and other forms of
identity and digital registration
systems and identity management systems
where do you see the specific benefits
and moving from the one to the other
very quickly it's um it's one is much
more accountable than the other where
we've introduced biometrics and just
from a straight accountability for
resources which have been allocated to
us and I must add that where we're at a
time when there's less resources being
provided for humanitarian operations
when actually the needs are going up and
so we have to do whatever we can so we
have to ensure that the the person who
is we have qualified to receive
assistance the most vulnerable the most
protected or the ones who actually
receive it and so through the biometrics
we can be we can ensure that the person
with that unique identifier is the one
who receives assistance and where we
have introduced biometrics around the
world we've usually seen a reduction in
the numbers of we've been like what's a
deduplication or reduction in the
account the potential forward by
anywhere between 17 and 30 percent so
the use of biometrics to provide
increased accountability results in
significant savings particularly when
you look at operations which are
spending anywhere a quarter of a billion
dollars per year so if you can make
savings of ten percent plus this is
significant which can then be redirected
to the most vulnerable
so refugees of finding that when they
have biometrics they are less
intimidated by other groups to give up
their ration cards or to possibly make
false claims and so we found that
refugees actually want to be register
with biometrics because that provides
with greater guarantee that their
identity can not be misused by others so
when a I'm gonna move along the panel I
read an article called the refugee
identity from pork urine leading up to
this panel and I want to quote from it
very briefly he says in the article the
attack service of the individual
identity is all the points at which
identity is rollin or award to misuse or
abuse digitization increases the attack
service by linking identity data to
other systems making the refugee more
vulnerable while decreasing the
capability of the refugee to mitigate
that vulnerability having heard what
Andrew said and sort of the need for
bringing in identity identification
processes but also taking that into
account
what would you say yeah I mean I guess I
think you brought up some really
interesting points I guess in the in
response to the to the point about
increased accountability I'd be really
interested to know what a digital
identification system looks like the
increases accountability not in terms of
the humanitarian operations but
accountability to the people who are
being registered and I think you know I
it's fair that I guess in some cases
people are very keen to be registered in
order to get certain yeah access to
certain services but I also wonder what
does informed consent look like when
you're saying you have to go through
these systems in order to access what
you know shelter access to territory
that kind of thing because I think I
mean an you know maybe this is an open
question of whether there was an
alternative system that didn't require
people to give up biometric data I'm
also reminded of in I think it was
November 2018 the there was a group of
ringing in the in a refugee camp in
Cox's Bazaar and Bangladesh
who actually went on a three-day strike
directly in response to the way that
UNHCR was collecting their biometric
data so I think you know I think it's
very context-specific
they have some very very detailed very
very detailed manifesto they're
incredibly well organized but the points
included things like not being consulted
about how their data was being collected
not being sure who the data was being
shared with not having any alternatives
so they they said that when they refused
to give their biometric data they were
blocked from leaving a certain small
area and for me that's very much not
informed consent and we I would say that
we all have a responsibility to kind of
prioritize the rights of people who have
been particularly the rain you're
refugees in coming out of Syria who have
been already so persecuted to think
about what their response or what their
rights and what they want more than what
would be potentially easier on the
operational side and then I guess
another topic that heavily comes into
plays as you mentioned in earlier Andrew
the dynamics between the state actors
and and different actors that come into
play the may be also private sector
companies which we'll get to in a minute
fighting different identity solutions
but of course also the power dynamic
between you and agency are and and the
countries you're operating in yeah I
mean I think the other thing to add to
that is and this is something that we've
been doing some research around lived
effects of digital identification
systems in the refugee context one thing
that comes up a lot is what is the
recourse for refugees or for people who
don't feel like their data is being
handled in a responsible way what can
they do
given that UN agencies are immune from
national legal systems what are the
legal accountability processes that
anyone can go through to say this was
not done well there was a whatever a
data breach even you know something like
that there's currently it's currently
very blurry and maybe maybe you have
answers to this as to what people can do
to you know to assert their rights so
consent and accountability other other
critical aspects that we haven't yet
and in regard to data protection and
Identity Management for in these
contexts yeah I mean I think for me
there's a difference between a digital
identification system that includes
biometric data and one that doesn't we
did some research in I think 2016-2017
looking at the specific problem that
biometrics were seeking to solve and we
found overwhelmingly that the problem
from the monetary incide was around
reducing fraud and deduplication like
Andrew mentioned but there were cases
and but there were many cases where the
risk of gathering that data was so huge
potential risk was so huge and for
example in the Rehana context there big
concern is that the biometric data that
is being collected by the Bangladeshi
authorities in collaboration with the
own HCR would be shared back with the
Myanmar government who have just or who
are committing a genocide against those
people so to me there's it's it's very
hard to see the use case in which
gathering such personal immutable
unchangeable data could ever be in
respond be kind of reasonable in
response to reducing fraud to one
respond before move on just just quickly
the but the reinga situation is probably
also it happens in almost every refugee
situation where people are scared
they're concerned they don't want david
be shared they don't know why they're
giving up the data and that was
certainly the case last year like I went
to Bangladesh a couple of times I was
involved in the registration in
preparing for the registration the the
population coming out of Miami were
obviously extremely traumatized they
didn't want to be forced back and they
did not want to be registered but over
time our teams have been discussing with
them we've not a just UNHCR bird but all
the humanitarian actors there saying why
is why particularly for the row hangars
why it is so important to ever to have
an identity and so now I can basically
say there's at least a thousand people
and more people coming per day and being
registered and seeking that identity
this was not the case six months ago
because the issue of trust we mentioned
the issue of legal recourse the legal
recourse is important but most important
for UNHCR and others is a credibility if
we do not have the credibility with the
refugee population and the trust with
the refugee situation with the rift with
refugees and with the host authorities
everything else is basically lost so we
we having this feedback mechanism having
the trust with the communities is
absolutely important for us we can we do
things better absolutely and I think one
of the issues that having a digital
identity offers us is to make use of
feedback mechanisms how can we do this
in a more collaborative manner certainly
not just from UNHCR how can we have much
more independent CWC community working
with communicating with communities
feedback mechanisms that are independent
and can actually report back to
objective interlocutors about what is
going on what are the concerns of
populations so take that into account
very much informed consent we try and do
as much as we can in that regards we can
do better and we must be doing better in
relation to accessing services accessing
protection everyone has a choice if you
look at biometrics elderly people with
cataracts often cannot have their RSS
scan so we look at biometrics
facilitating multiplying our delivery
assistance protection mechanisms but
everyone has got the option to opt in or
opt out and I think this is one of one
of the the key areas and again all the
reports and all the elements that you're
raising we take into account when we
need to take those into account what
recourse again goes back to the trust
and credibility so we need to be
listening to the populations trust and
credibility good keywords I'll take to
bring you into the conversation hurt
your original movement with the
blockchain came from realization of how
difficult it was to open a bank account
for refugees in Europe
so I'd like to ask you to share that
experience with us know that your point
of inspiration to get into this whole
this whole business so basically our
project started at during their refugee
crisis in Europe from a realization that
was just mentioned that we I happened to
visit the refugee camp in Norway and it
turned out that it's more expensive for
someone to go into the city then for me
to travel out because I can pay with
card just for the distance of the trip
but someone without a bank account bank
card has to pay for the entire bus fare
and that was like okay they get like 300
euro a month and they can travel cheaper
and we had a long discussion and the
person we interviewed being living in
Norway speaks perfect Norwegian but
can't have a bank account because of
legal reasons and that was like shocking
like this person speaks better Norwegian
than I do
understands the culture better but they
she just can't get a job in Norway you
need to have a bank account to be able
to sign a contract so it was like oh
this is like crazy like we can't talk
about Social Inclusion and like openness
and everything when they can just have
no chance to start and so I was familiar
with the technology blockchain and we
started to look into could it be
possible to create a solution that
enables them to access our financial
ecosystem and not like an alternative
cryptocurrency based and that's how we
stepped onto the story of banking for
Refugees three years ago so I'd like to
ask you just as Andrew sort of outlines
the different use cases let's say that
you need an identity for for you to
outline the different solutions that are
out there today we've talked a bit about
biometrics but can you just give us a
general overview of digital identity
solutions of on the market sure but I
think it's important to go one step back
and like digital identity can be a lot
of things so mostly what we are talking
about our personal identifiers that can
prove who you are that there's like that
are related to your persona your birth
registration your biometrics for for
authentication perspective but it's not
particularly or like
your bank card is a digital identity
Esper because whenever you pay you
authenticate yourself towards a system
which is a payment trail but it is also
an identity so like mostly in these
situations we are talking about the
lower levels of identities which can
enable the access to go higher into
service reown however the protection of
these different RIANZ can differ and
maybe should be fir and the question was
different solutions classic so like
basically there is a range of different
solution one you might have heard it's
called Facebook it's great if you are
willing to give up your data from a
technology perspective the Gateway to
their system is an open source both
Facebook and Google use the same
technology however like they store
everything that you do and they collect
even more that you don't know about well
we can argue very along it why is it not
so good their business perspective but
they are much more effective than any
other identity service ever before the
largest government-issued system
currently is in India which is a
biometric based identification system
which they basically they collected
north of 1 billion biometric identities
of all their citizens in roughly 3 years
it is an insane large government push
the only issue was that back then when
the system was created India didn't have
privacy rights there was like none so
donors of the system had access to data
not and it wasn't only biometric but
like that was the bottom layer of India
stack which was access to banking access
to insurance and so on and so on and so
like donors of the system had access to
to the stack information it has changed
it is better now but it is still not
perfect which is a government system
there is like the Estonian identity
which many of you might have heard this
is a much better implemented
government-issued identity
has distributed nature so it's not like
one system manages everything it's they
created a system after their man got
hacked where the different in tissues
and in the government communicate with
each other and sort of the hopefully
next three on which my company and a lot
of other companies are standing for
itself serene identity or self managed
identity we are basically data storage
and data management are happening on
user side so the user is able to store
data in a way that it's technically
provable that he or she is the owner and
also able to consent at a-- which is
used for different service accesses so
what it would create is the second is is
the ability to access every level of
these these like different realms of of
services with different ways of using
your identity because for example when i
entered here i had to show my government
ID but they are uninterested in my name
but it had my actual number on it it had
my birth date so I gave up theoretically
a lot more information than they were
actually interested or have the rights
to be interested in so being able to
create subsets of your identity which
you can still prove digitally which is
much better than a plastic card is a it
can become extremely powerful if
implemented well I want to ask you two
more questions on this topic so
classically the state the nation-state
is the provider of your your passport
your formal identity and and and you as
a citizen get the sort of the general
right to have one but it's something
that's of co-owned between you and the
state in this version of self sovereign
identity is this something that you
visit happening on a government
supported public blockchain or how would
that exactly take shape who would be
sort of the manager of the system the
provider of the infrastructure behind it
and how does the self self report
actually work so I think the only
globally accepted identity is Facebook
and
your passport the passport is actually
useful but the problem with that you
actually don't own it the government
owns your passport you are a user of it
you are subscribed by being the citizen
but if you are not a citizen anymore
it's not valid and if it's taken away
you can't prove you ever had it Andrew
mentioned that like a lot of people had
trust issues registering liens that are
the same happen when they enter in the
in Europe there was a huge black market
of Syrian passports because Syrians had
a simpler way to apply for citizenship
all across Europe and a Syrian can tell
the story that he's Asteria or she is a
Syrian while a person with a Syrian
passport can show a passport that he or
she is a Syrian
so like trust issues are to both
directions and going back to like to my
mind which again forget the question the
question was how does the self sovereign
cloud actually work and how would it be
a public blockchain with a public park
chain be state this provided
infrastructure how does it work what
role does the nation-state playing
future and where does the self sovereign
Park comment so we're not going to go
into blockchain because it's a
technology framework what's important to
understand itself so an identity doesn't
need blockchain and the blockchain
technology needs also an identity so
like what the whole not the whole but
like many companies are looking into is
only registering a public address on a
on a blockchain which is a publicly run
infrastructure not owned by anyone but
miners are creating security and upkeep
for the system but then only using that
own chain and they're moving
transactions in a secure environment but
off chain because basically a blockchain
identity which is using actively a
blockchain for transactions would be
like tweeting your digital life
constantly maybe not no one wants to use
it but if someone they can search for it
we didn't have knowledge it's it is
public so sub certain identities are
registering functions on a blockchain
but they're moving hopefully they are
moving off chain to store and manage the
transactions themselves and the data
itself so I know data should go every
one of object I'm guessing that some of
the things you say would make some
people coming more from the sort of
public sector side or actually side a
little bit nervous and and I want to I
want to just try to take them apart a
little bit so a this sort of nobody owns
anything it's kind of a translucent
thing but there are private companies
sort of involved in some way or private
persons who are miners that seems like a
very sort of convoluted space which is a
very different thing to saying here's a
nation-state government that provides
you with your passport so that's one
thing that makes past people little bit
nervous the whole Facebook thing makes
me completely nervous on a whole
different level but maybe we'll get to
that in a minute
sorry pointed out earlier already the
question and also the dangers connected
with traceability there are many people
in the world who might not want their
identity bt as sort of a linear
traceable thing so as you pointed out I
would be were able to sort of I'd say
which bits of my identity I communicate
to who when but of course there's a file
ability in or technical systems and that
idea behind the blockchain sort of
locking in in an unchangeable way
information about me which could include
my nationality and that's maybe
something that I care to hide if I
become a refugee how does that come into
play so there is so there is the ability
to to destroy or or make these
identities disappear in most
implementations or hopefully and most
because there is an e-rep like a global
right the right to be forgotten which
should create a system where these
identities can be deleted my question is
that if I want to be deleted from the
German refugee system can I do that
under the right to be forgotten because
it's good that the technology enables
but is a nation-state under the right to
be forgotten scheme or can I become not
a Hungarian citizen anymore actually I
can't you have to be a citizen of a
country
unless your refugee but I can't become
on purpose just the refugee because it
sounds fun it's just sort of a side note
it's not only technology but from a
technology perspective like it's it is
all possible because it's like we create
the technology the really the end goal
is like what are the use cases you want
to apply it and how can we avoid
creating the ability to collect
everything that are related to these
identities so the blockchain is not that
big of a question because hopefully no
one will ever save any data on the
blockchain which is comes to identity
like at least like from like serious
projects so I don't think that is a
biggest concert for this debate but the
bigger question is how we can avoid
collecting this data because if it's
consent of all I someone can just gasps
please give me all your data and you can
become a citizen and then it's there is
an incentive to do that that's how it
works is it you can jump in if you like
it's also making you a little bit
nervous any mentions of Facebook is the
biggest trusted global identity platform
is whirring we can get that your your
words I think I guess I I mean I'm not
familiar with your company so this is
kind of a general a general concern I
have with mentions of identity and
blockchain and generally actually the
the kind of conflation between a
person's identity and an identification
system that conflation kind of makes me
nervous I mean we started with the
question Who am I and I think for me if
you'd asked me who are you 10 years ago
I would answer that very differently to
how I would now I think that part of
being human is kind of the fluid the
fluid nature of our identities and the
ability to change over time the ability
to present certain attributes to hide
certain attributes is an inherent part
of being human and being able to
interact with the system in a you know
sponsible way and i think the biggest
thing that came up for me and geraldine
you already brought it up a little bit
is this confusing accountability that I
think I'm not sure I entirely sure I
follow and I think going to your point I
feel like credibility but the
accountability is a huge part of credit
building credibility that having
objective or kind of external
accountability processes to say this did
not work for me is a huge part of
building credibility and Trust and then
yeah I guess the other I mean a big
question that I would have around the
the blockchain or private company
related private sector involvement in
all of this is GDP are like data
protection regulation if you were to say
I want to remove all of my data from
this blockchain or this company that
kind of thing I I have no idea how that
would be possible given that it's
immutable maybe that's also a question
how you address that having been
introduced last year how has that
affected your work um the GDP are weak
unhcr is probably like there's other
organizations who probably got even more
stringent data protection including ICRC
but as far as the UN is concerned
UNHCR was the first agency to put in a
data protection policy and guidelines
going back to 2015 so all the
discussions on data and refugee
protection cannot be distinguished like
but we have to be we have to have secure
data we have to have privacy not just in
theory but in practice because again it
goes back to the the trust and integrity
of everything we do if our systems get
hacked and people lose trust in who we
are as a protection agency then that's
that's that's goes to the core of our
mandate so when when we talk about
issues of identity in regards to privacy
many of the regulations the policies the
practices that we've put in place going
back to 2015 actually predated European
regulations and so what what I can say
is that where we try to be an alignment
as much as we can
and everything given given the world is
changing so rapidly given the capacity
to hack given the increasing value which
people put on personal data we also have
to be agile we also have to calibrate
our responses and L in our requirements
we've got a Data Protection Officer but
we need more like we need to be much
more serious because the capacity to
intercept - to hack into systems is also
growing so we as an organisation who
puts privacy and protection very core we
have to invest much more in our
understandings so as quite genuine sort
of saying about your studies are things
that we actually take into very
seriously the recommendations are things
that we try to put into account we've
actually got a data meeting in
Copenhagen today where privacy and
protection and how we can have more
enhanced guidelines are in play so for
any new technology that we put in play
which could have an impact on data
protection we have a data protection
impact assessment to go through all
these elements I was gonna ask because
I'm sure that's a very difficult thing
to balance sort of being open for
innovation I know that you HDR's its own
sort of innovation hub let's say and
some ecosystem and trying to bring in
new solutions that sort of do a better
service to the people that you're trying
to provide services for but yet having
very little space to experiment of
course because people's lives depend on
it
well the again I want to keep saying
that you and a cell Protection Agency
but innovation is no use to us if we if
we jeopardize that protection space so
what is key to almost everything that we
do is to make sure that people are at
the centre we try and ensure that we
move forward on getting feedback
mechanisms in play not just being UN HCR
centric but across the whole
humanitarian space we look at
collaboration we look at making sure
that we can bring things to scale so
it's not it's not a situation where it's
it's alien us to sort of look at
innovation but also trying to ensure
that we've got greater data security and
data privacy what we what we have to try
and balance is particularly an emergency
situation how can we do our job better
how can we improve
how can we improve assistance and when
it comes down to it we have to ensure
that refugees and others including
stateless persons have a choice so in
the end we have to give them the dignity
the the the trust in them that they will
make them informed decisions I want to
leave some time and space also for your
questions and comments if you want to
start bringing them in the people in the
room who will come to you with a
microphone have probably also better see
you than I can so if you want to start
raising your hands and guess from now on
is a good good time to do so or maybe if
I see correctly there's a microphone
stand here in the middle and you could
possibly use that as well if you want to
step forward so you're trying to develop
solutions with your company that will
come into this context like how do you
go about doing that just also in a
practical way in terms of dialogues with
organizations like even HCI also with
maybe people like Zahra like how you try
to build those solutions so we are
focusing a lot on research from
technology perspective and also we are
at really actively like contributing to
a larger knowledge group on supporting
the whole movement if anyone is
interested in south so an identity we
created a paper called SSI paper if you
search on Twitter hashtag SSI paper it
will come up with German block chain
Association which is a basically to
support paper for like from every aspect
why I serve so an identity can be
beneficial what are the circumstances
that it could be disadvantages and how
public agencies can look at it and can
understand it so anyone is interested
just go on Twitter and SSI paper so
that's like one part which we did which
was a really large work but it really
enables us to have an easier
conversation because a lot of what we do
is education education education and
conversations to better understand every
aspect and just reply quickly to Sarah
how do you know that you are deleted
from an other system that's nothing to
do with lock chain because someone told
you it happened
because someone told it told me it
happened him because I know that there's
huge fines as part of the GDP are if
they didn't that's the answer it's
technology there is a way to solve it
and they did completely so you have no
trace I'm happy to explain how I think
maybe as a comment from my side like
preparing for the session I have to say
like I found this one article that I
cited earlier and then I found a
plethora of articles that celebrate
technology and that is a little bit part
of my concern or perhaps also shared
concern that a lot of these ideas are
seen from a very technological
perspective rather than a human centered
perspective and there's a lot of hope
put in the technological side but it
it's a little bit of a it seems to have
a little bit of a naivety attached to it
especially taking into account that
there are so many unforeseen things the
question of function creep how do we
design subsystems today that cannot be
exploited
tomorrow we cannot predict exactly how
either politics or technology is going
to develop so how do we yeah how do we
design for future scenarios basically
that's a pretty complicated question
generally speaking like the communities
from a technology perspective the
community is following events differ
than GDP our standards and privacy and
think of future scenarios which our
regulators are still very far from to
understand or or to act it on and on the
other side like like privacy is a big
issue but the whole conversation started
on there is 1 billion people who don't
have identity but they also don't have
smart phone or even carrier service
where they are mostly so like what are
solutions that can be delivered to them
and have the future capability to become
like part of a global software and
identity network or an interoperable
identity without maybe all the level of
privacy requirements but but the ability
to deliver at least some form of
identity to people so that they can be
registered they can be missed from
school from health care
and then they can as they develop their
identity and their presence in society
they can actually access to other
services that are built on because
currently no identity system talks to
each others the UNHCR's identity system
don't communicate with virtual programs
identity system yet this is such a
tricky thing
it is such a tricky question that you
brought up and I am reminded of a panel
that we did quite a couple of years ago
on the topic of big data and developing
context and I remember you being very
very clear on the question that you
cannot balance human rights like that it
doesn't work to say oh but people need
something more so they don't get the
right to privacy because they're hungry
I'm what would you respond today I mean
kind of similar to Republic at 2015 and
I think who are you think it I would
actually be really interested in this
goes back to something you were saying
earlier to think about so those 1
billion people who don't have access to
a digital identification mechanism what
is the kind of digital identification
system that they want so rather than us
sitting here and saying you know what
they want self sovereign identity how do
we get it to them I would be much more
interested in kind of the flip side
saying for example one thing that really
surprised me with the Rohini case was
one of the reasons that they were
striking was that they specifically
wanted the label rania on their cards
and in many other contexts the the idea
of having a label of your ethnicity on
an identification card is unthinkable
and horrible and that was a very I think
a very good example of how
context-specific
a lot of this is so the idea that yeah I
think we have to start with respecting
people's rights respecting their dignity
starting from that place asking them
what kind of system makes sense for them
in their context why do they need a
digital identification card what are the
problems that they are trying to solve
what are the barriers that are standing
in their way that a digital
identification system of some kind could
solve for them I think anything that is
kind of us saying you know what you
actually need this more than you need
your right to privacy is it just seems
very colonial to me what we're seeing it
more and more
the days of old when refugees would come
across into a refugee camp and be
registered by UNHCR
a fast disappearing it's still the case
you have situations such as in Miami
refugees coming across into Bangladesh
they don't really have any choice they
came to cooter blonde camp they were
they were had a very rough registration
to begin with because they were
concerned plus you had 800,000 people
come but more and more it's becoming
more of a context that we're seeing of
populations going through say from the
Sahel to North Africa towards Europe or
from the Venezuela situation people are
bypassing traditional registration and
they're looking for their own solutions
and so more and more we have to not come
from like a northern Western un
perspective to sort of say this is what
you should have as far as an identity
and this is the type of technology that
we will use we have to adapt and sort of
say okay what is it that you want what
is it that you need what does the
minimum viable data we need in order to
better protect and assist you and how
can we work with others to ensure that
you're in the best position to achieve
your goals in a more dignified way
because like if you go back to the
situation that were being faced with
with the Syrian crisis Syrian crisis
regards to Europe when we had so many
people going towards some Europe and
2015/2016 every academic institution or
geek basically came up with their own
app to sort of communicate with refugees
most of them were useless most of them
were not trusted most and were
irrelevant to refugees because we tried
to sort of say this is what they need to
better communicate like what refugees
will choose is what's useful for them
they will use whatsapp they may use
Facebook but then if Facebook is lost
its credibility then they'll go / that
they will go to telegram then we use
what they believe is most important for
them so it goes back to saying
digital identity is needed for
populations as a basis but what's more
important is that that digital identity
protected and is putting them in a
manner which is of most use to the
individual thank you but you want to
respond quickly no I mean I was just
gonna say I totally agree with what you
were saying and some of the the research
that we're doing right now is looking
into you know precisely what are those
those lived effects that are sometimes
hard to see if we're not kind of
specifically looking for them we have a
interventional question if I could see
correctly it's this conversation here
today very much builds on a conversation
we had last year on the same stage
actually and Kirschstein actor was one
of the panelists then also from UNHCR
please Carr continuation of last year's
discussion even for those who weren't
there last year but what I realize no
longer being with UNHCR is that
obviously it's a niche discussion it's
because it's it we are talking about
digital identity about refugees which
are very vulnerable and therefore it has
its merits
however I believe that the maybe the
organizers of republika 2020 maybe
should be thinking of having a broader
discussion on digital identity because I
am of the opinion that there are new
regulations coming everyone talks about
gdpr but the European countries for
instance have allowed have have new
regulations coming when for instance the
digital private companies identity
companies will be accredited and have
the right to operate there is another
regulation coming which will allow
financial services provider to run all
your bank accounts your Google pays your
Apple pays and descended and I would
think that most of us 10 years from now
will be subscribing to a digital
identity company who will manage for us
our digital identity and what is
happening right now is that business
models are being sawed left right and
centre how this could be done and how
could be this beneficial to the
companies obviously and and maybe a
blockchain comes very often across and
especially
this idea of self sovereign that you
know this is we are at last realizing
the promise of the internet you know you
know the the self the sovereign internet
the free internet for everybody and I
think what is really happening if you
look at the the big companies who are
doing research there that is exactly the
same thing is happening again that the
very big companies are researching
digital identity how digital identity
can be sold to each of us thank you
thank you so much Carl that was very
important points that you raised there
you were nodding you were looking
concerned can you let us know a little
bit more about this
EU biometric system that's being
introduced so once that one step back to
two regulations the EU is introducing or
working on a proposal to create a wide
refugee registration biometric system
with all the consent that they would
need as their decision is a nation state
level decision without regards of how
can someone opt out of this system and
while talking about the Chinese credit
scoring system how bad it is so like
there is nothing black and right even
the West is creating systems that are
extremely violent towards privacy
especially of refugees just because when
you put the terrorism on anything it
becomes like a very different topic and
unfortunately the case of refugees very
often mixed with with the potential
effect of terrorism regarding the
question like the quote I do agree with
this UNHCR has the potential to become
an identity provider from a very
different perspective as of delivering
these identities often very complicated
as technology is not present whereas
some of those companies that the
gentlemen might have meant are mostly
operating environment with very
excessive act access to technology
as we have already nearly reached the
end of our panel I'd like to ask you all
for sort of some closing remarks Carl
gave a look into the future which maybe
not all of us would feel is quite bright
with identity being managed by a set of
different or a field of different
private sector companies looking ahead
into the future and what we want in
terms of digital identity management
although I would very much like to take
it to account what you said Zara and I
feel like we could also offer a platform
here for some more inclusive discussions
involving people who might be bent in a
better position to answer this question
than I see on the panel today but
looking into the future the digital
identity solutions that we'd want what
is it that we'd wish for what would be
your wishes to them perhaps the as are
the the people developing such solutions
or managing and implementing such
solutions same question for you and to
and also for you would you like to start
I'm happy to start so generally speaking
privacy is becoming a new issue like
much more people realizing that privacy
is much more important and I can open a
browser and I can do whatever I want
because you leave traces and and there
are people collecting those traces or
their companies collecting those traces
so access to privacy and being the
ability to live in an environment when
there are regulations around your
privacy to protect you is very very
important and for that you also need the
ability to manage these traces and your
privacy so you need an identity
management which has to align or even
deliver higher standards than the
regulation itself and I would say this
is what we are working towards with the
addition of how can it be delivered to
situations which are not highly
technically advanced yet thank you Sarah
sure I think for me I'd start with
really clear problem definition and that
driven by kind of operational needs but
also by the context and by the people
who will be part of or who will be
registered under that identification
system thinking about the minimum viable
to pick up yeah the minimum viable
amount of data that needs to be
collected and also what data retention
how long does that need to be stored and
how can that be deleted after that
period of time is over there in limited
data sharing I think actually kind of in
contrast to what was being said earlier
the fact that these systems don't talk
to each other for me is kind of
reassuring sometimes I think it's fine
that they they don't always share all of
the data all over time and then yeah I
guess building in kind of recognizing
the amount of power that we have in even
talking about kind of designing these
systems and implementing these systems
and instead creating ways kind of as
Andrea was saying to not just to do more
than kind of here in a feedback loop but
to give that power to the people who are
going to be within that system Andrew
this this this a lot of work already
being done in regards to the principles
regards to identity in regards to data
security but it goes back down to what
is it in the interest of the individual
and it's concerning like what what has
happened on the 18 for April with with
with the adoption by Parliament all
these rules and regulations within
within Europe because can somebody has
been discussed can somebody be forgotten
like are the are the principles that we
are so like including Europe is pushing
for so much have they adopted them
themselves within their own within their
own guidelines so I don't know I don't I
doubt it I think there's much more
issues in regards to security regards
control then what is maybe necessary if
you look at the waffle nurse if you look
at the specific purpose if you look at
the accuracy the quality the ability for
refugees and others to update their in
their own information do who owns the
data who owns the identity and I suppose
it's a crux of it and if you're working
for people if you're working for
individual
the individual has to own the data they
have to elect when when it's the right
for somebody else used to use that data
and not be sold not be commercialized
not be used for nefarious purposes thank
you so much I think that is a wonderful
statement to end this panel on and I
would very much like to continue this
discussion with you hopefully next year
and take cause incentive to do so I'd
like to thank partners from VM said and
Gi said for enabling this discussion
here today and the three of you for this
interesting panel I hope you enjoy the
rest of Republica
[Applause]
[Music]