hello everyone
i'm patreon here from chinho university
today i'm going to talk about our work
conference
a decentralized blockchain with high
throughput and fast confirmation
this is a joint work of chinhoy
university and conference foundation
to begin with i'd like to talk about
what an ideal blockchain is like
we think ideal blockchain should have
the following properties
the first is robustness that is it
should have strong safety to defend
against
double spending attacks it should also
have good liveness to be against denial
of service attacks
secondly the system should have high
performance you know since then it
should achieve both high throughput
and no confirmation latency at the same
time
certainly it should have good
decentralization
that is it can scale to large amounts of
participate
and are now optional to join and leave
the network without permission
not to most valuable pronouncing systems
bitcoin and ethereum both have good
robustness and discrimination
but still suffer a lot from performance
problems which brings undesirable user
experience
non-processing dna and scheduling
transaction fees
for example the typical transaction
throughput of bitcoin is about 7
transactions per second
and the eastern throughput is about 30
where other central services like paypal
or visa
can provide hundreds or thousands of
transactions per second
which indicates the level of support
needed in real world
in order to better understand why
confidence can be superior to
alternative
existing blocking systems let's first
look at some background
about how bitcoin and ether work
typically a public
and decentralized blockchain system like
bitcoin is built upon
a peer-to-peer gossip network where each
node is connected to several other nodes
transactions are packed into blocks a
block containing user transactions
will be broadcasted in the network and
rapidly to all the nodes
the blocks form a chain and the nature
for the
transaction history and all the nodes in
the network will eventually represent
the same nature
in the chain of nodes the nato one can
be treated as a vote to the only one
every node in the network can generate
new blocks to vote for the previous one
if the voting is cheap an untangle can
easily create tens of nodes
to actually manipulate the pronounced
teenager this is called civil attention
in order to avoid this vulnerability
bitcoin and ether introduce a mechanism
called
proof of work that uses computation
power and voting rate
specifically to generate a block a node
needs to solve a puzzle which consumes
considerable communication resources
this process
is called mining bitcoin and
its variants adopt the knack mode
consensus
where the language chain rule is
organized in the language chain rule
all the honest participants agree on the
language chain
and the vending systems in history in
practice
the length of the chain also considers
the consumed computation power
and the weight of the block which is
called the mining difficulty
normally the security guarantee are not
commodore consensus event
as long as more than 50 computation
power is owned by honest nodes
long exchange also formed by them a
superficial reason
and why this system can only achieve
there are no throughput event
they typically employ snow block
generation rate and small block size
for example bitcoin adopts one megabyte
block size
per 10 minutes variation adopts about
100 kilobyte blocks per 50 seconds
these parameters significantly limit
their throughput
so what if we run a further consensus
with nigel block
our first terminal generation rate
simply doing this does not work because
if so we will get a nature look like
this the issue here is that
there are a lot of folks in the nature
this is because it takes the time to
broadcast a new new minor product
across the entire network during this
delay other miners may not be able to
see this new world
neopreneur and still mine their own
openers following the same older block
and therefore introduce the fault
natural block sizes means longer
broadcasted delay
which means more concurrent bars and
lots more faults
the faster pronunciation rate and a
similarity
there are two drawbanks if the name
nature has too many folks
first in the ninth chain rule unemployed
in the language chain are considered
valid other blocks on the force will be
discarded and with networks and
processing resources
secondly exemplifies the security which
is a more severe issue
to see why it is not safe anymore let's
see an example
if we have the same number of blocks the
more force that the nature have
the shorter israelites chain suppose the
lungs here only contains 10 percent of
drugs in the nature
this means the attacker can only have
use only 10 percent computation power to
reverse
the longest chain which significantly
reduces the security guarantee
later on another consensus algorithm
called ghost
has been proposed to address this
security issue
caused by folks it is also going to net
all the nodes agree on a single chain
indonesia
but instead of using longest chain rule
it
applies the heaviest subshell
specifically
to connect the blocks into the
earthquake chain it starts from picking
the genesis block into the agreed chain
the genesis block is the first one in
the nature then
it iteratively advances to the child
block
with a heavy sub tree and include it
into the grid chain
here is an example we first connect the
genesis block into the aggregate chain
the genesis node has two child blocks a
and b
the sub tree of a has six blocks while
sub-shell b
only have five blocks so we sneak a into
the agreed chain
then following the same rule we will
have
c e and h also included in the chain
when generating an obnox it follows the
next national interchange
unlike the longest chain rule ghost
makes all the nodes including the blocks
in the force
contribute to the transnation and hence
does not have the security issue that i
mentioned before
however ghost still suffers from
niceness a tank
here is an example assume the honest
nodes from two groups
and there's a misty dna d between those
in different groups
while the communication dna of nodes in
the same group
or between a tanker and any other honest
node can be ignored
because of such messy dna there can be a
period where
the nature consists of two folks of
group a
and group b the tank can secretly mind
blocked on both the folk a and f of b
and does not immediately expose its
nodes towards node
later on when group a match some new
blocks following the force a
and send them to group b the tanker may
obser
observe this before group b because of
the network delay
between the two groups it then
exposes the blocks mine alpha b to group
b
this will make proof because the folk b
is heavier than folk a
so they will continue to mind blocks in
for b
and then the tanker transpose the bronx
minor in force a
to the nodes in group a this will also
make those into placing sent
called a is still heavier if the block
generation is much faster than b
then if there will be a lot of
intransitive blocks during the delay
and a tanker with little computation
power can store the consensus forever
and this is what we call venous attack
the attacker can balance
to substitute to maintain folks and
prevent knives
one fixed to this issue is to use what
we call
structured ghost approach then if we
only choose a small fraction of blocks
to have weights
for the transaction and all the
remaining blocks only contributes
transaction
this will be secure against navalness
attack if the function of weighted block
is small enough
because this makes the concurrent
generation of weighted blocks very rare
for example it still considers the case
where you have two groups
a and b and the system is under a
beneficial tank
the dense numbers do not have weight for
transaction
at some point a weighted block is
generated by a
which is shown in the double line block
still
in group b cannot see it immediately so
it continues to generate blocks in front
b
however after a time delay d
group b observe the weight of node a
although at this time both a and b have
the same number of blocks
but force a has heavier weight because
of the weight of the block
then group b will start to generate
neuroblast funnel in the force a to
break the balance
the problem of the fix is that the
confirmation latency is no
it cannot benefit from the first
generation rate anymore because
weighted blocks are generated slowly so
is there any way we can keep
fast confirmation and laminates under
tanks at the same time
the answer is yes we can combine
original ghost and structure ghost
to achieve this and this is one of the
key idea of conflux
so confidence uses a mechanism called
greedy heaviest adaptive substrate
just in short so this is the issue in
gust
components are then different with
different dogs
it still uses heavy substitute to sniff
at a great chain
since we call pivot chain
and it needs all the blocks or the nodes
to consistently decide a total order
of all the blocks based on the keyword
chain
in normal scenario where the attack
campaign is
equally to blocks just like those and
achieving your optimal throughput and
confirmation latency
when attack happens you will the
heavyweights to a small subset of growth
in this case the operator is an
extraordinary ghost by snowing down
confirmation
it ensures that consensus can always
make progress
so how to make honest participate
automatically switch between the two
scenarios
before talking about this mechanism
let's first look at how confidence
organizes the laser structure in conflux
it organizes the blocks in what we call
tree graph structure
each block has one parent age and shown
as
solid arrow each block may also have
multiple reference edges
and shown as density angle the reference
edges simply represent the happening
before relationships
among blocks for example
there is a reference edge from e to d
that means
block d is generated before block e
when a new block is generated it's next
to the nostril in the pivot chain and
its parent
and creates reference edges to all the
other blocks that do not have incoming
edges
it is in the tree growth structure
capture the history
block the history blockchain state for
each generated block
we define the past sub-graph of a node
as other blocks than the block generator
can see when generating the block
for example the path graph of a new
block
is all the current blocks while this is
the past sub graph of block h
in order to automatically decide a block
weight
we propose to derive the weight from the
blocks past the sub graph
that is essentially to design a function
which takes the past sub graph of the
block as input
and output its corresponding weight the
function is to detect whether the
current situation is on the bandwidth
attack
in other words whether the path stop
graph is stable enough
if it is stable which means no tank is
detected
it is assigned with one to the block
otherwise the other
way h to the block with probability one
over h
uh the assigned with zero to other
blocks
since all the honest participants will
have consistent view on the past
subgroup they will have a grade on the
weights of the blocks
even with the presence of a tanker
the high level intuition of how we
design this weight assignment
function is based on this right now that
is
for any pure chamber of a that is
generated for a while not enough
while this charge block a prime has
become dominant
it means the total weight of the
substrate of a prime
to take major function in the total
weight of all the blocks generated after
block a
in other words most of the future blocks
after a should accumulate to the
substrate of a trend
otherwise a balanced tank may happen so
for a new generative block component
details whether this pen
has been variated into a subgraph if so
it switches from the normal mode to the
conservative
structural ghost mode and later on the
important weighted loss will accumulate
on the substrate of a frame again
and this will make a prime substrate
become dominant again after a while
the small switch could start the tank
once the tank disappeared they will
switch back to the normal mode
there is a new problem about how to tell
if a block is generated not enough
simply using the time stamp in the block
header is not working because
the tanker can fill in any time stamp he
wants and make his neural degenerative
noise look old
so how can we get a trust of no
generation time in a monitor's world
the answer is another blockchain we
introduced timer chain to solve this
problem
the timer chain is absorption embedded
in tree graph with non-gas chain rule
and logic
no block generation rate embed hair
means some tree graph blocks called
thermoblocks
are selected to form this temperature
the lower generation rate is achieved by
the same method next structural goals
where we only see enough very few blocks
to become obnoxious
after having a stable blockchain we can
estimate abnormal generation time
when everybody in an example here
the time machine starts from the
generation of t and ends with not e
block d is not is not in the path of
block a
but its parent block c is in the path of
meaning block c is the latest timo block
in the past of block a
so we measure the generation time of
block a and the temperature height
of block c the time machine cannot be
manipulated by the adversary
so the generation time can trust it
okay so we have talked about how
confidence handles memories attempts
to attempt to weight the risk question
is
how we can make all the participate
nodes
to agree on the total order of all the
blocks and transactions in the nature
and make them contribute to the system
throughput or today altogether
the key idea is that since all the nodes
agree on the pivot chain we should have
a consistent ordering method based on
the pivot chain
here is an example
first each pivot block from one import
and i option block down to the first
evolve whose corresponding pure chain
block happens after it takes block d
for example p is in the past
subgraph of e so it happens before you
but d
is not in the past of its parent block c
so e is the first so e is the first
pivot block after d meaning d belongs to
the e power of e
after assigning each belongs to an epoch
the ordering algorithm is quite
straightforward
first will order blocks based on their
input then with topographically sorted
nodes in each effort
and break ties based on their block id
we can see that the blocks are ordered
epoch by import
and the pivot block on y epoch is always
ordered and lost
because by definition or other blocks in
the same input
will be topologically before it
we have implemented confluence system in
rust and it is open sourced
we have launched our test needs which
can be publicly accessed
on top of the consensus protocol we also
built ethereum virtual machine aka evm
to support the smart contract our smart
contract is mostly compatible with
ethereum's smart country language
solidity
in practice there are several key
optimizations and i would like to
briefly introduce a little bit
the first is that in order to apply the
heaviest sub-tree rule
we have to maintain the total substitute
for each node
which will be continuously updated when
the nature grows
in a naive implementation for each
neopreneur entering the tree graph
it helps update the substitute of all
its ancestors
another chain passed to the genesis
block this introduces a high computation
complexity
of on and cannot be tolerated in
practice
we therefore apply a fancy data
structure called ninka tree
to maintain this weight which reduce
this complexity to
unlocking and becomes acceptable
a second issue is that the
second issue event the pivoting close to
the tail of the nature
will not be then stable and a signage
for a while the total order of the block
close to the tail of nature
will converge to be stable gradually in
a short period
if we immediately execute the
transaction in the block
once the block international because the
total order may change
this will introduce redundant execution
in order to avoid this waste when choose
a deferred execution mechanism where we
will wait for the order of the block
becoming renting stable
then execute it this will not cause
actual confirmation latency of
transactions because
to confirm the transaction we already
have to wait for a block to have a
stable order
after talking about why conflicts can
achieve high throughput and
fast confirmation at the same time here
we run some large
skill generations based on
implementation
we run up to twelve thousands of
conflict funnels are among the insane
two virtual machines
and named the bandwidth of each phone to
20 megabits per second
and the network latency is simulated
between funnels
we made it achieved throughput and the
confirmation latency
we are considerable confirmed if its
confidence is the same and
waiting for sixth block in bitcoin
this is a result where block size is 300
kilobytes and the block generation
weight
is four branch per second its first nuke
and throughput
for confluence reports 9.6 megabits per
second
this is a typical measurement of the
system through put
in such kind of high support branching
system since consumes the protocol
is not a bottleneck at all and the
system is botanic
and natural boundaries so this
measurement is about the bandwidth usage
for
effective block transmission without
incurring significantly
increasing of the message dna and
9.6 megabits per second in roughly half
of the maximum available network
bandwidth
which is near optimal for the p2p
network transmission
this translates to about 4000
transactions per second
with typical transactions as in bitcoin
comparatively this is up to 32 times
the throughput of ghost under the same
city and
it's worth noting that the throughput of
contact keeps stable regardless of the
number of nodes because
orbitals are eventually committed but
the super ghost decreases with the
number of nodes because
increasing the number of nodes will
increase the network dna and cosmophores
making it making next blocks included in
the
pivot chain in addition the transaction
confirmation latency is about 50 seconds
on average in complex
which is a small constant factor of the
block broadcast dna
which is about 15 seconds in our
measurement
and the transformation latency are
stable when we increase the number of
nodes which using
conflux can scale very well to more than
10 thousand
phonons
to conclude components achieve both high
throughput and fast conformation at the
same time
confidence also is safe against both
double spending and the numbness attacks
this is achieved with a normal
concentrator contrast
which allows different ways to pronounce
adaptively and automatically
with 12 000 of those confidence can
reach
9.6 megabits per second throughput
and confirm blocks within one minute
thanks if you are interested in cover
the project you can check
our website here thanks for listening
you