hello everyone my name is chihan nam
i'm from kaist in this presentation i'd
like to introduce
a security enforcement network style
called bastion
or container networks this work is
joint work with kaist and sri
international
okay now let's get started
let's first think about what is a
container a container is an abstraction
at the application layer
that contains everything we need such as
code
libraries and comprehensions in order to
run an application
and containers are much faster and
lighter than virtual machines
since they share the same host with
common and
run right on top of the host os like
typical processes
with such advantages these days the use
of contamination technologies
particularly for the scalp instantiation
of products microservices
has grown so fast
however along with this popularity there
have been so many security issues
around the container world for example
according to three wires state of
content security report
six percent of organizations already
experienced
some security incidents in 2018
47 percent of containers they deployed
had vulnerabilities
every two percent of organizations have
difficulty in investigating security
issues
in their continents
likewise i think these statistics
represent
our current state in continuous security
well
then what kinds of secure solutions are
there for continents these days
i think we can categorize current secure
solutions
in three major parts container image
integrity
application isolation and runtime 3d
detection
based on what they focus on and through
these solutions
we may be able to improve our content
security
but i'd like to highlight that
they mostly focus on containers which
means that
they still have less concern about the
security of container networks
yet so
here i'd like to first show how a
container network looks like
when we think about microservices we can
do them as shown in the alpha figure
however in reality the continents for
microservices are connected to each
other
like the lower figure especially in
darker environments
there are multiple bridges for each
microservice
and containers are linked to the bridges
for their microservices
then how about current environments
in the case of kubernetes all the
counters are what's called the group
according to microservices all
containers are actually connected to
a single world network like the lower
picker
as quantities aims and multi-node
environments
from this container network architecture
some of you may
notice that current container networks
probably have some security problems
due to their architectural design
so in this work we point out five secure
challenges
in current continentals first
we lose the context of a container as
soon as
a network packet from a container is
passed to
a container network we can think that a
container network
is a small version of our latest network
which means that once a packet is
delivered to a container network
or specifically at the host side it's
like the packet
is in the middle of a network somewhere
between network switches
does become the actual guarantee where
the packet
originally comes from and it is possible
that some articles for its metal packets
will be help of any other containers
second there are some limitations in
i-based access controls
used by container networks especially
iptables
current network policies are mostly
defined
based on the ip addresses of containers
even though some secure solutions use
labels instead of hyper addresses to
define net policies
such labels still need to be changed to
specific ip addresses
internally likewise since
all access controls are done by ip
addresses
container networks are still vulnerable
to layered
attacks
third as iptables is located at the host
site
all network policies for containers are
managed
inside of ip tables in a centralized
manner
which means that the number of network
policies will
rapidly increase as the number of
containers increases
and eventually we can face some
performance issues
when the number of policies is beyond
hundreds
due to ideals design issues
fourth one is containers can easily
access the services
running at the host site without any
restriction
all containers have the gateway of a
continental
or external accesses however the gateway
is
actually located at the host network
namespace
which means that a malicious container
can scan
host services and even exploit them in a
malicious purpose
through the gateway
finally there is a special container
called
a metal privilege container it doesn't
have
actual privileges but shares a network
namespace
with the host so it can directly expose
container services through the host ip
addresses
here a critical security concept in a
network privileged container is that
the container can actually access all
network interfaces in the host
including those for other containers
furthermore current secret solutions do
not care about such containers
even though they have a great power in
container networking
for better understanding police wrapper
or paper
in the paper we explain these issues
with the screenshot-based proofs
okay so far we talked about the security
issues in current container networks
then how can we make our container
networks secure
to answer this question we propose
bachelor
that is an intelligent content-aware
communication center box
for intercontinental networking
in this world we focused on how to
protect network
the abuse the secret challenges we
discussed
and how to isolate the content networks
in a more fine-grained way
then to act to achieve such goals
we designed three key components batch
manager
and data visibility and track visibility
services
which are two key services of belgium's
security staff
here is a general container environment
and
this shows the over architectural
bastion especially
where bastian is actually deployed
we see that bastion is deployed at the
network interface of each container and
additionally at the external interface
for
the overall network in the case of
grantees
here we don't modify any existing
container platform or container network
but all network traffic is controlled at
the closed locations from containers
and delivered to destinations through
bastion
instead of a container network or a
security purpose
now i'm going to briefly explain our key
components
and let's first start with the batch
manager
the main rules of the batch manager are
collecting all network information for
deploying containers
through container platforms like docker
and kubernetes
and managing bastion security stack for
each container
first in terms of container network
information
it includes container deployment
computations
and metal policies for each container
and based on such information bastion
first builds
a content network map for all containers
then it automatically discovers in the
container dependencies among those
containers
by figuring out what kinds of containers
are deployed
and how they have some dependencies on
other containers and finally
it builds an intercontinental dependency
map like this
in the meantime bastian deployed the
security stacks
for newly created containers
and update the container network
and intercontinental dependency maps
into their security stacks
if there is any change in the container
network
and intercontinental independence maps
for the existing containers
bachelor earth updates them into the
secret steps for
the containers whose information needs
to be updated
in runtime now we have all information
we need
for fine grain network control and
network isolation
so let's talk about the security
services
fashion provides
as the first secure service bastion's
network
service restricts unnecessary
connectivity among containers
to do this two key functionalities are
introduced to handle container discovery
and intercontainer communications
in terms of intercontinental networking
container discovery is the first step to
identify
other containers that would be
communication targets
using arp requests however
as we get as you guess current secure
solutions
do not control room eye-based
communications
the this process can be exploited by
malicious containers
so best jumpers filters out any
unnecessary container discovery
that doesn't pertain to the present
containers
dependence map simply
since all network information for
dependent containers
is in the container network and
dependency maps bastion blocks
any container discovery for unknown
targets
by directly handling all records for
container discovery by esl
rather than broadcasting the request to
the container network
unfortunately although the direct arp
handler
handle prevents containers from
performing unbounded to police discovery
this coverage is limited to container
level isolation
which means that it does not address
medicine's accesses
among dependent containers so
to further restrict the reachability of
containers
bastion implements container aware the
dog isolation
we can simply think that this is a kind
of an
access control mechanism specifically
designed for containers
since all accessible services for
dependent containers
are in the inter container dependence
map
whenever a pack comes from a container
to bachchan
it inspects the packet with the given
accessory services and if there is no
match
you simply drop the packet otherwise
import the packet to
the corresponding destination
next the third visuality service
provides point
point integrity and confidentiality
among continuing network pools as the
first step
bastion conducts the search verification
of incoming packet
in the case of current secure solutions
they simply use
the source ipm mac addresses impact
headers
however you can easily guess that they
can reverse by malicious containers
so as an alternative solution
often research may be used with incoming
virtual reports
for search verification however
open way switch does not support a nut
operation
which means that we need to specifically
define net
policies for all possible individual
follows between containers
thus unlike such solutions in bastion's
source of education deliveries the
current metadata
to verify the specific sources of
incoming packets
lastly current linux network stacks
cannot prevent
the exposure of intercontainer traffic
from other containers
if you are wondering why they cannot
prevent such exposure
please wrap up our paper
anyway if a malicious container has a
capability to
redirect the traffic of the target
container to itself
it can monitor all traffic from and to
the target container
so to implement less privileged traffic
exposure
that can utilize the recent linux
networking features
xp and evpn and directly inject net
packets
from a source container to a destination
container
so the network packets actually bypass
the container network at the host site
which means that no one can see the
network traffic
between the source and destination
containers from the
container network
okay now i'd like to show how our secret
services
can prevent containers from network
objects
before that i'm introducing an alt-tex
scenario that shows
the current state of container network
security
here there are two microservices and
the lower one is allowed for anyone to
access
and the upper one is only allowed for
registered users to access
here the basic idea of this scenario is
that
an attacker tries to access the
microservice for
for public and get into one of the
containers
in the microservice then while
monitoring network traffic
coming from a registered user the
article replies
the contents requested by the user
with the fake contents and the user
actually received the fake contents
here i'd like to show the steps that the
article carried out
once the article got into one of the
containers for the public microservice
the optical versus scan neighbor
continuous
and we can see that the autocross found
all containers
not only in the public micro service but
also in the microservice for registered
users
then the autographs put the a target
container
and reduced all network traffic of the
and the article injects a big contents
while dropping the original one
so finally we can see that a user
receives the fake content
instead of the original one
these objects are quite straightforward
but
what i want to say here is that they are
still
visible in the current container network
then how can bastion prevent containers
from such natural hotels
first let's see how bastion restricts
the topology's visuality
of the article's container we see
there is no restriction on the
container's reachability without batcha
but once we deploy background
as shown in the lower screenshot the
article can only see
the containers that it depends on
second in terms of how bastion
hides the network traffic from other
containers
here we assume that the article always
built the target container
and could redirect both traffic
of the target container
and as shown in the office upper
screenshot
in general we can see the network travel
of the target container at the optical
side
however once we have once we deployed
bastion
no packet is actually monitored at the
optical container
by the way here to show the difference
we intentionally allowed the source to
destination flows to be visible
the destination to source flows to be
hidden by
bastion
third in terms of packet injection
when the article injects a fake packet
in the case in this case a tcp reset
packet
into a container network the packet is
naturally delivered to
the target container if no fashion is
deployed
however as soon as bastion is deployed
those fake packets are immediately
dropped
at the net interface of the article's
container
due to bastion's source verification
at this point point you may wonder if
the over network performance might be
degraded when bastion is deployed
since bastion performs additional
security inspections
so let's see how it performs
here this table shows the therapist
of intercontinental communications
within the same host and across holes
you can see that compared to the
baseline the overall purpose were
improved when
best when we uh deployed bachelor
since bachchan's director fought in
macon gym
particularly made all network traffic
between containers
bypassing a content network more
specifically
bypassing the network step at the host
side
but in the case of intercontinental
communications across holes
the baseline was quite low so the
improvements
by bastion or not that high
and we also deployed bastion in several
container networks
and so the performance implements as we
expected
the in the cases of all container
networks we used
we could see batch change shows better
performance than the existing container
networks while providing strong network
security
okay now let's sum up this presentation
in this work we have investigated the
security of current container networks
and discovered several security
challenges that are critical
in continuing networking then
to cover such security issues we have
proposed bastion
which can intelligently isolate into
container communications
in a more fine-grained way and
effectively mitigate lateral attacks
that abuse the security issues against
pure containers
okay this is the end of my presentation
thank you for listening if you have any
questions please contact me by email
thank you
you