hello everyone i'm hassan from the
university of michigan
and today i'm going to present our work
only lip is a lightweight and efficient
data path for remote memory
at its core it uses an online
prefetching technique
to reduce the latency bottleneck during
remote memory access
and this eventually improves the
end-to-end application level performance
this work is done by me and my advisor
mosher of chowdhury
so before we start to talk about lip
let's first discuss
why we care about remote memory what are
the issues with existing remote memory
frameworks
and how we come up with the design idea
of limb
memory intensive applications are widely
being used in many cases
like low latency services and data
intensive analytics
this kind of application can provide you
significant performance benefit
when the whole working set can fully fit
into the host machine's physical memory
however if the host machine cannot
provide them with enough memory
they need to go through expensive disk
operation and at that point
they face severe performance drop to
illustrate this
we run tpcs workload on top of an
in-memory database system named voldevi
and measured its performance in terms of
two foot per second
here higher throughput means better
performance
as you can see if we take away 25
percent of the memory from the host
machine
volte will start to swap to the disk and
at that point
it loses almost 80 percent of its
performance if we take away 25
more memory that means in 50
configuration
voltaville loses almost 95 of its
performance and it can hardly run
same thing happens for latency sensitive
applications like paragraph
here we run page rank algorithm on top
of twitter data set
of our paragraph and we measure the end
to end completion times in terms of
performance matrix as you can see
similar to voldemi when you take a half
of the memory from paragraph
it starts to show up to the disk and
loses almost 75 percent of its
performance
this is obvious you take your memory
your application will lose performance
but this performance drop is highly
disproportional to the memory loss
for example for vol db and paragraph
taking a half of the memory causes them
to lose 38 times and four times of their
performance respectively
and to handle this while deploying this
kind of application in the cloud
users usually allocate more memory than
needed and this put us
in a situation between a rock and a hard
place in one case if we allocate less
memory
we will face severe performance loss and
on the other hand if we allocate more
memory than needed
then we will face significant resource
under utilization in the cluster
for example in big clusters like google
facebook and alibaba
almost 30 to 40 percent of the cluster
weight memory remains under utilized
most of the time
more importantly this under utilization
is not uniform throughout the cluster
some machine can have significant amount
of free memory while the others are in
under civil memory pressure the idea of
memory desegregation can solve this
problem
by exposing a cluster with global memory
pool in this setup
when a machine is under severe memory
pressure like machine one in this figure
it can use the free memory available in
other machine in the cluster
and therefore it can run more tasks and
more applications
the idea of memory desegregation is
getting much popular these days
with the availability of ultrafast
network like rdma
over the last few years people designed
memory designation framework
to use the remote memory during paging
file access
and even running the whole operating
system in a disaggregated manner
in this kind of frameworks memory uh the
network is in
involved and and for this reason the
performance loss is inevitable
for example to access a four kilobyte
page from the
local disk local uh memory it can takes
hundreds of nanoseconds
however to access it from the remote
memory
through the rdma it takes around four
microseconds
and this is without any kind of
background load at the presence of
background load
it can cause up to tens of microseconds
which is orders of magnitude higher than
the local memory access latency
recent study shows that to maintain the
performance loss
of such frameworks under an unnoticeable
bound
the end-to-end memory access latency
should not go beyond three microseconds
and existing memory desegregation
frameworks can hardly achieve that
our analysis says that there are two
prime reasons behind this
the first one is the traditional data
overhead while accessing the remote
memory
and the second one is the latency
variation in the network
to understand the root cause behind this
latency overhead
let's see what happens inside the linux
panel during a page fault event
in linux when a page fault happens by
process
the kernel stretch to serve it from the
storage device
and in traditional setup this is the
here to provide a faster data service
the operating system maintains page
cache
if the page is found in the cache it can
be served instantly
however if the page is not there then a
disk access is a must
in that case the device mapping layer
initially figures out the position of
the page within the disk
and therefore it creates a biorequest to
the generic block layer
now the generic block layer is optimized
to hide the disk
signal it always tries to maximize the
sequential
excess as much as possible that's why it
intentionally adds delay by putting the
biorecast into a
request queue so that it can match
multiple continuous buy requests
to a single large request and eventually
the bio request is served from the
storage device
and in existing memory segregation
framework all the remote memory access
requests go through all of these buyer
operations
even though they have no value in remote
storage
if we look into the latency breakdown of
database operations we can see that if a
page can be served from the cache
this can be served within hundreds of
nanoseconds and this
is the first path of memory access
however you can if
it cannot be served from the cache due
to the expensive buy operations
it goes through a delay of 30
microseconds on average
and in the worst case it can go up to
milliseconds and even hundreds of
microseconds
and this is the slow path of memory
access as you can see
the latest in the slow path is way
higher than the three microsecond
requirement we mentioned earlier
so here the takeaway is if we want to
provide a better performance during
memory desegregation framework
we want to increase the number of first
part access
and to do so we need to increase the
cache
here an effective prefecture can improve
the cash rate by bringing more accurate
pages into the cash beforehand
and the second obvious thing is we want
to make our slow path more faster
as bio as bio operations are completely
unnecessary during remote memory we need
to get rid of them from our slows path
considering these two observation we
designed our framework leave which is
basically an online remote memory
prefetcher
this is a software solution to identify
memory access pattern of each process
and therefore to prefetch pages in a
fast
cache efficient and resilient manner
without modifying the application or
hardware
in lib we cut all the unnecessary block
layer operations from the slow path
and make it much much faster and leaner
we track each process page access
history into an fixed size circular
buffer
and we employ and majority-based pattern
detection technique on top of them
to find the availability of any pattern
within the page access stream
we therefore bring more accurate pages
into the cache and
improve the cachet to reduce the cache
allocation wait time
we employ an eager cash prevention
policy here in this presentation i am
going to talk mostly about the linux
mostly about the leaves prefecture in
our paper we have detailed
description about the rest of the
components
so before we talk about the lips
preparation let's see how the existing
prefetching techniques work
and how leaves prefecture is different
from them
in today's linux they use a read ahead
graffiti technique which is ideally
optimized to hide distinct time that's
why
when accessing a disk it always suggests
to bring
few more extra pages around the page
address
and while making this prefetching
decision it does not consider the page
access history
it only considered the last access if
the last two accesses are sequential
then it aggressively prefetch more pages
into the cache
and this might sometimes cause cache
pollution
on the other hand if the two excesses
are not sequential
then it becomes much more conservative
and it shut down the prefetching
these are the two exchange situations
moreover linux prefetcher cannot
distinguish the processes which call the
prefetch request
this has some drawbacks for example in
linux processors share the same soft
space
so if two different process calls page
fault on two different pages
which are basically in continuous
subspace linux will consider them a
sequential access
and therefore it will bring more pages
into the cache and eventually
waste the cache space and the most
important thing
is that is that linux cannot identify
any short term irregularity in
the page access history now to become an
real-time prefecture and prefetching
algorithm should have
certain following certain properties for
example
it should have low latency in
computation and it has
low resource overhead to be generic it
should be transparent to
applications and it should not depend on
any specific hardware or software
requirements
it should be aware of temporal and
special logic in speech
in page access events and most
importantly
it should keep the cache position as low
as possible
next online and stride are too easy to
implement and generate prefetching
algorithm
but they causes high cache pollution
most of the time instruction-based
pre-phasing technique
usually depends on a specific hardware
device or
it depends on the in um compiling
injected code
and that's why they often cause high
resource overhead
moreover they cause a high cash
pollution most of the time
linux video head has most of the
following
most of the mentioned characteristics
but as i mentioned earlier during the
presence of irregularity
they also cause high cash pollution
while most of the prefetching techniques
fall short of either either of the
characteristics our prefecture lip can
fulfill
all of them and now we will see how it
works
on a high level leap has two components
the trend detection algorithm
detects the availability of trend in the
page access stream
and based on the availability
availability of the trend
and preface utilization the prefetch
window size detection
algorithm defines how many pages we need
to bring
with during a prefetch request and both
of this component works
in linear linear time and constant
memory space
so after we determine the prefetch
window size
if there is a trend in the page access
history
leaves prefetcher will follow the trend
to bring more pages into the cache
otherwise it will stick to the
previously found trend
and if the prefetch window size is zero
we do not prefetch anything we just
bring the requested page
and during train detection leaves
prefetcher do not look for any strict
pattern
rather it looks for the majority
elements in the page access stream
and this makes us flexible to any sort
of irregularities in the page access
pattern
so when a process follow a
train for a certain period of time this
can be
easily detected from the last few
excesses of pages
and that's why lib initially
do not look for the do not look over the
whole
page access history rather it takes a
smaller
window size which is basically a
fraction of the latest element of the
page access history
and therefore it employs a linear time
one more majority voting algorithm to
find the majority return within the
window
if the window does not have any trend it
increases the window size
and repeats the same process again and
again until
it reaches to the maximum size capacity
the whole process will be simplified
after we go through some examples
let's say at nsm t3 our history buffer
has a size of 8
and it has the following four components
now the numbers on top of the boxes
shows the page addresses the number at
the bottom of the
boxes like t0 t1 these are the timestamp
when the page
accesses were requested and the number
inside the boxes are the difference
between the last two page addresses
here the colored box indicates the head
of the buffer at current time
now at time t3 the page addresses follow
a trend of -3
and this can be detected by the majority
element within the window of t0 to t3
let's say at time t4 the after the time
t4 the trend of minus 3 is going to
disappear
and a new trend of plus 2 is going to
appear
now when a trend starts it is hard to
determine whether this is a
real trend or something irregular is
happening
in between while prevailing the previous
trend so at time t7
lip does not mandate for any nutrient
however
after the arrival of the th element now
we can surely say that
a new trend has started and we will
forget the chain of minus 3
and we'll follow the trend of plus 2
during prefetching
in the next example we will see how lip
can detect the
trend even at the presence of
irregularity
let's say at time t 11 instead of
following the trend of plus two
the page addresses following follow a
trend of plus four
at time t12 something random stuff is
happening
and from time t14 the trend of plus 2
continues
and we can detect the trend within the
window within the
history buffer using the majority
elements of the winter
here in the smaller window of t12 or t5
t2 to t15 even though the trend is not
available
if we look into the larger window of t8
to t15
here the majority elements are plus two
and hence we can detect the majority
detect the trend of plus 2 among the
irregularities considering the majority
elements
while detecting the prefetch window size
we consider two information
the number of cash and the availability
of trend
here the cash sheet indicates a preface
utilization
leaves tracks the number of cashiers
between two consecutive prefetch
requires
and therefore it adjusts the prefetch
window size accordingly
it increases the prefetch window size
with the increase in the cache
however if there is no cachet that means
either random access is happening
or our prefetching algorithm is doing
bad in both cases
we need to slow down however instead
we do not while slowing down we do not
do
drastic shutdown because this may cause
steel situation in prefetching
whether here we look for any
availability of trend
and if we find any trend in the page
access history
we cautiously say to bring another extra
page along the requested one
however if no trend is found then we
don't bring
any extra page along the requested one
which has been the requested page
here during the slow down we always do
it gradually
so that we our briefing prefetching
algorithm
remains flexible to any certain changes
in the page access
page accessories we implement lib
inside linux kernel version 4.4 and
deploy it on a
rdm enabled cluster we integrate it
on top of two state-of-the-art memory
desegregation frameworks infinity swap
and limit regions we therefore evaluate
it using both micro benchmark and real
world applications
integration of link improves the
performance of both of these frameworks
however due to the time constraint here
i am going to present the benefit of
leave over infinite swap
due to its lightweight data path lib
improved the
remote page excess latency during
sequential patterns
the integration of leave improved the
infinites of
median four kilobyte page access latency
by four times
in linux when the stride size is
greater than the maximum frequency
window size every
prefixed page will be and waste however
in lead both the stride and sequential
exercises are identical
that's why lift provides the same
low remote excess latency during any
sized pattern of
any size any size straight pattern
leaves majority-based pattern detection
has benefit over the
strict pattern detection technique for
example for paragraph
lip can detect 30 more sequential
excesses
in linux they only consider the last two
accesses and that's why
any non-sequential access is basically a
straight access to it
on the other hand as we consider a
certain amount of page access stream
we can efficiently distinguish between
irregular and straight excess pattern
for example for paragraph lip can detect
the 4
almost 14 percent of the non-sequential
excesses as
irregular axis pattern and during
irregularity
it does not prefetch and for
applications
with high irregular access pattern like
memcached
this no prefetching helps most by not
wasting the cash
space not wasting the cpu cycle and the
network bandwidth now we will see the
performance benefit of lip
over real world applications as you
mentioned earlier
throughput sensitive applications live
boldly when half of the memory is taken
away from them
they faces almost 38 times performance
drop
due to swapping to the disk swapping to
remote memory using infinite swap can
improve the situation
but here we still faces students
performance drop
however due to the lightweight data path
and efficient prefetching
in lib volume faces almost the local
memory performance
benefit when it is integrated with
infinite straw
leaves performance benefit prevails even
at the presence of
extreme memory constraint for example
when the host machine can provide only
25 percent of the memory
voltav cannot run with disk with
infinity swap
it can run hardly almost losing 95
percent of its performance
on the other hand lip provides almost
some linear performance drop in such
situation
here even though almost three-fourth of
the memory is taken away
integration of flip provides the vault
db only
2.4 times performance loss
finally we'll see the benefit of each of
the leaps component
removing the unnecessary block layer
operations from leaves data path
gives a single microsecond latency up to
the 95 percentage
inclusion of the prefetcher gives a sub
microsecond latency up to the 85
percenter and the tail latency improves
by 12 percent
on top of this lightweight data the
eager cash eviction policy
reduces the page allocation wait time
and therefore it improves the tail
latency by another 22 percent
our expense only
from our experience only we realize the
scope of falling research direction
to further enhance its performance in
today's linux memory address space
is managed at the process level thread
specific prefetching
and page tracking can help us to
efficiently identify multiple concurrent
streams
originated from different chairs however
to do so
we need to significantly modify the
whole virtual memory subsystem
in a future work we want to realize the
scope of low overhead threat specific
prefetching and page tracking
in our current work we mostly focus on
augmenting existing remote memory
frameworks
that's why it doesn't live in such a way
that it remains
transparent to the remote io interface
in our future work
we want to integrate an optimized i o
interface
considering the effect of load balancing
fault tolerance
data locality and applications
application specific isolation in remote
memory
to summarize lib is a lightweight and
efficient data path for remote memory
which can operate without any
modification in the application and
hardware
at its core it employs an online
preferencing technique
which is complemented by and linear data
path and eager cash eviction policy
with a goal to improve the remote eye
latency
and application level performance and
that's all from me today
thank you for being here and listening
to my presentation