hello
everyone my name is funjang i'm going to
present our recent work on fine-grained
window-based
stream processing on cpu gpu integrated
architectures
this is our joint work of yemi
university of china
technical university berlin national
university of singapore
this is the outline of our presentation
next i will introduce a background
first let's look at two important
concepts
in string processing bulk synchronous
parallel model
and continuous operator model for bug
synchronous parallel model
it is conducted on the query granularity
where the whole query with multiple
operators
on each batch of input data is
dispatched
on one device saba is an excellent work
forensic mode 16 and take this model
such a mechanism naturally minimizes the
communication
overhead among operators inside the same
query
it is hence suitable in discrete cpu gpu
architectures
their pcie overhead is significant and
shall be avoided
as much as possible for continuous
operator model
it is conducted on the operator
granularity
where each operator of a query can be
independently placed
at a device please note that cpu and gpu
can
concurrently execute in both cases
only the granularity is different
previous research
mainly takes bulk synchronous parallel
model
however we find that continuous operator
is also useful and particularly
it is very suitable for integrated
architectures
the integrated architecture usually
consists of a cpu
an accelerator such as gpu under shared
memory
in 2011 amd releases
its integrated architecture called apu
next intel nvidia also released similar
integrated architectures
compared to the discrete cpu gpu
architecture
both cpus and gpus are integrated on the
same chip
the most attractive feature of such
integration is the shared main memory
which is available to both devices the
integrated architectures
have no pcie transfer all ahead and have
shared global memory and high energy
efficiency
we show a comparison between the
integrated and discrete architectures in
this table
these architectures are used in our
evaluation
although the integrated architectures
have low computation capacity
than the discrete architecture currently
the integrated architecture is a
potential trend for
future generation of processors moreover
its price and power are usually low
we consider supporting the basic sequel
functions with
screen precision as shown in the figure
sql on screen precision consists of the
following four major concepts
data stream which is a sequence of
tuples
a tuple is a finite ordered list of
elements
and each tuple has a time step
window which refers to a finite sequence
of tuples
which is a data unit to be processed in
a query
the window in stream has two features
window size and window slide window size
represents the size of the data unit to
be processed
and window slide denotes a sliding
distance
between two adjacent windows
operators which has a minimum processing
units
for the data in a window in this work
we support common relational operators
including projection
selection aggregation group by
and join queries
which are a form of data processing each
of which
consists of us at least one operator and
the space down windows
additionally note that in real stream
processing system
such as saba data are processed in batch
granularity
instead of window granularity a batch
can be a group of windows
when the window size is small or a part
of a window
when the window side is extremely large
now let's look at the motivation
we analyze the operators inquiry and
find that
different operators show various device
preferences on
integrated architectures some operators
achieve higher performance on the cpu
device and others have higher
performance on the gpu device
we use a simple query of group by and
aggregation on the integrated
architecture
for illustration as shown in the slide
the gpu queue is used to sequentially
execute
the queries on the gpu while the cpu
queue
is used to execute the related queries
on the cpu
the window size is 256
tuples and the window slide is 16 4.
each batch contains 64
000 tuples and each tuple is
certain tool bytes the input data are
sinceritically
generated which is described in our
paper
when the query runs on the cpu google
buy takes about
18.2 microseconds and the aggregation
takes about
5.2 microseconds
however when the query runs on the gpu
go by takes about 6.7 microseconds
and the aggregation takes about 5.8
microseconds
we first evaluate the performance of
operators on a single device
in the table this table shows that
using a single type of device cannot
achieve the
optimal performance for all operators
the aggregation includes the operators
of
sum count and average and they have
similar performance
we use sum as a representative for
aggregation
from the table we can see that
projection
selection and group by achieve better
performance on the gpus
on the cpu vr aggregation and
draw achieve better performance on the
sound on the gpu additionally
projection shows similar performance on
cpu and gpu devices
specifically for join the cpu
performance is
about 6 times the gpu performance
such different device preferences
inspire us
to perform fine-grained screen precision
on integrated architectures
based on this analysis we propose our
key idea
fine-grained string precision a
fine-grained string precise method
that can consider both integrated
architecture characteristics
and operator features shall have better
performance
first corrun the operators that do not
reach the memory bandwidth limit
second put operators on the preferred
devices that can bring more performance
benefits
however enabling fine-grained stream
precision and integrated architectures
is complicated by the features of sql
stream precising
and integrated architectures we
summarize
three major challenges as follows
the first challenge is application
topology combined with architectural
characteristics
application topology in string
processing
refers to the organization and execution
order
of the operators in a sql query
first the relation among operators
could be more complicated in practice
the operators may be represented as a
deck
instead of a chain which contains more
parallel acceleration opportunities
second with architectural
characteristics considered
such as the cpu and gpu architectural
differences
the topology with computing resource
distribution becomes
very complex in such situations
how to perform fine-grained operator
placement
for application topology on different
devices
of integrated architectures becomes a
challenge
the second challenge is sql query plan
optimization with shared main memory
first a sql query in stream precising
can consist of many operators
and the execution plan of these
operators
may cause different bandwidth pressures
and
device preferences second
in many cases independent operators
may not consume all the memory bandwidth
but quaranism together could exceed
the bandwidth limit we need to analysis
the memory bandwidth
requirement of qurani third
cpus and gpus have different preferred
memory
access patterns current measures do not
consider these
complex situations of shared main memory
in the integrated architectures
the third challenge comes from the
adjustment
for dynamic workload during stream
precision
stream data are changing dynamically in
distributions and
arrival speeds which is challenging to
adapt first workload change detection
and computing resource adjustment need
to be done
in a lightweight manner and they are
critical to performance
second the query plan may also need to
be updated
adaptively because the operator
placement
strategy based on the initial state
may not be suitable when the workload
changes
third during adaptation
online stream processing needs to be
served
efficiently resource adjustment
and query plan adaptation on the fly
may incur run time overhead because we
need to
adjust not only the operators in the dac
but also the hardware computing
resources to each
operator additionally the adjustment
among different streams also needs to be
considered
now let's look at our solution
called find stream
we propose a framework called fun stream
for fine-grained stream precision on
integrated architectures
the overview of fun stream is showing
this slide
the workflow of one stream is as follows
when the engine starts it first
processes
several batteries using only the cpus
or the gpus to gather useful data
second based on this data it builds a
performance model for
operators of a query on different
devices
third after the performance model is
built
the dispatcher starts to work and the
fine-grained stream precision begins
each operator shall be assigned to the
course of the cpu of the gpu for
parallel execution
additionally the workload could be
dynamic
for dynamic workload query plan
adjustment and resource reallocation
need to be conducted
we first study the topology
the query plan can be represented as a
dac
in our paper we concentrate on
relational queries
we show an example in this slide where
opi
represents an operator op7
and op11 can represent joins
we follow the terminology in compiler
domain and
call the operators from the beginning of
the operator after join
to the operator that merges with another
operator as a branch
hence the query plan is also a branch
tag
file stream involves suite optimizations
the first optimization is branch qurani
which means that the independent
branches can be
executed in parallel we use an
example in this slide for illustration
assume that the time for different
branches
is showing in their slide if we corrupt
the three branches simultaneously
then the execution can be partitioned
into
three stages with different overlapping
situations
if the required bandwidth for stage i
exceeds the system maximum
bandwidth we can perform a branch
scheduling optimization
the second optimization is batch
pipeline
we can also partition the dac into
phases
and perform co-running in pipeline
between
phases for precising different batches
for simplicity in this part
we assume that the number of phases in
the deck
is two please note that when the
platform has
enough resources the pipeline for
operators
can be deeper we show a simple example
in this slide
the operators in phase 1 and the
operators in phase 2
need to be mapped into different compute
units
so that these two phases can corrun in
pipeline
figure b shows the execution flow in
pipeline when fund stream
completes the processing for back one in
phase one
and starts to process batch one in phase
two
find stream can start to process part
two in phase 1 simultaneously
phase 1 and phase 2 can call run because
they rely on different compute units
the third optimization is for handling
dynamic workload
in fine stream we use a lightweight
dynamic resource reallocation strategy
when the workload ingestion rate of
branch decreases we can calculate
the reduced ratio and assume that
such proportion of computing resources
in that branch can be transferred to the
other branches
we use an example in figure 8 for
illustration
in figure 8 19 workload
after operator op1
flow to op2 when the workload
state changes to the state in figure b
part of the computing resource
associated
with op2 shall be assigned to op3
accordingly
we present the system execution flow in
this slide
thread 1 is used to catch input data
where thread 2 is used to process or
catch the data
the detailed execution flow is as
follows
first when find stream starts a new
query
the dispatcher ethicals the query on the
cpu
for batch one and then on the gpu for
back
tool second during the single device
executions find stream conducts
online profiling during which
the operator related data that are used
to build the performance model are
obtained
including the cpu and gpu performance
and the bandwidth utilization third
with this data file stream builds a
performance model considering branch
co-running
and batch pipeline first after
building the model find stream generates
several query plans
with detailed resource distribution
with a generated query plan the
dispatcher performs
fine-grained scheduling for precising
the following
batches when dynamic workload
is detected fund stream performs related
adjustment
for the operators in fine stream
when we use the operator code from
omnidb
please note that the goal of this work
is to provide a fine-grained
stream precising method on integrated
architectures
let's look at the evaluation
we perform experiments on four platforms
two integrated platforms and two
discrete
platforms the baseline is a bug
synchronous
parallel model which is server in our
experiment
we use four data sites in the evaluation
the first data set is google compute
cluster monitoring
which emulates a cluster management
scenario
the second data set is anomaly detection
in smart grids
which is about detection in energy
consumption
from different devices of a smart
electricity grade
the third data side is linear road
benchmark
which models a network of totals
these quizzes come from real world
applications
the first data set is a synthetically
generated data set for evaluating
independent operators we are each
tuple consists of a 16 4 bit timestamp
and six certain two bit attributes
drawn from a uniform distribution
we use snack queries to evaluate the
overall performance of the fine-grained
stream precision engine on the
integrated architectures
for example for the first query
we select timestamp category and
cpu information from task invent
and group by category
let's look at throughput we explore the
throughput
of one stream for the night queries
result shows a processing throughput of
the best single device
saba and the fine stream for this
queries
on both the a10 7850k
and ryzen 5 2400g
platforms fine streams achieve the best
performance in most cases
this slide reports the latency of
different queries on the integrated
architectures
in this work latency is defined as a end
to end
time from the time a query starts
through the time it ends
fine stream has a lowest lessons among
these measures
we show the relationship between
throughput and the latency
of both fine stream and server in this
slide
which shows that queries with high
throughput usually have low latency and
vice versa
we further studied the cpu and gpu
utilization of saba and the front stream
and use a 87850k platform for
illustration
as shown in this slide
in most cases fine stream utilizes the
gpu device
better on the integrated architecture
current gpu on the integrated
architecture is less powerful than the
discrete
gpu the discrete gpus exhibit
1.8 to 5.7 times higher throughput than
the integrated architectures
due to the more computational power of
discrete
gpus however the integrated architecture
demonstrates lower processing latency
compared to the discrete architectures
when the data transmission cost between
the host and memory
and gpu memory in the workload is
significant
fine stream on integrated architectures
shows a high price
throughput ratio compared to saba on the
discrete architectures
this slide shows the comparison of this
price throughput ratio
on average fine stream of the integrated
architectures
outperform saba on the discrete
architectures by 10.4 times
we also analyze the energy efficience of
fine stream and saba on average
fine stream on the integrated
architectures
is 1.8 times energy efficient
than saba on the discrete architectures
let's look at the conclusion
we propose a first functioning
window-based relational screen
processing framework
that adopts continuous operator model
and
takes advantages of the spectral
features of
integrated architectures
we develop lightweight query plan
adaptations for handling dynamic
workloads
with a performance model that considers
both the operator
and architecture characteristics
we evaluate find stream on a set of
stream queries to demonstrate
the performance benefits our current
opportunities
thank you