hi my name is alex conway and i'm at
vmware research
and today i'm going to talk about a new
key value store called splinterdb
our goal with splinterdb was to create a
key value store that would perform well
across a wide range of parameters and
configurations
and this especially means focusing on
some of the hard cases
the three sort of hard cases that we
focused on were the following
the first is fast storage and our
approach to fast storage is to use new
data structures which lower io
amplification and cpu overhead while
enabling concurrency we also wanted to
tackle the common hard case of small
key value pairs and our approach to that
is to keep our key value pairs sorted
and packed into data blocks
and to delay merging as much as possible
we also wanted to do this while using
only a small amount of cash
and our approach to that is to make all
of the data structures in splinter
swappable in order to gracefully degrade
under cash pressure
in this talk i'm going to start by
discussing some of the challenges with
fast storage
then i'm going to give an overview of
splinter db and talk a little bit about
its
performance then i'm going to dive into
some of the details of the data
structure underlying splinter db
the size tier be the epsilon tree
finally i'm going to discuss a very cool
algorithm enabled by that data structure
called the flush and compact algorithm
okay so let's start with fast storage
back in the day people used to use all
kinds of things like slide rules vhs
tapes and fountain pens
and they used to use different
performance models depending on whether
they were doing their
processing internally or whether they
were writing their data out to disk
and you can see this for example if you
look at key value stores
so for internal key value stores you see
data structures like hash tables and
binary search trees
and you see implementations like
memcache d redis and others
however if you look at uh
key value stores that write their data
to disk you'll see a different
set of data structures like b trees and
more modern data structures like log
structured merged trees and b the
epsilon trees
the implementations that you'll see are
different too like rocks db and cila
and this makes a lot of sense if you
look at the type of devices that these
models were originally created for
such as hard drives so let me take a few
a minute to explain what's going on with
these thermometers here on the left
so suppose that we have a two gigahertz
processor that's writing some
that's processing some data that's being
read or written to a hard drive
and first suppose that uh the access
pattern of that data is random so the
processor is only going to process one
64-bit word
in every i o that the hard drive does
in that case the process will have about
200 million cycles
to process that word which is
essentially an eternity and that's
shown over here on this red random
thermometer
if on the other hand the access pattern
is sequential and the processor
is going to be processing every single
word in all of the ios
in that case the the process will have
about 120 cycles to process
each word which is substantially fewer
and that's shown on this purple
thermometer here
now solid state drives are substantially
faster
and this particular solid state device
in this example
uh leaves the processor about 100
000 cycles uh to process each word in a
random access pattern and about 30
in a sequential access pattern which is
already starting to get a little bit
tight
now on modern and block addressable nvme
devices such as the intel optane series
the process will have about 20 000
cycles if the access pattern is random
which is still a lot
but in the case where the access pattern
is sequential and the
algorithm is using uh its ios
efficiently
the process will have about six cycles
to process each word
now that's a very small amount of time
that maybe is enough time to route the
data somewhere or do some simple hashing
but it's not enough time to do
substantial processing on the data
do sorting or anything like that and so
the takeaway from this is that for nvme
we're going to need
data structures that optimize both they
need to be efficient with the i o
but they're also going to have to be
efficient with their cpu in order to
keep up with the i o capabilities of the
device
as a result where for key value stores
one will often talk about the right
amplification of an insertion workload
um you'll hear me in this talk refer to
uh this sort of loose term work
amplification
which is meant to encapsulate both the i
o and the cpu overhead
okay so now i can introduce splinter db
splinter db is a key value store which
handles these tough cases
fast storage small key value pairs and
small cash
now in this talk i'm mostly going to
focus on the fast storage side of things
but you will see that in our benchmarks
we use small key value pairs and a small
cache
splinterdb approaches this problem by
using a new
a new data structure called the size
tier b the epsilon tree
and the idea behind the size to the
epsilon tree is to reduce the amount of
work
that uh that workloads perform both in
terms of i o and cpu
while enabling a high degree of
concurrency on both uh
lookup and insertion workloads
so before i dive into the details of the
size tier be the epsilon tree
let's look at splinter db's performance
in order to do that let me introduce the
state of the art rocks db
reading from wikipedia roxdb is a high
performance embedded database for key
value data
it is a fork of leveldb by facebook
optimized to exploit many cpu cores
and make efficient use of fast storage
such as ssds for i o bound workloads
so the setup that we use to benchmark
splinterdb
has an intel optane 905p block
addressable nvme
it has 32 gigahertz cores and we perform
our
benchmarks on small key value pairs and
using
a cache size that's about five percent
of the total data set size
so let's look first at insertion
throughput
so this plot here shows the insertion
throughput for the ycsb
load workload which is a uniform uh
which is a workload that consists
entirely of uniformly random
keys so here the y-axis is the
throughput in thousands of operations
per second and so higher is better
so as you can see splinterdb can perform
about seven times as many insertions per
second as roxdb
what's interesting about this is if we
look at the i o amplification
that both systems uh incurred during
this workload
splinter db has about half the i o
amplification of roxdb
and so what this means is what this
leaves us is that splinter db
is using substantially more of the
device bandwidth it uses 95 percent of
the device bandwidth on this workload
whereas roxdb only uses about 30 of
device bandwidth
now this insertion performance does not
come at the cost of lookup performance
so here on the right is the lookup
performance from ycsb
run c which is a workload entirely
consisting of zippy and distributed
uh lookups and the y-axis again
throughput in thousands of operations
per second
as you can see splinerdb can perform
about 40 more lookups per second than
rocksdb on this workload
if we look at the entire ycsb
application suite
you can see that splinterdb
substantially outperforms roxdb on all
of the workloads except for run e
which consists mainly of short scans
okay so how does splenidb achieve this
performance
it does so using a new data structure
called the size turkey the epsilon tree
but before i can describe that i'm going
to go through a little data structural
background
and we're going to start quickly with b
trees
a b tree is a b are search tree the
internal nodes consist entirely of
pivots
and the leaves consist entirely of key
value pairs
in order to insert a new key value pair
we follow the pivots and the internal
nodes down the tree until we reach a
leaf at which point the key value pair
can be inserted in the leaf
it is well known that b trees have an
insertion and lookup cost that is
logarithmic
in the number of key value pairs in the
data set
that takes us to b the epsilon trees
a bdf's long tree is a search tree like
a b tree
but where a b tree has internal nodes
that are consistent entirely of pivots
internal nodes and a b epsilon tree have
b to the epsilon pivots and the rest of
the node is a buffer
in order to insert a new key value pair
into a b the epsilon tree
we first start by just putting the key
value pair in the root buffer
once we've done so that key value pair
is already incorporated into the data
structure
if we keep inserting key value pairs
into the root
at some point the root is going to
become full when a buffer becomes full
what we're going to do is we pick a
child that's receiving the most messages
and we're going to flush those messages
down into that child's buffer
this creates more room in the root
buffer and now we can accept more
insertions
if the root buffer fills again we repeat
the same process we flush down to the
child and in this case the child's
buffer is now full as well
so we again pick a child receiving the
most messages and flush them down the
tree
and this process can cascade down the
tree all the way to the leaves
look ups in b epsilon trees are very
similar to lookups and b trees except
we don't just follow the pivots down the
tree we also have to look in the buffers
along the way
so if we're looking for the key 71 we
start by looking in the root
it 71 is not in the buffer so we use the
pivots to
progress down the tree we keep checking
the buffers along the way
and eventually we find 71 here in the
leaf and we can return the correct
answer
so implicit in this algorithm
is a certain amount of work
amplification for
insertions let's see why
so here i've zoomed in on one particular
bd epsilon tree node
and it has some data that's already in
the node it has three key value pairs
when i flush some more data into the
node we're gonna have to rewrite the key
value pairs that were already in that
node
if we keep flushing data into node we're
going to have to keep rewriting all that
data that already is there
over and over again and in the worst
case
the average message is going to be
written be the epsilon time over two
times in each node
and note that this merging and rewriting
of the
node incurs both an io overhead of
having to write the node out again but
also cpu overhead of having to process
that data
and collect it together
if we multiply this out by the height of
the tree we get a work amplification
that looks like this
splinterdb uses a new data structure
called the size to be the epsilon tree
that tries to address this work
amplification problem
so a size 2 bd epsilon tree is similar
to a b to epsilon tree
in that each node has pivots and buffer
however in a size 2 b epsilon tree the
buffer is stored separately from the
pivots
and in several pieces now
i'm going to refer to this part the part
of the node with the pivots as the trunk
of the node and i'm going to refer to
these buffers that
are these disjoint buffers as branches
so how does an insertion how do
insertions work in size chirp b the
epsilon trees
so here suppose we have an empty node
with these three pivots
um so it just has a trunk and no
branches
when new data is flushed into this node
from higher up in the tree
it gets added to the trunk as a new
branch
so we just set a little pointer in the
trunk that points to this new branch
when more data comes in is flush from
above
we're going to do the same thing we're
going to add it as a new branch just
using a pointer
and we don't have to rewrite any of the
old branches that are already in the
node
so note here that these branches may
have overlapping key ranges
so if i color the pivots of this node
and their children and i color in the
key value pairs with the child
that they're going to be flushed to
eventually you can see that these
branches have
can have keys that can go to any child
so let's add another branch to this
flush another branch into this node
and now suppose the node is full
what's going to happen is exactly what
happens in a beat the epsilon tree we're
going to pick a child that's receiving
the most messages
and we're going to merge them together
into a new branch
and we're going to flush that branch
down into the child
so note that in this process each key
value pair
is read and written exactly once in each
trunk node
during this last merging or compaction
phase
as a result if we multiply this out by
the height of the tree
we can see that a size 3 b epsilon tree
on an insertion workload it's going to
have
b the epsilon times less work
amplification
and that's and that's great and this is
also reflected in the insertion cost in
the external memory model
so let's look at lookups in a size to be
the epsilon tree
they're going to function very similarly
to lookups in a b the epsilon tree
so if we look for 71 we're going to
start in the root and we're going to
check all the branches along the path
down the trade so here these rectangles
represent
uh branches which i've sort of squashed
down to simplify the diagram
so we're going to look in each branch of
the root and having done so we're going
to move down the root using the pivots
down the tree using the pivots we'll
look all the branches in this internal
node
and finally we get to a leaf we'll look
in all branches and perhaps in one of
these branches we'll find 71
and we can return the correct answer
so the problem here is that because
these branches are stored
discontinuously we can end up doing b
the epsilon times more ios in the worst
case
to try and find our key and that's not
really what we want to do
so let's go about fixing lookups in size
to
be the epsilon trees the problem is that
each node has these multiple branches
that we have to check when we're doing a
lookup
and the idea that we're going to use to
fix this is to use filters to avoid
searching all of them
a filter is a probabilistic data
structure which answers membership
queries with one-sided error and
particularly they have no
false negatives there are many kinds of
filters such as bloom filters cuckoo
filters and quotient filters
and splenidb uses quotient filters for
this purpose
so in this node i've drawn uh i've
pictured
these pink sieves here that represent a
quotient filter for each branch
so we have one per branch now
uh when a lookup is searching the node
it's only going to search those branches
which contain the key
plus some occasional false positives
so if we're looking for 64 we will look
in this node here
and we will look in all the filters and
the filters will tell us whether we have
to look in the branches or not
and so perhaps in this last one we do
have to look because there is 64 and we
can return the correct answer
now if we can make this false positive
rate low enough
then we can perform lookups in an
expected constant number of ios
and in practice this is usually about
one io in general
so to recap the size tier b epsilon tree
is this data structure which has less
compaction
than similar data structures related
data structures like bd epsilon trees
and log structured merge trees
uh and as a result it performs less i o
and also has less cpu overhead
it does this while maintaining a low
lookup cost and while i didn't get to
talk about scans
it has slightly more expensive short
scans but can perform long scans at disk
bandwidth
i encourage you to see the paper for
lots more details about scans
okay so now i'm going to discuss a cool
algorithm called flush then compact
which is enabled by the
size tier to be the epsilon tree
so flush and compact is an algorithm
that's motivated by sequential
insertions in b trees and be the epsilon
trees
so if we do an insertion into a b tree
it's going to bring the entire root leaf
path into cash
so as a result if we perform sequential
insertions
those subsequent insertions are going to
be cheaper because the entire retrieve
path is in cache
they will be they it will not incur any
io until we
reach a boundary of the leaf or boundary
of an internal node
similarly with bt epsilon trees if we
perform sequential insertions
they're going to fill up the root and
then that's going to trigger a flush
that's going to go all the way down the
tree into the leaf and that will bring
all these nodes into cache
now subsequent insertions are going to
be cheaper because again they're only
going to incur
i o at the node boundaries
so this motivates the idea behind flush
the compact
we'd like to perform sequential
insertions that also have this property
that they
incur less io that
less io but we also want them to incur
less cpu overhead and so the idea is we
would like sequential insertions to
incur
less compaction total so
here is a a regular sized here be the
epsilon tree
and let's see what happens when we
perform sequential insertion
so here is a node it has a collection of
branches that contain
some sequential insertions if we flush
these down into the child
as a new branch and there's already some
data that's present in that child
this is going to trigger a flush again
but before that
all this data is going to be compacted
together and so we can still end up
performing a merge of data on each level
of the tree
and that means that we're going to
perform the cpu
and potentially the i o the i o doing
that
so let's look at what how flushed and
compact addresses this problem
so here i'm going to replace
i'm gonna i'm gonna draw the this box
around these branches with this one big
arrow
to represent all the uh all the pointers
from the node
to those branches and this will help
simplify this diagram
okay so here suppose we're gonna flush
this data down
to the child the way flush the compact
works is we're first going to flush
references to the branches
but we're not going to do any compaction
then we're going to use metadata to mask
out the data
so each node sees the data it's
logically supposed to have
in particular the parent is only going
to see the unflushed data
and the child is only going to see the
flush data in these branches
now before compacting we're going to
flush again
so suppose this child node here is now
full
it can flush to the grandchild and the
grandchild now
will have references to these branches
and any other branches that were in the
child
and we'll again use metadata in order to
make sure each node can only see that
the the key value pairs it's supposed to
finally we're going to kick off
asynchronous compaction jobs
to clean up these references and compact
them into single branches again
so the advantages to this algorithm are
is
the first advantage of this algorithm is
that no work is immediate is done on
data that is immediately flushed again
so any of the key value pairs that get
flushed from the child to the grandchild
aren't going to be compacted in in the
child level
and the extreme example of this is when
we're doing sequential insertions
sequential insertions are going to
trigger flushes that go all the way down
the tree from the root to the leaf
before any compaction is is performed
and so they will only get compacted at
the end in the leaf
so pure sequential insertion should have
a work amplification that's near one
they will only be compacted in one place
the leaf
this also breaks a serial chain of
compactions
into a parallel collection of
compactions and these can happen
concurrently
across trunk nodes and even within a
single trunk node
and so this should result in improved
insertion concurrency
as well
so let's see how this actually works out
empirically
so in this plot i have the result of a
single threaded workload which has a
percentage of sequential insertions
and a fixed percentage of sequential
insertions and the rest are random
insertions
so here the x-axis is the percentage of
the insertions which are sequential
so on the far left we have uniformly
random insertion
workload on the far right we have a
uniformly sequential insertion workload
and note that the x-axis is not to scale
for clarity
the y-axis is the throughput in
insertions per second so higher is
better
so as you can see splinterdb smoothly
increases its throughput as the workload
gets more sequential
and achieves roughly twice the
throughput and with a fully sequential
workload as with a fully random workload
as you can see roxdb also improves but
at a much lower rate
we can also look at how insertion
performance scales with the number of
threads
so here in this plot the x-axis is the
number of threads that are performing
insertions
and the y-axis is the throughput in
insertions per second
as you can see uh for for low numbers of
threads
splinterdb scales somewhat linearly
once we start to reach the device
bandwidth of course this starts to level
off
but it scales uh it's it scales reason
yeah scale scales
okay so to conclude splinterdb is a key
value store
which tries to handle tough cases of
fast storage small key value pairs and
small cash
it does so using a new data structure
the size tier b epsilon tree to reduce
the amount of work on insertion
workloads while still
performing lookups while still
maintaining
good performance on lookups and it has a
number of cool additional algorithms
such as flush and compact
which further increases performance
thank you very much my name again is
alex conway i'm at vmware research
you can find me at my website or with
this email i really appreciate your time
thank you very much
you