hi everyone
thank you for joining the talk my name
is constantin tarana and today we'll be
talking to you about
s rdma which is our security extension
to remote direct memory access which
enables end-to-end authentication
and encryption srdm is a result of joint
work of scalable parallel computing
cloud
and network security group rdm is a
mechanism which allows one machine to
access memory
of another machine through the network
all these memory accesses
are floated to the network controllers
which enables high bandwidth and low
latency communication
rdm is widely used for hpc and machine
learning workloads
rgm is publicly available right now at
microsoft azure cloud and oracle clouds
and each year
we have more and more systems which make
use of rdma to speed up their
performance
such performance advantage comes at the
cost which actually is paid by security
even in december 2005 it was pointed out
in rfc 4297
that rdma has to support ibc
and tls however in march 2017 when
somebody asked
this question on the melanoc security
forum it was
replied by melanox expert that
infiniband architecture doesn't yet
support security and it's a challenging
problem
and right now in july 2020 ipsec doesn't
still support
rdma traffic one can ask whether we can
use actually
application level security in this case
since rdma completely of loads packet
processing to the network control
controllers cpu is not even involved in
packet processing
and if we use two-sided communication
then packets are also processed by the
network controllers
as a result the message has to be fully
received in order to be processed
and the cpu would spend its cycles on
verifying such messages
that's why we propose srdma which is our
lightweight security extension to rdma
which uses symmetric key cryptography to
provide header authentication packet
authentication
payload encryption and memory protection
srtm may effectively prevent if dropping
spoofing attacks replay attacks and men
in the metal attacks
srdma was designed to be back
completable
and it can be easily adapted by existing
infiniband architecture
from the user perspective we propose new
secure reliably connected viewpair
which requires the user to install
symmetric key
and required level of
required level of protection srd map
supports various security protections
it can be used to enable header
authentication and packet authentication
using hash based message of etk
message authentication code such as sha
or cipher based message authentication
code such as eas or poly1305
in addition srdma supports authenticated
encryption
which provides secrecy to the
communication
right now i'd like to talk about srdma
packet format classical rdma packet
consists of routing header transport
header payload and checksums
ipc usually encapsulates the packets and
it's even discussed right now that ipc
would encapsulate the rdma which means
the devices would need
to be able to process ipsec packets in
order in order to process
rdma packets that's why we think that
security has to be a part of the
protocol
and the its security header has to be
located after the transfer header
as a result this doesn't change any
algorithms how the packets are
processed in terms of routing and
calculation on the checksums
and already the devices can
process and already existing devices can
process such packets
the small change we propose to the
existing transport header is to use
three out of seven reserve bits to
indicate the presence of the secure
header
depending on the value encoded in these
three bits
we encode the size of the secure header
the secure header only contains message
authentication code
and if this three bits has value zero it
means there is no secure header present
which
enables back compatibility with existing
rdma architecture
the message authentication code varies
from 96 bit to
512 bits
another change which would require from
the hardware is
related to the packet sequence number to
provide
protection against replay attacks the
protocol has to
ensure uniqueness of the message
authentication code by
including unique value in computation of
the message authentication codes
ipsec currently used just packets
sequence counter for that
that's why we decided also to reuse
existing packet sequence number from
pin event architecture however this
packet sequence number
adjust 24 bits and if we take existing
network controllers which can eject 200
million packets per seconds
these 24 bit counters gets reduced after
80 milliseconds which means to provide
secure
communication application was required
to re-establish connection
each 80 milliseconds that's why we
proposed to extend this
counselors to 64 bits but we would
extend only the countersunk
end points we would still transmit
24 least significant bits in the packets
since the packet sequence number i
ordered
and get incremented by one for each
packet using just
24 least significant bits we can derive
the full
64-bit counter 64-bit value used
in the computation of the message
authentication
depending on the security code installed
in the connection srdma uses different
algorithms for computation of the
message authentication code
in case of authenticated encryption the
payload will be also encrypted
right now i'd like to talk about the
overheads of srd may compare to the ip6
which is does not exist yet
but it would have the following
overheads
of course in case of as128 when we have
n connections
the both in both for both protocols we
would need to store the key on the
device
which results in 16 but multiplied by n
bytes
however since srdma reuses the existing
counters we would need to only add 10
bytes
to the existing counters in order to
provide
protection against replay attacks ipsec
has its
own counters which would require to use
16 byte
per connection on the network
controllers
finally srdma stores only the message
authentication code in the header which
16 byte for the as128
ipsec header is much larger and this 32
byte
is the really lower bound value
and it doesn't even include the
encapsulation overhead
of the ipcx
since memory is a precious resource for
network controllers we
also want to decrease at this memory
overheads
many work reported that exhaustion of
the memorial network
controllers can significantly degrade
the performance
that's why we decided to use the concept
of protection domain from infiniband
architecture
infiniband architecture proposed
introduces protection domains as a way
of sharing resources between connections
all the connections are created
inside of this protection domains and it
means these connections
can share memory resources
we propose instead of installing
symmetric key per connection
install one symmetric key in the
protection domain
and then all compare level keys will be
derived from this
protection domain level key for the
derivation we would
we use the addresses of the
of the endpoints and it's guaranteed the
two end points will generate
the same symmetric key for qbl q
parallel key
as a result the network controller
doesn't
need to store key for each connection it
can only store the key for the
protection domain and derive the keys of
the couper
for the q pairs on the fly which
significantly
decrease the memory overhead
finally srd may provide extended memory
protection
to the infiniband architecture right now
the protection of the memory is based
on the notion of arches which are just
32-bit values which are transmitted in
the plain text in it packet
so if endpoint a wants to enable memory
access
to the sum endpoint b it would send this
r key value
to the endpoint b however it can share
this key within point c
or network if dropper can see this key
in the packets and gain the access to
the memory of endpoint a
that's why we propose crypto based
memory protection
whose main idea is to provide separate
uh crypto based
uh access keys to the memory regions
which are calculated
from the boundaries of the memory region
you
at the end point would like to access
the position to prove the position of
this key endpoints have to include it
in the calculation of the message
authentication code as a result
srdma does not require any extra message
any extra headers
for enabling this extended memory
protection and existing
field of message authentication code can
be reused
right now i'd like to talk about
implementation of sr gaming
so s rdma was prototyped on a smart nick
from broadcom
uh this was stingray eps 225.
uh this smart thing is equipped with
eight core arm 8072 cpu
and it has 8 gigabytes of dram
we chose the smart nic because it
supports
crypto acceleration
this marking has two ports of 25
gigabits
however for smartening capability only
one port is available
also since we implemented srdma on the
top of
normal rdma connection we had available
only 20.6 gigabits per second so this is
our line rate which we
try to compare with uh so
first we i checked the performance of uh
crypt engine installed in the smartening
and we tried d4
different uh uh encryption algorithms of
use and we used them for authentication
of the memory blocks so we tried three
block sizes 64 bytes
one kilobyte or two kilobytes and we
also tried different number of
threads so as as you can see for the
large blocks
uh we could achieve line rate for all
algorithms using all the frets
and we could actually achieve this line
rate
almost for all algorithms using less
threats
it was a bit harder for smaller blocks
since the hash based algorithms they are
not
uh tuned they were not designed to be
applied to the
small blocks that's why they have really
poor performance
however this is you will see on the next
slide that it's even
it's enough to perform header
authentication but
uh aes or like cipher based algorithms
are
better targeted for small
messages uh that's why actually for
ketervation we use
es algorithm because it was the fastest
one
working with the small sizes for the
blocks of small
small sizes it was the fastest algorithm
which could generate new key from a
master uh
right now i'd like to talk how srdma was
actually implemented
so let's imagine the case when we have
two endpoints we have endpoint a
and end point b each endpoint is
represented by
its host application and its smart d
and to send the message uh
between two hosts so host a wants to
send to messages b
we need to establish overall free
connection first
host has to establish connection with
their smart nic this connection
represents dma connection
and then we establish a connection
between smart nics
uh right now i would like to show how a
secure artimer write can be performed
on our platform so first they'd like to
send a message
write the message to the member of the
host b first it would send it to the
it's marketing smart depending on the
security level installed
it would uh calculate the uh
message authentication code and append
it uh to the
message and then it will send it
to the smart nic of the endpoint b
the smart link would receive it and it
would validate
this uh message of integration code and
if validation was successful
the smart nic will write this
payload to the memory of the host b so
as you can imagine the the latency would
go up compared to the normal case since
we have
three communications to deliver a packet
uh that's why uh so our baseline latency
was uh 9.5 microseconds for half round
trip and the full round trip it was
about 18 uh microseconds
so here i'd like to show you the latency
for the source authentication so for
write and read latency
right we showed the results for half
round trip and for read we show the
results for full
round trip uh so in the basic case so
the basic case is when we just
uh the nick has a key at the just uh add
the
mac and send it to the other side we
could see that for aas
this latency was less than microseconds
and
what is important that this one
microseconds is
uh comprises of two parts first part is
when
we calculate the message authentication
code on the sender
and when we verify this message
authentication code on the receiver so
overall it's 0.2
three microseconds on each sides
to work with the header authentication
uh of course uh hash based algorithms
such as
they had higher latency because as i
mentioned earlier there were not
designed to work with small sizes and
the the
header of the message is quite small
right now i'd like to show results for
the pt protection extended protection
case
so as you remember the pd protection
extended memory protection
requires key derivation and this latency
is actually worst case scenario that's
when the nic doesn't have a key to
immediately to calculate the message
authentication code
so it has to first derive it but in the
real case uh
the smart nick would cache it and we
would expect
the performance as for basic case but
here
this is the latency what if we sender
wants to send it
and its smartnig doesn't have a key in
cache and has to first
derive it to protect the packet
and the receiver as well it cannot
immediately
start verifying the packet the first
need to derive the key and then the
search
verification so in that case the latency
goes
up even higher so with each
process observation adds about one
microsecond
on each side and of course when we
had the experiment when we had uh
both enabled so we need to derive keys
twice
uh the latency even uh went up but i'd
like to
um point out again that this is the
worst case scenario this is
what if the key is not in cache
so we performed a similar experiment but
here we measured
the full packet protection so here we
calculated the message authentication
code over the whole packet
and on the top four lines is
read latency so this is a full round
trip
and for right latency it's half round
since the packet authentication depends
on the payload size we measured this for
different payload sizes
uh starting from 32 bytes up to two
kilobytes
and again we measured and the different
uh
with different features enabled in srdma
and these numbers again for pd
protection extended memory protection
are the worst case scenario so the key
is not cached and if it would there
would be cash
we expect that we would have muslim
uh hits because you never send just one
packet starting from the second packet
the key will be
in cash you would have the same
performance as for
uh basic uh right and reads
so as we can see the like the best
algorithm here
was uh pulley 1305 so it had
the lowest latency for full packet
authentication
and the ais was had a bit
higher latency however when we performed
the experiment with authentication
encryption so in this case
we authenticate the message and we also
replaced the payload
and turned out that eas had better
performance
and we will see the this difference even
more when we
run bandwidth experiments which was a
bit surprising for us
so here we can conclude that for full
message authentication
we think that the best algorithm would
be poly1305
and of course sha 256
had also good performance because it was
applied
to the large
message
but for authenticated encryption we
think that eas
is as the best performance
uh right now i'd like to talk about the
right bandwidth so first of all i'd like
to explain
the this baseline we had so
we took our infrastructure as you
remember we had this free
keeper connections between hospi and
host b to send so we measured
how much bandwidth we can achieve with
this
uh code base without using
any authentication encryption we just
actually
just send the packets from host a plus b
and we do not verify the packets
and turned out if we use just one fret
of our smart nic
we could achieve only about eight
gigabits per second
and we couldn't achieve the full wine
rate
however when we used four frets we could
achieve the full
uh line rate so this black line is
represents the bandwidth we could
achieve
without enabling any uh protection on
the packets
so the basic uh keys protection so the
basic case is like when we have
keys underneath and we can immediately
protect the packets for header
authentication we could achieve land
rate using uh
six frets for all protection codes
for full packet authentication we could
also do this
for all cypher-based algorithms
and only sha 512 could not
achieve it and actually es128 had hard
time achieving the
lane rate for eight frets however when
we switch to the
objective authenticated encryption mode
is
uh beats poly1305 uh algorithm
so which concludes our previous uh
conclusion
uh that as128 is better for
uh authenticated encryption poly135 is
better for packet authentication
then we measured the bandwidth for the
rights
when we have enabled bt protection
extended memory protection again here we
try to express the case like really
worst case scenarios we have
really small cache or somehow each time
we send the message
the the key is not on the underneath and
we need to derive it each time
so we each time we send the message we
have a miss on the sender and the
receiver
so this case we had decreased by 2
gigabits
per second for the all cases but we
still were able to achieve the
rate for header authentication and also
for
some algorithms for packet
authentication
and finally when we enable both and we
had constant misses
the performance got decreased by another
two gigabit
but for header authentication we could
still achieve the line rate
we performed similar experiment for the
read bandwidth uh
for read bandwidth uh our baseline was
even lower
so for no protection installed we could
achieve only 5 gb
per second so it's even slower for the
right case
the main reason for that that read
requests are
more complicated than
than right so in case of read the device
needs special capabilities
and even in existing infiniband you need
to install
the contacts on the initiator and on the
target uh so it's like special slots on
the device where it stores the context
for performing the operation
and we have to actually emulate uh this
in the software of our smartening
so that's why at the maximum
performance we could achieve was about
16 gigabits
and for one thread that was only five
gigabit
uh anyway so we measured the header
authentication backup authentication
and object encryption for this algorithm
and for header authentication we could
achieve land rate
for all algorithms for packet
authentication
we couldn't do that but we had the
algorithms
which were really close achieving the
line rate
so uh again the best one uh here was
pulley 1305
and in the case of authenticated
encryption the best one was
again as128 one thing i forgot to
mention so for read requests
uh we have to perform protection
uh the process of uh protecting
validating backing four times so
in the right keys we have the sender
which
protects the packet and the receiver who
validates so reit
request consists of the full round trip
so we have a
read request which which is protected
then that's get validated by the
destination then destination sends the
results
it protects it sends it to the to the
initiator the initiator
checks uh the validates the
uh the packets it's received so that's
why it's more complicated
so again with right with enable pd
protection extended memory protection
that's
uh the case when the keys are not cached
so that's worst case scenario
and we had similar results as uh for
rights
and uh also quite similar results when
we had
both enabled as we could see
actually we could still even this
enabled all this feature we could still
achieve really high
uh bandwidth using just general purpose
cpu this is like not really powerful arm
cpus
and we expect better results if this
algorithm would be
implemented in the fpgas for example
uh right now right now i'd like to
invite you to read the full paper
so the things i didn't uh explain that
our srdma also supports
uh memory sub delegation based on our
on our extended crypto based memory
protection which allows to
give access to the memory of other
parties in the network
uh in addition we have more detail more
details on the implementation of
s argument and extra experiments for
example we
integrated srtm in the heart kiwi store
and you could see the results of our
experiments in the paper
here i'd like to conclude my talk so i'd
like to remind the desert game we use
lightweight security extension to
argument
so it was designed to have as little as
possible changes to the current protocol
so and it has to be back
compatible in addition we take into
account the memory constraints of the
network controllers and try to reduce it
as much as possible and we think we
achieved it
uh in our implementation and our
evaluations we were limited by
the platform we were using for
prototyping but we
truly believe that srtma can be easily
adapted to the hardware
to achieve even higher bandwidths and
lower latency communication
so if you have any questions please
contact me through the email you can see
on the screen
thank you