hello
my name is daniel bittman let me tell
you about twizzler a new research
operating system designed to
realize the power of unix in a world of
highly shared persistent data structures
twizzler's design is based around our
beliefs for how programs will evolve in
the face of
new bite-addressable non-volatile memory
technologies or nbm
first we believe that nvm will
fundamentally change
our programming models and abstractions
we expect that programs will operate on
in-memory data structures thus
necessitating persistent data references
next we believe that the os needs to
provide pervasive support for
abstractions like persistent pointers in
order to
best enable simpler and more efficient
programs
so let's have a look at some upcoming
hardware trends
nvm is here you can buy it today from
intel
and throw it on the memory bus right
next to your dram this cpu can issue
normal load and store instructions
to it with a latency on the order of
that of dram
which means that we now have a low
latency per system store that
applications can get at
directly moving persistent data up the
storage hierarchy like this
changes the way that applications can
view and operate on data
in fact they must change to take full
advantage of what is being offered
the old way of getting to persistent
data where we would
explicitly load it into volatile memory
deserialize it compute on it
re-serialize it and then explicitly
store it to disk worked okay in the past
disks were slow and the latency of these
operations was hidden
and we had to issue explicit block
stores at some point but
when the latency of the persistent
device is less than that of even a
single system call
we can no longer afford the kernel
interposition involved in explicit i o
we can improve programmability as well
these operations
encompass the lion's share of systems
programming imagine how much useful work
we could get done
if we didn't have to do them imagine how
much time you would save both in program
time but also in programmer time
because we didn't have to worry about
maintaining multiple data formats and
the transformations between them
imagine how much easier data sharing can
be if the data is always in one format
as opposed to constantly moving around
this cycle
persistent memory offers us this world
but only if we take the steps to change
the key abstractions that the os
provides and to change applications to
best take advantage of this new
technology
we need to start treating persistent
data like it's memory
not like it's storage because in this
world it is
memory and don't worry we have a
compatibility story as well
directly accessing persistent in-memory
data structures
has some immediate consequences first
those data structures are persistent
which means we'll need some way of
constructing
long-term data references persistent
data
by definition outlives the actors that
operate on it
either because that data is shared
simultaneously across different programs
or shared across time that is
across invocations of the same program
because persistent data has a lifetime
longer than that of the processes that
create it or operate on it
we cannot store any ephemeral context
associated with those processes
in the persistent data this is a
recurring philosophy
all of the context necessary to
interpret data
needs to be stored with that data let me
describe what i mean by way of an
example
imagine we have some processes observe
process 1 and process 2.
they want to share data but that data
has pointers in it if this data
structure is persistent
i can't just write virtual memory
addresses into it because
virtual memory is by definition
ephemeral it's tied to the creating
process
instead we must store a persistent
pointer
one that is based on a more fundamental
notion of data identity
instead of an ephemeral notion of
location
building an efficient persistent pointer
design
is a key part of our work
the second implication of direct access
to
persistent in-memory data structures is
that the os's responsibilities
drastically change and reduce the low
latency nature of nvm
demands that the kernel no longer be
involved in the persistence path for the
most part
therefore the kernel does not need to
provide services
for mediating access to persistent
storage and therefore
no longer needs to act as mediator for
things like rendezvous
communication or naming the kernel gets
out of the way of user space
and many kernel bypass strategies
naturally fall out of this
an example of removing kernel
abstractions is a process
what is a process a pile of threads a
security role
a virtual address space and a bunch of
kernel state like file descriptors
but if we disconnect the virtual address
space from how applications access data
and we no longer need things like file
descriptors a lot of that kernel state
goes away and we're left with no reason
to couple a bunch of different
abstractions like
threads and security roles into a single
process notion
instead of mediating access to
persistent data the os provides
sufficient support for user space to
manipulate all data as in-memory data
without needing to coordinate on some
ephemeral context
we call an operating system data centric
if it provides this mediation-free
access to data such that that data can
persist that is all of the context
necessary
to interpret the data is stored with the
data
we contrast these two process-centric
operating systems which instead focus on
ephemeral actors as being the primary
abstraction
well what about alternative approaches
well it wouldn't be os research without
talking about posix
the hallmark of posix is kernel-mediated
i o
through explicit i o calls like read and
write
which already fails to meet our
requirements because of the explicit i o
calls
but posix often also ends up forcing the
programmer to think in terms of multiple
data formats
even mmap which does admittedly help the
problem somewhat
requires the programmer to still think
in terms of virtual addresses
we could try layering support for nvm on
top of posix
pmdk is an nvm programming library
which supports persistent pointer
abstractions and runs on top of posix
but it doesn't provide a complete
picture because it requires the
programmer to work both in a posix world
and in an nvm world at the same time
managing the complex interaction of
features between both
an example of this is naming and as
we'll see a little later on
cross machine sharing
twizzler is a point in the bounded
design space of data centric operating
systems
twistler provides low kernel involvement
for applications accessing persistent
data
it provides an efficient and flexible
persistent pointer design
and provides a standard library of
features necessary for effectively
writing nvm-based programs
the execution environment in twizzler is
one in which there is little distinction
between how threads access volatile and
persistent data
memory and twizzler both volatile and
persistent is broken up into objects
where an object is a flat region of
memory containing semantically related
data
the contents of objects can be directly
accessed and manipulated by programs and
is of course
largely application specific objects are
also the unit of access control
in twizzler an example of an object
might be a b
tree but an object could just as easily
have multiple b
trees in it and just as easily a b tree
could be spread across multiple
objects it all depends on how the
application wishes to do things
for example an application might wish to
have different parts of the tree
protected by different access rights
applications in twizzler are supported
by the twizzler standard library lib twz
which acts like a library os similar as
to an exokernel
and provides services for common object
management and manipulation routines
the kernel provides management of
physical resources as well as
multiplexing memory into objects
and providing services for thread
scheduling and thread synchronization
it also acts as the trusted computing
base servicing page faults and security
violations
for compatibility applications linked to
muscle a c library that we modified to
run on twizzler
we changed muscle system calls into
library calls to our library twix which
we wrote to support posix applications
through muscle and twix applications can
operate on objects using posix functions
at the cost of course of
explicit io this is another key
philosophy
applications need to change in order to
take best advantage of nvm
it is these applications that should get
first-class os support
instead of building support for exciting
new hardware
by shoe horning in that support on top
of existing ill-suited interfaces
we provide old software with
compatibility layers and design the
system
for how new applications will be written
okay let's talk about persistent
pointers
in twizzler objects have a unique
128-bit id
right now that id is 128 bits in size
though we could increase it if necessary
to form the kind of identity based
reference that we've been talking about
we could take that object id and combine
it with an offset
and then be able to reference any piece
of data within
any object however just combining the id
with the offset
would dramatically increase pointer size
and therefore have a significant
performance impact
additionally we would limit flexibility
because
application programmers would have to
work entirely within these 128-bit ids
without any possibility of abstraction
so in twizzler we play the classic trick
and add a layer of indirection
every object in twizzler has at a known
location
a data structure called the foreign
object table or fot
this table is an array of fot entries
each containing
the object id of an external reference
from this object
instead of storing a pointer as an
object id and an offset
we store an index into the fot along the
offset
our pointers can now be 64 bits but more
importantly
this indirection opens the door to more
possibilities
in fot entries we can store additional
metadata like protection information or
ref counts
but we can also store names instead of
relying on the file system to handle
naming for us
we get naming through the core pointer
framework of the system
these names can be resolved on pointer
resolution enabling
late binding and allowing programmers to
think in terms of human readable strings
instead of just
object ids let's talk through an fot
example
check out object o here o has an fot
and it has a pointer inside it that
pointer has fot index of one
so we can use that index to index the
fot and get back object id a
we can then use object id a and the
offset to index within that object and
get to the data
in fot entry of zero means that the
pointer is an
internal pointer it references data
within the object itself that the
pointer resides in
i want to stress that the fot is a per
object
and not system-wide data structure this
is a manifestation
of our philosophy that all context
necessary to interpret data
should be stored with that data per
object fots
makes objects self-contained
so consider now pointers and objects
refer to data
via identity and not ephemeral location
and
object ids are large enough to refer to
any object in the world
and objects are self-contained this
means
that i can share objects across machines
not just across processes on a single
machine
if i copy an object from one machine to
another all the pointers
mean the same thing let's contrast this
with pmdk
so in pmdk pointers are stored as an
object id offset pair
where the object id in this case is 64
bits
let's imagine we move an object from one
machine to another well the problem is
that
64 bits is not large enough to ensure no
collision in the object id space
this means that we have to do one of two
things either
we have to coordinate ahead of time on
the object id space which gets harder as
we scale
or two we would have to perform some fix
up operation on the receiving machine
the problem with this is that because
the object ids are stored
inside the pointers the fix-up operation
is necessarily application specific
adding complexity in twizzler we can
avoid both of these we can avoid the
global coordination
and the fix of operation through the use
of indirection
in addition to providing a comprehensive
persistent pointer framework
twistler provides basic services for
coherency and consistency
applications need to be able to write
crash consistent data structures in nvm
but the research is still in flux and so
we wanted to avoid
prematurely prescribing a particular
solution
twizzler does however provide basic
building blocks for
cache line flushes as well as a higher
level
transactional log that can be used to
safely persist data
of course twizzler provides a security
model designed around
nvm briefly the removal of the kernel as
mediator means that the colonel has to
be able to trust
security policy coming from persistent
data
to accomplish this we use
cryptographically signed capabilities to
define security policy and access rights
additionally since the kernel is not
involved in
much of the persistent data access the
kernel uses the
mmu to do much of the security
enforcement of the system
more details on this as well as when
access rights are
bound to threads for example are
available in the paper
implementation is a relatively small
system written in
c and c plus plus the design choices
that we've made
results in a relatively small kernel
that is still capable of
supporting a full user space more design
details for example how we use virtual
memory hardware
are available in the paper twizzler
itself is open source and it is
available right now at twizzler.io
in evaluating twizzler we wanted to
highlight the programmability features
our first goal was to demonstrate the
benefits and simplicity afforded novel
applications
written natively for twizzler our second
goal
was to show that existing applications
can be easily ported to twizzler
i want to stress that our goals are
programmability and not
performance of course advances in
programmability need to come without a
significant performance impact
and of course we do expect to see some
performance improvement
due to the simplification of software
layers that the twizzler model provides
our evaluation consisted of writing a
key value store or
kvs with some nvm focused requirements
and porting sql light to twizzler while
changing its storage backend to use
twizzler abstractions
let's talk about the kvs case study
first before going into the performance
tests
we built a simple kvs in c for twizzler
twizzler's model allowed us a few
convenient simplifying
design choices here first we were able
to hand out direct pointers to data
when performing a lookup instead of
copying the value out to a temporary
we were able to hand out a direct
reference to it because of twizzler's
flexible pointer model
when working with persistent memory
avoiding unnecessary copies
is important and natural second
we separated the index and the data into
multiple objects
twizzler's pointer model allows us to
construct cross-object data references
with no more complexity than
constructing an internal data reference
thus the additional complexity required
by managing
two different name spaces in a single
linear address space
as would be the traditional approach is
no longer justified
this means that for example we could
change the organization of the index
structure
in a factored way without needing to
rethink the global layout
next we extended the requirements of the
kbs to support
access control in twistler this was easy
instead of storing all values in a
single object we store them in
multiple data objects according to
access policy
since cross-object pointers are natural
in twizzler
adding support for this required almost
no modifications to the kvs code
when performing a lookup i may get back
a pointer to data
but if i'm not allowed to see that data
i won't be able to de-reference it
consider the implications here often
security is an
end-to-end thing implemented at the
hardware level the system level and the
application level
sometimes of course this is unavoidable
but what a win it is when an application
can reuse
lower level security features without
having to re-implement them
itself compare this to a unix approach
we implemented a similarly featured kvs
on top of posix interfaces
we found that the extra complexity
involved in managing paths
significantly increased code complexity
because unix doesn't support
a pervasive notion of cross file
references furthermore we weren't easily
able to extend that kvs to support
access control like we did in twizzler
because of the way that mmap works we
would have needed to know ahead of time
all of the accesses to be made or would
have needed to
remap all of the objects on the fly each
adding their own
flavor of complexity for
existing software our goal was to port a
relatively large
application sql lite is a commonly used
local sql implementation with a b tree
based
storage back end we ported sequel light
to twizzler
replacing the b3 storage back end with
twizzler based red black tree code
note that the rest of sql light remained
untouched demonstrating that our
compatibility layers are effective
we ported sqlite to twizzler in two
steps first
we found a port of sql lite that used
lmdb as its storage backend
lmdb stands for the lightning memory map
database
and it uses mmap to access persistent
storage
we took the lmdb port of sqlite and then
we implemented enough of the lmdb api
on top of twizzler abstractions to get
sqlite to run
in this process we discovered that
twizzler's pointer model actually makes
a lot of the interfaces in these kv
stores
obsolete because they were just largely
wrappers around pointer operations
we compared our port of sqlite to
twizzler to three other sqlite
implementations running on linux
the first was unmodified or native
sqlite
the second was sqlite ported to use lmdb
as its storage backend
for the third we took the twizzler lmdb
interface that we wrote
and converted it to use pmdk instead as
its storage backend
all of these tests were run on dell
servers using
real optane dimms our first
experiment used ycsb a common benchmark
to drive the database
this graph shows normalized throughput
so higher is better
we found that twizzler was faster in all
instances while pmdk's implementation
was often slower
of course again performance was not our
primary goal here but
here we see the effects of the
simplification of software layers
for the second experiment we compared
the latency of issuing queries against
an existing
million row database here we see the
results this time we're looking at
normalized latency so lower is better
here pmdk was significantly worse in
almost all tests while twizzler was
similar to the others
note that we're comparing two highly
optimized b3 back-ends to
two fairly straightforward red blacktree
implementations
we attribute the performance difference
between twizzler and pmdk
to twizzler's pointer operations being
more efficient and
also to pmdk's doubling pointers in size
which has
a significant impact on cache
performance and pointer heavy data
structures
twizzler is of course still under
development in many ways but
one of the directions we're most excited
about exploring is placing twizzler into
a distributed environment
the global namespace of object ids can
be truly that
global because twizzler has pointers
based on identity and not location
moving data around a network can be done
much more easily even to the point
where we can easily manifest either
computation or data
wherever they may be needed changing the
focus of distributed programming away
from manually marshaling data around
computers and instead
describing more clearly what the
computation needs to be
we're very excited about twizzler both
in sharing it with all of you but also
in where we can go with it we hope to
have gotten across
three key points in this video first
this technology
is coming and it has the potential to
greatly change our programming models
we want to be ready for that programming
has always been about data
and we have an opportunity now to make
our abstractions
really reflect this second the time for
a new os
is now not just because of nvm but this
greatly accelerates the need
but because new applications built in
new ways deserve
first class os support compatibility is
a vital feature to be sure but
the primary abstractions provided by the
operating system are not
compatibility finally
working with persistent data on nvm
naturally means that we'll be working
with persistent in-memory data
structures
these structures will need ways of
accessing and understanding data
that don't rely on ephemeral context if
we get this right
we have an opportunity to have a fast
but also flexible persistent pointer
implementation
that allows us to open our data up to a
global address space
so this is a new os it's a
rare and risky endeavor but we believe
that it's the right thing
not just for a future with nvm but for
any future
centered on data as the primary citizen
but of course the test of a new os is
how well it supports innovation and how
well it excites
people so we would love it if you read
the paper and gave us feedback
thank you for getting to the end i would
like to quickly thank my co-conspirators
peter pankaj daryl and ethan and my lab
mates for their
unending support we're really excited to
share this work with you
thank you for watching