a warm welcome after the coffee break
unfortunately the two presenters from
Simon Tech didn't get a visa so instead
of the dark side of the web assembly we
hear a very interesting presentation
about Android Android at the obfuscation
using static and dynamic cooperation
from Union Yanni from checkpoint thank
you good morning everybody thank you for
joining we're here to talk about mobile
threat detection I have two kids and for
quite a long time I had the bad feelings
that my kids cannot come to the
kindergarten and say something like my
dad is a firefighter but quite recently
my six-year-old son approached me and
said so that are you kind of a computers
policeman I chuckle the did feel a
little bit proud and thought about it
and said well maybe not quite a
policeman more like an investigator
Sherlock Holmes so for us threat
prevention on mobile is our day-to-day
job we proudly hunt malicious Android
applications for living my name is Ian
Eve nice to meet you my dear friend here
is the only Moses we're security
researchers at the mobile threat
prevention grouping checkpoint and as a
security professionals maybe not yet
okay so as security professionals we our
main task is to protect the mobile
devices of our users from any malicious
activity that might happen there and to
do that we have to process enormous and
ever-growing volumes of
application searching for increasing and
increasing numbers of malicious
behaviors and well naturally the only
viable way to process all those volumes
of data is to rely on automated
processes automatic types of analysis
and the precision and ability to scale
that those processes are the things that
actually define our success so while we
as security researchers usually want to
deal with a new zero-day or to find cool
and sexy new vulnerabilities the reality
is that our success is mostly defined by
our ability and our tenacity and
scalability to actually find all the
vulnerabilities that were there ever and
still mostly are relevant on very big
volumes of data and devices and
end-users and the companies so through
the course of the last year we little
bit departed from our usual let's find
new vulnerability kind of approach to
trauma mobile threat detection and we
invested a lot of effort in developing
new and quite innovative techniques that
actually allows to be much more precise
and much more scalable so one of the
things that we were able to discuss now
is deals with code obfuscation but first
let's talk a little bit how our whole
process works because the real story
here like weather will be like Bri texts
of black screens and like cold and sexy
things but the real story is that the
ability actually to to have a research
that ends in the production and actually
breeds does that value to to your
customers
so our analysis process I guess not
surprisingly works in cycles where we
first cycles are very cheap take
milliseconds and we mostly there it ends
like for the best amount of from a tech
forth of attempts it ends there a
millisecond and we we are done and we
know what it is and we are good good to
go first mostly these are known things
if things get more complicated we use
more and more expensive cycles until it
gets to cycles that take hours to
complete and there are various engines
that works those who seek for data those
who analyze that data and all the kinds
in between but generally we divide the
engines into the static ones until the
dynamic ones the static ones our project
practically those who behave in a way
like a human that tries to read the code
it the assembles there the applications
are try to understand what goes there in
a very theoretical way as a human being
reading it's printed on a paper while
dynamic approaches are the opposite its
sandbox the execution of an application
and in general we just sit on the
sidelines and try to understand what
goes down there so the static analysis
has its main advantage is that there is
practically nothing that prevents from
covering all the available code in the
application for the analysis because it
just blows through all of it and reads
it but the main weakness of it is the
dynamic loading that if an application
downloads actually parts of itself or
binary additional binary and runs that
during its its runtime then static
analysis has no there's no solution for
that because it doesn't have that
dynamic part also the encrypted parts a
problematic too because the ability of
static analysis to actually decrypt the
data a while it skims through the code
is very limited
while dynamic analysis is quite the
opposite it's it is very very good with
handling all the dynamic parts because
the application just runs so if it
downloads a binary they decrypt
something dynamic analysis doesn't care
because it just will
if application does something nature it
will just happen and we will just go on
but on the other side dynamic analysis
is quite poor with coverage because to
get to all the corners of an
applications it depends on on many
various things either it's a user
interaction like we have to click on
buttons in very particular way to get to
some corner and automatically it's very
difficult to do or it's based on on your
location on your device model on your
parading system on other application
installed on device and there are many
many factors that affect how
applications behave you all know
applications that are very malicious in
very specific locations but it's just a
funny game in all the rest of the world
so yeah when you think about these two
approaches together they they they in a
way they complete each other and it was
for a long time very logical for us to
think that okay if we can do all this
thing not divided in like two huge
approaches with with different efforts
but do it together then dynamic approach
allows us to get for example all the
binaries and all the decryption while
the static approaches can show what
should be Oh
the conditions and all the branchings to
get to the whole coverage yeah and
that's what we thought like five years
ago so I'm telling you oh very old news
why why did it take so long for us to to
get here first of all because it's very
complicated each one of these changes is
very complicated by itself and saying
that now we want something that is all
of them together is almost impossible to
do just like that also these are very
different skill sets these are very
different types of people who are good
at these two things static analysis guys
they are mathematical algorithmic guys
that good with data structures and
traversing trees and graphs and things
like those while dynamic analysis guys
they're very operating system people
they're also guys who recite Linux
kernel for their pleasure at night so
and also sometimes these two groups as
it many times happens with Challenger
the researchers think that their
approach is the best and all the rest is
redundant and why to bother so well okay
I still prefer to recite Linux kernel at
night and so eventually we we got to
understanding that we want that
investment because we want to be much
faster and much better on one side
understand we our ancients were mature
enough I think that my slides are kind
of progressing by themselves okay but
maybe sometimes we'll get them back so
and also our engines became mature
enough that we felt confident enough to
say that okay let's
just a leap of faith just doesn't matter
the time length whatever just plunge in
and and let's let's try to do something
good with it
so actually we we started there more
than a year ago with their with the
first attempts we first started
capturing the binaries on the dynamic
sides and transferring to the static
side which is technically quite easy to
do because you just move files and
there's very little interaction then we
had research about unpacking that
dynamic sides unpacks packed binaries
and passes the intro static suicide that
was a very interesting research that was
presented last year and DEF CON and now
it is in production and we are very
pleased with how it works so this year
we deal with with FISC Asian and the
interesting thing of the procession is
because there you cannot already solve
it with this easy interaction of just
take this file check that file
it actually required all the ancients to
work in kind of a pink pump like help me
here help you there and the more
interesting details Yummie will
elaborate Thanks ok so the focus today
will be really how dynamic analysis
actually helped static analysis deal
with obfuscated code in Android apps and
why is really an issue for us
obfuscation is quite common in Android
because as you know most of the code in
Android apps is written in Java which is
really easy to decompile and that's why
many developers choose to
to use obfuscation it can be a benign
developer that just wants to protect
their intellectual property from reverse
engineering and maybe it's a malicious
author that wants to avoid detection
so obfuscation is an issue for us I
think the you hear a strange feedback to
it so the most common biscuit technique
would be renaming of classes and methods
that the developer defined in their code
just to naming them to gibberish it's
not really an issue for automated static
analysis because it doesn't rely on the
meaning of names unlike human performing
reverse engineering who obviously relies
on on the meanings of the names but
string a ssin especially when it's
combined with function called by
reflection that's a serious issue for
static analysis and what do I mean by
that suppose an app wants to use a
sensitive Android API and it was to do
so in a hidden manner so instead of just
calling a function for regular function
call it can call it with reflection and
encrypt the name of the class and
methods that compose the API and so
static analysis can't follow this API
call also many other kinds of
interesting strings can be encrypted
like paths to content providers that
provide access to sensitive user data
like text messages so ok string
encryption is a problem for static
analysis why can't we just deal with it
on our own without asking for help from
these guys
well decryption is static analysis is
possible but it's hard because all
information is already inside the apps
code right otherwise the app itself
wouldn't be able to decrypt the string
on runtime so the decryption algorithm
is the
the decryption key is there but I don't
want to start implementing decryption
algorithms in my static analysis codes
and I don't want to come up with a way
to automatically find the decryption key
inside the app code doing static
analysis time it's just too much hard
work so okay if we consider that
decryption is done automatically when
the app is run maybe we should indeed
ask for help from our nice friends in
the dynamic analysis team and have
dynamic analysis simply read the
decrypted strings during analysis time
and then pass them over to static
analysis so before we show how this
actually works let's first take a closer
look on how string encryption looks in
the obfuscated app so a typical
obfuscator
would just take the string
initialization code and rapids with a
function call to a function that was
generated by the obfuscator itself and
this function basically returns the
decrypted string and it received as
parameters I guess you can consider it
is the encrypted string and maybe some
kind of decryption key this smaller
number and many times it would be a
static function which means it's not
dependent on the way the slides keep
moving on the road but never mind it's a
static function which means it's not
dependent on any previously initialized
objects so this is how it looks like so
I guess the first naive solution we
considered was just to have static
analysis look for calls to these
decryption functions maybe it's one copy
of the function call several times maybe
there are several different copies
nevermind so just find them in static
analysis and pass over
list two dynamic analysis and dynamic
analysis could place breakpoints so that
during runtime it can save the return
value which is the decrypted string and
pass it over to static analysis so
basically it's a nice idea but if you
remember if you recall you Neve
mentioned a major issue with dynamic
analysis which is partial coverage we
don't expect in this case that dynamic
analysis would be able to cover all
string decryptions because it doesn't
usually cover any possible flow in the
app's code so a better more
comprehensive solution will require a
bit more work during the static analysis
phase we will not only find all calls to
the decryption function in this case
it's the function here Bar will also
have to perform a backtrack search
looking for the values of the arguments
passed to the decryption function in
this case it's a constant string and a
constant number so that's not hard to do
in static analysis it's basically the
basic stuff that we do so no static
analysis can pass to the network
analysis a comprehensive list of all the
cripton function calls with the values
of the parameters so basically the Namek
analysis now has all the information it
needs to perform the cripton on its own
to execute the decryption code outside
of its ordinary context or flow so what
would happen then I reckon Allison would
load the apk but it wouldn't start the
app yet and start the main activity
instead it would patch Android runtime
to execute the decryption calls one
after the other and would save the
return value of the decrypted strings in
order to pass them all later the static
analysis and the static analysis can use
the values of the decrypted string to
sort of patch the code what do I mean by
patching the code first we just replace
the function calls to decryption with
the values of the decrypted strings but
if we also want to deal with the problem
of function call by reflection we want
to change these function calls to just
ordinary function calls that static
analysis knows how to follow so we will
look for calls to the method invoke the
API before a backtrack search to find
the names of the invoked classes and
methods and by now these names have
already been decrypted so it's ok and
then we just replace calls to method
invoke with ordinary function calls so I
hope it's clear enough but if not don't
worry it's a it's just a basic example
of how a patched code would look like
it's really a simple example without
reflection so basically what we have
here is a piece of code that wants to
get the device ID and to do so it needs
first of all to pass the string phone to
the gate system service API so in the
original apk we had the string phone
encrypted and now it's decrypted so as
some of you may have noticed there are
limitations to the solution that we just
talked about so first I mean I think
it's worth noting that for us the most
important thing wasn't to necessarily
get the best most comprehensive the
obfuscation solution but to really
implement and deploy to production a
feature that combines static analysis
with dynamic so it's okay for us that
there are limitations but you know let's
just state them for the record at the
moment it only works if the decryption
function is static and it's not
dependent on any previously initialized
objects
static and also receives constant
arguments and also we assume that the
decryption function doesn't have any
side effects right because now it will
run like twice instead of once so just
quickly about a little experiment that
we did to test our approach we wanted to
start with a relatively simple
obfuscator - oh it's a commonly
available commercial obfuscator and the
example previously saw was a code that
was indeed obfuscated with - oh so we
implemented a signature to find that
show samples we found about 600 samples
with - all string encryption in our APK
database and the example of strings
we've found there and so we ran our
complete solution on these 600 samples
we found that many of them had hundreds
or even thousands of encrypted strings
and it was nice to see that static
analysis detected new sensitive flows in
10% of these every apps
I mean flows that it didn't detect
before when the strings were encrypted
so access to Google account credentials
text messages user contacts and 10% may
not sound like much but Mary in mind
that most of these apps are actually
benign so it's perfectly possible but
they don't have a lot of access to
sensitive user data so easier said than
done
we did have to face some challenges at
the implementation phase because first
of all static analysis and dynamic
analysis weren't designed in our case to
work together and they run in different
environments because the narvik analysis
needs a fancy Android emulator and study
analysis doesn't and also dynamic
analysis had to violate a kind of prime
directive which is kind of similar to
the prime directive in Star Trek those
of you are familiar you're not supposed
to interfere with what you see but you
discover so dynamic analysis usually and
you don't want it to interfere if the
applications run because then it makes
it easier from our to realize that it's
being emulated being analyzed but in
this case we did interfere and testing
it's also required an interesting
infrastructure to run all these 600 apps
on both dynamic and static analysis so
just a quick note about what happened
when we deployed it to our production
environment first of all it currently
supports decryption of
- Oh obfuscated apps and also some
verses of text guard and most apps we
ran in production and had just a few
encrypted strings but some of them had
like megabytes of off encrypted string
data which really caused interesting
performance issues for us at first and
also the the whole thing was much more
volatile than you initially thought
because some apps are just not written
very well maybe they only work well on
some Android variants so they just
crashed in our analysis environment
before we even managed to run the string
decryption flow but overall it's
currently working in our production
environment and the performance impact
isn't very significant so to sum things
up and I hope we'll have time for a
couple of questions back to you thank
you ok so we were very pleased with our
results were running in two different
production for for a couple of months
for us so the main achievement was
actual ability to to get all the people
together and do that and reach that
stage where we just can actually
engineer that thing and the results were
so good
compared to like original skeptical
views that there is a lot of hunger now
to continue with this approach so we are
early working on much more sophisticated
depreciation techniques that actually do
handle state and try to work with with
more complicated situations where it's
even not necessarily a function because
not all ofus caters necessarily create a
separate function so we have to handle
actually pieces of a code that will have
to replicate and a lot of directional
things to do hopefully next year thank
you you have any questions
[Applause]