okay we have one more session to go
before we have lunch but it's going to
be an interesting presentation I think
shedding skin tone as fresh faces done
by good Baumgartner and Mike's good from
kaspersky lab's gentlemen all right
Thank You Ricard good morning everyone
thank you for attending today we're here
to talk about turtle activity that we've
been seeing in 2018 some of it is
preceded by activity and informed by
activity we've been seeing in 2016 2017
so we'll talk about some of that
activity as well but we're focused on
the here and now I'm Kurt Baumgartner
I'm a global or principal security
researcher with Kaspersky Labs global
research and analysis team I've been
part of the team since 2010 and I'm
happy to introduce a new member of the
team Mike Scott oh yeah hi Mike Scott
I'd fairly new to the team middle of
this year
previous to that I spent about a dozen
years in the US defense industry doing
network defense and Incident Response
and basically decided that I got tired
of working nights and weekends and on
actors time and switched over to the
threat Intel and threat actor tracking
side and I've been doing that for about
seven years and Allison alright so yeah
we're here today to talk about a large
threat actor they're capable well
resourced and they go back decades we're
gonna again talk about their activity in
2018 but we're going to sort of cluster
talk about clusters of activity Turla is
so large
they've many different things going on
at once and really this talk will focus
on some of their JavaScript or Kopi
Luwak and iced coffee activity and then
also what we've been seeing as far as
carbon mosquito Turla and it's some of
how it ties together related to wipe
backdoor we call the White Bear so this
is the sort of the larger mess that
Turla is and again we're gonna pick and
choose a few things that we're going to
focus on related to 20
teen activity this is not Turla this is
other stuff whether it's the Dukes sofa
see other russian-speaking apt if you're
paying attention to the news today you
may have forgotten that there is another
russian-speaking apt called Turla but
the sofa see and these guys are total
are somewhat separate and we have an
interesting finding about how separate
they are from Turla in 2018 the
targeting that we're seeing you can view
this map if you can't really read what's
going on here on secure list we've got
the link there for you
but generally Turla has been targeting
both remote and local organizations
foreign affairs organizations diplomatic
organizations government related
scientific and technical organizations
all over the world and this is simply
what we've been seeing towards the end
of 2017 and 2018 others we've seen other
public reporting on this group so in
some cases the problem is bigger than
our visibility than what we're seeing
and we'll point that out as this goes on
so related to Turrell is PE malware in
2018 we've been seeing new versions of
carbon and this is unusual this was
surprising to me we see carbon is
something that we mentioned back in 2014
as a part of the epic Turla operation we
posted on it back in yeah again 2014 and
we found multiple components to this
framework it's a it's a backdoor
framework the newest versions in 2018 we
see a new Orchestrator version 3 a 2 and
a new of injected object 4 0 5 some of
the new functionality that they bring
with it I have to do with anonymous
pipes and inter-process communications
so they are building and modifying on
something that's years old
it's interesting that we're also we also
happen to be seeing interpreter and
other open-source tools being used by
these guys to distribute and push the
new versions of carbon and in particular
we're seeing it in Central Asia they're
very selective about how their what
systems they're pushing it to so it may
be so it's it's just rare to find this
framework in the wild we'll talk a
little bit more about mosquito it's a
modified version of comrat that we
continue to see there's a lot of
activity from these guys and from this
operation in particular throughout the
world in 2017 and 2018 and again we're
seeing meterpreter and open-source
tooling being bundled into this mosquito
package and again it's remote and local
organizations that are Foreign Affairs
related and diplomatic in in these
regions and then finally we'll reflect a
little bit on white their sort of their
initial scripting efforts related to
spearfishing
and then and sort of their third Jase
that well the jscript of their building
into their their tooling okay yes Kurt
mentioned trellis used a lot of jscript
in javascript and in some of their
previous tools but iced coffee
aka Cheramie which some people and
including actors that's what they call
it that was kind of their first foray
into fully JavaScript backdoors this we
these initial samples were dropped by
and weaponized RTF and then some macro
alpha stocks and XLS the macro code was
very similar to what was dropping white
Alice also known as skipper so that was
kind of our early at you know way to say
hey this looks a lot like Lake Turla and
then fire I also blogged less 2017 I
think about some that 2702 61 and 27001
which was a prove esque that apparently
Turla and one other crime war actor
we're the first had the only access to
that zero day when I came out and one of
those was used to drop Jeremy
what's interesting is the macro code in
that they actually added a beacon
capability in the macro itself so when
the macro runs this it generates a
little bit of system information and
then sends beacon up to a c2 server and
we could work kind of hypothesizing that
perhaps that was a way to see you know
kind of gauge their delivery like the
effectiveness of their of their
exploitation and possibly the
gullibility of their targets you know if
the if the macro ran and we they got the
initial c2 then they'd know that the
microgram and it got a beacon was
successful but if then the system never
checked in fully with the back with the
ice coffee backdoor then either the you
know it was detected or failed or
whatever reason so kind of a interesting
tactic that they've started using that
Kopi Luwak did the same thing sort of as
well not a very robust backdoor I mean
it's it's fairly you know not very
feature-rich
it did a lot of use what WMI for
collecting a whole bunch of system
information that it's stored in a big
JSON blob and then uploaded it encrypted
it and and uploaded it to the c2 server
and but then it didn't really have any
command functionality per se all I do it
would just it would check into the c2
server and then depending on the
response from a server it could download
additional JavaScript and that qudoos to
run and then seven it was also backup it
you know not not very feature-rich Kopi
Luwak on the other hand was a kind of
the next generation if you will
different a totally different code they
overlapped in time a little bit but
similar kind of thing of drop initially
dropped by office docs proof point
actually logged on one that was dropped
by at dropper and then I was we'll talk
about later we've sought dropped by some
office shortcut link files the macro
code again was very similar to the white
atlas skipper stuff but then they had
actually added some new tricks to it a
new X or routine and some other things
for decoding the payload that JavaScript
itself is much more complicated than a
nice coffee was
and the way it works is it actually
drops a JavaScript to disk and then sets
up persistence and then the proof one
that when the it calls it actually
writes another level of JavaScript
that's run at runtime is decrypted with
rc4 and runs at memory so it makes it a
little bit harder to do forensics and
whatnot if you only have the JavaScript
you have to know the rc4 key to actually
run it this one news it does use the WMI
a little bit for system profiling but it
basically runs this huge giant block of
like net user IP config all the the
typical kind of host and network
forensics activity that writes it to a
file and Cripps it sends it up to the c2
server and then immediately deletes it
so similar kind of tactic to ice coffees
alieve tries to leave a very little no
you know very little footprint on disk
and leave very little behind for
forensics to discover kopi blog did have
the first version had about i think of
four commands that are supported that it
would based on the response from the c2
ver c2 server other uh-huh one of leg
you know it could it everything was
happy we just sit there and pause and it
would wait i think like three or four
minutes as somewhat randomization has a
little bit of randomization on how long
it would wait to beacon again they could
actually tell it to just kill itself and
wait until the server reboots or the
system reboots and then the persistence
will kick it on again if they wanted to
go quiet for a while it also had a mode
to just fully
you know remove itself completely and
delete all evidence of persistence and
then i'd also had a command command
capability similar to iced coffee where
it could run could download files get
download additional scripts things like
that all right
lots of scripting so moving back to
carbon and the carbon framework its
deployment really what it looks like
it's there are a couple of interesting
characteristics about carbon that are
unusual one is its unusually explicit
installer when we see the loader itself
it coincides with the presence of
meterpreter in some form which is really
unusual you've got amateur
functional and really interesting
codebase that they've been using for
years alongside meterpreter which is an
open-source freely distributed
Metasploit tool the carbon code when the
loader drops other components to disk it
uses the familiar sort of Turla
potty-mouth
error code messages in this case when it
succeeds it says hey lucky strike but if
they don't if they don't obtain
privileges to drop files to appropriate
locations they complain why the why the
F naught and then think other error
messages continue after that which is
kind of what you expect from Turla
certainly not a military discipline to
how they're deploying in writing code
the the loader is SRV RS RS vc dll
that's a file name that's been pretty
common across deployment so that's
nothing new but all the all the file
names mutex names everything they they
bundle into this package that could be
used as an indicator has been changing
across these minor increments so you
can't really use them from one release
to another to detect or identify carbon
it also suggests that somebody or that
the loader is being run manually and
somebody is inspecting the error
messages as they're running so the
loader that we were looking at is 621
621 K or 620 1000 bytes and here all the
filenames and internal component names
that they've been using and you can see
if well from earlier versions of carbon
they usually maintain these older
internal names and they just don't
bother to update the internal names when
they compile the code and push it out
which is unusual but that's what they're
doing so I guess one other interesting
thing to note about this file listing
and what you see on the screen here is
that
are multiple injected carbon libraries
it used to be simply an Orchestrator an
encrypted blob or a config file
encrypted with caste 128 and then and
then a transport library injected into a
browser an email client or I am but now
they've got an additional library and
it's it's large or I should say it's
smaller than the coinciding code that
had been previous really previously
released this is where there including
the anonymous pipes code the additional
stuff that they supplemented the older
code base with so mosquito has mosquito
is another package and another set of
activity that we're seeing globally from
Turla it's focused on diplomatic and
governmental organizations they're very
consistent about the target profiling
and they're less consistent about
locations in the world where they're
delivering it something that's not on
the slide has to do with their
man-in-the-middle techniques now when we
originally notified customers and Senta
and reported on this activity we noted
that there were men in the middle
attacks going on wood that we suspected
this was late 2016 early 2017 another
report came out towards the end of 2017
reporting on almost the same stuff so we
weren't the only ones seeing it and this
was a bit larger of a problem than we
expected interesting thing about the
installers that we had been seeing that
would support the hypothesis that these
guys are performing men in the middle
techniques that are Wi-Fi based have to
do with some of the installers gathering
and dumping all of the Wi-Fi profiles on
the system to an XML file and
immediately sending that back to the
situ that's followed up with a
collection of IP config information and
ARP - a or all of the MAC addresses that
the system has access to on the network
so they'll know what the
the Gateway mac should look like and
they'll know what the Gateway Wi-Fi
password should be so our flooding or
tools like silica or pineapples can help
you perform man-in-the-middle of
techniques if you ever lose access or
perhaps hit another organization or
location from the same organization so
in all likelihood we suspect and we have
data that that suggests Wi-Fi based men
in the midle techniques are going on and
not necessarily ISP level
man-in-the-middle techniques other
interesting things we saw with mosquito
and the sort of custom comrade modules
that they've been delivering is that now
they also are bundling in Metasploit
code it looked like they were tinkering
with challenges in injecting 64-bit
processes from 32-bit modules and they
started moving that into their code
later in 2018 so their use of Metasploit
has been documented publicly but
specifics like this just aren't
necessarily available so that's that's
interesting and it also is interesting
because it overlaps with what those guys
are doing with carbon they're also
delivering things with an interpreter
and the meta and components from the
Metasploit project real quickly I want
to mention white there is precedes all
this activity and this is where we see
some initial funky Java scourge a script
that they're delivering and using for
spearfishing targets so this is prior to
the iced coffee and Kopi Luwak stuff so
it's loosely connected through this new
scripting but one thing we also saw and
here's simply some more of their their J
script that they use in order to deliver
droppers to a system another interesting
point about white bear is that back in
2017 both white bear and Kopi Luwak
we're sharing the same command and
control server of a compromised work
WordPress site that they they
we use so it is tied of course it's not
a good technical presentation unless you
have some pie chart that nobody from the
back can read so I had to include one so
this is the UH knob this gated version
of an early iced coffee sample just kind
of show you it's a little little
daunting at first but as you can see
that that first function at the top
basically is a decoder for all of the
remaining lines at least a first stage
decode turlet loves to have multiple
levels of decoding and you know various
levels of a 64 and rc4 and all kinds of
crazy stuff they come up with for the
opposite for obfuscating their scripts
but it's really you know not a fairly a
simple decolo
and then you can see it applies to all
those lines below that first loop all
that this whatever and then that escaped
text and then the arguments that are
passed for the math functions and then
that's kind of what it looks like after
the first level of decoding you can at
least get a good idea what the scripts
doing you see they'll see - I actually
cleaned that up a little bit - made that
make the colors better I stuck some
quotes in there and stuff to make it a
little more readable that typical of
Turla almost all the c2 are compromised
legitimate servers a nice copy has it
some some help samples have like add up
to a dozen or so different c2 s they use
obviously compromise sites you don't
know how long you're gonna have control
over them so it's decent practice and
then at the bottom you can see the you
know the actors do call it Cheramie I
think that there is a V version 1.0.1
zero zero one well you see the first one
we saw I think 1.00 four is the most
recent I've seen anybody has anything
later than that I'd love to see it
I work traffic this is so this is that
first beacon that's generated by the
macro code itself it's not actually iced
coffee the interesting part is is at the
end of the get line you can see there's
a little bit of data that's there that
basic amount of system profiling
whereas that the ex may equals x and
then that next number is the process
idea of W script dot exe that's running
it should be running the backdoor the
next bunch of bytes are just a series of
queries about different registry
settings and things and then that last
word before the jpg is the like the
first two characters of the host name
that a username and then don't the
domain or one some combination of those
three just a unique somewhat unique
identifier for the machine that is
running on so that they could use
obviously use that to compare against
the beacon once know it you know if and
when that the actual JavaScript backdoor
starts starts working and here is the
actual beacon for the malware itself
really an interesting bit here is that
setcookie session equals if you base64
that decode that that is the rc4 key
which is then used for the the payload
which is all of that system information
that you know that the WMI queries that
it runs to generate a big JSON file it
then it are it RC for encrypt and then
base 64 encode x' and it sends it up so
it's nothing nothing super fancy there
the most recent Kopi Luwak that we saw
was late this summer or early this
summer I was kind of interesting we only
saw two targets scientific energy kind
of targeting government related but not
specifically government in Syria and
Afghanistan so two very interesting
targets in the way this works it was a
it was a zip link and you know with a
it's CV it with a document or at CV doc
or CV one one was disguised as a resume
one was disguised as a spreadsheet and
then within that there's PowerShell
within the the link file which you can
see is encoded first level of encoding
just simple base64 within that there's
more PowerShell which does the actual
carving the payload out of the link file
itself writes it to disk all that
there's just multiple levels and you can
see it'll write off SJS to disk and then
the decoy doclist XLS we get so you know
displayed to the end-user to you know
look like it actually did something
valid you know some of their code so
what the office J us does is it runs it
does all of the system profiling
commands it does it sets up persistence
in this case it uses a it sets up a log
on task that runs immediately and then
every 10 minutes so that'll keep you
know the main maintain the persistence
and keep it running and then it also
writes out this do you see that app data
roaming Microsoft chess stick check disk
j/s that's the actual of the actual
payload itself and then that persistence
that scheduled task will run
check this J s with a passphrase which
is the rc4 key that it uses to decrypt
within J when check this runs there's a
RC 4 encoded blob in the middle it is
actually the the money part of the the
payload and here is a sample of the copy
network traffic a little bit different
than some of the early versions actually
had a per user unique user agent the
latest version got rid of that it you
know looks a lot more legit again
compromised C 2 infrastructure and idea
I liked not gonna go and the payload
encryption is a lot more complicated
than with iced coffee then it's been
wild it was well documented by us as
well as a proof point later on so if
you're interested gotcha check out those
blogs we have references at the end but
what was really interesting is that
about two weeks or so before we found
these Kopi Luwak being dropped by the
link files
we'd reported on zebra c using linked
files to drop their their malware and
when we looked at it we've this that
third layer in of code
you can see they are exactly the same I
think there's one or two words that have
a slight case insensitivity difference
but all the variable names are the same
everything else it could be
you know I've ously it looks like some
kind of builder or some kind of tool
that's generating these because all you
have to do is change the you know change
the offsets and the payload and it
doesn't matter you know it's it'll work
from one to the next but I haven't been
able to find any other samples that
match these so either they're sharing
the same weaponize er tool or they're
you know perhaps like totally guys just
actually saw the does ever see one in
the wild and grabbed it and made their
changes to it or or they're sharing
tools or collaborating or buddies or you
know talked about it over beers one
night or something who knows yeah thanks
yeah that overlap is fascinating I
haven't seen that before so so to wrap
it up well there's some things that we
expect to see on the malware set side
and on the targeting set in for the rest
of 2018 and into 2019 from Turla we're
seeing increased open-source tooling in
malware this is surprising from Turla
and you know this is the group who
carried out epic Turla and was deploying
snake this incredibly complex route
kernel-mode rootkit for years had
hundreds of victims all over the world
really hyper high-profile interesting
targets and they're moving to scripts
and open source stuff they're continuing
to maintain and modify their older
elegant code like the carbon framework
but again deployment is rare we don't
see a whole lot of this in the wild but
we do expect to see more of it there are
indications that we're seeing a limited
subset of a new family of malware that
we haven't really digested but we do
expect to see a new family in towards
the end of 2018 we don't expect to see a
whole lot of zero-day from these guys
this is something they
we're capable of back in 2014 but maybe
in the past year we've only seen a zero
day from them nothing in 2018 I don't
think no water holing we haven't been
seeing them and certainly no kernel
rootkits so something is shifting and
changing within the group but they're
shedding all of their older skin and
then the newer stuff that we may not be
seeing that there's a lot of speculation
about why we might not be seeing some of
the newer more complex stuff from them
well maybe they're using BGP Heitkamp
hijacks boot kits maybe they're down at
the AMT level we don't know but it's
possibly something we can't see or some
of the mobile exploitation that we hear
about in the news and as far as
targeting goes it's probably going to
remain the same for the rest of 2018
the stands have always been a target of
these guys so sent all of Central Asia
sort of on a rotating basis takes on
targeting and it seems to rotate
throughout the year all of these other
regions in the world have been hotspots
in 2017 2018 we expect to see more of
that into 2019 so with that I'm gonna
wrap it up do you have any closing
thoughts all right thank you very much
for your time if there are any questions
oh okay thank you