okay everybody if you'd please take your
seats
sameer full disclosure in case you don't
know I work for easy Melissa works for
ESET but that's not why I'm expecting a
good that's that was your so my
motivation for doing this talk is to
address the problems and complaints that
I've heard over the years from people
who've been getting into the industry as
well as people finding more senior level
positions and this is such a new
industry
nothing is clearly set in stone and that
causes problems as well as benefits it's
not clear because it's not set in stone
we have a tendency to repeat things that
work well once which leads us to having
a large percentage of wong small subset
of people i think we all have a gut
understanding that no one of us can know
everything about security or even
something specific like malware research
there are a lot of things to know and a
lot of things to experience the more
different brains and experiences that we
can put together the stronger and more
resilient we all are it's important to
keep this in mind when we're putting
together security teams the more
different people we can put in one group
the more we can combine all of that
knowledge the better we're able to see
into the dark corners of the internet
the process of including more people is
about improving the way we do things for
everyone i hope to help you step back
and view things differently so that we
can all examine what dark corners we
might be missing from our own acquiring
practices whether or not you believe our
talent pipeline is too thin the fact is
it leaks like a sieve there are quite a
few systemic problems which boil down to
the effect of common mistakes being
amplified when they're all combined in
the US as in many other countries the
move to incorporate computer skills has
been very late in coming and in low and
low income in rural areas it's been
especially so teachers have little
understanding of how computers
much less how to instruct kids how to
use them safely this means a lot of the
kids who are getting to college are
already way behind their peers in terms
of being comfortable with technology
these kids are likely to shy away from
getting computer science degrees and
there's a feeling that computing and
security in general are more like a
magical security skill or like Wizards
skill that only a select few people can
do well we might like to think that
we're some elite minority of people who
can do what we do the fact is there are
a lot of people who could if they had
the appropriate training and we compound
this further by setting up crazy hurdles
that people have to jump through to get
a job so they may not even intern the
industry if they do get the right
qualifications once they do get hired a
lot of people in the most
underrepresented groups end up leaving
mid-career so what can we do to change
education problems even if they're out
of our direct control we can work with
education groups to help bring kids or
even mid-career switchers into the
industry that can also include
volunteering or giving money to
organizations to help kids get computer
education you can talk to your local
legislators about making computer
literacy as mandatory standard for kids
in school providing CS certifications
for teachers or about creating
technology internship programs currently
in the u.s. only nine states allow
computer science classes to count as a
math or science credit the availability
of both introductory an introductory and
Advanced Placement CS classes is
decreasing right now in both k12 and
many colleges and universities call it
computer science lags way behind the
current practices in teaching which is
project-based learning that relates a
subject to kids existing knowledge and
interests thus reinforces a view of
computing as lonely and boring I think
we all understand that computing can be
really fun and it is can be a useful
tool but it needs to be taught that way
you can talk to your local university
about what you need from students you
can also hire students as interns or
apprentice apprentices natella higher ed
is a better return on investment for the
majority of people or until they start
preparing students to jump into
positions without additional training
reconsider what qualifications you're
asking for for
applicants there are lots of ways to
improve inclusion the most obvious is
improving the percentage of women in
your organization the ideal for
inclusion is to aim for a similar
percentage within your company as is in
your customer base or your local area
we've probably all heard women make up
only 11 percent of the workforce
insecurity in the US while women make up
almost 50 percent of the total workforce
that's kind of a huge gap with a lot of
room for improvement but gender isn't
the only way that representation is
skewed not by a long shot
most of the these groupings are pretty
self-explanatory though neurodiversity
maybe in the new term for most folks the
term includes a wide variety of
different types of mental operating
systems like with unfortunate and
medical names like autism spectrum
disorder attention deficit disorder
dyslexia a fantasia amusia etc from a
threat modeling perspective each of
these demographics will have different
security and privacy concerns most of
which won't necessarily be obvious to
people outside of these groups each will
have different strengths to bring to the
table because the neurodivergent bit is
still so poorly understood and
influences so much of how we interact
with the world I'd like to clarify it a
little further we're still just barely
starting to learn how everyone's brains
actually work quite differently rather
than just assuming we all have the same
thing qubits for example a Fantasia is
lack of mental images which is a
condition that is only been studied in
the last few years
well a museu is a difference in auditory
pitch perception that was discovered
less than two decades ago both of these
things seem pretty simple but they can
have pretty surprising and far-reaching
effects such as in how we understand
instructions or how we proceed tone of
voice learning disorders like dyslexia
have been known about for quite a while
but most of it and most of us have a
pretty passing understanding of what
ADHD and autism are but even then
there's a lot of misinformation about
what these things actually mean for
instance most people have heard that
autism and ADHD mostly affect males and
that it's mostly because the original
studies only included males and a small
subset of males at that the way it
appears in females is different enough
that typically only the girls that are
most
only affected are the ones who are
getting likely to get the right
diagnosis the reason there's been a rise
in the number of people being diagnosed
is simply because diagnostic criteria
likewise are not set in stone they're
not well known and they're not
completely nailed down yet in the
general population especially among
women and minority communities learning
disorders such as ADHD in autism and
dyslexia are under diagnosed so it's
likely to that some of you in the
audience are neurodivergent and don't
know it yet
and where we find out the more it looks
like there's no so-called normal brain
each of us has our unique accommodation
strengths and weaknesses so things we
can do to help people with different
neuro types or not just something we do
to accommodate one or two people being
considerate of each other's mental
operating system is likely to help a lot
of us main thing to be aware of is that
other people don't process information
the same that way that we do don't
assume someone's terseness or lack of
eye contact is because they're being
rude don't assume that someone who's
always running late is being
disrespectful people with sensory
processing issues may be overwhelmed by
too much noise or light or they may be
distractible by when they have too
little input someone may prefer to
communicate over email versus phone
calls or vice versa sometimes it's
helpful to have instructions in writing
or as a diagram some folks have
difficult difficulty prioritizing input
and may need additional information
about what's most important so please
ask some of us take words very literally
need help identifying when things are
not as rigid as we assumed so please ask
questions early and often it's better to
err on the side of being very clear and
explicit then double checking to make
sure you have where your words have been
and received the way you intended them
and speaking of how the world appears
different everyone speak simple and
maybe unintuitive things are critical in
making things accessible for different
people without having lived the
experience it may be very difficult to
get a full same sense of how things
could be different for someone else for
example if you want to attract a
different group say you want to make a
product more usable for people who are
visually challenged and you're having a
hard time getting people who have this
experience so they know you know how
what accommodations need to be made to
make things more usable and it could be
that the area around your office is
really hard to navigate if you have
vision challenges so it might be that
you're having a hard time reaching
people in that group because it's
difficult to navigate to your physical
office the basic idea is that if there
are groups you're having a hard time
reaching it's always a good idea to
consult individuals to ask questions to
help elucidate things that might not
seem obvious and please listen to the
answers now part of the pipeline
improving the pipeline for security is
addressing our image I mentioned before
the weird idea that only a select few
people are capable of doing our jobs I
was recently talking to someone who is
trying to convince her son to get into
security this is a kid who at 17 having
never touched the car before decided
that he wanted his automatic car to be a
manual car and it's something he wanted
he learned how to do it
this kid is clearly curious he obviously
loves to learn he thought he's better
with hardware than mathematics and he
has no college degrees so he couldn't do
security I'm not exactly a traditional
security hayek candidate either no one
would have ever said hey kid who's
taking too many art classes hey let's go
stare at as a text editor all day I
would never have chosen security as a
career had it not been that had I not
had a chance to try it out first I fell
into my first job in this business and I
found out after the fact that it was a
good fit much like improving education
part of our efforts for improving the
image of security is actually getting
people from different groups into the
community creating or funding existing
scholarships for conferences helping to
make sure people are from
underrepresented groups are included in
etc and by improving good community I
mean improving safety for everyone like
for example keep reading and coasting
creating and enforcing codes of conduct
like the one VB did this year making
sure more types of people who are
included as speakers at conferences and
standing up for people who are on the
receiving end of jerkish behavior parts
of security industry have historically
had very hostile culture towards
everyone especially newcomers and women
it's kind of ridiculous to think that
we're going to get lots of new people if
newly new people are routinely hassled
a code of conduct should be about
establishing norms of behavior rather
than creating rules and regulations
those can easily be weaponized against
people who are not part of the majority
codes of conduct should be created by as
diverse a group as you can find whether
internally or finding people outside of
your organization it shouldn't be the
creation of a bunch of lawyers who are
just looking to mitigate risk
there are things company these are
things that companies can do as well as
conferences companies can also decrease
unfair pay gaps by being open about what
people are getting for salary and
bonuses and setting clear guidelines
about what the criteria are for
promotions by being transparent it takes
the guesswork out of whether things are
being applied fairly and this can also
help identify dead ends for certain
career paths even for technical careers
the usual path is going from technical
job to people management and we can all
probably think of someone who was
followed this path it was not
particularly suited for it their direct
reports may quit they may quit or burn
out and it's generally a bad situation
all around it's better to ensure senior
positions that allow growth within
technical skill sets by understanding
where people top out within your
organization organization you can set
things up so people can continue to
increase both experience and pay in
underrepresented groups this can be
extra problem attic as people get passed
over for promotion for reasons that
aren't necessarily related to promote to
performance
some people may avoid promotions
entirely if they see that managers are
expected to be a work for insane hours
and jobs flexibility is very important
for a lot of different types of people
for people who have children or aging
parents to take care of people who don't
necessarily excel in a busy office
environment the lack of flexibility may
limit their promotion prospects so
allowing people to work from home even
part-time may improve their ability to
get more done when you think about how
someone goes from it goes about becoming
a doctor there's usually a very set of
obvious steps between graduate high
school and start seeing patients and it
usually involves a specific path of
education certification and
apprenticeship that really isn't the
case for security there's a benefit to
this as well as a curse most of us never
did an internship or apprenticeship
there's a lot of us here without degrees
or certification we learned on our own
or we learned on the job but the
flipside is there's some serious
ambiguity in what the expected path is
if you look at existing ads for
positions at any level you'll almost
invariably see degree requirements or
something vague about equivalent
experience which means you're inevitably
turning a lot away away a lot of folks
so what can we do to turn this around
for starters hire people who are
actually entry-level meaning they have
interest and inclination without
specific experience you can also what
widened widen what counts as experience
for example doing projects like making a
blog or helping out in a forum or some
community group or creating their own
security tools community college degrees
are often seen as less prestigious but
they can often be a lot more effective
at training people for a job without the
usual hoop jumping that college degrees
usually require I know there are a lot
of folks who would argue that you can
learn very important things about
security knowing the difference but it's
entirely possible to learn to understand
ethics without knowing the difference
between kirkyard and cons but for a lot
of people college simply isn't
accessible this may change as more
colleges move online but it's unlikely
it will cease to be a huge financial
burden for people in some countries if
you do want to main retain degree
requirements you can help help offset
this burden by offering scholarships to
people looking into get looking to get
into computer security or talk to your
local schools about what knowledge
graduates actually need to be useful to
your company because technical skill
requirements can be a pretty quickly
moving target it might be more effective
for colleges to focus on getting
students fluent in meta concepts of
computer security or computer science
and that way students could gain new
skills more quickly without having to
constantly update college coursework our
current system is set up to ensure a
huge number of false negatives people
are being pushed out of the pipeline at
every stage and we're failing to detect
huge number of people that would
otherwise be ideally suited more
experienced security practitioners are
the more likely they are to be what wary
of red flags that indicate a difficult
work environment what can we do to
counteract this don't expect the right
people to come to you there's a badly
worded phrase about doing the same thing
over and over again and yet we post our
job listings in the same place over and
over again and expect will magically
start getting more in diverse candidates
by going where the candidates are and by
making your company visible to diverse
communities you can find more diverse
applicants and while you're at it skip
the equal employment opportunity type of
legal boiler page if at all possible the
impression it gives is less we're a
diverse workforce and more we need to
find a token minority and that usually
means a really bad time for the token
minority yep if you ask 10 security
analysts what they do day to day you're
likely to get 11 different answers to
help clarify things we can start using
standardized job description terms the
National Institute for cybersecurity
education has come up with a workforce
framework that makes a common lexicon to
describe security work I so if you know
picking terms from those lists I think
we've all had the experience of looking
at a help-wanted ad for a security
position where it looks like someone
took every computer computer resounding
where they could think of and made a
list out of it I've looked at job ads
for patient positions that I've left and
I knew that the job didn't require half
of what they were calling mandatory and
that's a massive mishap of mismatch and
if they weren't doubling their salary
range they would be seriously
underpaying this person and lastly don't
forget that interview interviews are a
two-way street
you need to be showing candidates on
your company as much as they need to be
selling them their qualities to you it
can be helpful to think about what
you're ideally trying to do as finding
the amazing candidates that everyone
else is missing I can't think of anyone
who's more experienced at convincing
recalcitrant people to do things that
they don't necessarily want to do that
are good for them then parents of small
kids if you want to see how creative
someone can be at hacking technology to
figure out how false technology to see
how it falls short and how I can work
better for them talk to someone with
vision or hearing challenges
and people with learning disorders have
had to learn to do what they need to do
with a different set of tools than we're
all assumed to have we're all good at
what we do because of our life
experiences not despite them incredibly
talented smart and motivated people are
being turned away at a time where we are
desperately in need of lots of good
people so how do we make an ad that's
really enticing to a wide variety people
well we've probably all heard about ways
you're supposed to be able to reword ads
to make them more lady friendly I'm not
entirely convinced it'll change as they
suggest our gender specific as much as
they're about encouraging community and
cooperation rather than competition a
lot of our existing culture both in and
out of tech tends to value beating out
your competition rather than people
working together I think we have a bit
of an advantage in anti-malware as
there's already an understanding that
there's lots to be gained by putting our
heads together by including words in
your ad that focus on long term learning
and growth you're naturally going to
increase the variety of personalities
that will find it compelling tell
kenneth's how they can contribute to the
success of your business or make the
world a better place they can probably
that skip superlatives and extreme
modifiers someone doesn't actually have
to be the best reverse engineer in the
world they can probably be a just a good
one and get the job done and for a lot
less expensive
speaking of salaries start off with
telling your applicants your expected
salary range too many companies make
salary negotiate negotiations some sort
of ridiculous guessing game and then
they disqualify people with no
explanation or lowball them after
they've already put in a lot of effort
and use accessible text for example
black on a very light gray background is
best for readability non serif fonts are
more readable than serif left-aligned
text is better than justified use short
paragraphs avoid idioms that can confuse
people who aren't native speak of your
language and use bold text rather than
it outs for emphasis
make sure screen readers can read all of
your text especially if you're putting
in pictures I talked before about a
scenario where the crimes were way off
from what the job entailed assuming
you'd like to avoid that what should you
consider perhaps reconsider about your
job requirements let's go back to the
education
background I've talked before about how
requiring college degrees is not
necessarily a good indicator having a
bachelor's degree doesn't necessarily
mean someone's at a certain level of
intelligence or that they have a certain
amount of knowledge a work ethic or
skill it's wholly possible they could
have taught themselves to do what you
need them to do on their own and then
there's the whole X years of experience
with wide technology
is there something magical about that
specific number of years is there
another way you can express it that so
the people who master the technology in
X minus two years won't be turned off
how about experience with solving X
kinds of problems a lot of different
groups can be turned off by overinflated
requirements especially people who
actually have experience that can be a
very clear sign that jobs that the
companies have really unrealistic
expectations and will hold people to
unfortunate standards certifications can
be a good way to ensure that people have
a baseline of technical knowledge but if
someone only has 90% are you going to
disqualify them because of that some
companies are moving towards asking for
employees to commit to taking a
certification within a few months of
starting their job as a way to motivate
people to get that additional training
it can also be helpful positions where
other skills are more important than the
technical ones and if you're in an area
that's outside of the usual tech mecca's
it can really open your options to offer
remote work there have been quite a few
studies done in recent years about the
effects of remote working to see whether
it's actually hurting or helping
companies bottom lines and any of you
who've worked in an open-plan probably
be unsurprised to hear that people who
can choose their own working
arrangements are a lot more productive
and a lot more efficient
studies show that teleworking can allow
people to decrease the numbers and types
of distractions in their day it's and
it's not just employees that are self
recording this while they're actually
goofing off two-thirds of managers and
once there a survey reported
improvements in their reports as well
other studies say more than 80 percent
of remote workers reported reduced
stress 80 percent reported better morale
and almost 70 percent showed reduced
absenteeism so it should also be no
surprise that attrition also decreased
by half
naturally opening to the possibility of
remote work increases your range of
applicants since you're removing
geographic boundaries among other things
the thing to be aware of though is that
remote working can highlight deficits in
your existing communication if yours is
a group that tends towards everyone
keeping their head down in their own
work or having a lack of transparency or
ignoring people who don't toot their own
horn these things likely cause problems
that said these are not good things to
have and so it could allow you to find
these deficits and fix them so that when
they're so easy to see it's really
helpful to branch out where you're
posting your ads to reach a wider
variety people well you will reach a
smaller number of people on alternative
job boards it'll have much more impact
by showing up where people feel safe
it'll show that they're important the
presence is important to you and I hope
this is obvious but if you're asking
security conscious people to put their
data into sites that are not secure it's
generally bad luck if you use recruiters
to find qualified applicants choose ones
who can prove they have a track record
of finding diverse talent or ask your
existing recruiters to start tracking
data so that you can start providing
data so you can track it you can also
tap networks of your existing plays by
giving hiring BOCES bonuses to people
who give recommendations especially for
diverse talent once you've gone through
your stack of resumes and started doing
interviews there's a whole new set of
things to consider we've probably all
heard horror stories about bad
interviews which is to say or it gets
around if your company is being
inconsiderate to candidates it's
important to remember interviewees have
lies and maybe an existing job that they
need to attend to don't put undue
burdens in terms of either the number or
the lengths of interviews if you do an
in-person interview find a calm and
quiet interview site there's a been a
trend of going to war in formal places
to decrease the pressure on candidates
but team interviews that involve
drinking in bars or even just busy
coffee shops are really not a great
place for being able to hear people
decreasing pressure on applicants is
always a good idea but don't shoot your
shell itself in the foot in other ways
some companies use in-home tests or
quick in office projects to get a more
realistic sense of how
people work with others or how they do
their job done well this can be a really
great way to see people in their natural
element but this isn't an opportunity to
score free labor more keep requests
brief they shouldn't take more than a
few minutes to an hour especially with
people who are new to the industry or
maybe younger they may not have a lot of
experience with business travel or tight
finances might cause someone to drop out
if they think you're expecting them to
drop a lot of cash to travel to a
faraway place I'll let people know in
advance what expenses you'll cover like
parking gas flights hotel that sort of
thing err on the side of not making them
pay upfront make sure you're giving all
your applicants and even chance it's a
good idea to have a panel of interested
parties come up with a list of interview
questions in advance that way you're
comparing apples to apples take notes
while you're reviewing and grade them on
predetermined criteria then review your
impressions shortly after each of
interview and if you're having multiple
do people do the interview include as
diverse a group as you can to get a wide
variety of opinions when you're creating
questions or grading your applicants be
sure to stick to job tasks and qualities
that actually pertain to what they need
to be able to do for example people who
work with code or sell them known for
their fancy dress habits and personal
charisma is not usually a necessity of
malware analysis of course that won't be
the case if it's a single job and please
don't ask people to answer trivia
questions or come up with obscure facts
that they won't actually need to be able
to do their job and they would just
search for Google if they had to once
you've hired somebody you want to get
the best out of them security is a brain
intensive task which means people will
need quiet time and space to do their
job open-plan offices and meetings that
could be an email or the bane of our
existence based in many of us got into
security is because it offers learning
opportunities if we don't continue to
learn we become less effective over time
make sure your reach researchers have
time and funding to go to workshops
conferences or community events to keep
their brains fresh having enough time to
do projects that actually fix problems
rather than just slapping a bandaid on
it is very good for a mental health it's
also important to establish
psychological safety so employees feel
safe taking moderate risks that means
being able to speak their mind without
fear of their getting their heads
been off or being ignored there are a
few things is wasteful and frustrating
is hiring security people and then
disregarding their ideas and yet we all
know how often this happens if you're
hiring someone to do security trust
their opinions work with them to
understand the business case for what
they're wanting have sponsors both for
individuals and for the security group
in general having someone who can speak
up for people when they're not in the
room can do a lot for morale and
longevity the things to remember for
bringing new people are sort of a repeat
of all the things we talked about before
have a good code of conduct make sure
people know it and understand it and
enforce it when things go wrong be clear
and explicit about performance goals
from the outset use the buddy system so
that people have someone who already
knows the ropes who can help them get
established to feel supported check in
frequently to make sure that they're
getting settled in ok and help them find
the right resources if they're having
problems so here's a few wall of text I
here's a few resources the first few are
about helping kids learn about coding
the project include has a lot of
resources about creating an effective
code of conduct and how to improve
inclusivity in tech black hoodie
workshop is a reverse engineering
workshop for a woman Esper girl society
or it has more information about the
presentation of autism spectrum and
women I mentioned the cyber security
workforce framework talking about the
security job descriptions remote Co has
a lot of information about how to sell
up tetons head how to set up teleworking
in your org and the national women our
Center for Women in IT is a great source
for statistics about women in technology
they just put out a report last week
about girls in k-12 and computer science
classes and finally different groups
there are the specific course
organizations for different rupes intent
thank you okay Thank You Melissa um
[Applause]