all right if you could take your seats
and thank you for attending we're gonna
hear my Paul and Warren from Cisco
Dallas talk to us about Olympic
destroyer take it away guys hey guys
thanks all for coming so we actually
Tunes the title a little bit our title
was originally who wasn't responsible
for a limit destroyer
we will very much cover that but we also
just realized that attribution is a
complete circus so we're gonna go
through some of the naivety that exist
and some of the complications that come
up with it so Paul's gonna do half and
I'm gonna do half and well will flick
through sue obligatory Who am I I'm
security researcher with Cisco towels
Paul and I worked together on lots of
interesting different apt stuff for the
last three or four years I like you're
gonna malware finder like pretty much
everyone in this room
my background is network engineering
moved into malware analysis threat
intelligence and if anyone ever wants to
tan I'm cool fine or be sighs Belfast so
I'll be very happy if you wanted to chat
and talk about that alejandra port works
yes it works fine so my name is Bert as
you can hear them I'm French but like
the previous speakers said to me two
hours ago for my English it's not my
fault it's cuz I'm French so yeah I'm
marijuana distance rich researcher at
Cisco Terrace so basically I work on a
lot of different apt related stuff don't
go it besides Belfast go at BOTS
confessor conference I organized of
course cuz Island is shitty its range of
the time extra kala lie Nala lie so come
in France the food a beta of course and
we have windup Guiness yeah everything
is better
we have dinners in versus arty
you got Liam Guinness yeah so more
seriously we are here to speak about on
MP destroyer
so everything start by this article for
me I really Thomas and they I think
something like that and it looks when I
read it it looks something interesting
so I started to work on the era stuff to
maybe find it if I was lucky
how will it bring you why I was lucky
and how powerful we are and just to have
an idea of the real impact about this
case is the ring the ceremony the
opening ceremony website was an
available ticket system well done so
people are not able to print it get to
to go inside of off any big game and the
Wi-Fi was unavailable on some part of
the organization and it was done during
few few hours so it could be worse
because finally everything worked and
the ceremony was here it was it was
streamed everywhere on the world etc but
there is a real impact on this case on
local people in in South Korea so here I
don't even know why we translate it I
think everybody is able to read but it's
text from incident response team manager
on this incident and 50 internal server
was impacted by this malware so included
Active Directory and database servers so
sensitive server as you can imagine and
Olympic game organization has around 300
service so it's not all the servers but
it's a large part anyway so how works of
Marwa it's very similar from
architecture part of use and what we saw
in the past like I want to cry not pitch
extra so you have the malware that scan
your internal network
he used legitimate protocol you
by every system and mr. otto in the
world like PS exact w a knife already
standard normal here provided by
microsoft and try to propagate inside of
the network so it's not magic you cannot
go from a machine to another machine
without any credential and stuff like
that so the Marwin need to have some
information Hue's several trick to get
this information the first one she
implemented a browser steerer so every
username and password are coded on the
brothers Chrome Firefox Internet
Explorer was exfiltrated was collected
by the malware and this created a
dictionary of password and try
propagation with this password because
as you know everybody use the same
password everywhere so that's why he
take brought up as well another way to
get password on system it's to steal
system password credential ash so to do
that the malware huge mimikatz it's a
very famous open-source tool to perform
pass oh hush so to get hash from memory
and to jump on another machine and he
simply repackage mimikatz
and use it like that to get a stop
password on on the system once he get
hold this password she created
dictionary lists and patch himself so
itself he patched the malware add this
credential and this copy was sent to the
next server executed and the same thing
was performed new password was add on
the list and etc so Moultonborough is
executed more you have after it password
inside of the binary finally the main
goal of what we named olympic destroyer
is to destroy the machine i will
describe you exactly the different step
for destruction and yeah here is a
screenshot of password stealer
basically sure he the brothers used the
SPLA light database we simply perform
query to get last well and everything
was sent by a named pipe to the main
module here he is the mimikatz code so
basically it's it's how it format
credential and here is on the binary I
analyzed first the opcode it password so
first when I open the document I thought
Z as a binary I thought the attacker
already had some password but in fact
it's bass well stolen from a previous
execution so it was executed on the
first machine and the sample hi had
access was not the first initial one but
another one if you check on VG for
example you can have sample we as the
killer boom boom so the last name of the
Vitesse and ducks inside of the binary
so i think there is a kind of infinite
loop so you send sample to VT VT
executed in sandbox generate a new
binary with viticulture this one is sent
to VT which is exhibited in sender so I
think it cost some resource to VT to
under this sample and yeah if you want
breaking news and something we don't
disclose on our publication how I detect
this malware my yahuwah's function
so really simplest URL we've ever
written
yes during Olympic game a crater yahood
wisp reaction cause why not and luckily
the domain the real domain of Olympic
game organizer his Pyeongchang 2018 so
that's how I found it here he is like a
little bit like previous speaker said
the Marat destroy Shadow Copy so
snapshot performed by Windows are
destroyed and he destroyed backup on the
system and something very interesting it
does not wipe the local file but he
Wi-Fi
on chef folder so not local stuff but if
you map a file on your server or laptop
he would destroy a file on this chef
folder
basically on company every important
fight I'm not store locally you can lost
your laptop you can be stolen whatever
if they don't care everything is put on
the chef and in this case the matter a
target share so it's very common for for
for wiper he destroyed a boot club boot
recovery and as on previous case he
destroyed event lock so same thing is to
annoy forensic investigation and there's
our stuff this one is less common the
malware list every windows services and
switch off each services one after one
extra so basically your system cannot
boot anymore if you if whole your
service are disabled so this is where it
could really quite funny for us and we
obviously published a lot of information
on let me destroy at the time obviously
what came out that similar to what mom
was talking about earlier researchers
will continue concepts and ideas that
have been published and all their
information to find out more information
which is cool so this is sort of what
happened after we published about lamp
destroyer Kaspersky came out with a
great report some I became I with an
interesting report about other elements
and we started to look at it a bit more
and this is where we came up with that
who was responsible for another
destroyer portion who the media circus
started like this definitely North Korea
actually no it wasn't North Korea
definitely wasn't North Korea it was
definitely China and I went from China
to Russia so we just named three nations
today it's just for the fun of it in the
media and King denote the we didn't
point out or name any nation states are
out to be disdain anyone at the time but
this is how it sort of started for us to
when you see different reports coming
out from different companies different
vendors and different researchers you
start looking back the trial understand
well did we miss something or what
further information could we ascertain
and this is where we started to look at
the links that were being talked about
sooo Lazarus group magnetically
discussed by lots of people all the time
and one of the overlaps that we started
to see was some of the blue north mal
were used by Lazarus group for some of
the swift infrastructure bank heists and
that was a very very simple one so again
when you Charlie the attribution I mean
one thought was brilliant and the whole
idea here is attribution never lets us
win we don't ever win because we can't
generally do anything about it is the
research organization as a van der as a
company et cetera law enforcement of the
people who need to win and that's
ultimately the people we need to try and
engage layers with etc add back to the
Metallica
so EVT chk was a string that existed in
the blue north group malware samples I
think of his EBT chkl but dot text and I
think this similarly used the dot text
inputs ooh a small link but one that
maybe points out this could be something
related similarly using finally in
patterns because it's something that
exists attackers continue to be lazy the
CM wiper crude sooner we were wiped the
first thousand bytes of the largest
files identified they didn't wipe
everything like some of the malware
that's a higher discuss was about wiping
whole files who infrastructures whole
systems olymic destroyer from a local
perspective was trying to wipe out small
sets of files the reason for this is
speed the Viking wiped things quickly I
can move on to the next file quickly etc
etc so these are some of the
responsibilities that lied with it that
we start at the overlap and then
Kaspersky came out with a great report
sukhasan steam at grid started looking
at rich header information now we look
at malware all the time how many people
honestly ever looked at rich header
stuff so like excellent except costly
because he doesn't kind this purpose at
so we're like one other guy it's not
something that I generally do I do think
it's something you generally do
generally you get the header to make
sure it's a readable file type of it's
not as it corrupted has it been tampered
with
is it sabotage can you fix it etc but
know that the guys at Kaspersky quite
quite rightly pointed out that the two
rich I don't have a pointer sorry the
two overlap and cool bases that exist
here within them are pretty much all of
the rich text header nor the poem with
rich tax errors
very very undocumented which again is
why maybe not a lot of people would cut
it
but what Kaspersky discovered is on the
left we see the blue North sample sushi
with laser script and on the right
dynamic destroyer samples we published
it but right down until the last like
four bites it's completely identical
that's not something that happens by
accident
it just is not an accidental outcome of
compilation and when you actually start
to look at the code what Eugene
Kaspersky did they identified that
whenever you decode the information
related to the rich text header you
actually start to understand water was
compiled by so the blue north sample as
you see on the left and the Olympic
short sample on the right would suggest
that were identified and compiled by the
just to do 2003 what you see the VC to
say the VC six element but in actuality
it's an AK 64-bit compiled platform that
was compiled and Visual Studio 2010 so
what's all that what's the point of all
that was a point to discuss in rich text
format well it was completely copy
pasted and I was a complete fabricated
header there was nothing real about it
from a compilation perspective that
rings alarm bells from each straightaway
and shoot all right in the world so
that's our first sort of interpretation
of multiple false flags that existed
within Olympic destroyer and then we
moved on to and some output from insert
labs who think are about here this
week's through insert labs write a very
nice code similarity platform and insert
labs
published some information about the
kotrina existed so apt 3 para PI an apt
10 men you pass well they also wanted
the genome on this party of a longer
destroyer because they also had cooled
over a lab that existed so similarities
that we were able identify were
credential stealers so this was open
source code which could mean it was or
wasn't a false flag they could have been
an actor who reused to see em open
source code they alternatively could
have been an actor who deliberately put
that in that there are multiple outcomes
that can exist there and then
similarities and the AAS function an apt
10 and one thing to point out about the
apt handling that is the only time
that's been identified so maybe it forms
a stronger link that this could be a
relation to a PT 10 but then why can't
it be related to a PT 3 or why can't it
be the laser script so we start to see
this combination
a false flag buildup happen and then we
seen what we dog nieta not patty with
the same propagation technique Perce
exact WMI using mimic huts that became
very very prevalent and samples and
attacks that we've seen over the last 18
months we've seen WMI used multiple
attacks to have the warm and propagation
technique to allow you to go from box a
box be too boxy again this one mentioned
automated operations become very
important for these type of skill
attacks you can't just drop a box and
wait for a remote user to access it and
then carry on moving around living off
the land on that infrastructure when
you've got automated operations like
this you need code that can go off and
do that and this is where worm
propagation type cout comes in and
seeing where the transfer still in
credentials to me and me and pipe so
again many cats if anyone has ever
looked at many cats you'll see that the
proof of concept code is out there the
fully code is on github it's open source
anyone can use it
ie Antioch tur can use it and a good guy
can use it which is used very he'll even
read him and any bad guy can use it
which we see very heavily under the last
18 months eternal romance is where it
get really really interesting for us so
Paul and I worked on a levee destroyer
quite a lot for maybe two or three days
and did all the things we need to do to
publish information and then a couple of
slides there I'll talk about some
attribution that came out from Microsoft
related to eternal romance so that made
us sort of revisit that because when we
were looking at we didn't see any
evidence of eternal romance so the best
way to see eternal romance is during
dynamic analysis where it will attempt
to open up SMB ports and will attempt to
try and spread propagate exploit
etcetera that just didn't happen and let
me destroy however when you actually
look at the code base you see the four
structures that relate to eternal
romance
being in there so they actually are used
sorry they actually are input in the
code but they're never actually used
anywhere and you see this sue this is
the proof of concept code for eternal
romance those four structures existed
within a limited destroyer if you go and
grab the olympic destroyer sample you'll
see all this code and they're just never
use never reference never called as a
function never used anywhere along so
how we go up to that was basically
windows defender sent a tweet out in
February
and said fresh analysis of this has led
to eternal rumors being used and we were
like yeah at this time I was a rib
pissed because I said I missed
something big and I started to to
understand why I fail basically and
where is the code of eternal remnants
and trust me it's real time consuming to
look for something that does not exist
you cannot prove a negative that is the
most important lesson I think the Pole
and I learned from this you cannot prove
a negative
so our boss was like where's the eternal
room outside of it there is no well it
can't be right Microsoft if said it and
that's Korea Microsoft do some awesome
research we got in touch with Microsoft
and started to discuss how do we get to
this point of play what what has led you
to say that's because we don't agree
with you that wasn't about public
slander or slinging anybody under a
posture and I think we got it was simply
Paul and I thought we had done something
wrong
pause about the seg fault and john-boy
at the window so we needed to stop that
from happening and understand what was
wrong so why we believe the Microsoft
team this conclusion was a view Google
some of the code that exists within the
structures that relate to eternal
romance the very first hit that you see
is a mess 1710 which is the eternal
romance platform so that's the code
available on github
we think what has happened is someone
has been analyzing and as we all do you
your Google in windows API is on MSDN or
you're googling random stuff like this
to try and make complicated tracks come
together we believe they've maybe Google
this information from the structure and
came to the point with God that
basically the exploit the Python script
existed first and they figured okay this
is what's happened so as I say we got in
touch with whom we discussed what the
actual with the actuality of this was
and then twelve hours later they put out
a tweet to say actually that didn't
happen so Paul and I were very happy
when our boss was very happy cuz he then
believed that we were good at our job
and we were actually doing things right
Paul knew longer seg faulted and we had
a happy life ever after and then we
ended up here and so we obviously
continue to look at it as well to see
who's going on and some of the
comparisons that we came to the
I've discussed really briefly I would
existed between Olympic destroyer and
yet district not Padua and bad Robert
so we've seen similarities and
propagation techniques we've seen
similarities and exploits used however
as I just discussed eternal romance was
not used on Olympic destroyer but when
you've got pieces of code base that
relate to they exist within your code
it's very easy to jump to the conclusion
that it is used which is what we seen
happen we seen many cats use we seen
credentials being passed forth and
passed back and forth mimic cats
we've seen some files encrypted we've
seen some files deleted we've seen some
machines destroyed so we get that point
in time where we have small linking
similarities that exist between these
multiple campaigns over the last 18
months
and what that also reports down to is we
believe this author purposely planted
false flags we went through Lazarus
group overlaps
we went through apt 3 and apt 10
overlaps and then we went through
eternal romance overlaps that doesn't
happen by accident
possibly one happens by accident where
you have code overlap you can maybe copy
and pasted something like the turn
rumors so that could very quickly cause
it a similarity engine to freak out
because it sees all this information
related to this sample but also in this
sample the open source related platforms
or warlock can happen ie mimic cancer
but we believe it was purposely included
false flag information what's the point
of that well it can be taken to the
extreme of a country denying an attack
on their party false attribution again
the biggest issue with attribution is we
as security researchers like that
overarching
piece of information that exists only on
under law enforcement so we can't write
indictments we can't write warrants we
can't smash down doors and take servers
we really nice of all of us could do
that because I'm sure would be very
successful in doing that and we would
have great fun doing it but we just
don't have the capability to do that
what we have the capability to do is
look at technical implementations of
code we look at how binaries operate we
look at how they work we look at the
codes that are used a long way and we
try and make a I don't want to say
derisory but we try and make an attempt
at attribution at times but we just
don't have the tools and I do want to
say skillset because I think some of us
do have the skill sets for it I don't
think that's a skill set that's missing
in this and this
I just think it's we don't have the
necessary tools to do it but it could
really go from the extreme of the press
saying it was North Korea the press
saying it was China and the press saying
it was Russia - this being said well we
think it was then because of this code
overlap the the point of that all that
Rommel is basically don't take for
granted would you read in a piece of
code because it's not always right a
limit destroyed specifically had real
potential to do a lot more damage we
don't really know why but they had the
potential to wipe that whole
infrastructure and wiped out all the
whole investment that had been in for
the Hong Kong Olympics they could have
wiped out all three hundred servers they
didn't we don't really know why we could
toss a coin and we could make
assumptions as the way a destructive
malware will continue to be popular
whose board a crypto jaqen I know I am
yeah who's bored of Bitcoin miners I
know I am so this gives us something a
bit more fun to look up because we need
to try and catch it quickly because we
need to stop machines being impacted and
we need to stop stuff being taken down
essentially and advanced reactors will
continue to evolve they'll continue to
copy each other whether or not that's in
VN I did premature or whether it's
because they think someone else was
better cooled in them the key and
there's some life lessons we'll never
really knew the point of this is
basically don't Luger cold dude assume
it's right and do this soon because it
exists in one platform that it's correct
on another platform and the circus is
not I closed today is your last day to
clone around with Fraulein
so yeah