okay
all right we should begin i think it's
working
so uh you might think that the best part
about being a program chair is dealing
with angry emails or conflicting pc
personalities or trying desperately to
stay on top of 450 plus discussions but
you'd be wrong the best part is actually
getting to help choose the best paper
award winners we had three such papers
this year and this is their session
we had one sort of unqualified best
paper that'll be the first talk and then
we have two best paper awards for papers
by early career researchers
so the first of our three best favorite
award winners today
is batch arguments for np from st and
more sorry uh from standard bilinear
group assumptions by brent waters and
david wu and david will get to talk
great thanks a lot for the introduction
and thanks a lot everyone for coming so
today i'll be telling you about batch
arguments and this is joint work with
brent waters
so in a batch argument for mp a prover
has a collection of mp statements and
his goal is to convince the verifier
that all m of these statements are
indeed true
a natural way that the further prover to
do so is the prover can send over m mp
witnesses one for each statement and
have the verifier check that each
statement witness pair is indeed valid
however a natural question that we might
ask now is can we do better can we have
the approver convince the verifier that
all m statements are true with a proof
whose sides grow sublinearly in the
number of instances and the can the
running time of the verifier similarly
be sublinear in the number of instances
that it needs to check this is the
setting of a batch argument for mp the
goal is to amortize the cost of mp
verification namely we seek a
construction where the size of the proof
grows with the size essentially of a
single instance times something that
grows polynomially in a security
parameter but more importantly
sublinearly and ideally poly
logarithmically with the number of
instances we impose similar efficiency
requirements on a verification time
where essentially the cost of mp
verification for m instances should also
grow sublinearly with the number of
instances being checked
so batch arguments for mp is a special
case of something called a succinct
non-interactive argument or a snark for
np however if we look at existing
constructions of snarks they are either
based on idealized models like the
random oracle model or the algebraic
group model or they're constructed based
on non-standard strong non-falsifiable
and knowledge assumptions or they can be
based on heavy cryptographic machinery
like indistinguishability obfuscation
here we see constructions from a single
standard simple assumption
if we consider the relaxation of snarks
for mp to the setting of batch arguments
then a series of works by shodori jain
and jin have recently showed how to
construct batch arguments for general mp
by leveraging the machinery of
correlation intractable hash functions
which can in turn be instantiated either
from the subexponential ddh assumption
in conjunction with the qr assumption or
more recently from the plane learning
with error's assumption
if we consider the setting of what's
known in the setting of bi-linear maps
we know how to construct batch arguments
based on non-standard but falsifiable
q-type assumptions over bi-linear groups
the focus of this talk is to give a new
construction of non-interactive batch
arguments for general mp that can be
based on standard assumptions over by
linear maps namely we can instantiate
our construction using either the k
linear assumption in the prime order
setting or the subgroup decision
assumption in the composite order
setting but i think the more interesting
and more salient point that i'm going to
make here is that our construction
is very low tech it all does not rely on
heavy cryptographic tools like foreign
interactable hash functions or on
general information theoretic primitives
like probabilistically checkable proofs
it takes a very direct algebraic
approach for constructing batch
arguments
in fact it harkens back to a classic
non-interactive zero knowledge
construction or an easy construction by
grosso strauss against a high that
follows a familiar commit and proof
paradigm
this is what i will show in a talk today
as a corollary of our main construction
we also obtain a ram delegation scheme
otherwise known as a succinct argument
or snark or p with a sublinear size crs
from standard bilinear map assumptions
previously
this was either known from in the
pairing based setting this was either
known from non-standard pairing
assumptions or
required a launch quadratic size crs
another corollary of our main
construction we obtain an aggregate
signature that supports bounded
aggregation from standard assumptions
over by linear maps previously this was
only known in a random oracle model
so now let me tell you a little bit
about how we construct batch arguments
for mp in our new framework we follow a
commit and prove strategy that's common
in the construction and many other kinds
of proof systems yes the second is as
follows suppose you have approver and
approver has a stack of mp statements
and it wants to convince the verifier
that all m of these statements are true
here we're going to work towards the mp
complete language of boolean circuit
satisfiability and for simplicity of
description i'm going to assume that all
of the gates are nand gates
so we have a collection of m circuits
and so essentially what you can see is
that for each of these wires we actually
have a vector of m wire labels one wire
assignment for each uh instance in my
relation
so what the first thing the prover is
going to do is the approver is going to
construct a vector commitment to each of
these wires in the boolean circuit each
each of these vector commitments is a
commitment to m wire assignments m01
values
importantly for our construction we will
require that these vector commitments be
succinct namely the size of a commitment
should scale polynomially in a security
parameter but importantly poly
logarithmically or better yet
independent of the length of the vector
or the number of instances that we are
committing to in our particular case the
length of the commitment will actually
be independent of the number of
instances
now once the approver has committed to
all of these assignments to all of the
wire labels across all of the instances
now the approver has to reveal or
convince the verifier that it actually
committed to valid
inputs so this is going to consist of a
sequence of validity checks first we
have to check that the commitments to
the input wires are actually consistent
with the statements being proved here
this will actually be quite simple in
our construction because the commitments
will actually be deterministic and so
the verifier can simply compute for
itself what those commitments are
next we have to check that each of these
commitments to the wire labels are
actually valid values in the case we're
talking where we are working with
boolean circuits
each of these wire values should be a 0
1 value it should be boolean value so
the wire validity checks will check that
each of these commitments is to a binary
value vector
next we need to check that the wire
values actually respect the gate
constraints namely for each gate in a
boolean circuit the commitments to the
output wires better be the nand gate
applied to the commitments to the input
wires
and finally we need to check that all of
the output wires are indeed one namely
that the circuit accepts on all of the
inputs so these are the four checks that
we will
describe
in our construction and the important
observation that we will leverage in the
construction is that each of these
validity checks can essentially be
encoded as a quadratic polynomial and
thus they can be checked in the exponent
with the help of a pairing that would be
the underlying idea
for our construction
so first let me describe how the
commitments operate here we would simply
use hedersen multi-commitments and for
simplicity of exposition what i'm going
to describe in today's talk is our
construction using composite order by
linear groups
so in particular the group g will be a
group of composite order and for the
first part of this talk everything is
going to work in the subgroup of order p
later on when i talk about the security
analysis we will actually use the full
group but for now everything works in a
subgroup of order p
so just to recall in the patterson
multi-commitment if i want to commit to
a vector of m things this common
reference string is just going to
consist of m random group elements
okay and for uh ease of exposition i'm
going to write this
as the exponents in bracket notation so
this will denote an encoding of this
particular value in the exponent so the
crs this consists of m random group
elements
denoted by these m random exponents
to commit to a particular vector here a
vector of wire assignments we're simply
going to take a subset product of these
group elements so if you look at the
action of what's happening in the
exponent we're basically going to take a
subset sum of
these random exponents so that would be
the commitment
to a vector
so
what remains is to simply show how we
argue that these committed values are
actually correct or actually uh respect
the circuit constraints so here i'm
going to describe how we're going how we
validate that every single wire is a is
a 0 1 value that is actually a
commitment to a boolean labeling of
every circuit in the instance over
across all of the instances
so we can encode this labeling function
as a quadratic predicate namely an input
x is binary value if x squared is equal
to x
so the key idea here is we're going to
now use a pairing to check this carrying
relation or this quadratic relation in
the exponent and just to recall what a
pairing is is an efficiently computable
bi-linear map that essentially gives us
the power to multiply exponents in a
target group this is the property that
we will leverage in our construction
so what we're going to do is the
following we're going to take the
commitments so the subset sum of the
exponents and we're going to pair it
with itself
and then we're going to also consider
the pairing of the commitment with a
commitment to the all ones vector namely
the sum of all of these exponents in the
exponent
okay so these are the two quantities
that we're going to study so let's see
why these two quantities are actually
useful let's first expand the pairing of
the commitment with itself
so when i pair the commitment with
itself the commitment is a subset sum of
exponents
if i pair it with itself i'm simply
going to get this quantity squared so i
can write out expand all of these
components and basically i can decompose
the result into two sets of terms one
set of terms i will call the non-cross
terms these will be the case when i take
the index i here and i multiply with the
component in index i here so the indices
match and i get something of the form
alpha i squared times x i squared
and then i will have a bunch of
frost terms which is basically the
products of an index i on one side and
index j on the other for i not equal j
so it won't matter what these terms are
eventually what we'll focus on is just
the non-cross terms okay so this is the
first
equation that we're going to look at the
second equation is we'll pair the
commitment well with a commitment to the
all one's vector let's see what happens
here something very similar happens
namely here we have a sum of all the
alpha i's here we have a sum of the
alpha i's we can again decompose this
sum or this product into a collection of
non-cross terms and then a collection of
whatever's left namely the cross terms
so here let's just focus our attention
on the non-cross terms what is the
relation that we're hoping to check well
we want to check that for each i
x y squared is equal to x i that means
that x i is a binary value so if x i
squared equals x i observe that these
two expressions are actually identical
so this means that if the prover
did the correct thing namely it
constructed a commitment to a binary
valued vector
these two equations these two relations
here would actually be identically value
modulo some differences in these cross
terms
so how do we complete the check we're
simply going to give the prover the
ability to eliminate the cross terms in
the construction so these two quantities
will be equal except it's some
differences in cross terms what is that
difference well is this expression here
that depends on alpha i alpha j for i
not equal to j
so what we are going to do is we're now
going to augment the common reference
string with a collection of cross terms
we're just simply going to publish
encodings of alpha i times alpha j
so this will be included now as part of
the common reference string and approver
uh
it can take the common reference string
and compute exactly the quantity here to
verify the verifier will take this
element pair it with the generator and
boom it arrived it derives the frost
term that is needed for the verification
relation to check out
so this completes the description of the
verification relation and then we repair
the commitment with itself pair the
commitment to the with the commitment to
the ones vector
b should be equal if the approver was
honest modulo some differences in cross
terms we'll publish the cross terms in
the common reference string so now
approver can provide exactly the terms
needed for the cancellation to occur and
satisfy this relation
so the non-cross terms here are going to
enforce the check that x i squared
equals x i this is the check that every
uh at every component is binary value
and then we have the non-cross terms
that basically correct for this pairing
check relation
we can actually use what i just
described the same general strategy to
enforce the gate constraints so here i'm
just going to give a very high level uh
sketch so our goal is to now show that
if i the commitments to the output wires
of each gate actually respects the gate
constraint on the input values to each
gate so again we can write this as a
quadratic relation namely the output
value should be the nand of the input
values that is exactly saying that the
output value should be one minus the
product of the inputs this is a nand
gate operation this is again a quadratic
relation we can use the exact same
principle that i just described to check
this in the exponent so i'm not going to
go into details here i'll refer to the
paper but it's using exactly the same
underlying mechanism
so this actually completes the
description of the construction so to
construct a batch argument all we do is
the following we
take a look at each of these wires
compute a vector commitment to each of
those wire labels and then we just check
that
each wire and each gate are properly
computed so the size of the commitment
is just a single group element so the
size depends only polynomially in a
security parameter and does not depend
on the number of instances or the length
of the vectors
for each of these wire predicates and
gate predicates again the proof is
basically this sequence of cross terms
that's needed for the cancellation again
one group element each so the overall
proof size only depend on the size of
the circuit times something that depends
on the security parameter completely
independent of the number of instances
that we're checking
so the one thing that i have not
described is whether this is sound right
so hopefully i've convinced you that
this is a complete construction mainly
if you have a sequence of true
statements you can actually the prover
can manage to convince the verifier but
is this sound right does this actually
work
the soundness here will require some
care
so if we come back to the original
construction the commit improved
strategy used to build non-interactive
zero knowledge by growth of strategy and
sahai they had this very similar type of
strategy so how did we how did they
argue soundness in their construction
in their setting they were what they did
was uh they relied on the ability to
program the crs in a way
that it is possible to extract a witness
from the commitment itself and for a
false statement if we have a false empty
statement no witness exists and so this
is sufficient to argue soundness in fact
statistical soundness of the
construction
so can we try to mimic a similar type of
proof strategy in our setting so here we
are going to run into a bit of trouble
the commitments that we use here are
succinct namely we're committing to a
very long vector using a single group
element and so we can't hope at least
not from some kind of non-knowledge
assumption to extract the entire witness
from just a single short commitment so
we need to rely on a slightly different
strategy and here we use something
called local extractability or somewhere
extractability that has featured
prominently in many similar works on
constructing succinct arguments and
batch arguments in recent years
though the idea here is as follows
we will define two different
distributions for the common reference
string
what i will call the normal mode which
is what i just described just having the
random group elements and then the cross
terms
and then there will be a second mode
which we will call the extracting mode
and the extracting mode will have a
special index i associated with it and
it will have the property that
when you sample a crs in the extracting
mode
there will be a trapdoor that will allow
you to take a valid proof and extract
from it a witness but not a witness to
all of the instances we can't hope to do
that because we don't have enough
information it will allow us to extract
a witness for just the i instance so if
the proof verifies i can find a witness
wi such that for the i instance this is
a valid witness
and moreover we will require that the
common reference string in these two
modes are actually computationally
indistinguishable so this is very
similar to notions like dual mode proof
systems or somewhere statistically
binding hash functions very similar
paradigm
and if we can show these two properties
this is sufficient to argue non-adaptive
soundness of the resulting construction
so first i need to tell you how we
sample the crs in these two different
modes the first what i've written here
is the normal mode for the common
reference string just the collection of
random group elements nothing has
changed so far i omitted the cross term
for simplicity
if i want to switch to extracting mode
on a particular index here denoted i
star what i'm going to do is i'm going
to take my crs which has m random group
elements and i'm going to lift element i
star from being in the subgroup to the
full group so far everything i have
described works in a sub proof of order
p
what i'm going to do now
when i want to switch to extracting mode
is i'm going to take that subgroup
component and lift it to the full group
that's the only thing i change in a
common reference string and i define the
cross terms analogous
by the subgroup decision assumption
which basically says a random element in
the subgroup is computationally
indistinguishable from a random element
in the full group of a composite order
group we can argue that these two crs
distributions are actually
computationally indistinguishable
so
how does this help
so the trap door in our construction
will be a generator for the orderq
subgroup and the way that we're going to
extract so suppose i have a commitment
that's commit that's computed with
respect to this new crs where in
position i star i have now switched from
an element of the subgroup to an element
of the full group
the way that we can extract is simply by
projecting into the order q subgroup i'm
going to say that a commitment is a
commitment to zero if its projection or
its component in the order q subgroup is
zero and is a commitment to one if it's
non-zero
so using a pairing i can efficiently uh
to perform this procedure
so what remains to show is that this
actually successfully extracts a witness
for the chosen target
the light i'll just demonstrate it for
the case of the wire validity checks so
consider again the wire validity check
that i described at the earlier on in
this talk i'm going to pair the
commitments with itself share the
commitment with the r1s vector and then
have this final component which is the
cross terms cancellation component
so let's study this equation in more
detail what components does the
adversary control well the adversary
gets to choose the commitment we don't
know how the adversary comes up with the
commitment it cooks them up an arbitrary
group element that's the commitment and
it can also choose this arbitrary
opening or arbitrary proof v for
satisfying the wire validity checks
those components are under the control
of the adversary
what's not under the control of the
adversary however is the generator gp
and this commitment to the all ones
vector these are determined completely
by the common reference string and we
can assume that the common reference
string was honestly generated so
these components are outside the control
of the adversary
the second observation that we will
require is that if this pairing relation
holds because we are operating over a
composite order group right a group of
order p times q by the chinese remainder
theorem if this holds mod n it must in
particular hold in the mod p sub group
and the order q sub group so this
relation holds in order p and the order
q subgroups and we're going to consider
what happens in the order q subgroup
so the final ingredient that we will
need in our soundness analysis
is that if we look at this expression
here
this verification relation has three
pairing products that is computing or
three pairing operations
the final component here we're going to
pair something in the order p subgroup
and something under uh that's controlled
by the adversary
the point is that because we're pairing
with the generator for the order p group
whatever the adversary does completely
vanishes it cannot affect what happens
in order q subgroup so what if we only
analyze what happened with this
verification relation in the order q
subgroup we have basically isolated a
single instance the instance i start so
let's just see
mathematically how that happens so let's
suppose that the commitment is just some
group element has some component in
order p group and the order q group our
adversary can choose this arbitrarily
the complement of the all once has a
particular structure determined by the
crs
so if we consider this relation in the
order q subgroup whatever the adversary
does here has no effect we can just
completely ignore it because it's
projected away
all we're left with is the relationship
here the relation that needs to be
satisfied for this equation to hold is
any order q subgroup whatever the
adversary chose for the commitment
quantity squared must equal whatever the
adversary chose for the commitment times
this honestly chosen value r
this equation has only two solutions
either t is equal to zero in which case
this was a commitment to the bit zero or
p was equal to r which in this case
means that this was a commitment to the
bit 1.
so in this way we have argued that if
the wire validity checks pass then in
the order q group the adversary could
have either committed to zero or
committed to one they must have used the
honest strategy in order to satisfy this
relation
and now by a very similar type of
analysis we can also show that the
extracted bits must also satisfy each of
these gate predicates so by very similar
analysis i won't have time to show the
details here
so this completes the soundness analysis
of our construction and actually gives a
complete batch argument for general mp
so again just to remind you how how the
construction works the approver starts
by committing to all of the wire
assignments across all of the different
instances and then the approver uh gives
a proof that each wire uh each
commitment to the wires are binary value
and that all of them respect the gate
constraints
so this is a commit and prove strategy
for constructing batch arguments
so now let me just tell you a few about
a few extensions to the basic
construction here so so far everything
i've described is a new setting of
composite order groups suppose you want
to work in prime order groups this is
actually
a fairly standard to do the way that we
will do it is we will simulate these
subgroups with subspaces in a prime in a
vector space and this projecting
property we will implement using an
outer product of vectors so using this
we are able to construct
an analog of this construction using
prime order asymmetric groups and we can
base hardness on a standard k linear
assumption for any k and that's at least
one
the second uh thing i want to tell you
is that if we look at the construction
that i've described so far it has a very
long crs right the crs consists of these
random group elements one for each
instance and it also consists of this
giant collection of cross terms right we
need to right now as i written it it's
the side of the crs scales quadratically
with the number of instances it turns
out that we can improve upon this using
a standard recursive composition
strategy some very similar to the one
previously used by collide netanyang we
can actually reduce the size of the crs
from quadratic in a number of instances
to m to the epsilon for any constant
epsilon so you can choose epsilon
however small you want of course we're
going to blow up by a large polynomial
and security parameter but the
dependence on the number of instances
can be an arbitrarily small polynomial
in a number of instances
finally
once we have a new batch argument for mp
we can use it to get
a succinct argument or snark for p or
otherwise called a ram delegation scheme
this essentially is just by plugging
everything in to the previous compiler
budgetary gin and jin so just to recall
in their compiler they show how to start
from a batch argument for mp in
conjunction with a somewhere extractable
commitment this can be used to obtain a
delegation scheme for ram programs our
work we give a new construction of batch
arguments for np
and our techniques essentially also give
us a somewhere extractable commitment it
doesn't follow as a black box but using
the same kinds of uh methodology we're
able to construct this also from
standard pairing based assumptions and
this country and this combination is
sufficient to get a delegation scheme
program programs uh where the size of
the common reference string skills
polynomially or sublinearly with the
number with the running time of the
computation being checked
so previously from pairings this either
relied on non-standard assumptions or
needed a quadratic size crs
okay so to wrap up uh this the focus of
this talk has been on constructing batch
arguments from standard assumptions over
by linear maps and the key feature of
our construction is that it gives a very
direct construction uh direct algebraic
construction of batch arguments and
avoids the heavy cryptographic or
information theoretic tools that have
been commonly used in previous
constructions it gives a direct complete
commit to improve approach for realizing
batch arguments
and at the coral areas we get a ram
delegation scheme we get an aggregate
signature scheme that supports bounded
aggregation in a plane model and with
that i'll conclude thank you very much
so we actually have plenty of time for
questions despite the late start
so
for questions
i encourage you to come down and use the
microphones on the side
maybe while people are waiting i have a
question actually can you uh say a
little something about the split
verification procedure
yeah so the split verification procedure
basically says um you want to you want
to split your verification procedure
into an offline phase and then online
phase so normal verification first of
all will require that the verifier read
all of the statements right because it
needs to check that your proof is
actually valid for a particular set of
statements and that will always grow
linearly with the number of instances so
with split verification what we want is
there's a two phases there's an offline
step and an online step the offline step
is allowed to depend on its full
sequence of statements and if
and it outputs a very short
verification state and online
verification then only needs to read a
short verification state and can scale
sublinearly with the number of instances
and that's actually critical for this
recursive bootstrapping because we want
that the verification algorithm that
we're going to compose with itself to
actually have a verification size that
is much smaller than the number of
instances so that's why we split it into
a pre-computation step and a
post-processing step
okay thank you
questions out we have some no yeah here
in the front
yeah
um
ah so you want to just from quadratic to
linear size cs
yeah so then you only have to
compose once so i think it goes from
lambda to something like lambda squared
yeah i would have to check the concrete
thing i think it basically blows it up
by a quadratic vector
ah so that was just for the
that was i think for the
uh the commitment to the all ones right
so the commitment to the r1s vector uh
in this case in the extracting mode we
had to move from the subgroup to the
full group so it was actually critical
for the soundness analysis that at least
one of the components in the crs
actually has a non-zero component in our
q subgroup but that was needed for the
extraction
why
ah so for the security proof yeah
uh yes so in order to invoke sub-group
decision it says that random element in
the subgroup is indistinguishable from a
random element in a full group so they
you cannot have the random element in a
full group have a one in the g2 subgroup
other questions yes here
yes
that's right
that's right that's right so you have to
be able to repeat
yeah so the question is about adaptive
soundness and can we hope to prove that
from standard assumptions
uh yes so
yes and no so i don't think there's any
barrier to showing a batch argument with
adaptive soundness now if you have a
batch argument of knowledge so you can
actually extract a full witness and it's
adaptively sound that would actually be
sufficient to get an adaptively sound
snark which but then by the gentry wix
separation would mean that we would
likely have to rely on some kind of
non-falsifiable assumption but at least
if we don't require full argument of
knowledge if you just want soundness it
is potentially possible that we can have
fully adaptive soundness i don't think
there's a separation currently though
time for one more question
yeah
yeah so basically that's a great
question so how does the proving time
interact with the sort of this recursive
bootstrapping uh so essentially what
happens is
uh
then each time you recursively compose
it it takes you from a crs of size uh
let's say lambda to square root of
lambda uh and the proving time uh and
the blow up sorry it goes from square
root of m to sorry to m to square root
of m and a flow up in the security
parameter roughly goes from like lambda
to lambda squared uh so basically i
think it would improve it uh you incur a
factor that is quadratic in the security
parameter
yeah so i think for concrete efficiency
purposes it's probably advantageous to
actually just use the base construction
and not use the recursive composition so
the recursive composition i think is
just interesting from a theoretical
feasibility perspective but if you were
to use the construction i would
recommend using the one with the
quadratic size crs
all right with that let's thank david
again great thank you
great thank you
you
all right so the second paper in this
best paper session and our first uh best
paper winner by uh
early career researcher is breaking
rainbow takes a weekend on a laptop
by lord villains and
surprisingly award we'll give the talk
support please
yeah uh so hello everyone yeah i'm
talking about gift chances of rainbow
um so i'll start by explaining what was
rainbow so it's one of the the finalists
in the nist sports quantum competition
for digital signatures
the other two being crystals lithium and
falcon they're based on structured
lattices and rainbow is different is
based on multivariate quadratic
equations
uh yeah it has some some good properties
the the signatures are quite small and
it's as good performance in terms of
signing time and verification time
uh the drawbacks are that the public
keys are quite large and uh yeah as it
turns out that it's not secure so that's
what we'll
talk about today
okay so the history of rainbow uh starts
actually before a rainbow was invented
so it's based on this scheme uh by
pataren uh from 1997 where he invented
the oil and vinegar scheme
but this game had the drawback that the
public keys are quite large so in 2005
ding and schmidt invented this
variant of rainbow that somehow combines
multiple layers of oil and vinegar
to get something with slightly smaller
public keys
and then there was a lot of
cryptanalysis in
right after it was invented but that
dried up pretty quickly uh and i think
in
the last attack was found so and then
there was a long period where nothing
really happened until
um rainbow was entered in the nist
process
and then people started to to look at it
again
there were some
results about mean rank attacks so these
are attacks that reduce a key recovery
on uh rainbow to the min rank problem
which is where you're given
some matrices and the problem is to find
a linear combination of them with with
low rank and there's been some some
improvements in solving this problem
actually uh one of the talks tomorrow is
about uh this this line of work
um
and so so yeah but this is more of uh
yeah the
it's not really a new attack it's just
like the the existing reduction to mean
rank uh got
got more uh efficient as an attack also
there was some new analysis of the
rainbow band separation attack
that showed that the attack was slightly
more powerful than we thought before
um
but yeah all in all there were no really
new
attacks on rainbow
uh
until uh
the third round so it was selected as
one of the finalists but then uh things
started to go wrong
so um
i had a paper at eurocrypt last year
where i gave like a different
description of of rainbow so the the
schemes are completely equivalent it's
just some different way of looking at it
which
is
yeah it avoids coordinates and changes
of variables so it's more elegant
mathematically and it allows you to see
what's really going on and this allowed
me to find some some new attacks
and uh yeah those attacks only reduce
the security level by 20
bits of security
which uh the the rainbow team claimed it
was they they claimed to have enough
margin to still meet their their goals
uh but then in this work i found a much
more
efficient attack that can actually break
the security level one parameters
in practice
uh yeah so yeah this is a table with uh
the estimated bit costs of the of the
attack
so as you can see the security level one
parameters for the second round uh the
the
number of
gates to do the attack is roughly two to
61 which translates to to one weekend on
the laptop which is where the the title
of the paper comes from right but for
the for the higher security levels
um yeah the the the cost is still quite
big so for example two to the
uh
131 first security level one from
security level three of the second round
uh which is still out of reach of
laptops and other computers that we have
okay so uh yeah that was the
introduction so i'm first going to talk
about this oil and vinegar scheme uh a
little bit more because you can't really
understand rainbow but without knowing
how the vinegar works then i'll talk
about rainbow then the attacks and and
then i'll end
so um i mentioned it's a multivariate
crypto system
um it's based on a multiplayer trap door
so what's that that's
yeah just
a trapdoor function that is
uh a multivariate quadratic function so
it's just a bunch of uh quadratic
polynomials in some variables like like
this this example is
a map in three variables with three
components and
this is what our trapdoor function is
gonna look like
so you can evaluate this function very
easily you just plug in your values and
evaluate the function
and the idea is that this map looks
random and for random maps
we believe that finding pre-images is
hard but actually there's some some
hidden structure and if you know the
structure then you can sample pre-images
for these maps
efficiently uh and then yeah once you
have such trapdoors you can just build
signatures exactly like how rsa
signatures work so your public key is
your trader function your secret key is
this trapdoor information and to sign a
message you just hash to to your output
space
uh and then you
your signature is a pretty much for this
uh this hash right so anyone can verify
if your signature is correct but in
order to produce a signature you need to
know this this trapdoor information
right so this is just exactly how rsa
signatures work
but the question is how do we produce
these these trap door multivariate maps
and yeah this is
there's multiple proposals but
the simplest one is this oil and vinegar
trap door
so um the type of structure is very
simple so it's just a linear subspace o
and your trapdoor function is just a
bunch of quadratic polynomials that
vanish on this space oh right so for
every vector
in in our space o p of o is going to be
zero
so so that's it so there's no extra
information to generate such a trapdoor
function you just first pick your space
all uniformly firmly at random
and then you pick your polynomials
uniformly at random such that they
vanish on all right so this you can
which you can do
so the question is how do you use this
trapdoor information to actually sample
uh premature pre-images
um and before i explain that i need to
uh introduce this this definition
so
if you have our multiplied map p we can
def define uh differential at some point
x
uh i call your d of x and it's just
defined as
p of uh
yeah
sorry that is p of x plus y minus p of x
minus p of y
and yeah you can you can verify very
easily that this uh this is a linear
function it's also a linear in the point
x
and this is going to be useful uh
to understand how oil vinegar works but
also for the attacks
right so now with this differential how
does the
how do you use the the trap door
so we're given our drive door space o
and some some output value y and we want
to find an x so that p of x is equal to
y the idea is very simple you just first
pick some uniformly random input v
p is not going to be a solution of
course but you can solve for some
correction term in o so p of v plus o is
going to be whatever you want it to be
and it turns out that doing this is just
a system of linear equations right
because um
with our definition of the differential
we can write p of v plus o as p of v
plus p of o
uh plus this differential right if we go
back to look at the different of this
definition you just move the p of x and
p of y to the other side
and
now
the trick is because p vanishes on o we
can ignore this this middle term and our
remains is just p of v which is some
some constant and then some linear
function of of your o
right so this is just a linear system of
uh m equations right because our p has m
components and we have m degrees of
freedom namely o can be in this space o
which has dimension m
so with large probability this will have
a solution and then you just
output as a signature or as your
pre-image p
you output v possible right and it can
happen that your system does not have a
solution but then you just try again
uh with a different
different tree right so this is how oil
and vinegar works it's i believe a very
elegant
scheme that it's
just
the only structure is this this subspace
on which p vanishes
um
so yeah that's that's quite nice
and now how how does rainbow work so
it's a bit more complicated instead of
one uh space all we now have two spaces
so one and o2 and they sit inside inside
of each other and there's also a space w
in our output space
and
the map p now behaves nicely on these
subspaces so there's three properties
namely its sense
o1 2w
it vanishes on r2
and then there's another property
involving this differential
uh namely for every point x we want that
uh the differential at x sends o2 to w
right this might seem a bit um
random for now but
this is what you need to
to sample pre-images i'm not going to
explain in detail how it works but
basically
you use the oil and vinegar id
first to sample the image that is
correct up to a vector in w
and then you use a oil vinegar id again
with o2
to to get a pre image that is correct uh
exactly
yeah but that's not too important for us
right now
so yeah now
talk about the attacks
um so
yeah we're going to use this uh this
property that i mentioned before about
the differential
so i'll repeat so for every
vector x if you look at the differential
at x
this is a linear map that sends our o2
space which is one of our spaces in the
secret key to to w which is another
space in the
in a secret key
so yeah we have a lot of these maps
which for every x we have a linear map
that behaves uh on these two subspaces
and our goal as an attacker is to find
uh mr find o2
um
so the the way i solved this problem in
my europe paper was to reduce this to to
a min rank problem uh but actually um
there's a there's a much easier way
to to use these differentials
and that is the observation is that
these differential are much more likely
to have kernel vectors
in uh o2
so why is that you can just compute the
the average number of
nonzero kernel vectors in o2 of these
differentials and it's uh this quantity
over there so
uh size of o2 minus one over the size of
w so
why is this this there's a 2 minus 1
non-zero vectors in o2 and each of them
has a probability
of 1 over the size of w of being in the
kernel right because
it's image under the differential is
just a unifor uniformly random vector in
in w
so with probability one over the size of
w will be will be zero right and um
the the dimension of o2 and w are the
same so this this uh
average number of uh
of nonzero kernel vectors is going to be
very very close to two one
and now this is useful to us because we
want to find these vectors in o2
that
now a good way a good place to look for
them is in the kernels of these these
differentials
um
so yeah i said the average number of
those vectors is one
but they come in clusters of size q
minus one because every time you have
one kernel vectors then all the
multiples will also be in the kernel
so heuristically the the probability of
getting
a nonzero vector in this in the kernel
of the differential
is
close to 1 over q minus 1.
you can have a precise formula but it
doesn't really matter it's
close close to this
so yeah with this observation the attack
is
quite straightforward
so what we're going to do is we just
guess a random x and then we hope that
the kernel of our differential
intersects with our space o2 that we
want to
find
and then that we try to find a vector in
this intersection if it exists just by
solving uh this this system so we're
looking for an o such that d of x sub o
is equal to zero mainly it's
the o sits in the in the kernel
and secondly we want that p of o is
equal to zero
uh just because uh p vanishes on on o2
so that
that's how we um
can look for for the o2
and
yeah so this is uh nice because the
first equations that d of x is equal to
zero those are just linear equations
right so you can use those linear
equations to eliminate variables from
the from the quadratic
equations p of o is equal to zero
and this makes the system much smaller
and
easier to to solve so you can just use
existing techniques to to solve uh these
systems
and
uh yeah if you use some implementation
of the we demon excel algorithm
then it takes only three hours and a
half for each uh attempt of solving uh
these systems
and on average you need to repeat q
minus one times and q is equal to 16. so
we need to repeat 15 times which gives
an expected runtime of
53 hours or roughly one weekend if you
if you
count friday evenings that's part of the
weekend then it's this one weekend
um
so this is how you find one vector in o2
and it turns out that once you know one
vector in o2 then you can recover all
the
all the
other secret key information uh very
efficiently
um so yeah how does this work
um
now first we have this property of the
differential so for every x
we know that d of x support will be in w
so since we know already a vector in o2
this gives us many vectors in w so this
immediately gives you all of w for free
then once you know w you can just solve
for all the
all the vectors uh in o2 that map into w
uh under these these differentials and
then you just solve a linear system of
equations to find
uh a basis for for o2
so the only thing we still have to find
is a one
and the way you do that is
you take a quotient by
o2 on the left hand side and by w on the
right hand side
and actually it takes a little
exercise to prove that this quotient is
uh well defined or at least that this uh
this your map p is still well defined on
the quotient but that's uh
that's true because
if you add um some vector in o2 to your
input your output will change by some
vector in w that's exactly
this condition on the differential so
that means that our quadratic map is
still well defined from these
portions
and then what's left is exactly the an
oil and vinegar public key like this
we have some some space and some
polynomials on them there's a space on
which they vanish and we want to find
this space we're going to find
the quotient of one by o2 so we can just
use existing attacks on the oil and
vinegar scheme
and we can do this because now this is a
very small oil and vinegar uh public key
because we quotient it out by two by two
large spaces
so yeah you can just use off-the-shelf
attacks against the oil and vinegar to
to find uh a one and then you're done
right then we
know uh the entire secret key
uh okay so that's that's it so
um conclusions are rainbow is not secure
at least uh the security level one
parameters you can break in practice
um it is possible to save the scheme by
moving to to larger parameters but that
would be quite expensive like the public
key would be
4.4 times larger the secret the
signatures would be 2.5 times larger and
the scheme would be five times slower
and it doesn't really make sense to do
this because rainbow was like um a more
complicated version of oil and vinegar
that was trying to be more efficient but
now with these attacks it's you're no
longer more efficient than northern
vinegar so we should really just move
back to the oil of energy scheme which
is much more elegant and older and much
better understood
so so yeah in my view
rainbow is really dead we shouldn't
try to revive it and make it more
complicated to to save it again we
should just
move back to this very nice and elegant
oil and vinegar scheme
and try to understand that one better
so yeah that's it thank you
we have any questions
no questions
nobody wants to hear about the the
follow-up paper what breaking rainbow
takes an hour on a blackberry or
something
well as i mentioned i think we should
stop caring about rainbows so
if somebody wants to write that paper go
ahead but that's not going to be
right in that case let's thank ward
again
okay
so our our final paper of this
best paper session
is some easy instances of ideal svp and
implications on the partial van der man
knapsack problem
by uh katharine vogt tyrell khan and
alice
marie
and catherine will give the talk
yes
okay thank you for the introduction and
i'm very honored to receive this award
together with my co-authors as already
said gashon analis pelimari both from
the university of bordeaux
and so i got in inspired by my own
little teaser video that i made for the
conference and i will try to give the
context and the summary of the
contributions in form of an analogy
so using a mathematical problem
for as a hardness assumption in
cryptography is a little bit like
walking on a frozen lake and hoping that
the ice is thick enough
and using the yeah and so the shortest
vector problem is a mathematical problem
on euclidean lattices and we are pretty
much yeah we are quite confident that
the ice is quite thick here
however if you would
restrict a problem to so-called ideal
lattices then past
works have already shown that there are
the ice has places where it's not thick
but actually you have puddles
and whereas the two puddles on the left
and the bottom are very
well
signed and you know how to verify if an
instance falls into the puddle or not
the situation is a bit less clear with
the puddle on the top right
and this deals with ideas that have
additional symmetries
and so the picture of our first
contribution is that we enlarge the
puddle so we make it a little bit bigger
but i think more importantly we put a
big warning sign around the puddle so
that now you can easily verify if a
given instance falls in it or not
and so now you can walk safely on the
frozen lake again
and the second part of our paper deals
with the so-called partial volume or
knapsack problem and without telling you
know what it is
exactly you just believe me that it
defines an ideological problem and we
have to put this knapsack somewhere on
the lake
and depending on what instance you have
it might be on different places on the
lake and now comes the second part of
our like the result is that we show that
there are specific instances of the
partial vulnerable knapsack problem such
that the knapsack
exactly falls into this larger puddle
that we've shown and we not only show
this theoretically but we actually
implement the algorithm and
run
experiments on it
and so with this image in
mind
i will try to lead you through this
mathematical result so i will first
explain what exactly are those easy
instances
then i will show how we can apply this
to the partial underneath problem and
then i will conclude where i clarify a
little bit the implications of this
result for lattice-based cryptography
okay so let's introduce the main
mathematical object of
this work
and euclidean ledges so an eulenian
lattice of rank n
is usually described by a basis and then
the lattice is composed of all the
linear integer combinations of those
basis vectors so i have a little picture
in dimension two you see all the blue
dots that's the lattice
and then we associate to a letter is a
minimum which is the shortest norm of
any of its non-zero vectors and i think
here you can see in orange those four
vectors are shortest vectors
and then the mathematical problem we are
looking at is the shortest vector
problem where we ask for an
approximation factor gamma to find a
vector such that the norm is at most a
gamma factor away from the minimum
so if we have for instance this violet
circle here then we have four more
points that now are short and would
allow would be a valid solution to this
problem
but now the main contracture
upon which lattice-based cryptography is
built upon is that there's no polynomial
time algorithm that solves the shortest
vector problem um neither on classical
nor quantum
quantum computers for polynomial
approximation factors
and so in this work we are looking in at
lattices that have an additional
structure that comes from algebraic
number theory so i have to introduce a
little bit the notions so we have a
number field uh k which is of degree d
and okay it's this ring of integers
and to every number field we can
associate a canonical embedding sigma
that takes a field element and maps it
to the real
space of dimension d so um yeah
yeah and then what we can do is we take
a structure in algebraic number three as
for instance a module of rank r and then
map it via this canonical embedding
to the reals and now we end up in a
lattice of dimension
in the space of dimension d times r
where d is the field degree and r the
module rank but now this lattice
inherits the module structure and this
is what we call a modulators and then we
can do this of course that's just
notation so if the rank is one then we
call this actually a an idea and that's
why we end up in ideal lattices and then
if i say
module show this vector problem or ideal
shortest vector problem i'm just talking
about the shortest vector problem i've
introduced before restricted to module
or ideal lattices
and why are people actually looking at
this quite special variant of this
problem because it's used as a hardness
assumption for practicality space
cryptography
and so the main question that has
occupied the community in the last 10
years or so is
whether the shortest vector problem
becomes easier once you restrict it to
those special modular id lattices
and
today i'm focusing on the ideal case and
for very specific ideas
and so
what's the state of the art of
polynomial solvers for the ideal
shortest vector problem on specific
ideas so those are exactly the puddles
that i had in the picture of the
introduction
so the first two works i would like to
mention are here the karma and
co-authors paper that solves the
shortest vector problem for principal
ideals if the generate if the generator
is a gaussian
and a second work so that was the second
puddle is another work of karma encoders
that now solves it for all ideas but
only if the approximation factor is
super large so sub-exponential
and so our work is
built upon those two works that was the
third puddle and um so the first one is
due to
pan and co-authors and they show
an
efficient solver for prime ideals that
have additional symmetries i will
explain later what i mean with
symmetries where the approximation
factor is quite decent with square root
of the field degree
and then later porter and co-authors
improved upon this by now applying this
to all ideal lattices with symmetries
but now the approximation factor is much
harder to grasp
and in a particular need the prime
decomposition of the ideal and its
norm in order to calculate this and it's
not a it's not very easy
and so our work now generalize this
results in several aspects so first we
are over all number fields
and then um
the set
of our um
yeah that we cover so that is what i
meant that we enlarge the puddle is that
so if we restrict the set of the
previous work to polynomial
approximation factor then our set is
strictly larger and in particular the
partial van vulnerability problem that
we will look at later falls into
only this larger set
okay and then
approximation factors are quite decent
and
yeah and that's what i said with the
warning sign so membership in our set
can be very easily checked
and i have a little star at the all
because it's actually not all id letters
but only those
whose prime factors are not ramified but
those are all but finitely many
okay so now i will there there's a bit
of math coming now and i will try to
explain what uh what i mean with
symmetries
so we have the number field of degree d
and we look at the group of
automorphisms
and then what we define is this number
and i that is the number of all the
automorphisms that fix the ideal as a
set
so
we know that in this group there's the
identity and the identity always fixes
the ideal so we know that this number is
at least one
but this group has at most d which is
the field degree elements so we know
that this number is also at most d
and now comes this main theory from our
paper where we show that if we have an
idea
whose factors are prime factors are not
ramified then we have a classical
algorithm that solves the shortest
vector problem on this ideal
in time roughly exponential
d the field degree over ni times log
gamma where gamma is the approximation
factor
so if this ni is one so the ideal is
only fixed by the identity then we
recover an exponential time algorithm
this is what we have for general
lattices as well
but
if this ni is a fraction of d let's say
d over 2
then we recover a polynomial algorithm
as the here the ni cancels out the d
and this is exactly what i mean when i
say that i the the letters has many
symmetries
and now of course it's relevant that you
it's easy to compute this ni
once you have a description of the ideal
like basis and a description of the
group of automorphism
and i think that's the just the last
technical slide regarding the first
contribution is that now i want to like
give a little bit of an intuition why
many symmetries help to solve the
shortest vector problem more easily
so the ni number that i just gave you is
actually the size of the decomposition
group so that's just the same definition
as what i gave you
and
we can look at its fixed field what we
also call the decomposition field so ki
and then the main technical lemma in our
paper is that
if you have you're given an idea
then you can intersect it with this
fixed field the composition field and
multiply it again with the ring of
integers to recover your original idea
and intuitively what that means is that
if you have a short vector in i then it
is also
contained in this smaller set i
intersected with this fixed tree
and what this means is that the larger
your hi so the larger the number ni
so the more automorphisms fix this field
at this ideal sorry then the smaller
becomes the fixed field because that's
an inverse
relation
and then the smaller becomes this
intersection and the easier it is to
find short vectors
so we can go down to a much smaller set
and then lift it up by multiplying it
with this ring of integers so that's
really at the that's the technical uh
part of this contribution
okay then let's move on on the partial
random knapsack problem
i guess that most of you have never
heard of it so let me introduce it
and so we
stay in our algebraic
settings so we have the number field of
degree d
and now we look at some prime minister q
such that we know that the ideal
generated by this number completely
splits in prime ideals of normal q so we
have d prime ideas
and now what we do is we select a subset
omega of those d prime ideas and just
look at the
product of those prime ideas
okay and now the passion on the knapsack
problem takes
as a parameter distribution over this
ring that only samples element of sure
no short norm
and then the problem statement is that
if we sample an element from this
distribution and compute the coset e mod
this special ideal given by those
factors then the problem asks to find
and recover this e
from the support of psi so usually we
take the parameter such that there's
only unique solution
and i didn't really specify how we
choose this omega and this is also
because in the literature there are two
ways of doing it so in the original
proposal by hofstein and co-authors and
they did not specify how to choose the
omega
besides some constraint on how large it
should be
and in particular they kind of suggest
that you can fix it
and
in subsequent works by loo encoders and
another one i co-authored we actually
decided to add more entropy and to
select this omega uniformly adrenal
okay so now i promised you that this
partial monomer knapsack problem lies on
this frozen leg of the shortest vector
problem
but
um it's
actually not defining a shortest vector
problem but a related problem that is
called bounded distance decoding problem
so i have to introduce that
over ideas so we are given an ideal and
i give you what we call a target vector
and we are promised that it's this it
can be described as the sum of a vector
that lies in the letters and some offset
e
where we are promised that this offset e
is of small norm so we know that we have
a target vector that is somehow close to
my letters
and now this bounded distance decoding
problem asked to recover either the
offset or the lattice vector that is
actually equivalent
and now if we assume that our
psi distribution from the partial
venomognessic instance is delta bounded
then
having a vector that is the offset e mod
this special idea is exactly the same as
writing it like a sum of a lattice point
and an offset that is bounded by delta
so it's really like just rewriting
partial monomer knapsack gives you a
bounded distance decoding problem
and of course now the missing puzzle
piece is that you have to map this
boundary distance decoding instance to a
shortest vector instance and here will
be a bit hand waving because it's
actually very standard technique and not
so relevant for this talk and the really
only important thing is that
we map an ideal i to some related ideal
i prime and that
those have a relation in the sense that
whenever i has symmetries then i prime
has also symmetries and vice versa so
this reduction preserves symmetry
somehow
and
now we can think about how we can attack
the partial volume and knapsack problem
so
whenever we can solve the shortest
vector problem defined by this special
idea then we can solve the partial
random and lapsec problem and it all
like with all what i've said in the
first part it comes down to
when does this ideal has many symmetries
and now i will
convince you by doing it from the other
way i will actually construct specific
ideals
for like this of this shape that are
fixed by many automorphisms so we know
they have many symmetries
and i think that's the last
math equations for this talk
is that so what we do is we take the
ideal generated by q
and fix one of the prime ideas p just
call it p
and then we take the subgroup of the
group of automorphisms age
and what you need to know and i think
this is like
algebra
two or one i don't know a math course is
that the automorphisms
act transitively on those primary deal
factors so if you apply this
automotiveness on p you will end up with
one of those factors you will always
stay within the set
so of course if you take a subgroup here
then this actually defines an index set
because you're permuting
within those primary factors and so if
we define this ideal i
omega h with respect to the subgroup
then
we actually have an idea that is fixed
by this subgroup by construction
and of like for example if you take a
power of two cycle atomic of degree d
then we can have subgroups of order d
over two so this is a fraction of the
very large subgroups
and yeah
so
we so what i
yeah so we implemented this algorithm
and
run experiments on two different
scenarios so the first scenario is what
i call a worst case omega so this is
when the adversary can actually choose
the omega on their own
for in a for them adventurous way and of
course they will choose the omega such
that is fixed by many automorphisms and
in this case when we take parameter sets
from the literature we can solve partial
venom and knapsack in in a very
short amount of time
in the second scenario where the omega
is sampled uniformly at random
we cannot do this because with
very high probability this
the omega will not be fixed by any
non-trivial automorphism so there will
be no symmetries but what we can do in
the distinguishing attack is that we can
forget some of the prime ideas so forget
some of the indie indexes in the in the
set omica then actually the problem
becomes a harder problem but we can hope
for finding at least one symmetry and
this is what happens with a
non-negligible probab probability
and then in this case when we take
concrete
parameter sets then we can reduce the
128-bit security claimed in one of the
literature to
so it's quite significant
and i think that was the last slide and
i move on now to clarifying what are the
implications to ladies-based
cryptography
so the first thing you might wonder is
if it's still a wise thing to use the
ideal shortest vector problem to build
cryptography
and i think it's a
it's a
complex question but
we try to give guidelines if you wish to
do so what we suggested you should
follow
and so the first thing we suggest is
that you check if you can increase your
rank from one to two
so that means that you're actually not
relying on id lattices but on module
lattices where we have no weaknesses
nouns or no puddles in the frozen lake
and if you can't do that then we suggest
that you use uh and the distribute that
you select your ideal randomly from a
distribution where we know that this
distribution is supported by a what we
call worst case to average case
reduction that means that this
distribution gives you
a idea lattice that is as hard as
possible
if you can't do that then at least avoid
bad ideas so one class of bad ideas are
the principal ideas with a gaussian
generator as in previous work or the
ideas that we
worked on in this paper that are fixed
by non-trivial automorphisms
and in all cases you should not rely on
the hardness if the approximation factor
is too large
then of course the question is what what
are the implications of our results on
cryptography that is based on the
partial random natsec problem i haven't
really talked about it but there is a
signature scheme and an encryption
scheme and also an aggregate signature
scheme
and when we apply our
yeah so our algorithm actually leads to
quite severe key recovery and photore
attacks but only if the omega is
this specific like very specific design
choices
if the omega is random then we can also
only do those distinguishing attacks
that half the lattice dimension of the
attack and of course this can easily be
mitigated by increasing the parameters
and last but not least what are the
implications for lattice-based
cryptography in general
i already said it but i want to stress
it again those attacks are only for very
specific instances of the ideal shortest
vector problem and having many
symmetries seems a very strong
requirement and very unnatural for id
ledgers to have
and so there are no implications to the
hardness of structured problems like the
ring shortest integer solution or ring
learning with errors problem because
actually they are based on the worst
case hardness of ideal shortest vector
problem so you would yeah so they assume
the hardness of the hardest instance and
not on specific instances and even if
you would have so those reductions
actually only in one direction even if
you would have a solver even if the lake
would completely melt for ideal shortest
vector problem then we don't know how to
use this to actually solve
for instance the ring learning reverse
problem
and
even though i did not even talk about it
just to make it clear that this work has
absolutely no implications on the module
learning with errors problem which is
the underlying hardness assumption of
miscandidates like dilithium and kyber
and um
i think this concludes my talk thank you
for listening
do we have any questions
no i think everyone's hungry so let's
thank the speaker again and head to
lunch