let's try this
okay let's hope uh this works all right
so this is a program chair report i hope
everything all right great all right
let's start with the statistics thank
you for waiting um
all right so in and out uh
we got 452 submissions after a couple of
um initial withdrawals i believe it's a
record for crypto
after early reject round our goal was to
reject uh early reject roughly speaking
half of the submission some of them were
very good it's just kind of as a
practical matter that
it's unlikely they would get in so we
slightly overachieved it was good so we
got 212
papers survived the rejection round and
then they accepted exactly and even uh
100 papers
um
one paper was a hard marriage three soft
merges overall there are 96 peaking
slots which is again a record for crypto
but slightly down from last year
but i think the papers are great i hope
you enjoy the program
uh we had 71 pc submissions
19 of them got in so
slightly higher average than
general population but i think not all
trenches within kind of the expectations
that pc probably submits uh slightly
higher on average papers uh and we also
in terms of number of submissions per pc
on average we get one submission per pc
member so everything at least according
to statistical uh eye test uh sim kosher
so no corruption sum on pc um so
this is a little bit let's see this is a
laser point this is a slide there's a
lot of topics it's hard to read so tom
asked me to put some kind of joke so i'm
going to try to put the jokes so while
you read that as i'm going to single out
two areas uh foundations and theory and
applied cryptography so those are the
closes that i could find to the program
chairs you can guess which one even
though i do work in applied crypto but
i guess it's probably the closest to me
this is closest to tom so this is
submitted papers
uh distribution um so usually people try
to submit to please the chair they hope
the chairs will push the area so what
happened in our case
uh so this is a distribution according
to self-proclaimed areas over here
um so foundations in theory i did really
well
you know so you know thank you guys for
uh you know whatever you did um so tom
let's see what thom is so hit it here so
you know we've run this but uh anyway
it's uh
uh it was all done by the pc but that's
my joke um all right so this is uh tom
did this amazing
uh tom did this amazing word cloud of
what is important in today's script it's
apparently not cryptocurrency not even
blockchain but
signature schemes by far proof
zero knowledge functions uh applications
actually becoming important who would
have thought anyway
so uh
what else uh so this is like the local
heroes villains depending whether you
want to look up to people there's a lot
of accepted papers so you hate those
people i don't know
which camp you are
so from my perspective
i really care about integrity of pc so
in terms of pc no pc member got more
than two papers accepted which i think
is within kind of expectations so well
actually maybe slightly below so
uh hopefully we didn't have very corrupt
pc
so if you really want to see what will
help you to get the most papers accepted
become friends with you well
so that's uh you know
better indicators than being on our pc
um
anyway so um
a few other facts pc reviews a lot well
two program co-chairs tom and i um
we had 72 pc members we're really glad
initially we were advised to take few
members we are so glad we took 72
because yeah we got a record number of
submissions um anyway some most of the
people got a standard load so everything
is fine we decided not to do this
highest standard for pc submitted papers
every paper just got three reviews uh
just because we didn't believe there is
any kind of corruption on our system
just papers will be treated uh fairly
especially with such a huge pc is just
kind of crazy so we did a simple thing i
think it worked out well uh of course
when there are problems we required more
pc uh great thanks uh to we got a lot of
external sub reviewers of course uh they
did a fantastic job um
uh so one innovation i'll talk about
investors later we did allow pc members
to submit up to four papers i was
you know despite the
advice of the icr guide to chairs but we
felt uh some high quality reviewers
wouldn't accept our
invitation otherwise i'll talk to show
you some statistics in a second
um
so
in indeed especially for students we
felt it was very important
especially for professors and so on not
to block them
when they have papers with students
so it resulted in basic reviewing load
of 18
but what we did
i'll discuss at the end whether we i
think it's a good idea or not but we
need some kind of penalty for people who
submit more papers you really should
shouldn't submit like i don't know
papers which you don't think will get in
but paper which are really important for
students or something so you pay
basically for extra reviewing loads of
every extra paper you save you beyond
the first loose i mean
after the first one you basically have
to cover one paper you know you
basically you get three reviews done for
you so you have to do three reviews for
somebody else it's kind of even steven
um so people complained initially but
kind of worked out so
you know
some more statistics so this is an
interesting one in terms of how many pc
members submitted zero one two three and
four so two is basically the standard
before our experiments three and fours
away a few people over here but there
were 12 pc members those were actually i
don't have statistics for that but those
were very very active pc members who did
a great job so we felt like this
actually experiment paid off we did get
good pc members for us and some good
papers um without uh you know accepting
all necessarily those papers and so on
so uh they overall like the experiment
all right the words in the interest of
time are starting straight over so they
were presented here so of course uh
congratulations to bran david uh ward
katarina errell ellis um of course we
had um really a privilege an honor to
have an amazing invited speaker you
there who give a fantastic talk about
mpc journey
uh something i'll flash it briefly it
may not be have been announced but we
have uh
more than usual but we had a really
strong problem so we'll have six papers
uh invited to journal of cryptology
maybe it's even news to the authors but
so here are the papers i will not read
them
in the interest of time but
congratulations to doctors if you see
your name you will hopefully get an
invitation soon
so this is a papers invited
to journal of cryptology
but it was very hard selection we had
really great papers so i don't want to
spend the rest of this talk about sounds
innovations which
both tom and i feel passionate about
and we would like them to continue so we
tried a lot of uh probably more than
average uh on average new things is
crypto so um in terms of reviewing per
um process our main goal was that each
paper should get constructive objective
feedback
and we all had our share of complaints
about some of the previous editions
where we don't even know if
some reviews were really low quality uh
we had the three battles people didn't
you know so
you know i will not repeat those things
i wanted to you know tom and i wanted to
make sure that listen our pc will be
different we will really do
very high quality job and have high
quality reviews but in particular
including
why and how the pc has arrived at its
final except reject decisions so
contrary to kind of so people don't say
us like i don't know maybe you disagree
with us but at least you see our point
we'll tell you how we did it so some
innovations that i will briefly mention
are discussion leaders interactive
discussion with the authors and
some non-three subtle both non-trivial
changes to the review form i'll go
through those things quickly and see how
it works out so in terms of discussion
leaders we
had one discussion leader per papers uh
that that person was responsible
effectively for all aspects of the paper
because we cannot tom and i cannot be
personally responsible for 452 papers
it's just infeasible uh but we felt like
um you know you know the normal
reviewing load i think was six
discussion review load was six so i felt
like it's reasonable for pc member to be
personally responsible for six papers um
and also the job is also including
moderating this interactive discussion
that we'll talk about in a second and
one other important thing to address is
things that people should know that the
paper was read and should understand
what really happened we introduced this
important field reviewer consensus
summary in the review form it was kindle
the roster until decision but it was
filled only by the discussion leader at
the very end
basically before notifications um
us and out to basically say listen we
read your paper this is roughly speaking
what happened and for most of the papers
you got this form few people didn't feel
the forum we bugged them repeatedly we
did our best but i hope you like this
innovation and we got some positive
feedback about it
uh so it worked out overall discussion
leader quite well there were a couple of
discussion leaders unfortunately who
were not up to the task really minority
strict minority by far
so
you know
we did the best we could but
you know that's
what we did
also it was kind of pretty tricky to do
this discussion leader assignments
because of late reviews again it is the
best we
we could and overall i would say it was
a success um so i think it should
continue uh another very important thing
which was the most controversial
probably things that we did is a new
rebuttal thing so i will not go into
details but i am i think both tom also
shares this view uh the old rebata thing
was like basically a complete disaster
it like almost did more harm that helped
it uh
overwhelmed and structured reviews
different reviews emphasizing different
things you had no idea what affects you
know
except reject things you write this uh
really a lot of time on community was
wasted you get emotional you write this
like long google doc so just utter
disaster basically kind of more harm uh
and often it's like you rises three page
three bottle at the end nothing changes
the reviews exactly the same just a
disaster basically so we had to fix it
so our solution was to make it short
focused and matter so the way we did it
and it was also part of the large
interactive discussion so what we did
this uh kind of in the first stage we
our review form
there was only one field that people
could see
after the initial reviews which is the
field i'll show it in a second but this
is a field which is question
clarifications to authors where before
the reviewer to really think saying
listen this is only thing the author
will say please think what is important
what can change your mind what is really
important for the paper why do you
recommend the paper to be accepted
rejected
and there are some mandatory things that
you have to put if there is a mistake
don't say there is a mistake and then it
turns out it's not a mistake mistakes
you have to put in so the authors have
to be given a chance to respond to
mistakes weaknesses and security things
oh this is a bogwood thing it's like so
weak and then it's actually not weak
again authors have to be able to respond
actually there was a lot of work for us
during an interactive discussion later
there was some of those you know
comments by reviewers so saying oh but
this is like weak so we made sure the
authors always saw those things so
that took a lot of our time anything
objective we wanted to make sure the
authors have a chance to respond
uh logical flaws and things like that
and of course there are logical
questions oh i think i have a simpler
proof uh if you think it really affects
tribulations it's also a very
complicated thing poor that's optional
but you know gives authors to respond
sometimes you're right sometimes you're
wrong but only as i said you really have
to think typos don't put typos it's kind
of garbage right i mean it's not going
to change except reject things really
think focus to think and
overall um the so so yeah so anyway this
is like a very long thing that you don't
have to read but we gave very precise
instructions and people biologically
followed it so i i think it was hugely
successful
they think so
uh and then of course we had the usual
rebuttal round which was kind of much
more you know the initial question you
know questions were much more condensed
on the full review um and some papers
had zero rounds and people ask us oh why
didn't we get anything well those papers
at least in our opinion everything was
clear usually you know really bad papers
so the papers which are really good i
don't know maybe they didn't get much
it's just everything was clear listen
you break something on the laptop in
whatever 53 hours you know there is no
questions you know okay you're in it's
fine right so um
for most papers uh you know one round
was enough so it was it was fine it
maybe didn't result some good things
kind of got answers so whatever um for
some papers we had many more rounds so
there was one famous paper not to be
named it actually was accepted i think
it's a good paper uh but yeah there was
a lot of back and forth uh between but
we got to the proof the paper got
accepted then i think it's a good result
so we go to the truth one round
definitely wouldn't have been enough for
this paper so hopefully the right things
happen so anyway i'll take a shameless
so i think basically we took it utterly
failed system and turned into something
successful so i think i strongly
encourage future chairs including i
guess helena next year to at least
continue a variant of this um so we
really like what we did here uh other
innovations i'll go very quickly so
video abstracts hopefully you um you
know went uh on sunday to some of those
things so if you didn't know uh
a lot of actually very good uh video
upstairs i felt it's actually a good
idea for people who want to get a quick
pitch to decide which talks to attend or
maybe don't want to read the technical
thing to read the video presentation by
authors i think it worked out great
hopefully this condition will continue
so if you haven't seen this please
watch it that's pretty cool
uh
this flexible submission by pc members i
talked about it briefly
uh one thing i mentioned was really
painful to do it with the system
assigning this discussion leaders
changing them especially this wearable
thing was a disaster so it shouldn't be
repeated unless the system
um you know we can help
the reviewing system early rejection
round continuing from fifth of 2001 21
overall it kind of worked i think it was
uh the over half of the paper rejected
overall help with fact focus the
discussion remaining papers we probably
made some mistakes uh
we did the best uh we could hopefully
not too many apologize to people uh who
got maybe a little bit of rushed uh
things but instead experiment hopefully
will be refined um
next year uh so as i said it felt a
little bit rushed but anyway a few very
quick reflections before i conclude
uh things which worked well um focused
rebuttal we're huge fans interactive
discussion it's great that hot crap
supports it so um i think it was very
very helpful people like that uh
increasing pc submissions limits i i you
know we got a lot of positive feedback
uh the other thing that we did this
variable load and maybe i actually i'm
you know yeah voice should probably be
enough but
i don't see why we need to have them i
think let people just decide if they
want to be on the pc
the community is so huge there are so
many reviewers i mean i understand if
there are like 10 at the early days of
crypto you can say oh it's like
everything is a pst the program will be
corrupted it's just kind of crazy you're
not going to corrupt the program with
like 500 submissions so so i think let's
just eliminate it and not worry about
this variable review discussion load
penalty and so on so this would be our
recommendation
so hot crap i mean it's becoming more
and more popular i think all the future
shares are using it fantastic it has a
lot of cool features so uh tags tags
tags we used them
some pc members complained but then you
got on board and you saw how powerful
they are uh helped us a lot there were
other things which were great
so um for this overall we like it it had
a bunch of things but overall it's a
very powerful system so thank you tom
for
convincing me to use it uh it's great
things which could be improved very
briefly early jack said we were a little
bit rushed
partially because the schedule initially
was okay but we didn't count some of the
reviewers would be so late and we didn't
want to start it when so many people
going empty things and then so some who
things got dragged on so then we were a
little bit rushed so
something should be
adjusted and we apologize that some
people of the early jax papers uh you
know got a little bit of a short end of
the stick but uh you know we did what we
could a deeper hierarchy would
definitely work currently we had pc
chair discussion leader so
you know from 452 to one
so maybe it's a little bit of a too
shallow hierarchy so especially if the
discussion leaders were not very
receptive we felt uh overwhelmed we
tried to do literally spend like hours
writing comments and doing discussion
leader jobs asking another pc member so
maybe area shares
maybe some guidance from my cr
would also help here but anyway i'll
finish this is basically the last thing
so
hot crab support for our needs you know
could improve definitely for the final
versions we have some hiccups
but
anyway um
i'll finish with the main lesson this is
just one lesson another is here so uh 98
work is a routine administration and uh
uh but you know anyway uh
thank you evgeny
all right you guys can go ahead and get
set up
all right two super quick announcements
so we have extra swag
feel free to pick up that tomorrow if
you would like some additional
whiteboard notebooks or t-shirts or
anything
also tomorrow at 4 30 we have two new
events um the women in cryptography
networking reception which is going to
be um just on the patio below uh corwin
out outside here and the panel
discussion on allyship and inclusion so
i encourage you to attend one of those
in recognition of our best video
abstract and runner-up awards i would
like to acknowledge the runner-up which
was non-deterministic hardness versus
non-malleability
and our best video award goes to lattice
based zero knowledge proofs if you
haven't seen it go check it out this is
their computationally indistinguishable
oscar
um so if the maker of that video could
come up and see me afterwards i also
have uh thank you yup let's give them a
round of applause
um i also have ucsb sweatshirts for the
runner-up and the and the winner so
please come see me in one of the breaks
thank you
you