um
sorry on the topic of who's being left
out we're missing sound and zoom
i think they're hearing me k are you
hearing me
yes just not mike uh i think we're
hearing him very quietly
hello citizens of zoom
this is mike calling good thank you
all right so everyone on zoom just
imagine i said something incredibly
eloquent uh and uh
good just yeah simulate that in your
head as we do in this community um
[Music]
one thing i wanted to mention is um feel
free to
feel free to get up and move a little
bit closer it'd be great if this is kind
of an open discussion we have like
great experts here with uh with with
great ideas uh but uh
everyone else in the community probably
has some really good ideas too it'd be
nice if this is like an open discussion
i really have no idea how to structure
this uh but we're all like adults and uh
we want to we want to hear from you if
you have something you feel like you can
add and then that's great we have a
microphone up here and feel free to come
up at any time everyone on the panel is
okay with
being interrupted at any time within
reason
good
so
as i was saying i sort of interpreted
the call for this panel to be like who's
being
who's being kind of left out of our
community and uh either actively or
passively and hey how could we like not
do so much of that
that's kind of my understanding of what
we can talk about today
i sort of had a few goals
that maybe we can all come away with
ideas of things that we can do those of
us who are kind of interested in in
being allies and kind of don't know what
that looks like
could come up with some concrete goals
on an individual level and maybe also
discuss uh things that could be done
at the level of the community maybe have
some ideas that could percolate up
through the iacr leadership maybe who
knows
um
good i think that's what i wanted to say
i hope you'll forgive me for having
notes because i want to be
precise about my language
good
so as an icebreaker i thought we could
start off by
asking each panelist to sort of share
an example of some allyship that they've
experienced in their careers
either a positive or negative one but
maybe a positive one will maybe inspire
some
some similar actions by the audience
members maybe we can start with with
anna who we're trying to
we're trying to preserve
the amount of speaking voice you have
right right so um i have laryngitis so
yes
so um
i want to you know talk kind of from my
own perspective with somebody who has
benefited a lot from allership
what it takes for somebody to be an ally
to me so this is personal
um and so i distilled it into three
rules
number one
show up
and
i don't i'm not going to comment on you
know
you'll know what showing up means it
sounds easy but it's not especially when
there's nothing in it for you so show up
as rule number one
um
rule number two is
lead by example like model the behavior
that you think is necessary
um
don't necessarily even talk about it but
just model it
and uh rule number three is be positive
so
um i'm going to illustrate rule number
two and rule number three with
personal stories
so rule number two lead by example
um so i want to call out two allies who
have led by example in my opinion
and have proved to be allies
and uh the first example is leo raisin
and there are very many instances where
you spin an ally by leading by example
but i'm just gonna tell you about one
um so when we were in graduate school
together
uh leah became a parent for the first
time
and uh
and it was very visible
so
he he brought his son with him to
various events he talked about him he
made sure that he wasn't working you
know
like
more than a certain number of hours a
week so that he could
um give his wife some breathing room
and i didn't know at the time that that
was allyship but it really is
and this is this is a behavior where he
is an ally not to me personally
but he's an ally to gender equality
so
thanks leo i'm not sure he's watching
this on zoom but
he's the la number one that i wanted to
mention and i also wanted to mention
another ally claudio orlandi again he
was an la to me personally
but when his wife got pregnant
he missed
a workshop that i think was important to
him because he really wanted to go to it
because he wanted to be with her
and to support her through this journey
so again leading by example
and it's not like he talked about how
he's a feminist he just acted as a
feminist so that's what i mean like um
lead by example
and then in terms of be positive i'm
going to tell you
another story which i think is somewhat
negative
um so i said a b positive song okay um
so um this was a few years ago
and i work at brown and we had a
discussion with undergraduate students
about applying to graduate schools
and
there were two of us leading the
discussion was me and a faculty member
in biology
and he was he is wonderful and he was
very eager to speak and share his ideas
so in fact he was so eager that he kept
interrupting me
and i don't mind it at all i mean i also
interrupted him i didn't feel there's
anything wrong
then
a little bit after the discussion the
students complained to the
administration about how the discussion
was gendered and called him out on his
male dominant behavior
and
that i think is a negative example
because
they didn't give him the benefit of the
doubt
they got him you know
real in real trouble for nothing because
i totally didn't feel like he was
interrupting me more than i was
interrupting him
so i don't think that that behavior is
helpful
even if they you know inside maybe they
thought he's not modeling good behavior
i think
i think um
calling him out like this was not
helpful
so that's why my third rule is be
positive tell people what you like about
their behavior as opposed to what you
don't like
so that's it
thank you
oh me next okay
then i think i'll hear something
personal
hopefully positive
about seven years ago when i was in my
first year phd i encountered this one
paper that i think it's great but is
discussing a new topic for me that i
don't understand
and i was
pairing my linear pairings you know
first time you see them you split a
little bit it takes a while to
understand and i had nobody that could
guide me that so i gathered strength and
wrote to one of the authors of the paper
who is a you know well-established
cryptographer dario fiora
me and the master student that was
working with me back then
and he was just so kind within one day
or two he replied to the email with you
know this is a literature you can read
these are the answers to your questions
these are the trick in my paper that you
didn't understand
and that
helped me so much it was a knowledge i
couldn't have gotten otherwise i mean
you have everything at the finger at
your fingertips on the internet but it's
hard to find the right thing if you
don't know what to search for in the
beginning of your career
and what is very successful is that that
research paper turned out sorry that
mock statistics turned out to be a
research paper and dario fury became
also my co-adviser and his
uh my personal role model
for how he is and whenever i feel sad
about bad things do happen i think of
him and it's like okay
there are good people around and if
there is this example i can also be one
of these good people and we can slowly
turn things to the shiny side
that sounds great i think
first of all
i'm very happy to be here with everyone
i i guess we have much more people than
i expected i'm very happy to see that
so so i want to share
a positive story but also a negative one
so that we see both sides of the coin
like what is good to do and what's not
good to do so i'm from colombia south
america and typically from these
underrepresented regions if you make it
to these places
is either because of one or two things
or
a perhaps three things
so either your university or your region
had someone who went out
years ago
build a career and return and help you
or
either
someone from abroad a
somehow was involved in in your
community in your region and help you as
well
or alternatively which we also see this
happen well you had opportunities that
perhaps other didn't you could afford
to pay a phd or something similar but
that's not rare but
in my case
the community we had in our city was
relatively small and i want to share the
story of someone who
helped me
achieve my goals
trying to get a phd and something along
those lines
this person is called puja farshin and
ashland connolly as well so they too
attended uh an event
in
in colombia so they attended an event in
bogota which was a summer school a very
small summer school that i'm sure nobody
of you have heard of it it's called
cryptoceo
and for us at least for my supervisor
there like for the people involved it
was a big event it's like it took so
much logistics to put it together and
so much
effort dealing with the bureaucracy with
the different universities and systems
that are relatively outdated and hard to
deal with
and this event got put together and like
they got a series of speakers from
abroad
and and that was amazing and as an
undergrad but then it was for me very
amazing to be even i had to travel from
one city to another and i think this was
my first flight my first time on a plane
and like i'm traveling to a conference
like a small conference in just another
city like 45 minutes away
so i go to this city
and attend the event
and ask questions and i and i
like what's going on and during a coffee
break i meet with this person with pujam
and he sits down with me
he asks me what do you want to do
afterwards and i say like i don't know i
mean i don't feel confident i just have
an undergrad by the way undergrads in
columbia take five years and we have to
write almost like a thesis but like i
just have an undergrad
and
i was like
thinking very
low of myself and he was cheering me up
like no look you are asking very valid
questions you have a very good
background you should apply to this and
this and this and this and this and this
and these places and i still have the
piece of paper where he wrote all this
you can read this and this and this and
this and these books you can contact
these and this and this and these people
these are the topics that are good for
you to check out these are like he gave
me a super
a comprehensive list of things
and
that's the first time i learned that
there is a thing called icr for example
or that there's a thing called crypto or
eurocrypt racial crypto latin crypt for
the matter and many many things and then
i learned about all this i go to the icr
website jobs option and then i see that
there some of the options he listed are
there
and
well i get to apply and he helps me with
that recommendation and that essentially
i think it
helped my application go through and it
turned out to be a great experience i'm
very happy i think the phd went
successful and like it's so it's all
good and i'm very happy that this
happens and it couldn't have happened if
this person and this group of people
wouldn't have attended there and be
there for us it's a small conferences i
don't think they get any any recognition
for these type of things in the
community and it has so much value not
only because of how they helped me but
also because of the people i have
managed to help afterwards so it's like
it's a whole chain
so that was the good story
and just for the negative one
sorry maybe i should have started your
way around
so for the negative one it's actually
the same event so it was a conference
in in bogota colombia
and
it was very depressing sometimes because
you could hear some of the international
audience making very inappropriate
comments of the facilities or of the
city
or of the quality of the talks that
students were giving or things like that
and sometimes i don't even think you
don't speak english or well but like
you're next to them they're talking
literally
super bad things about the like look the
bathrooms are like oh they talk a lot
all these things
this is this is this is not good so i
think it's pretty good to understand
that not everything or not everyone are
the same
to understand
historical circumstances why things are
one way or another and like not
criticized from a point of view that
perhaps may harm
the others in a way that you perhaps you
don't even know
but it was a minor thing
but that was it yeah
thank you thank you for all of these
stories this is
yeah so i'm going to share a positive
story that that actually impacted all of
my career
and so i'm i'm from north africa and
specifically from from morocco
and
i was lucky to to go to preparatory
classes and to go to an engineering
school to move to france
um
and uh so i decided to start a phd and i
wasn't in the crypto community at all so
i was just interested in doing crypto
and
i i travel like in france like it's easy
to get funding unfortunately like so it
was so i traveled to to financial crypto
um
to i think present a poster
so i was like really outside from you
know from the crypto community
and uh
and something that really
strikes me still now is that like this
is really like maybe like some people
they don't really think about it when
they ask but the first question that
maybe like most of the senior people
they ask students is who's your advisor
and who are you who are you working with
and once they hear
a name that they don't recognize or
somebody like you know that they don't
know
like you can see clearly like that the
the the conversation is is different
but one person
actually was completely different and
he's actually in the in the room cine
camara
and um he was completely the opposite um
and
um and i remember i was presenting
something on cryptid search
and uh the amount of interest that he
showed to i mean i was just finishing my
undergrad starting my phd
and the amount of interest was just
striking just striking to me like it's
it's something that
um for a student it matters a lot like
for somebody like me like just starting
seeing somebody who's really senior in
the area like and somebody i was seeing
back in there and back then that's
somebody who who's really pioneer in the
area of encrypted search listening
to a student
uh with no publications nothing
um you know and not only that like i
remember very well because like it's
something that's really i keep very dear
to to myself and in my memories is that
like he asked me to send him my papers
to read them
and
you know like you know the the the
modesty and like for some person to to
ask you this like i mean i was like
really like in my undergrad like you
know i remember and it excites me to
start working on encrypted search and
since then like you know we started a
collaboration and and you know and he
played a significant role for example
like you know i remember in 2014 like
there was an invitation only workshop
and he was sending an email to the
organizer i don't know there is a
student like you should you should you
should invite him and you know and
they will listen to him because he's
senior so and this is how he played a
significant role at very early in my
career
to actually actually access
uh
you know a kind of very you know small
community that without these kind of
like helps it's very very hard
um yeah so yeah so thank you yeah thanks
yeah thanks everyone for sharing those
uh those personal stories um so before
the before this panel like
all of us uh on an email discussion had
like brainstormed you know many topics
to talk about um i'm afraid like i'm
really worried that we probably won't
even be able to scratch the surface we
have a lot of interesting things to
discuss
but i wanted to start off by um
by mentioning that
there have been some uh like affinity
events within our community like for
women in cryptography and previous uh i
think in previous cryptos maybe there
have been like a queer crypts meetup um
and i'm wondering if uh
if if anyone on the panel has any
reflections from things that were
learned maybe things that can be
reported back to those of us who are
like interested in in supporting these
communities um and also from anyone in
the audience who has some uh
some feedback for
for anyone who wants to be an ally to
these groups
well i guess i can take that one
and of course feedback from the audience
is welcome any kind
so um
i haven't attended that many queer uh
crypto events but uh after eurogrip this
year uh i was there with chris pruska
and we were like okay there is nothing
for you know queer crypt and so just
sitting on the sofa we was like okay why
don't we organize something how hard can
it be and it took us 15 minutes to drop
some nice flyers and find a way to print
them and then hang them in the bathrooms
because we thought that was the way you
could be more private if you don't want
other people to know about these things
of yours and it turned out to be a great
success
we had a dozen people showing up most of
them young and you know new people in
the community
and
after the first five minutes of
introducing names you know who you are
what are you studying where you come
from
it was exactly the same kind of
discussion as you have out there
everybody was talking about crypto
and say oh you should read this paper oh
but do you know about that result so i
think it's just great and it's how same
the same way as somebody can connect
with people from their own university or
people from the same nationalities or
people that speak the same language as
you that's just a different kind of
community and having it it makes you
feel you belong to yet another bubble
which is so good when you feel isolated
and alone or maybe somebody pulls your
leg and then it's like okay you know i
have a lies i have somebody that just
shares something with me even if you
know we just talk about crypto
so that was a very great experience and
i think the lesson to learn here is
lead by example you want something to
happen make it happen it's not that hard
i understand it is hard to do alone but
just find a body and then in two people
you can go a long shot with your 15
minutes work
and change somebody's life because they
got a new body that they can do research
with they wouldn't have met otherwise
and this can be done for queer crypt but
can be done for many other initiatives
not just at conferences but also within
your own institution
great thanks
you're also loud club
if you want to
just scanning the audience in case
anyone
wants to join in don't be shy we're all
friendly
there is a microphone
i hope this is
not a too problematic question but i
remember our discussion with some of my
colleagues one year ago when we were
talking about this kind of event for
queer people or for women or for
minorities
things like that
and thank you
and um
i remember one of the comments of my
colleagues that said oh but it's
something that's made for for example
minorities so
uh you know
it's not uh it's i mean the papers that
are uh chosen are not legit enough
because of that which is a garbage
comment i agree but
how can we avoid this kind of stuff for
this kind of event in your opinion
because i that's a criticism that's
um that
comes and comes again a lot i think
okay so do you understand correctly what
you're saying is like people that don't
belong to this description feel like
okay i cannot attend this event
no then i don't hear there's this
problem but also the results of these
events are discarded because they are
kind of reserved
uh often as reserved to
uh queer or women or minorities and
[Music]
i mean
i i have heard some criticism because of
that so i was wondering if you had ideas
to solve this problem
okay so like
the way we did like we also had some
people that say i don't belong to this
bubble but i'm supportive and then we're
open to that so then you know you don't
only have
people that could feel labeled by
something but in general i think it's
just a stigma that it's not there and
somebody brings it up it's like okay
then you're part of another bubble like
it's not that you know this is the green
eyes people like uh it's i think like
just don't discriminate others
when you create something and people
that say oh but this is only uneven for
that it's just bad because only like no
but i can understand in some cultures
and in some country it's hard to maybe
come out as gay and you don't want to
people to know that you don't want
people to label like that or to you know
point a finger but
i hope the iacr community can do better
than that
so that this could be a safe place where
you can belong to whatever sub community
you feel you do belong
to but i can also take long discussions
afterwards
uh thanks for that question um i wanted
to talk a little bit about icr
conferences kind of in general um
since 2018 as far as i could tell we've
had a code of conduct at the icr
conferences
and i'm kind of curious to know
whether that has changed anything has it
been successful has it accomplished
anything is it just a security theater
or conduct theater
is there anything that that should be
revisited
from the code of conduct
any
if there's any comments on that
i mean in in general i think i i don't
have a lot of experience on the ircr
conference in general but like
fortunately i think the community has
been very supportive and i personally in
the
sort of group i belong to never been
criticized for this um
but
i think this is just because the the
group for instance i belong to
i think
people in general agree that that that
something should be done right like
people in general like like like oh
interesting to know that you're going
through this
and
we didn't know and we want to support
you and like this is in general the
feeling i've get
but i'm aware that that's not the case
with all
communities and all the
particular groups that we have in our
community like there are problems
that perhaps the community is more a
reaction likely less less willing to
accept that there is a problem in
certain settings
i fortunately have never been a well a
victim of that so to speak but i wanted
to hear i would like to hear if someone
else maybe has
good time good time to mention
that um the the icr has um
indeed has the code of conduct policy
and um
i mean i think it's a little bit of an
on account it's just like this is what
we expect the kind of behavior we expect
um enforcing it of course is another
question because we don't go and police
the attendees we don't really know what
people are doing
so this is more like you know but laying
out the expectations of behavior
is better than doing nothing so that's
that's kind of a baseline
um and then we also have the iacr
ethics committee which is a
form which was appointed by the ico
board of directors
and i'm actually serving on the ethics
committee
um and when
when there's an ethical issue that
our members feel requires um
some kind of a grown-up intervention um
sometimes we we hear from members of the
community about these issues
um
the majority of issues actually uh
issues of academic
ethics
you know
plagiarism
things like that
a small number of them
may be regarding the code of conduct
so we haven't fielded a whole lot of
complaints about
about
icr members
behaving inappropriately which i think
is a reflection of the fact that this is
actually a very healthy community
with responsible adults um so we're
lucky
i hope that answers your question
yeah that's fine yeah michelle go ahead
so uh actually right now the code
right now the code of conduct uh one of
the issues that we have is that it tends
to be associated just with the
conference
and uh
for instance in problems can happen
outside conferences in our field and i
think we need to address that that's
actually one of the points that tao
rabbin is actually
we have to work on because i think we
have to make this more
wide within the i mean like it has to be
something central to the acr so that
people have us a way to contact us
even outside when the problem doesn't
happen within a conference but i think
it's a problem that
unfortunately does happen i personally
don't know
the cases like these are
some of this information is private so
but uh
it has happened and problems with uh
within
a conference
of harassment and things like that so
we would like to think that it's not
something that would happen but it
unfortunately does
i think
i should also i should also mention that
dal is a hero for taking this on because
it's a it's this isn't something she
does she's not on the ethics committee
she's more kind of an ombuds person that
people can come to
if they have issues and they don't know
what to do and she did you know and then
they
sometimes they bring the issues to us in
the ethics committee and sometimes tal
just gives them good advice and
that suffices so i think we should all
you know thank her for doing this very
big very and pretty thankless task
and thank you michelle for sharing and i
think like maybe we don't need to know
the specific of what happened and who
was involved but it's nice to have some
sort of statistics so that we're
actually more aware of these things
i never experienced anything myself
within this community i experienced a
lot in workplaces or around the world
went on visit for research studies but
never at the conference but so it's like
i always perceive this as a very open
and welcoming community from that
perspective of you know physical safety
uh
but it's good to know that you know
there are counter examples
um yeah i generally agree that we are
healthy community but
i think within the last weeks and
especially in the post quantum area we
have seen within the last weeks a couple
of things that i think or a couple of
examples of behavior and communication
that
shouldn't probably take place and i
think it's great that we discuss this
today but maybe
like discussing the way we are
communicating independent of having
policies and all these things like this
is a great event here for uh inclusion
and all these things um but i think like
maybe communication is more basic and
also maybe we should at some point
discuss this and uh how we want to like
like be behave based on that or how we
want to change such behavior all both on
the internet maybe like on twitter for
example
where we have seen these things very
recently and i don't know i think
this is
although in general we are a healthy
community i think this is not very
healthy
yeah agreed i'm not on twitter so i
don't read all of that but i heard the
rumors despite not being on twitter
yeah
thanks for that remark um i i had a
chance to talk to someone uh earlier
this week who is a former general chair
of the
of an iacr conference and asked them
about the the code of conduct and and
they reported that
um
it was actually helpful to have a code
of conduct when you had to have that
discussion with someone who needed to be
uh kept in check
like
you know i it's it's not just the
general chair being a capricious uh
arbitrary person but we have a code of
conduct and if you don't shape up we're
gonna kick you out of the conference uh
that conversation was made much easier
by the code of conduct so that's uh
maybe one data point in in favor of the
code of product as well
so on the on the topic of general chairs
uh as we're still talking about uh iacr
conferences is there any
any message you would want to give to
future general chairs who are organizing
events like there's something that you
wish
that someone would be brave enough to
try
or something you think they should they
could do
to make this a a more inclusive event
i can i can say a couple of ideas that i
think
would be really helpful for at least
some some countries and this brings me
to the topic of uh
of
of the timing
of the of the crypto conference so if
you notice like for example the
acceptance date it's around april may
kind of like you know these these months
and then the conference is in august
so
so for some authors who are from
different locations who require visa
three months is not enough
three months isn't if even if you up you
submit the paper and of course like you
know there is a possibility
of presenting your paper in a
in a remote way but there is nothing
that replaces in person right
so
so given three months is just like um
it's almost impossible it's just like
saying like you know if you are from
this country and this country you will
never come um and this is something that
if it would be possible to replace and
to think about for example if just
having like more
time between the acceptance date and
also the the event that would be really
really helpful uh usually
from what i have heard from france from
north africa
for example as a data point
it's around six months
uh to get an appointment
and usually like a week or two to get
the visa so let's say six months so six
months is the average uh so
uh and it doesn't really depend whether
you are you have money in your account
it doesn't depend it's really like it's
a process that everybody needs to grow
to go through so
um yeah so this is the the the one maybe
suggestion too hot to at least you think
about you so yeah
yeah i think i think that definitely
makes sense and it's also important to
take into account that after copies
these six months in several places have
became like they become like three years
two years one year like it really
depends on the on the console the
drivers you're applying from
and i think so so there are there's a
big question our big debate about what
can we do as a community and i think
i don't think there's a simple and um
like single simple answer that you can
give to that i think it's something that
we have to build together all of us
those who are affected by it and those
who are not affected by it
uh but i do want to mention i mean it's
hard to be
concrete right about like we can do this
we can do that we can do this but i
think the first step towards solving
this issue it's a systematic issue and
it's also not an issue that i mean we
are just simple
uh walking citizens like this is a
governmental like this is a systematic
thing that we cannot solve but something
we can do at least
just be aware of it
so
regarding something concrete how can you
be aware of it well being in this panel
like it's a great way of doing that but
also towards the next a an upcoming
is student communities in the different
conferences a good concrete idea
that you can apply is for instance
opening and closing remarks you can
thank explicitly the people who went
through the art was expensive and and
exhausting process of getting a visa and
managed to be at the conference and also
acknowledge those who perhaps couldn't
do it so that we just know oh there is a
list of people who wanted to be here and
they just couldn't be here like couldn't
it's not a matter of like oh they didn't
do things in time or yeah they they just
didn't
whatever like they just didn't get a
paper accepted and their institution
doesn't allow them to travel if they
didn't get access to a paper it's not
about that it's really like it's it's is
impossible so so i think this is
something concrete that could be done to
raise awareness
and small steps like this could take us
to our to a more healthy community where
we understand someone came here
from india or from certain regions in
africa or from south america wow you did
so much to be here it's so nice that you
can be here i'm grateful that you're
here so i think that's something we
could do just as a start
if
if it's okay i
would like to chime in
um so i i think
part of what i see um with hybrid
conferences is that there is a way for
people to attend and i i understand and
hear the comments about how it's not a
substitute or it's not a one-to-one
equality with
attending in person and i agree
and
i think that for some folks um it has
been difficult to travel for whatever
reason for covid for children for
caregiving for visa problems you know so
to
urge
future general chairs of conferences to
please have hybrid and i know this
sounds self-serving because i run the
hybrid conferences i don't mean it like
that i mean it in the sense of if iacr
is an international organization then
people from everywhere should be able to
attend so i would just really urge
future general chairs to consider the
hybrid option
that's all
thanks thanks k
mike
mike can i just add something very brief
to to what k just mentioned i think i
just yesterday hear the story also in a
conference it was not an icr conference
but
it was a hybrid event and there was this
person who has a
these two persons they have two papers
and they agree that one of them will
present one paper and the other will
present the other paper
one of them couldn't go because of visa
and the conference
chairs mentioned oh i mean that's fine
your other
colleague can present both papers
and like i mean i need my face to be
seen right this is important for my
career but no we prioritize in person
talks
i know there is a psychological factor
to it you're sitting here and you're
either looking at the screen and there's
no one to interact with or there is
someone standing there looking at their
face it may or may not matter but i
think for this person not to present it
really does matter so when we say when
we say let's have hybrid conferences and
only let's have them but it's actually
be completely okay with person with
people who cannot attend i think there
has been certain pressure in not
accepting
online talks or like at least
oh can you do something maybe someone
else can present for you or like one of
the six authors and at least one of them
is there then why not let the author
who's there i think it's important we
also are
accepting with this
um so
so not just on the on the side of
organizing uh the conferences but just
in general within our community uh to
talk a little bit about like a culture
of international respect so
within our community these are not not
maybe i see our
official events but we have like
regional events like the ones that come
to my mind are like latin crypt indoct
africa crypt um and i'm probably missing
a few i apologize um
the it seems like these events uh
sometimes have kind of less stature than
than they deserve like when you compare
them against like similarly uh ranked
conferences and so i'm wondering um is
there something we can do within our
community to sort of uh fix that and and
you know improve the
the culture of respect
well i think it does i can start and um
i think that uh you know
hopefully in the future like
i'm i'm being optimistic that africa
creates latin crypt and in the crypt
will will reach at some point
the level of uh let's say a flagship you
know
crypto conference
but i would say that there is
something that icr can do a little bit
to improve
um
like given the importance to these
conferences like for example i would say
for uh for africa crypts i know that
iscr has some relationship to africa
maybe it's an affiliated event or
something like that i am not
the um uh the exact you know um uh
affiliation but
uh one thing that it would be really
helpful is that to have
for example um
summer schools that are affiliated to
that conference for example africa
crypts
yes i understand that many students they
would prefer submitting to a flagship
because this helped their career and you
know i this is completely understandable
this is something that i do as well and
you know this is just the system where
we live in but if for example icr allows
for
or adds summer schools where they they
they encourage really prominent
cryptographers to give talks and you
know for example for them just hey you
know there is a summer school on npc
summer school on encrypted search or
summer school
on any topic and they will invite many
researchers to go there physically in
person so it has a lot of advantages uh
first of all the student of that region
or that country can fly or can just go
there to meet in person with with really
researchers they just hear or just see
in videos but also it will serve as an
education because like really like many
of the countries like i'm speaking at
least from north africa is that we don't
really need i mean yes conferences they
are great but what really we need there
is really um tutorials schools to help
like really the student there to to
interact with researchers to learn about
a topic and as
daniel said
you know he was lucky to find this
person who told him exactly what to do
this something like it will take maybe
an hour for if you are senior but you
know if you don't have that help it will
take years and maybe if you do it wrong
you are all all set for your career so
sometimes like you know these small
helps like when you just have a
one-on-one chat with a senior person
it's really helpful so so definitely i
think that if icr can invest a little
bit into adding really
good summer schools like that which
would be really helpful for this
conference and hopefully in the long
term it will help
you know maybe paper people will start
submitting to these conferences because
they know researchers are there and you
know it will help you know bring in this
conference a little bit
yeah i can encourage uh you from my
personal experience i can encourage uh
attendance at some of these conferences
um i only have personal experience with
the indo crypt but attending indocrypt
was probably the most successful
recruitment activity i ever did
in terms of recruiting grad students so
i was invited to give a tutorial there
and one thing i didn't realize was that
students from all over the country
anyone who's interested in crypto
comes to indocrypt uh anyway everyone
who can at least and so
there are students from all over the
country uh attending the tutorials at
indocrypt and as a result of that trip
um i saw the
i saw lots of
you know i'm not used to seeing students
who necessarily know about crypto
applying to my university uh in the main
pool and then all of a sudden there were
like students who knew about
cryptography and knew about garbled
circuits in the uh
in the pool and as a result i uh i got
one of the students to come and uh she
has a paper here at crypto this year it
was a great success so um i know maybe a
selfish motivation but uh i definitely
encourage my colleagues to
think about
attending some of these
more regional conferences
i just wanted to add something as a you
know in my capacity as a member of the
board of directors
um you know if you want to lead by
example you don't have to wait for the
icr to come and organize a summer school
where you feel one is needed in fact um
you can organize it yourself and and uh
ask the icr do
to help fund it we have a schools
committee we accept proposals for for
icr schools in various subjects and
areas
and when considering these proposals we
definitely value geographic
diversity so we like seeing proposals
that are from
on from
from areas
where it's currently difficult for
researchers to attend our flagship
conferences
maybe i can chime on giving the latin
crypt version of it so i attended the
laticrim latin crypt in person only
during my phd a couple of times and it
was a lovely conference so i don't
understand these comments it's like so
great
like
first of all of course what we can do as
a community is some make your papers
there
second you go to very nice places you
have amazing people that are super
hospital and you know what the wi-fi is
usually iffy but this means you actually
talk with people
and there aren't that many people so i
had you know a one-to-one chat with the
shamira for 10 minutes in cuba
who else gets that chance
so it can give you different things that
you don't get at such a large conference
where i won't have the time to actually
talk to everyone and to know things
about every one of you
right yeah so um
just to to to compliment them what about
the icr conferences and so on i think
there is an important i want to share a
quick story so when i was a
during my undergrad it was a reading
papers and then you see papers published
everywhere and you like crypto eurocrypt
asia crypt africa crypt blood encrypt
into crypt and name it crypt all of it
means the same for for you it's like i i
don't really have any ranking on any of
this
and it was very exciting i was like oh
wow we have geographical location i mean
it's like
it's like you have the world cup and
like everyone goes to the world cup and
and latin america is equally important
as african-american asia it's like like
all these regions matter and like you're
all the same they're like use the local
original cops or or whatever
it came as a surprise that started
progressing that like like people will
tell me
yeah
oh there is something called login creep
oh i didn't know but this isn't cool
africa there you know i like there are
many more that i don't even know
so so i think
the first thing that could happen that
could could be done is that like making
these conferences be better is an effort
that is an effort that we also have to
be engaged with it's a matter of
stop joking about this paper is so bad
that they won't even accept it at africa
crypt because i have heard this
personally so stop joking about this
that's the first step and then from that
we can jump to saying this paper you
know what is good we it deserves being
there and i think
we've seen recent conferences that
are born
because
enough people with enough credentials
if i'd say you know what this looks good
let's create a conference let's all give
value to it like bitcoin you know like
oh let's let's give value to it and then
it has value
so so there is one thing obvious they
just reaching consensus that this should
be a thing
uh but second it
take the string committees from this
conference and so on it's a joint effort
they should also limit the amount of
papers to raise the bar of course it's
gonna be like a free
ride like there should be a marriage to
become like a much of a better
recognized conference it should be a
joint effort from the community and also
from the syrian communities and just
along those lines i also want to mention
that um well as i said i thought there
was a geographical association to them
and so on
but but it's clearly political like like
why is africa trip less quality than
eurocrypt
someone please come and tell me that's a
coincidence because that's not so i want
to
just again this is this is where
everyone can dream but like what about
removing geographical tags to
conferences
like it could be a thing like what have
eurocrypt and crypto
which is essentially use crypto or asia
crypt why not just have different
conferences that jump from one place to
the other every year and if i cannot
make one i can always make the other i
know these statements are very bold and
like hard to make and so on but it's
good just to let it go to the air
because it's good to be aware of these
of these things i think what if you
could pick where to present according to
you know maybe you cannot travel far
away or maybe dates that collide with
some personal things and then you can
present to another conference
once it's accepted yeah so so i i think
i think i think what to do on how to
solve it is a big deal that we could we
can solve this right now but like i know
daniel shooty for example before just
gave a very interesting suggestion like
why not having a single i mean again
this is just like oh why not of course
we're not gonna do this but like we're
not having just a single event with all
the flagships into it and there are like
different issues so to speak uh they're
gonna take part in different places
you're playing you submit to one you can
accept it to this very single conference
but like okay you get to publish in the
one that happens this time in chile and
you get to publish in the one that
happens in indonesia and it's all the
same conference we all got accepted to
crypto or to the icr
conference suit or whatever we want to
call it but like just a single thing
anyway i don't think this is gonna
happen anytime soon but i think just
brainstorming about this is healthy just
talking about it i think is healthy
yeah we have seen the community is
growing the number of paper is growing
we need a new model anyway
yeah this all sounds like a really uh
informative uh productive feedback for
the the discussions that are going along
in the
in the iacr board about the
revamping rethinking the publication so
i would just encourage
the people on the on the panel here who
have uh strong opinions and big ideas to
participate in the and people in the
audience as well to participate in the
the discussions on the icr chat uh
chat.iacr.org there's a discussion for
um
publications if i'm not mistaken
we are we are
nearing the end um i have like 10
million other things we could talk about
um but i wanted to make sure if anyone
in the audience has like some
something burning thing that they would
like to contribute please go ahead
yeah um so it hasn't really been said so
i want to say it explicitly i really
think it's amazing that this is
happening now this this panel thank you
very much
thank you for being here
um
and i just want to stress that
leading by example and visibility are
two very important things and
you know i'm i'm not a woman but the
fact that there is now a meetup for
women in cryptology that shows also hey
we as a community care about this that's
where the event is here
uh the same applies to you know queer
crypt which kind of was a rogue thing at
europe but the fact that this exists and
that that is there
i mean even if you're queer and you
don't end up going to it or if you're
not queer and you and you don't
necessarily are in the target target
audience it still shows like
this is a community that cares about it
this is what the values are
uh that there are pronoun stickers by
the way i think is really cool as well
at this conference
i mean for many people this might not be
something that they personally need by
but by them being available and by many
people using that you show okay people
that are you know in a in a gender
minority you are accepted as well we
facilitate you being here and we we love
that you're here
um so i really want to to encourage
everyone in our community to keep
showing that that you care and keep
making things visible and
uh often it's like the small gestures
that really help a lot uh and the and
the big gestures like this event are
help even more so i really hope that
this is not a one one of thing uh these
examples that i now mentioned that they
keep
continuing and everyone i think in in
this community can help doing those
things and keeping that vibe going and i
really hope we can make that happen
thank you
hi
i just want to make a small comment i
unfortunately was not able to see the
majority of this panel i just came for
the last few minutes because i was at
the women's event
i think that's really unfortunate and i
just wanted to bring up that
these events are really important like
really really important and i think that
it would be great to recognize that
there are inter intersecting issues that
are impacting um people in more than one
way so i'm a woman i'm i'm queer
um i you know i'm jewish like there's
identity aspects that we all have that
we all bring to the table and they're
all different and they're all like
coming together um so i think that
uh
i would have liked to be here for this
panel and hear your thoughts on all of
this so maybe next year we can do
something more intersectional
and forever
to come together and be together in this
space
sorry i just want to point out that this
is recorded so you can watch it later
so
out of respect for everyone's time it it
seems like it's about time to wrap up
we've scheduled an hour for this event
and it occurs to me that we have lots of
brainstorming uh just questions for
discussions that we should probably save
for the next iteration of this event i
look forward to uh
being an audience member in in the next
version of this panel um
so thank you everyone for coming um and
and showing your support for this kind
of event and it's nice to hear uh uh
that you're supportive of these kind of
things i want to uh thank again uh
allison of course for organizing and of
course the the panelists for
participating and thank you all for
coming uh and we'll see you and continue
the discussion at the beach barbecue
thanks