and the rump session
to follow we're going to start this
evening
with
a memorial for nishant kumar we'd like
to thank visa research for making a
donation in his honor to support student
attendance at the conference and we're
going to be giving some some remarks in
his memory
uh this was a this was a remark uh from
nishant chadron at microsoft
nashant kumar was an amazing person
he was a very creative upcoming
superstar
being one of the first research fellows
on the easy pc team he wrote outstanding
papers with us co-authoring both crypt
flow papers
nishant had really rare technical skills
spanning across theoretical cryptography
as well as systems he had a deeper
connection with microsoft too having
spent two years in the azure backup team
before joining us
he had a real strong drive for research
which led him to give up that position
and then join us
he had this childlike enthusiasm to
learn everything he could
but above all nishant was a really warm
affectionate person with an endearing
smile
and anyone who interacted with him will
vouch for that
he was extremely caring and considerate
i fondly recall my everyday
conversations with him on research
careers life and life in india
he wanted to return to india soon after
his phd
and along with a
fellow mayank he truly made the lab and
team atmosphere exciting and lively his
passing leaves a large void in the
cryptography community
the msr family and me personally too so
we'd like to
thank nishant for submitting those
remarks
and we also are going to have some live
remarks by uh both schweda agarwal and
nishant's advisor so we'll start
with swedish
can you put the slides in presentation
view
hello everyone thanks alison
uh i'd like to talk a little bit about
nishant uh his uh sorry one second let's
make sure we're um i'm not projecting
this correctly on the screen in the room
okay
sorry go ahead
yeah hi hi everyone uh i was nishant's
undergraduate advisor can everybody hear
me fine
kevin
yes
yes we can hear you in the room as well
okay
so uh i was nishan's undergraduate
advisor and uh i'm grateful to have the
opportunity to share his memory with you
all for some time
nishant was the kind of student that
every advisor wants to have as was also
read out just now he was
very very honest very highly motivated
full of curiosity always brimming with
life i mean he he was full of questions
he wanted to talk about everything and
obviously he was very good at science he
was doing extremely well uh in research
all of us know that
what i'd also like to add is that uh you
know besides these wonderful qualities
of a student and a researcher he was
also
a wonderful
person a wonderful relationship uh
to have so
for instance he did not uh
just interact with me as as a student it
was not just you know that he would he
was showing up to to meetings and he was
doing everything he was asked to and so
on but
over and above that he he made the
relationship really warm and personal he
would
you know stay in touch uh
even aft after he
stopped being my student
he would write me these long emails you
know full of details about what was
going on and often uh asked ask me what
i thought about various things he was
very appreciative of the role that
people
played in his life and
he was really
warm and uh
he made he made the relationship so
almost like a younger brother you know
so it was really something very special
and uh
it's it was it was the kind of uh
relationship that you know you you
you treasure and you hope for as an
advisor so i know that there are many
people who want to say things so i won't
uh
hold hold up too much but
his passing was
much more than you know just
the passing of i mean a student is like
a younger sibling and it was really
heartbreaking
but uh
wherever you are now nishant my
friendship and affection are always with
you thank you
was my phd student at uiuc
he was there for about
two years a little less than two years
he was he was my protege he was so hard
working so sincere
so curious
so passionate about cryptography and he
was ready to take on the world
and as nishant and shweta have already
said he was he was an amazing a dream
student
to have and also just a really great
friend and person to have around and he
livened up the atmosphere all around
and um
we really miss him um he passed away in
a tragic accident on april 10 earlier
this year
and i
want to say two things about him that i
still think about all the time
one of nishan's beautiful qualities um
that set him apart was how open and
trusting and genuine he was
um all the time
he would often tell us about his family
back in india and how much they meant to
him
he would think about every little
detail very very carefully and this is a
great skill to have of course as a
graduate student especially helpful when
you're writing proofs
but he would also think about and want
to talk about every decision in in a lot
of detail and as a result i would end up
talking to him
about research
other decisions and just generally about
things um
you know many times every single day so
you would be pinging me and it was it
was really nice to have
um someone that was so
so honest so warm um
around all the time and wanting to talk
and
um
and yeah and he was so authentic and so
honest it was very hard not to think of
him as family
and um you know sweater also already
said it it's and it's not just me
um but also other students at uiuc
including amit ruta and sora who are all
here and james who couldn't be here
you know we all thought of him as family
and we're really devastated at having
lost him
um
and we still miss him all the time
academically nishant was one of the best
students you can imagine having
both in your classroom and as a phd
advisor
he loved long deep technical
conversations he was happy to keep
talking for
any number of hours on end and nothing
was no number of discussions were ever
too much for him
and
i remember especially after in-person
meetings which became rare because of
kovid um he would often have a visible
smile on his face telling me that hey
dakshita this was fun we should try to
do this more often and you know i wish
that
it had
he and i had been able to meet more in
person i wish he could have been here
today meeting some of you attending
crypto
um talking with some of you here um
but um
his memory will live on and we'll
continue to
keep thinking of
of him and how
how great an influence he was
on all of us
in the short time that he spent with us
thank you