and our first talk of the session will
be time space trade-offs for sponge
hashing
attacks and limitations for short
collisions and the talk will be given by
ashu ji goshal
hi everyone
this is joint work with cody freytag and
ilan komargotsky
very broadly this work is about a new
pre-processing attacks and limitations
for
finding short collisions in the sponge
construction
hash functions are one of the most
fundamental primitives of photography
that have many different applications
and certain applications like password
hashing etc require a hash function to
handle different input limits and it is
infeasible for us to design a different
hash function for every
input length
therefore we use iterative hashing as a
mechanism to design a variable input
length hash function from an underlying
fixed input length primitive and the
most commonly used iterative hashing
mechanism is the merkle dam guard design
where the fixed input and primitive is a
compression function that takes as input
two embeds and
outputs n bits and hashes a message by
breaking it into blocks and repeatedly
applying this compression function
uh this is used in
constructions like md5 sha-1 and sha-2
after some attacks on
md5 and 0 in 2006 nist started a
competition to standardize a new hash
function
and after almost a decade uh the family
of hash functions sketch act emerged as
the winner
ketchup is based on a new iterative
hashing mechanism
which is called the sponge construction
uh which is a noble alternative to the
merkle dam guard design
uh the one main major point of
difference for the spawn construction is
the fundamental underlying primitive
here is a permutation instead of a
function
very briefly this is how
the sponge construction works
it is parameterized by the bit rate r
and the capacity c and the underlying
primitive is a permutation on r plus c
bits the hash of a message m is defined
with respect to a hash key or
initialization vector iv
as follows
the message is first padded
appropriately and then broken up into
blocks which are bits long an initial
state consisting of our zeros followed
by iv is defined
uh the first message block is exhort to
the state and the permutation evaluated
on it to compute the next state
then the second message block is exhort
to the the state and the permutation
evaluated again and this is done till
all the message blocks are consumed
uh this is known as the absorption phase
of the sponge
this is followed by the squeezing phase
where the permutation is repeatedly
applied to the states and the first r
bits extracted out as the hash outputs
until there are sufficient number of
bits
for the purpose of this talk i'll
consider a simplified version of sponge
where we just have r bits output because
we are interested in studying in any
studying uh any compressing sponge hash
construction
one of the fundamental properties that
any hash function needs to satisfy is
collision resistance which entails that
given a random iv
it must be hard to find two distinct
messages
that hash to the same output
pictorially this is how a collision
looks like the shaded part denotes the
colliding hash output
we are interested in
studying the hardness of finding
collisions for the sponge construction
and the most common approach to do this
is to model the underlying permutation
pi as a random one
ah when doing so one can show that there
is an attack which requires a minimum of
uh two power r by two and two power c by
two queries uh to find collisions
uh the uh attack with two power r by two
queries is essentially a birthday style
attack where you keep evaluating the
permutation with different
miv until two of the evaluations produce
outputs which match in the first orbits
uh the attack with two parts c by two
queries uh instead finds two evaluations
where the outputs match in the last c
bits this can then be turned into a
sponge collision by appropriately
choosing the second message blocks
one can show that this attack but the
style attack is indeed optimal in the
setting and the proof is via showing
indifferentiability of the sponge
construction to a random oracle with our
output bits uh up to two power c by two
queries for the permutation
however typically uh in the real world
this permutation pi is a public one and
an adversary might be able to do better
by doing a lot of pre-processing on the
permutation
uh and in in this setting this birthday
style attack is no longer optimal uh in
particular the indifferential
differentiability framework no longer
applies
uh the setting of pre-processing
adversaries has
been studied
previously in many earlier works for
example in the context of functioning
version collision resistance etc and in
particular captures the setting of
non-uniform attacks for example
attacks using rainbow tables
and so on
uh the auxiliary input random
permutation model was introduced by
quality at all
that captures the power of
pre-processing adversaries against
random permutations
the uh
pollution resistance of sponge is
formalized in this model as follows
and adversary is
modeled as a two-phase one uh its
pre-processing phase has
full access to the permutation and it
can compute any arbitrary s bits of
advice which is passed on to its online
phase
which additionally gets its input a
randomly sampled iv
it can make at most
total of t queries to the permutation in
its inverse
and it wins if it can output two
distinct messages that hash to the same
output
this such adversity a is referred to as
an st adversary uh we parameterize the
advantage in terms of snt
and define it to be the maximum
probability of any st adversary
in winning this game
uh we note that in allowing the
pre-processing phase to compute any
arbitrary as bits of pre-processing uh
we give it a lot of power
this means that any limitations that we
prove in this model are extremely strong
guarantees
quality at all gave a tight
characterization of this sd advantage
for pollution resistance of sponge that
is they proved an upper bound of st
square over 2 part c plus t square over
2 power r
and gave an attack that achieves a
disadvantage
however uh the attack that they gave
finds collisions of length roughly equal
to t
uh and for usual values these
these are very long collisions uh of
no real practical use
on the other hand
it seems that shorter collisions are
somehow harder to find
therefore we ask the question uh can we
characterize the hardness of finding b
block collisions for the sponge
construction
uh this question has been recently
studied in a series of work uh for the
case of mercury dam guard and the key
take away from those works uh is that
there is a quantitative jump in hardness
with the value of b in particular
collisions become easier to find as b
grows i refer you to the next talk in
the session for more details for the
case of mercury number
in this work we give new attacks and
proof limitations for b block sponge
collisions
very briefly these are our results uh we
give a new attack for finding one block
collisions and this attack in particular
uses a helmet's func
helmet's random function inversion as a
subroutine we give a different attack
for other values of b uh which is this
attack is inspired by rainbow tables
we prove limitations for values of b
equals one and two using two different
techniques
uh one thing i would like to highlight
here is uh the ability of the adversary
to make inverse query to the permutation
actually helps us give this new attack
for finding one block collisions but at
the same time makes proving limitations
significantly harder than for merkel
dengard
also the
bounds that we have for the the best
attacks and the
best limitations we can prove
do not match thereby leading to several
open problems which i'll talk more about
at the end
in more detail
we have a new attack for v equals one
that has disadvantage
uh the one here in the subscript uh
uh the advantage for finding one block
collision
uh uh the previously best known attacks
for finding one block collision was
essentially what we call the trivial
attack uh where the adversary just uh
remembers collisions for s different ivs
in the pre-processing phase and if the
iv it got as input in the online phase
was not among those ssivs it just did
about this style attack
for the case of mark and damgar this
attack this trivial attack was in fact
provably optimal
however the new attack that we gave for
sponge is actually better than the
trivial attack for certain ranges of
parameters
for example when c and r are the same
for s equals two power four c by five
and t equals two power c by five uh our
attack has constant advantage while the
trivial attack has advantage that is
exponentially small in c
uh
we give a a different attack for other
values of b
this attack is essentially the analog of
an of a similar attack for mark and damn
guard for values of b greater than
equals two and this is inspired by the
rainbow tables attack ins
introduced by wesley
uh we proved the following limitation
for
for the best possible attacks for one
block collisions uh using the uh bit
fixing technique uh
which
reduces which upper bounds the advantage
of an sd adversary with the advantage of
an adversary that has no preprocessing
but can instead fix at most s times
three points of the permutation and
making the analysis easier
uh we believe that the first term
in this bound is not tight and
it could possibly be improved
uh we finally we proved this limitation
for finding two block collisions via the
multi-instance framework
which was recently introduced by chung
at all and akshay metal uh and in turn
inspired by the techniques for proving
constructive chart of bounds by impalia
zone covenants uh this framework
involves reduction to an adversary
where diversity has no pre-processing
and has to find collisions with respect
to s randomly chosen ivs
one interesting
very interesting thing about this result
is that it shows us it is strictly
harder to find two block collisions than
t block ones
thus giving a separation similar to what
we already know for merkle dam guard
further uh this shows us that our attack
for b equals two is actually optimal
when st cube is less than two part c
uh and uh we believe that the last term
in in our bound is not tight and uh
there's room for improvement
so
summarizing after our work this is what
the state of affairs looks like for
spawns and the only thing i'd like to
highlight here is that for all values of
b
there are gaps for the best attack we
know and the best limitation that we can
prove
uh i refer you to our paper for more
details about our two limitation results
and the attack for b greater than equals
two and for the rest of the talk uh i'll
be uh covering our new attack for
finding one block collisions
so we given a tag that has this
following advantage um
looking a bit ahead uh i'll define this
quantity epsilon h
to be the square root of the quantity
inside the omega
this is essentially the advantage or
achieved by helmand's attack for
inverting
random functions
the reason that this appears in our
bound is because we will be using
helmand's attack as a subroutine
so when an adversary has to find a one
block collision
for sponge what it really has to do is
it has to find two distinct messages uh
m and m prime such that the evaluation
of the permutation
on m i v and m prime iv produce the same
first r bits of the output
uh
here i'll use the index one and two to
denote the first r bits and the last c
bits of a spawn state respectively
uh as a first step to constructing an
adversary what we'll do is we'll try
we'll switch to
trying to switch to
make that version solving a much harder
problem
where
not only do we want an adversary uh to
find two messages m and m prime such
that the evaluation of pi on m i v and m
prime iv have the same first r bits of
the output we want those r bits of the
output to be all zeros the reason for
making the switch to a harder problem
will become clear very soon
to that end uh let's take an alternate
view of the problem
let's define a function f which has c
bits input and c boots output
as the last c bits of the evaluation of
of pi inverse or on r0s followed by the
input
uh the main thing i would like to
highlight about this function f is it is
independent of iv
uh we actually switched to solving a
harder problem because we wanted the
function to have this property
and this property would in turn allow us
to use existing pre-processing attacks
for function inversion let's see how
so we propose the following attack
strategy
given on a random ips input we invert
the function f
uh
on
iv to find two distinct pre images x and
x prime
and then we compute the message m as the
evaluation as the first r bits of the
output of evaluation of pi inverse on r
zeros followed by x and similarly
compute m prime and output these two
messages
okay why does this even make any sense
uh
uh observe that if indeed x was an
inverse of iv under f we have that the
last r bits of the evaluation of pi
inverse on r zeros followed by x is iv
and we already know from its definition
that the first uh our bits of the
evaluation is m
this means that uh the the
first are our bits of the evaluation of
pi on m and iv are all zeros
and we can prove uh the same fact for m
prime
so now given that we can invert uh f on
iv and find two distinct premises we
have an attack but how do we do this
so function inversion is a has been in
the pre-processing setting has been
a well studied problem
uh it was first studied by helmand and
later by fiat and r
the specific setting that we are
interested in is when the function f is
a random one
ah there's an adversary which is a two
phase one it's a pre-processing phase it
gets the function as input
it can compute any arbitrary as bits of
advice on it
and which it passes on to the online
phase
which gets additionally a randomly
sampled value y from the image of the
function
can make at most t queries to the
function and it wins if it can output
some x such that f of x equals y
hellman gave an attack
gave an explicit adversary that has the
following advantage
epsilon h which i defined earlier
ah now the question is are we done can
we just plug this in
uh turns out there are several technical
challenges that we need to overcome
uh first off this function s is not a
random function while helmets attack
works for random functions
uh secondly uh the
challenge that the random iv may not
even be in the image of the function
finally uh hellman's attack guarantees
us
only one pre-image while we need to find
two distinct primitives
i'll
speak very briefly uh how we handle all
the three challenges
so for the first challenge uh
first we note that there is a more
general algorithm for function inversion
that works for general functions by fiat
and r
but using that does not really suffice
for us because the attack we end up
getting finally has advantage worse than
the trigger type what we end up doing
is observing that f is close enough to a
random function
for us to adapt the helmet's analysis
on to the second challenge that the
random iv might not
be in the image of f
so an initial observation is a constant
fraction of the co-domain has at least
two pre-images
but note that this does not suffice
because
a helmet's attack might fail for this
constant fraction of the co-domain
so what we do is we analyze elements
attack and prove a very strong statement
showing that
uh
for any fixed value in the
codomain the elements attack succeeds
with probability that is proportional to
the number of pre-images that value has
and uh this turns out to be enough for
for our
case
finally uh we need to find two distinct
pre-images while helmets attack only
guarantees as one
uh the first thought could be to just
run the online phase twice
uh with different randomness and hope
that it gives us two distinct images but
it's not immediately clear that it works
so we further analyze elements attack
and show that in fact for a value y it
finds a
premade uniformly in f inverse of y
and this
this in turn shows that it's enough to
actually run the attack twice with
different randoms
and in and that's one of the reasons we
end up getting an epsilon h square
type of bound
uh there are of course many technical
subtleties for which i refer you to the
paper for details
uh so there are two main takeaway
messages from this work
first uh the ability of an adversary to
make inverse queries in response
construction are actually very useful
to give new attacks
in fact the this ability allows us to
give an attack for sponge and analog for
which does not exist for merkel dam
guard
secondly uh just like mark lam guard
even for sponge finding short collisions
like two block collisions are probably
harder to find than arbitrary length
ones
uh there are several open problems of
course uh one is tightening improving
tight bounce for values of b equals one
and two
second our attack for uh values of b
greater than equals two uh do not
leverage the inverse query in any way
and coming up with new attacks that do
would be an interesting open
or interesting question for
uh uh investigation
uh finally
proving
new
limitations for values of b greater than
equals three
would also be a possible direction of
future research
uh the full version of our paper is an
eprint thank you
thank you we have time for one question
is there any questions
all right let's thank our speaker again
up
oh hold on i'll introduce you
uh our next talk is going to be on time
space tradeoffs for bounded links
collisions and merkle dam guard hashing
which is a soft merge with time space
lower bounds for finding collisions in
merkle dam guard hash functions
and akshima will give the talk
hello everyone
today i will be talking about a work uh
about finding collisions in md-based
hash functions uh with pre-computation
uh this is a joint work with cr go and
japan glue
um
so uh ashrajit was kind enough to
introduce what is merkel damgard but i
would just go about it again so
merkle dangard is one of the most
popular constructions for
hash functions
it is so popular that it motivated us
and a lot of other prior works to study
this particular construction
uh a lot of hash algorithms like md5
sha-1 sha-2 they all their designs are
based on this uh construction so
how does this construction work
this construction uses a one-way
compression function to hash messages of
arbitrary length and how they do that is
they break the message into blocks of
fixed size
uh for the rest of this talk i will
always denote a compression function by
h and they would always be in the uh
like it would always be from the
domain uh of size n times m
to a range of size n
so in this diagram this uh the message
is x
and it's broken into b blocks x1 through
xb and then the compression function is
iteratively applied on
these blocks to obtain the output of mdh
assuming that h is a random function it
is known that any adversary that makes t
queries has an advantage of up to t
square over n
but this is uh when we think that when
this is when we uh when the adversary
has no information about h beforehand
uh it it is perfectly possible and
practical for the adversary to
pre-compute some information about etch
and use that later to find better
attacks
um
in fact rainbow tables is a very good
example of precomputing adversaries and
their power to launch better attacks for
function inversion
and now we wanted to study the power of
pre-computing adversaries for finding
for collision finding in merkle dam
guard based hash functions
so um
this is our problem statement and i
would like to establish some uh
parameters in our model so we would be
talking about uh
adversaries uh that get s bits of advice
precomputed advice they make atmos t
queries to edge and they're required to
find collisions that are at most b
blocks long
so a lot of prior works have studied
this problem of collision finding with
pre-computation particularly for merkel
dam guard based hash functions
and this is this table lists all the
results of those prior works
um
kuretal's work from 2018 were the first
who studied this problem and they showed
indeed it is true
that uh precomputing adversaries can
launch better attacks they can find uh
it is easier for them to find collisions
uh with pre-computation
uh so they give an attack they presented
an attack that achieved an advantage of
st square over n
uh they were also able to prove that uh
that was that those are like that is the
optimal attack but there is a caveat in
their attack
and i would like to talk about that
caveat with an example consider sha2
which is an md-based hash function
uh where n is equal to 2 to the 256 and
m is a 512-bit space
for any adversary that uh
store that has an advice of 2 to the 70
bits
and their st square over n bound implies
that the adversary needs to make about 2
to the 93 queries in order to achieve
constant advantage
so however the uh the attack that uh the
curating it all presented their attack
finds collisions that are also like 2 to
the 93 blocks long
and 2 to the 93 blocks is like yota
bytes of data
uh think about the applications where uh
hash functions are used like digital
signatures and um like hashing passwords
like any adversary that finds that's
finding yota bytes of data
is like it's meaningless that's not uh
any meaningful attack
so uh in one of my previous works with
david andy and hotec we wanted to study
what happens if an adversary is has to
find like a b bounded length collisions
so for b equals to 2 to the 20 the best
attack that we could find required 2 to
the 166 queries instead of 2 to the 193
2 to the 93 queries so our best attack
like uh it would achieve the advantage
of stb over n instead of st square over
n
and this made us wonder if uh
the st square over n bound uh was
uh was pessimistic in in a practical
setting where we are looking at bounded
length collisions
uh so we conjectured that so we gave
this attack of uh that achieved stb over
n as i uh told you before
and we conjectured that it was the
optimal attack however we could not
prove that for all the precomputing
adversaries we could show that only for
a restricted class of adversaries and
that is what this red esteric denotes
uh
what made us believe in our conjecture
was the fact that we could prove it for
two block collision finding uh that the
advantage is st over n and it is indeed
the case that finding uh short
collisions is harder than finding uh
collisions where there's no restriction
on the length
uh the follow-up work of gushal at all
which has been accepted at this paper
it's at this conference itself and uh
soft merge with our work they managed to
show that uh the stb conjecture of acdw
is indeed true for constant b
and uh how they did that more precisely
was they gave uh they gave a bound
that has a factor of log square s
exponentially large in uh b
so
exponentially large in b and uh so this
reduces to a polylog factor when b is a
constant however this bound very quickly
becomes meaningless as b grows larger
they presented another bound
which holds for any precomputing
adversary and any b and that bound is s
to the 4t b square over n
however observe that when s cube b
squared would be greater than t
in that case this bound is worse than
the st square over n bound of courier at
all so this does not say anything uh
about this parameter range like whether
finding collisions is harder like or not
so this is what motivated us to study
this problem further
and uh also like the attack like the
proofs that were given by the acdw paper
and gk paper uh they were very
complicated so uh another
objective for us was to simplify these
proofs and we managed to do both of the
both the things
um and this so we managed to prove a
bound of stb over n times max of one and
st square over n
for any b and any pre-computing
adversary
let us look at our more like this very
unreadable bound mode carefully
so what does this bound mean it means
when st squared over n is less than or
equal to 1 our bound would be stb over n
and for so we managed to prove the stb
conjecture for this parameter range
when st square over n is greater than
one in that case our bound would be stb
over n times st square over n
and even though this does not uh prove
the stb conjecture it is worth noting
that this bound would always be less
than st square over n
and which confirms that finding bounded
length collision is definitely harder
than finding collisions where there's no
restriction on the length
so before i talk about our techniques i
would like to precisely uh define the
model uh ashraji did that in his talk
but i would just like to trade because i
have made the slide so uh so uh
in the pre-computation model the
adversary works in two stages in the
first stage adversary guess gets
computationally unbounded access to the
compression function h but it has to
output a bounded length advice
which would be s bits
then in the second stage the adversary
gets the challenge sort
it takes the advice it gets to make t
queries uh to etch and it is required to
output messages that collide under mdh
with the challenge sort and there is an
additional restriction that these
messages have to be at most blocks long
um so
i would just like to point out that why
analyzing this model is so hard so
observe that these q1 through q2 qt
queries the responses to these queries
can no longer be thought of as ids
because
the adversary gets x-bit information on
edge
so that's why they're querying it all
they reduce the problem to uh finding uh
like bounding the security in another
model namely the pre-sampling model
so the pre-sampling model is uh it works
like again an adversary in this
model works in two stages in the first
stage the adversary gets to fix
uh and fix uh the function h at p points
then in the online phase it it does not
get any advice it just gets uh the
challenge sort it gets to make t queries
uh to this function h and it has to
output collisions uh so this where this
etch
is
is the function with the hard coded
points so when i say hard-coded points
what that means is whatever was prefixed
in the stage one for those points the
adversary has to output the fixed uh
point like the fixed uh
response and for the other it can like
uh respond with ids
so uh credit it all showed that
for any if the advantage of any
adversary in the pre-sampling model
where the adversary fixes st points and
makes t queries uh is bounded by delta
then the advantage of any collision
finding adversary in the pre-computation
model where they adversely
make gets s-bit advice and makes t
queries is of the order delta
so apart from giving this reduction they
showed like the advantage of for
collision finding in the pre-sampling
model is of the order st square over n
which
implies their bound in the
pre-computation model
the actw paper showed however uh
we cannot hope to get any better bounce
in the pre-sampling model for bounded
length collision
uh and that's
they showed that by uh giving an attack
for two block collision finding in the
presom sampling model that achieved an
advantage of st square over n
so they reduced the problem to another
model like solving in another model
which is namely the multi-instance game
now what is multi-instance game as the
name suggests
it's just the adversary gets multiple
instances of a problem and it has to
solve each one of them in order to win
so for our particular case the adversary
gets uh
s solves one at a time and it gets to
make t queries and it has to find
collisions on each of these instances in
order to win
note that here again the adversary does
not get an advice
and it just has to solve all these s
instances
uh so actw paper showed that if the
advantage of any uh collision finding
adversity in the multi-instance game can
be bounded by delta to the s where
the adversary is making t queries for
each instance and it gets s instances
then the advantage for any adversary in
the pre-computation model can be bounded
by two times delta again the adversary
here is getting an advice of s bits and
making t queries
uh so they also uh the acdw paper
bounded uh there uh i bounded the
advantage of this multi-instance gain to
st plus t square over n to the power s
for two block collision finding which
implied they're bound in the
pre-computation model
um the gk paper um they used a similar
approach as the acdw paper but because
they were looking at like constant uh
block collisions
uh they had to cut they had a lot more
types of collisions that they needed to
handle so it was difficult for them like
it was a more challenging task to bound
the advantage in multi-instance game uh
which they managed to do so uh for more
details please refer to their talk on
youtube and um they their paper is also
up on e-print
uh finally i want to talk about our
techniques so we also reduced to the
multi-instance game uh
but we the way we viewed the
multi-instance game model is slightly
different and how we analyze it allowed
us to get better bounds
so let's fix an adversary and let x i be
the indicator
uh variable that adversary wins on salt
ai
what acdw paper and gk paper did was
they looked at the probability that the
adversary wins on all the solves
simultaneously
so what so if this like this box this uh
this depicts uh s source and
t uh queries and responses that are made
for each of these faults
so what they tried to do was if an
adversary has to win on all these
assaults it has to find collisions on
all these which means there
should be s collisions in these st
queries
and
then these collisions can be compressed
uh using this adversary
however
it should not be possible to compress h
because h is a random function
uh
so that's how they were able to bound
this probability that all xi's
are one
uh it is worth noting that uh in this
like when they are like looking at all
like this when they're like bounding
this simultaneously uh there are a lot
of different types of collisions that
can happen
and in order to like compress each of
the cases uh sometimes like this this
compression
algorithms can become like very crazy
and like unintuitive of what exactly is
happening in the single instance
so
how we viewed this model is slightly
different
we uh
we instead of bounding the like this
on the left the term on the left we
bounded the probability that uh
the adversary wins in the iath instance
given that it wins on all the previous i
minus one instances
so uh
if the adversary so in the previous i
minus one instances the adversary would
have made a total of i minus one times t
queries which is always like less than
equal to st queries so we think of those
as offline queries then the adversary
gets the ith challenge sort ai and then
it gets to make t queries which we refer
to as the online queries
so uh this sort of looks like still
still like a single instance
problem and um this
and now now we need to bound this
probability of x i given x less than i
to a term a to a to a bound that is
exactly the same as what we need in the
pre-computation model
so this becomes a little more intuitive
so in order to explain our techniques in
a little more detail i would just focus
on one particular type of collision and
this is this collision um here
this curved uh arrows depict uh they
are they denote queries q2 and q3 and
the straight arrow one is q1 and for
this type of collision like this
collision depicts uh the colliding
messages would be like m1 concatenated
with m2 and m1 concatenated with m3
and we are looking at the collision type
where q2 q3 happen in the offline they
happen among the offline queries and q1
happens among the online queries
the idea to note here is the output of
q1 is limited to certain values what are
those values
they have to be the input sort of one of
the st queries in the offline among the
offline queries
which means the probability that there
exists a q1 like online query is at most
st square over n
but we can do better than that because
there is more structure to what these q2
q3 queries can be so these q2q so this
q2 query like the query
whose input solve has to be the output
of q1
has to be a query uh
that shares the input sort with another
query that has the same output so
basically we should be looking at how
many q2 q3 type pairs can exist among
the offline queries
so that's what we want to look at how
many pairs can there be and we call this
as useful knowledge gain that we get
from the offline queries
so in the worst case
in the worst case there can be st over
two such q two q three type pairs uh
because if we assume that every query in
the offline uh
phase shares this kind of structure with
another query then in that case there
will be st over two such pairs
and this implies a bound of st square
over n
but it's worth noting that the pro the
the chance that we can get like st over
two such pairs in the offline query is
very unlikely it's like it it has a very
small chance and this
what this st over two pair like this
bound is sort of a worst case analysis
and this is very similar to what was
happening in pre-sampling because
pre-sampling was allowing the
adversaries to fix these st points
so
and we believe that
we should be able to bound better via an
average case analysis which is which is
what we did so and we showed that the
probability of finding more than s pairs
uh q2 q3 like pairs is in st queries is
very very small
so which implies uh
with a good probability there are only s
such pairs among the offline queries and
which allows us to bound uh that the
probability of uh there existing a q1
like online query to be st over n
um
now there are a lot of different types
of collisions that can happen for b
equals to two and like general b
so uh this is just a brief overview of
how our proof works
we identified all types of useful
knowledge gains from the offline queries
for each type we showed that the
probability of high knowledge gain is
very small even conditioned on winning
in all the previous rounds
and when none of the knowledge gain is
high we can easily bound uh this
probability of x i given x less than i
as required
so um
for future work one of the most
important things that we would like to
know is
whether for st square greater than equal
to n if there is a better attack or if
there is a better security bound that is
definitely one of the most important
future works that we look forward to
doing
and thank you our paper is in
our paper is on eprint please give it a
read and thank you for your
attention do we have any questions
all right let's thank our speaker again
foreign
all right our next talk is going to be
sustain space and cumulative complexity
trade-offs for data dependent memory
hard functions and blake coleman will
give the talk
okay
thank you for the introduction and this
work was with my advisor jeremiah blochy
so
specialized hardware such as a6 can
evaluate hash functions orders of
magnitude times faster than standard
hardware
this is a problem because it offers an
advantage for offline attackers who
brute force passwords
memory hard functions aim to minimize
this hardware advantage
and as a result they protect loan trippy
secrets like passwords from brute force
attacks
so first we acknowledge that
memory cost is relatively uniform across
these different types of hardware
and so what we want is a function whose
computational costs are dominated by
memory cost
in particular we want to force an
attacker to lock up large amounts of
memory for the duration of the
computation
this will make it expensive even on
customized hardware
but now the question is how can we prove
that we've done this how do we quantify
memory hardness
well a standard way to characterize the
space cost of a function is via
space-time complexity
the space-time cost of an evaluation
algorithm is just the maximum space to
use times the duration of the
computation
and the space-time complexity of a func
of a
function is just the uh space-time cost
of the cheapest evaluation algorithm
this is great because there's a rich
time space trade rich theory of
time-space trade-offs
but unfortunately it's not appropriate
for password hashing or many other use
cases for memory hard functions
the reason is that it doesn't amortize
well
so what you can do is if you have a
function that might have high
high space time complexity but you only
just have to sustain the maximal space
for a short amount of time you can
essentially stagger their start times in
parallel
and about evaluate the function many
times with a space time cost that's very
similar to if you evaluate it at once
at high level
we really want it to be true that making
10 password guesses in parallel
is 10 times as costly as making a single
password guess
so how we can get around this is by
using cumulative complexity and this
just measures the sum of the space used
across the duration of the computation
and at first glance this looks very
promising because
it turns out that the cumulative
complexity of evaluating a function
m times in parallel
is m times
the cost of evaluating it once
so now we can look at an example script
is a widely used memory hard function
and it was proven to have maximal
cumulative complexity of n squared
where n is our running time parameter
so now the question is does this maximal
cc actually align with our intuitions
for memory hardness
and the answer is not quite because we
can evaluate a script using constant
memory for n squared time
and remember what we wanted out of a
memory hard function we wanted to force
an attacker to lock up large amounts of
memory for the duration of the
computation
so how we can fix this is by using a
host metric that is
very tightly correlated to what we want
so now we can use sustained space
complexity which measures the time spent
above a certain memory threshold
and
you can see that this is stricter than
cumulative complexity because
if you're if you sustain s space for t
time
then your cumulative cost is going to be
at least s times t
so now that we have this
way of measuring cost that's very uh
you know it aligns with our intuitions
for memory hard functions we want to
know how good can we do
ideally we want to construct memory hard
functions in which any evaluation
strategy sustains in space for in steps
unfortunately
this is impossible because any membrane
heart function can be evaluated
using only interval login space
although these evaluation strategies can
have exponential runtime
so now since we can't do that we wonder
if we can
relax
our goal slightly and still have say
something strong about uh guarantees
so we want to know whether or not we can
force any attacker that has low
sustained space complexity to pay a huge
penalty in
cumulative cost
and so in this work
our goal is to construct a memory hard
function in which any strategy either
sustains
in space for n steps
or has cumulative cost much greater than
n squared
so we examine the sustained space and
cumulative complexity trade-offs for two
practical memory hard functions
and then we give a theoretical
construction that actually achieves the
achieves near optimal trade-offs
we've already seen that for script we
can evaluate it using constant space and
n squared cumulative complexity
so the first function we consider is dr
sample it's a practical side channel
resistant memory hard function
and we give some slight modifications
and show that any strategy either
sustains n over login space for n steps
or has cumulative cost n cubed over log
in
next we take a look at argon 2.
argon 2 is widely deployed it won the
password hashing competition in
and it's in many cryptographic libraries
we show that any strategy either
sustains
n to the one minus epsilon space for n
steps or it has cumulative cost slightly
more than n squared
finally we give a theoretical
construction which actually achieves the
maximal sustained space
sustained space parameter that we were
hoping for so any strategy either
sustains in space for n steps
or it has cumulative cost n to the three
minus epsilon
so now i want to talk about
how we did these general proof
strategies and then i'm going to talk
about
our construction
so first a memory heard function is
defined with respect to a random graph
family and these encode data
dependencies
the input to our function maybe it's
like a password and assault
and so from here we compute the labels
for the nodes the label for node 0 is
just the hash of the input
and the label for any other node is just
the hash of the labels of its
predecessors
the output of our function is just going
to be
the last label in our graph
so some nodes have what's what's called
dynamic edges and this is how the you
know random graphs play role
and these edges depend on the labels of
a node's predecessor for example node
three has a dynamic edge which we denote
r3
um and that's going to use the
randomness from when we take the hash of
the labels uh
of labels zero and one
so it could either land on zero or one
according to some probability
distribution
and the important takeaway here is that
uh
this edge uh which node it lands on
depends on these previous labels and
those previous labels
in turn depend on the input of our
function so then these edges depend
directly on
the inputs
and that's why we call graphs with these
dynamic edges data dependent memory hard
functions
if they don't have any dynamic edges
then we call them data independent
memory functions
great um so now how do why do we even
care about data dependent memory hard
functions
well remember our goal was to
construct a memory hard function in
which any strategy either sustains in
space for n steps or it has cumulative
costs much more than n squared
it turns out that any uh data
independent memory hard function can be
computed
using cumulative cost
strictly less than n squared
and this actually makes these trade-offs
impossible
so ideally we want to use these dynamic
edges to get stronger guarantees
so to prove these results we proved them
using dynamic pebbling games so here
we're going to be placing pebbles on
nodes in the graph and you can
essentially think of a node as a label
so placing a a pebble on a node is like
computing a label and keeping a pebble
on a node is like storing a label in
memory
so
you know the rule is you can always
place a pebble on a node whose parents
all have pebbles on them
and again these dynamic edges can appear
when you pebble all of the static
predecessors to a node
and these edges appear land on nodes
according to some
predetermined probability distribution
again our goal is to place a pebble on
the last node in our graph the sink
so now i'll give a quick pebbling
example we're going to pebble this graph
you can always place a pebble on node
one
now we can place one unknown too since
we have pebbles on nodes one and two we
can pebble node three
this causes a dynamic edge to appear
which just happened to land on node two
so we'll pebble node two
four and five
okay so now we're ready to talk about um
our proof structure
and just as a reminder our goal is to
construct memory hard functions such
that any strategy either sustains
in space for n steps or has cumulative
cost much more than n squared
so in general um our setup is the
following we have a graph where like the
first half is
highly connected according to some
metric and it has high cumulative
complexity
the second half of our graph
has dynamic edges coming from the first
half
the idea is that if a strategy only has
a few pebbles on the graph
then there's a good chance they're going
to have to re-pebble
a lot of that first half of the graph
and they're going to incur a very high
cumulative cost
so in our construction the graph that
serves
to have these
but to achieve these connectivity goals
are what is called st robust graphs
so sd robust graphs have n inputs and
outputs
with the property that you can remove
any k nodes from the graph
and there's still a sub graph with n
minus k inputs n minus k outputs
with a path from all of the inputs to
all of the outputs
our second ingredient is depth
robustness a graph is e d depth robust
if you can remove any e nodes from the
graph and there's still a path of length
d
this is useful because if a graph is e d
depth robust then it then it has
cumulative cost much
at least e times d
as an example this graph is one for
depth robust and you can see this
because you can just remove
any of the nodes and there's still a
path of link four
so what we do is we combine our first
ingredient which were stirred us graphs
and with our second ingredient depth
robustness
so what we do is we overlay a graph
that's n by n to the one minus epsilon
depth robust onto the inputs of our st
robust graphs
so now re-pebbling these inputs is going
to cost
have cumulative cost n to the two minus
epsilon
now the question is how can we make a
low sustained space attacker re-pevel
these
inputs many times
what we do is we add a line graph to the
end of our construction
and then we have dynamic edges coming
to each of the nodes in line graph from
the ran from random outputs of our st
robust graph
so now
if an attacker wants to place a pebble
on some node in our line graph
but they only have relatively few
pebbles on the graph
then there's a good chance they're not
going to have a pebble on the random
output they need
and with constant probability there's
going to be paths from many of the
inputs to that particular output
meaning
they'll have to re-pebble these inputs
and that's going to cost
cumulative cost
into 2 minus epsilon so we can show that
if an attacker is frequently low memory
then they're going to have to
repeal the inputs a linear number of
times with respect to our runtime
parameter with high probability
and so putting this all together you get
that for such attackers their cumulative
cost will be n to the three minus
epsilon
on the other hand if an attacker is
trying to pebble a no no-line graph but
they do have a lot of pebbles on the
graph
we can just count that towards our
sustained space complexity
so putting this all together we get that
any strategy for evaluating our memory
heart function either sustains n pebbles
for n steps or that it has cumulative
cost
n to the three minus epsilon
so in this work we showed that there are
some current and practical memory hard
functions which have high sustained
space and cumulative complexity
trade-offs
we also gave a theoretical construction
with near-optimal trade-offs
this also generated some open problems
first like you know our proofs were done
in this dynamic pebbling model with
these pebbling games we want to know
whether these claims can be proven in
the random oracle model
for memory hard functions that don't
have dynamic edges
there's actually a general reduction
that relates any evaluation algorithm
with a
equivalent cost pebbling strategy
so we wonder if you can give a reduction
a similar reduction for memory hard
functions that do have dynamic edges
finally our theoretical construction is
very costly to implement
and so we wonder if there's a practical
memory hard function that still achieves
the maximal sustain space parameter
so is there a practical memory hard
function in which any strategy
must sustain in space for n steps or
have cumulative costs much more than n
squared
thank you
thank you we have time for some
questions
um see if i understood correctly you
mentioned that you proved your result uh
in a very nice
and intuitive pebbling model but when
you try to
actually prove it in the random oracle
using compression or something
the proof gets stuck unlike previous
results where i think you do have this
proof can you let me point what's the
difficulty so
when you try is it like hopeless yeah um
so
um i think people have yeah we've worked
a little bit on trying to do such a
reduction um
essentially it just
uh i don't know it's just uh kind of
difficult with the randomness right so
you know that's why for script for
example
they opted to instead do a direct proofs
uh that's their paper where they prove
that it's maximally memory hard right
um
so yeah it's still you know a difficult
open problem uh but it's not like an
obvious barrier that somehow you know
you just try and some coincidentally
just there is no hope
oh no
so so i i believe there is hope for uh
constructing such a reduction uh we just
haven't uh figured it out yet
and also just in terms of optimal
parameters so
when you say much greater than n square
at some point you said exponential uh so
what is optimal is n and and cube
optimal so and cube is really obviously
optional so so what i meant was um
by exponential is that uh
as the result that any memory hard
function can be evaluated using n over
log in space uh the thing is that that
the run time can be exponential to those
um n cubed is the best you can do uh
just by some
uh
previous work and uh space-time
trade-offs um yeah the best you can hope
for is like a penalty of n squared but
we haven't achieved that yet so n n and
cube would be the optimal which is
almost everything yes
so maybe to actually use question yeah
so it's always complicated when you know
either there's randomness the edges are
dynamic or there's a pre-computation
that they don't know and in fact there
are two counter examples where you can
show that the the pepping strategy does
not imply a bound for the random oracle
model i forgot exactly the thing but
basically you can ignore notes and that
actually helps in some sections so in
some cases it's simply wrong and we
don't know
um i forgot the link it's in some paper
in some appendix there is this concrete
counter example of the graph where it's
not true oh okay uh i wasn't aware of
how to delete
um
you mentioned many different complexity
definitions in the beginning of your
talk are there ones that you tried along
the way that you didn't mention here
um no we didn't uh quite try um
space-time complexity but
i i thought it kind of
helped understand how we got to using
sustained space and why we had to
also use cumulative complexity
all right let's thank our speaker again
all right our final talk of this session
is going to be a video so i will ask
kevin to share screen and then wait for
us to confirm that we can see it please
thank you
all right we're ready to go
hi
i'm shakha and this is joint work with
money now in this work we study
communication complexity in
computational settings
first let's recall communication
complexity the input is split between
alice and bob but they can communicate
in order to compute some target function
if communication complexity we are
interested in protocol with as little
communication as possible
you can think of a simple target
function as the quality predicate
alice and bob have to figure out whether
their inputs are equal or not most of
the results apply to almost any
reasonable predicate
where there is no input identical to
another also in our computational
settings we'll also require predicates
to have an efficient description in some
sense
two known network layouts in
communication complexity
are the interactive model where
participants can communicate without any
round limit
and the simultaneous messages model
where participants can send only only a
single message to a third party as we'll
see next
the randomness is also an important
property of the model whether there
exists shared public randomness or not
we are not considering here the
deterministic protocols
the communication complexity of the
equality predicate is well studied
and known to be in the interactive model
constant in the presence of public
randomness and login otherwise
let's move on now to the simultaneous
messages model
in this model alice and bob get their
input and produce one message each
these messages are sent to a third party
a referee and the referee has to compute
the target function with some constant
high probability for example assume that
alice and bob have to check if their
inputs are equal and have no common
randomness
they can use a good error correcting
code arrange the code words in a square
and now
alice's message will be a random war
and bob's message will be a random
column the referee just compares the
matched symbols by the arrow correcting
code the arrow is bounded by a constant
and hence this protocol can be amplified
easily by parallel repetitions
observe that the size of a row or a
column is square root of n and hence
this is the communication complexity of
the protocol
this protocol matches the known lower
bound for the equality predicate in the
simultaneous messages model with no
common random list
this lower bound was proved several
times the proof of bar in gmail is
general and holds for any non-redundant
predicate as a side note you can see
that the result is also a trade-off
between alice and bob messages size and
the previous protocol can be tweaked to
match it in our work the central
question is can the communication
complexity be reduced in a computational
world
one motivation is to discuss settings
closer to the real world
we study how communication complexity
models can be fitted to be computational
hence
we redefine the publican domains
consider a stateful participant and a
computational adversary instead of
closed cased input we discuss two
computational variations
the preset randomness model where there
is a common random string but the inputs
are chosen by an adversary who also sees
that common randomness the second model
is the free talk model that we'll
discuss later
now
we move on to define the preset
randomness model
first we have alice bob and the
adversary no inputs yet now the public
random is sampled and visible for
everyone then the inputs are chosen by
the adversary
then the participants can sample fresh
private randomness and have to compute
one message each the referee gets the
messages and outputs a decision
notice that assuming collision resistant
hash functions the communication
complexity of the equality predicate in
the preset randomness model can be
reduced significantly by simply running
the information theoretic protocol on
the digest
that is the square root of n lower bound
in the simultaneous messages model and
log n in the interactive model can be
outperformed assuming scrh
our results
go in the other direction
we show that breaking those known lower
bounds in the preset randomness model
implies the existence of dcrh
distributional collision resistant hash
function this year age is where only
random collisions are guaranteed to be
hard to find
that is we show an explicit construction
of a crh function from such a protocol
we also show
that there are no protocols of constant
communication in the preset randomness
model regardless of assumptions we used
techniques from baba and kim spoof to
show those results
the main idea behind the proofs in the
preset randomness model is the
characterizing multiset the idea is that
for any input alice's behavior can be
approximated by a multiset
that is
there exists a multiset with the
following property
when we run the protocol we can use a
uniform sample from this multiset
instead of running alice and still get
with hyperability the same output as in
alice in the protocol
hence for every input x alice can be
replaced by a multiset
we show that such a multiset can be
sampled with high probability
by running alice multiple times on that
input x independently
we construct a function by sampling
a public random string and three random
tapes of alice
the input of the function is an input x
for alice
and the output of the function is the t
messages alice produces for this input x
and these three random types and public
handle
now we'll sketch the proof
that this function is a dcrh
first the function is indeed compressing
now
the main observation is that a collision
in the function is two inputs that share
a characterize in what is it that means
two inputs that make alice behave
similar however since our predicate is
non-redundant there exists twice such
that f of x y is not equal to f of x
prime y but since alice's behavior is
similar
the output of the protocol will be
incorrect at least on one of the pairs
we got that a collision finder for that
function can be used to find bad inputs
for that protocol
however we claim only for dcrh and not
cr since the characterization property
of the function is only with high
probability and that means that there
exists input x such that h of x doesn't
characterize x and hence there exists
bad collisions collisions that won't
necessarily induce bad inputs for the
protocol
the second model is the stateful free
talk model in this model alice and bob
can communicate freely before the inputs
are chosen
then the inputs are chosen by an
adversary and now the communication is
measured
in this variation
we study the simultaneous messages model
we consider an adversary with two
additional advantages the first is
russian and can choose the input for bob
at the last moment after seeing alice's
message
and the second he doesn't have to attack
a specific session he can wait for an
opportunity to attack
we showed in this model
that very efficient protocols
imply the existence of secret key
agreement
note that assuming secret key agreement
optimal protocols exist as we'll see
next
first
let's recall secretary agreement
security agreement is where two parties
with nothing in common agree on a secret
key
the key
has to be known only to the participants
and not to any listening adversary
now let's walk through the steps
in the stateful free talk model the part
is talk freely
the adversary receives the transcript
and chooses the inputs for alice and bob
the parties get the input and send to
the referee a single message each the
referee output a decision
how secret key agreement implies optimal
equality protocol
the security agreement protocol can be
used in the free talk phase hence the
secret state of the participants will be
the secret key after receiving their
inputs the participant will use the
secret key to sample a pro as
independent hash functions
the inputs will be compressed by that
functions two messages and sent to the
referee the referee just compared the
messages now that this protocol is a
resilient to the mentioned patient
russian adversary
in the other direction towards
constructing security agreement we first
achieved the weaker notion of secret bid
agreement that is part is a clay on a
bit with some probability and that bit
is secret in some weakened option
note that the notion of alpha beta sql
bit agreement is a generalization of
secret gentlemen
and it is known when and how
alphabetical bit agreement can be
amplified to a secret key agreement
hence it is sufficient to show a
construction of alpha beta signal bit
agreement with suitable parameters
now
assume we have such a new optimal
protocol for equality
that means
we have a way to generate secret state
for alice involved
we have functions from inputs and secret
states to messages and we have the
function of the theory from messages to
a beat
our 6th week agreement protocol will be
as follows
first
the secret state is generated
and ali sampled
a secret bit b in two uniformly random
inputs x0 x1 alice evaluates in the
equality protocol a message for xb
she sends bob this message in x1 bob
evaluates its message for x1 in his
output b prime is the output of the
equality referee on its own generated
message and the received message
alice's output is her sample b to b
the agreement parameter of this protocol
that is the probability that b is equal
to b prime
is given by the equality protocol
for showing the secrecy we show that
given an adversary who can predict that
beat
we can construct an adversary for the
quality protocol
given a secret beat agreement adversary
the quality adversary will be as follows
in each session he sets a random input x
for alice and waits for her message
now he samples another random input x
prime and uses the secret bit agreement
adversary to check if that random input
also matches that message
that is
diversity wants to find two inputs that
can make alice produce the same message
with some probability if he finds such
inputs he attacks that session by
passing bob x with power bt half or x5
with probability half the intuition is
that
if the adversary finds two messages x
and x prime that make alice behave
similarly the referee is going to be
round on at least one pair
x and x or x and x prime
to conclude such a secret bit agreement
adversary contradicts the properties of
the equality protocol hence the secrecy
property of the secret bit agreement
protocol holds and the secret bit
agreement protocol can be amplified to a
secret key agreement protocol
before we finish let's mention some
related work
first the consecutive messages model in
this model the public random string is
chosen after the adversary chooses the
first input
hence a one-way function is necessary
and sufficient to break the square out
of n lower bound the lower bound is
shown via distributional one-way
function that is known to be
existentially equivalent
to one-way function
unlike the case with dcrh and crh
in the adversarial sketch model there
are two phases the sketch phase
where each party receives its input
online without any interaction with the
other party
and the interaction phase where there
are no inputs only sketches and the
parties communicate in order to compute
the target function
they showed a lower bound for the sketch
size that is very similar to the quote
of n in the simultaneous messages model
in the property preserving hash
functions model the target predicate
also should be computed from sketches
different levels of robustness are
defined the more access to the hash
function given to the adversary the more
robust the property preserving hash is
the full access robust property
preserving hash functions might be seen
as very close to our preset randomness
model simultaneous messages but here
there should be negligible and the path
is our deterministic
for further research
it will be interesting to figure out in
the preset randomness model
whether crashes are equivalent to
protocols that break dimension bounds
or to break those bounds with weaker
primitives in the free talk model we
would like to know whether protocols
that are secure in weaker notions
also imply security agreement
let's thank the speaker
and i believe the speaker is here with
us in the zoom room if there are any
questions
is that correct is he still here
yes yes
all right i have a question um so you
listed quite a few different further
research questions there at the end can
you talk a bit more about whichever of
those you think is the most uh
compelling
i think the the gap between this rh and
the crhs
because it's not clear if it's
a
technical barrier or
or something more significant
sorry i'm having a little bit of trouble
understanding your audio
can you say that one more time
can you hear me
yeah it's just a little muddled
but um but yeah i think it's i think
it's good now so
uh yeah just please repeat
okay i think the gap between
crhs and the dcr ages
uh a the most compelling
yes sorry i'm just i can hear you volume
wise fine but the um the words are
coming out a little muddled so i'm
not quite sure
at least the the talk was a
pre-recorded
yes
are there are there any questions in
zoom you can put them in the chat or any
further questions in the room
oh all right well i think everyone is
anxious to get to lunch so we will go
ahead and do that a quick announcement
if you're interested in arranging a ride
share uh back tomorrow they've started a
chat channel for that so that's
accessible from the link on the main
program
and we'll start sessions back up today
at 150 thank you
sorry