my name is dominique and i'm happy to be
the session chair today
so the first talk is actually split
between two papers it's a soft merge and
the the both authors will switch in the
middle so in case you have a question
then please make sure you address the
question of course to the right to the
right author
the title is better than at this
advertised security for non-interactive
threshold signatures by mia bellaria
elizabeth wright jelisa comolo marie
muller stefano tessaro and chen jui su
i hope that this was correct
and a little bethel will start with her
talk
i'm going to be talking about the
security of non-interactive threshold
signatures this is joint work with me
here belare chelsea comolo mary mallor
stefano tazzaro and chenzi zoo who will
be my co-speaker
threshold signatures allow multiple
parties to jointly sign a message where
some threshold of them is required to
sign this is important for distributing
trust
because if we have a single key this
represents a single point of failure
but if we distribute the key amongst
multiple parties
then we can tolerate some
fraction of corrupt signers
this is important because threshold
signatures are being used to secure
cryptocurrency wallets
threshold cryptography generally is
being standardized through nist as well
as specific schemes like frost
in this work we're going to focus on
non-interactive threshold signatures
so consider an example where two out of
three parties are required to sign
if we consider a user called the leader
and a fully non-interactive scheme the
leader will send a message to the two
signing parties
they will each then form a partial
signature which they send to the leader
the leader then aggregates these partial
signatures into a final signature
representing the group
examples of fully non-interactive
schemes include threshold bls and
threshold rsa
but what about discrete log based
schemes and in particular ones that are
pairing free
so currently there exists no fully
non-interactive schemes
but there is a scheme called frost which
consists of two rounds
there's a single signing round preceded
by one message independent
pre-processing round
we refer to this as partially
non-attractive
for ecdsa there is also a scheme that
consists of a single signing round
however it also incorporates multiple
pre-processing rounds
which we do not consider in this work
so in this paper we propose a formal
framework for partially non-interactive
threshold schemes
we introduce a formal syntax as well as
a hierarchy of security notions
these can be applied to bls frost and
other schemes
but why is this framework needed
prior to this work there existed no
formalization for partially
non-attractive schemes
so we provide the first formal syntax
we also note that existing security
notions were actually weaker than what
the schemes can achieve
so we propose a fine-grained security
hierarchy with stronger notions of
security
we also note that the original proof for
frost relied on heuristic assumptions
so in this work we analyzed the security
of frost based on our security hierarchy
we also analyze the security of bls and
note that it achieves a stronger notion
of security than was previously realized
this is also implied by the concurrent
work of yensgra
in this talk i'm going to focus on the
frost threshold scheme
and our concrete contributions are as
follows we present frost ii
which is an optimized version of the
original frost scheme that we call frost
one
frost two reduces the number of
exponentiations required for signing
from t to one
we proved the security of both frost 1
and frost 2 under the one more discrete
logarithm assumption in the random
oracle model
this assumes a trusted dkg
we proved the security of frost 2
together with the distributed key
generation protocol proposed in the
original frost paper
this allows any number of corrupt
signers and in particular a dishonest
majority
our security framework
introduces a separation in the notions
of security achieved by frost one and
frost ii
but as we'll see both schemes achieve
some of the highest notions of security
in our framework
so now i'd like to talk about frost in a
little more detail
ross stands for flexible round optimized
schnorr threshold signature
and it was introduced by common goldberg
in 2020
it consists of a distributed key
generation protocol
and a concurrently secure two-round
signing protocol
also importantly it outputs a signature
which looks exactly like standard single
party snore so this means that it can be
used as a drop-in replacement anywhere
where schnorr signatures are used
we also note that there were prior
attempts at achieving a two-round secure
threshold schnorr scheme but they were
thwarted by the ros attacks which we
also show are feasible
so frost was first published in 2020
and since then it's being used to secure
cryptocurrency wallets
it is also being standardized through
nist
and there's an ietf draft which is
almost complete
there are also more than five
implementations of frost
now we'll talk a little bit about the
distributed key generation protocol
so we call it ped pop and it consists of
the pedersen dkg
together with proofs of possession
these proofs of possession are
themselves schnorr signatures so this
requires a knowledge of exponent
assumption
this is for simplicity because we did
not want to add rounds to the dkg
it allows any number of corrupt signers
including a dishonest majority
now let's look at the frost construction
which we'll call for us one
we consider that the two out of three
signers are participating
in the first round each signer produces
two nonces so a nods are and announce s
and this is the generator raised to some
uniformly random element r and the same
for s
each party produces these two nonces and
then sends them to the leader
at this point the leader chooses the
message to be signed and sends that
together with the signing set and the
set of nonces for those parties
each signer then computes the following
so they compute a hash which takes us
and put the signer index
the message
the public key output by the dkg as well
as the set of all nonces for all parties
the aggregate nods is computed as a
product of each of the r values the s
values raised to this hash value called
dj
then each party computes the hash of the
aggregate public key the message and the
aggregate nots
they then use this to form their partial
signature
so a partial signature z
equals r plus this hash value d
times s plus the hash value c
times the lagrange coefficient for that
signing set times the secret key
they then send their partial signatures
to the leader
the leader computes the aggregate value
z by just simply adding the partial
signatures together
the final signature consists of the
aggregate nonce r and the aggregate
value z and note that it verifies
exactly like standard single party
schnorr
also note that you can't actually tell
who participated in signing which is
great for privacy
one of the observations that we made in
this work was that you don't actually
need to have a different hash value per
signer so instead you can actually use
the same hash value for all signers
so i've highlighted and read here that
the value d no longer takes as input the
signer index
everything else stays the same
verification stays the same but note
that this does reduce the number of
exponentiations required for signing
from t to one
now we'll talk a little bit about
proving the security of frost 2 together
with the ped pop dkg
so we observed that some of these
reductions in the past have had flaws
due to the complexity of modeling
multiple parties interacting at once and
also trying to extract a solution to
some hard problem
so in particular these reductions kind
of consist of two moving parts
we have to simulate the honest users
with the adversary and we also have to
extract a solution to the hard problem
and our idea was actually to separate
these two aspects of the proof
so it looks a bit like this so we have
frost two signing
and which is a multi-party scheme and we
introduce an intermediate assumption
called the by assumption you can think
of this kind of like a single party
assumption so we first provide a
straight line reduction from multi-party
frost 2 to this kind of single party
assumption
we then prove security from the by
schnauer assumption to the one more
discrete logarithm assumption so this
separates the multi-party aspects from
the rewinding required for this part
then for the ped pop distributed key
generation i mentioned that these uh
proofs of possession are schnorr
signatures so we introduced the schnorr
knowledge of exponent assumption and we
prove it under the discrete logarithm
assumption
note that using ped pop again
allows any number of corrupt signers
including a dishonest majority
and now i'll hand it over to chunky
hello
um yeah so thanks yeah
yeah so uh from
uh from the leaderboards part we saw how
frost protocol work
and now i'm going to um show you a
framework and a security hierarchy that
can be used to analyze like a fully or
partially
incorrectly terrestrial signatures such
as the frog
yeah so before we go into that let me
briefly recall the
uh two motivations
the first
there's no formalization for partially
non-interactive schemes
yet so the original frost paper um a
trader
scheme is a general interactive
protocols
and the simpler abstract abstraction
only exists for fully non-interactive
schemes
and second more importantly
we find that
the existing security notions are weaker
than a scheme can achieve
so in particular uh in a security game
defined by most of previous works
an m is so a message m is considered
signed as long as one on its part is
signed
so
this provides actually a very weak
guarantees when
when
the adversaries does not crop many part
signers
however only a very few
prior works consider
guarantees stronger than this
so i will now first introduce
our definition for the in syntax of
non-interactive structural signature
so in our setting there are n signers
and a one leader
so for simplicity let's consider the
case where n is equal to three and the
threshold t is two
so after dkg the each signer will
get
a shares of the secret key and the
leader will get a public key
and
during the pre-processing run each
signer will send the
tokens to the leader
and then the leader started to create a
leader request which contains a message
m to be signed
and a set of signer
that are involved
so which denoted as assets
which
require to have side the list t
so over here
for example it can be just one and three
and this little request also can change
some auxiliary information
that can depend on pre-processing token
and for example for frost
the auxiliary information adjusts all
the pre-processing tokens
i will set the nouns
for the designated sinus and then either
send a request to all the designated
signers and then each signer replies
with a partial signature
and finally later combine those
signature partial signatures to get a
valid signature for the mathematics
so the security in terms of security we
want to get uh the schemes to have i
guarantee the unfoldability
um
so and uh
so in the uh so in the setting we
consider the leader as the adversary
and so sorry yeah and
they can corrupt um
uh at most t-minus one signers
and we're corrupting means uh just
so the adversary will learn is the
secret key of those signs the crop
designers and then the anniversary will
uh can interact with other audience
signers
and the goal is to output
a signature for the message m star
and here the unforgivability trying to
guarantees
that
the rosary cannot forge any non-trivial
signature
so here the question is uh
what is a trivial signature
so it's the same as to ask
it seem to ask
what signatures are considered to be
issued during the interaction
and
it turns out that uh this was the
major problem we are dealing with in
this work we find it's not easy to
define
the
define it for the structural signature
and also there's no canonical way to do
it
so before we go into that uh i will
introduce
our general framework for modeling the
security
so in
in this work we use a game-based
definition
so we use the theater to know the set of
crop designers
and the interaction between the
so between the adversary and the honest
signers are modeled by
um a true oracles with pp oracle and a p
sign oracle
so for the
so when an affiliate query
and index i to the pp oracle
it sends a returns
tokens for the signer i
and when it
queries the p sign oracle for index i
and the erect
uh it will answer the lrac um
on the behave be on behalf of the
designer i
and here the i have uh must be a honest
signer
and the university can make arbitrary
numbers of curry to them
and here there are three wins if
the final output message and signature
pair is not of trivial faulty okay so
let's come back to the problem of what
is attribute boundary
so here it turns out there so the rough
picture as follows there is a
several ways we can define it
and a different way leads to a different
security levels
and moreover
uh the more strictly the security level
the most restricted the trigger forgery
condition will lead to a stronger
security level
and which will give us a security
hierarchy
so uh
so the starting example is i'm going to
talk about the simplest and the weakest
one in our hierarchy which is the tsuf0
so here we uh let the l denote the set
of
all adversaries queries to the p sign
oracle
and uh so for tsuf0
and
folder is considered to be trivial
if there exists a query to
an l such for the m for the message m
star
so more visibly so if there was three
as long as it makes a query to the p
sign oracle for the amp star
then
um its folder is considered to be
tribute so in other words
uh this yes you have zero guarantees
that as long as the anniversary
um
um so
the adversary can afford the signatures
uh
as uh if
only if there is at least one only
signer that signs m star
and this is notion considered uh by most
of the previous work
and
so when the graphic set is less than t
minus one
firstly that
there are stronger security
considerations
so to give you more intuitions so
consider anniversary
that does not corrupt any signer
and it make a single query to p sign
oracle for m star and then it outputs
um
a signature for m star
so
you can see that this does not root out
by tsuf zero security
but however if you're thinking about it
we're in a
a threshold setting we have a threshold
t so it's reasonable to require that at
least t signers to require to
to answer to get a partial signature
into for it to get the signature
so this leads us to define our next uh
security level
so
um to define it uh
we first introduced a very convenient
notion called mss
for so intuitively this
um the mss force a message m represents
a set of
only signers that assigns m
so with this notion we can define the
tsuf0 simply as um
so
so the trigonophobic condition is
the
size of ms for m star is greater than
zero
and so to extend to tsuf1 security
um
the
the trigger folder condition is
transitioned as the size of ms s for m
star is at least t minus the size of
corrupted party
and this is a notion uh so this security
is considered by a few prior works
and so then the next question is uh do
we go even stronger
so um to answer this we have to thinking
about like what is missing in this tsu
f1
and it's turned out that
the over 3
it's actually possible in this tsuf1
setting to
um
to combine different partial signatures
plus message m star but from different l
rack
and it's natural that uh together we to
root out these
um so this uh
this lets to define securities beyond
the tsuf1
um so our first
and
another
meaning notion called rss
so it was similar to mss but it's
defined for each individual
leader request instead of the message
so intuitively this means the set of
only signer that answered the lrac
and now um so the next security level
defined is called tsuf2
and it's defined as the
so a message signature pair is
considered trivial if and only if the
existing leader requests such that
uh leader requests for message m
and it was answered
by a number of honest signers that is
least
t minus the size of corrupt parties
and intuitively this
this will like rule out the possibility
to combine different
partial signatures from different lraps
and from this we can go all the way to
the top of our security hierarchy
which we call tsuf4 where the difference
from tsuf2 is that now the rss for l
rack is required to be all the only
signers
that is supposed to be query so in other
words so this security guarantees that
as um so inversely uh can um
when it makes curry to erect they have
to
um send queries to all
the uh
or the only signer that is supposed to
be sending together signature
and
the highest to consider
and we also consider uh about like
stronger affordability in this work
so for
which is analogous to the strong
affordability for a signature scheme
so for signature schemes
the stronger forgivability is defined as
um
um so the
so anniversary
get the signature from a signer
um even if you get a signature for
message m it is not possible for it to
forge
a different signature for n
however find it it's not easy to
define it for stressful signature
because now
we have a partial signature instead of a
thing a real signature sent by signer so
it was unclear which signature is
actually being issued
therefore
we have to reach
so we'll restrict ourselves to a special
class of
schemes which has determination
which means that
for each public key and the leader
request there is a unique message and
signifier that is supposed to be
issued if all the parties
follow are
protocol
and we denote this map by phi
notice here that this n must be equal to
the leader uh the method containing a
leader request
and also note that it does not mean that
the signature have to be deterministic
have to be unique to each message things
like
this signature can be differed given a
different lrac
and the example for schemes such as
schemes including frost one and two
and with the help of this five function
we can define a stronger forgibility
version of the cross the tsuf2 and tsuf4
where the difference are the highlighted
part
um
and so uh in so in short like
so the
so it changed the
when you're tracking the so the
difference is that when you're tracking
the
uh
to your forgery condition you only check
you only check the leader request
such that it was direct exactly
corresponding to the output forgery
now here's the full picture of
our
uh our security hierarchy
um
so the arrow from the a to b represents
the security a implies b
so i will now briefly mention the
the result we're getting based on this
hierarchy
the first will show a loose reduction
from a tsuf0 to psuf1 with a factor of
n choose t
yeah
and uh for bls we show um that it is tsc
uf one secure but not here you have two
and this is showed uh
the security is proved under the
pvc dh assumption with the new
assumption we proposed in the random
oracle model
and for us one for frost one we show
that
it is tsuf3 secure but not here yes you
have four sig
and for frost two it showed is ps as you
have two secure but not yes you have
three secure
um so from this you can see a separation
from the security of frost one and two
and we proved their security under the
one multilog assumption in the random
oracle model
so note here that all previous work for
os and frostic only consider psu of zero
security
and finally we also show a general
transformation from ts
from the third level security to the
force level security
uh so
finally i would like to
give you
uh some brief intuition about the
separation between the frost one and two
so let's consider the following
anniversary for frost two
so in the setting there is a
four signers
and the threshold is three
so
then the anniversary first crop the
parties three and four
sorry the sign is three and four and it
makes two queries to the p uh pp oracle
and getting the
tokens for diner one and token was
signed at 2.
then it created a leader request with a
message m star and the designated signer
is one two and three
and then it sets the for the token part
it sets the
token for
party one and two honestly
but
he sent set a token for
party three in the malicious way such
that it can and only need to make one
query to
assign a one to get a valid signature
so why this is interesting
well we find that this attack is not
possible for frost one so for first one
it was perhaps the query both sine of
one and sine of two
and in general it's uh required that
uh it to make queries to all the honest
signers that
who says tokens are honestly sad
so
this uh subtotal
security consideration actually leads us
to define the psuf3 secure which is
satisfied by frost one but not cross two
and to conclude uh here's
a few highlights of the main
contribution of this work and for the
future work it's interesting
to know that what are the applications
for each of our security level
and other interesting questions include
like how to add adaptive security or how
to consider the uc models
and also uh they're possible to also
capture the general dkg protocol in this
framework
so that's
yeah that's all for the talk thank you
thank you for this
hello yeah please go ahead hello uh
thank you for the nice talk i wanted to
ask with respect to
the future work adaptive security do you
have any intuition on whether you may be
able to do it with the current number of
rounds
or whether you might have to increase
the number of rounds to have an
adaptively secure protocol
uh
yeah thanks for the question um yeah
we're we we're not like yeah we're not
like doing
yeah have many results on adapted now
uh and i
uh i think yeah it was hard to prove the
like frauds have adapted security for
now because of like um
in the standard like i'm proving the
standard model and you need the
windings and then you
you cannot yeah so the there are some
technical difficulties there
thanks for the nice talk so i have a
question about the first two so you can
understand correctly your optimization
relates to
random questions or
aggregating the random nonsense
um in that case like is it okay to
derive the random quotient by hashing
the product of rs and s or do you need
to
hash all these separately that's a good
question um so because we introduced
this intermediate assumption the by
schnorr assumption
um you actually need to have all of the
nonces be separate i should note though
that this isn't necessarily the case if
you consider the multi-sig version of
this then you can actually do the
combination
okay thank you that's very interesting
thank you
yeah um thank you very much for the talk
i i just wanted to ask it looked like
from some of the like between your
security levels the separation was like
oh and this one it's enough to get
um
like
answers for this please sign this
message corey for this lrec but then for
other ones you needed them all to answer
like the same specific lrex so the
adversary couldn't append for like the
servers that he knows like the partial
key couldn't append
um his signatures the signatures he got
from the honest player i didn't
understand the significance of this
since the adversary can like send any l
wreck so he can send the same l wreck to
himself
and then hence sign also i i think i
missed level three
i only saw levels one two and four
yeah oh yeah sorry uh we yeah i accept
the
uh the the level three yeah because it's
more technical
and for the
yeah for the question of yeah so the
signing you mean like the university can
choose the l rack itself so like it's
like
you can so you can choose that rack so
like in include all the property party
has is that what you're right so he can
he can send the same l wreck to himself
that he just sent to them to the honest
players and got the answer for and then
he can append so i didn't see like the
separation
and uh yeah i see so so
um it prevents some attack like so
diversity they don't actually
do this so they they send different
l-rack to different party
um for some reason so and then like we
want to like show that it's not possible
like you just you just send like like
different erect to just each one of them
and then like each one they just feel
they just receive one but they're not
um
yeah so it basically prevents there's
some there's some basically it prevents
adversary from like um being favorable
with respect to its lrx like there's
some attack that it prevents and we can
take this later yeah
thank you guys very much for the talk
thanks
so let's uh thank the speakers again
the next and the last talk in this
session is threshold signatures with
private accountability
by chelsea acomolo and then bonnie and
chelsea will give the talk
once the slides are there
all right you're good to go
okay uh hi everyone i'm chelsea comlow
and i'm here to present joint work with
dan bonet uh and this work is on private
signatures or threshold signatures with
private accountability uh and our eprint
is coming soon so
uh watch out for that
so we just looked at threshold
signatures in the past talk um so i'll
just recap them briefly just in case you
forgot so what a threshold signature
scheme is is it's a public private
scheme
where you have some secret key that's
partitioned among the set of parties
and so here we look at a two out of
three scheme there's three total parties
um
and then the threshold in the scheme is
is two
and um here the public key uh represents
the entire group so here we have one
single public key and then uh private
keys shared amongst all these parties
and to sign um
you
basically have a message coming in and
then each of the signers sends a
signature share
to the combiner and so what's important
here is that out of the three total
parties um two of these parties are
required to send signature shares
and then the combiner outputs a
signature that represents the group
and what's nice about these types of
schemes is that
when participants perform signing
they're not actually sending secret key
material uh over the wire to each other
and so um what's nice is that secret key
material stays local and they can really
use like generally like public but
authenticated channels in order to send
uh
or to communicate with each other when
performing this protocol
so looking at the literature um there
what this is something that we formalize
in our work
but there's actually two types of what
are actually mutually exclusive
threshold schemes uh in the literature
today
so the first type of threshold scheme in
the literature is what we call a private
threshold scheme or pts and we'll look
at next what privacy actually means but
just keep in your mind this is sort of
one category of threshold scheme
and then the second category is
an accountable threshold scheme and we
refer to this as an ats
and in the literature you can also think
about these as um
accountable subgroup multi-signatures so
that's sort of the name that's been
given to them in the literature but we
call these ats's really for symmetry
so what do you you might say like okay
pts versus ats how do these actually
differ
so with the pts um
there's or with each of these schemes
there's two types of information that we
care about the first type of information
is the signer quorum and the second type
of information is the threshold
so uh really the way that these schemes
differ is what information is exposed to
who
so for pts on the signing forum uh is
not learned either by the public so
someone who isn't allowed to participate
in the signing scheme
or signers so looking at a signature
after it's been published you can't see
who participated in that signing
operation
and then for the threshold looking at a
signature after it's been published the
public also doesn't learn the threshold
but if you're a signer you trivially
learn the threshold just by
participating in the signing protocol
for an ats all this information is
learned by everyone so once the
signature's been published you're able
to kind of learn everything um whether
or not you're allowed to be a signer or
not
and so really uh what we do in this work
our major contribution is we introduce
what we call a taps and this is a new
type of threshold signature so i want to
emphasize that um this is kind of a new
primitive to the threshold signature
scheme literature
and you might say okay what is the taps
well
uh it's really like combining these two
notions so we talked about privacy and
accountability and what etaps does is it
allows for both of these notions to be
achieved
so like a pts um
for a taps the public does not learn the
signing forum or the threshold so to the
public a taps looks exactly like a pts
but like in ats the signing forum can be
recovered by a designated entity
so essentially the differentiator here
is that if you're a designated entity
you can participate in what is
essentially an ats but if you're not
everything else looks like a pts
and you might say like okay this looks
like magical cryptography why do we care
about this
and this is actually very useful if
you're say a financial institution and
you share secret signing material with
your clients um your client might come
and say like hey you participated in
sending all my funds away and like i
didn't get to participate in that so
please give me my money back
with the taps you're actually able to
prove or disprove that you participated
in issuing these signatures without
revealing uh more information publicly
and something that i think is really
interesting about atops is that um we're
actually able to achieve a notion of
post-compromise accountability that
hasn't been able to be achieved in the
literature before
so in threshold schemes in the past
really the threat model has considered
the adversary being able to compromise
up to a threshold number of signers and
after that you generally just sort of
consider threshold schemes to be broken
so after an adversary controls this many
number of parties
uh all security properties are lost
and so here like we can't prevent
unforgeability if more than a threshold
number of parties has been corrupted but
we can provide a notion of
post-compromise accountability so even
though maybe some bad behaviors happened
and adversary control's more than a
threshold you can at least go and
identify later uh what has happened and
so i think that's kind of
um a key distinction of the taps that
makes it useful in practice
so driving home how it taps
relates to a threshold signature again
we have our two out of three parties a
message comes in your signers send the
signature shares to the combiner and the
combiner outputs a signature
but
um here this in the tops the combiner
also provides a proof that t signers
signed and we'll look at how this proof
is actually produced later
then
the signature can be input into this
tracer which is our designated entity
and the tracer is then able to output
which parties participated
but again this tracer is our designated
entity and so no one else is able to
produce this information
so this is sort of writ large on how a
taps augments a threshold signature
scheme
and if you're familiar with
sort of multi-party signatures in the
literature you can think of a taps as a
generalization of a group signature so a
group signature really allows for this
these same properties but only with one
signer and so what a taps does is it
takes that and it allows for more than
one signer
so a little bit more formally when we
think about attacks we think about these
five algorithms so a key gen sign
combine verify and trace algorithms
and we say that a taps must be secure so
it has to be unforgivable it has to be
private and accountable so let's look at
what that means next
i guess looking a little bit more
closely at these algorithms
so again like a threshold signature
keygen will output the public key it
will output secret keys for each of the
participants
but then a little bit differently output
secret keys for both the combiner and
for the tracer so uh these secret keys
for combiner and tracer is what is
different from a lot of threshold
schemes you might have seen before
and while i show this here in a
centralized manner this could also be
performed in a distributed manner as
well
sine looks exactly like you'd expect in
a threshold scheme so it takes message
the secret key for the participant and a
coalition of signers
and outputs a partial signature for that
participant
combine takes the secret key for the
combiner the message the coalition of
signers and those signature shares and
it outputs the tap signature so it
really takes all of the partial
signatures and outputs the tap signature
for the
public verify is exactly as you'd expect
for threshold signature so it takes the
signature public k message now puts a
bit indicating if it's valid or not
and then trace takes a secret key for
the tracer so this is what um makes the
tracer a designated entity
the message and the tap signature and
either outputs the coalition of signers
or failure
um so this is sort of
what takes this tap signature and it
says who participated in signing
right so now we're going to look at um
the security properties for tops so i
said that attacks has to be unforgeable
private and accountable so let's look at
unforgeability and accountability next
so for unforgiability what we mean by
this is that an adversary cannot output
a valid signature
without controlling
or if they control fewer than a
threshold number of parties so this is
the same unforgeability notion that we
learned about in the prior talk and so
this is basically the same sort of base
notion of unforgiability you'd consider
for a threshold signature
for accountability what's interesting
here is we actually don't put
a restriction on the number of parties
that the adversary is able to control
um so for accountability all we say is
that the adversary can't output a valid
signature that traces to an honest
non-signer
so the adversary here can control more
than a threshold number of parties this
is what gets us that kind of
post-compromise
accountability
but we say that even if they are in that
setting they can't frame someone as
having signed that didn't actually
assign
so a little bit more formally for our
enforceability and accountability games
as we have our adversary and our
environment
and the adversary begins by choosing the
number of total parties the threshold
and the number of parties that it wants
to corrupt
and in return it re receives the public
key and the secret key is for all of the
parties that it chooses to corrupt
it's able to query for partial
signatures of any parties that it
chooses
so it can say i want a partial signature
for any of these end parties
and at the end it's required to output
some valid taps signature with respect
to a message
and what's interesting is here um we're
actually encoding both the
unforgeability and the accountability
games
so there's two win conditions that can
occur
so
um an adversary wins if it meets either
of these conditions
so the first condition is if the
adversary produces a valid signature and
it controls fewer than the threshold
number of parties so this is our
unforgiability setting
it outputs a valid signature that traces
to an honest non-signer this is the
accountability setting
so really what changes here is um the
the set c that the adversary designates
and we say that a tax is unfortunate
unforgivable and accountable if the
probability of it wins is negligible
so i think that's kind of uh what's neat
in in this game is that really the key
difference is the number of parties that
the adversary controls
so for privacy we actually um
sort of split privacy into two different
notions
so first we refer to privacy against the
public and this is for any entity that
um
isn't a valid signer so again as we
talked about before a tap signature is
considered private against the public
if they're not able to learn either the
threshold or the form of signers
and then we then
sort of go a bit more strongly and we
say that there's this notion of privacy
against signers so these are entities
that are allowed to
hold
secret key shares
and we say even if you're allowed to
participate in signing looking at the
top signature it shouldn't reveal
anything about who participated in
signing
so again looking at these games for the
privacy against the public game
the adversary here is again able to
choose the total number of parties but
here it chooses two different thresholds
so t zero and t one
um and then key gen is performed with
respect to some challenge uh
one of these two thresholds uh chosen at
random so this bit b is chosen at random
and then uh keygen is performed with
respect to tb
the adversary receives the public key
and then it's able to query uh
sorry i'll go through this a little bit
more so it's able to query um four tap
signatures that's the output of the
combined algorithm
um but again it provides two different
coalitions so c0 is a coalition that is
with respect to t0 and c1 is with
respect to t1
and it receives a tap signature that is
with respect to cb
so it's with respect to either one of
these uh coalitions which one the
adversary does not actually know
and then it's also allowed to query the
tracing oracle
um at the end outputs a bit b which is
its guess
and so we do put a restriction on this
game where the adversary can't query the
tracing oracle for anything that it
received uh from the combine oracle and
that's just to prevent a trivial one
and
yeah so basically uh this is a
distinguishing game so the adversary
wins if it's able to guess b correctly
um and if if it guesses b correctly then
it it's able and reliably it's able to
gain some information about the
threshold
and we say that taps is private against
the public if the probability that it
wins is negligible
so then
we
encode
the notion of privacy against signers
so here the adversary again chooses nnt
it doesn't choose a challenge
and what's interesting about this game
is it actually receives all of the end
signing keys
so this actually probably looks quite
different from a lot of the threshold
security games you've seen in the past
so it actually receives all of this
information
again it's able to query for
a tap signature with respect again to
either of these two coalitions
and again it's able to query the tracing
oracle
and it uh outputs a guess
b prime at the end
and we have the same restriction where
it can't query the tracing oracle with
outputs from combined again to prevent
the trivial one case
and um we say that adversary wins if
it's able to reliably guess b prime
which means that it can infer some kind
of information about the quorum of
signers
and so we say taxes private if the
probability that it wins is negligible
so i think what's what's interesting in
these two games is um they're
distinguishing games and the public game
the adversary is able to guess the
threshold or it's able to provide the
threshold and it must distinguish which
one is used
here um it's able to provide the
coalition the coalitions and it must get
guess which coalition is used but it
also is given the secret keys for all of
the signers um
and that's that looks a little bit
different than probably things you've
seen in the threshold literature in the
past
okay so um those are security notions we
then provide a generic taps construction
so what the generic taps construction
does is it um essentially
encrypts an ats signature and then it
proves in generic zero knowledge that
this encrypted ats signature is valid
so um again sort of referring what ats
is is it's an accountable threshold
scheme so just by looking at a plain ats
signature you should be able to see
who's signed
but here for the generic construction
what we do is we encrypt it and then we
prove in generic zero knowledge that
this uh signature is valid
and this um encrypted ats signature is
encrypted to the tracer so because the
tracer has a secret key it's able to
decrypt and therefore recover uh the set
of signers
uh and then on the threshold is we don't
reveal the threshold in the clear the
threshold is provided in the public key
simply as a commitment
and so again this generic zero knowledge
proof is able to prove that this ats is
valid it has
the proper set of signers with respect
to the public key where the threshold is
committed to
so um driving into this a little bit
more so what a generic taps signature
looks like
is again it has this public key
encryption of the ats signature
it has a zero knowledge proof that the
ats signature is valid
um and then we also require that the
combiner
um
authenticates this tap signature and
that's because we allow the adversary to
have access to this tracing oracle in
all of these games
so in order to
prevent different kinds of attacks we
require that the combiner does
authenticate this signature
so then
after we designed this generic scheme
what we wanted to do is we wanted to
provide a snore construction
so um
in looking at this though we actually
came up against some challenges
so the generic scheme requires proving
that the signature is valid in generic
zero knowledge
but schnorr requires proving that the
output from a hash function is derived
correctly
so in schnoor as we'll look at in the
next slide i the verifier derives um the
challenge
which is itself a hash of the commitment
and the message and this is expensive to
do in generic zero knowledge
so
in looking at this we actually had the
goal of finding a simpler more efficient
solution
uh and happily we were able to do so so
first i'm going to re-explain a little
bit about the structure of schnorr
signatures
so um if you recall schmore signatures
uh they're a tuple
of two elements the first element is a
commitment to a nonce
so this r value is a commitment to
randomness that's used during the
signing protocol
and then the second element is the
response so this is the the proof that
um the signer sign using their secret
key with respect to a message
um
where there's randomness that was
committed to in r
and then in shore like i said before the
verifier derives the challenge which is
the hash of
uh the commitment and the message and
then they check um that the response is
valid with respect to the public key the
challenge and this commitment
so um we actually had this insight which
is very simple but actually quite
powerful and allows um everything else
to sort of follow quite simply
and so our insight is that publishing uh
this commitment in the clear doesn't
actually hurt privacy so only publishing
the response or only the response must
be protected
um so once we have this insight we're
like oh we can actually publish r we can
deviate from the generic construction uh
creating this schnorr taps became much
simpler
so uh our snoretaps deviates a little
bit from our engineering construction
where we additionally publish this
commitment and what that allows for is
improved efficiency and simplicity over
the generic construction
and so the verifier drives uh the
challenge directly
so
i'm going to show you the zero knowledge
relation now very quickly you don't need
to understand all this math but uh the
reason why i'm showing you is because um
it sort of drives home the fact that in
our short construction we're able to get
something which is actually quite simple
for the zero knowledge relation
so um the statement and our schnartops
we have the generators
we have a commitment on to the threshold
t which is just elgamal
we have the schnorr commitment
fishner challenge
the encrypted ats or
the encrypted ats signature
and then for the witness we simply have
randomizers along with um
uh
the ats response
and bits indicating which sign are
signed
so then our relation is very simple so
first it proves that the response is
valid for a subset of public keys
so what it does is this response is in
the witness so it says for some uh
subset of public keys
at least t of them
this response must be valid
it then proves that the ciphertext of
this ats is valid and it's a valid
encryption to the tracer's public key
it then proves that the signing form
contains key signers
and then
for completeness it proves that each of
the bits are zero or one so really what
these last two lines are is it's proving
that at least t sign or signed without
revealing what t actually is
so this is how we're able to achieve
proving that this ats signature
is valid without actually revealing what
the signature is or what the threshold
is so this is sort of all the magic in a
nutshell
um and the performance of our schnoor
taps is actually quite good
um it does grow linearly with respect to
the number of signers so in the public
key
for both
constructions that we give but
considering most instantiations of
threshold schemes
you know we're looking at two out of
three examples
so if the total number of signers is
three this is actually quite reasonable
um and then however when the total
number of signers is large
uh we do provide a bulletproof uh
instantiation so essentially the
difference is we provide a sigma
construction
where it's reasonable if the total
number of signers is small
if the total number of centers is large
you can use bulletproofs and
that means that the signature size
is remains quite reasonable
so overall what do we do in this work um
we
uh introduce a new type of threshold
signature scheme and we refer to this
threshold signature scheme as a taps
and what a tops does is it um
it ensures both privacy and
accountability of the signature
we define a generic construction uh that
employs an encrypted ats
and then we define a schnorr
construction that actually leverages the
structure of
signatures to simplify the
zero-knowledge relation
so we do provide a generic construction
but then we're able to do better in our
schnoor instantiation
and then we define both sigma and
bulletproof's instantiations of the zero
knowledge argument for our external
instantiation
and that's all so thank you very much
yes i had a secret key it did not have
the secret key
um
so yeah so i should have gone over this
a little bit more in detail so keygen
outputs secret keys for all of the
signers it outputs a secret key for the
combiner and a secret key for the tracer
so that secret key for the combiner just
allows it to authenticate on the tap
signatures that are output so it's not
the same secret key as what all of the
signers hold so
yeah so it can't
forge signatures it can't really do
anything that signers can do it's just
to allow authentication of the taps
so um it it depends a little bit so for
uh
actually quite a lot of um
at least some of the use cases i know of
uh signers are distributed but um the
proof for example if you're producing um
a more involved proof the prover is
actually one entity
so this is uh
for example in the z cash setting uh the
signers are distributed but the prover
that actually produces the snark
demonstrating that you know all these
you know relations that the merkle trees
past miracle trees valid um that's a
single entity so this kind of use case
actually fits very well in that setting
if you wanted to distribute the role of
the combiner you could also do that but
really here the combiner's
trusted
to aggregate signatures and not disclose
the privacy of the signers and and
that's it
so
hi
thanks for talking they asked a question
about the accountability definitions
that they prevent adversary to do the
signature that's uh
traced to strictly subsets strict subset
of designers so that some malicious
party can
sign without being translated because i
saw the definition only says that you
prevent someone the non-like
some someone that doesn't sign this
being traced but it doesn't prevent some
right
um
so let me just restate the question and
make sure i understand so
uh
accountability
means that
uh a dishonest party cannot frame
someone who did not participate in
signing but he doesn't prevent someone
that few times but like being entrees
later right it's possible that someone
died but he can he can prevent the
insurance
um that should yeah so if you look at
our our definition it it prevents
against that case i just didn't uh talk
about it very closely but yeah so
accountability means that you can't lie
about who participated in signing so you
can't frame
a signer but you also can't exclude
yourself so um if you look at our
definition tracing must be like exactly
tracy that's that assignment right yes
yes it considers that but yeah we can
talk more
um so
i was just trying to figure out when
you're talking about privacy from the
signers
it seems like unless you're doing some
extra blinding sort of thing um the
signers who participated know that they
were in on the on the forum they just
don't know who the other members of the
forum is is that the idea
so
right so this so privacy against signers
is it's a bit ambiguous so here
you're you're correct that if you
participated in signings
you'll know that you participated in
signing um that's sort of a different
notion we didn't know how to give that
notion a name so we don't actually
consider it and it also seems hard to
achieve that without
extra notions like
private channels and
um anonymity and like
additional things
um so yes this
doesn't prevent um
if you're a signer knowing that you
participated in signing of a particular
signature but you can't know who else
participated in simon right so if
if alice and bob both participated in
signing in a two of three scheme alice
knows she signed but she doesn't know
whether it was bob or carol who helped
right
um that's a little bit outside of what
so here we don't consider that because
um for example in sign it takes the
quorum of signers
in our algorithm so it would be it would
be a different scheme to not know what
other signers signed okay so i guess
what i'm trying to understand what's
what do what do you guarantee from the
signer privacy then because i don't i i
just realized i don't understand what
the what the definition is from the
signature looking at the signature you
can't extrapolate who signed
okay so i can still remember what
happened my own participation i just
can't look at a signature and say oh now
looking at that i know
art okay yeah so this actually it
depends we have a note on this um so
which signature scheme like this whole
remembering thing
um you it will influence um this
uh
signer privacy notion so like for
schnorr for example
if i participate in schwarz signature i
can look at the commit commitment later
and say like oh i participated in that
um you can have the combiner do some
kind of blinding step and we note that
as future work
um but yeah by this notion we just mean
looking strictly at the signature can
you explain information from that all
right thank you
um hey thanks for the talk hopefully a
brief question so everybody can go uh
just follow up on that question uh
because the key gen also generates like
a secret key for the combiner so like
this this scheme doesn't support the
generic thing that like you know there's
there's a big group of end potential
signers and then people would pat
different people would pass them
messages which they can examine decide
if they want to sign and then combine
right it's only that one combiner can
query those like n servers for
their
signature shares
right
let me rephrase the question to make
sure i understand uh so you're asking
like does this model
assume like anyone but the combiner can
query signers yeah um
so in our in our notions we assume that
adversary can
query so like in the unforgetability
game the adversary is querying for
signature shares
um so i think we do consider that notion
unforgeability and accountability
um but i'm happy to talk more yeah yeah
for sure yeah thank you thank you
so there are questions from
from the internet
so the first one is the following group
signature tracing openings normally
output a publicly checkable proof that
the tracing was correctly done do you
have something similar to this for tabs
do you consider the trace uh to always
be honest
um
here
right so here the the tracing algorithm
does output either
just the coalition uh there's no reason
why it couldn't also output the
um unencrypted
ats or depending on whatever model so i
think that it can be extended to that
setting we did not do that but
there's no reason why it couldn't be
okay and the second question
am i right that you couldn't do the zk
proof alongside the planche no sick
to have accountability on top of a plane
to norsic because you need to hide the s
um sorry
let me rephrase so the question is
asking that this your knowledge proof is
to ensure accountability for the
encrypted
uh
schnorr signature
is is that the question or
um it seems to me the question is
towards why you didn't do it exactly on
top of schnoor maybe the person online
can rephrase it quickly
okay so the reason why we didn't do it
on top of plain snorers because it's a
schnoor ats so looking at the plain
schnorr ats you can tell who signed so
we have to encrypt the schnorr ats in
order to hide in order to achieve
privacy and then in order to prove that
the signature is valid we have the zero
knowledge proof
did this answer the question online
hopefully
yeah he got it okay great
good thank you
people from the internet
let's thank chelsea again
thank you very much
yeah
that's it from us at the safe trip back
thank you