knowledge session um everyone the first
talk of the session
is
by tian singh
and it's going to be an orion a zero
knowledge proof with linear prover time
okay thanks chair for the introduction
and i'm teen chancellor from uc berkeley
and i'm going to present oriole
generally proof with linear approval
time this is joined to work with hong
jong and don soon
a general proof
enables approver to
prove some proof some validity of some
statement to the verifier without
nikki's own secret information
and
it mainly
satisfies these three properties
companies sadness and zero knowledge
the accompanies means that honest
proverb can always pass a verification
and soundness means that malicious
approval can only pass verification
with negligible probability
and zero knowledge means that the proof
itself does not need any information
about the secret
and generation proofs actually started
by
government mccarthy and rakov in 1985
and later is followed by kilian and
mikali for
generic
construction
and there are still many
following theoretical works
it's also some of them are also
presented here and since our paper is
mainly focused on a concrete
instantiation so
we will we will for the
rest of work uh the talk we will focus
on this
efficient uh general proof systems
and at 2018
there are many different uh general
proof systems based on bilinear pairing
proposed by these people
and
this works uh may one many focus on
concrete incidentations so they gotta
make out some
trusty setup and all of these works are
actually very fast in practice and some
of them are actually deployed in the
industry
more recently
there are different uh general more
different general proof systems based on
more techniques
such as iop
and
interactive roofs
or
code based proofs
and and npc-based proofs
so
these proofs mainly focus on removing
trusted setup
and have a better scalability of
approval
so what caused the such development of
generality poops
is mainly because there are some
many different
applications of zeolite foods
such
as the application scene
in blockchain it's called dkrobs mainly
focused on
making blockchain more scalable and more
private
and there are some there are many
different startup companies focusing on
these thicker roll-ups which are
spinning of evaluations
and there
still other uh
different
applications
we got
machine learning for
tk machine learning for inference
and technology proof for program
analysis for
secret programs
and more such as dk middle box for
network traffic analysis their call for
jquery oracles and so on
despite all of this the recent
developments however there are still
some challenges on approval overhead
we mainly categorize this
all of these protocols into three
different categories
and for the first one they are based on
fft where
the ffd itself
incurs and not going to blow up
and second category is based on
explanations mainly
multiscale experimentations and such
exponentiation will cause a logarithm
factor too
and there are another line of work where
it does not cause
any uber overhead if you assume that aes
can be done in constant time however
they
they are they are mpc based and
their
proof size is actually linear and
they are not publicly verifiable
there's another line of work where which
they can actually achieve succinct
and scalable proof
it started by the jonathan bruto as 2017
however this works actually they most of
them are theoretical results
and
only gls
21 is
concretely instant shape however this
part this this paper got a sunless
problem the sun is actually is uh one
over party it's not negligible
so
and there there is another line of work
is boolean circuit
which also achieve very efficient linear
time proving
and
however in our work we mainly focus on
arithmetic circuit so
we will continue on on this line of work
astronomical circuit work
and here is our result
so
we propose a new system called orion
and the the approval time is actually
linear here and we achieve
simultaneously we achieve a log square
of proof size
and our sun is improved from one
overpoly to all the way to a negligible
based on a new technique called new
sampling technique
and here is our list of
technical contributions
we
first we build a linear time encoder
bond error credit code based on expander
code
and all previous constructions are
either not practical
or they got a
very huge
non-negligible value probability and
later we build our efficient proof from
our new expander code
based on this uh
so-called
circuit
code switching technique
so
for the rest of the talk we are going to
talk about our technical details
first is the new linear timing codable
error coding code
and so the first question is
why why does xeron improve is related to
the linear timing codable linear uh
arrogant code
sorry why whether this
relative error connection code
so because there are many works
actually
did the following
the three phases first they prior parts
of witness into matrices
and then they use linear time sorry they
use error critical to encode this matrix
both row wise and column wise
and they have that may commit this
matrix using merkle tree
for for query i'm going to
i'm going to show you a query example
for for for query they are going to
first do a random linear combination on
this
row of uh code words
and they are going to check
different uh random columns of this code
words
so why does this work what does this
work because
the error current code got a distance
property
minimum minimum distance property such
that
for every two different
uh co valid code word that the minimum
distance is actually
uh constant so there are constant
fraction of them are different
for malicious prover if they only change
a few entries of the uh of the code so
they're going to get an
invalid aerocratic error code word so it
will be detected afterwards
and if they if the malicious approval
change a lot of them actually they may
convert it into another valid code
however
it may not be consistent with an initial
mercury commitment
so
either way the malicious approval will
be detected
using
based on the general property of the
error question code
so
and there are many
concrete instantiations of this error
correction code such as resumer code
however this resource code actually
requires fft so that's why
it's not scalable in our
case
fortunately
there are many different
uh instantiations of
aerocratic code that is linear timing
codable such as the the code proposed by
the spielman and zucchini shy
and grs plus
this this this arrogant code are all
expander-based codes and next i'm going
to introduce a definition of xmender and
how how does this code encode
so here is an example of
expanded graph
it's a bipartite graph and
all of this code following the following
simple diagram
where you just
for each outputting node you just sum up
the input
according to these edges
so
we conclude that the expander is first
bipartite graph
and it satisfy
some expansion property
for example in this example
if you select randomly select a subset
of
left nodes you're going to expand into a
much larger write node
right right set so
and there are many challenges to
construct this expander code
for example if you try to do some
explicit construction
there is actually a paper from
uh
20 20 20 uh 2002 it said however this
paper got some very large constant
actually two to the maybe 100
constant and this
they require
expander to be super large so the
parameters may not be practical at
all and then there is there is a random
expanded construction
however this random expanded
construction also got some problems
they
the probability of
sampling successfully sampling this
expander is actually
one minus one word party so you got a
failure probability to be manual protein
and
you cannot actually distinguish
uh whether we successfully sampled or
not so it's it's not it's very insecure
to directly use
random
random based
expander generations
to solve this issue we proposed a
new technique to distinguish
between
successfully generated expanders and
failed expanders
so our algorithm is based on the density
sub graph uh algorithm
uh which i will introduce you later why
we use this technique
so our algorithm can improve this random
sun is to
negligible suddenness
so
so now i'm going to introduce why are we
using density subgraph algorithm as our
black box so if you look at a correct
expander here
and you calculate the density it will be
9 over 3 plus 8 where 3 is the size of
left set and
right set is eight so the density
definition is actually number of ages
divided by number of nodes
and if you look at an incorrect expander
for example here
the number of node is actually much much
smaller because the expansion property
is not satisfied
so it will be 6 over 2 plus 3 and you
can notice that the density here is much
smaller than the density in the
incorrect expander
so
based on this intuition you you can
eventually you can find that if it's
actually an expander
you got
a threshold for the density
so if it is expanded the density must be
lower than this value and if it's not
the expander the density must be higher
than this value
so
you can actually distinguish whether
it's expanded or not of just by looking
at the density using using this
algorithm maximum density subgraph
algorithm
and this algorithm can be
can be implemented in
polynomial time it's actually very fast
in practice
and we actually implemented our
tester in
and the code is available on github
and there are some other technical
issues where i'm not i do not have time
to cover
so
there are still
in our paper it's not just trivial
expanders it's actually called nozzle
expander and
to
test this expander we need to
repeatedly subsample the data set
and test whether whether using use
tester whether
there is a dense graph using density
subgraph algorithm
and repeated repeated this process a
sufficient number of times it's actually
unknown times so
then we can conclude that this is a loss
examiner
and we use a rejection sampling to
sample this nozzles vendor
and since the
the original successful ability of if
random random sampling is already high
it's actually one minus one will
probably so the expected running time of
our algorithm
is constant
sorry
expected number of times is constant
yeah
so
now we have expand efficiently expander
and we can use this commander to
construct our linear error current code
so next i will introduce how to
construct a zone proof from this
expander code
plus there is another technique called
code switching from wrong
me remind you about how do we use
expander code to encode first you pass
the witness into a matrix matrix
then you encode the matrix using
expander code so this step will cost you
a linear number of operations due to
like
sorry the encode of the expander code
and this is a commit and encode step
next i will go to the verifying query
step
so
upon a query on
this random value r
you are going to answer this query so
the query is actually an inner product
query so you
you take
the coefficient of this matrix
and your inner product with this r
so this is a definition of y
and we got four different checks
so first check will be
you take a random uh you take a random
column and the inner product is r0
for this check you're going to
if you implement this check naively
you're going to need to transmit the
whole column of the matrix
and for the set for for this check you
are going to
transmit the whole row of the matrix so
basically so basically if you implement
all of these checks naively you are
going to get uh all square to and in
terms of proof size because you need to
at least transmit one row and one column
of the matrix
the cost of the verification is
not satisfiable but fortunately we got
the code switching technique
and
the code switching technique is
you will notice that this is on this old
script file in terms of the instance
size so you can actually recursively
feed the instance into another
genre-proof system based on maybe
realism code
since the size of a
size of the problem is only square
different you can actually
use an organ technique from here
so
you
construct the circuit using uh
the convex circuit here the input is a
message
and you pass it through an encoding
circuit and you finally get this row
sorry is corner
and you
simultaneously do an inner product
circuit
for example if we are doing check one
you can simultaneously your inner part
circuit here
and you got this result
however the output of this
circuit is still large because you still
got a lot of code words where the size
is square different
and you can
but you can you can reduce it by run by
adding a random selector
and you only select
nominal number of uh different entries
in this code world
why that is sufficient because it's an
arrogant code
aircraft code has a minimum distance
property ensures that
if it's it's inconsistent with code
it's the minimum distance between
this correct code and this malicious
code is
constant
sorry the
fraction
there are constant fraction of arrows in
this uh in
this committee rows so
if you randomly sample
number different entries the probability
you hit at least one
inconsistent entry is actually two to
the
minus number
so
you can just check randomly check a
subset of these entries and you get a
very high probability of catching
the malicious program
so after we apply this
the overall
communication complexity is actually log
square and dominated by this
recursive proof
and
now i'm going to show you some
experiments on the system
first is
our polynomial commitment
compared with breakdown
and
if you compare with breakdown we have
comparable prover time notice that
breakdown is grs plus 21 so it's a
reasonable work
and if you compare it with it we got
comparable proof time and our proof size
is actually
much much smaller than them because they
got square to them in terms of proof
size and we only got
a knock square
so there is more than 10 times
difference between our proof size
and for more
comprehensive
comparison in terms of general proof
systems we compare our system with
aurora liquor role and breakdown
and
our proof our proof is one of the
fastest proverbs here
order of magnitude faster than legal and
aurora
and our proof size is actually
uh here so
our proof size is still still much
smaller than other systems
because we got a polylog proof size
and that's all all from my talk
here's a summary so we construct our
system using linear time codable linear
code from expander
and we reduce our proof size from code
switching recursive proof
and here is the code here is our paper
and you can scan the qr code to get get
more information about me
and thank you
any question
[Applause]
we have time for one short question
so let me ask one question so it seems
that your bipartite
graph testing technique is pretty
general so i was
your expander graph technique testing
technique is pretty general so i was
wondering if you plug it in in other
existing xeno knowledge proof systems
could you maybe quickly comment on how
data efficiency would improve
uh sir can repeat you
so i'm saying that your um
like your graph testing technique
um it seems pretty generic but it builds
general and it seems that you can plug
it in in other proof systems
yes um so i was wondering how would you
know if you could comment on how their
efficiency would improve
oh i see so
yeah we can
other so since proof systems are
actually
rely on a higher
higher level
description is actually relying on the
error cleaning code itself
so we can actually apply our aeroclink
code to other systems directly
yeah and we may need the code switching
too because if you directly apply our
graphing code
you need to
this error clean code does not have a
nice property such as multiplicative
property as
the resume code so you still need to do
some other modification modifications to
achieve
succinct proof sites such as
what we did in our paper is called code
switching
yeah
the speaker once again
so our next speaker is leonard brown
from university of oregon and he's going
to talk about efficient vector only and
zero knowledge blues
okay yeah thanks for coming welcome to
my talk on mozzarella uh this is joint
worked with carsten alex and peter or
from awesome university
so we are interested in zero knowledge
boost for arbitrary circuits in this
case arithmetic circuits for rings that
due to the k so the approver has some
input w and it wants to prove and
convince the verifier that
this w
uh fulfills this relation defined by the
circuit so that makes it circuit output
one
we want the usual security properties
such as soundness zero knowledge
completeness
and
the question why are we interested in
this setting that to decay
so we are talking about the numbers or
the integers modulo power of 2 with
normal additional multiplication
other protocols uh often work a lot of
time field but we choose to use this
ring instead
so on the positive side the rings edge
to the k map very well to the data types
register sizes in modern programming
languages and cpus
so that makes it easy to convert
existing programs
to
circuits that we can prove in zero
knowledge or it allows us to reason
about programs in a nicer way
and moreover the implementation can also
that we
get more efficient because we get
essentially reduction modular powers to
almost for free compared to
reduction modular prime
on the downside z2k is not a fiat so we
have zero divisors we can't divide by
any multiple of two and polynomials can
have lots of rules so it's not bounded
anymore by the degree
so that means unfortunately many common
tricks in protocol design don't work
anymore so we have to work around them
the protocols get less efficient the
proofs get more messy
so on one side that just okay is very
nice for the application
and maybe for the implementation but
it's not so nice for the cryptographer
nevertheless
we think it's quite worth it to look at
the setting
coming back to our proof we're using the
commit and proof paradigm where the
prover commits to the circuit inputs uh
some intermediate values in the circuit
and the output then proves that these
consistent error these commitments are
consistent with respect to the circuit
that is computed
and of course that the output commitment
is the desired value one in this case
we're using linearly homomorphic
commitments and this gives us already
zero knowledge for linear functions but
of course we want to have arbitrary
circuits so we combine this with a
multiplication check
given three commitments to values a b
and c we want to prove that the values
in these common commitments are indeed
fulfilled with relation a times b equals
c
so these two steps also correspond to
our contributions first we show how to
more efficiently instantiate the
commitments using vector only so that is
okay and then we give a more efficient
multiplication set a check in the
setting
so
in our zero knowledge setting we have a
designated verifier we have a linear
time proven verifier and also linear
communication in the circuit size now
main goal is that the overhead of
proving the circuit and zero knowledge
should be minimal compared to evaluating
this circuit and plain text
so both with respect to computation and
memory overhead so we want that
[Music]
it should be at lightweight as possible
so how does these commitments look like
if we had a large field then we can just
use information theoretic max over this
field to create these commitments
here the approver holds the value x and
the mac one of this value x whereas the
verifier has
the mac keys where delta is some global
random key and kx is a value specific
key so
due to this format we have
like a linear
homomorphic commitment scheme so we can
just add two commitments get a new one
scale it by constant etc
this method has been used in prior work
for example in mac and cheese then
glassy crypto or in wolverine
and that to decay it's a bit more tricky
we have to
go
go to a larger ring that 2 to the k plus
s
where s depends on the security
parameter
this is due to
we having zero divisors and if we
multiply something by an even number
bits would be cut off and that's bad for
security so we need to work in this
ladder ring but other than that
most of
the the commitments work still the same
note that here we have x tilde as a
representative of x so that
it agrees with x on the lower k bits but
we don't really care what's up in the
other bits
so how do we get these commitments we
use vector oblivious linear evaluation
or vector only
which is a functionality a kind of a
generalization of oblivious transfer
here the prover inputs the value vector
x and the verifier which is like the
receiver and the vector lead particle
inputs a scalar delta and another vector
k
and then the sender which is the
approval gets the mac vector out of it
we can also
look at a slightly different variant
where all these values are sampled
uniformly at random by the functionality
and then we get the chosen input or the
standard chosen input variant just by
sending some correction values
note that here delta is chosen from a
set
that two to the s where s is again
security parameter but the other values
are live in a larger ring
so this how to realize the functionality
is the first part of our paper
and
in the history there are a couple of
different options how you could do this
one thing would be to use oblivious
transfer or homomorphic encryption but
then that would give us a communication
at least in a linear and the length of
the output vector
and with oblivious transfer we would
also need
quadratic communication in the bit size
because we need one ot per bit of the
scalar data
and every ot has like vector size bits
so um
another line of work uses pseudo-random
correlation generators which is defined
for for arbitrary
correlations and there two or more
parties come together and
create a short
seat which then later on can be
non-interactively expanded to a long
correlation
and the important thing here is that the
communication cost is sublinear and the
output vector size
and many of these constructions are
based on the learning parakeet as noise
assumption
however active security for vectoral pcg
pcgs have only achieved a field so far
if you don't consider like generic
multi-party computation approaches
therefore in this work we present an
actively secure vector or e-particle for
the that 2k setting with sublinear
communication
let's take a look at the lpn assumption
so the idea is that we take a short
uniformly random seed then we expand the
siege or encode the seed with the
generating matrix of a random linear
code
we add some sparse error vector on top
where in our case this error vector is a
regular error so it consists of several
blocks and every block has a single
nonzero error
value so this whole thing should look
uniformly random like a long uniformly
written vector given that the random
matrix is public
so this lpn assumption has been studied
for quite a while and it's mostly used
for either
bits or larger fields but here we
consider it over rings that should decay
now how can we use it to
expand a short vector e correlation to a
much longer one
so assume we have a short correlation
let's say we use the t based protocol to
generate this
the costs don't matter that much because
we only have to do it once
so they say we have m of these c
factorials
here in the blue
vector
then we need to generate some this noise
vector so we run a so-called single
point vector e-protocol on smaller sizes
a couple of times one times for each
block in our error vector
and single point vector only means that
the value vector has a signal nonzero
coordinates
so this corresponds to the error in the
rpn
and then by linearity we can apply the
generating matrix add the error on top
and we get a long vectory correlation
out of it and by the lpn assumption this
looks uniformly random
now we need even more vector release we
can just
use up to m uh
of these or
we need to save m of these and then we
can just repeat the process
as long as we want essentially
so this paradigm has been used in recent
works for example in wolverine
and we are also using the
wolverine protocol as a starting point
to
build our single point vectorly for that
to decay
because the single point actually is
really the crucial thing in this whole
expansion step because here we have
actually the output size of the whole
vector like n
and we want to realize this without
having to communicate as much so
essentially we only want to
as a communication cost to depend on the
number of error code units plus maybe
some logarithmic factor in the output
so now like a quick overview how such a
single point vector e protocol can work
so
again we want to have this relation w
equals delta times u plus v where u has
a single non-zero entry beta at position
up
so if we want to distribute some long
random value we usually would use a prg
or prf
now we have two vectors that are almost
the same they differ in only one
variable
so we use a punctured prf here
we can use a build a punctual prf
following the gegm paradigm
um that means we have a short or we have
a normal seat which is the prf key we
have a length doubling
prg and then we can expand the seat in a
two device version
and every path in this tree corresponds
to one evaluation of this prf
now we want to have a puncture pf that
means
whoever gets the puncture p should be
able to evaluate this prf at all
pointless one but one so we want to
remove one of these paths in the tree
and
we can do this by giving this evaluating
party these blue nodes which allows it
to compute all the nodes below them so
that means all the prf outputs except
the punctuation point
um we can realize this by using
oblivious transfer like one ot per level
corresponding to whether this red path
in the tree goes to the left or to the
right
so in our protocol the receiver samples
a prf key then both of them
are torque via updated transfer so that
the sender
selects the punctured prf key at a
position alpha but the receiver does not
burn out
so this can be already used to
define the whole output of the receiver
so we just take v as the output of the
prf for the indices and w is the same
except for position w alpha
so there's one step missing we need to
set this w alpha correctly
here we use another base vector only so
like a previously generated fully and
then the receiver can just send a
correction value that depends on all the
values
vj and the sender just
oh this allows the sender to compute the
missing value uh wife
and this is basically the passively
secure variant of this single point
vector v protocol
however a malicious receiver could
attack in two ways it could
feed inconsistent inputs to the ots
which makes this tree inconsistent and
dependent on what index the standard
shows and that can also send garbage for
this value data
and since both of these values are used
depending on the coordinate alpha that
should be secret
this can lead to leakage later on on the
noise coordinates in the lpn which in
turn could help the approver to solve
the the lpn problem with a higher
probability so we need to prevent both
of these attacks
prior work
such as wolverine uses a
random linear combination in their large
field
to
catch both ways to cheat at once but
random linear combinations over that to
decay are tricky because we again would
have to enlarge the ring by at least as
bits to ensure consistency of the lower
splits
so one iteration that would be fine but
if we want to
iterate this vector the expansion
protocol uh again and again then we
would have to start with a really large
ring that shrinks a bit in every
iteration
so that's a bit annoying so we chose a
different approach
first we use the universal hashing base
trick to ensure consistency of the gtm
tree following like a similar trick from
boiler down
so we add another layer to the gdm tree
now all the left leaves will be our
outputs as before but all the right
leaves we will feed into a hash function
that the sender selects
and the verifier just responds to the
hash and this
makes sure that it cannot
create an inconsistent tree
so
this
prevents attacks against the gtm tree
and for the
second attack vector for the d we use a
binary linear combination after all
however binary coefficients well you can
guess a single coefficient with
probability one half
and if the
malicious receiver guesses the
coefficient k alpha then it can be
effectively bypasses check
we say okay this is fine but
we compensate
for this potential leakage by increasing
the overall noise rate
so our
well ideal single point vectoring
functionality is not not as ideal as we
would like but we can compensate for
this leakage
okay how can we
use this vectorly to
or how can we use these commitments that
we just created to get zero knowledge to
arbitrary circuits
so this check
we call quark silver it is based on a
prior work quicksilver and to remind you
of what we want to do we have three
commitments a b and c and we want to
verify that a times b equals c
so the authors of quicksilver observed
that if you take the mac equations
multiply them in a in a clever way then
you get an equation that is quadratic in
the
in the
verifiers key delta
and here on the slide all the blue
values are known by the provers and the
green values are known by the verifier
and
what is important
if the proof is honest then this first
coefficient here like the coefficient of
data squared should be 0 because then c
is equal to a times b
however if it tries to
do something fishy then this might be a
nonzero value so we have a quadratic
equation otherwise it's linear
so
in a normal way the approver would just
send these first two values to the
verifier and then the verifier checks
this equation
and if we want to check multiple
multiplications in a batch we can use
the random linear combination which is
fine in this way because we don't have
to like repeat it over and over
so what if the proverb tries to cheat
well essentially cheating corresponds to
choosing a quadratic polynomial but the
first coefficient is the the error that
is induced here so it has to be non-zero
modulo 2 to the k
and now the check passes if this
polynomial has a root at position delta
since
delta comes from a very large set this
should be very unlikely because the
approver doesn't know anything about
data
and yeah as i said the polynomial has
degree two if the approver tries to
cheat
over the field everything is fine we can
say p has at most two roots so soundness
arrow is
2 over q
which is still negligible
however in a ring we can have many more
roots so
in this particular setting we bounded
the root number of roots by something
like 2 to the k
2 to the s over 2. so the square root of
all the possible values can be roots in
the worst case
hence we need to
use a larger ring overall and then we
end up with something like 2 to the k
plus 2 s plus 2 log s plus 3.
but overall this is still better than
previous solutions
um yeah we have to do it with it i guess
before i summarize i want to
leave a few words about the performance
so we implemented
this uh both protocols and the swanky
npc framework and for like 64-bit
arithmetic 64-bit integers you need to
work over
a
162-bit ring
to
ensure that you get
40 bits of statistical security
so for large batches and land setting we
can
generate roughly 20 million vectors per
second and then for each vector e we
have to send about a single
this gives us a performance very similar
to wolverine which did essentially the
same work over fields
for the quad silver zero knowledge
protocols we have to send one single
ring element of this larger ring per
multiplication because we have to commit
to the output of the multiplication
and this gives us a performance of about
1.3 million multiplications that we can
check per second
if we take a look at what performance
the quicksilver offers achieve then
their number is about five times larger
but they they have i think a prime
of size 61 bits
which means you can't really uh emulate
64-bit arithmetic so if you have two
arbitrary 64-bit numbers the result will
be 128 bits and then you would have to
do the reduction
so to emulate this kind of arithmetic
you would have to
use a larger prime which in turn leads
to more communication and
more
expensive arithmetic as we already have
in our z2k ring
in contrast to them we don't have to
care about material reduction modulo 2
to the 64. it's just
built in
natively
okay to summarize we constructed an
efficient and practical vector e
protocol which which acted with active
security and sublinear communication and
we only have to send back a single bit
or a bit more depending on the
parameters
moreover we have a new check for
a verifying
multiplications module that to decay
and
there we only need to send a single ring
element per multiplications
but we have still some open questions
for example
this larger wing we have to work in can
we reduce the overhead
of
the ring size compared to the cables
we're actually interested in
depending on the protocol
we have to work in larger or smaller
rings but we always have this kind of
overhead
then many recent protocols for fields
use that fancy polynomial tricks or use
some some code properties but all these
or many of these techniques don't work
anymore for rings so can we get
something similar efficient in the 2k
setting
so if you're interested in more of
mozzarella take a look at our full
version or ask us now or later
and yeah thanks that was it for me
are there any questions
if there are no questions let's thank
the speaker again
alright so the next talk is by abraham
kothapali from cmu
on nova recursive zero knowledge
arguments from folding systems
for a new notion known as folding
schemes oh that's that's better um yeah
and this is joint work with trina seti
and iana ziela
okay so our goal is to design practical
zk snarks for recursive computation and
what i mean by this is that we want to
design a succinct non-interactive
argument of knowledge that allows us to
prove that a non-deterministic function
f applied n times to some initial input
z zero results in some output c n and i
say non-deterministic because we want to
allow f to take additional witnesses
along the way
now this can be instantiated to
derive various cryptographic
applications and primitives right
so by just by instantiating f correctly
we can derive verifiable delay functions
we can derive zero knowledge verifiable
virtual machines and we can even derive
zika roll-ups which allow us to prove
that many transactions to a blockchain
are have been updated correctly
now i hope with these applications i
sort of intuit that we no longer really
care only about the theoretical
properties of recursive proof systems we
also care about how useful they are in
practice and how fast we can get them to
be for real world applications
now you might think okay well there
seems to be a naive approach here right
well we can just take the function f
apply it to itself uh n times throw it
all into an arithmetic circuit and then
just prove that unrolled statement using
your favorite snark okay
while this approach nominally works the
key issue is that this fixes and ahead
of time which means that for certain
applications like virtual machines where
the number of recursive iterations might
actually depend on the input program
this actually will not work and moreover
if we can somehow make it work we still
have that the approver memory and the
verifier pre-processing time are
dependent on n and depending on the
start that we're using we might even
have a situation in which the verifier
time depends on n
so to get around these issues back in
2008 valiant introduces this notion of
incrementally verifiable computation
the core idea of incrementally
verifiable computation
is that well we can write a proof for a
single iteration of f but then later
come back and very cheaply update this
proof over time as we keep incrementing
the applications of f okay
and the core challenges of ibc are that
well we want to be able to arbitrarily
increment as many times as we want and
this allows us to recurse indefinitely
and the second core challenge is we
actually want to make sure that these
proofs don't grow in size as we keep
going okay and these two challenges make
ivc a difficult primitive to achieve
both in theory and in practice
so nova is a built zk snark for
recursive computation which uses ibc as
a core building block so specifically
what we do is that we design a very
efficient implementation of ibc using
this new notion of folding schemes okay
so specifically at a very high level a
folding scheme allows you to reduce the
task of checking two instances in a
relation the task of checking a single
instance in that relation
and we show that if you have a folding
scheme for an mp complete relation then
you could derive an ibc scheme okay so
specifically we designed a new
characterization of np called relaxed
r1cs which is designed to be very
quickly and efficiently folded
now putting all of these techniques
together we get ibc proofs which are
linear in the size of the function f
and they in no way depend on the
recursion depth n
but suppose we wanted even more
efficiency guarantees in practice
well we then show that we can actually
add a layer of sickness and zero
knowledge on top of our ibc proofs so
specifically what we do is that we first
design a zk snark
for relaxed r1cs and then leverage this
zk snark to design a very efficient
proof
that proves the existence of a valid ivc
proof okay and using these techniques
we're able to go from proofs that are
linear in the size of the function f to
non-incremental uh but very short proofs
that are logarithmic in the size of the
function f
now nova putting everything together
represents one of the fastest and one of
the most efficient
proof systems for recursive computation
so nova is implemented in rust in about
6000 lines of code and is available on
github and if we feature the smallest
per step private time which is just
dominated by just two
multi-exponentiations per recursion step
and a recursion overhead is also the
smallest in literature now what i mean
by recursion overhead is that because of
how these systems are built we end up
having to prove the function f as as
well as a little bit of additional
overhead and this additional overhead in
our case per recursive step is just two
scalar multiplications
um and finally using our
proofs and sickness techniques we're
able to get down the proofs down to
logarithmic and the size of f and
roughly if we're able to represent the
function f in about a million
constraints
then we can get proofs that are eight
kilobytes in size
so today specifically i'll be talking
about the theoretical backbone of nova
so specifically i'll be talking first
about how
we can use a folding scheme for np and
use that to imply an ivc scheme and then
after that i'll actually go ahead and
develop a folding scheme for np by
developing a phone scheme for relaxed
r1cs
so before i begin it with our own
approach to ibc it's important that i
intuit the original approach to ibc as
well as more modern approaches to ibc to
intuit how our solution works okay so
valiant's original approach to ivc was
actually very very elegant
so the core idea is that well
let's not only prove the function f but
let's also prove a little bit extra okay
and let's represent this little bit
extra on the function f as a large
circuit f prime okay
and this little bit extra is going to be
a snark verifier that verifies that
there exists a snark that proves all
prior iterations of the function f prime
okay
and then we can say that well to
increment this proof we can write a new
proof about this latest circuit okay f
prime and call that pi i plus one
now specifically what pi i plus one test
is attesting to is that well the
function f was run correctly and also
there exists a proof of all prior
iterations of the function f prime
okay and what this means is that pi plus
1 really is a proof for i plus 1
iterations of the function f prime so
essentially if we have converted a proof
of i iterations into a proof of i plus 1
iterations
now valiance approach is incredibly
insightful in theory but when we
actually try to instantiate the pieces
in practice it turns out that it's quite
inefficient okay so the core goal when
we're trying to instantiate these
objects in practice is that we want to
make sure that the overhead over the
original function f
to derive this function f prime is as
small as possible okay so bc tv actually
go through the process of instantiating
valiance approach using the most
efficient snarks in practice today which
are these snarks uh with a constant time
verifier that rely on pairings but they
show that to make this even remotely
possible in valiant setting we actually
need to use very expensive cycles of
pairing friendly curves okay
and also um because these snarks rely on
a trusted setup the ivc scheme itself
also inherits this trusted setup
all right so you might say okay well
maybe we can get around these efficiency
issues um by using snarks without
trusted setup right
but the core issue here is that those
snarks actually have verifiers which are
not constant time they're actually more
asymptotically expensive and they
actually incur very large overheads over
the original function f okay which goes
against the our goal of trying to
minimize this additional overhead
so for the longest time valence approach
was considered just a theoretical
interest until very recently in 2019 bow
green and hopwood introduced a new
approach okay in which they say well
let us
not only uh let us not check the entire
proof in the circuit okay let's
specifically only check a very small
part of it and then defer the rest okay
and essentially what this allows them to
do is avoid having to implement a bunch
of very expensive snack machinery like
pairings and things like that in the
circuit okay and this means that they
avoid
cycles of pairing friendly curves and
they also avoid this trusted setup
so a little bit more into detail what
they do is that well they design
something called an accumulator okay
that allows you to take that proof
and check a little part of it and then
defer the rest of it into that
accumulator so this is accumulator
doesn't keep growing in size over time
okay but checking this accumulator is
equivalent to checking all the proofs
that were deferred into it
now to increment this proof or complete
the recursive cycle essentially what
they do is they say well we can write a
new proof which attests to the latest
execution of f
and also a test that this accumulator
was built correctly
now more recently uh
buns ksl in mishra and spooner introduce
a technique where they say well
this proof doesn't even need to be
succinct okay and what that does is that
affords them to
make it even cheaper in the circuit okay
their proof machinery is even cheaper
and they use even less additional gates
of the original function f
okay
um
so
these results in general bring us a lot
closer to practice okay because we're
really just throwing as much proof
machinery as possible from the internals
of the circuit okay but the core issue
is that well we looked at this and we
said well
maybe there's a way to make this even
cheaper in practice okay
and
to to answer that question we said well
okay where are the costs here and it
turns out that
well
even partially checking this proof in
some of these uh systems is is quite
expensive okay and generally even
generating these proofs is also both
concretely and even in some cases more
asymptotically expensive okay so then we
said okay
what if we get rid of the proof
abstraction entirely succinct or
otherwise just completely get rid of it
okay and we say
what if we only talk about claims okay
so specifically what we want to do is
say that suppose we had a claim that
just talks about the correct execution
of the last instance of f and another
claim that talks about the correct
execution of all prior instances of f
prime
okay well then suppose we had a magic
black box that could reduce two claims
of the same structure
into a new claim of the same structure
okay
now this new claim the same structure
essentially attests to both prior claims
okay because checking that is equivalent
to checking both private claims
according to this functionality
then essentially it could be the case
that checking this new claim is a lot
cheaper if we just create this just
right so these claims don't grow in size
over time and the corresponding
witnesses for these claims also don't
grow in size over time
okay
and now
using the analog of prior approaches we
can also increment this claim by just
you know writing a new claim about the
correctness of the latest iteration of
this computation of prime and together
we can go from a claim of i iterations
of f prime into a
uh claim about i plus one iterations of
f prime
okay well now the burning question is
how do we actually implement this fold
functionality okay and specifically we
need to be able to reduce claims
preserve their size and also make sure
these claims are powerful enough um to
capture mp constraints because we
actually want to capture any arbitrary
function f prime
so to do so we actually start with a
simpler goal and our goal is to say well
let's just try to derive an interactive
analog of this first okay and then we
can maybe use standard techniques to
compile this down into a non-interactive
version okay so what we do is we derive
something called a folding scheme okay
so folding scheme concretely reduces the
task of checking two claims u1 and u2
into the task of checking a new folded
claim you so syntactically what this
means is this is going to be interaction
between approver and a verifier okay in
which the verify takes as input two
instances to be checked
and the approver takes us and put the
corresponding witnesses now they
interact a little bit and eventually the
verifier outputs a new folded instance
which is satisfied with it says it's
it's going to be satisfied with bin
checking in place of the original two
instances and the approver outputs a new
forwarded witness which presumably
satisfies this folded instance
okay
so we can derive naturally the
completeness and soundness properties
for this okay so specifically
completeness is that well if the two
input claims are valid
then we should have the output claim is
also valid
and for knowledge soundness we must have
that well
if the approver is able to maliciously
output a w or a witness that satisfies
the folded instance then it must have
known the two input witnesses that
satisfy the two input statements to the
verifier
and one very important piece is that we
also have a very
critical efficiency requirement okay
that is we want the verifiers cost of
interacting in this folding scheme to be
significantly less than just directly
checking these instances
or even checking one of these instances
okay and one other key piece that i need
to mention here is that well
if we have a folding scheme that is
public coin that is the verifier only
sends randomness to the prover then we
can just use the fiat trimmer transform
to make it non-interactive okay and now
putting all the pieces together
essentially
if we had a non-interactive folding
scheme that is powerful enough to encode
np relations okay then f prime can
verifiably fold the two claims ui and
capital ui into a new claim capital u i
okay
now you might notice well this isn't
quite like that fold functionality that
we had before right because this voting
verifier actually needs additional hints
um to fold this uh these claims okay and
these hints are in the form of the
transcript from the non-interactive
folding scheme okay so specifically the
overall ibc prover along the side runs
this voting verifier and keeps track of
the witnesses corresponding to these
claims
okay
so
it seems that we're getting really close
to our final construction really like we
went from ibc uh to requiring just a
folding scheme for np okay but now how
do we actually construct a folding
scheme for np complete relations okay
well we have many options but we'll
start with r1cs which is a very elegant
algebraic way of looking at mp
constraints okay and we can try to use
some algebraic properties to very
cleverly try to fold two r1cs instances
okay
um so recall they an r1cs uh statement
consists of constraint matrices a b and
c which represent the computation itself
and the public i o vector x which
represents the inputs and outputs to the
computation
now witness which is the vector which
might represent the computational trace
say is satisfying if for a new vector z
which is equal to w x 1 we have the a z
times b z is equal to c z now say times
here to mean the harder product okay
that means we're doing entry wise
multiplication and we're checking each
entry
okay well now we have this relation
let's try to fold it okay so suppose the
verifier takes as input two statements
with the same computational structure it
turns out this is enough for ibc okay so
abc x1 and abc x2
okay and the prover takes us and put the
corresponding witnesses w1 and w2
well we can try to use the bluntest tool
available to us we can just try to take
a random linear combination
so what the verifier does is send over a
challenge to the approver which is just
a random field element and together they
just take a random linear combination of
the statement x okay and then the the
prover also takes a random linear
combination of the witness
and together they output the new folded
instance witness pairs
now the question is well does it satisfy
completeness that is is a b c x
satisfied by that new witness w
okay and it turns out unfortunately it's
not okay so
you know letting z be the folded vector
z that is z1 plus r times z2 okay where
z1
is equal to
w1 x11
okay we have the az times bz
is not equal to cz okay and intuitively
the reason for this is well just
expanding out cz
we have that it has this very nice
purple term and this yellow term okay
but
if we try to expand out a z times b z
because of that harder mark product in
the middle
we end up having these annoying cross
terms highlighted in red
okay
so and not only that we have that the
yellow piece is also scaled by r squared
instead of just r right so it seems like
there's no hope of both sides of this
equation actually to be equal
okay so our core intuition was to say
well what if we extend r1cs itself
just enough that we can sort of handle
all these additional garbage terms that
show up okay so what we do is that we
first
introduce a new error vector to the
statement e
okay which is designed to absorb all
these additional cross vectors in the
middle
okay and then we introduce a scalar u
which is designed to absorb the
additional r squared factor at the very
end okay so specifically we're going to
define a variant of r1cs called relaxed
r1cs which is just like in our cs
statement but additionally contains the
error vector e and the
scalar u okay so specifically a witness
vector w
is satisfying if for z is equal to w x u
we have the a z
times b z is equal to u
times c z
plus e
now it turns out that this statement is
structured just right so that when you
take two statements of this form you can
define a folding operation that allows
you to get a single statement of this
form okay and i want to give you some
intuition for why that's the case
so specifically we're going to design a
folding scheme for relaxed star with cs
which is almost right and i'll fix a few
caveats here and there in the next slide
so i only want you to focus on the
pieces highlighted in yellow which
represent the changes from the original
folding scheme for r1cs okay so
specifically now the verifier also takes
as input e1 u1 and e2 u2
okay
so now
using its witnesses the prover computes
all the cross terms okay including these
new uh u terms that we've introduced
okay to send over to verifier requesting
it to encode it into its new error
vector okay
and now the verifier sends back a
challenge and computes u and x in a sort
of expected way just taking a random
linear combination
but now the proven the verifier compute
the new error vector okay it is computed
in a way
that accounts for both the old error
vectors as well as all the new cross
terms that we've produced in this
folding procedure okay and this is
essentially what allows us to balance
both sides of the equation
okay and of course the prover computes
the witness as expected and together
they output the new folded instance
witness pairs
right so it turns out that we can show
that this satisfies uh completeness okay
but we haven't said anything about
knowledge soundness just yet okay so
specifically it turns out that well
after the prover sees the verifier's
challenge it can try to do some trickery
to
try to compute a w that satisfies this
folded instance
without even knowing satisfying
witnesses w1 and w2 for the original two
instances
okay
so essentially that like what this boils
down to is the verifier can't actually
enforce that the prover is trying to
create w as a random linear combination
of its two inputs w one and w two
okay
and the other issue is that well because
e
is linear in the size of w just because
of how these dimensions work out in the
relaxed carbon cs statement um we have
that the verifier is not even succinct
okay so we could have gotten away with
the privilege of sending with a witness
and that would have been a more
efficient voting scheme okay so
how do we get around both of these
issues
right and here
we introduce uh succinct uh additively
homomorphic commitments think the
patterson scheme okay so specifically
the core idea as well instead of
throwing um
instead of exposing the verifier to both
these error vectors we're just going to
expose it to commitments to these error
vectors okay which are succinct and
small and instead the proof is going to
hold on to these error vectors in its
own uh witness okay and moreover we're
going to allow the verifier in the
statement to have
commitments to these two witnesses okay
and this allows the verifier to force
the approver to compute the new witness
as it chooses okay so specifically what
happens is now the approver just like
before
computes the new
list of cross terms okay but instead of
sending them directly sends over a
commitment to these lists of cross terms
okay and now the verifier sends back a
challenge they compute x and u as
expected and then the verifier now
computes the new commitments to w w bar
and e bar
okay and because of the way the verifier
computes these new commitments taking
advantage of the additive homomorphisms
the prover is forced to compute its
witnesses and its witnesses w and e in
just the right way okay so together they
output the new folded instance witness
pairs
now in our paper we show that well this
satisfies completeness and this also
satisfies knowledge soundness okay and
moreover
notice that if that commitment right
there is zero knowledge or sorry is is
hiding then we can achieve zero
knowledge for this scheme right here
okay so this concludes our entire
development um we've essentially
developed a folding scheme for np over
instances with the same structure
because we developed a voting scheme for
relaxed r1cs
okay so in summary now working bottom up
essentially what we've done is that we
designed a folding friendly variant of
r1cs called relaxed r1cs we then show
how to develop a folding scheme for
relaxed iron cs that's highly efficient
okay and then we use this phoning scheme
to develop a highly efficient ivc scheme
and because we cared about making each
of these steps as practical as possible
we achieve a recursive zk start with
state-of-the-art efficiency thank you
are there any questions
hi thank you for the great talk yeah i
have a question so instead of doing the
ex recursively and sequentially have you
considered uh doing for example a
wide version of the computation such as
the data parallel computation that's why
this scheme also works do you mean like
more like tree based recursion yes
apologies okay yeah so folding actually
is very specifically designed for this
straight line path um stuff it turns out
that when you try to extend folding
algebraically for
tree topologies maybe you end up with
these quadratic blow-ups um there are
other schemes out there like
accumulation schemes which might be
better designed for tree based
structures
thank you
speaker once again
um the last talk of the session is by zl
lang from um rice university on a new
approach to efficient non-malable xero
knowledge
hello everyone i'm here to share this
result let me start with the definition
for knowledgeable commitment and
knowledge about your knowledge
a phenomenal commitment we care about
the so-called mind middle execution of a
commitment protocol and
it has two parallel sessions you can
think of in this way in the left session
the honest committer is talking to the
my in the middle address three the
honest commenter commit to some message
m
and in the red communication the my
middle adversary plays the role of a
potentially malicious committer but he's
talking to an honest receiver
and
the goal of nominable commitment is to
make sure that the value committed by
the honest committer in the left
and the value committed by the middle
address 3 in red these two values should
be essentially independent
so
how do i want to capture this
requirement formally a
we will care about two values in the
main limit execution the first value is
just the
a
in the middle's view uh the second value
m
is the value you can think it as the
value statistically bound in the in the
in the
right communication for simplicity let's
focus on statistical banking scheme for
now and in this world we care about uh
the distribution of this tuple we
compare it with the
so-called simulation world
in this world we just replace the whole
left session by a simulator and this is
a little bit different from zero
knowledge this simulator it cannot
remind the honest receiver because the
receiver is honest but
it could run the mind mode sorry
internally and potentially rebuild him
so
well our requirement for this simulator
is a first line standard we just
required to be
efficient
but
importantly this simulator doesn't know
the value m
which is value committed by the
on this committee in the middle
execution
and we see that the protocol is
nominable
if this
if this simulator
if there exists such simulator that is
able to uh output a simulated tuple that
is indistinguishable from the one
coming from the minor mid execution so
here the intuition is the
what whatever the main middle can do in
the real world with the help of the left
honest commuter now can be done by an
efficient simulator
in this way the value committed in the
red session
should be independent of the value
committed in the last section because
this uh simulator doesn't know the exam
at all
so
if i just put the definition in this way
actually this definition is impossible
to achieve because there is a very
trivial but uh hard to deal with attack
so let's say the main middle just
relay the message from the left to the
right without any modification so in
this setting you can see that the value
committed in the left m and value
committed in the red i'm sure that
they'll be always equal this is a
non-trivial relation now they are depend
depending on each other however you will
never be able to simulate that in the in
this world because this simulator has no
information of this m at all so this is
something like
i think this is a definitional issue
like no matter how hard you try as long
as you said definition as the previous
one i've shown you you'll never be
achieving this definition so to deal
with this issue actually we will only
focus on something called identity based
commitment or someone called tech based
community this coming scheme you can't
think in this way for every execution of
the coming scheme there is a
id or tag integrated in the
communication so if you want to copy the
communication just like the trivial
adversary i described earlier for
information back and forth then you are
bound to copy id
and this can be done like
if you have one function you can easily
make a
a command scheme to be identity based so
so our initial definition is we focus on
identity based commitment scheme and we
only have this requirement
condition on the left session id and
rest session id are not the current
okay
now with the definition of a number of
equipment in mind it's now easy to
understand definition for about zero
knowledge so instead of considering the
minimum execution commitment scheme we
consider that for the
zero knowledge execution
again our intuition here is one to make
the
last session execution independent of
the last session so
what we do here is that we focus on the
value uh
this is the final output of the verifier
is a binary bit indicating if the wi-fi
accept or not and here we have this
emulator again the simulator is not
revolving the verifier but it it could
internally run the machine m and do some
uh
some some tasks to help help him to
force the verifier
it's again on this verifier
to output the b that is uh
conditionally indistinguishable from the
real world execution
the intuition is uh whatever the minor
middle can do here now it could be done
by the simulator without the help of the
of the left on this program so that
means uh that means uh
the nightmare s3 cannot prove any
statement that cannot arrange
meaning without help of the left
communication
that's our those are our definitions and
before going on i want to say that these
two notions nominate welcome and zk they
are pretty useful a number of equipment
has been helped us to reduce the run
complexity of mpc
protocols and also the numerable zero
knowledge gave us a better concurrently
secure npc protocols
so let's look at let's look at the state
of the arts for
the other theoretical side things are
very beautiful a after long-term
research we eventually get the constant
run constructions from the minimal
assumption one functions
in practice we do have a very efficient
construction for normal equipment it's a
bgr v15 protocol
this is the ccs paper it actually
implements an earlier result by grv
it is based on ddh
it gives you a very fast implementation
however the situation for non-variable
zero knowledge is less satisfactory
there's basically no reported
implications at all before resort a
for those who are familiar with the
literature you may realize that okay
there is a standard transformation uh
going from nominal commitment to nominal
zero knowledge it's simple it's just
a ask proverb to commit the witness
using a nominal document and then you
just use the standard zero knowledge to
prove that the committed value is indeed
the value business
for this protocol uh actually the first
step is coming down very fast for
example you just use the pgrv15
as your underlying implementation but
the issue happens at the second step
because you are proving something about
a non-valuable equipment this number of
equipment is very complicated it's not
like
as small as an hour it has a large
circuit implementation and if you want
to do that it takes four reasonable
parameters it will take more than three
minutes
so that's uh basically the current
situation so
our result here is we give the first uh
practical
enemy key protocol in the play model
meaning without any sap
and we only need symmetrical exceptions
basically one function plus a clean
recent hash
also our technique also implies the
first
practical number of equivalent
that is from symmetry consumption only
this is in contrast to the previous bgrv
paper i mentioned which is based on ddh
yeah
now
in the following i will talk about our
techniques and by the time
by the organization like this we first
built a i'll first describe a new
template for nominable zero knowledge
protocol if you just care about
impossibility results there are several
ways to do that but uh we'll show you a
specific one that has the potential to
be implemented efficiently
once you have this template
we will identify the efficiency
bottlenecks if you want to implement it
and then we will
show some new ideas
to
to deal with the bottlenecks and
eventually get a efficient protocol here
comes the catch
we start with the numerable zero
knowledge protocol but because of the
new ideas we use to make it efficient
at the end we lose numerability so we
all we only managed to prove that it's a
simulation sound your knowledge i only
define this notion formally here
but i just want to mention that
this is a very useful notion it's
incomparable to normal ability but
i would say for 99
times a as long as the numerable zero
knowledge works you can't replace
numerical zero knowledge with simulation
standard knowledge and it will still
work
but but anyway
as long as you have simulations on all
these there are standard transformations
to make it uh
to give you normal level zk and also
nominal commitment and uh and preserve
the free dropping efficiency
so let me start with this template this
construction uh actually is a very
simple
first uh
the verifier commit to a random string
of a length of security parameter use
the extract for equipment
next the proverb
commit to a
string sigma prime using the enmc emc is
a basically nominable cleaning scheme
but it also it is also extractable and
next uh the verifier will dig meet the
sigma he committed in the first stage
and eventually we give a
statistician w-i-o-k a very
indistinguishable argument knowledge uh
where the proper proof that okay i know
witness of the
of the statement i'm trying to prove or
i actually set sigma prime sigma prime
to be the value of sigma the very far
committed before
this paradigm looks i mean everyone
should be very familiar with this just
uh looks very familiar similar to
ferguson
or fsfs paradigm so the intuition here
is the verifier setup chapter
and
if you are able to learn this sigma
somehow and commit sigma prime equals
sigma then you don't need to to do this
part honestly you don't need to know
witness you just use the chapter that's
actually how symmetrical works if you
want to prove this protocol user
knowledge but first one is we know that
a malicious proverb
will never learn this stigma before the
verified meet so it's done
uh we've seen this uh kind of structure
a lot of times but here are the the the
main differences for this stage we are
using the normal level equipment
and that this is actually what by us
normal about your knowledge
so
i don't want to get your lunch delayed
so i'll give you one page security proof
showing many of the intuition uh so
intuition here is a this is nothing but
the minor middle execution of our
protocol
what we want to show is uh
the left a direct execution and the left
execution are independent
so what we do is we want to make the
left communication
independent of the
awareness
and we
meanwhile we make sure that the
adversary commits the verifier with the
same probability if we if we manage to
do this that means a
red communication
that means the left communication
doesn't help at all right so to do that
we're just doing what you would do for
uh variation measure knowledge we
extract the chapter and then
commit to the chapter instead of all
your streams
previously on probably using windows now
we have a trapdoor we switch that we
switch to the chapter in this
so
there is only like one point i want to
mention actually
the only risk for doing so is uh
we are
extract capital and commit in commit to
it in the last session however
nothing stops the mind in the middle
adversary to perform the same thing in
the rest station right
he could also potentially extract the
sigma tuber and come into the sigma
tudor
if his if he is able to do that
you cannot say he's using the w to the
in this stage right
so but this is actually exactly what the
a non-valuable commitment captured in
the second stage
the nominable equipment definition tells
us that if we switch the value sigma to
a sigma prime
the
man in the middle cannot switch the
value he committed here otherwise that
means his value coming here is dependent
on the value we commit in the left
so because of this uh because of the
numerability of this commitment stage
actually we can't do this change but my
middle cannot so here's the probability
of commissioner bar in the red won't
change
so
now here comes the real meat i will talk
about how to make this protocol
efficient if you stare at stare at this
protocol for a few seconds you'll
realize that there are only two
efficiency bottleneck the first one is
this normal welcome stage and the second
one is this
a statistical
um
we'll address them one by one we'll
start with the last stage this protocol
uh first i want to
say that you see it has two states uh it
it's there are composition of two
statements right but for the first
statement this is something we have to
do because at least enormous your
knowledge is your knowledge
your goal is to prove uh a statement
this is the price you have to pay
however the second part of our statement
is something
by us normal ability so we should we
should we should like uh make his cost
as small as possible
so
the
naive way to do that is uh okay i just
uh view this as an mp statement and use
the state of art faster zero knowledge
implementation for example the geralt
protocol by hiv
this turns out to be slow for the same
reason because this statement need to
this statement is actually about the a
number of equipment which has a large
subject description so our solution here
is try to use the old composition
technique developed for sigma protocols
originally by cds and t4
so let me briefly recall definition of
sigma protocols um
but now i would just say it's a
three-round public coin protocol it's
honestly very very fair your knowledge
and it's also wi and i know that
we have actual requirement for example
special service but it's not that
important for this talk okay so let's so
let's
ignore that for a little while so the
the the cbs technique is for uh to give
you an efficient way to prove or
composition statement of this form so
if you want to perform this task um the
naive way is that you just view x or x
prime as a
as a single instance and run the
original protocol right but that that
could be i mean
that could be large you need to reduce
this uh or composition to an empty
statement and that could blow up the
size of the statement
so
cds is an alternative way to do that it
basically it allows you to do that with
a cost of two times the sigma protocol
for a single statement at the most but
what what the problem do here is
actually you can think of this as two
parallel execution of the zebra protocol
in for now let's assume this is a
witness for x to prove this oxygen and
just need to know one winning thread so
in the left session the proverb play
honestly using witness w because he has
witness w then in the red session the
proverb is going to use the honest
verifier simulator
so to use on this verifier simulator
so the simulator will want to sample the
challenge or public point chain string
right but
if you just do it naively like meaning
you ask the verifier to give you
uh beta and beta prime then you don't
have you you cannot use the beta prime
chosen by the verifier so what we what
should we do now the idea is that we
just combine these two challenge stream
beta and bed prime to be a unique stream
and ask verifier to sample unix stream
to the program the prover would give
approval the choice to decompose it as
an extra of to run streams
so in this way actually the plural can
run the simulator for the red session
first and the respirator will sample
beta prime and
you will just use that beta prime as a
share here and then the remaining share
beta can be computed as a beta prime x
or beta hat which is the constraint
chosen by the verifier and
in this way you lose control of beta
but it's okay because beta is a part
you're gonna beta will be viewed as a
challenge for the left interaction for
which you have the witness you can enter
any change so that's how uh that's how
this uh or competition idea works
and as you can see
the only cost you pay is actually the
proof for the
left session for the rest session you
are in a simulator if you pick some
particular sigma protocol which has a
very fast answer for simulator this
protocol could be very fast
and that's what we do
here is our or competition statement and
uh we will pick see this ligero as our
underlying sigma protocol and
implementing this idea
so your cost will be just the proof for
a
a for this the first part of the or
statement which is something you cannot
avoid right
and the simulator okay to give you more
information the hiv ahie is based on a
zero knowledge pcp and then follow
following the the the killian approach
uh
for this kind of a pcp based protocol
it's it's it's slow if you want to
generate the pcp but it's easy to
simulate it's nothing but just a random
openings of a merkle tree path so that's
very fast
okay here i want to mention caveat
what i said it looks very like it sounds
very good but however legal protocol is
not a signal protocol the main
difference is that this sigma protocol
is three wrong it has basically one
challenge response slot beta and gamma
but ligero actually it has two chinese
stars you can think of fixed alpha then
beta 1 gamma 1 beta 2 gamma 2. for this
kind of protocols
it comes well known that
this cbs or competition doesn't work
especially like i think people working
in signature they will face this problem
but in this work we do develop the
method it's kind of general to deal with
like a multiple change response slot
protocols uh how do we do our
combination for them but unfortunately i
don't have time to talk about that you
can check our paper for details but
that's an idea how we make this last
stage efficient
let's say or completion next the
emmc stage
first i need to open this date and show
you the structure this is the
construction by pgrb and you don't need
to understand what it's doing i just
want to show you a structure it's
nothing but the commuter commit to some
field elements and then the the receiver
send challenge which is also fuel
elements and then the commuter uh the
commuter just a response with again a
few admins
finally you prove some inner product
relationship so
for this structure
a
why pgrb is fast the reason is they pick
algebra big assumptions and take
advantage of that for example their
equipment is some kind of variant of l
gamma encryption and their zero
knowledge is uh basically schuner's uh
identification scheme or not zero
knowledge so
these two things go together very well
so they eventually have a very fast
implementation but now we are
like we only want to use magic
constructions the naive way to do that
is you just replace all the equipment
use the aes based command and then you
use the ligera general process dk to do
this proof
again very slow because the
circuit size is large
so
our idea
here is like we want to reduce the new
problem to the one we've already solved
right so we just show how to make this
part fast by our composition can we
review the idea here
at first glance is unclear because uh
this is not an or statement it's just we
oh they said we call it proof of
consistency it's just a zero-knowledge
proof there's no other thing but
to review the idea just augment it let's
say this is a non-valuable kind of
scheme now
we additionally give the commuter a
witness and a sediment pair
and we modify this zk argument
to prove the original consistency
condition and also
you can
this or condition you just prove x in
the language so if if you would give the
commutator a choice if you have witness
you don't need to behave honestly here
you can cheat
as long as you can use this weakness
otherwise if you don't have witness you
just do everything honestly you can
still finish finish this as the original
emc
so
now i make it a composition so i can use
the original approach uh
here
uh
as i said before computer has a choice
right if the statement you are going to
prove
is large
maybe maybe if this statement is even
larger than the original uh
consistency condition then you just uh
actually you don't do this you just
prove the original consistent
consistency condition but
this structure will give you benefit if
uh the statement you want to prove is
small
i uh i mean at least a smaller than the
original condition now the the the the
the efficiency of the accommodation will
will kick in
okay uh that's like we summarize this as
a new primitive called the
instance-based nominal equipment
instance means this uh statement wins
pair
so that's the idea but as i said before
there's a catch if you do this
previously this is the nominal equipment
however now
if the x is true
the true statement here
you don't know if the minor middle
adversary has witnessed or not however
as long as the act is true the middle
expert has the potential to use some
witness so
that means this
nominal equipment may not be performed
honestly so it may not be nominal at all
because of that reason we cannot show
its nominal abortion but we can show
that this simulation sum
so what do we get so far the simulation
from the sun zero knowledge and and i
said as i said earlier there are uh
standard transformations to make it a
about decay and normal bulk and
you again you don't need to know the how
it works and why it works i just want to
we just want to focus on efficiency
right so bottleneck is the final stage
how do we solve it it's our statement so
look same idea at before
and uh
yeah here on show some numbers this is
uh a
urdu and a nominable our number about
your money protocol on a
chart shar250
sharp256 instance
and uh this is a normal level equipment
committing to a single bit
uh the mental way here is uh we are not
trying to
provide a
off-the-shelf solution i just want to
show you that uh nominal zero knowledge
can be within the reach of practical
competition
so we didn't try much harder to
push this number smaller and smaller
it's just a demonstration concept
that's all i want to share and i'm happy
to take questions
are there any questions
hey nice talk
i just want to complement your list of
references because i didn't see it can
you hear it
sorry
yeah it's good
so
euro came 2003
we had
something called omega protocols which
are an extension of sigma protocols
which achieve no manual zero knowledge
and they're in the crs model so i see
but at the time was the first sufficient
non-modification protocol after clause
and we use also there are
composition trick
and
yeah
i see i see um check it out yeah the
issue is i i know the i know the title
of your people i never i never read it
so i will go back and read it and give
you the uh updated version so by
efficient we don't mean you know we
don't want to implement it yeah yeah
yeah at the time the only thing that was
available was class
right so
i see i see yeah and we also go through
simulation sounds
cool
sure and the the the situation is uh uh
we are mainly focused on like the play
model like yours are in the series mode
but but you already i need to give you
the reference because
because i also like a survey all the
existing constructions in the crs model
and in the random work model yeah but
but i just want to mention that you know
in a crs model if you if you get
nominable primitives
it's hard to use when you when you want
to do composition for example you see
yeah you need to program crs maybe your
larger protocol already programmed these
kind of things yeah but i will i will
study
is there any other question
all right let's thank the speaker again
thank you
and this is the end of the session