welcome everyone um
to this afternoon session on postpartum
crypto we have
five papers and four talks in this
session
and this first talk is going to be about
post quantum simulatable extraction with
minimal assumptions black box and
constant joint and it's authored by
nairo jia kai ming chong ciao yang
takashi
yamakawa and xiaoliang is going to go
talk maybe we wanna
we don't hear the speaker
hello
yeah hi everyone uh i'm here to share
without some post condom extract
simulator for extraction this is john
work with uh
and takashi yamakawa okay
uh the last name of climbing ends with
c-h-u-n-g so i added that on purpose so
you won't forget this is one of your
courses okay
so uh i want to start with the extract
for equipment i think everyone here know
what it is but i just want to make sure
that we agree on the same definition
and there's something i want to stress
address so let's focus on statistical
funding commitments for now
such equipment scheme is extractable
uh
in the following sense we will compare
to work the first word is nothing but
the real execution between a potentially
malicious committer and the honest
receiver
at the end of the execution
we denote the final state of c star as
st c star and b is the banner bit
indicating if the receiver accepts mod
the
trend denotes the transcript transcripts
all the messages exchanged between them
in this
real game
we will focus on this tuple as tc star
and b is pretty straightforward so i
want to define this value vowel trend
list value statistically bound in the
transcript
okay we compare this game with a
simulation extraction board
where we replace on this receiver with
ic which is a simulation extractor
and
the job
by the way the simulation extractor
could potentially rewind the c star and
is trying to simulate this tuple he's
trying to simulate the final state of
stc star
uh meanwhile extracting the committed
value until out
so this scheme is
extractable
if there exists such an efficient as c
make these two tubals indistinguishable
here the thing i want to address is uh
usually in the classroom setting we care
more about extraction
but here i explicitly require that the
extractor also simulates the final post
extraction state of the malicious
committee
let's first take a look at a very
typical construction for
extract equipment in the classroom
setting
this scheme again i think everyone knows
that so to commit this value m a
committer pick to run string a10 and a11
they basically form a two out of two
secret sharing of this message and he
repeats this procedure for enhance where
n is the security parameter
then
he commits to these random shares
independently you'll say uh not our
commitment
next the receiver select a run stream of
length n
and give it to the committer the
commissioner will decommit accordingly
so
this construction is very popular in the
future you can find it on basically any
zero knowledge or npc paper but it got
popular for some reason uh it enjoys
these good properties first it makes
only black box usage of the underlying
assumption of which is the only function
the reason is you can't get the nars
commandment in black box from a function
and to do this you only need a
commitment so you have a box
construction phone one function
eventually and also it comes around now
these two properties are very important
for
efficiency concerns
the third one is like we usually take it
for granted in the classical setting but
i want to say that it's very important
for a protocol composition purpose for
example if you want to use this scheme
to build something else for example
point housing or to pc
it's a gadget appearing in the middle
vapor pole you want to make sure that
after extraction the final post
extraction state remains closed to the
reward so that you can use composition
lamps to simulate the remaining parts of
the protocol
but
this wire says take for granted because
in the classical world
you can just if you want to build a
extractor your extractor can just behave
like on this receiver finish the real
execution straight line and then you
learn the final state of a potentially
malicious committer you just record this
number or record the state and then you
remind the execution back to
right after the first message and then
do whatever you want to perform the
extraction in this way you can finish
your extraction and get the post
extraction state
easily right
however i want to mention that this
procedure is typically hard in a
postponed setting meaning if the
committer is a malicious quantum machine
because in that case because of the no
cloning theorem you cannot do what i
just said in the classic setting if you
finish the protocol
learn and record the final state of the
malicious commuter it's hard to run it
back
and extract information out right
so
let's take a look at the state of arts
if we want all the good properties
uh shown uh earlier in this in last
slide
basically there are four known
constructions you can see that only the
last one achieves a black box
construction and only the second one
which is content runs
in this column i also show
if the honest parties to execute the
protocol
need quantum power for confusion and
communication
and here are the assumptions you can see
that the first construction it
assumptions as strong as obvious
transfers and the second construction
which is very elegant but it used
a little bit
a little bit heavy it falls like a fully
homomorphic encryption for corn circuits
yeah
so it looks like the silver is not that
satisfactory but actually there is a
reason this problem is hard even if you
only require these two properties
and the reason is uh such a commitment
with these two properties will imply
construction knowledge
in the postponed setting for which we
have negative results
due to time limit i won't explain these
conditions if you're interested you
can't find this paper in your reference
so
what do we do now because
we cannot get everything
we want shown here
and
these things we don't want to give up
because there are there are good
properties for efficiency
purpose
you you want to use minimal assumptions
so
eventually we choose to relax the
security goal
we relax it to something called epsilon
simulation
the
there are two words these are just the
tools i showed you on the second side
previously i require the distributions
of the output are
conventionally closed
here i change this
this in this
definition i will give a noticeable
function epsilon as a parameter or input
to the simulation extractor
the requirement here is a
as long as you fix epstein give it to
the simulation extractor the simulation
extractor's running time will depend on
this epsilon however it can
simulate to uh epsilon
up to epsilon error or for whatever
epsilon you pick
so this is a
okay for for people who are familiar
with epsilon zero knowledge i think this
is also standard so but before going on
i want to
mention that if some simulation is
really useful still useful because
a if some simulation security or implies
a anti-based or game-based security in
the sense that
epsilon zk will imply witness in
dismissability
so
we ask the question if we are happy with
ibstrum simulation can we have a
construction achieving all the remaining
good properties
uh in this work we showed that it is
indeed possible
and uh i think the classical setting
extract document is a very powerful
primitive you have that
you can have a lot of applications and
we are just uh doing the same thing in
the post quantum setting
uh you
the three the first three implications
are uh kind of not that hard achieve you
just do what you will do in the
classical setting but replace the
extract.com with our or our ipsum
version
so i won't really discuss about this
three but i will at the end of the talk
i will mention a little bit how we do
the last step
uh
all the properties all the protocols
shown here enjoy this good purpose but
uh since our extra.com is epsilon's
meaningful so we only managed to achieve
gibson's simulator version of all these
primitives
there's something i want to say about
the
blue error
we know that if you want a two-part
computation the minimum assumption is
actually uh it's announced ot
but uh
that's like in the post-quantum setting
you require that the
honest parties has to perform classical
tasks
if you are happy with the quantum
computing and quantum channel for the
honest parties
you actually you can replace something
on ot with the post quantum sql function
plus a quantum communication
implementation
so let me talk about our technique
i want to start with a closer look at
this classical construction i just shown
i just showed before and i want to see
if you want to make it or if you want to
quantize this proof
what difficulties will you encounter so
to remind you how the extractor works
first recall that all these columns of
this matrix are the two other two secret
sharing of the same message
so how do you do
extraction you can just
rewind the extension back to the second
stage and pick a fresh c prime
and expect that the c star will dig to
you
as long as there is one position where c
and c prime differs you can recover the
m by just x or the two shares of the
same column
so
this is how we do extraction in the
classical setting now we want to contact
this proof you can see that we need to
handle rebounding
and also extraction simulation
in the post in the post quantum setting
where the system is the quantum machine
we don't have much tools to use actually
you you may be able to use the waters
for example to handle simulation but uh
here we are also in a constant run
regime
so in this regime i guess the
most closely related lemma is this
simulation extraction mamma from a
previous work by uh
cha chong and yamakawa
so
we will take a look at this dilemma and
see if we can use it in our setting to
contact this proof
let me first explain what does this lama
say this islam is also compared towards
again let me first explain the first
word the first the first war is nothing
but we have a malicious committee
and he performed this committee
commitment stage to commit a value and
obtain a intermediate state he passed
this state to the dickman phase they
this represents a ticket phase adversary
just
perform the deployment and uh the output
of this game is defined as follows
if the dikmint is valid then
it is not valid then we we just ask him
to return bot we don't want to submit
anything
however as long as this commitment is
valid we will will return the value and
the commitment randomness together with
the
final state of the
uh
of the adversary at the end of the
ticket phase
as the output so
this uh cco llama says
this world actually is a epsilon close
to the second word what is the second
word it's
the same as the first word
except for the red text
you can see that the only thing we do is
we insert here the
simulation extractor
what it does intuitive here is it try to
extract the commit value try to look at
tutor
uh before the dignity phase happens
meanwhile
after this extraction he also wants to
simulate
the
intermediate state rule because in the
concern if you extract something you may
disturb the state
this simulation extractor will extract
value and return the original set back
to you
even though it's only if some calls the
remaining steps is the same as here
except for this uh additional condition
here the intuition is uh
if your extraction is not valid you just
output bot
so in this way we want to enforce that
this simulation extractor should extract
the valid valid commitment value okay
so
you can see that uh this one
you want to extract the value and finish
simulation together and this
in some sense that is for you can i use
this lemon in this setting
after this is just epsilon simulation
a
it turns out to be that is unclear there
are basically two obstacles uh the first
one is uh if you look at this real game
closely you'll see it it considers both
commitment stage and dignity at the
decrement stage you'll learn the value m
explicitly
however in this world it considers only
commitment stage and no one will tell
you the value n unless you do this
extraction by yourself in the classic
setting
and in the clone setting it's not even
clear how you can do that right
a second issue is uh
about uh
this is a commitment so if it's
statistical bonding as long as you have
this commitment there is a unique value
found within the government
but
this commit stage is more like flexible
i said that all the columns should be
the actual of the
it should be xor to the same message n
however
the malicious c star may not follow the
protocol
so maybe he finished execution but
there's no m well defined
this represents the two obstacles
because of that it's actually unclear
how we can use this level
so we will address these two obstacles
one by one we start with the second one
uh it's about the well-formedness of the
committed value for now let's assume for
simplicity that
the c star will cheat in whatever ways
but he will give
he will give a consistent commitment
here so let's first address the first
issue and
assume that the second issue is not
not there yet
yeah but even in this setting again
because of the
the problem i mentioned earlier there is
no one that tells you the committed
value m
so
it's unclear how you can how you can
define the machine that gives you m and
then use the specified lama
at least in a blackbox way
so we will handle this issue by opening
the security proof of ccoi and
do some number box modifications
to do that i first need to
remind you of the
security proof i will give you a very
high level
explanation
i mean a lot of details but i think it
captures my intuition basically if you
ask me what is the idea behind ccoi i
will say the power of uncomputing
it works as far as we want to do this
extraction simulation given a state role
we first
decompose it by something called draw
dilemma
into two portions the first portion
represents
a
the the state in the super position
where the
where the dignity algorithm will will
will will tell you the correct decrement
with probability greater than epsilon
the epsilon
you defined before because you want if
some simulation
now
the second part is just the portion
where this the digimon algorithm
responsible with probability smaller
than epsilon
now
if we do this decomposition there exists
a
unitary operation
which we call amplifier
it works in the following way we apply
it in row it applies to these two
portion separately independently
and it will amplify the response
response probability in this greater
lifestyle portion to overwhelming
but
on the second the smaller than epsilon
part we lose control we don't know
what's happening there however the
medical ways it will work on these two
branches separately it won't get mixed
so this this algorithm you can take for
granted and uh
let's see if we have this algorithm what
do we do next
next is you just apply the stigma
algorithm on the state you obtained in
the second phase let's analyze the
behavior for these two branches
separately you can see that for the
first branch
uh
the
the decrement algorithm responds to you
with probability overwhelming so you can
extract m from there
however for the second part as i said we
lose control so but for this one we
don't care about it because we are only
targeting the ips simulation
after this step we at least learn the m
in the good part and we memorize it
technically you can think that we are
denoted into a new register
then we can and compute
because quantum computing are always
reversible you can view step two and
three as a big unit operation
what do i mean by reverse just apply the
a conjugate transpose
so
after this operation
let's look at these two parts
again the easy part is a smaller than if
some part as i said we lose control we
don't know what's happening there but
good pattern bad part always like
independently perceives so it won't
affect the good part then for the good
part what we do is we amplify the
responsive probability and then we
extract
we already know that they will response
us with priority overwhelming then by
something called a gentle measurement
dilemma
we can extract information from this
state without disturbing i mean almost a
perfectly extraction okay
so to summarize what we do is first we
use something called jordan
decomposition to decompose it and then
we amplify the response probability in a
good part for the bad part we just
ignore it
now the real extraction happens at the
step three and four we succeed in
extraction for the m in a good part
adjust
now we do uncompute
the problem i mentioned earlier is that
this cci plumber
have
explicit construction of a machine that
will tell you the value amp
however in our
in the extractor column i just showed
you before there's no such a machine so
let's take a look at these three steps
you can see that step one two three
depends on this uh
uh
secret teller right so
our hope here is uh
can we find such a
counterpart in our extractable equipment
construction so that we can plug it in
to this uh template
replace this uh becoming algorithm with
it and then maybe we follow if we follow
the same uh template we will we will
we'll get
we'll get symmetrical extraction
so how to do that the starting point is
uh
we
look at the classical extractor this is
what the classical extreme does at least
it extracts the value for you and we
want to view it as the secret header
however the problem is this extractor
works only in the
only in the classical setting if you are
in a funnel setting
maybe
again you cannot perform a rewind it's
hard
however
[Music]
fortunately
using a technique developed by unrule
for post quantum proof of knowledge we
actually can't finish the extraction but
without simulation so
this uh these results give us a
simulationless extractor it can tell us
the
value m at least
now we just use this simulation
extractor to replace the decommitment
algorithm in the cc valence and
it will
finish the proof basically the thing
here what happens here is
this first will get a simulation
extractor and this is sufficient for
step one two three and then this
template will take care of the
simulation to give you epsilon close
simulation i admit a lot of details but
that's the intuition behind the
construction if you're interested please
check our four version paper
i solve this problem by uh assuming
the committee's commitment is
well-formed because they are consistent
according to the
real definition of the construction
however in general historically cheat
right
this actually is easy to solve just add
zero knowledge to prove all the
commitments are performed honestly but
we are also targeting at a box
construction if you use your knowledge
proof on some
commitments you are making number box
used comments however
this issue actually is well known in the
classical setting people developed a
very powerful tool called pc they have
basically
it is the black box commit and proof
technique
addressing exactly same setting here so
we just take their method and to make
this commit and approve strategy
blackbox i won't talk about this uh due
to time constraints but i would say this
is a very interesting technique you
should you should like read about it and
basically
for all the blackbox constructions in
cryptography i would say 95
of them are using this technique so you
can check our paper we have a good
presentation with
i want to give you some words
a what i told you before is the extract
for comment if some simulatable in the
standalone setting however actually to
use this mpc's in the head technique uh
if you want to maintain constant run
construction
there will be some parallel repetition
of the extrapolate
and
it turns out that our x.com is not
parallel secure but we
did achieve a weak version in the sense
that uh
you view all the sessions and happening
together if one session board you can
think that every like you don't want you
don't need to submit anything you can
sing all the session about
uh
the this is this turns out to be
sufficient for the mtc in head technique
because there's only a single commuter
who's committing a lot of things to you
and if one second board you can think of
the receiver just reject doesn't
simulate
but
don't try to use this construction in
the uh for example
parallel your knowledge setting because
uh there you would want to simulate
other and board sessions even though
some sessions have brought it but our
landmark won't take care of that that's
actually an interesting open question
so for the
application to blackbox to pc
we basically need
to find some competitors but there are
like a lot of competitors in
the literature but we have restrictions
we want black box and constant run
construction
this
cdmw09 is a tcc paper this one is a
black box and console it takes some so t
plus a special commitment id
functionality
i will give you stamina also t and this
special audio functionality actually it
was implicit in the ancient literature
shouldn't see ancient old dc charts but
it just got abstract out by a recent
work geos 21 giraffe 31 the reason is
the these previous competitors they are
more focusing on the uc setting they
claim the standalone setting uh but they
didn't really
provide enough details and i think this
is the first word get part explicit and
rigorous
uh
once you have measures to pc there is a
black box constant around the compiler
to compile it into a two specific
protocol so what we show here is our
epsilon simulation uh simulatable
expression that is triple component can
be used to implement this idea
functionality so we have the final
result this is something i already
showed you before if you are happy with
quantum communication then you can take
one function and uh
this will give you a sentence it's an
alternative
approach to inventory reach to pc
so finally i
will mention some
concurrent work uh there is a recent
work by uh
alex mumbai and from ima nick spooner
they also achieved epsilon simulatable
extraction commitment and the difference
is they give a new and very powerful
notion for a simulated running time what
they
that is what they call coherent expected
uh qpt time
this time this notion is strong it
implies uh epsilon's measurability the
difference is their construction number
box and they need super polynomial
harness of a one function
uh another application of our reality is
our extravagant plus the reason work by
uh
pitansky lin and smelly
will give us the first uh log star
lambda run post quantum number variable
equipment from the minimum star span
assumption of all functions and uh
in a little bit more detail the box 21
actually gives us a compiler going from
any
k round post quantum extractable
equivalent to the
k times log star lambda on postcolumn
nonmetal.com and uh our
post quantum
extract document can be used here here
in the caveat
this this compiler uh requires a
natural closed simulation for the post
post extraction state of the measures
computer however uh since you know
non-metabolism is essentially a
game-based definition or ind notion so
in the same sense that if some
terminology impressed witness in
distinguishability
you can replace the fully simulated or
extra document with a ipstone simulation
version
and uh i will take the
last seconds for uh to give an
advertisement you can see that uh now we
have a lot log star lamina around the
construction for our postcard normal
document
can i hope to achieve concern
actually these questions uh was pretty
hard in the classical setting even and
they took a lot of effort to go from
lobster laminate to to come around
because even though the house run
complexity the gap may not be that that
large but they took totally different uh
techniques in the classical uh in the
classical world so are we going are we
going to run into the same trouble in
the post quantum setting
and i have some good news for you and
there is a recent work
by me
and takashi yamatawa and we built the
first constant around the postpartum
number
from the minimal assumption of post
quantum 1 functions and if you are
interested you should check this link
and that's all i want to share i'm happy
to take questions
thanks for this talk uh we have maybe
time for one quick question
is there any question in the audience
i don't see any questions in zoom so
then let's join join me and thanking
speaker again
and while the next speaker sets up i can
read you this very long title that's
actually a soft merge of two papers the
first paper is the gap is sensitive to
size of three images collect some
property doesn't go beyond quantum
collision resistance for pre-images
started hash functions
that was the first paper that's by xu
jiaoz
way and ray 2
and the second paper is
much shorter title and it's called new
constructions
of collapsing hashes
and it's by mark sandri and mark is
going to give the talk so
whenever you're ready
just go ahead
meeting um
all right uh yeah so this talk will
cover uh two recent works uh seeking to
understand the security of hash
functions in a quantum world
okay so let's start with the notion of
classical collision resistance uh so
here we have a compressing function that
maps large inputs down to small inputs
and we want that despite it being
compressing and there being a lot of
collisions that exist in this function
that is nevertheless hard for a
computationally bounded adversary to
find one
okay um and this this ability to
compress inputs while still uh
computationally hiding any collisions
has tons of applications throughout
cryptography and has made collision
resistance one of the fundamental
cryptographic building blocks
uh so the natural question is when we
move to the post quantum setting what
type of security do we want out of our
hash functions
and the the boring answer is why don't
we just uh insist that when we talk
about computationally done at
adversaries we allow them to be quantum
adversaries now so efficient quantum
adversaries
uh and we ask that
you know it's hard for such an adversary
to find a collision
so i'll call this notion post-quantum
collision resistance
and unfortunately uh this is not the
necessarily the right answer
um so let's see why this is this is well
known by now um so let's consider one of
the canonical applications of hash
functions which is to give us
commitments i'm not going to worry about
hiding because hiding isn't too too
interesting in this setting
and i'm just going to focus on binding
so i'm going to i'm going to think of
using a hash function
to give a binding commitment
to to a message and why might you want
to use a hash function well maybe you
want your your commitment to be small
so
i'm also not going to define what the
security of the commitment scheme we
want but at a minimum the following game
should should be hard whatever
definition of a commitment you want you
would at least hope this game is hard
where the
adversary first sends over a commitment
then the at some point the the the game
gives them a random message and they
have to somehow open the commitment to a
random message so by open i mean come up
with the random coins r such that the
commitment is h of m r
so this should definitely be hard if
you're going to use your hash function
as a commitment
um well unfortunately
uh it turns out that this uh that the
notion of collision resistant hash
function
you know upgraded to the quantum setting
to be post quantum is not enough to
guarantee that this commitment is
binding
in particular and venus at all
what they show is that there exists
collision resistant
post quantum hash functions
such that there are not binding when
used as a commitment
with the caveat that this is relative to
an oracle so it's not a standard model
separation but it you know at least
shows
that you won't be able to prove a say a
black box um
that the hash function is a good
commitment in this setting just from its
collision resistance
all right so so what's the intuition i
won't i won't go into the proof but the
intuition for why this is the case
is that if we you know we're trying to
prove a reduction we have an adversary
that say breaks this binding notion for
commitment
we somehow need to construct a collision
but this binding notion only gives us
one pre-image of a hash function where
where do we get a collision from
classically we
can actually complete the reduction and
get a collision and basically what you
do is you run the adversary twice using
what's known as rewinding
unfortunately as as was alluded to in
the previous talk rewinding is known to
be problematic quantumly this has to do
with the no cloning theorem and quantum
mechanics
and and what the imbainus at all result
does is it really shows that you know
not only is rewinding problematic but
there are cases where it is just
outright impossible
so instead um
unruh in 2016 proposed the following
notion for collision resistance that's
called earth's right the falling notion
of security for hash functions that's
called collapsing
and here's here's the game
so the adversary gets to come up with a
superposition of inputs they they send
it to
the challenger
and the challenger does one of two
things either they just measure the
superposition of inputs and send back
the resulting collapsed state which will
just be a single classical input
or
they measure not the
not the input itself but the result of
applying the hash function to x
so on the right what the resulting state
is is it's a superposition over all
pre-images to the hash function that map
to the you know given output so rather
than just being a single classical
string it's this is collision i realize
this superposition
um nevertheless what collapsing demands
is that
these two these two cases are
indistinguishable
okay so this might seem like a bizarre
notion for for a hash function but the
the intuition is that if
uh if you thought of h as being an
objective function instead of
compressing
um with an injective function if you
were to measure the output it actually
would fully collapse the state to
a single pre-image just because every
output has at most one pre-image
so in some sense what collapsing is
saying
is that in some quantum sense
a collision or a collapsing hash
function is as good as an injective
function which is you know some way of
thinking about what classical collision
resistance was also
um all right so so this is the
definition we're trying to achieve i
won't spend too much time on it because
it turns out it's actually not super
important for this talk
but the point is that now this has been
this is widely regarded as the right
notion of secured in the post quantum
setting and
it has been shown to be sufficient to
lift many classical results into the
quantum setting
okay so now let's talk about what was
previously known
uh so
unruh in 2016 showed that random oracles
are collapsing this is a good proof of
concept that says like you know if
random oracles weren't collapsing that
might suggest that
the definition is just unachievable
um and then in another work by owner and
a follow-up work by um
and myself
we we show that
we can achieve collapsing in the
standard model
by going through something called a
lossy function which in turn we can
instantiate via lwe
okay
and then here's another sort of positive
result for collapsing
um so we we showed that if you had a
post-quantum collision resistant hash
function that was not collapsing
that this would give you some pretty
powerful objects and um
quantum cryptography that have been
notoriously hard to construct and you
know that while there have been
candidates many of them have ultimately
been insecure
so if it turned out that your favorite
hash function
was post quantum collision resistant but
not collapsing this would actually allow
you to solve some you know long-standing
open problems in quantum
quantum cryptography
on the other hand we have this negative
result that says well at least relative
to an oracle you can't have all um
post quantum collision assistance and
hash functions be collapsing there will
be some
negative results
but this is this is really a frustrating
wide gap between what the positive and
negative results are you know it could
be on one hand that all standard model
post quantum collision is in hash
functions are actually collapsing right
the only negative result we have is
relative to an oracle or
um you know some some assumptions that
have not really withstood the test of
time or the other possibility is that
maybe
lwe based
constructions or in particular lossy
function based constructions of hash
functions
maybe those are the only collapsing hash
functions we have and everything else is
actually not collapsing we just really
you know prior to these works we really
didn't know
okay so so this brings me to the results
so i'll first discuss the results of the
concurrent work by kal and zu
so what they showed is that
if you assume
a post-quantum collision resistant hash
function
h
h may or may not itself be collapsing
but if you impose a certain regularity
condition on the hash function they call
almost regular
then you can compile that hash function
into a collapsing hash function
and as a corollary what they show is
that the cis hash function
is almost regular according to their
notion and therefore you can compile the
cis hash function into a collapsing hash
function
now i should note that the as a from a
feasibility perspective going from cis
to
collapsing was already known
right in particular cis and lw are
equivalent under quantum reductions
by regev
and so then you could just plug in the
lwe based
constructions of collapsing hash
functions
however
the
kawan zoo result does not use lossiness
anywhere in the proof and so it's really
a fundamentally different proof than
what was done before it shows that
lossiness is not inherent to justifying
uh collapsing hash functions
all right so so now let me discuss
our results um so we show how to
construct collision resistant hashes
under any of the following assumptions
the first is this what we call
semi-regular post-quantum
collision-resistant hash function um
semi-regular being our term for some
regularity condition which is um
somewhat
milder condition than the almost regular
notion and therefore more broadly
applicable
we show that you can construct
collapsing hash functions from the
hardness of lpn in certain parameter
regimes
which essentially match what we know how
to use lpn for to get cloud to get
collision resistance
we can construct collapsing hashes from
the quantum partners of finding short
cycles and exponentially large expander
graphs the canonical example of this is
isogenase over elliptic curves this also
matches what we know of for getting
collision resistant hashing from
exogeneous over elliptic curves
and then finally we show that we can
start collapsing hashes from any
optimally secure
collision resistant hash function here
we don't require any leg regularity
assumption but require this notion of
optimally secure which i'll elaborate on
later
um and then as a trivial corollary we
get the first feasibility we get these
feasibility results where we get the
first post quantum statistically hiding
commitments and first post quantum
succinct arguments under any of the
above assumptions
okay so let's get into techniques
so both work start from the the same
theorem
which says that if a function h is post
quantum collision resistant
and it's at most polymer polynomial to
one so no image has more than a
polynomial number of pre-images
then we can conclude that h is
collapsing
and
the the proof is uh pretty
straightforward um so the idea is all we
all we do is we we
um so we are given the state from the
absolute superposition of inputs
we measure it once
to get one input
then we apply the distinguisher the
hypothetical collapsing distinction we
measure the result we actually don't
care what it says we just throw it away
and then we measure the resulting state
again and get another x
and the claim is that this gives us a
collision with non-negligible
probability
uh just to get a sense of why this might
be the case let's consider the case
where the function is actually two to
one
in the two to one case
we can uh
we can more or less project down onto
two dimensions so suppose x1 and x2 are
two colliding inputs and the adversary
gave us
a superposition of these well okay we
measure the state we get
we get you know x1 or x2
and now the distinguisher the
distinguishing measurement is some other
measurements in this two-dimensional
plane and the fact that it actually
distinguishes the case where we measured
the output versus measuring the input
implies that the the basis for the state
is somewhat far from the from the basis
of x1 and x2
so when we measure the state we get say
x1 and now we measure the distinguisher
we're going to move a little bit at
least a little bit away from x1 and then
when we measure the the state again
there's some non-trivial
uh probability that we'll actually end
up transitioning to x2 and that gives us
our collision
so we show that this generalizes to
higher dimensions the issue is that the
loss in the reduction decreases with the
number of colliding inputs and that's
why we can only handle a polynomial
number of
colliding inputs
okay so now now both works try to extend
this result and we extend it in slightly
different ways
um so
what kal and zu show is that
you can
take a hash function h that maybe now
has a much larger input size than its
output size maybe it's exponentially
many to one
but as long as it satisfies this
regularity condition you can
compile it into a collapsing hash
function
and we show essentially the same thing
but with this semi-regular notion and
let's not worry about the difference
between almost regular semi-regular
there they're just some way of saying
that the worst case number of pre-images
is not too far from expected
where
what we mean by not too far unexpected
differ from in the two definitions
um so i'll i'll sketch our proof of this
theorem the the proof in by kalamazoo is
different
um so here's our construction it's it's
a merkle dam guard-like construction the
difference is being that um we're only
going to incorporate a single bit of the
message at any point in time at any
stage we're not going to be able to you
know incorporate a security parameter
number of bits or anything like that
and also at every stage we interleave
the applications of the hash function
with the ky's independent function f
the very rough intuition for why this
works
is that
we can show that the each stage of this
application
is at most polynomially many to one on
the image from the previous step so we
can apply our
um
our theorem from the previous slide
to each stage to see that each stage is
collapsing
and then it was already proven by prior
work that merkel dambard preserves
collapsingness so if we have that each
stage is collapsing then the overall
hash function is collapsing
now there are some technicalities that
make this
actually somewhat non-trivial to prove
um so so one thing is that we in order
to get the proof to work we need that
every stage uses its own kos independent
function
um and then maybe the more annoying
thing is that we actually need to
um we need to not incorporate even a
single bit to the message at every stage
in most stages we're actually going to
incorporate zero
and only incorporate the next message
bit occasionally
roughly the reason we need to do this is
we're trying to control the image size
at any given stage and it might be that
um you know every time you incorporate a
message a bit you could actually have
your image size at that stage
grow by a factor of two and if you had
too many messages in a row
maybe you end up getting your image size
to be way too big and now you won't be
polynomial to one anymore
so by inserting these zeros we can show
that sort of every time you insert a
zero you decrease the image size a
little bit
and then you you make sure to decrease
it enough that when you when you
incorporate your next message bit you'll
find that you doubled the image size
okay so let's move on to applications so
the first application is the cis hash
function
given here so the inputs are short
vectors x
shorts in
l2 norm and the hash function is
specified by a random wide matrix a and
you just evaluate by doing the inner
product and
reducing mod q for some appropriate cube
um so what calendars you showed is that
the sys hash function is almost regular
and many parameter settings
and we know that the cis hash function
is post-quantum collision resistant
following from the post-quantum hardness
of various lattice problems
so as a result you get
collapsing hash functions from bias
problems
okay so what about lpn hashing so
superficially lpn hashing looks very
similar except we've changed the norm so
now instead of short and l2 norm vectors
we have sparse vectors as our inputs and
also everything's mod 2 instead of mod
mod q
um
so it was it was previously shown that
the
that this lpn based hash function is
secure is a post quantum collision or as
a quantum path is a collision existing
hash function under
certain
lpn parameter regimes
and
we show that lpn hashing is semi-regular
so
what this allows us to do is then
compile lpn hashing into a post quantum
collapsing hash function
all right what about expander based
hashing so this was
introduced by
charles alter and goran and so here we
imagine there's some implicitly
represented exponentially large expander
graph together with a designated
starting node
and what they propose as the hash
function is you interpret your input
as describing a non-backtracking lock
through this graph and you just follow
the walk and whatever node you end up
with is your output
right and
so the the collision resistance of
of this hash function
follows from the hardness of finding
simple cycles in this graph
which could be positive this problem
could be positive hard for things like
the the graph of
isogenes over elliptic curves
so what we observe is that prior work
already showed that non-backtracking
locks on expanders will mix
and
data just immediately basically
trivially shows that the this
expander-based hash function is
semi-regular so then again plugging into
our compiler
we have a
semi-regular hash function uh collision
is in hash function we can compile it
into one that's
all right and then finally let's talk
about optimal collision resistance so we
define optimal collision resistance
as being any polynomial time adversary
the probability that the output of
collision is at most polynomial divided
by two to the n where n is the bit
length of the range
okay and note that um
you know random oracles for example are
often collision resistant both
classically as quantumly for different
notions of for different values of the
poem
so what we show is that if the
domain is not much bigger than the range
say you add log bits
to the domain
and if h is optimally post-quantum
collision resistant then h is actually
also collapsing
and the proof is
is not too hard the observation is that
if you have optimal collision resistance
what it means is that maybe there do
exist um x or that have many that
collide with exponentially many points
but it's actually hard to find
because if you could find an x that
collided with too many inputs you would
actually be able to break the optimal
collision resistance
so
so it's hard to find x that collide with
too many inputs and then we can more or
less use the same analysis as in the
polynomially mini to one case to
conclude that the hash function is
collapsing
okay um and that that's basically it for
the talk so um i guess the takeaway from
this is collapsing is perhaps more
prevalent than previously bought really
before all we knew was collapsing from
lwe or idealized models and here we
showed a number of new ways
to build uh collapsing hash functions
and essentially what we have matches all
of the
all of the known post-quantum
collision-resistant hash function
feasibility results so any
most of the assumptions we have that can
build collision resistance and withstand
quantum attacks will now also give us
collapsing hash functions
and that's it thank you
thanks for the nice talk are there any
questions
okay i don't see any questions here or
in soon so let's thank the speaker again
and while they switch the slides
uh the next paper is called
statistically sender private ot from lpn
and derandomization
by near butansky and superior right side
and sapir will give the torque
do you maybe want to full screen this
sir
um
okay hi everyone my name is sophia and
i'm going to tell you about
statistically central private oblivious
transfer form npn and the randomization
and this is a joint walk with anil
bensky
okay so just before i start let me
let me tell you about the work in a
nutshell
so what we the main goal of the work is
to expand our reach of the learning
party with noise assumption or lpn in
short
and we focus on two methods
statistically central pipeline limits
transfer
which is an oblivious transfer protocol
where we really take the round
complexity and the security to the
extreme
and the results we achieve is first we
construct an ss plt protocol
in the common random string model from
lpn
and then we remove the crs using the
standard the nissan vectors on style the
randomization assumption
okay so the talk is going to be divided
to two parts so in the first part i'm
just going to give you a brief overview
of the work and the definitions and then
i'm going to dive into the construction
itself
okay so first of all let me tell you
about lpn
so
npn
is the problem
where
first of all everything is over the
binary field here
and we are given a random binary matrix
a which indicates a random binary and
linear code
a is a
is longer matrix
and our goal is to distinguish between
the case of when we are getting a noisy
codeword
or just a random vector in the space of
all codewords
and the assumption says
that for every computationally bound
adversary this pro it's how to
distinguish between the cases
so lpn comes
with a so the noise
uh of the code words is distributed
iid bernoulli
and we have a parameter epsilon which
indicates the noise rate so as long as
epsilon is bigger the problem gets
harder
okay
so whenever we talk about lpn uh
we should keep in mind it's twin problem
nwe the learning with error the
assumption which is defined exactly the
same
uh only that we walk over a larger field
of q for some large q
and the error is distributed and
discrete gaussian instead of bernoulli
so both problems are considered to be
hard and resilient
to quantum attacks
but although they are very similar in
flavor they are very different
and generally speaking lpn is far behind
nwe both in terms of applications and in
terms of known hardness results
so from lpn we know uh mostly how to
construct a
pretty basic primitives like public
encryption secret key encryptions
commitments and so on while from nwe we
know how to extract much more advanced
primitives like fully homomorphic
encryption non-interactive zero
knowledge and much more
and in terms of awareness results
we know how to
prove
worst case to average case reductions
for interesting noise
for interesting parameters of the nwe
problem
and from lpn we or we almost know
nothing actually
uh so why do we still uh i want to
stick with with lp why do we answer
sorry so why do we still care about lpn
and not just want to stick with lwe so
first of all a lp hand has a very high
potential efficiency because it only
contains simple bit operations
and also of course because of robustness
we want to base crypto on as many
assumptions as possible
and lpn and nwe although they are
very similar they are not comparable to
each other and they are just different
assumptions
and also of course theoretical uh the
problem of lpn is related to
the very long static problem of decoding
random binary
linear codes
which is very interesting
and we want to understand it
okay so the lpn research continues uh
both in terms of applications and
harness results and our main
contribution is in the applications part
where we build
the first statistically central private
oblivious transfer from the lpn
assumption and an additional
randomization assumption
okay so let me tell you about oblivious
transfer
so oblivious transfer protocol is a
really fundamental protocol in a
cryptography
and it consists of a two parties the
receiver and the sender
and the receiver has a choice bit c and
the sender has two messages m0 and m1
and the common goal of two parties is to
let the receiver learn the message of
its choice emcee
we also require two s security and
guarantees and they are that the center
doesn't learn the bit of the receiver c
while the receiver doesn't know the and
the other message of the
sender m1 minus c
so
as most of you know this um
protocol is really basic and it's
complete for multiple computation and we
are interested in making it the best
possible in all features of interest
such as around complexity security level
and so on
okay so in this talk we focus on
statistically standard private oblivious
transfer
or ss plt in short
so this is a an oblivious transfer
protocol where we require the minimum
around complexity of only two messages
one message from the receivable to the
sec to the sender and the second message
from the center to the receiver
we require computational receiver
security meaning that the choice bit of
the receiver is kept hidden from any
computationally bounded sender
and also statistically center security
meaning that
every any receiver cannot learn the
other message of the sender even if the
receiver is unbounded okay so formally
it means that the first message of the
receiver fixes a
message that it won't be able to learn
okay so we are really taking on
complexity and security to the extreme
because it's really the minimum around
complexity
and with only two messages we cannot
hope for a statistical receiver security
so this is really the best we could hope
for
and uh okay so this this is an oblivious
transfer protocol which is very short in
their own complexity and very secure
and therefore it's not surprising it
found many applications
in the literature and then there are
many examples here
so a bit about firewall
so up until recently we only know how to
construct ss30
from number theoretic assumptions which
are breakable
and quantum computers
and there are a
post quantum
constructions of ssp
that were constructed pretty recently
and all of them are from lwe
and what we know
from lpn is how to construct an
oblivious transfer which is
computationally
secure in the common reference training
model
okay so let me again uh
repeat the results that we get
so again we construct
the first two methods statistically
sending private oblivious transfer
form lpn in the common random string
model
and then we show that we can actually
remove the series
using the randomization technique
okay so there is a caveat to a work
which which we should mention and it is
that we rely on the so called the
lpn in the low noise regime meaning that
it's breakable in quasi-polynomial time
so it could be viewed more as a
feasibility result that we can construct
the spirit from npm
but we should keep in mind that there
are also other basic primitives which
are only and on how to construct from
melbourne in this low noise regime
such as collision-resistant hash
functions
uh and also there is a potential
complexity barrier here
so right now uh and we know okay so lp
and epsilon if okay sorry if lp and
epsilon implies ss plt
then it means that lpn epsilon
is breakable in sdk
but right now we only know that uh lpn
we in the low noise regime is breakable
in sdk
so it doesn't mean that it's not
possible to to construct to achieve
experience from lpn with higher noise
but it means that uh it could be harder
to construct
such a
such
ss plt from lpn with higher noise um
it might be harder and it would break
the limit of what we know about the
complexity of lpn of course it's a very
interesting question raises up here
okay so this was the end of the first
the first part of the talk and now let
me dive into the actual construction and
we're going to be a bit more technical
here
okay so
we are starting with the receiver at the
center and the crs is going to be
is going to consist of a long matrix a
and a random vector v over the binary
field of course
and the receiver is going to sample
according to the lpn assumption
s and e and it's going to calculate v 0
which is going to be equal a s plus e
plus c times v
and it's going to send it to the center
now the sender is going to
set v1 to be the sum of v plus v0
v from the crs
and it's going to sample two vectors x0
and x1 according to some sparse
distribution here
and it's going to send for each bit it's
sending x transposed v plus m
and an additional information in the
term of x transpose times a
and then the receiver for a choice bit c
it outputs the relevant first
a part of the message from the sender
minus the second part
multiplied by the secret s
okay so why this
this should work so let's uh first um
talk about correctness
so note that vc
when this when the receiver and the
center are
honest then vc is just equal s plus e
and therefore the expression the
receiver outputs it just equals simple
calculation shows that it equals x
transpose a plus m c
and because both e and x are going to be
sparse enough
we are going to make sure that x
transpose times e is going to be equal
to zero with high probability
okay
the reciprocal privacy follows directly
from the lpn assumptions because
assumption because as plus e looks
random to any computationally bounded
sender so it completely hides the choice
bit of the receiver c
and
and uh regarding sender privacy
okay so first let's uh consider the case
of semi-honest receiver just for warm-up
so note that
v one minus c
equals a s plus e plus v because how the
center
a sets a v one and v zero and the
receiver here is honest
and therefore the the expression that
contains the second message of the
center is going to look like it's going
to look like the expression written down
here it's x transpose times v plus m1
minus c plus plus something that is
independent of v
and
because v is an inner product extra
extract or seed
we get that x transpose times v looks
random even given the leakage x
transpose a and we are going to make
sure that this distribution 3 also has
enough entropy
to to make this claim
okay so we are going to
so he
has to have enough entropy and it has to
be sparse enough
and this is why um
the protocol is uh this is like an
intuition why it should be correct
and i want to mention that
already here in the semi-honest case
uh we receive the bound on epsilon which
is a
going to be equal order of log n and
square divided by n and the calculation
shows that this is really
what happens here
okay so really the the construction
itself is pretty uh simple but the
challenge here is when we wanted to
prove that
[Music]
that the ssp
property
is is correct in the malicious receiver
case
so where is the challenge here so now
the receiver may choose v0 adaptively
and depending on the seed v
and therefore the extractor argument
no longer works
so the okay so the question rises up
here is does any adaptively split of v
to two seeds
v equals v zero plus v one contains a
good extractor v i
and this is because when the receiver
fixes v zero it actually fixes such
splits because remember that v equals v
0 plus v 1.
okay and we want to
what we want to argue is that one of the
messages still stays hidden
but
it turns out that the inner product
extractor is generally not resilient to
such linear quantum attacks we also show
a counter example in the paper
and therefore just arguing that he has
enough entropy is not going to be enough
but fortunately in our case we have a
specific leakage form x-transpose a
and also we can choose the source
okay so we choose 3 in the following way
so here is going to be the sum of k
independent unit vectors
which
we and we choose here like that because
it behaves nicely with the fourier
transform
and we summarize n divided by log n
vectors okay and after choosing three
what we want to show formally
is that without probability over the crs
for every split of v into two parts v
equals v zero plus v one there must
exist some vi among them
such that extra suppose
the eyes still looks random even given
the leakage x transpose a
okay
but how are we going to prove this
so i'm going to give you a
sketch of the proof
all the details are of course in the
paper
so
again this is just a reminder of our
goal here
so what we prove
in the paper is the following lemma and
it says that for every matrix a and
vector w
the statistical distance between these
two distributions is actually bounded by
how balanced are all the vectors in the
both set a plus w
and we use a fourier transform to prove
this
there is also a formal expression
for this state but i'm not going to dive
into the formal expression here
but i'm just going to try and give you
some intuition of why this maybe should
be true
so let's ask ourselves the other
question and it is when x transpose w is
actually predictable given x transpose a
so note that if
if
by chance there exists some vector some
small vector in in hemingway in the
coset a plus w
then x transpose a is actually
predictable given x sorry suppose w is
actually predictable given x transpose a
because x transpose times e star here
which is a low hemming weight vector is
usually equal to zero
okay and also if it happens that there
exists some large vector in the coset
then we can still predict x transpose w
and this is because the way we chose 3
which implies that x transpose time the
vectors of all ones
always equals to k modulo 2. this is
just also a simple calculation that
shows this
and therefore we we
these two observations tell us that we
must have that all the vectors in the
coset are balanced to have good
statistical distance between the
distributions
uh and dilemma shows that this is
actually
enough
okay
so now our goal becomes to show that
with without probability over the crs we
can vent for every split of v we can
find some vector for which the coset a
plus v i
is actually well balanced meaning that
all the vectors in the coset are well
balanced
and we prove this using a case analysis
and also we prove the following two
lemmas
so first we prove that with high
probability a is what we call the thinly
balanced meaning that for any w
in the coset a plus w most members are
well balanced so using this lemma we
control most of the balance parameters
but still we have maybe some
vectors which we don't
know what's going on with them
but for this we prove the second lemma
which mean which states that with a
probability v is what we call a balanced
four sums meaning that for every split
of v
e to two
seeds v equals v 0 plus v 1 there must
exist v i among them such that in the
coset a plus v i all the members are
somewhat balanced
so combining these two
bounds together we get a total bound on
the on the whole the all vectors in the
concept and it turns out to be uh just
enough
okay so this is a
this is a the end of how we prove
the statistical central privacy property
and now let me
tell you about a few words about how are
we going to remove the common random
string here
okay so we have the ss plt protocol
which we just constructed
and first we are going to use a
technique by dwarkend and all of reverse
randomization
and to get
some
middle results
of a protocol where the receiver
security holds for every crs even if
chosen by a malicious sender for example
and then we show how to transform the
the emitted results the middle result to
the
to the construction in the plane model
of ssplt
and here we
randomize the crs
uh using a prg that fools and
non-deterministic cells
which is known to be applied by standard
and disinvictus on style worst case
assumptions
so the challenge here is that we need an
algebraic characterization and it
captures what we call the bet crss
meaning the crss they don't have the ssp
property
so maybe this set of bit crss
cannot be
efficiently certified but maybe what we
show in the paper is that we can find a
bigger set that is still not too big
that is certifiable and it contains all
the bet crs
okay and then we use the prg and the
peer and the
and we we
we have the proof that the prg contains
a lot of good crss
and therefore if two the two parties
execute this pseudo-random generator and
use the outputs as common as the series
says
then it it's enough
and there are more details of course in
the paper
uh okay so the open questions uh
raises up here is
can we achieve accessibility from npn
with better noise
of course and also how expressive is lpn
in the
you know in the next noise regime like n
to the minus epsilon uh can we build the
collision resistance hashing from it uh
what about hardness in sdk and so on and
also in general how far can we push this
assumption of lpn
uh
so thanks
and
if you have questions feel free
thanks for this talk
are there any questions
hello so in azure crypt 21 we have a
paper showing that using a ring lwe it
is possible to give a version of the
protocol it is much more efficient and
also using
can you start obviously i wasn't
can you begin again yeah yeah so in asia
2021 we have a paper with a statistical
center private ot
showing that using ring lwe it is
possible to improve the efficiency but
also simplify part of the proof using
the fact that whenever you have one
short vector you have n linearly
independent ones
and so the question is did you look at
whether using ring lpn it is possible to
do something similar
actually
we didn't talk about training lpn
so
i don't know
thanks so let's thank the speaker again
thank you very much
that brings us to the last talk in this
session it's
called constructive post-quantum
reductions and the papers by
near bhutansky spka bakerski and joel
kalai
and
the talk is going to be given by
nir
hear me at home
okay great
um so hi um i'm near and uh i'd like to
tell you about uh constructive post one
from reductions and this is work with
that's vikka brokerski
and uh yeah collide uh so we're still in
the context of postquantum cryptography
we want to design classical protocols
that we stand quantum adversaries and uh
you know postdoc photography is
something that our community has been
studying for a while
and as you know uh as you know it has
required us to rethink uh many of the
aspects of crypto one obvious thing
is assumptions we can no longer use
assumptions like factoring that are
quantumly broken
we have to turn to new sources of
hardness like lattices
another aspect is how the quantum
adversary interacts with our classical
protocols
but perhaps uh an even more basic aspect
is reductions right
to the
many implications that uh we proved in
the classical setting
also hold in the quantum state for
example
the one-way functions still imply all of
symmetric key
cryptography
and this is going to be our focus today
reductions so let me be
more concrete about this
so
you know uh
we typically construct some
cryptographic primitive p
from an underlying
assumptions thank you
and we would like to show that breaking
p is no easier than breaking q and as
you know the way that we do this is by
designing the sufficient reduction
algorithm that can take any
adversary that breaks b
and use it in order to break right
and such rejections are really the the
bread and butter of uh cryptography um
we've been working on them uh for a
while
and you know it would be a shame if we
would have to redo all these reductions
from the classical setting in order to
achieve post-quantum uh security
um and then you know this this sort of
raises the natural question of like
whether we can lift all the reductions
that we have from the classical setting
into the post-quantum setting
and there seems to be a you know a good
reason to hope that we can do so because
really most of the
reductions that we have in costco crypto
or what we call black box we don't
really care how the adversary is
implemented in particular why should we
care that it's quantum these reductions
uh should still work
but it turns out that this question is
somewhat more nuanced and in particular
this is a known problem saying the
interactive setting
and the reason for that which is
something that xiao already mentioned in
the the first talk
is that something very basic
that the classical reduction would do
is rewind the adversary
some intermediate
point in the protocol
and
the problem is that in the quantum we
have what we call the the observer
effect whenever the reduction sort of
views
the
messages of the adversary its
intermediate quantum state is disturbed
and now we no longer have guaranteeing
what's going to happen next so this
doesn't generally work and as a matter
of fact we can even show examples
of interactive protocols where you have
a classical reduction to say lwe which
is allegedly a post-quantum secure
assumption and yet you can quantumly
break these protocols
so we really don't expect there to be a
post-quantum uh reduction you know
assuming that lwe is really uh both
quantum secure
okay
so let's put aside interactive protocols
and focus on non-interactive limitations
like random generators public key
encryption uh et cetera there are still
of course plenty of reductions in this
uh setting that we would like to uh
carry over uh to the post quantum regime
and you know here it may seem that that
things should work right after all the
adversary has no intermediate state in
the protocol it's a one-time thing you
know the reduction pairs it was a
challenge it immediately spits out an
answer and that's it
but the thing is that we should be a bit
more careful because what we actually
want is we want reductions that would
also work if the adversary has some
quantum auxiliary input
right
and such auxiliary input could come from
different places it could be the result
of expensive pre-processing
uh it could be some intermediate state
in a larger protocol where you're using
your primitive
and so on
but the problem now is that we're going
to encounter the same difficulty that we
just did in the interactive setting
because if we have a reduction that
calls the adversary multiple times
then again the states this auxiliary
quantum state is going to be disturbed
and after we make the first query we
actually have no guarantee whatsoever
on what's going to uh happen next
okay so
perhaps there's a
a simple solution uh to this problem
which is sometime
taken in the in the literature which is
why not just supply the reduction with
multiple copies of this
quantum state then everything should
work perfectly
and the problem with this is that it's
not constructive
right
so in general
you cannot copy a quantum state let
alone do it uh
efficiently
and you know maybe
in some contexts you wouldn't care about
this maybe if all that you care about is
your underlying
assumption q and you're sort of willing
to assume that it holds with respect to
any auxiliary quantum
input regardless of how many copies then
you're fine
uh but i want to argue that in general
we do care and
what we really want is constructive
deductions
and what i mean by that is that we want
the reduction to work
given the adversary and the same quantum
auxiliary input it shouldn't use any
further resources that it cannot
generate on its own
efficiently
and really reduction based cryptography
is is much about this win-win paradigm
right we want that if now someone comes
up with a concrete algorithm a complete
way of breaking our cryptographic scheme
it should immediately lead to some
algorithmic advance right and we should
be able to run this algorithm right here
and right now
and we're really not the first to argue
this this is also something that is
targeted uh classically right this is
why we put a lot of stress on designing
uniform as opposed to non-uniform
reductions
okay
so
another goal um on top of
constructiveness which
the gold doesn't really come up
classically is what we call durability
right like uh what we'd like is for our
reduction to
keep working forever someone actually
gave us an algorithm that breaks our
cryptographic scheme then now we should
have an algorithm that sort of works for
eternity that that is what would happen
in the classical setting we don't want
it to work only once or degrade over
time and then we can no longer use it so
this is another goal which we call uh
durability okay
so now that you know what we want let me
tell you uh what we actually uh show in
this uh work
so
basically we show how to lift a large
class of reductions uh from the
classical setting to the post quantum
city
and these are reductions from
hue to
breaking uh
some other primitive p
that have the following properties so
first the reduction should be black box
this sounds almost inherent for such
general lifting
theorem
uh the second thing is that we want the
reduction to be non-adoptive
meaning that it generates all of its
queries to the adversary ahead of time
and the last restriction is that the
primitive p we're reducing to should be
either a decision assumption like say a
pseudo-random generator
or maybe a search problem but with a few
solutions
and
the post-quantum reductions that we come
up with are all
constructive reductions and they're also
durable okay once you get them you can
sort of use them
forever
now along the way we introduce certain
uh intermediate models of
stateful adversaries that i think that
are interesting on their own even from a
classical perspective and i'll mention
those uh in a bit
and we also show a negative result that
sort of complements the
positive result we showed that this
restriction
on
on p on the the primitive we're reduced
to this restriction to say decision
uh assumptions is somewhat inherent
i probably won't have time to touch this
today but you can look at the paper
okay
so these are the results and for the
remaining time i want to give you a
taste of the techniques
some of you may already recognize this
dog from our video abstract
um
she's really in charge for some of the
techniques in the paper
um okay so
what we do is basically we want to sort
of bridge uh different
adversarial models
our finish line
is you know
what we know okay it's the setting where
classical reductions
actually work
where you're able to sort of make calls
to the same adversary again and again
you know as many times
as you need this is what we call a
stateless adversary
and what we start from and the quantum
setting is quite far from that is what
we call a one-shot adversary okay so we
have an adversary that breaks our scheme
but you know it does so
once and once we
even make a single query
the state is disturbed
we don't know what's going to uh happen
next okay so this is the the gap and we
want to somehow
bridge it
and we're going to do this in
several steps and i'll tell you about
these uh
steps
a little bit
so um
the first step is what we call
transitioning from this one-shot
adversaries to persistent adversaries
so what are persistent adversaries these
are adversaries that sort of you know
they never run out of steam they keep
solving so perhaps their internal state
changes
but the probability that you know they
break your primitive
remains roughly the same okay it still
still remains high
um
over time so these are uh persistent
um adversaries
and uh i'm not going to dive into how we
uh bridge this gap
but in a nutshell we leverage here a
recent quantum rewinding technique
uh but he has a mass owner and
anzandri
but i do want to mention that the
restriction to decision assumption etc
already comes up
here
but as i told you it turns out to be
somewhat inherent
okay
so this is sort of the the first step
now we have
uh a persistent adversary
and perhaps before uh moving on to the
next step we should ask ourselves why
isn't it enough right because now we
have an adversary it's a good you know
it's a good adversary
throughout uh uh time it will keep
breaking our assumptions so you know
what what is missing
and the point is that even though sort
of like the set of instances that the
adversary is able to solve
remains large remains roughly the same
size
it sort of drifts around okay the state
does change and it sort of drifts around
it's it's not really fixed
and this could present a problem for you
know reductions that make multiple
queries that could be very correlated
to each other
okay say like the the goliath levy if
you
think about it and in the extreme case
it would be that after you make your
first query
the state somehow remembers this query
and later on
it wouldn't answer correctly any related
query any query in its area and then
you're in trouble your reduction
won't really work okay
so we can't stop that persistent we have
to uh some somehow move on
and the next model we're going to uh uh
consider is what we call memories
adversaries okay so we're not just
persistent but also memoryless in the
following sense so here the adversarial
strategy is fixed ahead of time
independently of the queries that we're
going to make
but it could still be a different
adversary
at every time point you can think about
it as an adversary that simply has a
clock but otherwise it doesn't keep
any state
so we show how to move from persistent
adversaries to adversaries in uh
in this model
basically we show how to simulate
such uh
memories memoryless
behavior
in the case that our reduction is
non-adaptive so the non-adaptive
nanoductivity requirement already uh
comes up here and this sort of the
the most uh technical part perhaps um
in the paper let me uh tell you about it
at least uh
in uh
in a few words just give you some some
intuition so
we want to simulate this mirrorless
behavior we want to prevent
this extreme event where somehow the
state remembers our queries and then
refuses to answer correlated queries
and the basic idea
is to leverage the fact that after all
the adversary state is polynomially
bound
okay
so you know it only has some limited
memory of
past queries and what we're basically
going to do we're going to somehow flood
it
with queries in a way that prevents it
from sort of
remembering the meaningful
uh queries so let me be a bit more
specific
so whenever we want to make the i query
of the reduction
what we're first going to do is we're
going to sample many dumb equipments
okay we're going to sample many dummy
queries from the marginal of the ice
quarry and we're going to plant our real
query
somewhere at random between these
queries and then perform all these
queries with
our real query hidden between them
to the
uh
to the adversary
and what's the intuition here the
intuition is that the adversary cannot
really tell
the real query from the dummy queries
that come from the the same distribution
and because its memory is bounded it
cannot remember all of them
okay so that's the the intuition and why
it could work
and we actually managed to prove
that such an execution
is delta closed if you look at the the
query answer distribution that you get
it's actually close to an execution with
some predetermined set of oracles so i'm
not going to tell you how to define them
in a word
we're defined only depending on the
dummy queries and not
uh uh the real queries
and to get this closeness we of course
have to make sure that the number of
dummies the number the amount of noise
that we introduce
is sufficiently larger than the number
of qubits in the adversary state
okay so formally this is showing using
quantum mutual information arguments
you can look at the paper okay
so
this is how we bridge uh uh
um
from persistent to to memoryless and
we're still not
at the end
like
the the the gap is that at the moment we
know that at each time stamp we have a
different adversary providing us an
answer where we want to get is we want
to have basically the same
adversarial algorithm answering all of
our work that would guarantee that our
classical reduction would work okay so
this is the the last thing
that we need to bridge and here we show
another sort of uh uh
simulation uh argument
um
in two words the way that that we're
going to do this basically we're going
to answer
every query
with one of these oracles the trend okay
so every query we get we're going to
choose one of these oracles at random
and provide
the answer using that oracle
and here again we're going to leverage
the fact that reduction is non-adaptive
so we can make this random assignment
ahead of time
okay you have to watch out for
collisions etc
but uh
it works out
okay so
this way we eventually uh
bridge
the gap all the way
to the setting where we can actually
apply
our classical reduction
okay
so
we constructed uh all these mini bridges
we uh bridged the uh
the entire gap
and uh as i said i think that uh
this model this the stateful model and
also this uh memory models are pretty
natural to look on uh to look at on
their own right you could ask what can
you do when you have an adversary that
sort of adapts over time is stateful i
think these things uh uh are interesting
uh and in fact uh um
these kind of questions were also uh
explored in a concurrent work
uh by chen freitag and uh in past they
uh call it uh cosmic security uh in
particular this uh last step this
memoryless model and this last shuffling
uh step is also something that uh they
do there
okay
so uh
this is mostly what i wanted to say uh
um
about the techniques and uh the work but
uh i do want to leave you with uh
something to think about uh so what we
showed applies for non-adoptive uh
reductions
and really many perhaps most of the
reductions that we have in frasco crypto
are non-adoptive
but there are some notable examples of
adaptive reductions perhaps the most
notorious ones is pseudorandom
generators from
general one-way functions not say
regular or objective volume functions
but any one-way function this reduction
turns out to be uh
adaptive uh actually i had no idea uh i
discovered this uh recently uh it is
adoptive um so you know it's a very
basic question what what can you do here
and one thing you can try is of course
come up with a non-adaptive reduction
for prgs
from one-way function people have been
trying to do this for a long time good
luck with that
but more generally can we still do this
constructive lifting also in the
adaptive setting maybe this is a very
interesting question
uh okay so uh this is all that i want to
tell you uh thank you
thanks for the nice talk are there any
questions in the audience
um
what about a situation where um the
uh there is a random marker involved so
the adversary uses it so somehow the
reduction has to
simulate it to do any of these
techniques would uh have you thought
about that or do they yeah they won't
really work so this is uh a different
setting so what we considered is
completely non-interactive you can think
about like non-interactive things
there's also some access to an oracle
let's say okay even you know sort of
random functions and uh signatures
um and this is something that uh
uh
we didn't uh look at and their things
are uh
sort of challenging because the
adversary does you know inherently has
an intermediate state between different
oracles
uh and actually there are some
interesting results of also on
an archive or
recently i can tell you about this
offline thank you sure
any other questions
then let's thank the speaker again
that concludes this session on post
quantum crypto thanks everyone for
staying and
please make sure to bring some warm
clothes to the beach can get quite cold
there
you