uh
so good morning everyone
welcome to the session about signatures
we have three talks in this session
and um the first speaker or the first uh
presentation is about
locally verifiable signature and key
aggregation this is the joint work of
rishab goyal and we not by kundalini
and rishabh will give the talk
so mark for the introduction uh am i a
little loud or is that okay
okay
it feels a little loud to me
uh yeah so thanks a lot for being here
especially after the drum session it was
a late night and everybody could make it
it's a larger audience than i was
expecting
but okay so today i'm going to tell you
more about locally verifiable signatures
and pre-aggregation
so the starting point of this talk is
digital signatures which we need no
introduction they are one of the most
basic and fundamental building blocks of
cryptography and basically using digital
signatures we can sign messages
digitally such that they cannot be
forged they cannot be faked by anybody
else and they can verify the
authenticity of the underlying message
and there are tons of applications where
digital signatures are used in trying to
create certificates or in blockchains
for authenticated transactions or for
even as simple uh functionality as
trying to visit a web page we rely on
digital signatures
given the ubiquitous nature of digital
signatures and numerous applications
digital signatures have been studied in
various different models one of the most
well-known models of digital signatures
is also called the aggregate signature
model aggregate signatures are special
types of digital signatures which have
one very special property in addition to
generating digital signatures you can
publicly aggregate a bunch of signatures
an unbounded sequence of signatures into
one single short signature
that typically means consider a sequence
of l messages and signature pairs
if this was an aggregate signature
scheme then you can compress all these l
signatures you can aggregate them into
one single short aggregated signature
and the property is that you can verify
you can use this aggregated signature to
verify all the l messages authenticity
of all the error messages at the same
thereby reducing the total space
requirement on the system
and aggregate signatures have seen tons
of applications because they guarantee
unforgeability for all signed messages
even after you sort of perform this
compression and aggregation step and the
applications range from trying to sort
of compress uh certificate chains or
trying to use them in secure bg uh bgp
route attestations or even in trying to
sort of reduce the footprint of digital
component or the cryptographic component
on blockchains
and due to the ever growing nature of
the number of applications aggregate
signatures unlocks it's very interesting
that
and how many different new ways we can
use aggregate signatures
and although aggregate signatures are
like a fantastic object they have been
studied for numerous decades so far
there are many different variants such
as the single message waiting which is
also called multi-signatures the
synchronized aggregate signatures or
sequential aggregate signatures we have
multiple different constructions ranging
from different assumptions such as
pairings factorings multinational maps
obfuscation whatever you like you can
pick that assumption and come up with an
appropriate
aggregate signature signature scheme
with relevant properties
but given this progress there is just
one big caveat that we face while using
aggregate signatures they're a
fascinating object but they have one big
limitation which has not been addressed
so far
the problem is the cost of aggregate
signatures it comes at the core or just
here the aggregate signatures comes at
the cost of verifying or for having a
larger verification time so the verifier
now needs to read the entire list of
messages that it needs to verify
so basically consider this example where
we have these l messages and signatures
pair
and we have this aggregated signature to
verify this aggregated signature you
need the signature but you also need all
the error messages
and it seems kind of intuitive that you
need to have all the elements that you
are trying to verify
but it turns out what's happening is
that the compression that we're getting
in aggregate signatures that's coming at
the cost of a larger verification time
suppose you only want to verify the
authenticity of one particular message
out of those l messages in an aggregated
signature you still need to read all the
elements you still need to run the
verification algorithm on all different
l messages
and the question that we're interested
in this work is can we basically
aggregate signatures without sort of
spending as much time to verify or more
generally is there a much better
space-time trade-off that we can uncover
if we sort of revisit the notion of
aggregate signatures
so
in this one okay so maybe my pointer is
moving a little bit slower so sorry
about that but yeah this was supposed to
be here right now okay so in this work
what we do is that we study this concept
of locally verifiable aggregate
signatures trying to sort of focus on
this problem trying to fill this gap
which has been left open for the longest
time
and to that and we define these locally
verifiable aggregate signatures and the
intuition behind locally verifiable
aggregate signatures is as follows
that the local verifier can basically
verify an aggregated signature just for
a single message it does not read
read the entire list of messages
and how could we possibly formalize that
so let's just look again at the example
of sign and aggregate so one possible
idea could be okay there is a local
verification algorithm in which the
local verification algorithm just takes
this input an aggregated signature and a
single message and it basically outputs
whether the message is a valid message
or not as per this aggregate signature
so this is the dream version it would be
wonderful if we can build this because
then this gives us not only compression
but also very very fast verification
and
it turns out that if we want a local
verification algorithm which only takes
us a single message
then it's quite good but it's too good
to be true
and the reason is that there's a very
simple incompressibility argument which
you can show you can use to show that
this is impossible and the idea is as
follows suppose there is a sequence of n
messages messages could be integers one
through n and a certain subset of these
messages have been signed and have been
aggregated now you only have the
aggregate signature and suppose these
locally verifiable aggregate signatures
only take us and put a message one
particular message so what you can do is
that you can potentially sequence
sequentially sort of just run through
all the possible messages and check
whether that particular message verified
or not so depending upon which messages
it verified for you can extract the
entire list of messages which have been
aggregated
and using this you can basically recover
the entire list from a short signature
the signature does not grow with the
number of uh messages that have been
aggregated so basically sort of just
here gives us that there's an
incompressibility happening and we can't
sort of just build this dream version of
locally verifiable aggregate signatures
so it seems like maybe there was no
actual there was actually no gap
aggregate signatures best thing that we
can hope for but it turns out that if we
sort of
just maybe turn the tables a little bit
or just think about the problem a little
bit different then there is a way to get
the best of both worlds and our idea in
this case to avoid impossibility what
we're going to design we're going to
give the system a special
uh hint generation algorithm to aid the
local verification so the goal is still
to make sure that the local verification
is very efficient it does not grow with
the entire list of messages that you
have aggregated but maybe we can sort of
just here make sure that there isn't
possibly inefficient processing
algorithm in that case you can generate
some small hints and those hints could
be used to aid the local verification
algorithm and what that means is
we again have this aggregate signature
and now there is a local opening
algorithm or a hint generation algorithm
and this algorithm also takes us input a
target message for which you want to
generate a shorthand and the sequence of
all messages and it basically computes a
shorthand which is independent upon the
of the entire list of messages and now
the idea is that you can simply throw
away this particular
list of messages and just given the
target message
uh the aggregate signature as well as a
shorthand you can sort of just run a
special local verification algorithm to
efficiently verify that this particular
aggregate signature contains is a valid
signature for a signature containing the
message m
so just trying to formalize a little bit
further the local verification algorithm
it takes this input this aggregate
signature message m and this hint h and
tells you whether it's invalid or
invalid uh message
and for security it's very important
that we design these signatures such as
such that we can guarantee
unforgivability even when the adversary
can control or can generate arbitrary
hints because we don't want to rely on
who's generating the hint or particular
the local verifier because the local
verifier doesn't even have the entire
time to verify what the messages look
like
so the idea is basically that an
attacker cannot create an aggregate
signature as well as a hint such that it
is a valid uh signature and hint pair
for a particular message that was not
signed by the challenger
and if you don't sort of satisfy this
property then it's insecure if you
satisfy this property then you can sort
of just yeah have this best of both
worlds
but at this point you might be thinking
okay what's really going on we said that
it's kind of impossible but we designed
this local opening algorithm or the
local uh hint generation algorithm that
sort of just tried to aid this
particular primitive locally verifiable
aggregate images but why is it still
interesting why can we sort of just
still use that in many applications so
let me sort of just here run through
some potential applications where we can
actually use the local verification
algorithm as we have designed
so consider the example of uh
certificate transparency logs so
certificate of transparency is just an
internet standard in which we basically
have multiple certificates which are
stored by uh in a certificate log which
which verify the authenticity of
different web pages so in that case
suppose a web browser needs to access
and verify that a particular thing is
valid or not it needs to go to the
certificate transparency log it needs to
verify the authenticity but what happens
is that the certificate transparency log
is pretty big using aggregate signatures
we can compress the entire footprint the
memory footprint that uh the log needs
to keep
but if we use aggregate signatures then
each verifier which is simply basically
a web browser or a particular small in a
very
low level device that needs to read the
entire list of messages to verify that
transparency law but using locally
verifiable aggregate signatures we can
just provide a small hint to the
verifier so we can not only reduce the
footprint on the server but you can also
provide a short hint using which a
verifier can efficiently verify the
validity and we can sort of also sort of
just imagine the same to be happening in
blockchains imagine alice is a tenant
that pays monthly rent to bob and alice
sends some money over block over bitcoin
monthly or whatever the rent is but bob
doesn't want to store all these
different transactions as different
signatures it wants to store all these
aggregate them together and store like
one single aggregated signature in its
particular uh
in its particular wallet but now what
happens is that uh whenever bob wants to
spend this particular aggregate
signature then it has to sort of provide
all the sequence of messages but using
aggregate these local verifiability
property it can just generate a local uh
a hint a short hint using which it can
spend just one of those particular
transactions it does not need to share
all those transactions and it turns out
just having this not only gives us an
efficiency gain but also provides us
some type of privacy guarantee because
when you compress this then the
shorthand is not going to leak all the
information about the remaining
transactions and i can go on and tell
you more about applications through
redactable signatures or even sort of
just a general time space trade-offs
which locally verifiable aggregate
signatures sort of unlock so here is a
table that's also present in the paper
but it basically captures that using
locally verifiable aggregate signatures
we can basically cover the entire spread
spread of what was covered by a banner
of signatures or aggregate signatures or
just using locally verifiable signatures
directly so we can sort of just create
like a very smooth trade-off between the
server space the server time the per
client space or the perk line running
time and how these things can be sort of
just here depending upon your
applications you can choose the
appropriate parameters and make the use
of this particular smooth trade-off
and i want to emphasize before going
forward that all these applications this
still makes sense even if we are working
in a single sinus setting a single sinus
setting for aggregate signatures
basically says that there is a single
party whose whose signatures we are
trying to verify
and the reason we want to or we are
trying to aggregate because uh in for
example in the case of blockchains alice
is sending the payment to bob each month
alice is the same party you still want
to sort of just accumulate aggregate all
the particular uh transactions that
alice has performed
so just trying to study this object in
the single sinus setting is already very
useful because it unlocks even just
these interesting applications
now in the remaining talk i'm going to
sort of just here tell you about the new
constructions and feasible results that
we obtain about
these locally verifiable aggregate
signatures
and the constructions that we obtain are
we obtain certain new practical
constructions
from rsa and
pairing based assumptions and also we
get a feasibility result from snarks
although it's not super efficient it
just tells us that the best possible
version of uh locally verifiable
aggregate signatures is also possible
because the practical constructions that
we obtain they are only in the single
server setting whereas the using snarks
we can show that we can achieve this
general model of locally verifiable
aggregate signatures the only difference
is that in the general model there could
be multiple different users whose
signatures you want to aggregate and you
want to open it at a later point in a
single sinus setting there's a fixed
single sign-in and you want to aggregate
signatures and later open just one of
them or a few of them efficiently
so next let me just here tell you how to
actually design these locally verifiable
aggregate signatures and the focus of
the remaining talk is going to be on the
factoring based signatures
in the single sinus setting and towards
the end i'll quickly mention how we can
use these ideas and the underlying
algebra in a similar way over pairings
as well to unlock the same potential in
or for pairings and how they can sort of
just potentially be used in snarks also
but if uh let's just see if we can get
to stocks or not today
but uh yeah so the starting point of how
to design um
using uh factoring based assumptions how
to design these particular signatures
let's just revisit the most fundamental
object from rs that we know which is the
classical rsa based signature scheme and
the idea is that the verification key
contains an rsa modulus n
and an exponent e a prime exponent e and
a signature on a message m is simply you
hash the message and you take the eth
root of the hashed message to verify you
simply check whether uh the signatures
eith power is the message that you want
to verify
that's just revisiting the classical rss
scheme
and
it turns out although it has not been
formally defined to the best of our
knowledge there is a very simple
folklore way of trying to aggregate
these particular signatures in the
single sinus setting and the idea is
very simple just multiply all these
signatures
and that's going to be your aggregate
signature so suppose you have these
signatures h of m one the e the e f root
of h of m one and the e th root of
picture of m l and all of these things
and you can just multiply all of them
together and the sigma hat is just going
to be the multiplication of all these
elements and that's going to be an
aggregate signature
and now to verify this particular
aggregate signature what you can do is
that you can raise the aggregate
signature sigma hat to the eighth power
and check whether that equals the
product of all the messages that you
want to add that you wish or that you
want to check have been aggregated in
this particular signature
so okay so first step is done we know
how to create single sign and aggregate
signature schemes from rsa based
assumptions now the question is that can
we make this to be locally verifiable
so local verifiably the verifiability
simply says that first we need to create
or we need to understand how we can
create these short hints which will make
sure that the local verification can be
spreader
so to that end an idea is very simple
that to make sure that they can be
locally verified we can sort of create
this as the following hint suppose you
have these l messages m1 up till ml and
there's a target message m that you want
to open this particular signature too
and you want to create a short hint for
it so the hint you can sort of sort of
said to be it could be the product of
all the hashed messages except the
target message
and you can efficiently compute this
because this is just in the base of the
rsm modules
and now the idea is that given this you
can perform this local verification
check to be sigma hat raised to the
power e is equal to v
h the hint times the hash of the target
message and that's how we can
potentially verify
and now everybody must be thinking okay
all is good it seems like by just
performing this pre-processing we can
efficiently make sure that local
verification can be done
but there's a big problem here and the
problem is that this is totally insecure
because the hint can be adversarial the
adversary can create any arbitrary hint
and there is no structure that we are
enforcing or we can even check because
we don't have all the messages that were
signed because the messages are lost
once you sort of just generate this hint
i can't have access those particular
messages because that's the whole point
and for example consider h to be one
over h of m and sigma had to be one
that's basically a valid forgery on this
particular scheme
so it seems like
maybe it's unclear how to sort of
aggregate signatures using this rs
landscape but what can we do
now our observation is that the issue
the issue that we're facing here is that
the hint that we're generating in this
case it's just product of all these hash
value of these messages it's totally
unstructured
and we cannot ensure well-formedness of
the hint
anyhow without sort of just reading
through all the other messages
now how to get around this problem the
idea that we employ is that we're going
to sort of just switch the base and the
exponent we're going to move the
messages to the exponent and sort of
just keep in a way the
the rsa part on the messages rather than
on just like a fixed exponent and what i
mean by that is so consider the phoning
scheme in this the verification keys
contains again an rsa modulus and some
base element g
and a signature now is the h of m root
of g g is part of the verification key
and to verify this particular signature
you just raise this the signature to h
of m and you match it to be the element
g that was present in the digital
signatures and this is basically the
gennaro halevi and rosario's
signature scheme that was sort of
defined in the late 90s and it has been
the basis of many other
uh interesting signature schemes so the
idea is that the structure or the the
inversion is happening on on um it's not
happening on a fixed prime but on a
prime that depends upon the message
now let's see how we can potentially
verify this or locally aggregate this or
simply just aggregate this again if we
have the sequence of messages m1 ml and
their corresponding signatures g raised
to the power 1 over h of m1 up till 1
over h of ml
the idea is that again multiply all of
them that's going to be an aggregate
signature
and to verify this aggregate signature
what you're going to do now is that
you're going to raise sigma hat the
aggregate signature
to all the hashed messages not just one
prime all these particular hash messages
and you're going to check that it equals
a product of l terms and each of these l
terms is itself g raised to the power
all but one particular hash message
so you basically omit one particular
hash message because there is one over h
of m i in that particular right hand
side on the top part
so
seems like hopefully you understand that
completeness of the scheme of this
aggregate signature scheme does follow
now the question remains that can be we
have made this switch we have make sure
that the structure of uh this thing is
switched it's in the exponent can we use
this to make sure that we can come up
with a locally verifiable aggregate
signature can we generate efficient
hints for it
and it turns out yes we actually can so
and yeah i forgot to mention this but
i'm assuming for simplicity that h of m
is always a prime and we can handle this
by sort of very well known techniques
i'll but i'll defer
that to later so let's just see how to
sort of potentially
uh
generate a hint suppose i want to
generate the hint for the first message
m1
now the idea is going to be the verifier
simply checks this particular equation
i'm going to use a notation that h of i
is equal to the hash of the message mi
now i'm going to write the rewrite the
left hand side as all the hash values
except the first hash value so sigma hat
raised to the power h2 h3 up till hl and
h1 on the outside and similarly i'm
going to
divide the right hand side into two
components one that depends upon
that does not depend upon h1 the other
one it depends upon h1 and the remaining
terms
and now the idea is that so for example
consider that uh l is equal to four then
in that case this basically simply means
that the equation is that sigma hat
raised to the power h2 h3 h4
and h1 is equal to be
g times h2 h3 h4 and g times h2 h3 plus
h2h4 h3h4 raised to the power h1 so
that's basically the verification check
that we're performing
now the point is if you sort of just
focus in on these circled components you
look at the product of his here here and
the sum product of h is
then these terms do not depend upon h1
they depend upon the remaining messages
and this is what we can pre-compute and
set it to by our hint because during the
hint generation process we know all the
messages so we can generate these hashes
and we can sort of just perform the
simple arithmetic operation
the idea is that this is basically going
to be a hint for this particular message
m1 now to verify this local or just
verify this particular message for the
aggregate signature you're going to
simply sort of check the following
equation that sigma hat raised to the
power the first element of the
hint value
times h1 is equal to ga times gb raised
to the power h1
that basically substitutes these circle
values with a and b in this particular
equation
so it means that we are able to get
these
simple properties that we can
efficiently verify this
and the intuition behind security is
that
you can simply rewrite the equation on
the right hand side as follows you can
move all the h1 dependent components on
the left side
and you can rewrite it as follows that
sigma hat to the a divided by g b raised
to the power h1 is equal to ga
and it turns out now you basically use
the fact that if adversary finds a
forgery sigma hat such that this is
satisfied then in that case i can use
that to find the h1 root of a known
element because g is like a known
element we can sort of just use some
clever algebra to make sure that we can
sort of just create a forgery out of it
create like the rsa challenge out of
this
so it seems like great
everything seems to work we have
generated hints we have kind of argued
how security might hold
but it turns out if you look a little
more closely then it's very simple but
it's flawed and the reason it's flawed
is that the hints are very large and the
hints are large because uh we don't know
what v of n is and
because v of n guarantees what security
is and fee of n is required to reduce
the elements in the exponent without
knowing p of n we have to compute these
as integers and integers multiplying
these n integers or l integers that's
going to be o of l bits that's pretty
large so it seems like we're back to
square one we perform some processing
but again we could not sort of just
solve this
but to this end sort of just one very
simple trick or just the well-known
chummy's trick came to our savior so
it's just what xiaomi strict says it
says given elements x y alpha and beta
such that x a x to the alpha is equal to
y to the beta and alpha and beta are
co-prime there is a way to efficiently
find the alpha root of y
so now we can use this ramis trick over
here and sort of simply rewrite this
particular equation so that again we can
put h1 related components on the left
hand side h1 independent components on
the right hand side i can say this is
going to be my x
this is going to be my beta that's going
to be the alpha that's going to be the y
so i can generate g raised to the power
1 over h 1 using chemistry in this
particular way
and that's basically my hint
and to verify this particular hint you
can sort of just raise it again to h1
and that's going to be equal to g and if
that's true then you can verify the
signature but if you focus a little more
you might imagine that this you might
sort of just
understand that this particular hint has
a wonderful property that it's not just
a hint that you can use to verify the
hint is actually the signature for this
particular message m1 so it turns out
this scheme has a wonderful property
that not only we can compress signatures
but we can perfectly decompress all the
signatures typically whenever we think
of cryptographic compression we lose
information here we are observing not
only we can compress but we can
perfectly decompress so just really the
magic of number three at play where we
can sort of perform local verification
but also recompute the original
signature entirely
and just trying to sum up quickly about
locally verifiable aggregate signatures
the main technical tool is that we
ensure this well formless can be
automatically performed in the exponent
without uh us doing anything because
some at a very high level happening is
that if you write the chinese remainder
theorem sort of terms in the exponent
then they're going to sort of align very
well and they're not going to intersect
with different terms and that's going to
really help us
but what's very cute about this
construction is that the hinge
generation tells us that we can
perfectly uncompute or create the actual
original signature from aggregate
signatures and this is the number theory
magic at play and uh one thing that i
was sort of just here hiding in the rug
which was this how to sample how to hash
messages in a deterministic way to
primes but we can rely on sort of just
known techniques due to mikali raven and
wadahan and for loops where they sort of
just use these techniques in the
literature of verifiable random
functions but we can use those ideas to
prove security in the static setting or
also in the full security in the
numerical setting
so just trying to summarize we gave new
constructions from rsn pairings and
although i won't have time to tell you
that how to get it from pairings but
there's a kind of interesting uh
comparison or like a juxtaposition that
you can do for these techniques and i'd
be happy to talk about that later but
let me sort of just try to summarize
that in this work we sort of introduced
the concept of local verification for
application signatures circumventing and
defining that there is an impossibility
we can sidestep it and this still lets
us new applications and sort of just
interesting space time tradeoffs
and next we also sort of show how to
develop these new algebraic techniques
which unlock this amazing property about
the rsa signatures which was not known
before that we can not only compress
information but also perfectly
decompress it which seems fascinating to
us it'd be happy to sort of just
understand that why it's real i mean
it's happening the math works out but
it's really it's bizarre and also sort
of just really fun and i forgot to
mention but the painting-based
signatures that we came up with they
also have interesting properties that
the openings are fully public you don't
need the signature even to sort of come
up with the opening it can be performed
in a totally offline phase and we gave a
result about feasibility from starks and
also i didn't get to mention but it's in
the paper and we're happy to talk about
later that we also show that we can
extend the aggregation concept to secret
to encryption systems as well where
multi-user encryption systems
and sort of this sort of just leads to
many interesting questions that can we
come up with more applications of these
algebraic techniques or can we sort of
just here come up with these general
models general model solution for
locally verifiable aggregate signatures
and even can we
study the concept of aggregation beyond
ibe for which we have interesting
results or other non-encryption-based
systems
and yeah so thank you so much and be
happy to take any questions but i think
we are time for questions
so if there's any quick questions please
come up to the front of the microphones
yeah so i guess a quick question i
assume since you didn't call this talk
de-aggregateable signatures the
pairing-based construction isn't as nice
as the rsa construction
do you think it's possible though to
come up with a pairing based system
where you can recover the original
signature
okay so in case uh hopefully everybody
sort of just heard the question it's a
great question can you get uh the
perfect decompression property out of
anything else other than uh factoring
based assumptions i've been thinking
about it i don't know yet i i can't
answer this because i don't know that's
that's the short answer it'd be
wonderful if we can do it uh you can
probably throw a bunch of assumptions
but just purely doing from bilinear maps
i don't see it right away maybe
something could be done that'd be very
fascinating too but i don't know right
now how to do it
thanks yeah thanks for the question
again
you know
i'm a bit puzzled by the
incompressibility argument that you you
presented because when you have a
signature you have many messages for
which the signature is valid in
including the one you're looking for so
in
when you you have exhaustive search you
will find many other messages so it
doesn't really decompress
uh
do you mean the incompressibility
argument is doesn't guarantee that you
can extract all signatures correctly is
that the question so
in the incompressibility argument you
presented you say that from the
aggregate signature
you should be able to
uncompress all the message all the
messages which have been signed by
exhaustive search but if you do so you
will have a much bigger set so you won't
you won't have the original set of
messages
so it's not really decompressing so i
wonder if this argument has been
formally proven that you cannot have any
uh locally verifiable aggregate
signature all right
is there any other stuff okay i
understand the question okay let me uh
please clarify in case i'm not
misunderstanding the question the
question is that typically i'm assuming
that the messages that the the the set
of messages for which we are trying to
sort of just locally aggregate them that
is a priority known and that's a fixed
size set for which you can kind of over
basically do like a brute force search
and so just come up with the this
testing operation but if the message
says exponential size
in that case how to sort of just make
sure that you can potentially sort of
just here follow the same uh
incompressibility argument is that the
question
so i wonder if the argument that you
presented is formally programmed yeah it
is formula one yeah it's in the paper
yeah i'd be happy to talk about it yeah
it is
all right let's thank the speaker again
so next up is a
talk about
multi-model private signatures this is a
work by kawa nugent
willie susilo and women young
and unfortunately the speaker could be
here at scoring
and we're going to run a video of his
presentation and i see
kevin has already set up the video so
i guess i guess kevin you can get it
rolling
hello everyone i am from the university
of wollongong australia
today i am going to talk about new
approach to address the tension between
privacy can you please wait up a second
on zoom can you please hold up thank you
okay now you can return
thank you
hello everyone i am wing from the
university of wollongong australia
today i am going to talk about new
approach to address the tension between
privacy and accountability in multi-user
authentication systems
this is a child work with my colleagues
at the university of wollongong fujungo
willie sushilon and bomin yang
we call our new cryptographic primitive
multimodal private signatures
here in the plan of my talk
first i will discuss several prominent
examples of previous multi-user
signature systems with privacy and
accountability features
and our observation regarding their
shortcomings
then i will demonstrate how our new
primitive can
address these
shortcomings
next i will sketch our definitions and
constructions from multimodal private
signatures
finally i will list
several interesting questions that we
left open
let us first consider the setting of
principle majors
one of the most well-known private
signature systems
we have a group of users
each user has a secret signing key which
can be used to sign message
in an anonymous manner
here signup
personal identifiable information id can
issue a signature on any message
in a way such that the signature
verifiers can be convinced that a
signature was from someone in the group
but cannot determine who is
the actual assignment
here
green signature provides absolute
privacy for signers
absolute anonymity could be a nice
feature that protects the users in
certain situations
such as visual blogging
however it can also be abused for
unethical or illegal purposes
therefore
it would be desirable to restrict the
acceptance anonymity of users in ring
signatures
in fact
there have been several attempts such as
linkable resignations or traceable
resignations
however the linking and tracing
mechanisms in this system
can only be activated if the signer is
questions has generated at least two
signatures
if a malicious signer only issue one
controversial signature and then went
offline forever
then it can avoid accountability
it will look for a primitive offering
both anonymity and accountability
then the most well-known example is
group signature
in group signature we have an opening
authority
whose secret can be used to trace any
very signature and recover the identity
of the signer
this authority is supposed to take
action only in case of disputes
but wait if zig authority is corrupted
then it can open all signatures at will
and in that case there is essentially no
privacy for users
there have been several attempts to
restrict the power of the opening
authority in group signatures
such as traceable signatures group
signatures with message dependent
opening are accountable facing
signatures
however in this system there is always a
party who can break
signers privacy without any consent
so on the one hand we have ring
signature
and variants that give too much
privilege for users
on the other hand we have group
signatures and variants that provide too
much power
for the authorities
finding a solution that is reasonably
fair for more users and have authorities
a solution that balance privacy and
accountability
was a challenging problem
for a long time
a new approach towards solving this
tension was proposed last year at
eurocrypt
in a work by libert myself
with us and jung
we introduced bifurcated anonymous
signatures of bias for short which can
be seen as a hybrid of ringside natures
and good signatures
more precisely
a given bias could be traceable or
nontraceable
depending on a predicate big p
computed by the signer before signing
if p is is
zero then the signature is not traceable
and the authority can learn nothing
about ali as in ringside nature
if p is one then the signature is
traceable
and the authority can recover id
as in group signatures
since the user knows p in advance
it can control its privacy and
accountability
in the traceable case it can decide
whether to sign the given message or not
on the other hand
the authority can also ensure that
signers of all traceable signatures will
be kept accountable
so
bias
seems to have provided a nice solution
to the tension between privacy and
accountability
however
there are still problems
there is in fact a crucial disadvantage
of bias
approved signatures and all similar
proposals
we observe that accountability in these
systems
is realized
via a total tracing procedure
during which the whole identity of the
trace users must be disclosed to the
authorities
this level of accountability
is indeed a serious violation of users
privacy
why privacy
can be a very complicated notion
in its previous sense it can be defined
as the right of an individual
to control
which piece of information about herself
or himself can be disclosed
furthermore in many real-life situations
it is not necessarily
the highest priority for authorities to
perform a total basing
for instance
the authorities could only be interested
in learning whether
an anonymous user is over 18 years old
r works in a given organization
r lives in a particular area
r has an annual income exceeding certain
threshold
r has been fully vaccinated against
covet knighting etc
this observation motivated us to
consider systems
in which users and authorities have
certain agreement
on which
piece of information
can possibly be disclosed for each
signature
our proposal can be summarized as
follows
when setting up a system we specify a
list of signing functions and a list of
k disclosing functions
denoted by g1 t2 and so on to gk
where k is a positive integer if user id
wants to sign message m with respect to
assigning function f
then it first computes
f of m w and id
where w is an auxiliary information that
we call a witness
it serves
as an evidence
for the solubility
of the toggle mw and id
the value of f is an integer between 0
and k
if it is 0
then m cannot be signed
and the user aborts
otherwise
when f is non-euro the user can generate
a very signature that is anonymous to
everyone
but the opening authority
so
what the opening authority can learn
then
if x is equal to 1 then it can learn the
function g 1 of id
and nothing else
if f is j for some integer j then it can
learn the function t j of id and nothing
else
the value of f indeed determines which
disclosing function will be activated
looking back our proposal captures
ring signatures group signatures and
bias as special cases
ring and group signatures correspond to
the case of a single disclosing function
for releasing natures it is the euro
function
for group signatures it is the identity
meanwhile
bias corresponds to the case of two
disclosing functions
the euro
function and z identity functions
as an example application
let us consider a scenario where we have
anonymous financial transactions
each has a hidden amount of money such
as in the privacy preserving
cryptocurrency system monero
the authority for instance can regulate
the system as follows
when an amount less than 100
the transaction will be anonymous to
everyone including the authority
however
when the amount is between 100 and 1000
the authority will be able to learn
the country of the center
when the amount is between 1000 and 10
thousands
the authority can identify the country
and the organization of the center
finally
for an amount at least 10 thousand
then the full identity of the center can
be traced
in other words we can have a
fine-grained accountability feature
depending on the underlying transaction
amounts
the authority can learn different pieces
of information about the center
now let me summarize our contributions
first we propose the concept of
multi-modal private signatures or mps
which is a new approach for addressing
the tension between privacy and
accountability in multi-user signature
systems
signatures in mbs are anonymous to
everyone
except the opening authority
who can learn some virtual information
of
the user identity
that piece of information can be defined
in a flexible and fast manner
based on a set of disclosing functions
privacy
is naturally achieved in nps
because signer can decide
which piece of personal information can
be disclosed
accountability is also achieved
since the authority can learn the
desirable information if needed
next we provide rigorous definitions for
mps
this step is quite exciting and is not
straight forward at all
we would like to make our definitions as
general as possible
by capturing not only the privacy and
accountability of green group and biased
natures
but also the five grand concerns on who
can sign which message
as in attribute-based policy-based and
functional signatures
it is also worth highlighting
that
the privacy definitions for mps is quite
involved since we have to address the
case
where the opening authority is fully
corrupted this level of privacy is
impossible to achieve
in ordinary root signatures
we provide a generic and modular
construction of mbs for arbitrary
functions based on commonly used
cryptographic building blocks
our construction can be instantiated in
the standard model from pairings
we also obtain a concrete lattice-based
construction in the random oracle model
regarding security of mps will require
two main properties privacy and
enforceability
privacy roughly ensures that each party
in the system
can only learn the piece of sinus
information which designer intends to
disclose
there are in fact two notions of privacy
that we should consider
first without the oa secret key it
should be infeasible for everyone to
learn anything
about
designers private information
second
even a fully corrupted oa
can not learn anything beyond the value
tj of id
this is
a very strong requirement indeed
unfoldability captures several
requirements first it should be
infeasible to generate a very signature
with respect to a turbo
mwid which is not assignable
second it should also be invisible to
mislead the signature opening
and third no one even a coalition of
corrupted group manager and
corrupted opening authority
can issue signatures on behalf of an
honest user
the second and the third requirements
in fact resemble the notions of full
traceability and non-flammability in
dynamic root signatures
in terms of constructions we obtain a
generic construction of mps for
arbitrary science functions and
arbitrary disclosing functions
the construction relies on commonly used
cryptographic building blocks
namely ordinary resources nature's ccseq
public inclusion and non-interactive
neurologic proof for general statements
as a feasibility result the construction
can be realized in the standard model
from parents
via the growth of slovsky hypo system
and from lattices via the parker's
saharan roof system
our construction follows the
size and encrypts improved paradigm
which is typically used for designing
good signatures
the group manager
certified the membership
by assigning the user's identity
when issuing a signature the user
encrypts something
improves welfareness of ciphertext as
well as knowledge of a valid membership
certificate
note that in group signature user
typically encrypts its phone identity id
in bias the ciphertext contains either
id or euro
here the main difference
is that cyber self-attack contains
exactly what needs to be disclosed
proven well-formed of such a subject in
general knowledge is the most important
step of the construction
as illustrations we instantiate the
system with concrete signing and
disclosing
functions
the correct evaluation of which can be
efficiently proved in your knowledge
we obtain a parent-based construction in
the standard model as well as a
lattice-based scheme in the random
oracle model that potentially enjoys
most quantum security
to be more specific in both
instantiations we consider the setting
with a single signing function f and
four disclosing functions
we let message m
be a commitment to witness w and define
function f
based on integer ranges
this is to capture our motivating
example about anonymous financial
transactions with hidden amounts
we also consider this closing function
as linear transformation
of id which are sufficient for many
applications
the bearing based and let bay
construction follow the same paradigms
as the generic consumption but we employ
some of
the
dedicated building blocks for efficiency
reasons
specifically the bearing basically
employs medicine commitment
a structured preserving signature by
clintus on the bonnevillian signature
tap based bke by
kings and the ghost sahibus
meanwhile
the lag-based scheme used the ktx
commitment a signature scheme with
efficient protocols by libertarian
ccseq pke obtained from the gbvib and
the csk transformation
and the stern-like neural argument
systems
finally
as the first work on multi-modal private
signature
we do not expect to provide a totally
thorough study of this primitive
we leave several interesting open
questions for future
investigations
the first question
is to construct
practically usable npsc schemes which
expands expressive signing and scoring
disclosing functions
designing efficient mps schemes with
both quantum security is also a
fascinating question
note that our proposed parent based and
lagged weight consumption
do capture quite expressive functions
but are not very efficient
from the theoretical perspective
it is worth studying the connections
between mps and other advanced
primitives
like functional encryption
in fact
the idea that decryption reveals a
function of the identity
is closely related to the spirit of
functional encryption
however
so far we have been unable to obtain a
conception of mbs based on
functional encryption
another appealing question is to equip
mbs with
additional functionalities such as
verifiable opening
of user revocations
and let me conclude my presentation here
thank you for your attention
i am happy to answer your questions
either online after the talk
or via emails thank you
okay i think q a will be very short in
case you have any question you can
contact the authors by email and you i
guess you are able to find the email in
the paper
and send you questions there
all right
so this brings us to the final
presentation of the session
so the title of the paper is pi cut shoe
and friends compact blind signatures by
a parallel instance cutting shoes and
more
and this is a paper by rocha tone
character
duchenne hanslick julian los angeles
benedict wagner
and we have actually two presenters
benedict and rochaton will present the
work together
slides are there
you can see the slides in zoom as well
it's like running a video so a quick
view of the talking in backward
direction
now we're good to go
uh
hello okay hello um so today uh we're
gonna present uh pikachu and friends
come compact line signatures via
parallel instance cut and shoes and more
um this work is a joint work with los
lucian julian anna and benedict
lucian julian and benedict are from
cispa and anna and i are from brown
today the talk is going to be split into
two parts the first part i will talk
about in the second part benedict will
present it
uh so first uh what are blind signatures
blind signatures introduced by david
chom
there's a cryptographic protocol
including a signer and a user
the signer controls the secret key while
the user has a message that it wants to
be signed without designer knowing the
message
at the end the user will receive a
signature
so why do we care about buying
signatures
it's because there are applications such
as unlinkable payment system electronic
cash also voting
our goal here is to
get a blind signature construction that
have efficient parameters these comes in
the front the form of
the signature size and also
the communication complexity
so what security
properties do we want for client
signatures
the first one is called blindness
um
here um an adversarial signer um when
interacts with users and even if it at
the end it sees the message and
secondary pairs
designers can still
can still not um link these message and
secondary pairs back to which protocol
execution it was from
um the second security is
unforgivability property
uh in particular uh one more
enforceability
um so here we have an adversarial user
interacting with designer
um the user can interleave the protocol
executions as as it wants and then
after some number of signing sessions is
completed the user cannot learn more
than that number of messaging signature
pairs
um note here that um
here you don't want to use a normally
used unforgivability definition because
because of the blindness property and
the challenger does not know
if a new
message in signature fair outputted is a
new one or not
um
so
what is state of the art for blind
signatures
in the random oracle model where our
work is also based on
there are many of efficient
constructions
however some of them uses non-standard
assumptions such as interactive
assumptions uh for example one more
discrete law or something like that
um
some others efficient constructions
does not support polynomial number of
signatures
in particular um their security grantee
only allow
logarithmic number of signatures to be
issued
and there are also works that although
it's not that efficient but supports
polynomial number of signatures and also
uses standard assumptions
the goal is to find
a construction that is efficient
supports polynomial number signatures
and also um utilizes standard
assumptions
and now before we go into uh
into our um we'll introduce the work
that our is based on
we call it the boosting transform
so from the state-of-the-art slide
before
there are these signatures that
are secure
only when you
issue logarithmic number of signatures
we'll focus on a certain class called
the linear blind signatures
which is a three move blind signatures
as this one
so from last year ac
cuts laws in rosenberg uh
introduced a boosting transform that
transformed these linear bias signatures
into one a blind signature that supports
polynomial number of
signatures to be issued
the technique used here is
one other than cutting choose in the end
interaction
um so why does
so why does this transform work
um one of the properties of the linear
blind signature is that
the reduction or designer can simulate
the signing protocol without using the
key
if it knows the message and randomness
that the user is using
and here when you do cut and choose
um
the user has to commit the randomness
and the messages
that it's going to be using in the
protocol sends it to the designer and in
this case in the random oracle model the
reduction can
extract these randomness and messages
from the random oracle and then
use them to simulate
the
signing protocol
and you might wonder why we have to use
these it's because the linear blind
signature only supports logarithmic num
issue hello hello sorry
um
and that means that
for
for us for this for the construction to
support polynomial number of signatures
um we have to
a lot of those signatures to be
outputted in the reduction has to
come without using the
secret key
and here i'll outline what the boosting
transform does
in the end interaction designer just
sends
a number and saying that here we're
doing one out of encounter and choose
the user
then the user commits its randomness
sends back to the designer then they
interact and
the underlying
linear blind signature protocol
and then the signer picks one of these
and
protocol execution
and then the user opens the randomness
that it commits
before for all but the selected session
and then they complete the protocol
uh
you can see that there are these steps
that takes um
communication complexity with linear
dependency on n
and this is um inefficient
so for our results
um we use the same technique
and get the same result as
the boosting transform but we have a
communication complexity with
logarithmic
dependency on n
and so
from the boosting transform what we do
is that
these four steps here
okay
these four steps here um
we made changes to them so that the
communication complexity is reduced
um for the first one
we just
for the end commitments we just commit
them using a random oracle into one
commitment and sends them from the users
designer
the same is for for these challenges in
the
third part here
and then for the first messages sent
from the signer to the user
um
we have the signer only generate log end
of them and let the user derive um any
of them from there
uh so what about the last step of
opening the commitment
um so here
we use a cryptographic primitive called
punctuable pseudo random function or ppr
from sahai and waters in 2014
here we use the seed and then use the
pbrf to generate and pseudorandom values
we can reveal some of these
and the rest are still hidden
however
in random oracle model we can
uh instantiate the pprfs using the
random oracle and
the gtm3 construction and
when we review the values we can get the
communication to log n times the number
of non-revealed values
and here
to apply this to the cut and choose
transform um
so at first we can use the pbrf to
generate the randomness
and since we review all but one of the
selected sessions
here um we only have log communication
and we reduce the communication
complexity
and the next part benedict's gonna take
over
thanks so uh yeah i will present the
second part of this talk
um
so champ showed you this this generic
transform that that we have um from a
logarithmically secure linear blind
signature scheme to a fully secure blind
signature scheme and it is efficient in
terms of signature sizes in fact it was
before we started and our new version of
it is now also efficient in terms of
communication
the problem is that if we want to put
this to practice there are still a lot
of challenges for us to solve
let me let me show you why so the first
challenge is okay there's a gigantic
security loss from the underlying
assumption to this linear blind
signature scheme and this is actually
inherited
in our fully secure scheme
okay so the second problem that we have
is that the concrete communication
complexity
while it depends logarithmic on this
parameter n the coefficient
associated to this term depends on the
assumption i will explain why this is
the case in a minute
but in combination these two lead to
very inefficient concrete parameters so
we did some example calculation for the
case of version or instantiation and in
fact if you want to support 2 to the 30
signatures then you need to use a 12 000
bit size group which is clearly
impractical
okay so
let's look at this communication in a
bit more detail
where do we start from actually it so
mentioned we start with this linear
blind signature scheme where we have
this free message flow we send some r
get a challenge c send a message s
and this r is the image of some
lowercase r under a linear function for
example exponentiation in a in a cyclic
group
and now when we do this boosting
transform we have to send in our new
version logarithmic number of these r's
from the signer to the user
and
of course the size of one r depends on
this option
okay so this is the problem for our
communication so why
don't we just drop this first message
and go to a two-round scheme
so in this case we use bls
you will see why
in a few slides just trust me now that
this is a good choice you don't have to
understand all these details if you
don't know the scheme already what is
important for us is that we check
if we can still apply this boosting
transform right so for the boosting
transform we need essentially two
properties the first one champ already
mentioned this is
we call it property star because it's
important
you can simulate the signer side without
having the secret key
as soon as you know the message and the
randomness
okay you can do that by programming the
random oracle and the second property is
logarithmic security
okay so for blind bls we still have the
first property you can just uh if you
know the message you can and the alpha
you can cancel out the alpha and use the
standard way of
simulating bls signatures
okay but the problem is the second
property because for this scheme if we
want to rely on non-interactive
assumptions then we only have key only
security so to recall in a signature
scheme key only security means that the
adversary does not have access to a
signing oracle
and only to the public key
okay
so um this means that we need to
understand how we can change our
boosting transform to support key only
security right because now it only
supports logarithmic security
for that we introduced this new
technique parallel instance cut and
choose or for short pikachu
and to understand it we need to first
understand how does the original
boosting transform by cuts loss and
rosenberg works
so let me let me tell you that so we
consider a signer and a user or in a
security proof assigner oracle and the
adversary and what they do is they run
these n sessions of the underlying blind
signature scheme
and then one of them is chosen at random
and this one is completed while the
other ones are opened and by open i mean
that the user sends this message and
randomness that he used that he
committed to before
to the signer
okay so now we will look at these
sessions and distinguish between
malformed sessions and honest sessions
so what is a malformed session by that i
mean that the adversary
did not honestly commit to his message
and randomness or he computed the
challenge in a in a malicious way
okay so let's say the adversary mal
forms two or more
of these sessions then as he has to open
all but one of them
we never need to provide a response
because the signer will abort right the
the adversary will get caught
okay so that's good for our reduction we
don't need a secret key because we don't
need to provide a response the second
good case is where he is just honest he
commits to all of his randomness and
messages honestly
and then we can actually extract using
the random oracle because we use some
random oracle-based commitments and then
use this cool property star because now
we have the message and the randomness
to simulate without the secret key
okay
the tricky case is if he cheats in
exactly one session because in this case
we could hit this session with our cut
and choose index
and then we actually
need to ask the signer oracle of the
underlying
line signature scheme because we don't
have a secret key
okay so this happens with probability
one over n
and let's see what that means for the
entire experiment
so in each interaction it happens with
probability one over n such a successful
cheat and
as the the this parameter n grows over
time we can sum this up and see that the
expectation of the number of cheats so
this is also the expected number of
times we have to call our signing oracle
of the underlying scheme is logarithmic
and this is why
why it works for logarithmically secure
schemes but keep in mind that we want to
use it for a key only secure scheme now
so we are not allowed to query a
logarithmic number of times we have to
get this down to zero
okay so how do we do that our first
trick is to scale everything right just
take some constant scale everything um
and then we the the expectation also
scales so we get it down to less than
one this is already good but now for
security we don't need in expectation
anything we need it with overwhelming
probability but the concentration bound
will only give us a constant probability
so what can we do we can just repeat
everything in parallel with independent
keys and independent randomness
okay and that means that
with overwhelming probability there's
one of these instances one of the keys
for which in the entire experiment the
adversary never cheats successfully and
that means we never need to ask designer
oracle for this key so what we can do we
can just guess this this instance i star
embeds the key of the underlying bls
blind signature scheme there
and then um
we don't need a sign org
okay so that's good but now you may ask
this guy he's talking about concrete
efficiency and now he blows up
everything by a factor of k
so this is this seems to be not
efficient
and this is why we use
blind bls actually because for bls we
can use a lot of techniques from
aggregation we heard about aggregation
in the first talk we can aggregate for
example the responses the signatures and
so on and essentially this cut and
choose over multiple instances comes
almost for free now
okay
so that brings me to an overview of our
concrete schemes we have one concrete
scheme that i didn't show you which is
based on the rsa assumption so we
instantiate this framework from the rsa
assumption and to improve
uh the communication and signature sizes
we use some rsa specific optimizations
and the second one this is the one i
explained at a high level is the one
from the key only secure bls scheme
which is based on the cdh assumption for
that we use the parallel instance cut
and choose technique and these
aggregation optimizations to get a fully
secure blind signature scheme
okay so to wrap up our talk what have we
learned
we have uh generic results this is what
champ showed you where we take this cuts
lost rosenberg boosting transform and we
go from
linear communication in the number of
interactions to uh
to logarithmic communication okay
and then for concrete parameters we
constructed two
uh
two schemes that use these ideas one
from the rsa one from the cdh assumption
and we actually take the security loss
into account to estimate concrete
parameter sizes
um
which i think are rather practical
okay
so
that's it this was fun thank you
thanks any questions
please come to the microphone
hey thank you uh so one quick question
for your last uh for the evaluation can
you tell us something have you
benchmarked the designer performance for
that
uh no we actually didn't look at
computation we only looked at
communication and signature sizes
but yeah
i expect that the signer
computation is okayish the user
yeah i mean
yeah
so there's still this parameter n right
right and the computation is still
linear in this parameter
right right
so so does this depend on n and what did
you set into
uh
what what does it depend i mean what is
a reasonable end you have in mind i
guess where oh okay so so this this n is
the it's like
this the counter that designer increases
in every interval right but what is a
reasonable upper bound you'd expect for
do it which you like oh it's 20 so so
for these for these sizes we uh we take
the maximum to be 2 to the
30. okay yeah thanks
thanks to both of you for the very
interesting talk so i have a question
about this boosting transform so you run
many instances of this base uh
blind signature scheme but then you open
a bunch of them yeah that's a great side
um and i'm worried that when you open
one of them it reveals the the client's
message which is supposed to be kept
secret so i'm wondering how that is
resolved
it's a good question i mean uh
the the trick is that you instead of
using the message itself you use
commitments to the message
independent commitments in each of these
instances and then
this the commitment that you use here is
not revealed
and
and you here you you actually only
reveal the commitments that go into the
underlying schemes okay so i should
think of this as you're doing a blind
signature on a commitment of a message
yeah but you can include the commitment
randomness and the final signature then
so
yeah thank you good question
right
so i don't see any questions in the zoom
so let's thank the speakers again
but this concludes this session now we
have a short break and the sessions will
continue at 10 am