analysis session
so the first stock is differential
cryptanalysis in the fixed key model and
the talk is given banned by tim bainer
okay can you hear me yeah
so
like mario just said so this talks about
the friendship groups analysis uh in the
fixed key model
so um
i mean i think the people who go to this
session probably have some idea what
differential crypto analysis is
but it doesn't hurt to just uh quickly
view that so we have a function f i'm
gonna call it and then we'll take an
input x add some difference a to it
and we're going to see if the output
pair has a certain difference b
and ideally we want to find such a pair
of differences that's also called a
differential so that there are many
inputs x so that this kind of difference
equation
holds and then the number of search x
divided by 2 to the n is what we call
the probability of the differential
and so the basic problem that
this paper deals with is how to compute
this probability
so
in general that's pretty difficult but
usually we have some structure
so the structure we have is that our
function is a composition of a number of
much easier functions and
what we then do is we build a sequence
of intermediate differences that's what
we call a characteristic
and what you have is then that the
probability of your differential is the
sum of the probabilities of all the
characteristics
so
that's the first simplification but
um it still leaves open the problem of
how do we actually compute this
these probabilities of the
characteristics
and to do that
people
basically make an assumption which is
that the propagation under each of those
functions fi
can be assumed to be independent which i
mean doesn't really make sense because
all the intermediate values are just
deterministic functions of each other
but you can make that somewhat more
reasonable by saying that
if you add
round keys so uniform random round keys
after each of those functions then the
average probability of a characteristic
can indeed be computed by just
multiplying probabilities
uh but that gives you the average and
you actually want to know more than the
average you want to know i mean ideally
we would actually want to know the fixed
key probability
and so to bridge this gap between the
two uh people have introduced this
hypothesis that for any particular key
the probability is probably close to the
average value and that's so does this
hypothesis of stochastic equivalence
so we can actually try to check if that
makes sense for some examples so here i
take a
differential for six rounds of spec 32
and then
because spec32 has only a 32-bit block
size you can just
experimentally test how many right pairs
there are
and so if the hypothesis of stochastic
equivalence was correct you would expect
that like in near this red line we would
have some kind of peak in this histogram
so most of the keys should give
probability that's close to this
but as you can see that's not really
true so you have lots of different
peaks in there and a lot of things going
on
i think the most important
for practice the most important
conclusion for this is that if you were
to use the average
then this would actually give incorrect
conclusions in this case because for
example let's say you think okay i take
2 to the 13 pairs and then on average
i'd expect one right one
but actually um
there are a bunch of keys for which
that just wouldn't be enough so you'd be
saying that your successful build is
much larger but this is still a moderate
case that can be much worse
and one thing i want to mention here is
that
i've been talking about this average but
i mean actually it's not the average
because the round keys are also not
independent so even if you
just want the average i mean this you
can't just assume that the wrong keys
are independent
so in order to address this this problem
and to kind of explain figures like the
one i just showed
what we introduced in this paper is a
new technique that we call quasi
differential trails so it should really
be called differential trails but
unfortunately the terms already taken
and to get there i'm
i'm going to first introduce some
sort of extension of the different
distribution table and then from there
get those trails
so
um
so these matrices this glass of
differential transition matrices
the way we get them is by applying a
sort of recipe
so the recipe is
what i've introduced in the context of
linear cryptanalysis as the geometric
approach
which
just like
the very basic idea is that you have
some combinatorial problem and you
convert it into a sort of more geometric
problem
um so the combinatorial problem that we
are interested in here is you have a set
so you're going to encrypt these sets
and then you want to determine the size
of the intersection with the set and
some other sets
and you can make this
kind of more geometric by expressing
this this
this intersection size as an inner
product between two vectors
and i mean two vectors are two functions
that's basically the same thing and and
the vectors we consider here are the
indicator functions of sets so um the
indicator function of a set is just zero
everywhere except it's one on the set
so
if we have that so
we were talking about these indicator
functions but we actually want to know
also if you have an indicator function
of a set how does that change if i apply
a function
and that's actually that there's a
linear relation between this
um and um given by some matrix so just
do a matrix vector product and
the the matrix is very easy to define
it's just mapping delta x which is zero
everywhere except it's the value of x
so it's just a vector with a single
non-zero entry to delta f of x
um and so
this is some matrix that gives this
relation the only thing here is we are
working with pairs not just with
individual values so
we need to do the same thing basically
on sets of pairs
but the id is exactly the same you can
build some kind of matrix
and in fact if you are familiar with
tensor products then you'll easily see
that
your matrix or transition matrix for
pairs is just a tensor product
so
um so now we have this transition matrix
for pairs so that's cool
and it really fully describes
propagation of sets of pairs so
theoretically it also describes exactly
the probability of
differentials but
like practically speaking that's i mean
what we've done is completely useless we
just rewrote the problem a bit so to
actually make this into a useful theory
um i'm going to
introduce a change of basis
so
change of basis so the idea is just that
um so let's say you have here a picture
of my co-author and then you do some
linear transformation the blue matrix
uh and then you get some other picture
so this this linear transformation is
represented by this blue matrix
with respect to the blue basis right and
and you get a different matrix if you
choose a different basis
and
um so when when you look at it from the
point of view of the blue basis it's
actually a pretty complicated matrix
but if you choose for example the red
basis
then it suddenly becomes a diagonal
matrix which is much nicer to work with
so
the idea here is actually for choosing
this red bases i chose vector such that
uh so this this vector here so anything
parallel to that will actually be mapped
to itself
and and here this one you know it just
gets flipped right so
that that's why this is this is a
diagonal matrix
so we're going to do the same thing now
let's do this
really big matrix the transition matrix
for pairs
uh and that means we have to choose a
basis of course so how are we going to
choose the basis there are
two
sort of
natural properties that you would want
this basis to have
the first one is that you want to
include the indicator functions of sets
of pairs with a constant difference so
those are these delta a functions and
the reason for that is that this this is
what we use in differential
cryptanalysis right
and then you also want
your basis and this is related to the
whole fixed key thing
to be
so you want everything to behave really
simple when you're going to add keys so
key addition means you're adding to both
halves of the of the pair you're adding
the same constant
so you want it to be a translation in
variant basis
and there is a solution for that so this
is one possible basis
um and there are sort of two to the two
and basis functions and i will index
them by value u and a value a and you
will be called a mask and a the
difference
so
you can immediately see that if you put
u equal to zero so this becomes one then
you get uh
the the functions we wanted to include
so that's good and uh if you're going to
add some something so do this
translation
then because the sky u that's basically
-1 to some linear function of x
so you're just going to get a constant
vector that doesn't depend on x or y
so
uh so we have the the properties we want
that's good
uh and i mean if you are
like more theoretical
then you might wanna like if you wanna
generalize to other groups you might
wanna know this the reason why we use
this particular basis is because this
kind of view is a group character
so now we have this basis and then we
can just do a change of basis on our
transition matrix and that's what
this graphic differential transition
matrix is
so there's nothing more to it but if
you're a practical person you probably
want to know what the actual coordinates
of of the matrix look like now so what
they actually look like is
so i'm going to index the coordinates
that's the first thing i should say by
these most different pairs why because
otherwise i have to number the basis
vectors in an arbitrary way and it seems
a bit
silly to do that
so what you actually have is some
product of the probability of the
differential and then some term which is
two times the probability minus one and
if you are familiar with linear
cryptanalysis that's what we call a
correlation
so here we are actually so this is a
measure let's say of how biased some
expression is so here we're measuring
how biased some linear combination of
inputs and output bitsis
um and we're doing that only for the the
values that satisfy the differential
um so you could say that in a way
this quasi differential thing is just a
sort of linear crypto analysis
restricted to the set of right pairs
so um then we can compute this for
specific s boxes so for example this is
a rectangle s box you have the ddt of
that and then your quasi differential
transition matrix is a kind of zoomed in
version of that so where for every
element of your ddt you would get a
whole sub-matrix of your
quasi-differential transition matrix
and then so the top
left elements in each of those like that
that's going to be uh the probability
of the differential
and then uh if you take um differences
equal to zero you get this correlation
matrix so if you're familiar with linear
grip analysis that's a very important
object there
so
um now we have this matrix
and then we can try to
so i'll show now how we can go from
there to trails so the main property
that we need for that is that if you
have a composition of functions
then the quasi differential transition
matrix is just going to be the product
so the matrix product of a bunch of
these
uh you know for the these functions are
the quasi differential matrices for
those functions
and then you can just take these matrix
products and write out the coordinates
uh just just as a as a sum right so you
get some sum over some products
and then the terms in that sum are what
we call these trails
so there are sequences of pairs of masks
and differences
and uh so then the products here are
what we call the correlation of a trail
and this is useful because the
correlation of trails is usually easy to
compute because your functions if i do
have some structure that makes it easy
to compute this because the differential
transition matrices
and then the interesting part is if we
so if we take
masks equal to zero for both the inputs
and the outputs so then we get on the
left here that's the probability of the
differential and then it shows that the
probability of a differential is exactly
equal to some sum of uh correlations of
a number of trills
and the idea will be that we select the
most important trails and work with them
yeah if you were to
remove all the terms from the sum where
the mask is
non-zero so you keep only masks which
are zero then
you basically get the standard thing we
do so just
summing the probability of
characteristics where those
probabilities are computed by multiply
so but this shows you actually need to
take into account a bit more
so
another thing that you might want to do
so that's for computing probabilities of
differentials so you often also want to
directly compute the probability for a
characteristic
and then you do kind of the obvious
thing so you just sum only over the
masks because the differences are
already fixed in your characteristic
and it's easy to see that this works
like the differential characteristic is
just a differential but for a function
where your intermediate values are also
part of the output so then if you
specify the differences here this
fixes your internal differences if you
specify the masks
so that there's this general rule for
how the masks propagate it's basically
the same as in linear kit analysis then
because this is zero there will be
arbitrary masks before and after your
forking operation
but they have to be equal so you have to
sum over all these trails that's why you
get this result
so
now we have trails
um
so those sequences and then we can try
to use them to actually explain some
phenomena
so um
yeah in
so
first of all if you so you want to find
the best trails because that's i mean
we're going to still do an approximation
where we replace this sum over huge
number of terms which is the sum over a
small number
um and for that um you can use uh some
automated tools in this paper used as
smt modeling
and then um for the small functions you
need some algorithms
to compute to make the quality
differential transition matrices and um
so there are some algorithms that are so
you can compute it in about the same
time as
the size of your matrix so that's pretty
good and for modular additions and
bigger functions we have a formula
and then we apply this to
three ciphers that we chose mostly based
on how easy it is to talk about them
so rectangle where we show the best
attack that's been published doesn't
actually work although you can fix it at
least partially
um then knot that's a hash function in
the lightweight crypto competition there
were some collision attacks proposed on
that but it turns out the
characteristics used in that attack just
have probability zero so you're not
going to find a collision with that and
then we also looked at specs so just
briefly say a bit about specs so
first i want to go back to this example
i showed at the beginning
so here if you do this automated
analysis or even manually if you have a
bit more time
then you'll find there are five
trails which really have a much larger
absolute correlation than the other
trails then if you just take into
account those so there are
three
key bits three linearly independent key
bits this one is just a linear
combination
that uh actually uh can influence this
probability in a significant way and
then you could you know you can just
compute what possible values can that
give
and uh so this is the red lines here and
you can see that it matches those peaks
i mean you can also compute how many
keys there would be in each of those
peaks of course
uh and
so so this
gives a sort of simple model if you want
to improve you just need to take into
account more trails
so
similar to that you can explain some
experiments that were recently published
at sec i think
that's even easier actually that case
there you only have two trails
um and then we also looked at some
actual key recovery attacks
uh so uh yeah basically
the conclusion there is like most of the
key recovery attacks that have been
published only work for like
one in four keys or less with some
exceptions like spec 96 where it only
works for 164 keys
um the positive side to that is that for
the keys for which that they could
actually work you can do with a lot less
data than what's expected
um
i just want to mention that it's not
like i tried to find differentials where
like the
results would like from from the
literature would be wrong or anything so
i expect that if you try uh any attack
that is very likely you'll find that
actually there are
some inconsistencies or some
improvements in some cases
so just to conclude so we've got this
new thing called quasi differential
trails which are constructed from
quasi-differential transition matrices
um
and then
we applied those in the paper to a
number of
attacks
um so we used
smt to find it and we can find the
source code for the
smt tool we have uh at this link
but yeah i think there is a lot of
future work here
so
one thing is that you can just take any
attack
and then
actually try to take into account these
additional trails and see if
the key has a significant effect and my
expectation is that in many cases
that will be a very significant effect
uh there are also uh some
i mean i think it's interesting to
improve these tools because i mean there
are some actual very specific
optimizations that could be done that
because our paper doesn't focus too much
on the automated analysis
and then one last thing i want to
mention is that the limitation of this
method is just the same as in linear
cryptanalysis so this is
a theory where you have trails
but trails don't explain everything
because you can have a large number of
trails
which have a combined effect that's
still very important but for that you
need to go beyond uh
just uh theories with what i call in
this geometric framework one-dimensional
trail so you need to go
further than that
okay that's uh
that's the
that's everything thank you very much
so are there any questions
there is a question in zoom from
michael abramson i'm going to read it he
says have you tried this attack on this
since that is where differentiation
analysis began
so if you try to apply this on this
so in the paper there is an analysis of
the um original characteristic that's
used in the attack uh by bihar shamir
so there's actually i mean it was known
there that there is a quite significant
effects of the key
uh which is actually i mean if you use
so there are actually two
characteristics that are used in the
final attack on ds to compensate for
that kind of
and um
so yeah you can explain that with just
one uh quasi differential trail which is
local to one round so if you iterate
many rounds you you'll get several
copies of that
um
yeah i also checked then if there are in
that case even more who has the
differential trails but it turns out not
to be the case so that's the main effect
there
so but yeah we looked at it
thanks
i have a question maybe a bit naive one
but so in the cases where you found out
that the attacks didn't work or that a
small proportion of the keys
would be the the ones for the attack
work could this give vessels information
on the value of the keys uh when the
attack doesn't work for instance would
could this be
to recover like information
yes
i mean not much but a bit yeah sorry a
little bit of information about the key
yeah and you don't think that it would
be exploited to uh i don't know to learn
monthly
yeah i mean so
it depends because so the it could like
so
in the uh
like for example for these attacks on
specs so let's say you have this thing
where it only works in one over 64 keys
so you find out that
it doesn't work then you know
yeah that is not one of those this is a
you can know exactly what this class of
keys looks like but i mean
those will be internal bits of the key
so that's already less clear if you can
directly use it in a key recovery or
something
but yeah you get a little bit of
information
yeah it doesn't really save the attack
okay
are there any more questions in the in
the room or into
so if there are no more questions then
let's thank team again thank you very
much
and the second talk of this session is
simplified meet in the middle modeling
for permutations new quantum attacks and
the talk is given by andres morton
okay you have a voice yes
thank you for the introduction
um so yeah this is a joint work with
mark sivans and this is going to be
about submitting the middle attacks
modeling permutations and quantum stuff
so i have to unpack a bit here
let's start
with permutations
so cryptographic permutations there is
no key in this presentation there is no
clear at all but we're still going to
try to find a tax on that
and our goal here is to find an input x
which has some relation between the
input x and the output p of x you could
say for example
i want to search a fixed point of this
permutation if there is one and that
means x equal p of x
the way to solve it with the meat in the
middle technique is to
select two subsets of the internal
states of the permutation
one that's going to compute uh forwards
the forward path
and one that we're going to compute
backwards the backward pass
and um we're going to compute them
independently so we take all the
possibilities for this forward states by
all the possibilities for these backward
states you compute independently
and then
there are points at which this
two subsets are going to match to two
meets
and we take all the possibilities all
the pairs
of possibilities which are going to
match in this point
and once we have something that matches
we're going to recompute everything and
to try to see for conditions all
satisfied
of course this works because uh there is
uh this condition here which basically
closes the computer the computational
path
of this permutation
but this is broadly the the idea that we
use
um the application of course is to find
pre-images on hash functions and the
best example for this is haraka 512
one of the permutations that we studied
in in our paper
because saraka is a hash function that
is directly built on top of a
permutation
actually it only hashes inputs of 500
bits
for this version and the way it does it
is simply it has a permutation which
operates on five floor bits
and it exhausts the output permutation
to the input
and then it truncates to 256 bits and
then you have your your hash
so of course finding a pre image of this
for example a primitive zero this is
exactly a meat in the middle problem you
want to find an input x such that
truncation of x equals truncation of p
of x
more generally this is going to happen
when we have a compression function
based on the block cipher
and if we fix the input of the key
inputs because on black cipher you have
not only the input x but also an input
key if you fix that you get permutation
and so you could still apply the same
techniques
why do we care about quantum attacks
well in the case of haraca
actually the hash function has been
explicitly designed to be used in close
quantum digital signature schemes such
as strengths plus
so we're going to care of course about
this classical security but at some
point we have to ask the question of its
quantum security
the classical generic preimage
attack on harika 512 would be in time
for the 256 because you can search
exhaustively
um and we already know since you're
21 uh by a paper by by which add that
there is an attack because you can find
a pre-image using a meat in the middle
uh attack in less than that
but then you could still argue that well
okay there is a classical attack
but
it could still be safe against a
mountain adversary because having a
premature attack in time here to the 240
does that mean that i have a quantum
pre-match attack better than the generic
one generic one is actually quite good
because we have grover's segregated like
modern setting and this one is in time
to d128
so to have a quantum premise attack i
need to do better than that
but actually in our paper we show that
you can also do better than that in the
column setting so you have a premature
attack that runs better than grover
search or higher perfectly
um
now meet in the middle attacks can
become quite complicated um there are
many techniques applicable if you
combine all of this uh it can become
quite difficult
but um
to search for this very complicated
attacks
what we can do now or try to do is to
use an automatic tool
now the idea is you're going to use some
sort of modeling
to to model the space of possible meet
in the middle attacks
and to search for the best one among
them and this was originally proposed at
record 21 in the same paper
where the authors basically modeled the
the ies-like compression functions i'm
going to talk about this a bit later
the idea is simply that you have a
description of all possible forwards and
backward paths which define completely
the attack
and now you try to find the best attack
among all these possibilities
now in this paper
uh the possible backwards and forward
but they were basically defined and
constrained by a set of local rules and
i'm not going to go into this details
because we use a very different
approach
so modern strategy is actually specific
for permutations
so it's not
it's not going to include the key
schedules which was the case in the
previous paper
but it's actually allows to target a bit
more than aes like permutations which is
good
and also
the the model that we get out of it is
actually extremely simple so that i can
hope to present it
uh during this presentation
and um this modeling also includes
quantum meet in the middle attacks hence
the result of haircut that i just talked
about
and of course there are many that can
apply it can be applied we applied it on
many primitives you can select your best
one out of the list but i'm gonna speak
uh specifically about haraka here
okay um
so
now i'm gonna start by explaining how we
abstract out a permutation design
specifically a substitution permutation
network
and and this is going to require first
because the only thing we have to do
here is basically throw away all the
details we don't care about and keep
only the structure the abstract
structure that we need to use
and then i'm going to explain how
exactly
the search is done
on this meet in the middle attack and
how we model this into milp
and finally some examples on harca
factory
okay so we start with permutation design
an spn permutation so a substitution
permutation network it's like an spn
cipher without a key
and so but that's how it's uh usually
it's represented
with a state which is made of a certain
number of sets
let's say b cells of w bits so that will
make a state of w times b bits
and uh the round function operates
with a nonlinear layer which applies as
boxes
independently to all the cells and a
linear layer which applies a
linear function
now
i'm going to
focus on the example of present here
actually this is not present it's a it's
a small present because it had to fit in
the side
but present is actually it takes
actually this uh linear layer which is
the permutation layer um very literally
because the linear layer only permeates
the bits in the states
so uh initially the state has 16 cells
here it's going to have four sets to fit
in my slide
but uh this is the kind of design we'll
we're focusing on
so you have these xbox layers
and during between these box layers it
just permutes bits in the states
but this is nice because you have a very
like this is a graph basically
and you have a very nice representation
for the scheme
unfortunately harakai is not based on
present
it's based on aes so here goes my nice
representation and here comes the aes
um as is basically the i guess the the
most well-known block cipher out there
and this time it has a state which is
represented as a matrix of bytes
so the xboxes operate on the bytes
and the linear layer does two things
first it permutes the bytes
that's the shift flows operation and
then it mixes so it applies a linear
function on the columns of the matrix
now this has nothing to do with my
previous drawing
but actually it does
if i use the following technique
the supers box which basically consists
in putting together
the xbox layer and the mixed columns of
the previous rounds
now i obtain
basically
a biggest box that operates on columns
on 32 bits
and between these layers of supers boxes
the only thing that remains
is the shift rows the permutation of the
bytes
so now i have a layer of surprise boxes
followed by a permutation of bytes
followed by a layer of super boxes etc
so you know in our paper
basically started from the present uh
representation of these permutations and
actually we could then include aes
by basically i mean using the same
representation
so this is why i can focus on these nice
graphs
weighted graphs
okay so now we get to the
abstract representation of this spn
permutation
first of all if there are round
constants there are one constants
usually we just remove them we don't
care about that
and
the x boxes uh of course they're still
here they could be arbitrary functions
we also don't really care
um and we're gonna just i mean
instead of writing the wrong function
we're just gonna replace s box each s
box by this cell here
and we're gonna say that
each cell is basically a small list
which corresponds to the possible values
that this s-box can take
so here this is an s-box of four bits
that's basically four bit inputs and
four bit outputs so there are two to the
four possible values here in this
small list
so now we have all this uh all these
cells in our graph and they are
connected by linear relations
the goal
uh the the thing we're trying to solve
is basically to find an assignment of
values to all these cells that satisfies
all the linear relations in them
and now i have removed practically
everything and i just have a graph that
remains and this is how this is what i
input
through to my code which is going to
find the attack
so now let's find the attack
the we're going to define the following
so this is just a fancy way of of
of saying what i said at the beginning
of this talk actually the meet in the
middle technique is just computing
something forwards computing something
backwards and then trying to merge
to to match uh between the two
so we're going to define this i think we
call it a reduced list it's if you take
a set of cells in the graph there are
some really some relations between them
and you want to find all the assignments
uh to these cells that satisfy other
relations
now the meat in the middle
characteristic the whole attack is
defined only but by three sets of sets
and actually only two the one that
defines the forward computational path
the the one that defines the backward
path and then the union of the
two there is also a small constraint
here because for the attack to to to
actually work the union of the two has
to cover around in the middle that's
just technical
okay
and what the attack does is simply
compute the forward path all the
possibilities for it compute the
backward path or the possibilities for
it and then try to match the path so
compute all the possibilities when you
take into account the relations between
the forward and backward sets
know i need to convince you that
for any choice of this forward and
backward sets there exists indeed an
algorithm that does this
and that has a time complexity that we
can compute
and this is going to be quite simple
let's uh have a look at the forward list
um again on my representation of a small
present like permutation
the forward list
is going to repeat it it's going to be
computed forwards
and what we do is simply the following i
arrive here at round zero and i need to
to
take a value for this cell
there are four bits here that i don't
know because i'm only starting so i take
four i mean i take four bits
i guess four bits now i have value for
this step
and then i can pass two bits to the next
cells because there are linear relations
here
so that's good i already know two bits
for the next one
but i need to
i mean i'm missing here three plus three
bits so i take values for them
and i continue like this round by round
and then at the end what did i do i
obtained basically only by guessing bits
i obtained the valid assignments
a valid
choice for the forward path
and you can see that the total
number of such valid assignments is
exactly
the sum of the weights so number of bits
of the cells
minus the sum of the the edges that they
are in the graph
in that case it will be 12 so i need to
guess 12 bits to obtain the value
that's the forward path
now for the backward path
i just do the same slides and i change
the colors
uh because we can do exactly the same
thing but in the other direction
now we go back uh if we want to find all
valid assignments for this four cells
here taking into account the relations
we just start from the last one and then
we go backwards round by rounds
each time guessing what we need
and of course in the end we can obtain
like this all the possible also
possibilities for the backward path
now we arrive at
the interesting
the interesting moment
the final
final step in the attack is to compute
all the posts of backward and forward
path which are going through to match
because you see this backwards and this
forward list here they are seeing each
other there are linear relations between
them which are supposed to be satisfied
so if i put them together here
in this example i have 12
bits of linear relations between them
and fortunately it is possible to
compute efficiently the list of births
of this backward and forward values
satisfying the new linear relations
that's merging the two lists
and the merge i mean the list of
assignments the merge list here is equal
to the
size of the forward time stars or
backwards divided by the amount of
linear relations that we match
so
we have an algorithm for the three i
mean that completes the meet in the
middle attack because now we
can really for each choice would just
recompute everything and check the rest
so we have an algorithm and this
algorithm depends only
on the sizes of the lists
and the sizes of the lists depend only
on
the choices of cells
so we have immediately for any choice of
cells
even a bad one
we have an attack
with a classical time complexity which
is going to give given by this
assuming that you first compute the
forward list and that's afterwards you
basically go through all the
possibilities for the backward path
that's a bit of technical point um and
in that case you need to store the
forward list so you have an algorithm
with these
complexities that's the classical attack
for the quantum attack
well we also have a quantum algorithm um
i'm not going to go into the details but
basically the chord algorithm it's it
looks like what the classical one except
that
um in the step when you go through the
backwards the choices for the backwards
and merged you can do that with grover
search
and so you get this nice uh square root
time speed up associated to grover
search
with some more technical details and the
quantum memory is also this
storage of a list
but what matters here is that i have
formulas that depend only on the choices
of backwards and forwards
so i have a search space all the
variables for the backwards i put
boolean variables for backwards and
forwards
and from them i can deduce the sizes of
the lists using only linear inequalities
and this is a modeling like this is a
mixed integer linear programming
basically
and from them i can deduce my objective
function which is the complexity of the
attack
there are some technical details but i'm
just quickly
throwing them here um i i presented a
very simple version actually to to get
really nice attacks you need to reduce
the memory use as much as possible
and this is done by
creating some
global some guesses inside the path
and they will naturally appear uh this
is basically precomp you can basically
pre-compute some matchings between the
backward and forward path
something which is also very important
for aes and also for haraka is that in
the aes case
this box
that uh you see here
it's actually
it's
it's actually a mixed content there is a
mixed content in there which is a linear
operation so actually the matching can
traverse a box even if you don't know
the value of this precise cell you can
go through it
that's really important but again i'm
not going to
uh detail that
okay let's see what this gives for
hierarchical f51
so harca 512 as i said is already broken
from eurocrypt21 actually this attack is
an attack on an extended version of it
and it runs in time to day 2014.
in our paper what we showed that we
didn't reduce the time complex skill
this attack but we showed that you could
reduce the memory complexity from 2d 128
to this 16.
now this is actually quite nice when we
go to the quantum setting
because if i give you a classical attack
which has a time to today
which at this time here at the memory
today 128
even if you apply grover search as much
as you can
um
grow resource is not going to reduce it
can reduce your time complexity
sometimes but it doesn't reduce your
memory complexity
so with this you couldn't hope to obtain
an attack
doing better than the quantum generic
one
but with the path that we obtained here
we can basically put a square root
complexity on the time and we don't have
this problem anymore and there of course
it's not exactly a square root and there
is some uh
some factor that goes in there but it's
basically what happens
i just wanted to talk a bit more of an
attack on five rounds exactly so just a
full version which is classical and in
time to be 224.
uh by the way this is how it looks like
um it's kind of a mess right
so
that's a representation of hareka as my
present like uh
as a present like permutation and
basically each each of these boxes here
is is a colon
and it's a big permutation it's actually
four aes states so you have like 16
columns
and of course there is then an exchange
of the bias which is a bit a bit messy
and it doesn't
print very nicely
but what matters here is that well the
path is extremely complicated and i can
assure you that i wouldn't have found it
by hand
it's kind of the point of using
automatic tools to uh to find this kind
of thing
this attack on five rounds uh runs in
time to date 224. i just wanted to
mention that
224 is quite large right as a complexity
but actually the attack is kind of
practical
um
in a certain sense because
because uh
what what you can observe uh is that
actually it has a very small memory and
it comes from the fact that
this full pre-image attack is actually a
partial pre-image attack that will
repeat many times
so instead of going for the full per
image what you can try to do is to go
for a threshold per image and this this
one is going to become practical you can
really observe it by hand
so um so what i did here is just uh so
compute something to to get 64-bit
partial pre-images instead of having a
full zero only have 64 bits to zero and
the attack runs in about time to the 32
and memory to 32 as well so it can run
on my laptop not exactly taking a
weekend a bit less than that
uh but um yeah this is a bit better than
doing today 64 computations
all right so just to conclude um i
wanted to stress the fact that modeling
this meeting the amino attacks it gets
really simple when we face
permutations and and also that these
attacks actually perform quite well in
the quantum setting we got up to a
quadratic speed up on some some of this
however of course this approach is
really tailored for permutations if you
have other degrees of freedom that come
from a key schedule it's much more
difficult and it's an important and
interesting open question
so you can find the food version the
paper only prints and the code on github
and thank you for attention
thank you andre are there any questions
in the room or in zoom
i have a
when do you think it would be uh
possible to adapt the tool to take into
account bike leaks for instance or even
the middle for the matching have you had
a look at that
so by clicks i don't really know um
the sieve in the middle
uh so far i'm getting the impression
that um it can be somehow
uh handled i'm working on this at the
moment so basically the sieve in the
middle is something where
uh you're you're attacking a so you're
doing a key recovery attack right you're
attacking presents and you're remarking
that
um
if you know if you know multiple edges
here and multiple edges here like two
here and three here you can have some
matching also in the middle i think this
is more or less um at least partially
covered uh by making some kind of
guesses so like
by um sorry about some kind of guess and
determine technique which is partially
covered by this framework
but i must say that this is uh ongoing
work
thanks
are there any more questions
okay then if there are no more questions
let's thank andre again thank you very
much
and
okay thanks so the next talk is
construction and and the constructing
intentional weaknesses and symmetric
ciphers and the talk is given by
gregoriano
so this is joint work
[Music]
with christopher
tim and patrick
so
as an introduction
we think that
backdoors or
intentional weaknesses which is i think
overlapping and
objects
an interesting
research problem and an
interesting topic in many dimensions
yeah so it's a politically interesting
it's interesting because we saw these
things being deployed and
our main point is it's also interesting
from an academic view
and maybe one important disclaimer so we
think it's bad yeah so and i hope it's
clear without saying this but i i i
thought that i better make it clear so
our main point is not
to advertise for
deploying vectors but
understand and then prevent it
okay
so there are many different flavors
of bacters and they have different
you can have very different um
properties and i'm not going to define
this um
precisely in
in the talk but just give you an idea
what i mean so
so the the main
the main
properties that we were interested in is
in undetectability which means you will
not find the vector no otherwise it's
not a good background
untraceability um means that if somebody
uses the vector you're not able to tell
so that's more the case if
if you think for a for example of a
tweakable
block cipher and maybe there's a special
tweak which makes the cipher weak
then even if somebody uses this special
tweak you shouldn't be able to tell that
this was the special tweak which made
the uh
vector which activated the vector and it
should be practical
meaning that if
you use the vector then you are able to
practically break the scheme
otherwise it's not
much worse and if you actually achieve
all these
properties then you basically get a
public key
and we don't so we aim at less
but
it's interesting
approach to public health
okay yeah and what we are not achieving
maybe i should say you're not see uh
achieving this untreated uh
untraceability so our vectors once used
are kind of revealed
and we have two in the the paper is two
two four two contributions uh one is
deconstructing and there we look at the
ga1 algorithm i'll briefly recall what
this is
and explain how this vector and or maybe
more intentional and weakness was built
what we think it has been built
and we are going to explain ways
following the malicious framework how
you can
actually build nice what i think is nice
and natural looking
block cypher tweakable rock surface with
a backpost
okay i'll start with
the the constructive part
and
namely
um how to build speakable block ciphers
with the vector yeah and this is uh we
build up on uh work
on this malicious framework
uh from crypto 2020
and there the idea is that it's a trick
with block cipher and without getting
any giving any details there there are
tweaks to a pair of tweaks two specific
tweaks and if you use them then you will
find the probability one differential
and then you can use this to recover the
key
so this is the idea
and it's good in the way that the way
they do it because they has the tweaks
it's undetectable so you you will not be
able to find the backdoor and it's
practical leading to practical attacks
uh it has also some
downsides and this is why we i think
it's worth looking at
into it again namely it's very
non-natural yeah so
they start with
these tweaks and basically have to
modify the round function the linear
layer of this round function in order to
to be able to to make sure that this
differential is probability one so they
have to basically choose a random linear
layer
for the round function for the linear
layout
of the cipher and this means you you
look into low mc in cyphers which is a
cipher which has its corner to exist but
it's not the natural and
general purpose block server
okay and our idea is basically to to not
to do the same thing but not build a
probability one differential attack but
try to build
um
and
the weakness
on invariance instead of differentials
and here is what we do we we have two
examples one is based on aes and i'm
only going to explain this one and then
we have another one which is more
involved and
i i
think it's interesting if you're
interested you should have a look
so there's one
a yes and things and so andre i don't
have to explain and i hope anyway i
guess if you not don't know how as works
then you may be in the wrong session so
and there's a there's an invariant space
namely if you take an aes space and you
you put the first and the third column
to the same value and the second and the
fourth columns have the same value then
this is not going to change through the
wrong function yeah so if you apply some
bytes this is clearly not going to
change if you apply the rows and you
check carefully check it's not going to
change and for mixed column it's not
going to change because if you input the
same colors i'm going to output the same
colors
okay
and so why is this not breaking a s it's
not breaking a yes because if you add a
key
then automatically this
is going to be destroyed with super high
probability yeah for one round it's very
unlikely and for more rounds it's just
not going to happen okay so this is why
yes
now we wanted to have a weak cipher so
it's very easy to to get that weak we
just modify the key scalar so we the
first change we do is we modify the key
scattering and
so you take a key scheduling and i'm not
going to explain you what exactly we do
but the main point is you only output
symmetric um keys
so you have a
key so each
round key is only 64 bits but it doesn't
matter if you have enough rounds it's
not not a big issue so also the round
keys are like the first first column
equals the third column and the second
column is equal to the first column
and with this
you now get um
an invariance and weakness which works
for any number of rounds so this cypher
is weak i'm just going to explain you
how to how to use this turn this into a
key recovery that you can do no
so you get the weak cycle okay but now
the problem is we have a big cipher that
is weak always so we have to make sure
that it's weak only
for the tweak the vector that we want to
um
to embed
so the second thing is we add a tweet
and so there's one thing so you take a
tweak t0 you fix it you randomly choose
it and then you hash it and this hashing
is basically
the idea in malicious framework how to
make sure that you cannot find the
vector
now you hash it and then you get as an
output a spring which is just long
enough so imagine this is
long enough and then long enough meaning
that we take for each round we take 64
yes 64 bits yeah two columns
of this of this hash as the
round tweak
okay and for the for the rest of the the
remaining columns of the uh round tweak
is just zero all the time and then
given uh this this this tweak we're
going to choose the constants yeah so
there will be wrong constants like in
any good cipher there should be wrong
constants and we choose the wrong
constant so that the sum of the tweak
and the wrong constants are symmetrical
okay so
what happens is you start with this
symmetric state you apply all these
round functions you get the symmetric
state you add the symmetric key
you get the symmetric state and now
comes the
tweak
so you take this tweak you hash it and
because the tweak is t0 this thing is
symmetric
and you get uh cipher which is
which is
symmetric so it can be broken practical
for the tweak sorry for the tweak t0 and
now what happens if you take a different
tweak if you have a different tweak then
this is going to not fit to the wrong
constant now just basically because of
the hashing you need the random values
here and so the probability that this
one is symmetric again it's super small
and so you get something which is not
secure which is not um
weak except
if you input t0 and nobody knows t0 so
that's achieves what we want yeah so
it's undetectable nobody will be able to
find this t0
um and it's practical i don't exactly
explain how it's practical but you see
that the weakness is strong
okay
so this uh maybe it's not
super surprising
um we have yeah as i said we have
something called boom sla
i'm not even sure i pronounce this
correctly
tim's uh
pointed like this
and so this i think is so the the aes
variant everybody will will be able to
tell so this is foreclosing well-known
weakness but this one uses um
a nonlinear invariant over two
consecutive rounds and it's hard to
detect how to detect in the sense that
we don't have automatic tools to find
these weaknesses yeah maybe we could
build but for now i mean
it's really hard to to detect
so um yeah so the this shows that they
are known for the uh versions and so the
same thing
okay
so that was for the first part
and now let me come to the ga1 the
deconstructing um
[Music]
weaknesses
so ga1 is this no actually it's not this
because it's for all phones yeah so it's
uh was used in
in
in former
versions of of
gpes
for the data encryption of mobile phones
okay and
it is actually a
stream cipher
which takes a
64-bit key and has a 96-bit internal
state and this was not public but
at some point
last year at eurocrypt
it was published and there was a
weakness
i mean it was broken and where how was
it broken it's broken because if after
the initialization phase
and the the joint state of this register
a and c which together has 64 bits
so it could have after initialization it
should have all close to all possible 2
to the 64 possibilities if you run to
the possible 264 keys but it doesn't you
only get 2 to the 40.
so um and then the attack is super easy
and you guessed this 2340 and you you
you compute this and check if it happens
so this is easy and actually not so hard
i mean if you to to find this vector i
don't know it's always like with script
analysis if you have the right idea it's
easy so here's only finding this black
vector is linear algebra now you have to
compute the kernel of this mapping it's
not like you have to run to this 2 to
the 64 to see this because it's all
linear algebra computing the kernel of a
matrix is enough to
to see this attack
okay so then the next question is
how did they do it how was this
constructed is it easy to to find these
lfsrs
so is it maybe an intentional weakness
or it's just unlucky
and so what
what the paper last eurocrypt
did is
to check how likely this is to happen
then you can have such a graph so you
take
i think one million lfsrs pairs of lfsrs
of the right dimension and check
what is the dimension of the
image of the space or what is the
dimension of the kernel so this is the
kernel because if you want this a small
image you want the large kernel so here
i
have on the x-axis the dimension of the
kernel and for ga1 this is 24. and in
this one million tries the highest
kernel that was observed was dimension
9.
and if you extrapolate a bit and and
make a
reasonable assumption about what's the
probability and the probability
or the effort uh to find such a con
configuration is 2 to the 40 or 2 to the
50. so that's
250 times trying elephants computing
linear algebra and this in the early 90s
is not possible this is not how they did
and so there's two things there must be
a way to construct this and the second
thing is this was not unlucky so this
was on purpose
okay and yeah this is two points the
question i want to answer is how was
this constructed so
we don't know right basically uh
we have one way to construct this but if
this is the way they did it who knows
so we have to look at the initialization
because this is the thing that makes it
weak so this is register a and this is
register c and and this is
what happens initialization works by
feeding in the bits of the key
so super that's how you do it that's how
everybody would do it so you fit in the
key and then you clock the register you
fit in the next bit of the key and you
clock it and so on and for the for the
second register you actually start with
a different
bit but basically you do the same now
you fit in the key
and so what you want you want that this
the image
of this linear mapping mapping the
64-bit key to these two states
the image is small so you want the last
curve you want many keys to be mapped to
zero in both lfsrs zero state here and
zero state
okay and just for some notation
you will have this feedback or the
characteristic polynomials of this lfsr
if this is denoted by g then the linear
mapping describing
the initialization key goes to initial
state i denote it by mg okay so what i
want is i have to look at this linear
mapping mapping the key s to this state
and register a and to this state in
register c and i want this to be 0
so there's one interesting data already
said so you start with a different key
in registers
different bit in register c yeah so it's
just shifted
and i'll explain why this makes a big
difference
okay first of all we have to
rewrite everything in polynomials yeah
so if you know a bit about lfsr that's
not super surprising yeah so
what you what we do you you write down
this 64-bit key as a degree 60
a polynomial of degree at most 63 by
basically just putting the coefficients
as the key bits no so there's some tiny
mistake and not mistake but i'm
simplifying here but yeah
and then the interesting way why is it a
good idea to rewrite it like this
because
being mapped a key being mapped to zero
is then equivalent
to this polynomial
being the key dependent polynomial the
key representation the polynomial
representation of the key is divisible
by
um the
um
characteristic
why is this intuitively the intuition is
that this initialization is nothing else
than computing this polynomial modulo g
now you flip a bit and depending on if
the set or not you're going to add the
polynomial g so that
makes sense that this this is like this
yeah so it's just reducing mod g and so
if this is reducing mod g then it's zero
if and only if it's divisible by g
okay
so now we want uh
we're looking at the variant without
shifting so that's maybe the more
natural variant which we would design so
you have register a without shifting and
register
c without shifting
so now you want so this link i just
explained and what you want is you want
it to be you want to count the number of
keys which are mapped to 0 in register a
and mapped to 0 in register c
and with this link so it has to be 0 and
both with the link that means that this
polynomial p of s is divisible by both
the error the feedback polynomial of
lfsr a and the feedback polynomial of
the second register
and now because those are primitive and
different degree if they both divided
the product is to divide it
but the product now is the degree 64
polynomial
and this has to divide a polynomial of
degree 63 at most
so that's not going to work so that's
only going to work if this polynomial is
zero so what does it mean if you don't
have shiftings then the only key which
is mapped to zero in both states is the
zero key so that this
makes a good cipher because it tells you
that if you do this initialization you
get
no entropy loss
so this this is a nice construction so
but they didn't do it like this yeah so
there's the shift and why is the way why
er
is the shift
what is the effect of the shift
in in this polynomial setup
so yeah i show the shift again
so what happens is
you can think of shifting as the
polynomial being multiplied by x to the
32 and then reduced modulo x to the 64
plus and just wrapped it up and this is
the ribbon
and now what you want again you want it
to be zero
in the first polynomial and you want the
shifted key to be zero in in the second
ellipse
and now you do again the same conversion
with with the link i explained to the
polynomial so now this means that the
first polynomial has to divide this p of
s and the second polynomial has to
divide this
rotated point
and now there's no obvious link because
with respect to factorization this
polynomial and this probably normally
they behave independent
they are not independent but of course
heuristically and also experimentally
they behave very independent yeah so the
visibility of this one and the
visibility of this one is two different
things and so there's no contradiction
anymore so it's possible yeah
and
yeah it's a nice
it's a nice small
change that makes this
attack possible this weakness possible
okay so
that's important but it still doesn't
explain how you find those now
so how do we find we still have to find
this ga and gc now we know
how to write this in polynomials and
so far i didn't explain how to find so
the idea is you turn the problem around
instead of trying to find these
polynomials starting with polynomials
and trying to factor trying to to see if
if they have a good polynomial you start
you're starting with the kernel element
and and try to find the corresponding
volume the the feedback polynomials
yeah so we given p of s we try to
construct
uh ga and gb so that this given key is
mapped to zero
and that's easy so what you do is you
take this polynomial ps and this other
polynomial and just factorize it and you
hope
that it has a irreducible a primitive
factor of the right
size and why is this a good idea to do
it like this because
primitive polynomials are not rare
so if you pick a random polynomial
so then that its primitive is not not
very unlikely okay
you can write down the formula this
multiplication here already assumes that
things behave independently and
it works i mean we
did experiments and
and
after
like roughly a thousand tries you're
done you find this setup that you wanted
okay
so now i explained you
how um you can rewrite everything
polynomials and how given how you can
can efficiently find
um and
polynomials so that at least you have
one element in the kernel namely the one
you started with
but still we don't want a kernel of
dimension one which is no clear we want
the
kernel of dimension 24. now in the case
of ga1 and how do you do this you choose
ps special and basically you make sure
that
yeah okay you look in the paper if you
want to know how to do this so there's a
a special a choice of p so that if this
p is in the kernel then you know many
elements in in the kernel
rotated variants in base in principle of
these powers indica okay
so um and this works yeah so we we
implemented it super efficient so it
also was already efficient in the 90s
and you can check if the kernel the
excellent kernel of ga1 is of this form
and it is of this form um
it's interestingly that you could weaken
it below 40 bits yeah so now the
security is 40 bits but you could also
do with the same setup achieve
even weaker systems but they didn't do
it yeah so and this 40 bits is something
which more or less officially
was export controller
in the uh in the eu so it makes sense
that it's 40 bits
um
okay and see all these details are in
the paper and kind of the correct
version of all what i said is in the
paper
without the simplifications and that's
all i wanted to say thank you very much
thanks greg are there any questions in
the room or in zoom
okay thanks hello thanks again
so the last talk of this session is
siemens algorithm and symmetry crypto
generalizations and automatized
applications and the talk is given by
lucas then
yeah hello everyone thanks for the
introduction i just want to add the
papers joint work with federico canal
and gregoriana
and i mean well the paper is titled
simon's algorithm and symmetric crypto
so
um i want to start by explaining what
simon's algorithm is and simon's
algorithm is a quantum algorithm that
solves a rather specific problem namely
simon's problem and for simon's problem
you are given a function f that maps n
bits to envip n bits
and your promise that the function is
such that
there's a secret period s and that means
that f of x is equal to f of x x or s
for all x
for x yeah and now the goal is to to
find the period s
and in a classical world you can show
that you will need at least
or roughly two to the n over two queries
to f so that's essentially the
birthday problem because you have to
find a collision in it but in the
quantum world there's simon's algorithm
and with simon's algorithm you only need
big o of n quantum queries and then some
basic linear algebra to to recover s and
yeah i mean that's that's nice it's an
exponential speed up but why do why do
we care about this we as like people who
are doing symmetric cryptanalysis and
the reason why we should care
was essentially given by kuvacaro and
morin
first in 2010 where they gave a quantum
attack based on simon's algorithm
against sweyan faisal and then in 2012
they gave one against the evan manzo
construction and this i want to present
here
so for evan mansour
we
i mean it's a construction to to
construct a block cipher and we need
um
we need uh two secret keys k0 and k1 and
one public permutation so everyone knows
this permutation and that what we do is
we we simply um add k02 to the input
then apply our permutation at the other
key and that's what we need to do to
compute the the encryption of x
and in a classical world you you can
prove that this is a secure block cipher
but in the quantum world we
when we consider this function f of x
which is simply the the encryption of x
x or the the
public
permutation p
then we will notice that when we when we
write this out then that we have this p
of x x or k 0 and then x of p of x
so this means that if we add k 0 to the
input then this will be cancelled out
but k 0 will appear here and that means
that the output value will not change
right because it's it's the same as
before just swapped around
so
as i just said then if we have a
function of this form we can use simon's
algorithm to the simon's quantum
algorithm to find k0
with just a polynomial amount of queries
to the encryption
and once we have k0
finding k1 is is easy and therefore the
the quantum version of the evan mansour
construction is is wrong
okay so that was the motivation for for
our work
and now we have two contributions and
the first is
an automize or an automatic way to to
find new applications that means
essentially to
to find these periodic functions for for
other constructions and then our second
contribution
is a negative result
on potential generalizations of simon's
algorithm
okay so let's start with the optimized
applications
and
i mean like like i just said
once we have a periodic function you can
just use simon's algorithm to to recover
the period and then you know maybe the
period is
uh like just depends on on the secrets
and can be then used for a distinguisher
or maybe the period is
the the
secret key or something then we can also
build key recovery attacks and the
important point is
that these attacks will be fast in the
sense that we will only need
a polynomial amount of quantum queries
in contrast to let's say grover's
algorithm where we still need an
exponential amount of queries
so
i mean for for the evan mansour
construction
finding this function is quite easy
because the construction itself is
rather easy but if you study more
complex construction it becomes really
cumbersome and you don't want to do it
by hand anymore and
so
we want to optimize it we want a
computer to do this for us but
the question is how can we do this
and our approach is
quite simple actually we will just
enumerate all sensible functions
and because the devil is in a detail
what does sensible mean for us sensible
means that the the periodic function
somewhat depends on on the construction
yeah
so
i mean for example for the evan manzo
construction we we use this internal
permutation p and maybe the the
encryption itself and then xor that's it
and then once we have such a function we
will in instantiate it with a small
block size say for example four bits or
something
and then like checking if there's a
period is is easy because we can just
evaluate the function on all the inputs
and then use a trivial brute force
approach to see whether there's a period
and once again the the periodic function
for the evangel construction or the
the attack on the evidence construction
looks like this
and to to represent such functions
we we are going to use circuits so
the circuit for this function would look
like this so here we have an input and
then we apply the permutation and the
encryption and then we exhort this
together
okay so let's go into a little details
there for circuits so this is actually
the circuit
or the the circuit representing the
the function that was used in the attack
on the furon faisal cipher in 2010 which
is actually in contrast to the
one on evan mansur just a distinguisher
and
so i want to use this as an example for
what we
what we understand the circuits so
i mean most importantly the circuit is
essentially just a graph here so a
directed at cyclic graph
and
a subset of the nodes
is i mean rd input so this is this
capital x and notice that we here have
like the the small x is just the
the input of the function but we can
also have like constant in in our input
set so here the the alpha there's an
alpha zero and an alpha one in the
attack which are constants and then
there's an additional input with b
which essentially switches the
the um
the values of these alphas
okay and then
other than that for the for the
non-input nodes the non-input nodes are
labeled with gate functions so here el
is the left part of the three-on-five
cipher so the output of the freon python
and this is just xo as usual
and then for i mean for the x or
the order of inputs of course does not
matter but for for the encryption
because it doesn't matter which one is
the left and the right or the first and
second input and so we are also going to
to label the edges to make clear what
the order of inputs is
and last but not least we we need some
some notices actually the the value the
output value of the function and for
convenience this will just always be the
node all down below
okay
so then let's consider some examples on
what an abstract example of a circuit
and notice
here
there's a
node that is not really used anymore and
i think intuitively it should be super
clear that it makes no sense to to
consider such a circuit because
i mean if we consider the same circuit
without this node would compute the same
function right
and then there are two other nodes
both are labeled with g
g 0 so they both compute the same
function
and
they also have both the same inputs so
again it makes not really sense to to do
this like this so we don't want to do
this and essentially we we say that such
circuits are then in a non-normal form
and we only want to consider circuits
that are normal so
an example of of an equivalent circuit
that computes the same function
would be this and
thereby we can reduce the number of
circuits that we actually have to to
consider and therefore we reduce the the
runtime of our search
by quite a lot and
this is not enough yet so we need even
more
restrictions
and
to do so i mean we we just say that we
want to define some rules and the rule
just takes a circuit as input and then
output 0 or 1 depending on whether the
circuit is useful or
not
and just some example for such rules
so
these rules are more concrete yeah so
not on on abstract circuits but
when we for example know that
the one of the gate functions is x1
which will always be the case then again
it makes no sense to consider circuits
that compute something like a x or a
because
oh i mean not only for the output but
also in an intermediate step
because when you want to have a zero or
a constant zero then you can just add it
as a
constant to the input nodes
and also we could restrict the number of
queries that are actually allowed so we
could say that the the function that
i mean the the function we are looking
for should only query the
the construction that we are trying to
attack like only once or only twice
something but like this
and of course we can then also say that
uh the query to a construction should
depend on on a non-constant input and to
do so we i mean this would just be like
a reachability test on the underlying
graph
and i mean you could go on like
essentially you can do whatever you want
it only has to be efficient and i think
this is also clear right if you say that
the rule is that the circuit that you
have in the end has like a period or
something or should we
did what you want to search for of
course you could define this in theory
but it makes no sense in practice
and
the key point here is that these rules
are not only checked before we do our
period test but on all intermediate
steps so that we can
i mean if you think about the the whole
thing as a search tree then we try to
you know to cut
as soon as possible like when we go down
from the wood to and the leaves are the
the circuits which we actually will test
for periods we try to cut large parts
out of the circuit
and to to give you some numbers
here is um
the the search for for foreground files
so another attack that's what was
already known before
and so we first tried to to rediscover
known attacks to see whether our
approach would actually work
and this solid line
is the number of circuits you would have
to test if you
do the uh
like trivial approach where you don't do
any
any of these tests or normalization or
anything like this and notice that this
scale is logarithmic so here is already
2 to the 40.
so to
check circuits with no 6 non
input nodes you would
need to check two to the 43 circuit so
that's
would take a bit longer than in a
weekend on my laptop at least and
but what you can do now is
so
if you do
this and we
define our rules then you only need to
do like two to the 23 rules and then and
i mean these rules are easy to check and
so in the end we only have to test about
two to the 14 or six and ah no wait it's
over
not so important
but
what made us is that we can then do all
these these checks uh in only a couple
of minutes
um
okay so let's
talk about a specific example so one of
our new attacks
is on the forum missy rfk construction
so
missy is here um it's kind of similar to
faisal but the round function is not a
here in the middle branch but one on the
side
and this rfk means that we consider
uh
i mean the round function is not a new
random function in every round but one
fixed function and then we add a one key
after we apply the d1 function
and so the the setup of our search for
this was that we just had one input node
which i mean just the input of the
function and then as gate functions we
had
xor and then the left part of the
encryption and the right part of the
encryption
and the the round function and also the
inverse of the one function so in
contrast to to physical we know that the
round function actually is invertible
and then as rules
of course we use this this normality so
that there are no nodes
that aren't used anymore or there are
also no nodes that compute essentially
the same
and then again also the xors should be
should be senior i already said that we
don't want to do like a x or a
also something like a x or b x or a also
makes no sense
and then since we have this f and f
inverse they also be good
this could also cancel out we also don't
want to do something like this
and one i mean one technicality
in
all our gates will take two inputs but
of course f only takes one input
and but in our implementation it
actually has to take two inputs but then
we just enforce that these inputs are
the same so in the end it's just one
input
okay and
so again here the trivial approach would
have been to to test two to the 25
circuits but with our
our approach we only need to check two
to the 18 rules and then
the the number of circuit that
let's say survive that have to be
checked for for periods is only two to
the twelve
and what i our search then finds is this
circuit
so we
take the input we apply the round
function we add the input again and this
is then the second so the right input
of one encryption query and the left
input is just our the input of the
function
then we
we
add
the
outputs
so the left and the right output and
we then see or we then can show i mean
the our implementation then tells you
that this has a period and then it's
easy to see or easy to verify that the
period is actually k0 and that means
that using simon's quantum
simon's quantum algorithm you then can
recover k0 with just a polynomial amount
of quantum queries to to the missing rf
uh construction and therefore this is
also then totally wrong
in the quantum setting
so we
have some more attacks
and all these constructions as we that
we studied or that i
give here were actually already
studied before but only distinguishers
were were found and these were actually
similar to to the
distinguishing attack by kovacado and
movie against the three-on-five so with
like constants
as input that switch based on on one
input bit and in contrast to that we
give key recovery attack so on forward
miss the fk that's the one i just showed
also on five won't miss the lfk
and on four and five four and five fk
with
um you know a small
small thing for the fifo and daddy
the uh round function must be a
permutation so invertible which strictly
speaking must not be the case for faisal
functions
and
one
one thing about these distinguishers of
course one could
you know use them to build key
recoveries based on for example the
government simon approach but then again
the the number of queries one needs is
not
not polynomial anymore more but
exponential
and
since we
only rely on simon's algorithm we only
need a polynomial amount of credits to
it
okay then let me quickly talk about the
generalization part so about our
negative result
and and
okay so let's first consider the fourier
transform of a boolean function f
which is just
you know the sum of all y
uh of negative one to the inner product
of x and y plus the the
function evaluated evaluated at y
and we can rewrite this as the the
matrix product of h0 so the standard
data matrix which is i mean just the the
entry at x y is negative one to the
inner product of x and y
and
we multiply this with the vector where
we just take
the the function value to to a negative
or we take negative 1 to the the value
of the function at this point
and
now
if we
actually we don't really study simon's
algorithm but but the bernstein vasirani
circuit which is
rather close to simon so it's not a big
deal but there essentially the circuit
in the quantum attack
yields a vector from the
the span of
all the points that lead to a non-zero
for a coefficient
and now if we
uh consider a function that is
essentially as in simon's promise so
there is a unique period s
then we would have that uh
this this vector as such that the inner
product of the secret period is zero so
this is why where this comes from why
this is close to simon
and now our generalization is that we
look at i mean like a slightly different
transform
where we don't use the the standard
hadamard matrix anymore but just any
part of our matrix so just a quick
reminder hadamard means that the
transform of the matrix times the matrix
is the identity and of course the the
entries are
negative one two to some function g on
the base
that takes its input the entry
and now the the question network is what
meaningful
properties of f we could catch with some
or such a non-solid hadamard matrix
and especially we are interested in
whether we could
find out something about linear
invariant properties because in
symmetric cryptanalysis all the
properties that are interesting or most
of them like linearity differential
uniformity and the algebraic degree
are all linear and variant and that this
means that for um
for any inverter
invertible matrix a
f satisfies this property if and only if
f after a does
and now our main theorem here is that
and if for any a
there exists a b so both invertible
matrices
such that for all f's we have that
this this transform regarding h
of f after a is the same as the
transform of f after b
then h is equivalent to h0 and
this means that if h is not equivalent
to h0 then we cannot
catch
a linear invariant properties and
therefore we
believe that the standard hardware
matrix is is the way to go if you want
to study
or if you want to to
use this for symmetric cryptanalysis
okay so let me quickly recap the talk
so we have
had two contributions first the
automatized
uh
applications and there we
developed a way to to automatically
search for
quantum attacks based on simon's
algorithm
which only take a polynomial amount of
quantum queries and we use this to
actually find new attacks against the
misty and deviser construction and for
the generalization part we study
generalizations of simon's algorithm and
also the fourier transform thereby
and there we concluded that the standard
hadamard matrix is the best choice if
you want to study
symmetric or properties that are
relevant for symmetric analysis
and so if you interested in our work the
full version is available on eprint and
sage implementation
of our code to search for the periods is
available
on github and
if you have any further questions or
want to contact us then these are our
mail address and that's it for my site
and thank you
so are there any questions for luca
yes please go to go to the mic please
and i my computer died so if there are
any questions in zoom uh please could
someone let us know
okay i was just going to ask have you
looked at any of the hashing like the
compression function
kind of structures the things where you
have the block cipher and then the and
you're using the the key and feeding
forward or something like that
we looked uh also
for example at hashcount and something
like this there were also again
attacks already known which we could
also rediscover
and i guess we also i mean we can also
use essentially the same idea to to
search for a text based on the
government simon
approach and there we also find some
attacks
i guess on the permutation based edm
construction and
something else i think i just forgot but
yeah so
we looked at some construction but i'm
not sure whether these are actually the
ones you were talking about but thank
you
thank you i i have a question look at
have you
had a look or do you think it could be
adapted your tool in
some cases uh we do an exoplanet search
of
part of the key and then try to find the
if it applies simon in the
in the states or combining global
segment do you think you could detect
this kind of attacks
you know like i just said we can i mean
essentially use the same tool and like
add another node which is then
essentially the part where you would
apply grover
to do this and yeah you could do this
but this of course then
increases the runtime so
okay thanks are there any more questions
okay there are no more questions then
we'll thank you again lucas and all the
speakers of this session
think there's a break until half past
four now right