okay okay we'll start the next session
which is about advanced cryptographic
primitives to distinguish it from
primitive cryptographic primitives the
first talk is by malian arachova on
advanced cryptography on the way to
practice thank you good morning so today
I'm going to advocate that it's time
that some of the advanced cryptographic
techniques that we have been developing
also be put on the map of practical
cryptography so in the first question of
course is what is the definition of
advanced cryptography so the for the
purposes of my talk this would be
anything can you primitives and
techniques that look beyond the security
of data at rest and communication
channels and for this we have been using
techniques such as encryption and
digital signatures so we will be
interested in other types of techniques
from cryptography more specifically
techniques that are looking at the
protection of computation on sensitive
inputs so the type of functionalities
that we will be interested will be
giving us the ability to have multiple
participants that have private inputs
and we would like to be able to compute
some specific functionality from their
inputs while protecting the privacy of
these inputs and of course we would like
to be able to achieve this without
having this magic hat but rather and any
trusted party in the system and in this
talks I will touch on three types of
such advanced cryptographic primitives
which include multi-party computation
differential privacy and zero knowledge
proof so when I think about the
development of cryptographic research it
has constantly interrupting introducing
new techniques and new functionalities
but at the same time the adoption and
practice have been limited to for a long
time on very narrow part of these
cryptographic primitives and more
specifically focused on these data
protection primitives only in the last
couple of years we have seen companies
both big companies and small startups
starting to tap into these more advanced
cryptographic primitives and I'm hopeful
that in the future we will increase the
rate of adoption of this much more
powerful cryptographic techniques and in
this talk I will overview for you some
of the development in these three areas
that kind of give me this hope and I
should also first tell you that my
inspiration for this talk came by
listening to the invited talk of Chaka
levy at CCS this year where he made the
statement that advanced cryptography is
needed fast enough to be useful and also
not generally usable yet so in this talk
I will give you my perspective of this
question and I would like to start by
saying that when we think about
efficiency this should always be coupled
with utility and they're often not
Universal measures for efficiency it's
always good to be fast but sometimes
communication is the limiting factor
because this is a shared resource
bandwidth shared resource and we have to
compete for it in different settings we
might have incentive to do some pre
computation and sometimes the
participants in our protocols have
different assymetric resources that we
have to be careful about and also there
are many settings where we can really
make meaningful trade-offs between
efficiency and utility and also some of
the example that I'll be talking about
in this talk will be inspired from what
I saw in a privacy preserving machine
learning workshop that we organized with
Europe's in December so let me start
with the need for advanced cryptography
I think we all agree that nowadays data
is one of the most valuable resources we
like to gather a lot of data and analyze
it would like to build machine learning
models and then use them to predict and
target and one of the properties is that
often times the value comes in settings
where we are putting together private
data sets that are coming from multiple
sources so this inevitably brings
challenges when it comes to data use
having private data is inherently like
ability you have to be careful about
internal and external adversaries about
being subpoenaed for your data
there are many regulations that also
restrict the use of private data and
sharing of private data and if you are
not careful with your algorithms you
also they also might become source of
discrimination so in this context
privacy preserving computation brings
the promise that we can get utility
without sacrificing the privacy of our
data so we can reduce liability we can
enable new services for analysis that
were not possible before and we can also
have better user protection so in my
talk I will focus on two scenarios and
give you techniques that have been
developed for two scenarios that I think
are indicative for many of the practical
applications where we are thinking about
privacy preserving computation the first
scenario considers several
computationally powerful participants
that are connected and available to
participate in our protocols and this
model settings where we have several
companies for example that are
interacting and wanting to compute
something that depends on their
distributed resources the second
scenario is named federated learning and
considers the setting where we have one
powerful computation party and then we
have many weak devices that can talk
only to this one computational parties
and these devices have limited resources
and also may drop out during the
execution of our protocols so let's
start first with the first scenario and
look at some techniques that have been
developed in cryptography to facilitate
privacy preserving computation and this
setting and the first example that I
will give you is the functionality of
private set intersection which asks the
question if we have to input parties
that have two input sets how can we
compute the intersection of the sets
without revealing anything more about
the inputs so this simple functionality
has been useful in many settings where
we have for example two hospitals that
want to
they're common patients or we were we
have the list of terrorists and then a
list of passengers on a flight and we
want to find the intersection and this
problem has been widely studied in
cryptography we have had many solutions
developed and here I want to show you
the efficiency of the currently most
advanced techniques and here in the
setting we consider two adversarial
models in one of them the weaker one is
called semi honest where you assume that
parties behave as prescribed by the
protocol and the other one is malicious
that allows the participants to
arbitrarily deviate from your protocol
so the current state of DRA tells us
that we can achieve private set
intersection for sets of over a million
elements in the semi honest case in
under 10 seconds and in the malicious
case in about an hour so one application
of a related problem called private
intersection some is also used by Google
for aggregate at attribution another
example that I would like to discuss is
called private information retrieval
where we have one server that contains
that has a database and then we want to
enable a client to retrieve one record
from this database without revealing
what exactly is being retrieved because
maybe the selected record depends on
some private information some health
information or some preferences that we
want to hide from the server the
solutions for this problem leverage
powerful cryptographic primitive which
is called homomorphic encryption and
which allows us to compute on encrypted
data and I chose to show you this
example because this showcases the
current efficiency of who morphic
encryption techniques and what we are
able to do today is we were able to run
private information retrieval on
databases of size over 4 million where
the data items are of size 288 bytes in
about 12 seconds so this there this
shows the immense advancement in the
techniques for whom Orphic encryption as
well and certainly we would like to also
look at the question of general to party
computation that allows us to compete
any function that depends on the inputs
of two parties without revealing
anything more about their inputs and
there has been a tremendous amount of
works that have developed general
computation frameworks and oftentimes
the functionality that's used to
benchmark such implementation is secure
computation for AES where one party has
the key one party has the input and I
have selected here a few representative
works there are many many more just to
demonstrate the improvement in
efficiency in these protocols over the
past twenty years so we have seen
multiple orders of magnitude improvement
in the computation time starting in the
beginning with needing hours in the semi
honest case and more than a day in the
malicious case and nowadays we can run
secure AES in the semi honest case under
one millisecond and in the militias we
need about six point a six milliseconds
so that's another very impressive
development in general secure
computation and as I promised to you
some of the examples that I want to
cover here are coming from privacy
preserving machine learning which is
another area that I think is a very high
use of such techniques and here I want
to start with the statement that if you
want to get the most efficient
approaches for a privacy preserving
machine learning probably out of the box
use of secure computation techniques is
not the right approach oftentimes we
need to make the machine learning
algorithms and PC friendly and what do I
need what do I mean by this for example
most machine learning algorithms are
expecting to use floating point
computation and when it comes to secure
computation this is very very expensive
so many approaches have been trying to
redesign these algorithms to be able to
work with fixed point arithmetic also
some nonlinear functionalities that come
from ml are very expensive in secure
computation so people have been coming
up with efficient approximation such as
approximation for the real off function
also we can go from the other direction
where we'll be optimizing secure
computation techniques for machine
learning algorithms in particular we can
come up with specialized primitives that
are targeted at widely used
functionalities such as matrix
computation and machine learning or we
can build NPC protocols that exploit the
fact that we'll be interested only in
approximate computation and we have some
examples for example approximate fhe
constructions also machine learning is
the place where we can really trade-off
between accuracy and efficiency
especially regression type of algorithms
that have this iterative nature where we
can really choose what level of accuracy
we need and what pricing efficiency we
want to pay so and one last point is
that sparsity is really matters in
machine learning can there have been
developed a lot of computational
approaches that for example are
specified in the sparse blas standard
interface that aim to leverage sparsity
and we can try to translate this also in
the machine learning in a secure
computation techniques so let's look at
some examples from what has been done in
this area and the first example is
privacy-preserving
computation for distributed linear
regression so the setting here is that
we have a database and this database is
vertically partitioned between multiple
parties and the goal is to compute a
linear model using secure computation on
this data so in a work with several
co-authors we looked at this question
and the main technique that we used to
compute these linear models is solving a
system of linear equations so we
considered multiple ways to solve the
systems of linear equations and secure
computation and we found out that up an
approach based on conjugate gradient
descent that allows us to really
trade-off accuracy and efficiency seem
to be the best performant and for this
purpose we also needed to come up with a
variant of this algorithm that works
well with the fixed point arithmetic so
what we observed is that if we run CJD
only for 20 cents which means that we
don't have to go to convergence of this
algorithm we already get the error that
we also get from exact solutions and
this also allows us to improve on the
efficiency compared with the computation
of the exact solution in secure
computation and we can run this in a
couple of hundreds of seconds just as a
reference point running the whole
computation of the linear learning the
linear regression model on five hundred
thousand records depending on the number
of attributes from twenty attributes it
takes about 15 seconds and going to 500
attributes it takes about two hours to
compute the ML model and of course when
we talk about ml we have to look at
neural networks so here is an example
where we have two parties one of the
parties has a convolutional neural
network model and the other party has an
input that needs to be classified
according to the model in a secure
manner so here I will give you an
example from a work from UNIX this year
that proposed a hybrid approach between
fully homomorphic encryption and garbled
circuits and they evaluated their
solution on the amnesty data set that
contains images and the goal is to
classify this image as a particular
digit so they explored several CN &
topologies and all of their solutions
ended up running in less than a second
and their major distinguishing factor
was how much communication they needed
which depended on how much garbage
circuits versus fhe the approach was
using and as I mentioned sparsity is
often very important in machine learning
so that's why we developed a framework
that proposes secure computation
techniques that leverage sparsity for
machine learning algorithms and we try
to emulate the components of general
architectures for scientific computing
which propose different layers of
abstractions starting from a layer
that's accessing memory going to a layer
that does linear algebra and then the
application layers that build on top of
it so we developed all of this primitive
started for
use of sparse data and proposing this
layered architecture on which you can
kind of obliviously implement
applications on top of them so just for
purposes of comparison we run
computation of logistic regression
training using sparse data and we
compare it with the state-of-the-art
which is the secure ml paper from
security and privacy 2017 and we showed
that by leveraging private sparsity in
the input data we can achieve to times
improve of two to five times improvement
on the times for running the secure
computation depending on the input
sparsity so next let's move to the other
scenario that I described to you which
is federated learning where we have this
start communication with one powerful
and then weak devices so in the setting
one applications if scenario is secure
aggregation where the goal is to have
each of the devices yes don't make me
scared so the goal here is to have each
of the devices compute a local model and
then use some aggregation algorithm to
aggregate the parameters from the local
models and obtain a global model that
depends on the input of all participants
so there's a word from Google from 2017
that implemented such an algorithm and
it showed how its efficiency scales with
the number of small devices that are
participating and with the length of the
vectors that model the parameters so you
can see that even if you have 500
thousand even if you have 500 clients
and the length of the vectors is 500,000
the protocol still runs in a few seconds
and seamlessly handles drop out of the
parties in the protocol you could also
consider the same question but with a
little bit different architecture where
instead of
you have multiple servers that help you
do this processing and also add the
additions that each party apart from its
small device apart from contributing its
input also gives a proof of its validity
for example proving that it's within a
range so there is a very nice work from
Stanford from this year that implemented
such a protocol and this protocol is
actually being deployed in Firefox and
here is an example for the overhead that
this solution brings in terms of the
slowdown of the throughput that can be
handled by the server's and you can see
that this is the case of training D
dimensional square regression so
depending on the dimension the slowdown
goes from five point six times to eleven
point six times but just you're able to
handle between one thousand two and two
thousand requests per second so now that
we have looked at these settings of
computing aggregated functionalities we
can also ask a different question now
that we have the output of this
aggregated functionality does this
output reveal anything about individuals
who are contributing data and here we
meet the notion of differential privacy
which exactly tries to construct
algorithms that give us such type of
guarantees and there are two main
scenarios for which differential privacy
can be defined one of them is called the
central model which assumes that we have
a trusted aggregator that has access to
all the private inputs coming from the
individual contributors and this trusted
aggregator computes aggregated functions
and releases them and the goal is to
argue that this output of the aggregated
functions do not review an individual
data and differential privacy develops
this mechanism that captured this
intuitive notion by saying that the
output of this aggregator function on
neighboring databases that depend that
differ only on a single record will be
close and this closeness is
parameterised by a parameter epsilon
that will be used to trade-off between
privacy
utility in these mechanisms the other
model for differential privacy which is
called the local model no longer assumes
distrusted aggregator in this setting
each party has to locally randomize its
input before sending it to the untrusted
aggregator and we want to maintain the
same type of privacy guarantees with
respect to the individual contributors
and as you can see this setting a flock
of the local model matches much better
the setting of federated learning where
our central server is also our adversary
from which we want to hide the privacy
of the individuals contributing their
inputs so there has been a lot of work
developing general differential privacy
mechanisms in the central model as well
as specialized methods for particular
functionalities of interest but since
the local model has been more relevant
in this setting of federated learning
this has been where some of the
companies have been looking at and
Google and Apple have been leveraging
some local differential privacy
techniques in order to aggregate to
collect aggregate statistics and the
challenge really here is to achieve good
trade-off between utility and privacy
because in general in local differential
privacy we need to have more noise to
protect privacy compared to the central
model and this framework that came from
Google which is called rapport has
turned to be the main example to compare
against when you are developing new
local differential privacy techniques
and in the next two examples that I will
show you we have seen some work that
improves on what has been achieved by a
rapport so this first example comes from
Europe and 2017 and has developed an
algorithm that detects heavy-hitters
using local differential privacy and
this the result in this work improved
the total work that needs to be done by
the server while meeting
worse-case error that has been proven in
these models and as you can see from
this result you can see comparisons
between the estimated frequencies using
this algorithm compared to the exact
frequencies in a data set of 10 million
samples with about 26 thousand unique
words and you can see that smaller
values for epsilon will mean more
privacy and we expect that then this is
where we'll have more error in terms of
the utilities and you can see that this
algorithm performs quite well for
counting the heavy hitters for different
going from the most frequent items even
also in the setting of the less frequent
items and the main comparison against
rapport really comes when you are
looking at the least frequent less
frequent items where this new algorithm
comes much closer to the exact values
compared to the rapport estimate another
work from USENIX 2017 also develops a
general framework for local differential
privacy that improves the choice of
parameters and as a result of this
achieves better trade-offs between the
privacy and the utility and what you can
see from these graphs is that as you
increase the epsilon value which means
that we reduce the privacy guarantee it
achieves smaller errors and at the same
time achieves higher true positives and
when we are talking about this
comparison between the central and the
local models for differential privacy
and natural question is to ask whether
we can use secure computation techniques
to get the best of both worlds and what
I mean here is to get the utility from
the central model while providing the
privacy guarantees from the local model
and their generic construction that
composed the two but often times these
are not the most efficient and some new
model that has been introduced this year
which is called the shuffle model has an
interesting observation
that if you take the inputs that are
coming from the local model or the ones
that have been locally randomized by
each of the parties and you shuffle them
randomly before sending them to this
untrusted aggregator you actually need
to add much less noise in order to
achieve the same level of privacy in
particular you need to add on the volga
rhythmic noise in this shuttle model
compared with the local model where you
need square root nose and this new
shuffle model has been used also in a
new work coming from google which is
called Wroclaw and there the shuffle
algorithm has been implementing using
edge X and they have demonstrated that
this performs much better than rapport
in terms of detecting how many unique
words for example you are coming from
the input of these small devices and
also when we are talking about this
amplification from GP and MPC I also
wanted to point out a new interesting
work that came from bu this year which
also has a very interesting title
turning hate into love where love stands
for a large scale one server vanishing
participants efficient MPC or more or
less the federated learning model that I
described and hate is a new primitive
homomorphic ad hoc threshold encryption
and then they demonstrated how you can
construct this federated learning
protocols from this new primitive and
give you different instantiations of
this primitive and also their protocols
meet the lower bound that they can prove
for this model in terms of how many
messages you need to exchange okay so
this also brings us to the last
primitive that I want to tell you about
in this talk which is zero knowledge
proof and there are knowledge proofs
help us prove that we know some secret
without revealing it and for example if
we have this small device and it wants
to send an encryption of some input but
at the same time we want this device to
be able to prove that this input is
within a specified range so why do we
want to use zero knowledge proof I
assume all of you know their application
in the context of work chain of proving
properties about encrypted data but this
is by far not the only interesting
application of zero knowledge as we saw
in the context of machine learning you
can prove properties about your inputs
you can also generate proofs that you
have correctly run the training
algorithm for a machine learning
algorithm or the evaluation with respect
to a commitment of certain uncertain
data and when we talk about zero
knowledge protocols there are several
efficiency properties that we should be
thinking about this include the prover
sufficiency the verifiers efficiency the
succinct nests which means how long are
the proofs whether our protocols need
interaction between the prover and the
verifier and finally whether we need
trusted setup and what does trusted
setup mean is that we have some phase in
which we need to embed some secret into
in what we call common reference string
and it is very important that this
secret remains hidden from every anybody
who'll be generating proofs because the
soundness of our proofs will depend on
this secret not being deep so in this
with respect to distrusted setup I would
like to distinguish snarks which means
succinct non interactive arguments of
knowledge versus other techniques for
zero knowledge because as far as we are
concerned with existing constructions
all snark constructions require trusted
setup and we have some new work on
hybrid constructions that offer you
dwell mode of execution that it could
behave in there either as a snarf or as
a non trusted set up system but let's
look at these two major types of zero
knowledge so if we want to talk about
zero knowledge snarks then most of the
existing constructions
average technique which is called
quadratic arithmetic programs which we
introduced a few years ago so there are
several systems that implement this main
technique in various different flavors
starting from our work Pinocchio and
maybe the most widely used one nowadays
which is lip snark
and in terms of what is their efficiency
I will give you an example from paper
from music this year that introduced
ways to paralyze the computation on the
prover note that in the case of snarks
since the proof is so short usually the
verification time is very efficient and
the optimization goals are on improving
the run time of the prover so this paper
achieves prover time that takes ten
microseconds per gate and the verifier
time is also very fast so if we want to
look at specific applications if you
want to generate the proof or the
correct training of linear regression on
20,000 points in dimension 500 this
takes about 95 seconds if we want to
look at zero knowledge without trusted
setup then we have to we have a lot of
trade-offs between the proof size and
the verifiers work that are between
logarithmic and linear there have been
many approaches to construct such such
protocols some of them are based on
discrete logs which include bullet
proofs which has been a paper with lots
of applications recently there are MPC
based approaches such as GK boo and Lee
hero then there are some other
techniques that I put in the category
are you yuppie based techniques such as
hyrax
GK Starks Arora so here I have some
graphs from the hyrax paper that really
show that there are many different
trade-offs when you look at these
systems in terms of proof size and
verification and prover efficiency so
you have to be very careful with respect
to your specific application what you
choose these numbers are for proving
knowledge of assignment
corresponding to the root of a Mirko
tree so you can see what's happening
here and since I'm running out of time
let me try to conclude I try to give you
a few examples from techniques from
advanced cryptography which all of them
are accompanied by implemented systems
so how can we use this advanced crypto
so a word of warning is that none of
this system is really out of the box use
system and there are good reasons for
that
because sometimes hiding complexity in
order to facilitate usability also
sacrifices efficiency and in many of
these scenarios we cannot afford to do
this we really need to squeeze every
last bit of efficiency so if you want to
use this systems you really need experts
even for choosing your parameters or for
doing comparison across different
frameworks the implementation code is
research level code so it's not
definitely not production level code if
you're interested to learn more about
these techniques their ongoing
standardization efforts in the area of
zero knowledge and fully homomorphic
encryption and also there are some links
that give you a starting point to learn
what's available out there for MP CDP
and zero knowledge and since I started
by saying that the inspiration for my
top was shakily which talk let me finish
also with something from his talk which
said that it's really time to put to use
these techniques in practice so I would
like to thank you and take any questions
[Applause]
thank you we have time for why don't we
have questions okay our last question
what's your favorite open questions what
would you like to solve in the next
three years five I mean it's it's
interesting to put together a lot of
this technique so if you're thinking
about the question of federated machine
learning right we we are still kind of
struggling to to compose in a very good
way differential privacy and MPC and
also there is the space of bringing zero
knowledge in terms of guaranteeing
correctness for the inputs so I think
combining and developing these systems
that will have very I think a huge
impact in practice is something that's
still an open question for me we have
some promising start thing points but
there is a lot of work to do in that
thank you
[Applause]
okay so the next talk will be deploying
MPC for social good and the speaker is
Lucy Cheng I'm a research software
engineer at Boston University and I'm
going to focus on one of the techniques
that Mariana just spoke to and mention
how we've use it in practice so I'm
speaking today on deploying MPC for
social good so I want to begin by
highlighting a variety of different
applications that we at Boston
University are collaborating on in the
space specifically of MPC for social
good
so from enabling joint medical studies
to allowing social scientists to share
research data to protecting data of
those recovering from opioid addiction
there is a wide array of societal
problems that can significantly benefit
from the use of MPC however the work
needed to actually go from taking an
idea to deployment involves a lot of
important work that happens outside the
scope of the cryptography itself which
will be the focus of my talk so today
I'm going to focus specifically on three
use cases and deployments and begin with
a study on pay equity and to make sure
we're on the same page of secure
multi-party computation or MPC is a
cryptographic technique for computing
some function f over private inputs
while yielding a public output so our
work and MPC began with this story here
in 2013 the mayor of Boston at the time
Mayor Menino set out to make Greater
Boston the premiere place for working
women in America and he wanted to do
this by removing the visible and
invisible barriers to female advancement
so this later led to the creation of
something called to the Boston Women's
workforce council and this council seeks
to one understand the root causes of the
wage gap to work towards closing that
gap in three evaluate the success in
doing so so currently there are over 200
businesses in the Boston area that have
signed on to a compact with the Boston
woman's workforce council and in this
compact they
agree to contribute their salary data
and also to a number of other
initiatives honing in on best practices
toward actually addressing the societal
issue so we at Boston University have
been working towards enabling this data
a contribution process by using MPC to
protect company level data while still
allowing aggregate data to be brought
forth to the public for analysis and for
us to really understand the wage gap
itself so in the originally proposed
workflow of how Boston wanted to conduct
a study of this level they wanted each
business to submit their data in the
form of spreadsheets in its raw form to
a trusted third party and that trusted
third party would take all of that data
do the proper analysis on it and
generate the results however the lawyers
at these companies were weary of any
entity receiving that raw salary data no
matter how trusted they actually were
and also the trusted third party later
backed out for similar reasons they were
also afraid of a data breach and they
didn't want to be sued potentially by
hundreds of different companies so so
this is where we got to MPC so our team
proposed an MPC based solution and as
shown by the challenges in the original
and proposed workflow there are a
variety of different concerns coming
from the perspective of different roles
involved in this type of study
so our MPC based solution has taken into
consideration all of these concerns in
order for successful deployments to
actually happen so first I'm going to
talk about the lawyers concerns as I
mentioned they are very concerned about
liability and the protocol itself thus
federates trust between Boston
University and the Boston Women's
workforce Council so individual level
data can only be revealed if the two of
us decide to collude and I argue that
neither of us are incentivized to do so
for the good of both of our reputations
and for the cause of the actual problem
so the Boston Women's workforce council
itself is concerned with participation
they want as many companies in the
Boston area to sign on and actively
contribute their data
towards us initiative so therefore the
solution has to be easily accessible by
a wide range of different companies so
here we have hospitals a law for firms
financial firms all contributing and
they have different types of corporate
environments so therefore we can't do
things like set up servers on specific
ports or run virtual machines or have to
manipulate different things involving
their firewalls so we chose to use a
browser-based solution since hopefully
everyone has a browser and all the code
here runs in the web client so the HR in
diversity personnel at these individual
companies is the person who's actually
contributing this data and using the
platform and going through this process
and they want to make sure that the
process is as easy for them to navigate
and that they can correctly contribute
their data so we have thus focused very
heavily on the usability and we start
out by first using a standardized
template that is familiar to them and
they are ready to use versions of this
for regulatory purposes and we're also
continually working on a number of
different things to improve the
usability of the platform which I will
speak to you later so lastly we have the
IT personnel at the companies who is
interested in verifying the code itself
and making sure that it provides the
security guarantees that we claim that
it does so therefore our code is open
source and available on github for
anyone to audit and we have purposely
written it so that it is as clear and
concise as possible so that it is easy
to verify and in managing all of these
concerns of the roles there is another
element of simplicity that I want to
emphasize so we use an additive seeker
sharing scheme under a semi honest
threat model so protocol here itself has
existed for some time now and there is
nothing really new in it it's in itself
and there are definitely more
technically sophisticated platforms out
there that deal with these complex
issues of scalability and performance
that come along with MPC but as I
mentioned the simplicity here is really
intentional we need to be able to
explain the solution to CEOs lawyers to
all the different roles that I just
mentioned and they have to be
successfully convinced enough to want
give over their data to us and believe
that it really will be protected and as
you see here we add a random mask to the
data which is passed along to Boston
University while the masks themselves
are given to the Boston Women's
workforce council there for segmenting
trust and the image here is the actual
explanation that we use to the various
different types of people that we need
buy-in from and we have been
successfully able to do this to actually
get them to agree to this contribution
process and we also hold training
sessions where HR and diversity
personnel can attend ask questions and
be walked through the submission process
itself and here is a stripped-down
version of what the platform actually
looks like you can see the full thing at
a hundred talent org so each user is
given a session key and participation
code as I mentioned before there is a
standardized template that they receive
in Excel form and they can pre-fill it
and then drag and drop it here and it
will autofill all the fields necessary
or they can go through and fill out each
cell in the spreadsheet manually on the
platform itself so this screenshot only
depicts total annual compensation but we
have also gathered aggregate data on
performance pay which measures bonuses
and also the length of service to get a
more granular look at this problem
itself and we also gather data based on
race and job category so we can look
across the different levels from
executive down to more entry level
positions so an interesting lesson we've
learned here is that we've had to be
very specific about the language we're
using when we actually explain what's
going on on the platform so words like
upload or submit have a general
connotation of giving over data in its
plain text form but here that doesn't
happen it never leaves the actual
browser in that form so we do not use
the word upload in the drag and drop box
here we also had to very explicitly
state what submit means in this specific
context
so since recovering mistakes under MPC
can be expensive we have added error
checks to help make sure the process is
as error-prone as possible we have
information about what the upper
bound uncertain metrics might be given
the cohort of different companies that
do participate in the study so therefore
we can provide warnings when numbers
exceed that upper bound and we also
provide checks to make sure that the
format itself is correct before we allow
users to submit so as you can see here
there are a number of errors that can be
triggered and they all have to be
cleared before the user can actually
submit their data and we also provide
something we call a totals check
throughout the process we just count up
all the different personnel that were
included in the data and therefore
employees can look at that and have a
sanity check of whether the total
actually matches up with their
organization so we do also allow users
to resubmit their data and overwrite
whatever has been previously submitted
in case there is an error and we
conducted this MPC submission process
over a period of a week so if they
discover something on day two they can
still go fix those problems and then
submit later on so as I mentioned we
want to emphasize usability for the
employees actually submitting the data
as part of this process we asked a
number of high-level questions such as
the relative ease of preparing the data
for submission and the type of training
that they've had in doing so and the
answers to the survey responses here are
also seeker shared we have also been
interested in getting more granular
level data on the user experience itself
but we can't use a third party web
analytics engine like Google Analytics
without potentially revealing data so
therefore we've added some basic web
analytics such as errors users encounter
the average time spent and mouse
movement into the MPC protocol this data
is secret shared along with the actual
data about the salaries and the survey
questions that I just mentioned and this
is only seen in aggregate form so the
picture on the right here shows the
mouse movements from a Mechanical Turk
study we conducted using this method
moving forward we want to a be test our
platform to have a better understanding
quantitatively of the user experience so
because of the security guarantees at
MPC
provides the work done in addressing the
wide spectrum of concerns from different
roles involved in the study we have been
able to successfully deploy this twice
now first in 2016 and again in 2017 and
in 2017 a hundred and fourteen employers
participated in this and that accounted
for sixteen percent of the workforce in
the Greater Boston area and we are once
again deploying this in fall of 2019 so
the results here are unsurprising and if
you're interested in learning more about
what the wage gap problem looks like in
the Boston area
you can feel free to read the reports
that the Boston Women's workforce
Council puts out based on the results of
this data itself so and although studies
have been done in the past on wage
equity we are able to gather data
longitudinally with more participants
added each year as our mayor Marty Walsh
notes in 2014 there were only 38
companies committed to this study and
now there are over 250 and since the
study occurs periodically we are hoping
to gather data on specific cohorts over
time to be able to assess of the wage
gap is widening or closing as different
practices are implemented this also
helps us actually drive accountability
towards addressing the problem since
we're seeing the different effects over
time in the data itself because of its
granular nature can help drive a more
nuanced discussion of the wage gap in
Boston we are able to see where the gap
is wider and how that varies by job and
race and in the next employment we're
also working towards industry specific
breakdowns as well so we can compare
different industries and how they match
up with the average and the granularity
of the data also allows us to get more
specific about the solutions and allows
us to address the places of the grossest
inequalities and of course although the
MPC is an important piece in gathering
this data it is only part of the broader
solution towards this societal issue the
Boston Women's workforce Council is
involved in making connections with all
of these companies hosting workshops and
hearing from the businesses themselves
on the roadblocks that contribute to pay
equity they also talk about best
practices toward advancing women in the
workforce as a whole so this data can
help drive the
conversation but that conversation still
needs to happen between actual people
coming together to discuss the changes
that need to happen in the workplace and
with that I want to discuss another use
case of MPC in the city of Boston that
we have been involved in so we're
working with the Greater Boston Chamber
of Commerce on an initiative to promote
economic inclusion companies are
expected to increase their supplier
diversity here by supporting local women
and minority-owned businesses and we
collect metrics similar to the other
study in aggregate form on spending
toward these types of businesses versus
total spending by these companies as a
whole and right now there are currently
around or they're more than ten
companies participating in these
deployments so it's happening at a much
larger smaller scale than the pay equity
study but we've been able to repurpose
the same platform for that study here
with a simple configuration file and
we've also applied the same lessons
we've learned in usability and
accessibility and auditability and in
how we've been communicating MPC to
allow for successful deployment to
happen and this was first employed last
spring and we're looking at an upcoming
deployment in March and so now I'm going
to switch gears and talk briefly about a
different use case in detecting serial
perpetrators of sexual misconduct so
close there was a non-profit that
creates technology to combat sexual
misconduct and they first created a
sexual assault reporting tool on college
campuses so with that platform they were
able to see some really great impact
where students were six times more
likely to report through Callisto and
there were three times were more likely
to seek out medical and emotional
support and they also found that 15% of
the survivors using the tool were
actually able to be matched with another
survivor that named the same perpetrator
going off of the me2 movement last year
Callisto wanted to expand this work into
tech serial perpetrators in industry
settings in a way that was empowering
for survivors so they were interested in
a cryptographic approach that could stop
the spread of sexual violence while
protecting the privacy and civil
liberties of both the survivor and the
accused so this is where my
and some others come in on the crypto
side of things so we work together with
kalisto on a design and implementation
that guarantees that identifying
information about a survivor and accused
can only be decrypted by a lawyer when
at least two users name the same
perpetrator so I'm going to describe a
very watered down version of the design
omitting a lot of the details here in
order to just highlight a few key
takeaways but for more information you
can refer to the white paper shown here
so let's say Alice and Bob named the
same perpetrator the same key is then
determine distally deterministically
generated this key is then used to help
encrypt any identifying information
about either of them and Mallory so
let's say we have another user here
Carlos who names a different perpetrator
Eve an entirely different key is then
generated and through the use of an
oblivious pseudo-random function with
two different servers involved the slope
and intercept values here for Shamir
seekers sharing are generated based on
the perpetrator identity so as I
mentioned this uses from your secret
sharing with a threshold of two and the
secret of the perpetrator identity is
embedded in the slope and the key which
serves at the y-intercept so Alice and
Bob then have the exact same slope and
key values but differing hashed user IDs
which ultimately generate different Y
values and these x and y values then
represent Alice and Bob as shares that
can be used to reconstruct that original
key this then reveals that key which we
can use to decrypt information about the
users and the perpetrator and as you see
here Carlos who named a different
perpetrator Eve cannot be used to
construct the key in the same manner oh
and I wanted to point out there are
other techniques involved that I have
not mentioned so once again refer to the
white paper so I wanted to bring up this
example specifically because it is
another deployment where the crypto has
been successful in tandem with advocacy
and that advocacy work is rooted deeply
and understanding the population that
the technology itself serves
there is important work happening
Callisto on trauma informed design and
making sure that the process itself does
not reach Ramat eyes the user who's
using it and they also put out a
survivor guide that a numerous different
resources outside of the technology that
users can benefit from yeah and there's
also real empathy because of the word
Callisto has already done on college
campuses they're building off of
information and lessons learned from
that process so there is a credibility
and human sense of trust so the crypto
code here is also open source and
auditable by anyone who would like to
view it and of course the crypto on its
own would fail to take on a life without
all of this work that has come before it
and also along with it and this touches
back on the same critical pieces of work
that needs to be done on the usability
and accessibility side and in making
sure you are fully communicating the
guarantees to your users so hopefully I
have demonstrated that MPC has broad
appeal in applicability to a variety of
causes and feels the techniques I've
mentioned have like additive seeker
sharing or Shamir secret sharing have
existed for decades and are not
necessarily novel but they do show how
even very simple protocols can have a
huge impact when joined together with
strong partnerships and vital work in
addressing all of this stuff outside of
crypto such as the usability
accessibility and auditability so I'm
really excited about the play that MPC
can be applied to to help tackle
different social problems and I hope you
are as well so thank you
thank you questions I first I just
wanted to say thank you this sounds like
fantastic work and like I'm really glad
that people are working on it across
both the advocacy and the technical side
and that's part of my question is from
the first case study where you talked
about with the sharing of the salary
data you can very easily imagine that
the lawyers get together in to say no
this isn't gonna happen
we're not gonna give it to any third
party and obviously you need some
trusted third party in order to do this
so the whole project to shut down how
did that gap from that business side of
it - like how did anybody think like
maybe somebody at Boston University
knows a way that we can do this without
sharing the data like how did that
happen yeah yeah so I think it took a
lot of work on our team - like I said to
make sure we're communicating those
guarantees very properly so I think it
is we've done a lot of iterations of how
we explain MPC and additive secret
sharing itself so we've tried out
different graphics different visuals and
throughout time have refined those more
and more but yeah it's just a lot of
making sure that you're testing out
different ideas and seeing how they
click with the exact users your I guess
in this case the lawyers that you're
speaking to and really honing in on what
their concerns are
I really cool work on the Calista's
system I had a question who who enters
information into the system and what
prevents like a party just like trying
to probe and in exfiltrated information
out that is it is it access control in
that you have to be a lawyer to enter
information into it or no so the
individual users are the ones entering
their own information but the lawyers
are the only ones who can actually
decrypt that information and they each
have their own private keys that are
necessary before they can even access
the platform itself okay Thanks so
multi-party computation requires a bit
more math than
typical stakeholder would be familiar
with did you have any difficulty
explaining to them what you were doing
it and and getting them to trust you
yeah yeah so so that's all we really
have to go back and focus on these types
of visuals so we've used things in the
past like perhaps like cakes so
demonstrating it in something that's
let's focus on math and more something
that's a bit more tangible we've also
used different levels of bar graphs and
showing how if you take one bar graph
and then you subtract out some other
bars from it and something of that sort
showing the end results we also have
some paper demos that we've run through
with people where we have them write
down their own secret number have them
pass that sheet of paper along to
someone else have them add a mask and
repeat this process and allow people to
ask open-ended questions about it and
follow up on that did you did you have
very many people you met with very many
decision-makers who just never came
around who remained resistant so there
are some people who on the opposite side
of things have agreed to participate in
the process
but then done things like give us an NDA
for the data when we've gone back and
said hey we don't have the data that is
actually the core guarantee here that
we're making so we've definitely seen
stuff like that thank you any other
questions so hi this one
is it better yeah thank you for the talk
it's very interesting so I was wondering
is there a chance that an employee or
the HR personnel could submit the salary
information which is not exactly the
information that goes to the pay slips
of the employees like can they submit
wrong information just to show that they
like in in terms of wages hey sorry I
couldn't write the entire question would
you mind repeating it slightly louder oh
yeah sure so is there a chance that an
HR personnel submits salary information
which is not the actual information that
goes into the pay slips that are in the
passage just to show that they are
providing equal wages but they're not
actually so is there a need for
verifying the salary information yeah I
think that is something that would be
ideal so actually because of the way
that the Boston Women's workforce
council communicates with these
companies that's not something we're
able to provide so the companies that
can choose to contribute their data or
not as you saw there were over 250
companies actually in the compact but
around half of them actually contribute
data so some of these companies want an
element of being able to say like hey we
care about this issue so we're going to
be in this compact but we're not part of
this data that was actually in there
because we're doing well so they want
that ability to have an out in that
manner so therefore we can't actually
verify who is in the data set and who
has contributed data and because that we
also can't verify any notion of
correctness so for things to move
forward in that fashion there would have
to be some changes in the communication
with these companies and changes
fundamentally and how the compact is
structured thank you thank you Lisa the
next stock
[Applause]
so the next talk is towards transparent
zero knowledge computation and Kurt
Nilsen will will give the talk yes yes
okay thank you I will continue the the
disc to talk about how to convince
people about using this fantastic
technology serum cylinders computation
or multi-party computation so I've been
I'm not a disclaimer I'm not a computer
scientist I'm an economist but I heard
about this technology for 15 years ago I
was convinced about this and as a
researcher we made up we raised money
and we farm years after we created the
first use of this technology which was
commercial use and the company that used
this I wanted to buy the solution
afterwards so we did a university
spin-out which is Patricia and what I'm
talking about is what we have been doing
and trying to convince people about
buying into this technology and use that
for a number of applications yeah that's
that's basically the the talk and it has
been used commercially for 10 years by
now so it's it's not the new - G - yeah
it has been used basically so let me
just talk to you talk to some of the
challenges that we have been facing so
clearly doing computation it's just in a
black box like MPC requires that
convince people about what what do we
actually doing so transparency and and
the platform that we're using is super
important so the first case that we we
had was a was very tangible in terms of
running a multi-party computation it was
an industry set up some contracts needed
to be exchanged among buyers and sellers
and each of the parties you can see the
pictures there they came with their own
laptop and the USB stick with the
cryptographic materials so it was very
tangible that they were they were
connected least three computers and he
computed the clearing price so this
applications actually distributed the
exchange it was a standard exchange
mechanism that was implemented using
this technology so that was the starting
point
sorry that was pretty slow but the
running an auction like this was not
really an issue because there was a
plenty of time she to wait for the
result even though I think it took
fifteen minutes or so with everything
since then the the protocols has
improved tremendously buying by by the
contribution from a lot of you so and
that sort of leads mg makes it possible
to apply the technology to two other
applications and that's what we have
been trying to do so definitely doing
more auctions in the beginning moving
into key management doing more
statistics and and so on so that's one
side of it the other side is to move
into platforms that are more scalable
but maybe also a little less transparent
using cloud computing but you could run
it on on separate cloud service
providers at least it's just to signal
that it's truly just distributed or what
we are doing recently is to use
blockchain technology to have maybe
create some more transparencies that's
at least what we will claim and done
right I guess we could also get this to
to scale I'll be talking more about this
but basically one of the challenges is
that we are selling trust so it's we
have to convince people that it's more
trustworthy teach you just to be you the
system instead of just pointing or
basically a counter bribe a consultancy
to do a trust trust to solve the the job
as a trustee and that is the challenge
it clearly is and when you convince them
about that then the next question is who
should actually run the notes so the
initial case where we had the some
natural groups of persons buyers and
sellers you could basically hand and
note to each of these
groups other cases you might not know a
priori who's who should actually who
would be the posting interest in this
this setting so you need some notes and
that just continues to be a chance but
that's also some of the things that we
had shrugging in within solving so let
me introduce so what we have been doing
is that we started the petition ten
years ago and then we tried to sort of
sell the the big vision and which was
difficult at that time but that was
people who who who saw the the use of
having a tissue field option and we
found the first industrial investors did
a cloud solution option systems and then
we moved into two key management got the
first institutional investors and along
the way we've been looking a lot at
statistical solutions and that has been
but that's something that we have spin
out spin doubt in in in a separate
country oh sorry a separate company
recently and and and what we're doing
now is actually to combine some of these
resources that we have been working on
and into something they called privacy
blockchain and I would talk a little
more about that in in a minute
so basically I want to sort of walk
through some of the applications that we
have been doing and then go back to this
idea of privacy blockchain and maybe try
to convince you why we need an
infrastructure like this so the
beginning was auctions so you basically
remove that weak third party institution
distribute the option is to make the
institution more trustworthy and maybe
also more cost efficient and that's what
we have been doing selling various
commodities like spectrum rights used
for telecommunication
rough diamonds working on that on
high-stake option for rough diamonds
working on electricity options so it's
solve a problem in that in that space a
similar type of mechanism is matching
and a case that we are building as which
week is off exchange matching or
basically what is known as the dark pool
so we take the dark pool operators and
distribute that one of the challenges
with these dark pool is that if they get
hacks you get a lot of valuable
information and so they're so they are
an example of a wonderful third party in
the financial system that could be
improved by a distributed set up that's
also gave to us a lot of chances so the
Year requirement was high this should be
run really fast this should be for
tolerance they wanted as many notes as
they could get so I think we ended up
passing the requirements with seven
notes and this technology is now been
moved in she brought change so this is a
also becoming a blockchain application
because the the design is really it's
this institution has been designed to
have institutional investors trade on on
on financial markets but smaller smaller
smaller buyers and sellers meeting the
same chances on selling crypto assets in
in the blockchain space so that's what
we are trying to choose solve with this
solution that would be a separate entity
well that would be announced relatively
soon so that's the market design
solutions
in terms of statistics we have been
focusing on privacy-preserving statistic
in different settings the the first one
the one to the left is a is a very
interesting case so this is about the
Danish statistics and it's about the
Dainius health care data that is to
public registers that has never been
combined they're not allowed to combine
this but now they see the opportunity to
use a two party system so they can claim
okay they don't really combine the data
but it's still making them available to
run analysis on these combined data and
healthcare and socio-economic data which
is clearly highly valuable especially
because in Denmark where this is
happening they have registered all the
citizens from their birth for the past
250 years so that's a really long track
record on on URIs on a full on and on on
an unbiased sample of the population so
you can match in a number of scenarios
in pharmaceutical companies coming in
and simulating a phase two trial which
is super valuable if you can if you can
detect some challenges with a new drug
at an early stage and things like that
so but this is this will be some very
controlled type of computations were
these two public registers they would
say they would look at the computation
that you would like to run and they will
say go and no go and then you can run
the D computation and get your
aggregated statistics at the end so
that's one case the other case is
another blockchain application which is
remove or basically disrupting the data
broker so it's a decentralized system
that give control to the data subjects
so you as a data subject you can sell
your data to a Data regressor so the the
youth
NPC in this is that that's running a
number of two-party matching of the
requesters needs and you you a personal
data and if you match the criteria then
you get to trade your data in a token
economy so so yeah so that's basically
what it what it does distributed system
that removes the the central the
middleman as a data broker and
distributed to you the individual data
subjects and that's the thing that this
technology can do so the last this one
is is basically a treasure cryptography
it's solving things like more secure
solution for crypto wallets more
cloud-based key management systems and
we actually have the full the number of
people from the from zip you're here
today so just let me know if you want to
an introduction so with that's sort of
the the the some of the basic things
that we've been going on and as I
mentioned there's actually a crypt took
a blockchain application in each of
these fields market design statistics
key management and what we have been
felt and that we have been going on for
the past year or two and that we want to
combine and the insight that we have we
have achieved by this work we combine
that into this new project so we have
that the key management is actually a
component in this solutions and the
first tier application which is in
matching and the dative brogan the
distributed data Roga is two nice
examples of what you could do with an
application with an infrastructure like
the one we want you to construct or is
basically constructing as we speak we
just want to make it easier for people
to to create applications like this in
the future
yes so blockchain and privacy might be
sort of an evolution and and what we're
focusing on is basically step three so
where you have a lot of information that
involved from many uses
so using zero knowledge proof is not
feasible you need something that is that
can that are more flexible that can do
to narrow your computations and that's
basically what this project is focusing
on whether you believe in this vision or
not it's at least something that is been
articulated the web tree data where you
get some sort of a blockchain computer
and you and to have this to solve real
property definitely needs as serious
privacy meshes and that's what we are
trying to g22 add in a distributed
fashion so going back to that
infrastructure from our perspective is
basically three things so you have the
the lecture you have the smart contracts
you have the privacy meshes which is
basically what you would need to to
solve a number of problems and I will
come back to that try to ask you what is
the class of problems that we we are
focusing on so just two more words about
this infrastructure so one thing is the
notes so you have the blockchain which
we are we're just not really changing
anything just taking the best practice
blockchain but that's sort of a separate
job to solve as a node then you have the
this what we call seek a computation
which is MPC which is a it's a separate
task for these nodes and typically you
have large networks for the blockchain
infrastructure for the MPC you'll have
smaller ad hoc networks so if you need
and you need to separate these two and
they
need to collaborate to get these get the
synergies out of these two different and
networks and that's what we are
struggling with getting that in place we
it's it's really all about orchestration
it make it simple to come with your
problem get a provable secure protocol
delegate trust in the in the system and
then then get a efficient simple and
robust execution which is what we've
been working on for for these past 10
years and also met other requirements
than just getting it to run fast like
robustness what happens if the note is
not available and and so on so that's
the infrastructure that we are we are we
are working on and the next slides is
actually some sort of a an attempt to to
a key come with a class of use cases
that needs a what we'll call privacy
blockchain
so as an economist is really all about
taking a decision so you have two
components you have alternatives and
then you have some preferences on these
alternatives so getting this big data or
getting more data about the alternatives
as well as you the Preferences of course
makes it possible to make better
decisions if you take into account the
complexity of these decisions so you
might have you have the overall
strategic decision you you have the
other end you have automated operational
decisions that hopefully move you in the
in the direction of your strategy so
that's one problem to solve and then you
everyone is part of some strategic
interaction with a number of other
partners you have privacy concerns there
are regulatory concerns there's a number
of concerns about these stations that
should that realize these these better
decisions so somehow we need to mitigate
between keeping the Eastasia private and
use the data to to make it better
decisions so that is of course some core
stuff though for economists and and this
resource is actually one of the starting
point for for petition is from result
from 1979 so it's nothing new
it's the revelation principle and it's
it's kind of a nice small result that
says okay with with you can have any
mechanism if you could if you could
instead of you being the strategic
player you basically just tell the truth
to a impartial trusted third party that
behaves in your interest and that's it's
really easy to see that that can always
be better than any mechanism so that's
what economists use as a sort of
theoretical basis for creating
mechanisms so this is sort of the
starting point and then you try to
create your mechanisms that solve the
real world problem but that's your
benchmark and it's been more like a
construct so personally when I heard
about this technology for the first time
it didn't take me many seconds to
realize that this would be a fantastic
technology which if you actually have
what is called the social planar the
impartial trusted third party then you
could basically allocate the resources
in a more efficient way in in general so
I personally think this is a very strong
argument for for using for MPC so and
that's mechanisms and mechanism is
actually a way to certain navigate
between which we use to organize the
economy could be a contractual
relationship with DVD society as such
whether it's decentralized or
centralized system which we have an
option you actually set up the rules for
how to do the the how to facilitate
competition that solve some of the basic
problems that you have in the economy
whether you are in a decentralized or
centralized well so that's that's pretty
that's a lot of there's consensus about
these problems whether you have the
decent rise you will have the market
failures in the central well you'll have
the governmental failures and in both of
these well you have lack of information
which is creating a lot of these
problems so that we are solving with the
with the big data we get the artificial
intelligence so we can map these
preferences map the alternatives and
just put them together and here we go
and we all have better decisions except
that there is some conference so the
first one to the to the left is Google
Trent it's artificial intelligence
competing with privacy who's interested
in in most and on the other side is just
one of these many studies and Trust in
Indiana trying to ask people about their
trust in institutions in academia in
researchers in global companies in
government's one of the challenges is
that the logic the global companies and
the government which are usually those
that would set up a system like this is
not the most trusted institutions so you
might actually need to maybe rebuild or
build trust and and that the argument
would be that that really requires some
strong commitments and if you and that's
what cryptography comes in if you commit
to a cryptographic protocol let's say we
are arguing for the no single point of
trust that's really a strong commitment
and use that TG to rebuild a trust so
that's I think that's is where
cryptography has a super important
in fixing maybe some of the most basic
problems in just in both societies maybe
at the moment at least an increasing
problem so back to the to the
infrastructure with the three components
the the information that is publicly
available the smart contracts run
computation and these information and
the privacy measures you can actually
implement these mechanisms that makes it
met provide incentives for people to to
make better decision you can combine
this with the with when you have all of
this and data analytics and these
mechanisms and you can make these better
decisions in a combination of this of
these two technologies blockchain and CK
computation so maybe two words about the
the type of of market mechanisms or
solution that you would typically look
at so you would either consider some non
collaborative solution over your
competing about the winning and option
competing in a negotiation there's a
number of very of different non
cooperative games but there's also a
huge class of cooperative games which is
maybe the class that could gain the most
from an from a infrastructure like this
and it's actually also in most cases
where you can get the most values out of
a collaboration by finding the the
coalition finding the right person and
make them collaborate there's a number
of example of this farmers have done
this for for many years I think I come
from a country where this was like
hundred and fifty years ago this is
probably the basic of the
the wealth generation that some small
pool farmers went together and bought
the equipment to process the in the milk
and the meat and then they actually
managed to create a lot of wealth this
way that could have gone wrong in many
different ways so he needed to
concentrate all the wealth and if they
had if they have had corrupt managers
there was running away with the money
then that would not have happened so
that way you could do with a with an
infrastructure like this you could make
sure that you find the coalition in a
privacy-preserving way and then
implement the cost-sharing scheme or the
revenue sharing schemes that one example
so it doesn't have to be small players
this is another example of the largest
shipping companies that are too small
for certain jobs so they could they do
what is called tanker pools they they
they pool the different ships that they
have for certain jobs and run a
cooperative basically as a cost sharing
and revenue sharing scheme taxi drivers
and that example and then you you moving
towards the watson non cooperative
solutions energy system you need to make
sure that make more room for renewable
energy you need to combine a lot of
resources that's also requires a lot of
information a lot of price selling
supply chain clearly bidding auctions
some of the to negotiations mergers and
acquisitions so this is some of the
example of of classes of problems that
could be solved by an infrastructure
like this so we but we have soaked back
with some of the basic chances that we
and those of you have been trying to
solve this most likely I would imagine
has faced that you need to find those
that is running these notes and if you
have a situation like the one with data
broker you might have
some natural opponents like the data
requested the data providers you can run
you can set up the system to run and
never have to party problems you might
have other situations where that is not
possible so for the most of these cases
you will have a generic you schedule
where you will have a lot of players in
the beginning a lot of information then
you'll find some matches and then you
see the execute the the decisions so in
the in the first step you might need to
delegate the trust to do some more
generic type of notes that could be
ready to run these computation whenever
needed so who should those notes be and
that's you should go in and find some of
the trustworthy institutions in the
society and clearly there are some like
like some industries are more trusted
than others so you could try to organize
these entities and make them basically
allow them to profit on selling trusts
in in a system like this you could also
go to to public institution maybe that's
the least and if you look at the
government this is the United States but
I think in this picture is pretty much
the same in many other countries it's
but there are other studies that is
actually showing that there's a lot of
trust in some of the institutions this
is comparing the police whether you
trust the police whether we trust other
people say so there is a lot of trust
out there so you could organize and you
if you have this sort of distributed
cryptography this is actually a - - to
create these social institutions great
put these trusted institutions persons
into networks and create even more trust
and use that to realize some of these
prospects in a data-driven economy
and I think that was actually my
conclusion so the conclusion is that
okay this is this has been used I mean
there's an increasing opportunity to use
MPC to solve a number of problems and we
would like you that there's a nice
complementary in matched between the the
blockchain and the and the the MPC
technology and that's what we're trying
to neutralize so exciting prospect that
we could actually realize this data
German economy and you know
privacy-preserving
manner so this is not really new hal
varian at 1995 he he wrote in in one of
his papers who should be these
institutions that is safeguarding these
these data that we had just talked about
in realizing the such a data turning
economy I think that was that was it
thank you
we have time for questions hi my
question is why blockchain and wouldn't
something like a trillion personality
solve the same trust issues without all
the hype
hey let's go sneak predict my question
was why blockchain and wouldn't
something like a trillion personality
solve the same trust issues without all
the hype around the term blockchain yeah
blockchain is is one solution so what
we're trying to do is to utilize some of
the things we think works well with with
Brockton's we and combine that with what
we think works well with with MPC we
don't want to just go in and maybe just
take the first random notes in a public
blockchain and have them running and an
MPC so it's it's a different setting
that we are focusing on yeah but I think
that would be that would require a lot
more information about this what we have
building and we would like to sort of
poke through on that a little more okay
thank you hi you're claiming that you
use the blockchain to perform in PC I'm
curious having worked on blockchain
technolon to kind of ensure the correct
computation here because it doesn't
necessarily add any transparency unless
you use what certain techniques Oh what
techniques are you using to accomplish
that transparency in comparison to like
a cloud or just another trusted
companies network that has physical
security and stuff like that yeah so so
that's what we what we would like to
present
later stage for day you're presenting
you later yes sir so that's what we are
grading we're creating this
infrastructure now so I've just sort of
laying out the this new project in in
some weak terms do you have a proof of
concept up at all or yeah so we have the
first proof of concept of the basic
network so this is what we create so the
two applications that I've talked about
the tailor-made solution for the
blockchain and MPC that's one way of
working with this several entities who's
actually running a business using this
technology then we say okay that looks
that looks great we want to actually
make it easier for others to do the same
and and we have some some learned
lessons from from this combination and
that's what we're using to create this
infrastructure that mixes that combined
rock chain and MPC and the the more
details about this first of all that's
why I'm giving the talk I will not be
able to reveal anything Susannah mr. so
you'll you'll and we will need some more
time to get the the basics in place but
we do have actually a first
implementation and you yes cool thank
you thank you again and have a good
build we can reconvene at 2:00 p.m.