but not the first talk of the second
session and it's going to be the hill we
must dial so over to you guys thanks
great
good morning everybody
thanks so much for coming here and the
telev is a hill we must die on
cryptographers and Congress who are we
I'm Gabe Kaptchuk I'm a fourth-year PhD
student at Johns Hopkins and I'm
co-advised by avi Rubin and Matt green
and and I am an American which is
important for the context of this talk
and I'm Shannon Connie I'm a fifth year
PhD student at Panik also in
cryptography advised by Nadia Henninger
and Jonathan Smith and I am actually
Australian which is interesting for
today's talk and we work together in
Senator Ron Wyden s personal office in
Washington DC he's a US federal senator
he's a Democrat and from Oregon neither
of us had prior political experience or
really much policy experience before
going into our summer experience but
both of us come from research groups
that do have interests in policy even
while they're actually dedicated to the
technical work rather than to the policy
side so before we get into the meat of
the talk itself I wanted to make sure
that we kind of set some parameters in
terms of what this talk will be and what
it will not be first of all this talk is
going to be very different than the ones
in the preceding group you're not going
to see any key exchange diagrams here
this is not going to be a advertisement
for a particular set of political views
we did both work in a democratic office
but we're going to try and make this
sort of broad enough that everybody can
take away the best way to advocate for
the cryptographic community no matter
what your personal beliefs are this is
not going to be a talk about the merits
and evils of exceptional access
mechanisms I know we could all talk
about that all day but we really want to
keep this sort of away from the
hot-button issues and talk about the
best way to sort of approach the process
of interacting with government similarly
this is not going to be a u.s. civics
lecture so don't worry you don't get to
take a nap wait yet
we want to make sure that everybody in
the room is able to take something away
and bring it back to their home country
even if it's not the United States
obviously the context that we worked in
is very us centric and so we're gonna be
using that for a lot of examples but the
takeaways themselves are sort of broader
than that and can be applied to
virtually any country and lastly this
talk is not a view into what's secretly
happening in the Senate we can't tell
you all the things that we did which is
a fun thing to say but we are going to
be able to sort of give you the flavor
of the things that we worked on and give
you an insight into how things work
within the federal government
this talk is finally two perspectives on
what we learned from our summer on
Capitol Hill so what motivated our
desire to go into policy and what should
what is one of the things that maybe
should motivate you so we have this nice
full quote from Philip Roth away's paper
on the moral nature of cryptographic
work and he's essentially saying that
cryptic cryptography and power are
inextricably intertwined cryptography is
an inherently political tool and thus it
should be relevant a relevant
consideration for all of us to think
about the implications of what our work
produces in a broader policy and
political context so why work in policy
otherwise so governments struggle with
complex systems I'm sure many of you saw
the Facebook hearings and our elected
officials in the US were manifestly
unable to grapple with some of the
complex issues that are now forefront in
the minds of many individuals both in
America and around the world governments
also set trends so not just in America
but governments set standards that are
often adopted by industry and so the
ramifications are broader than just laws
and regulations that may be set that
impacts our technical lives as well as
our everyday lives and also the loudest
voices that control a lot of policy
debates today aren't technical devices
and in the case of cryptography there
are very few voices from our community
that make themselves heard when it comes
to discussions in Capitol Hill outside
of the one or two hot-button issues that
everyone is used to talking
and finally working in policy gives you
a chance to really magnify the impact of
your technical work so while our
research papers are broadly disseminated
within the community and shape industry
working in policy gives us a chance to
magnify our impact through advising
lawmakers and policy setters on
different ways that research advances
can shape their understandings and
present both costs and opportunities to
the broader community so a little taste
of us civics for those of you who aren't
familiar so that we can help give you
some perspective on what we were doing
so the United States government is
broadly divided up into three different
branches enumerated in the Constitution
and the kind of core concept here is the
idea of checks and balances each of
these branches is going to have powers
that impact the others and work together
to provide a way of making sure that
there's no overreach in terms of powers
so two of the branches that we'll start
with the judicial branch which
interprets the laws and applies laws to
cases and the executive branch which
actually execute the laws so this would
be things like all your government
agencies the IRS customs and border
control NIST is part of the executive
branch which some of you may be familiar
with and we would love to give you a
live demo of calling up the executive
branch and and showing how to work in
policy but unfortunately they don't seem
to be in the office at the moment so
maybe we'll give a pass on that one and
the third branch which is the one where
we worked is the legislative branch so
the legislative branch is most commonly
known for making and writing laws and
passing them many US schoolchildren are
familiar with this little cartoon bill
which passes through the legislative
process ins made laws as made into a law
by Congress however the other really
important function of the legislative
branch that many people often overlook
is the oversight function so Congress is
tasked with overseeing the other two
branches and has various powers that
enable this oversight function such as
the ability to requisition documents and
issue subpoenas and hold public hearings
in order to perform investigative and
oversight functions that ensure the
other two branches are doing what they
say they are doing
and finally we worked in a Senate office
a personal office of a senator so this
is the senator chooses which staff
members he's going to hire he or she and
these are each of these staffers are
divided up into issue areas the
particular staffers that control a
policy area are known as legislative
aides and we work to underneath one of
those the staff will identify problems
and issues and suggest to the senator
what stances he or she should take and
they derive their the set of issues they
identify issues often through the media
through consultation with experts that
they happen to know with lobbyists who
come in advocating for particular
positions and constituent concerns that
are forwarded to the office so going
into the summer both of us wanted to
have some goals set for ourselves and I
think we've sort of laid out a short
list of goals that we had that sort of
contextualized some of the lessons we
were able to learn as we left our summer
experience so first of all what are the
ground rules for doing work in
government as both PhD students were
very familiar with sort of the academic
ground rules tried to evaluate the value
of a citation for instance is something
that we can kind of get on board with
but try to understand how you push
issues around how do you talk to people
and really what are the rules in which
people are able to do work in the
legislative branch was something we both
want to come away with secondly can two
people make a substantive impact at all
so we were two people working at the
Fellow level sort of you know unpaid
people and and we wanted to gauge how
much actual impact we could have both in
our community but also sort of in the
general legislative process very key
takeaway is was there any overlap
between academically interesting
problems and policy interesting
and I think this is often times where we
see a breakdown where members of our
community are not super willing to jump
into the political sphere because they
don't necessarily see the same issues as
interesting right and so trying to find
an overlap there so we can really sink
our teeth into the issues that the
political arena is interested in and
finally how can we best represent our
community right what steps can we take
in terms of teaching each other and
learning on our own such that we can
best represent the cryptographic
community when it comes to a political
stage so what did we actually do well
this is what our parents thought we did
they thought we kind of just walked
around the hill and took nice pictures
and got to see all kinds of famous
people walking around unfortunately
there was work to be done so we had to
do more than just that um what did our
managers actually think we do well as I
said before we can't tell you all the
secret things but this is kind of coming
into overlapping interests right other
interests that are similar between our
work and and what the alleged branch
actually cares about so we came in kind
of caring about the things that I think
many people would care about widespread
crypto protocol deployment right stuff
like the Phipps standards stuff like
government CAS and TLS right and all of
us have probably experienced clicking on
a DoD website Department of Defense
website and getting a big warning that
says you cannot go here I mean trying to
figure out why this is old and outdated
VPN protocols I'm sort of making sure
that everybody and the government is
using stuff that's you know genuinely
and and powerfully secure we also cared
a lot about government transparency
which I believe lot of people in this
room care about we're not going to talk
about that because I said the beginning
we're not going to talk too much about
some of the hot button issues um what
did our senator and and their staff care
about they carried a ton about HTTPS and
to say disablement and this
configuration on agency websites and
notice that this is a widespread crypto
protocol right so there is some overlap
here those sort of the details of what
they cared about are somewhat different
um lack of start TLS for optimistic
email encryption cared a lot about FBI
misrepresenting decryption details
around phones and mobile devices they
cared a lot about voting which we're
gonna hear a lot more about in just a
moment um notice that there's a lot of
overlap between these two groups but
it's not exactly the same right so there
still are interesting issues that we can
work together with so what is the actual
data
they look like well we wrote lots and
lots of letters letters are not
necessarily the thing that you think of
immediately when you think of the
legislative branch we oftentimes think
about a legislation but the way that
most Congress persons get their message
out is by writing these letters some of
them are very pleasant letters you may
have noticed that out of the Wyden
office over the course of summer there
is a nice little letter encouraging the
use of wire guard and maybe looking at
new VPN protocols I'm not going to say
that we were involved in that but you
know you can make your own conclusions
there was also some angry letters that
went out right there was a letter that
went out from the Wyden office as well
when domain fronting the the domain
fronting policies were changed at Google
and Amazon that was not the most
pleasant letter to read right so both
this were kind of pushing people in
industry to take a hard look at what
they're doing but also I'm encouraging
people within the government to make
good choices we also the opportunity to
draft some legislation there was a bill
introduced by the Wyden office just
after the summer which had to do with
data privacy and changing the way that
we think about data privacy in this
country we also conducted cryptographic
investigations and which kind of means
we just looked around to see where
things were broken in the government
which is surprisingly a lot of places
and we got to advise senior staff
whenever an issue came into the office
that was sort of relevant to data
privacy or crypt or something like that
another really important power was
actually getting to meet with people
from industry and different government
agencies and I'll talk a little bit more
about that in a second and we're really
the biggest thing that we did was we
argued we argued a lot and was kind of
nice as being an environment where the
two of us had similar views on many
things but very different views on other
things and we got to kind of yell at
each other and work through these issues
in a space where we were encouraged to
kind of grapple with the political
ramifications of what we were doing one
thing that was really nice is this
arguing actually in my opinion was
really productive
we actually got things done in kind of
clarified our issues which was really
relieving every once in a while in our
field topics tend to get a little bit
heated and we don't necessarily always
get to the bottom of things um Matt
green is my adviser I cleared this joke
don't worry at all good a highlight for
me and for both of us was actually got
to sit down with a bunch of high-level
people from the NSA one thing that the
that they were
able to say is that the officials at sat
down across from us that thought it was
really refreshing to have the
opportunity to have a direct
conversation with members of the
academic crypto cryptographic community
which was a really refreshing thing to
hear and I thought it was actually a
really productive meeting I will say
that and you know it's a little bit
unnerving that we were the two faces
that they saw as representatives of the
academic cryptographic community and so
maybe that reflects some of the work we
have to do as a community beyond that
unfortunately I'm not able to disclose
any of the details of this meeting but
feel free to buy us drinks later we
still won't disclose any of the details
so a couple of takeaways which we want
to give to you from our time there so
number one is crypto is everywhere this
isn't just in crypto standards like hips
or in places where it's most obvious a
nice example is the Census departments
use of differential privacy for the 2020
census a really interesting use of
cryptography and related techniques
cryptography also extends to use of a
large number of government services as
things are increasingly digitized things
like visa lotteries are controlled by
random number generators which leads to
a whole lot of interesting problems in
the cryptography space that overlap with
government which we don't always
consider lesson number two is that talk
is really cheap but ultimately is very
powerful and a lot of politics
particularly in the United States is
kind of performance-based right and the
things that we see our politicians do
are very much intended to be steamed by
the public right a good example of this
is hearings right when you hold a
hearing it's not actually so much for
the Senators to learn new information
from the people who understand it's for
the rest of us to hear the questions and
the answers and kind of engage in the
political process right and so this
makes the speech itself really the
biggest currency on Capitol Hill I think
there's kind of a big trophy at money is
the most powerful thing and after a
summer there that that really wasn't
true it was all about your ability to
convey an important message and have a
conversation importantly politicians
actually really do
and they have the opportunity sorry let
us say when they have the opportunity to
sit down with a constituent with an
expert they actually do kind of glean
information and it shapes the way that
they see issues oftentimes they don't
have the time to sit down with every
single person who comes in so their
staff has the opportunity to sit down
and staff are generally a little bit
more informed in whatever your issue
areas so for us sitting down with
somebody who's at least familiar with
the issues in the encryption or in the
crypto space is a much more helpful
conversation to have anyway it's not
particularly hard to actually get a
meeting you can kind of call or send a
note and channel talk a little bit more
about that in a moment and importantly
the conversations that you have with
representatives or with their staff can
just be seen as ideas right they don't
immediately need to lead to action and
they can sort of slowly bubble and
eventually come up into a law further
down the road there's some sort of
guidelines to take away when it comes to
the media right you remember the the
representative is not going to read your
paper and they likely won't read your
Twitter or whatever your way of
spreading your message out into the
world is but their legislative aide
actually is very likely to see your work
if you're doing a good job sort of
publicizing it and making it known I
mean that's a good way to sort of
influence a conversation in the office
some priorities that we that we have and
thinking about the way that speech is
regulated and number one don't make the
member look bad number two make the
number look good number three really
don't make the member look bad this was
given to us on our first day on the job
by the legislative aide we're working
with we kind of like to just extrapolate
this a little bit and say you know don't
do bad do good and and don't do that so
lesson number three you learn to talk
like the other kind of nerd the other
kind of wonk so they're on really
cryptographers wandering the halls of
Congress no one's gonna listen to you on
us idh key exchange proposal but you
there's still a way to communicate the
value and importance of ideas one way to
do this is to think about the mindset
through which politicians operate
because their constituents often don't
think in terms of deep subtleties you've
got to think about the way to portray
something either as good and contrast
that with something that might be bad so
for example TLS 1.3
good SSL v2 bad and so when you are
presenting issues to the Congress person
try and present it in a way that they
will then be able to absorb it and be be
able to communicate to their
constituents master the art of the
concrete ask is so telling the member
that hey you know you should really
improve your crypto protocol because
forward secrecy is really important
probably isn't going to get them going
but saying you know government agency X
isn't implementing forward secrecy
properly can you please get them to
enable can please get them to change
their configuration in this way to do it
that is something that's much more
likely to get done so here are some
examples of easier things to get your
member to do and some harder things I'm
not gonna go into great detail but come
up and talk to us after about that so
communicating with a member there are
three primary channels through which you
can do this number one is call and if
you call and just give an opinion you're
actually gonna be put forward in the
u.s. to an LC that's someone who just
communicates with constituents however
you should know that you can ask for the
staffer that handles your particular
issue area and this is really the
valuable thing because that's when you
can get connected to someone who's going
to approach the issue more directly
rather than just taking your one line
good or bad kind of feedback you can
then also ask for a meeting with the
staffer who oversees a particular issue
and this is a great chance to get your
point across and then one of the bigger
currencies in Congress is the
Congressional letter so knowing how to
format and write your letters in order
to communicate is really powerful one
thing one kind of Boogie word in our
community that we try to avoid is this
word incremental you don't ever want to
do incremental work right um but
unfortunately that's not Linda bleah the
best way to approach issues when coming
to the legislative branch big-ticket
issues the sexy issues oftentimes have a
lot of enemies right and so when you
asked representative hey can you take
action on issue X it's unlikely that
they'll may get much headway done if
it's an issue where there's a lot of
vested stakeholders right and and sort
of building compromise on these lo
issues is what's gonna get you progress
I'm so some good examples of problems is
hey we should be using MPC for social
good and that's kind of specific we're
gonna be hearing
about that later why does the government
misconfigure TLS in the certain place
right and the industry standards for
some particular phone protocol whatever
it is is broken and it's affecting a
population right so there's a real
impact and a very narrow scope it's much
harder to go you know don't back to our
crypto there's a lot of stakeholders
there and people are gonna get angry I'm
not gonna talk about more about that so
finally what can you do so if you're an
academic as many people here are embrace
the political and moral nature of your
work find a way to tell the stories
about how your work is going to impact
other people and use that to shape the
policy narrative consider doing some
work for your legislative branch that
might be helping out on a letter or it
might be helping out with some
legislation or even sending two of your
students to work on the hill for a
summer and be active in learning how to
talk about you're working on technically
if you're an industry again many of
these same skills are applicable reach
beyond perhaps your particular narrow
field and bring in a broader consensus
that you can then present to a
legislative body to present really good
ideas on how government can help improve
the state of cryptography and again tell
the same stories about how what you're
doing can improve privacy and security
for a members constituents and finally
if you are a concerned human please like
everyone else has always been telling
you take part in your political process
and be active reach out to either of us
if you have any more questions or
thoughts thank you to our sponsors for
the summer and thank you to Senator
Wyden and his staff and our and the
other fellows for facilitating our
summer thank you thank you
[Applause]
yes we have we have time for one quick
one or two quick questions I've got a
question
so these NSA people they'd never talk to
an academic before haven't they heard of
a telephone I actually can't tell you
what was said in the meeting we might
have asked about telephones but I can't
tell you okay any other questions
okay let's thank speaks again and let's
move on thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
hope it works trailer I'll signal when
it's like a few minutes okay good we're
almost there
so apparently crypto means cryptography
so I hand over to Matt okay so thanks so
that last talk I saw some news but that
less talk was so persuasive I've decided
to quit my job as an engineering
professor and joined the faculty at the
Georgetown Law School and focus on
technology and policy so thanks I've had
a huge change in my life but it's you
know you guys that was a great talk so
I'm glad I got in ahead of the game on
on on running to do policy work at least
part of the time so this talk is gonna
be about the role of cryptography and
elections and voting and it's very short
there really isn't so thank you very
much
and I'm going to talk a little bit about
why so this is basically to convince you
that elections are a really important
problem for us to be working on but
maybe not in some of the ways that we've
traditionally been working on them as a
as a community so the role of Technology
in elections has a very long history and
I'm going to apologize that this is
going to be a very us centric talk but a
lot of the things are applicable in
other parts of the world as well and
some of the problems are really
fundamental to democratic elections in
the democratic process so in fact early
elections in the United States were
pretty informal in the way they were
conducted they consisted of little more
than getting people together in the Town
Hall and having them raise their hands
about who their candidates were the
problem with that the reason we don't
really do that today for big public
civil elections is that it doesn't scale
well
and so technological mechanisms have
increasingly been used
and these technological mechanisms
quietly have properties some of them
security properties that some of them
good some of them bad that we've kind of
taken to become requirements and one of
the examples of that is the secrecy you
can't find out how someone else voted
and in fact you can't even prove that
you voted in a particular way and that's
regarded as a really important
requirement and we've evolved the
technology that we use in elections
earliest in the United States with
probably the use of paper ballots fill
out your ballot form put it into a box
and at the end of the day we've watched
the Box carefully and then we watch
everybody take the ballots out and count
them and that gives us confidence that
every vote that was put in the box
ultimately gets counted but we don't
actually tie who voted to a particular
ballot once it's come out of the box and
so that has some very interesting
security and privacy properties that
have really become fundamental to how we
think about requirements for a
democratic election we've moved on to
machine counted ballots of various kinds
partly because we want results quickly
and accurately and sometimes we achieve
that and sometimes we don't we've moved
on to machine cast ballots of lever
voting machines that were used in some
places or in punch card ballot machines
and I'll talk about those in a little
bit electromechanical voting mechanisms
and then finally and this is really a
21st century or largely a 21st century
phenomenon voting computers using
computers to actually cast your ballot
and ultimately public confidence in the
integrity of our elections and in in who
our elected officials are are our belief
in the outcome of elections is something
we rely on
has is now traceable in an increasingly
strong way to our confidence in the
underlying technology of the election
itself and so the technology issues have
become really important as a building
block of our democracy so we should
think a lot about what the requirements
are and whether our systems achieve
those requirements so I'm gonna talk a
little bit about these requirements I
will say I've been working in computers
across computer security and
cryptography and that kind of stuff for
25-30 years now and I have yet to
encounter a problem nearly as difficult
as voting in civil elections it's it's
the hardest practical real-world problem
I've ever seen and and I think there are
fundamental reasons for this I'm gonna
focus on two of them one is that some of
the requirements are in conflict with
each other and a big one is the secrecy
requirement I can't find out how anyone
else voted and in fact I can't even
prove that I voted a particular way and
that protects me against being coerced
to vote in a particular way because I
just have no way of showing that I voted
one way or another and but I also want
confidence that my vote actually was
counted at the end of the day so we have
this strong requirement for audit
ability and a strong requirement for
kind of a lack of audible audit ability
at the same time and this is we care
about both of these things very much but
you know ultimately when you make that a
technical requirement if it seems like
it's really hard to achieve both of
these things and the second problem
which is even harder than the
contradictory requirements is that
ultimately particularly in the United
States it's insufficient to merely
detect that there was an election
irregularity it's almost impossible to
have a do-over election if you discover
that the integrity of the election has
been compromised
then what do you hold a do-over election
well there may not be legal mechanisms
to do that it's extraordinarily
difficult in in the United States to do
that and it
unclear that it would even be fair to do
that under most circumstances because
how do you make sure that everybody who
took the time to vote the first time is
able to vote the second time and and so
on and so you know mechanisms that
merely say aha
well this cryptographic hash will be
different from the ultimate outcome and
that shows that there was some tampering
are incredibly unsatisfying in the
context of actual real world elections
we want recovery and and find out what
the true outcome was at the same time we
have incredibly high stakes for
elections in the United States we spend
much more money on political campaigns
trying to influence who votes to
convince people to vote one way or
another then we actually spend
conducting the election mechanics itself
and there is a long history of mischief
almost always at the local level
elections for mayor or dogcatcher or
City Council are actually historically
much more prone to somebody trying to
sell the the office than large national
offices and you know Trigg the
traditional threat model has been to
prevent a corrupt candidate or a corrupt
candidates supporters from being able to
influence the election in 2016 we had
put into focus very clearly that that's
not the entire threat model that the
threat model is larger than that and
includes very definite eight actors that
may want to in either influence the
election or do something that may
actually be easier than influencing the
election which is merely disrupting an
election or reducing our confidence in
the outcome and so state actors have the
two inherent advantages here first they
have resources that are likely to be
greater than any candidate and greater
than any election local election board
is going to have and
also have an easier task they don't
necessarily need to pick the winner all
they need to do is reduce our confidence
in who the winner is
and that is you know really a great
advantage to the adversary and a real
difficult problem for the defender so
let's look at the question of whether
new voting technology is going to enable
some of this kinds of mischief or
prevent some of this kind of mischief
and the answer is yes it does
so elections in the United States first
of all we have a very highly distributed
hierarchy of how elections are conducted
the federal government really sets very
broad standards there are four things
like well you know people are allowed to
vote and you know here's the age for
voting and you know you get to vote in
your state and so on but all of the
details are left to the states in
practice and part of the reason for that
is the constitutional principle called
federalism and there are also practical
reasons that that's simply where the
mechanisms are each state has its own
set of laws and rules and practices for
the specifics of this administered in
almost every case by an official usually
called the Secretary of State of the
state elections though are in almost all
of these states run by the individual
counties that's the most typical
granularity for who is actually going to
buy the voting machines and count the
ballots and get the voters to to
actually vote in most states that's
that's going to be your local County
that does that there are 3,000 counties
in the United States roughly so that
means really we have 3,000 or so
election administrators by that count in
fact the number is more because in some
places that are not counties and some
places are subdivided under the counties
so the number is really closer to about
5,000 different political entities that
control elections in the country and
they have different capabilities some of
them are you know have a single IT
administrator for the entire county
who's worried about things like you know
property tax assessments as well as you
know maintaining the voter registration
lists in that County and protecting
those those information systems others
are going to be more sophisticated than
that so it's very highly variable fifty
different sets of rules for the
different states plus territories and
the District of Columbia and then you
have these all these individual offices
who are administering it on top of that
elections in the United States are the
most complex of any democracy on earth
we've that is to say we vote for more
things than on a particular ballot on
Election Day than just about anyone else
so our ballots tend to be longer here
we're in California you're but you know
you you know you notice that not only do
you vote for particular offices and
there are going to be a lot of those in
any elections but you also valid
initiatives and and bond issues and so
on so we may be you know asked to make
you know twenty or thirty decisions on a
ballot in the United States not merely
you know check off the box for who you
want to be your representatives and you
know in fact there may be different
ballots even within a polling place
depending on where someone lives things
like school board elections and so on
may have multiple different ballots
depending on the precise residence of
the particular voter so it's very very
logistical II complicated which is to
say that the answer we'll just don't use
computers at all is likely not to be a
practical solution computers have a role
to play here and the question is how do
we get the benefits of computing without
the risks of inheriting computing
here's a picture that the older members
of the audience may recognize does
anybody remember this
it was a while ago this is a picture of
the Florida recount in the 2000 election
and this is a one of the recount
officials examining a paper ballot and
us the source of our a lot of our
troubles can be traced to this
particular picture and it's interesting
because I think the picture this picture
has changed in meaning over the 18 years
since it was since it was taken almost
19 years now this picture originally
could be you know a captions look at
those idiots in Florida and their
primitive election technology we've
really gotta fix this and now I think
the caption that I would put on this
picture is look at the strength of this
voting system where a human being can
examine a ballot and learn more about
what the voters intent was isn't that an
amazing property of the system that we
have this human readable human recount
Abal thing and I think that lesson is
one that we really need to take away
from this so I'm gonna talk briefly
about the 2000 presidential election
this was a voting machine used in
Florida and other states this particular
one was from Wisconsin but this is the
same model machine that was used in
Florida in the 2000 election and it's
called a punch card voting machine and
the interesting thing about this machine
is that it does not have any electricity
involved except for the light in the
voting booth
but it has a memory leak in it and that
memory leak had a really interesting
property that it only appeared on very
popular elections so in particular the
way this machine works and I have one of
them right here so this is a stolen from
Wisconsin the what the voter does is
puts in a paper ballot and then takes
this little stylus and punches a hole
through where the position on the card
associated with there can
is takes the card out and puts the card
in the ultimate ballot box the problem
with that is the little pieces of
cardboard from the ballot these are
these are ballots that end up having to
go somewhere it punches a hole through
the ballot and because of conservation
of matter that cardboard ends up going
somewhere and where it goes is right
behind the position in the little
machine where the candidate was now for
most elections that doesn't really
matter but if four times as many people
show up as the machine is designed to be
able to handle what happens is that you
have a buildup of these pieces of
cardboard behind the positions
associated with the most popular
candidates so by the end of the day
candidates become harder to vote for
physically because it's harder to get
the little stylists through the ballot
and what happens is that instead of a
nice hole as we see in the upper right
what you might end up with is just
dimple in the piece of cardboard where
that candidate is associated or you
might create a little slap where the
candidates position is the problem is
the way these ballots are read is
they're taken and put through an optical
reader that tests light through the
ballot and if that piece of cardboard
isn't is isn't is still obstructing the
position it won't register as a vote but
a human being can look at it and say oh
well they eyed too clearly in this
particular place but they only dimpled
it and a person can figure that out the
consequence was we didn't know for a
while who won the 2000 election it was a
big mess and it but it led to a piece of
remarkable bipartisanship in Congress
called the help America Vote Act and
that was hurriedly passed and it
basically mandated that we get rid of
this old embarrassing technology that
didn't involve computers and replace it
with accessible voting technology and
basically the effect was it created a
huge pile
money for the states to buy new voting
machines but those voting machines
mostly didn't exist at the time the
money for them was allocated and so the
market rose to the occasion and very
hurriedly produced computerized voting
terminals for the states to buy to
replace all of this old equipment and
the most prominent of the hava compliant
voting machines is called ad re machine
not to be confused with the doctor of
the same name but the but a direct
recording electronic machine in other
words a computer terminal that records
your vote in its memory rather than on
paper and this is an example of a D re
voting machine this is made by a company
called es ns it's called an aye vote
Roenick lowercase I capital V it's not
actually made by Apple in spite of that
but it's basically a touchscreen
computer that has an internal memory
that stores the ballot and this is a
typical example of such a machine it's
one that we looked at in my lab at Penn
on behalf of the state of Ohio in 2007
the observation here is this is not a
voting machine it's a computer that's
running voting applications it's a
specialized computer running software
I'm just going to say one thing about
software software is bad we don't really
know how to write software but the
correctness of software in this
application is critically important why
because it's recording the voters choice
in memory controlled by the software
that the voter is voting on so if that
software has a flaw in it that causes
the machine to miss record the vote
there is no way to recover from that we
don't have any way other than what the
Machine is telling us to find out how
somebody voted in that design software
as many of us have discovered we don't
have general techniques for determining
whether general software is correct
in fact we can kind of prove that we
never will for general software we can't
really test software under all
circumstances and complexity is the
enemy of correctness as we've discovered
software and election systems is used
all over the place it is before the
election to define ballots it's used for
provision voting machines it's used to
register voters it's used on Election
Day in voting machines and also in
devices that may maintain the role of
voters and it's used post election for
tallying and result reporting and for
auditing as well as for recounts now
there are potential vulnerabilities
across all sorts of places one yeah
there's the possibility of tampering
with results that are recorded in
machines tampering with results that are
reported to the County headquarters
tampering with the software that
actually records the VOSA votes in the
first place tampering with the software
that is counting the ballots and
reporting out the final tallies and so
on and then we've got the question of
how do we audit the software to ensure
that the software that we think is
running is the actual software that's
running let alone the question of
whether that software is correct so I'm
gonna make a humble observation which is
that cryptography doesn't help with most
of these problems in particular it
doesn't help with solving these problems
in ways that allow us to recover from
errors in good ways
so there are some safeguards and to make
sure that these machines are in fact
working well the most important is
called government certification of the
vendors and of the equipment the
machines need to be certified as being
correct anyone who knows how to certify
software as being correct is welcome to
step up and do that I don't know how to
do that but these machines do have to be
certified to
to do this and there are some other
mechanisms that I won't talk about in
great detail except to say that there
are really four major vendors in the
United States of voting equipment and
all of them have had serious questions
raised about the security and integrity
of the systems that they actually
produce so how secure is computerized
voting well as a Yogi Berra and later
John von Neumann are reputed to have
said in theory theory and practice are
the same in practice they're different
so Evo ting in theory should be a matter
of basically there should be a line in
the software somewhere when you cast a
vote for a candidate that says you know
votes or this candidate equals votes for
this candidate plus one and if that line
is there then the system is correct and
if it's not then it's not correct and
theoretically it should be just a
question of grep you know for that line
in practice there's a lot there a lot of
moving parts here county election
management software voting machine
software and firmware the communications
in the system and so on and there and
the huge temporary workforce of people
who have access to this the logistics of
a lot of elections are are amazing
there's some potential attacks and the
first one I'm going to list is the one
that the state actor might be interested
in which is denial of service and you
know how do you prevent the vote from
actually taking place well we kind of
don't know how to do that I'll give you
an example of the system a system we
were given access to at Penn in 2007 the
group that I led was a system made by es
& s it's the largest vendor it had
penetration in 43 states it had never
been actually independently looked at
outside of the certification process
before a quick summary of what we found
was that we could compromise every
component of the ESS system a in every
at every stage of the election process
and we could do this in ways with no
more access than a voter in some cases
voting or a precinct poll worker Oh
basically if you can touch it or get
near it you can compromise it and this
is a typical outcome when independent
people are able to look at these systems
you know the various independent reviews
that have taken place of these systems
have found just a crisis of practical
security vulnerabilities pretty much
every e-voting system that has reached
the market has had serious
vulnerabilities found in it and they're
all below the standards that we would
normally associate with high quality
critical systems so it's tempting to
look at that and say well let's just
find ways to build better software but
in fact the ultimate problems are
architectural so what should we do well
in the short term the first thing is you
can't just say well let's not hold
elections until we fix this and you know
as engineers we might say we're not
ready to ship but you know that we don't
have a choice there are constitutional
reasons that we have elections on
particular days and while we still have
a constitution let's enjoy it
so in the shorter term you know we kind
of need better audits more procedural
controls be aware of what the
vulnerabilities are in the longer term
we need better architectural models that
don't make us as dependent on
fundamentally insecure things and the
two components of this that have emerged
as the state of the art our first
concept first introduced by Ron Rivest
called software independence and
software independence is the property
that says the outcome of the election
should not be dependent on software
itself that is if there's a flaw in the
software you can still find out who won
the election I'm paraphrasing something
so build systems that don't have
software as a critical component that's
a pretty bold requirement but in fact
it's achievable in with technology that
actually exists today off-the-shelf and
the second is a concept called risk
limiting audits which is a way of
sampling statistically sampling voting
machines by doing a manual recount of
their results and comparing it with the
reported results in a significant
statistically significant way that will
give you confidence that if the software
worked on your randomly selected sample
after the election that it hadn't that
it was working well in the other places
and you can achieve a very high level of
confidence and this can help you achieve
the software independence property and
practice with things like optical scan
paper ballots which exists today and
they can be bought and in fact many
states are switching over and using them
so let me just get to the thing
everybody's going to say which is but
what about the blockchain and the
blockchain sounds perfect all right it's
a decentralized and mutable ledger bla
bla bla and isn't that what elections
are and we want to get consensus
mechanisms and so on but first of all
it's worth noting that even though
elections are about finding out what the
consensus is the components of an actual
conduct of an election legally are
hierarchical right so we have a
designated set of election officials who
certify the results we don't just all
kind of get together and say well we
kind of agree on who won the election
we're really trusting mechanisms and
officials to conduct elections and
report the outcomes in ways that we can
audit but it's ultimately not a
decentralized consensus application it's
telling us what the consensus is but
it's not but the mechanism itself is
defined by a hierarchy that ultimately
traces back to the US Constitution so
any solution that says just changed the
Constitution about how we think about
elections is already kind of a
non-starter the second problem is that
it's heavily dependent on software
integrity in particular the question not
of what is on the blockchain but is
what's on the blockchain actually what
people voted for which is what the
problem that we currently have look
like so it doesn't actually solve the
problem that current systems have which
is that the software used to cast votes
may be wrong it also have serious issues
of ballot secrecy and it addresses about
it really addresses tamper detection not
recovery what do you do if the
blockchain doesn't actually tell you the
right answer do you throw out some of
the votes you do over the election well
we're back to the original problem so
everyone just stop with the blockchain
stuff already okay
so for further reading when we recommend
two things first of all the national
academy of science engineering and
medicine just issued a consensus report
list here on securing the vote it is the
single best resource on the technical
problems in voting that I know of and
the second recommendation is if you want
to get involved with this where do you
start start by learning what the
problems are the best way I know of to
do that volunteer to be a poll worker
with your local county officials sign up
to be a poll worker they need the help
you'll work really hard for a day you'll
learn an awful lot about the
nitty-gritty of how elections are done
it is a absolutely great experience and
you get to give out those little I voted
stickers to your neighbors which are
heavily coveted so thanks very much and
I think that we have time for any
questions
[Applause]
yeah we have plenty of time for some
questions and sure you'll definitely
first so one spooky outcome of this is
potentially that you create an incentive
for the voting companies to say okay we
did it wrong by our V 2.0 it's better
it's more complicated how do you can't
how do you counteract that with this
kind of a Tara you know kind of harder
to comprehend you know it new is not
necessarily better you know how do you
deal with that messaging asymmetry yeah
so it's really tough and real one of the
parts of that problem is that we conduct
elections every year we conduct national
elections you know every four years and
elections for national office every two
years and you know we we have to do them
and we also have primary elections so
there's a fundamental practical problem
that there's a next election coming up
and we have to conduct it and you know
no solution that doesn't involve
addressing that part of the problem is
viable now fortunately we're in a in a
in a really unique situation in time and
I'm optimistic actually for the first
time since I've been working on this or
more optimistic or less pessimistic
let's say you left us a mystery the the
the first thing is there is bipartisan I
won't say consensus but recognition that
this is an issue that's worth solving
and there's agreement that we should
have systems of high integrity and it
that had this has previously been much
more partisan than it is now I mean you
know notwithstanding anything about the
last election Russian interference and
so on you will find prominent members of
Congress for example saying the same
things from both sides of the aisle
about the need to do this the second is
that the equipment purchased under the
help America Vote Act is now starting to
reach the end of its natural life cycle
and so the opportunity to get new stuff
is actually increasingly there so we
have both political will and a kind of
natural opportunity to
replacing the technology that we have
the technology to do you know risk
limiting audits in a software
independent way exists optical scan
paper ballots plus the risk limiting
audits we can do this and so you know
get involved at a local level encourage
your local county officials to want this
encourage your secretary of state to
want it that's probably the best way
forward here great thank you very much
okay over there hello
so I've heard an argument that the mass
that's described of the five thousand
legislative units or administrative
units doing it in all the different ways
of doing it is the best defense for it
it's just so hard to subvert because
it's such a mess and that any attempt to
make it more efficient and Harold Lee
makes it more subvert able and we
shouldn't even try yeah do you buy that
argument yeah and and it's interesting
because that's true probably if you're
interested in completely changing the
outcome of all the votes in the country
that's a strength but that's not
actually the problem someone trying to
subvert an election has first of all
most of the actual measure of intensity
about local offices and if you are a
national level adversary you know some
country you know rhyming with Usha
or whatever you are you have an
interesting job because now you have
5000 targets and all you need to do is
really picked enough of the weakest of
them to cause confidence to go away so
you're not going to necessarily pick the
hardest you're gonna pick the weakest
and there's a certain amount of
homogeneity in these systems because you
know they're using only a few different
vendors and so it's certainly you know
plausible that a national adversary
could cause widespread disruption and I
think the only reason that this hasn't
happened if if it hasn't happened is for
lack of trying rather than any inherent
rocky be just go time for one quick
questions make it very quick I think I
can be quick Matt you alluded to state
actors and you said one state actor or
you implied there's one state actor but
isn't this
over the last 50 years the largest
interferer in well maybe through but you
know probably not of us elections you
know when notwithstanding the Watergate
break-in right you know where there were
CIA operatives doing this say you know
if we assume that you know it's state
actors that we're going again even if
you believe that the CIA is secretly
trying to pick the president nothing I
said changes right we still want
mechanisms that are software independent
that are hard to attack that allow us to
get confidence without depending on
complex software and so on and so yes
I'm asking for ways that we can avoid
compromising democracy worldwide rather
than just yeah that is not in the scope
of my talk okay and with that call to
arms for next year we end a session
please thank everybody from the session
please before you all go don't get up
because it's really the most important
part of the conference is now turn it up
and I'm going to hand over to Dan yeah
all right Thank You Nigel great way to
start the morning let me just get set up
here
yeah that's not what I had in mind
[Music]
boy okay
yeah just blink at 60 Hertz and we'll be
fine we'll get there
does anybody have another dongle that's
that seems to be the problem use BCE to
HDMI thank you thank you plug in your
hardware into my machine please all
right so we can make the ecology work
even in 21st century although not for
voting great okay well so after this
wonderful morning session this is
actually one of the fun parts of the
conference where we get to award the
Levchin prize four-wheeled world crypto
so just to remind you the Levchin prize
is awarded once a year at this
conference it's actually it's a prize it
honors major innovations in real world
cryptography basically innovations that
have the significant impact on the use
of cryptography in the real world yeah
it's a lot of fun to do and the
selection selection of winners is is
always a fantastic task ok so I should
say the website for this award is left
in prize calm and I'll I guess I should
mention this throughout the the the
session that we're always looking for
nominations for more winners so please
go to this site there's a nomination
form and nominate your you know your
friends and and people you admire who
you think should win an award like this
so the prize itself started in 2016 it's
named after Max Levchin we probably know
Max Levchin is the founder of PayPal
he's been an enormous supporter and
champion of cryptography for many many
years over 20 years I guess in 2015 or
so we could have approached him about
creating this prize and he without even
blinking said yes I'll do it right away
and so we said we want to offer we want
to you know give out two awards a year
each award comes with a $10,000 prize
and max
has actually agreed to fund this prize
in perpetuity so forever so the surprise
will go on for many many years as long
as there's a need for wheel roll
cryptography okay so that's the price so
we've had a number of winners so far
it's actually by the way it's quite a
commitment from Maxis part so we're
really grateful for everything he's done
and you know it's wonderful that we can
make this happen
okay so we've had a number of winners so
far so the first winners were Phil
Rockaway and the mighty LS team then the
main and Moxie and Trevor Perrin for a
signal and of course the development of
AES and other cryptographic primitives
last year who go krafchick
won the award and the OpenSSL team won
the award for the remarkable work on you
know bringing making ssl as MPLS as a
widely deployed as it is and so with
that we are ready to announce the
winners of the 2019 live Chan prize
winner
okay so drumroll thank you okay so there
are two winners there are two winners
the first winner of the 2019 Lochan
prize ah okay here we go
okay is I mean here Volare
[Music]
yeah yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
your time okay yes okay awesome
all right so me here is a giant in our
field I'm sure you all know me here it
was actually kind of hard to distill all
of his contributions into a single
sentence that we can put on the trophy
but the award is essentially off
provided for outstanding contributions
to the design and analysis of real-world
cryptosystems
including the development of the random
Oracle model modes of operation H Mac
and models for key exchange and this is
really only a tiny tiny sliver of
everything that we here has done for
four-wheel rod cryptography so it's
really a pleasure being here to be able
to offer this award to you and I should
say the award comes with this beautiful
trophy it's a cryptex so it's actually
this bit so the the citation is here on
the bottom and then you can kind of
figure out the it's your challenge to
figure out what the secret password is
and open up the cryptex and find what's
inside so let me give you first of all
the award yeah so this is the first part
this is a second part so that's the
cryptex and then most importantly I have
to not forget to actually give you the
actual check so yeah
[Applause]
congratulations and traditionally the
award winners actually may get to make a
speech tell the community kind of put
the award in context tell the community
where they see the field going so the
stage is yours me here do you really
want to plug things in okay I have no
training as a cryptanalysts I'll have
trouble with that breaking that thing
it's an honor to be recognized but
particularly by RWC and Max Levchin
and thanks to max in the steering
committee for this and thanks also to
great co-authors over the years
particularly Phil of course and also to
the great students and postdocs they're
the ones who made everything possible
I'm glad to have been part of the
exciting early journey in bridging the
gap between theory and real world
cryptography those were different times
a smaller community the sense of doing
something important now it feels awkward
to get an award for things done so long
ago and that leads me to ask what time
has done and what I find with time is
that I'm thinking more and more about
broader issues in life where our work
fits into the social fabric how we
evolve as people in communities what is
the right definition of success and so
kind of returning to my roots in the
humanities I spend more time reading
sociology and philosophy and listening
and trying to understand how the world
in our minds work and I spend
correspondingly less and less time on
cryptography for which I have to
apologize to my students and as part of
this has been an evolution in my
thinking of what real world or practical
means and I think we benefit from asking
this question more and more when I
started it was a question of being
responsive to industry and implementer
needs to address what they call
practical problems and what people were
looking at and wanting to solve and now
I think that there are these are much
deeper questions like one needs to ask
whose needs one is addressing exactly
and in short who benefits from the work
we do and this is
more complex but it's important because
we live in a world that's fractured and
iniquitous and how much of what we do
helps rich corporations get richer does
it increase or decrease in equity who
benefits from making things faster our
beyond a certain point the constant
search for speed what sort of people do
we become when we cannot wait half a
second for a web page to load because
TLS is doing a round trip and we cut
corners is it a good or bad thing if
Facebook gets faster
I guess my worry is that these goals are
driven more by some entities financial
concerns then having value to our
development as people and I've come to
feel over time that what one does in
helping others is in the end the
greatest reward even for oneself and
excitement and ambition that one can
have in an area can die with time and
have seen that happen unless underlined
by some greater sense of purpose and
connection and that's what I feel RWC is
important but that's the community which
has come together with a broader more
holistic sense of what science and
cryptography are about and is really
trying to make the world a better place
and there are many ways to contribute
despite my real-world sympathies I feel
I'm still at hearted theoretician and I
feel sometimes the most important thing
we can give to others is ideas and that
beauty and depth of social value just
like art and inspire people and that has
been a tradition in cryptography that I
hope continues I feel like I'm turning
into a rambling old man up here kind of
embarrassed to bring that to you but if
I feel with time I have all questions
and clarity and at least I can take
refuge in Shakespeare's adage that above
all to thine own self be true and
luckily they don't give me more than
five minutes to speak to you
[Music]
thank you
this is uh quite thought-provoking
whether cryptography can help to make
the world a better place in other areas
and just protecting information all
right fantastic so with that as I said
there are always every year there are
two winners and so the second winner
this year I have to say was quite an
easy decision it was kind of an obvious
choice to make and so the second winner
of the Levchin prize for realreal
cryptography drumroll please
that's this thank you is Erik briscola
[Music]
[Applause]
all right great so Eric as you all know
is behind the standardization efforts in
T of TLS for many years and of course
this year thanks to the TLS 1.3 effort
we finally have we have a fantastic
protocol to this to deploy so let me
read the citations so this is for stage
sustained contributions to the
standardization of security protocols
and most recently the development and
standardization of TLS 1.3 so thank you
Eric for all the work you've been doing
we are extremely in your debt and I'm
really happy that we can give you an
award for all this work so here is your
wonderful cryptex we'll see if you can
figure out the secret word to open it
and of course don't forget the award
prize okay hand over the mic I'm just
glad the cheque isn't it in the cryptex
thank you thanks Dan and thanks max and
the committee it's really an honor to be
here on being the company of the
previous winners who I think have done a
fantastic work
I also want to thank the Tillis working
group I really did move this work on the
security research community he was like
me to actually not suck and Mozilla for
funding the work the one I was doing it
the past decade has seen a remarkable
increase in the use of encryption on the
Internet and this is driven in to a
great extent by the development of open
or operable communication security
protocols this allow anybody to build
their own implementation they can talk
to anybody else's standards are a key
element in making that possible
first they allow us to converge on
common protocols so that that actually
works they also coordinate the needs of
multiple stakeholders who have interests
and needs that are too hard for any one
person to comprehend and finally they
helped us build something better than
any single person could have designed on
their own no matter how smart they were
one three is a great example of this
when we started the one three effort we
had about 20 years of experience with
TLS implementations of deployments there
were dozens of papers analyzed in TLS
and we were also able to borrow from
other protocols like quick rapido so you
might have thought dot release easy
not true so as soon as we started
actually doing anything we discovered it
was just really hard to meet the goals
we were trying to set we found we had
problems with the anti repo mechanism is
er TT we struggled to add key separation
because the analyst told us it was
really important to be able to do
analysis the protocol which had been so
hard in 1.2 and finally when we actually
when it did deployment we found that
there were a lot of middle boxes which
just broke very badly when we tried to
1.3 through them and took us almost a
year to get to the point where that
worked properly
the final protocol had contributions
from over 80 people from the standards
community from implantation community
from deployment community and from the
research community and I have a list
here so this is everybody in the
knowledge mix of 1.3 if you're on this
list
give yourself a round of applause I see
another people here you also it turns
out how the right to a t-shirt if you
haven't gotten one thing that TLS chairs
ask them one thing that made this
possible was this critical feedback loop
between the standards community the
implementation community and the
research community so this let us try
out candidate designs quickly on
evaluate them for deployment evaluate
them for security and then roll them
into the protocol or not roll them in as
the case may be when I go back and look
at mail my mailbox from the period when
we were doing the development it's full
of emails to people like you go to
kochak and Karthik bhargavan saying
things like listen could you just take a
really quick look at this or maybe you
could run this through Provera for that
be ok
and people were credibly generous for
their time in doing that and being able
to ask those kinds of questions gave us
the confidence to make big changes the
protocol rather than just to run the
edges as we had previously increasingly
there's a consensus in the internet
community that in the words the Mozilla
manifesto security and privacy in the
internet are fundamental and encrypting
everything all the time is the only way
to really protect those needs
fortunately many of the companies that
control so much of the traffic on the
Internet are also committed this vision
and I want to give you two examples of
that first in 2014 let's encrypt was
founded by Akamai Cisco EF EFT
University Michigan is a law to provide
certificates for basically everybody the
internet for free in the time since then
it now has 50 sponsors or
it's the biggest sia internet and it's
issuing about a million certificates
today and this is what we can do when we
like all work together we're also seeing
companies moving rapidly to deploy new
protocols they're secure by default
they're doing this both book is better
for the users and because we've learned
the security performance as we thought
in the past don't have to be enemies you
can work together a few examples this
HTTP to the new version of HTTP is only
run over TLS essentially I'm tillis 1.30
roundtrip lets us send data and
essentially the same time as you would
have sent with ordinary unencrypted TCP
and finally the new quick protocols
under development not only a is faster
but B almost everybody in the wire
including all the metadata is encrypted
to the course tent we can make it happen
so hopefully we're gonna get all this
new tech and people always ask like
doesn't this take forever like when is
it actually gonna encrypt everything as
a reference point five years after tales
120 was deployed back in 2013
um we were just starting to add it to
Chrome and Firefox and about 11% of
servers supported it we're about five
months out of the standardization at one
point three it's already been in Chrome
or Firefox for quite some time
I hear it's coming other browsers soon
it's in about 10% of servers and I'm
told that over half of Facebook traffic
is already 1/3 this actually understates
how fast things can move when we try we
had es 130 test versions in the field
over a year before we actually published
the RFC this is how we found the middle
box problem but full credit by the way
to the team of Google really did all of
the work here and the same thing is
trying to happen without protocols like
quick on MLS where we just start rolling
our very early versions
what makes this possible is a
combination of better collaboration and
better design in terms of collaboration
protocol development uppers are starting
to be run like open-source projects they
have github repositories they have slack
channels with ADA coordination and what
this means is that we can roll out
versions very quickly and then when we
have to improve them we just keep
rolling that new versions and the
transition of the final version is
generally quite easy at least we hope
second the protocols are being designed
to enable that kind of version rolling
and that kind of extensibility and we're
getting much better at it so it's much
easier to have incremental new version
of rollout finally having verification
to feedback from the research community
because the confidence to make those
changes in deployed cryptography at
scale rather than waiting forever before
we do it
um this next slide for my second slide
is actual data from firefox telemetry
and shows the rate at which web pages
are loaded or HTTPS so if you go back
for years we're looking at basically 35
percent HTTP deployment and now we
rolling in over 75 and over almost 85
United States um and we have a ten
percent bump in the last year I remember
going back five years it felt a lot of
us like encryption was stalled like how
do we actually get to have encryption
everywhere but now actually we're
looking at a hundred percent web um you
know encryption and that's like insight
so that's an amazing thing for me to
feel open this in collaboration or the
core principles of this conference and
what I want to tell you here is
collaboration works and not only that
it's necessary for any large-scale
change and that's how we're changing the
world right now it's a privilege to be
part of that thank you
well said this is exactly what we lure
kryptos about well said all right so
thank you all and I again I want to
remind everybody that we're looking for
nominations for next year
so go nominate please we take the
nominations very seriously and we select
from what we get from the community so
with that thank you all again well we're
gonna have we're gonna break for lunch
now lunch is going to be served right
outside and we'll resume again at 2:00
p.m.