we'll start in one minute
okay let's get started come on in
all right take your seats come on in
everybody lunch is over
yes I'm stalling for time
all right so this is the start of the 2
p.m. session on cryptographic
standardization i'm brian LaMacchia I'm
one of the steering committee members I
do have a little bit of business from
the last session to take care of first
before we start so um is Brent sundel
who gave one of the lightning talks here
Brent Brent's the gentleman who got up
and admitted that it was three days
since his last used of blockchain
does anyone see Brent I have something
for you
okay I don't see Brent anywhere so I
will award this to Brent and hopefully
he'll come find me later because he
doesn't know this is coming okay so at
Asia crypt this year during the rump
session talk there were some prizes that
were donated to the rump session
committee by parties unknown they were
sets of cards cards against cryptography
now the sources for these are on github
and I took the sources for these and I
made some sets for my team and I brought
a couple extra decks with me so an
informal committee of the steering
committee for RWC decided that Brent had
the best lightning talk no one knew that
there were but I think we can all agree
that his talk was
[Applause]
[Music]
so he is hereby awarded in a you know as
close to official as any of these can be
an official set of cards against
cryptography and maybe you can get him
to play a game with you later so I have
that for Brent when he comes find me
he's on his way
excellent well if he gets here before I
finished the rest of my intro then we
can call him up I have another deck that
I will be awarding at 4 o'clock today
for another prize and you all can tweet
now and try to guess what that one's
gonna be for but I'm gonna hold that
till 4 o'clock ok so now I'm gonna stall
for time until Brent gets here or until
I run out of time as you all know we
were supposed to get an announcement
from NIST now of round two candidates
for the NIST post quantum competition
let me tell you how that came about and
why that's not going to happen for those
of you who are not in the United States
NIST publish to the mailing list that
they were going to make their round to
announcement sometime in January as soon
as I saw that I contacted Dustin moody
at NIST on behalf of the RWC steering
committee and I said Dustin we would be
honored if you would and we will make
time for you in the schedule if NIST
would like to make its announcement here
at RWC
we can't think of a better place to make
a real-world cryptography announcement
than RWC 2019 they looked at the dates
they came back Dustin conferred and the
rest they said yes we'd love to do that
please can you get us 15 minutes of time
and so we did that and we put that onto
the schedule and that's why it was a
late addition to the schedule and we
were all set to hear today the round two
candidates and then the government
partially shut down now for those of you
who are not US residents or aware of
this the US government gets funded
through a series of appropriation bills
get passed by the house of the Senate
and then signed by the President and
they appropriate money on a department
by Department basis and there are
currently something like nine major
cabinet departments including the
Department of Agriculture the Department
of Housing and Urban Development the
Department of the Interior the
Environmental Protection Agency and the
Department of Commerce
that are not funded right now NIST is an
agency of the Department of Commerce
when an agency is unfunded employees get
segregated into two camps the essential
and the not essential NIST is apparently
non-essential or at least everybody
dealing with anything that we all care
about is deemed non-essential essential
is you know preservation of life and
property and things like that which is
why the Transportation Security Agency
which is part of DHS Department of
Homeland Security which is also unfunded
they're all working without paychecks so
please when you talk to your TSA people
when you leave thank them for working
unfunded they're having a hard time
right now everybody who is working for
the government or as furloughed if
you're essential you have to work
without a paycheck and you will
hopefully get paid at the end of this
whole thing if you are non-essential you
are furloughed you are not allowed to
work and you are prohibited from doing
any communication or any work you're not
allowed to send mail you're not allowed
to read mail you're not allowed to stand
at a podium until who the round two
candidates are in the NIST post quantum
competition even if we pay for it right
and we actually offered to fly everybody
out there not a problem they're not
allowed to work so NIST really wants to
be here
they're not allowed to be here because
of the current situation in DC so I hope
we all appreciate NISS efforts to date
in the competition and we hope that the
impasse in DC is resolved soon and that
they're able to make their round two
announcements so that's why we don't
have an announcement here not through an
any fault of anybody from NIST and has
to do with some of the other people in
DC and and I'll leave my commentary
there okay ah and here is Brent you sir
you don't know why you're here deal Dan
Bonet told me I had to come to the stage
yes yes yes okay so they know and you
don't you had the best lightning talk
[Applause]
your prize is an efficient well as close
to official can be a set of cards
against cryptography yes congratulations
well done
[Music]
all right so with that out of the way
let's start with the first talk which
will be Jordan White feeling right yes
okay all right I ate into two minutes of
your time so we'll make sure you get
that back and there are mics there
great is okay mockers working great so
thank you for the opportunity for
letting me talk to you today and today I
want to speak briefly a bit about our
work that we've done with DAA with
myself and my co-authors so today I'm
gonna speak a bit about DAA in theory a
bit of the history how it came about to
be and some of the formal analysis work
that we've done on it so already this
year we've heard MLS used Tamron and
also we had the talk by noise Explorer
which was also using probe eros and
moving on from kind of the theory into
the real world we're looking to see how
we could apply it to DAA to something a
bit more concrete that hasn't been done
before so we proposed a vehicle use case
and I'll speak a bit about the
implementation be done and some of the
various lessons and challenges that we
faced so what is directed on a Sat
station or DAA
it's a anonymous digital group signature
scheme that provides previously reserved
event ocation standardized in the
iso/iec to triple zero 8 in 2013 and
this was a scheme that was originally
designed for the trusted platform module
or TPM which is a secure crypto
processor that creates stores and uses
keys and using the hardware we can
actually make Hardware back to Atta
stations to report something about the
status or the state of a host and there
are two ting properties for DAA so user
controlled anonymity and user control
traceability and since DEA is a split
signing scheme the host or the computer
has some kind of choice about whether
they want to remain anonymous or whether
they want to be linkable or not so DEA
was originally developed with the
trusted computing group and first came
to be in 2004 and was introduced in the
actual TPM 1.2 spec back in about 2000
and something and we see this today
still in the ISO triple zero eight two
more specifically mechanism for and as
daa itself has been developed over time
and the TPN has had various updates
regarding its ap API we're actually
seeing TPM 2.0 become released which
also introduced many different daa
schemes but in particular i wanted to
pick a pairing based schemes one based
on elliptic curves and this also made it
into the same iso standard a mechanism
for but since other daa schemes are
introduced new api's came out and the
TPM command calls were made more
flexible and also standardized in yet
another iso standard one one eight nine
the reason for this introduction while
RSA is slow and uses bigger key sizes so
ECC was meant to be or is more efficient
using smaller keys and smaller
signatures and beyond the TPM it's also
been introduced for Fido 2.0 for ECC DAA
and beyond TPM and also these Yubikey
type devices we also see enhancer of CIT
which is also being used in Intel's SGX
technology and in comparison to the
other schemes has improved to
reification capabilities so some of the
vulnerabilities that have occurred over
time have more been in the model and the
security models of DAA but one of the
pieces of work I wanted to speak about
particular today was the analysis done
by a cartel in 2013 where essentially
their analysis of the TPM 2.0 API
actually allowed a static diffie-hellman
Oracle which means over time da can be
exploited to essentially recover the key
after many different signing requests so
obviously this isn't a good thing to
have
so this required a change in the
protocol and also ultimately one or two
commands from the TPM being removed but
more generally a problem beyond the
scope of DAA is obviously the BNP two
five six curve which the da ECC da
scheme relies on and cryptanalysis has
shown this to be weak so we're looking
to see 128 bits of security get reduced
down to 85 bits so the fix to this is
kind of trivial well you move to a large
curve and lucky enough one's already
been specified for DAA using the
p68 curve so briefly daa aseye mentioned
previously is a split signing role where
the secured operations are done by the
TPM and the host can perform more
computationally intensive tasks and
together they form what's known as the
platform and this platform when it comes
out of manufacturing phase typically
comes endorsed with some type of key by
Infineon or potentially the laptop
manufacturer and to start off the da
process the TPM first generates its own
daa key and during this time it speaks
with the issuer who is a trusted third
party and make some kind of non
anonymous attestation to it to prove
that it's a valid TPM in some kind of
state so with that the issuer sees that
can verify that request and generate a
credential to give to the platform and
the platform will receive this
credential which you can use to make
later at a stations and then now using
this credential it can make anonymous at
stations with our verifier who is
another entity so perhaps this is some
form of data collector a bank some kind
of activity tracker when it creates this
message it signs some data with the DA a
key and randomizes the credential each
time meaning that if the user does want
to be anonymous or does want to be
linked then the host is going to
complete control of this and the
verifier then receives that message and
checks with the issue of public key
wherever this did in fact come from a
valid attested TPM so some former now
let's just work we've done using the
tamron prover is we performed a symbolic
security analysis of the ECC DAA scheme
and we actually discovered that if the
insecurity of a single TPM is affected
then the security of all TPMS are
actually compromised so what this means
is that we found a theoretical attack on
the authentication property of the join
protocol and we using our analysis we
identified a fix for this by including
the TPM public and/or
key in the proof of knowledge during a
sign so we do have some work on this we
currently have a paper under review and
we hope to make this available soon but
if anybody wants some more details then
please do come and find me so now moving
on to the implementation portion we
actually looked and tried to consider a
new novel use case where we haven't seen
DA before and in particular we wanted to
target vehicle to anything communication
or veto excommunication and this is what
we will see in future systems where cars
will need to communicate with one
another and some of the properties are
security and privacy properties that are
required in VTX communication are
actually not too dissimilar from that of
DAA so we fought our there was quite a
nice fit there so let's see how how far
we can take this and the current state
of the art proposes choose public key
infrastructure and various other
literature has said that there's
problems in terms of the scalar bitch
invocation in these systems and the TCG
also has announced in 2015 a oughta move
to thin profile so they're very keen and
they're pushing hard in industry to try
and get TPM chips within cars
so again picking the DAA algorithm there
was originally designed and as present
in the TPM seemed like quite a good
choice in a natural fit and what we were
wanting to do is have a shift of trust
from the infrastructure to locally
within vehicles which now have some kind
of trusted hardware inside them so
they'll be responsible to create their
own credentials sign them with the DAA
key such that all other vehicles or
other entities can actually verify this
so this just allows the shift to trust
edge points in cars so hopefully trying
to promote a more decentralized
architecture so these implementation as
I say we wanted to make it as real as
possible so you can see on the picture
there that there is a next com VTC in
vehicle computer and this is actually
computers that are in cars today they're
heavily resource constrained they are
about this one in particular had a Intel
Atom dual-core 32-bit processor so this
is the kind of level we're currently
working with in cars at the moment
obviously didn't have a TPM so we had to
hook it up to a Raspberry Pi and we used
a Infineon 2.0 developer module to do
this the software is fairly standard but
points of interest here are the Apache
molecular crypto library which we found
really useful and also use of the IBM
trusted software stack we took that
mainly because that's the stack that we
knew so to give you an idea of the
implementation we can see that the join
operation takes around eight hundred and
twenty milliseconds which is quite high
but in reality this is an operation
which may only be executed once but also
the pairings operation on this resource
constrained device taking around 200
milliseconds which considering the
capability that's not too bad so what
was some of the challenges well first of
all one of the more interesting ones is
even though we brought all the TPMS at
the same time and they all came out the
same box they actually all had different
versions on them which was quite
interesting so over time as I said as da
a has been developed in the TPM itself
has all sorts of Virata versions of
documentation comes out which means at
various points in different operations
we had to consider different ways of
actually implementing the protocol so in
this case we had a one point one six to
one point one four router which demanded
it be implemented in one way and so on
and so forth so this just made the
codebase much more complex and
potentially much more difficult to
maintain in the future and but on top of
the errata version and all the different
versions you have to be aware of and
where the documentation differs there's
also the complexity in the barrier of
entry to developing TPM so if anybody's
tried this before it's around 1,600
pages of documentation so it's not easy
to get to get into a tool and despite
this also the insecure curves being
announced on crypt analysis so that p25
6curv has been found signal weaker so
the p63 a curve we thought we would try
that even though it's specified in a
standard not a single TPM to this day do
we actually are we aware of that
implements this curve so we really need
to be
talking to each other the community and
also to the TCG to try and update the
standards to suggest some secure curves
that can go in so anybody that is using
this curve is no longer will no longer
be affected and compatible crypto
libraries it's slightly more exotic
so the crypto wasn't widely implemented
and the TPM has fixed points on the
curve and generators I very briefly want
to shamelessly plug one of the projects
that we're working on at the University
of Surrey so we're actually looking at
the next future TPM and in particular
making one that's quantum resistant so
the DAA scheme has been developed
further by some of my colleagues to make
a lattice based daa but on top of this
they're also doing security analysis of
the TPM to make sure that the next TPM
we a release is even better than now so
if you're interested to find out more
then you can visit their website future
TPM zouri you or you can contact them
directly on Twitter so to conclude my
talk TPM for the development is hard
just because of all the documentation
it's not trivial when you need to be
aware of absolutely every single small
change we to consider other use cases
for DAA because to this day we're not
quite sure who's using it so we're
really interested to find out if people
want to use it but also the Fido to
scheme ICI DAA because of some of our
formal symbolic analysis we're also
wanting to revisit that scheme to make
sure that we can make that as good as
possible so thank you if anybody has any
questions or comments thank you
[Applause]
so we've got time for one or two quick
questions if you imagine this being
deployed in a v2v infrastructure about
how pseudonymous and how on linkable do
you think the vehicles would be as a
practical matter so we only have kind of
like a proof-of-concept implementation
now so when vehicles do communicate with
one another that credentials will change
fairly frequently so DEA has been proved
to show to provide these properties but
actually when we have to consider the
cyber physical world as well perhaps
there's more work there where maybe
crypto will help or maybe it word but
we're not sure thank you all right let's
thank the speaker again and our next
speaker is Maarten Albrecht so how hard
is solving lwe anyway
I had the wrong way around goddamnit
I promise you it did work when I tested
it earlier computers nobody understands
them
I'm in the process of doing exactly that
huh all right success okay thanks for
having me and sorry for delay so the
question I'm asking is how hard is it to
solve elder b.e and entry based schemes
this is based on joint work with many
co-authors and also based on the work of
many other people which I had nothing to
do with all right so my opening gambit
is this so these are five schemes that
were submitted to the NIST a post
quantum competition which is not a
competition and so in the columns you
see five different schemes and in the
rows I give you the cost model or the
assumptions how long does it take to
break the underlying heart problem that
these schemes rely on and what you see
in this table are not necessarily the
numbers that designers have in their own
submissions but if you take the
assumption that these designers have and
then you run a standard attack under
these assumptions this is the bit
security that you get right so Kaiba's
assumption lead to an estimate of 180
bits of security for Kaiba and if you
apply the same assumption to Lima
another submission then you get 218 bits
of security whereas if you take the
assumptions that are made in the
streamlined angel prime submission then
you would get something like 500 bits of
security for Kaiba so what this table is
supposed to illustrate so it really
doesn't matter to compare the schemes
against each other I just picked random
parameter choices well really what I
want to highlight here that there's no
agreement in the community about like
how hard is it to solve this underlying
heart problem and that's maybe something
you want to address and I'm going to
kind of like I added the word entry to
the title because I was talking about
some entry schemes and now somewhat
shamelessly I'm going to sweep that back
under the rock and talk about lwe but
the same the logic that I'm discussing
it applies to entry based schemes in the
same way so fundamentally what the
the disagreement about is the difficulty
of solving this problem I give you a
matrix mod Q which is public so I guess
I give it to you how to set that and I
give you a vector C and this vector C is
computed by multiplying this public
matrix a by some secret vector S which
has small coefficients and then I add a
small perturbation vector E and then
given a and C your job as the attacker
is it to find s all right so that's the
hard problem that we're trying to solve
here the learning with eros problem so
straightforward attack on this would be
called the primal attack and we can
arrive at the primary attack by simply
looking at the equation that I've just
this plate but let's look at that over
the integers so all that means is
instead of having implicit modular
reductions modulo Q we write them down
explicitly right so I have to do some
additions in some subtractions of
multiples of Q to push everything in the
right range and then I can write this
down in matrix form and I end up with
this basis B which has Q on the diagonal
and then yet once on the diagonal you
have minus a and C and we know if you
multiply this from the right by the
correctly chosen vector then you get a
short vector that means you get the
concatenation of ES and 1 and as I told
you before the vector C has small
entries the vector S has small entries
and one certainly is a small integer so
what this means in the column span of
this basis if you do only integer linear
combinations there is a very short
vector there right so you can find a
combination of the columns that sums to
something that just very small and in
fact it is unusually small there will be
no other thing that is as small and
that's why this is called a unique
shortest vector problem approach because
we have something uniquely short right
and so this is the computational problem
that we're actually looking at how hard
is it to find this unique shortest
vector in the basis of this form and
this is what essentially these this
table highlights a disagreement okay so
how would we go about solving this
problem we apply lattice reduction and
when we want to talk about lattice
reduction it will be useful to talk not
only about the vectors which are the
columns of our matrix B
but also call talked about something
called the gram-schmidt vectors so the
gram-schmidt vector of a vector VI
denoted VI star is that vector but I
take away everything that was already
covered by previous vectors right so I
look at this vector and only look at
what is new essentially and so so this
means we speak of this as projecting
orthogonal e and so for example here
have two vectors on the slide V naught
and V 1 and V naught is its own
gram-schmidt vector because there's
nothing previously that I need to take
away but the vector B 1 well it also
goes a little bit in the direction of V
naught so how about we take that
contribution away and then if we do that
we end up with P 1 star which is V 1
star but only the new stuff that is ends
so to speak all right and if we have
these gram-schmidt vectors right for all
the columns of our matrix then we can
look at their length and we can look at
the lock of these lengths and we can
plot them so all the gram-schmidt
business was really to explain to you
what this plot means and you can see if
you take a matrix of the shape as the
space is B that I mentioned earlier then
you get the Z shape so you first have
your cubes and then you have your wants
and everything is already orthogonal
which way everything looks nicely
alright so that's the input that's the
geometric shape of the our input problem
now to show you what lattice reduction
does I'm applying the famous lll
algorithm so lll is the oldest lattice
reduction algorithm it is efficient it's
pulling on your time but it gives you
only a lattice that is somewhat good
right it doesn't give you something
that's good enough that we can actually
break these schemes but let's apply that
and then look again at the lengths of
these vectors or the locks of these
lengths and as you can see we now get
this line and essentially what we expect
from also stronger lattice reduction is
a line like that and our laps reduction
is the better the flatter the slyness so
the front comes down the back goes up
right and the more resources you and
investing the more you push the front
down and the more the back comes up so
that essentially lattice reduction and
what people are arguing about is to make
this line more parallel
okay so why does this matter it matters
because the slope tells you how
expensive it is to find this unique
shortest vector so this plot you have to
read from the back and what we want is
that this dashed line where the dotted
line and the solid line intersect is as
far to the back as possible because that
gives me the work factor that I have to
do to find this unique shortest vector
and so if I have an algorithm that
pushes the front down and the back up
then I can move this dashed line further
to the end which is where I want to be
because then my algorithm is cheaper and
this dotted line is essentially the same
process that I've done for the Commish
MIT vectors taking away all the previous
contributions I'm applying the same
process but to my target vector and
that's how I arrived at this dotted line
and that's the success condition that by
the way everybody agrees on right that
is the success condition you should
consider so this is not a point of
disagreement so far everything is nice
we agree on everything okay next step is
I told you lattice reduction what it
does is it reduces the slope so how does
it reduce the slope it depends on
something called the block size which is
the main parameter for our lattice
reduction which then in turn determines
something called the route how might
factor Delta which then in turn
determines the slope and again to
translate from the block size to the
expected slope is something that is not
contested right that's something that we
agree on you can compute fairly
accurately the expected slope that you
would expect from a given block size all
right
so I talked about block size let me
briefly tell you why this matters and
what this means so here I'm looking at
the because that algorithm which is this
algorithm that we are all considering
when we talk about strong lattice
reduction and my example I have block
size 5 so what I what that means is I
consider 5 up to 5 vectors at a time and
I'm going to ask an Oracle hey Oracle
you claim you a shortest vector Oracle
could you please give me the shortest
vector that is in the span of these five
factors okay so I call out to my SVP or
kill my ACP Oracle are they upset with
me says like yes I'm an SVP Oracle of
course here you go
so it gives me back a shortest vector I
insert it I hand with some linear
dependencies and I'm done with this
block all right then I move on to the
next five vectors and I'm not
technically touching those five vectors
I'm looking at some projections of them
but for now let's just assume I'm
looking at the next five vectors and I'm
playing the same game I say like hey
dear short is Mac the Oracle would you
be so kind to give me a shortest vector
and I said sure Martin here you go I
take it I insert it handle the near
dependencies and move on and I keep on
doing that until I hit the end and when
I hit the end I simply start at the
beginning and I keep on doing this and I
keep on doing this right and I stop
doing this when there is no more
progress to be made right so I keep on
going round and going round once is
called a tour and I keep on doing these
tours until my basis doesn't improve
anymore and this process will eventually
stabilize and then we say they have a
big hazard reduced basis but in practice
we just can stop after few tours because
the improvements that you make they
become smaller and smaller how much you
may ask and so here's an example of
running this algorithm on some lattice
the blue line would be the output of lol
reduction so similar to what I've showed
you earlier and then the orange line is
the output of Micah's at 60 so we have
60 vectors at the time that we are
considering and we we went through once
right and then the green line is going
through twice and the pink line going
through three times and then the brown
line as you can see these lines they're
approaching this black line right which
is what a theory tells us this is the
shape that we expecting afterwards and
it's not quite this line but the started
line but you can pre-compute that in the
simulation so that's also something
that's easy to predict alright
I'm finally in a position after this
preload of telling you about like what
are we actually arguing about to kind of
discuss one of the first disagreements I
just told you that after four to eight
tours we are done right so you need at
most as many and in each tool for each
index you're calling us VP Oracle so
that means you're calling us VP Oracle
each tour D times you have up to eight
tours so eight times D and whatever the
cost of my is VP or occurs right so that
would be some estimate for how
much work we have to invest in order to
compute the speakers at reduced basis on
the other hand you can argue that well
the basis keeps improving and maybe we
can amortize some costs so how about we
say well we have to call our SVP Oracle
at least once
right that's certainly true so how about
we simply write one instead of eighty
right and that would be a first
disagreement amongst designers simply if
you pick this lower bound and we have no
algorithm that achieves that or if you
pick the you know the estimate that is
slightly slightly too conservative
because we know we can do slightly
better somewhere in between is the
correct but on the other hand that gives
you a difference of maybe fourteen bits
and given how widely spread those
numbers are maybe that's not the most
important disagreement okay
so essentially what this algorithm does
it keeps on solving SVP over and over
again right and so and the number of
calls accounts for maybe fourteen bits
of difference but the big disagreement
of course is how expensive is it to
solve the shorter specter problem right
my Oracle that I call out to how
expensive is it to call this Oracle and
here is the big disagreement so the
first three lines in my table they they
are about in class of algorithms called
sitting and the last two lines of my
table are about an algorithm called
lattice point enumeration so saving
works by you produce many vectors so you
do essentially random linear
combinations of the columns of this
matrix then you have a huge selection of
vectors and then you pairwise check
whether when you add or subtract the
pair then you get something that's
shorter than the inputs if you find
something that's great you add it to
your set of vectors and you keep on
going and you keep on doing this process
until eventually you have something
which is short enough and the good news
about this algorithm is there is a
single exponential algorithm right so it
only runs in single exponential time
which as a Crypt analyst is very
efficient on the other hand before you
see these collisions right before you
actually hope have any chance of seeing
two things that sum to something which
is shorter you actually need
exponentially many vectors so this
algorithm infinitely requires
exponential memories
enumeration on the other hand is
essentially an exhaustive search within
the given radius of trying to find or
vectors that in this lattice and it uses
properties of projections you project it
down to one dimensional problem you try
to solve it there you lift it up you see
that how does it extend you lift it up
and so on and the good news about this
algorithm that it only requires
polynomial memory so that's great
the bad news is this is a super
exponential algorithm and it depends on
which class of enumeration algorithm
you're looking at what are you
considering it's either quasi linear and
the exponent or it's quadratic in the
exponent and as you can see the to our
cost smallest that I picked one of them
is quasi linear the other one is
quadratic right and so it depends a bit
on like how much pre-processing are you
doing that tells you in which of the two
regimes you are so let's look at these
two estimates a little bit and so both
of these estimates are actually based
off the same data so in UN Machane
thesis they have simulation results for
how long it would take to run
enumeration on lattices up to dimension
250 so that's the green line I hope you
can see this and then the difference
between these two cost models is simply
whether you fit across a linear function
through this or your physical graphic
function through this right and then
using that fit you extrapolate and then
that gives you the cost of the hole
attack because we don't have any data
for things that are larger than 250 okay
and the problem is we didn't have any
additional data and also no source code
was published in the thesis that would
allow us to extend this to see like you
know how does this develop however
things have changed since then and in
particular public open source
implementations of lattice reduction
have improved a lot and so what I've
done for this talk is I've extended the
data of you on my chain so I've run
essentially the same simulations as they
did you but at this time I can the the
source code of this will be made
publicly available so you can verify
that this was done correctly and so what
I've done I've extended this data to
dimension 330 or something like that and
as you can see the quasi
quasi-linear fit fits my simulation
quite nicely but the quadratic fit is
too pessimistic so it assumes that
lattice reduction is more expensive than
it really is right and here we're
talking about lattice reduction not in
theory but the lattice reduction is
implemented in a public open source
implementation namely FPL but of course
these are simulation results so a
natural comeback would be to say but
maybe the implementation doesn't
actually achieve what your simulation
predicts so on this slide I give you in
green this is the running time of actual
FPL so the actual software and then just
take seconds and translate that to the
unit that we're considering here which
is how many points in your exhaustive
search are you visiting the blue dashed
line would be the output of my
simulation as previously and then the
red dotted line is the I ask the FPL
software so how many points if you
actually visit and as you can see those
three lines converge which suggests to
me that indeed the simulation is fairly
accurate in predicting the efficiency of
FPL a last point I want to make about
the quasi linear versus the quadratic
estimate for enumeration is this also
the quasi linear fit actually fits quite
closely what theory would predict and
that is a cannon simulation which is
this family of enumeration that you know
has quasi linear complexity in the
exponent we know that the worst-case
leading exponent the leading exponent is
1 over 2 e and that is actually quite
close what this numerical approximation
gives us right so it seems we're
actually achieving the complexity the
worst case complexity that would be
predicted for current enumeration and a
natural question is if we are stuck in
this worst case or whether inside
because that we can maybe bring down
this leading coefficient so that is
something that is an open question all
right but the the big question of course
is the one in question is what is the
right cost model for enumeration but the
big question is of course sitting us in
a more
right so saving is asymptotically faster
but maybe the asymptotics only kick in
so late that we don't have to worry
about this right so because the
constants the hidden constants are so
huge maybe there's just no way in hell
that this will actually outperform
enumeration for the parameters that we
care about so to study this problem of
kind of how low can we push the cross
over between your numeration and saving
we developed jessyca which is a Python
in c++ framework for experimenting with
saving algorithms inside and outside
because it and in particular what we've
done is we not we haven't taken this
oracle view that I appealed to earlier
but instead we're thinking of saving a
stateful machines remember that we have
these large databases of vectors that he
carry around and instead of throwing
them away after we give you a shortest
vector we hold on to them to do some
further computations with them and then
we implemented several saving algorithms
so it's a whole class of algorithms to
be implemented some of them I want to
stress that we did not implement the
asymptotically fastest one that are used
in these estimates and then we applied
many recent tricks from the literature
and came up with some new tricks to make
serving faster and if you pull all of
this together we can report that saving
outperforms enumeration in block size 70
so the green dots this would be the same
thing that I've give you a showing you
before when I showed you the
experimental results so that's the same
software again and the red dots is our
SIF implementation for performing the
same task of computing the shortest
vector and as you can see it outperforms
or the crossover is in blocks i-70 and
to clarify blocks i-70 something takes
less than ten seconds right so the cross
over on if you're running this on one
big machine that has enough RAM to fit
all these vectors in between saving
enumeration is actually very small it is
not very late the canonical benchmark
for lattice reduction algorithms would
be the Dom chef SVP challenges and
despite being called the Dom shut SCP
challenge the dancer FCP challenge does
not ask you to solve SVP because it's
actually really hard to verify that the
thing that somebody gives you is the
shortest vector so it asks you to solve
a slightly
your problem so the red dotted line will
be my simulation for enumeration for
solving SVP exactly the green line will
be using the same methodology the
simulation of solving the problem that
the damped STP challenge asks you to
solve and then the blue and the red dots
would be entries from the hall-of-fame
right so people who claimed World
Records in performing this computation
and the time that they reported how long
it took them to solve this problem and
as you can see my green line and these
dots they seem to somewhat agree at this
point I want to stress that my green
line going through these dots in no way
diminishes the achievement of these dots
because my line is just a simulation
right and it's a simulation that assumes
everything paralyzes perfectly right and
we know that this is not the case so
that these guys actually managed to
achieve this complexity is a huge
accomplishment right then finally the
green dots are our saving algorithm as
you can see we are significantly
outperforming prior art when it comes to
solving these these challenges and then
we were also able to claim some new
world records in computing short vectors
in the dam's
SVP challenge up to dimension hundred
fifty-five all right I want to stress
solace this is indicative of lab sitting
is practical but on the other hand what
we have not is an implementation that
actually paralyzed across different
machines right and then there it's not
quite clear how this exactly is supposed
to work because you have this
exponential memory and then you have
nodes that have to communicate so this
is future work
also what is not clear at the moment is
the practical performance of the
asymptotically faster surfs we didn't
implement those and there will be more
overhead certainly so it's not quite
clear when exactly those beat the sister
we actually did implement and then of
course a fun open question is what if
you have dedicated hardware right so far
everything was on commodity CPUs and
then if we have dedicated CPUs or
hardware then then maybe there's
something else possible right I'm almost
done three more points so the first one
is we're talking here about the post
quantum competition which is not a
competition
but so far I've only talked about class
six estimates right all the algorithms
that are talked about are on classical
computers which is why we could
implement them and test them and since
this is we were crypto let's talk about
a bunch of algorithms or computers that
do not exist so what I give you on this
slide would be the the best estimates
for a classical and quantum saving and
classical and quantum enumeration and as
you can seem for saving the improvement
that you're seeing is actually fairly
minimal so the leading coefficient goes
from 0.29 to two 0.265 right where is
for enumeration you see the Grover's
Peter but you have to 1/2 and the
exponent which means you're taking a
square root and both of these are
actually like the strategies fairly
similar you find the place where you
have an exhaustive search and your
algorithm you slap your grover on that
and you claim your 1/2 and in the case
of enumeration you can't quite do that
so you need a quantum backtracking
algorithm but Montanaro has has provided
one and then some people worked out kind
of how to apply it exactly alright so
but a question that you might ask
yourself is why is the performance of
quantum serving so poor compared to
classical serving and the the reasons
that I want to give you is firstly
remember that saving works by producing
this large set of vectors and then
looking for collisions essentially but
whatever you do like however efficient
you're doing your collision search you
have to write down this large list of
vectors first right there's nothing that
gets you around that at least as far as
we know so that's it's an inherent
limitation for how low you can go
the second and perhaps more important
point is that these asymptotically
faster sitting algorithms that we see in
the literature they're really exploiting
that the search space that you're
searching through is not unstructured
it's actually quite structured in
Grover's search really is for
unstructured search to illustrate this
consider the simple SIF algorithm called
the Gauss if and if you if you do that
and do you know you're most optimistic
estimate for a slapping growver on that
then you end up with a quantum
complexity where the leading coefficient
is 0.3 1 1
you can actually achieve the very same
complexity classically without any
increase in memory by implementing the
so-called BG jaysis which is the one
that we also implemented in Jessica and
this is simply using the fact that the
search space is quite structured and so
this asymptotically faster always what
they're doing is they're successfully
reducing the list that you need to
search through which makes them faster
but now if the lists that need to search
through a smaller the speed-up that you
can get from Grover becomes smaller as
well so there's less of a potential for
grover star algorithm to improve so if
you want to have more efficient
algorithms quantum algorithms in the
spirit of saving you really need new
ideas right because the better serving
algorithms they make Rover hard and
harder to shine then I want to make a
point about lower bounds because the the
table entries that I've shown you at the
beginning they were not necessarily of
the form we think there exists an
algorithm that can solve this problem
with this complexity they were rather of
the form we think any algorithm in this
family of algorithms so plausible we'll
have to do at least this many operations
right so they're explicit lower bounds
and so what this means is polynomial
factors are completely ignored the
maximum depth like how long you can run
a quantum computation it's completely
ignored and also when we compare
classical and quantum we're actually
comparing CPU cycles and grover
iterations and one grover iteration is
most definitely more expensive than one
CPU cycle so there's this huge overheads
that are simply being ignored and thus I
want to kind of issue a word of caution
in two regards firstly if somebody comes
up with a new lower bound and maybe
here's a new plausible lower bound and
this in no way implies that schemes need
to update their parameters right because
a new lower bound does not imply that
they've actually found an algorithm that
achieves anything like this lower bound
all they're claiming is here's a new
lower bound so you have to be very
careful about how to interpret some
results from the literature and secondly
you want to be very careful about how
you interpret results in these models
and that is if you assume the cost of
lattice reduction is indeed the
then some classes of attack simply do
not work you don't need to consider them
it's just like this strategy is just
that it's just not efficient but
whenever you plug in an actually
realistic cost model for how long that
reduction takes then these techniques
start to work and so what this means if
if you always consider only the lower
bounds you might rule out some classes
of attacks that are actually quite
promising that actually allow us to
learn something about the problem but
we're not studying them because we
assume that they don't they don't work
because like look in this lower bound
model they don't work so you have to be
really careful about that okay final
points it would be irresponsible to talk
about this without mentioning and
stressing all the things that I didn't
talk about so first of all I've only
talked about very vanilla lwe problem
but many of the submissions to the nist
process they actually use small and
sparse secrets so they deviate from this
vanilla formulation and they're a
different family of algorithms applies
essentially you're guessing some bits of
the secret and so on and here i think
there is still some room for improvement
so this needs further studying also I
completely swept under the rug
algebraic structure so to make these
schemes efficient we don't have actually
random matrices a but these matrices a
have some algebraic structure in there
and it's not clear if this algebraic
structure can't be exploited so for
example the ideal SVP problem or some
approximation of the ideal SVP problem
is easy on a quantum computer then the
general problem that I've discussed here
and ring lwe if you pick your parameters
right and so on but usually nobody does
that for the schemes used in practice
then we as known as at least as hard as
I do SVP but it's not really clear if
it's harder or not so do these attacks
on ideal SBP do they extend in some way
to ring a double yi right so and that is
a pressing question future research and
then lastly I've only talked about
passive adversaries right you see some
ciphertext on the wire you say like
here's an underlying hard problem let me
try to solve this underlying hard
problem what we care about is actually
activate
right and so these schemes because they
add this noise
they stick they're prone to have
decryption failures right and then you
need to bount them and then these
decryption failures that might teach you
something about the underlying secrets
so that might then lead to a break of
your scheme so some of the submissions
to the nist process they they explicitly
rule out this right so they pick
parameters that you have no decryption
failure whatsoever other scheme saying
we are accepting decryption failures
with a certain probability and then the
question is can you boost this
probability somehow but doing some pre
computation and how much does that
affect the security of these schemes
right I want just wanna stress like this
is only a small part of the questions
that we still need to answer all right
that's all I want to say thank you very
much
okay we've got a few minutes for
questions and I see people heading to
the mics so it seemed in your slides
that the circuit complexity penalty of
having a exponential amount memory
wasn't reflected in the bit hardness
estimates does this suggest in other
words the the fact that enumeration uses
a lot less memory hmm
didn't seem to show up in them in the
number like you have two different kinds
of numbers appearing in the top half of
the graph some are including the cert
the circuit size some are not how do you
mean including the circuit size
you mean like something like that yes
are these top numbers just times or are
they taking into account or is it time
times remember all of these at times
today not none of this is an area times
time model yes so and then that's the
question right so how does this behave
and then in a way we can give you some
partial answer by actually implementing
saving when you have huge amounts of RAM
but the really interesting bit is when
you paralyze it across like for
non-uniform memory access and then this
is future work yeah absolutely right
thank you other questions all right then
I'm gonna take the prerogative to ask
one so back in the dawn of history when
I did some work on lattice reduction
with knapsacks obviously we couldn't we
were going after 50 60 dimension
problems and that was what we're able to
do at the time and we noticed a
catastrophic drop-off in the
effectiveness of lll so when what we
could approximate versus and then the
quality of the shortest vector the
difference between the shortest vector
lll found and what was the actual short
vector mm-hmm when you go run out at
these dimensions mm-hmm
when you don't find the shortest vector
but you find something that is close to
you'd still notice that lll running say
running bkz that sort of thing do you
get a catastrophic drop off at some end
point in terms of the quality of the the
answer that comes out of it or do you
sort of see a more you know smoother
progression and the quality of the
answer that comes out I think the the
picture
change in the sense of now the lattice
dimension of it tackling a much bigger
and we have a whole continuum of
algorithms right so we don't have this
kind of like you run ll and afterwards
you're dead and then there's a drop off
so that's why we don't observe it that
much because we simply run them because
at twenty right which like takes almost
no more time now like with all the
improvements so that's why we don't
observe it but you can probably for each
of those algorithms you can probably
have a similar thing of like Oh actually
and then when you go beyond dimension
eighty or something I'm making all these
numbers up now then then maybe you still
see that but it's not so relevant now
because you simply increase your because
that dimensions slightly and then you're
done Nigel so these are for post
constant competition parameters yeah so
and so you see you say you say you can
think of Allah loves because he - yeah
and you can then say you're saying and
we have this drop catastrophic drop off
then you have Big Easy twenty and if you
make the parameters huge like fhe land
you'll have a catastrophic drop off what
happens if you down move the dimensions
up to fhe level parameters like all
dimensions 16,000 32,000 65,000 so
catastrophic drop off means you actually
achieve the the quality that we expect
so LOL behaves much better than you
expect in small dimensions and then the
kerrick's traffic drop off means that
and then you get what you expect so what
we will be looking at is like in
dimension 16,000 we would we would get
essentially what this graph is
predicting so this would be the quality
that you're getting out and that that
seems to be accurate I'm not aware like
like doing this on dimension 16,000 and
I know of your standing challenge of us
to run actually lol in that dimension
but like the the in terms of the output
quality that you expect so there's no
reason to expect it will be different
from what this graph implies again
there's like
you
[Applause]