you wanna you want to run first or you
want you want me to or how do you what
do you want to do here Joe
Joe are you here Joe
given all the prizes away yeah we get 21
prizes what is 121 yeah so it was fun
being mrs. Santa Claus and now I have to
go out and mail these things for you for
you people having fun in the connect
track right now hold on just a second I
am wearing clothes today
all right stop you know what guys and I
know we I don't know how many people we
got in this channel right now we got 13
folks in the channel you know what we
survived this and and Wow
that's all I've got to say is Wow
too much fun in the Kinect track channel
right now thank you so Joe what do we
have left to give away Joe you're muted
oh you better you're giving the dog away
one last giveaway and that is the
Chromebook and that goes to Mary Cruz so
I will send that out momentarily did you
want me to do a quick call out for the
CTF winners yeah absolutely
okay
oh gosh I hate doing names cuz I know I
get so sensitive about mine alright
third place Alejandro a second place was
Robert and first place is Brady
yeah it was for CTF very nice merit meri
is showing a high degree of excitement
in the channel that she won something
thank you was that was that your
daughter we gave the Chromebook to two
years ago that's great
okay that's outstanding same company by
the way gave us a Chromebook this year
is the one that gave us a Chromebook two
years ago so there you go so that what
have you got I just say we have speaker
gifts that I personally picked out it's
a gift that I would want to get and if
you filled out the Google form then we
have your address if not please make
sure we have your address and we'll send
those out as soon as possible to make
sure we show gratitude for everybody
showing up and being on time and
following the rules and you know being
prepared everybody had great slides and
great content and that was really
helpful to us because you know we had to
do this all virtually and you guys were
pros at just joining this as well I
don't really know if we were pros but we
pretended like oh Patrick what have you
got we all really need to thank Patrick
because he's now at Netflix and we are
all falling on his mercy that he keeps
me oh he's muted sorry that he keeps
Netflix up and running for all everybody
else and I do not do ensure security at
Netflix yeah I try to keep things secure
but I just want to thank all of the
sponsors all the other organizers all
the speakers we had some really great
talks I was in the protect tract and all
of those here and there and just some
really great stuff so thank you to
everybody who and Patrick is West Coast
so he was up at what time this morning
[Music]
that is yeah yeah if I'm awake at 4:30
typically it means I'm going to bed yeah
when I saw him this morning I wanted to
I wanted to ask him if he had been he'd
just stayed up from the night before but
I didn't want to be presumptuous so I
will be taking a nap shortly
you've earned it buddy take two naps
Matt you got anything
there we go so I've got a few things I
want to do this one more time because
literally we could not have done what we
did today without them but I want to
acknowledge all of our sponsors one more
time
Time Warner Warner Media NCR Bishop Fox
my home department at home College
Council State University the Michael J
Cole's College of Business and the
Department of Information Systems
genuine parse company and coalfire I
also want to acknowledge synopsis and
critical path security at the Silver
level we want to acknowledge core light
guide point security kehna security
Black Hills information security Aaron's
in binary defense and at the bronze
level NCC group and our in-kind sponsors
the EC Council for their training
yesterday as well as a secure code
warrior for staging the VT VT Fi I'm
just making up acronyms now CTL I think
that's better than a CTF it's a very CTF
we'll also want to acknowledge the
organizations and individuals who gave
us items to give away throughout the day
and the raffle
my constant crosshair information
technology across the information
technology Joe gray information security
and the pen tester lab finally well not
finally yeah finally not it and I have a
surprise for everybody this has been a
virtual conference and we've been
pushing this map all day long and please
one last time we hope that you will
visit that map because we want to know
where you're from we want to know I'm
trying to get back and not sure that
that anymore I think I stopped I stopped
sharing that yes we want to we want to
know where you are please take a couple
minutes to drop drop the pin in the map
so that we know where you were hanging
out with us today from next a couple
weeks ago we thought we were going to be
physical we
we're gonna have this great plan to hand
out t-shirts we're gonna have t-shirts
for everybody and that was going to be a
thing right and then the world stood on
its head and we had to spin this thing
up into a virtual format with less than
almost less than two weeks notice and it
has been a challenge but one that I
think that we have successfully
navigated but one of the things that we
communicated to our personal sponsors
was that we were not going to be able to
handle t-shirts we just simply were not
equipped to handle that in in thinking
about everything else that we need to
get done along the way and so we gave
you an opportunity to ask for a refund
no questions asked we understood and we
had almost 300 sponsored personal
sponsors and less than 15 less than 20
left us and so a thank you for that and
B we had a t-shirt company reach out to
us and offer a solution and so we
believe that what we're going to be able
to offer everybody in two groups and
listen carefully now is that one of the
perks of being a personal sponsor was
that you would get a t-shirt we think
that we have worked that out and we will
be communicating with you how to do that
in the forthcoming week or so a couple
of weeks probably to get this all stood
up but what we will be relying on is the
email address that you punched into Tito
to place your ticket order as a personal
sponsor and so if that is not an email
address that you frequently check please
do keep an eye on it
because we will be pushing details out
about that and how you can go about
getting the shirt that is part of your
personal sponsorship those of you who
are not personal sponsors don't feel
left out don't feel slighted we have a
plan for you as well we are going to be
standing up a virtual webstore where
anybody can purchase the t-shirt for
today's of that and so we will be making
details about that available
again in next couple of weeks is we're
able to work through that we are also
looking at adding to adding to our
attire selection is there anybody out
there who like hoodies I'm looking in
the flak channel anybody like goodies
yes the t-shirt should say I survive
these these virtual b-sides
oh good lord all the yeses for the
hoodies well we think we can pull it off
no promises no guarantees but we're
looking at adding a number of items in
the virtual webstore and so good lord
all right enough enough enough I know
everybody wants a hoodie stop it
good lord so we we will be working to
make that available for you the next
couple of weeks also please do not walk
away from the slack workspace we've had
a great deal of fun in here today but we
actually knew this is not just a one-off
type thing to get us through the day we
we envisioned this as a way to stay
connected with you nice folks globally
throughout the year and so whether we do
this virtually next year or not whether
we do it in person or not whether we do
a hybrid a lot of decisions to be made
we're nowhere near making those
decisions yet but we want to stay
connected with you and one of the things
that we have talked about doing is
hosting webinars throughout the year
we're in the very early planning stages
of that it seems that the I think
everybody would agree the zoom worked
pretty well and so we think that we see
some opportunity here who wants socks
we're not getting socks in the stop it
we're not getting socks well maybe maybe
we'll get a socks I don't know no stocks
no definitely no stocks charlie no we're
working on it we're moving in that
direction so we we need to hit the
drawing board and figure out what these
intermediate
events might look like on a much smaller
scale but understand that is something
that we're looking at and one of the
ways that we will communicate will be
through the slack workspace another will
be through our Twitter account that's oh
wait oh good lord
Elvis stop it I'm just gonna stop so yes
I will sell my you socks queue
absolutely yes I will
so now we're just getting silly now it's
the end of the day it's been a long day
so just keep we've got a lot of things
cooking and we've got now that the
pressures off of us with today and
getting through today I think that I
think we all agree we've had some
conversations internally that there are
some real opportunities here and we
would like to see how we can capitalize
on that to maybe not just make b-sides a
once-a-year thing especially in Atlanta
so we'll see what that looks like we
will be in touch
keep an eye on the slack workspace keep
an eye on Twitter and I am I am just
gonna stop talking now because I am
tired and I want a cigar and a glass of
bourbon with that anybody else any
closing remarks and I thank you to
everybody we appreciate this this was a
learning experience for us and I mean
honestly a month ago we thought we were
still gonna be able to pull this off in
person and in less than a week had to
quickly pivot and start looking at other
options and we spent a lot of time on
calls and you know going sorry
going through people want to see the dog
yeah she's dying
just a bit on 10 walks by today but we
just a few tick appreciate everybody is
their time and attention you know I
guess what else did we have to do today
um but be quarantined and watch be sighs
which is amazing so we appreciate that
and I had a dissertation to work on and
I'm in the process of buying a house so
you know I got stuff yeah I'm just
saying so anyway enough so what else are
we done we're done good lord we did
let's see what the final count is a
hundred people in the in the webinar and
let's go look at did we spin back yeah
sixty-eight people on Twitter so we'll
take it god I look even worse on twitch
than I do live it in person so I think
we'll shut it down guys and girls
kitties of all ages wherever you are we
hope you found the day worthwhile and a
few are GMT plus four or five or six we
hope that the concept was worth staying
up throughout the night I think we'll
sign off from here and we will see
everybody
we hope sooner rather than later