hi everyone I just want to confirm can
you see my slide it should be chilly now
it's great to be here I'm calling in
from the west coast so it's a little on
the early side for me so that's why I'm
not sharing video my name is Eddie Glen
I work for a company called vinify and
just a little bit about me before I get
started I started off my career as a
software developer developing avionics
software so I spent many many years
concerned about software that controls
aircraft and making sure that it's safe
and secure and over time my career just
kind of led me towards being more
security focused so I'm very happy to be
here today to talk about software supply
chains before I get started I wanted to
tell a story and there's this company in
Europe called Maersk they're the world's
largest shipping conglomerate
and they're responsible for a fifth of
the world shipping capacity it's a huge
company lots of employees lots of
different offices spread around the
world and they had a really bad day on
June 27 2000 17 and I don't know if that
date rings a bell for any of you but uh
something really bad happened at Maersk
that that impacted a lot of people
around the world and basically what
happened is their employees started
seeing screens that look like this on
their computers and what had happened is
that they had been hit by the not petia
malware and 4,000 of their servers got
infected 45,000 pcs got infected it
basically wiped out all the data on all
their computers their voice over IP
phones stop working their ships stopped
moving that port terminal gates stopped
moving up and down so their their
customers couldn't get product through
the port and this ended up affecting not
just mayor split obviously all of the
customers that depended on them for
their worldwide shipping activities and
it took them about 10 days to to get
everything reboot it to where they were
operational again and their internal
accountants said that it had cost
them 300 million dollars but some
external experts thought that it was
probably maybe double or triple that for
them based on the number of days that
they had downtime so extremely serious
incident for Maersk and I'm sure that
their leadership will always remember
that that particular day but it didn't
affect just them it affected other
global companies Merck pharmaceuticals
was in the news in the US my brother
works for fur Merck and he he wasn't
able to work for about two weeks because
they were experiencing similar things
and and this happened with the
subsidiary of FedEx in Europe and the
list goes on with with other companies
that work that were impacted by it and
the estimate for the number of damage
has done worldwide by this one piece of
malware was ten billion dollars so
extremely significant amount of amount
of money and impact on companies and
companies workers so how did it happen
and this is what I wanted really to
focus on today is is the how it happened
and how what steps we can take to keep
this from happening to businesses like
yours so it turns out that there is a
small family-run Ukrainian software
business called link OS and they
produced a piece of software called me
doc that's basically used by all
businesses that do business with Ukraine
so all these global companies did
business with Ukraine so they had this
piece of software and we all know what
was going on and has been going on
between Russia and Ukraine for a number
of years and hackers within the Russian
military infected this piece of software
with no Petya malware and that ended up
infecting everyone that used it
and this is really you know an important
question that so far I've not been able
to find the answer to but if if link OS
was doing proper code signing practices
that shouldn't have been possible but it
was so obviously there was some problem
with code signing and that's what I
really want to talk to you guys about
today to help educate you on the
importance of how to do proper code
signing within your organization so when
we think about the risk that we have
from a security perspective there there
are two risks that are almost different
sides of the same coin first you have
the company the Ukrainian company
company linka linka and their risk was
around do they protect the software that
they deliver to their customers
adequately and did they infect their
customers which they did so that you
know that's a huge risk for especially
for those of you that work for
businesses where software is your
primary product but then there's also
the risk that you have to think about
from Maersk where if they got infected
with with malware it's going to disrupt
their business operations and you know
when I talk to our customers I
frequently say well which of these risk
is more palatable to your business which
are you you're willing to to bear and
most companies say well neither they're
both both extremely important and things
that I want to avoid so this kind of
leads us to the question about software
chain software supply chains they're
more vulnerable than ever and there are
a number of reasons for that first is
that our businesses rely on software
more than they've ever relied on
software before you know if you go back
to merican and think about you know
they're their port gates going up and
down I mean they stopped working because
they were controlled by software their
voice over IP phones stopped working
because they're controlled by software
so businesses rely on software more than
ever
the other important aspect is that the
software comes from many different
suppliers so if I'm part of the InfoSec
team I you know look at the inventory of
software that my a my company uses and I
would I would guess that maybe a hundred
to two hundred maybe five hundred
different vendors provide your company
software and how do you know that all
software's trustworthy and that it comes
from the source that it says it comes
from another aspect is that we're
downloading software from the internet
every day and your employees are
every day so how do you trust that
software that's being downloaded and
then finally but and it's not lie and
certainly not least here cyber criminals
are more active and creative than ever
before and we'll see that later on in my
talk here so there are other examples
where malware has infected of very
critical pieces of software based on
poor code signing practices and policies
just a year ago
the Taiwanese computer manufacturer Asus
had a very severe issue around hackers
adi malware to their software update so
i'm gonna dive into that in a little bit
more detail just a few minutes and then
if we go back a few years before that
you had the issue of Stuxnet that was
was causing quite a few problems and
then here's the thing that if I were you
I would really be concerned about is
that code signing is an effective way to
stop this malware for being inserted
into legitimate software hackers know
that so what are they doing now they're
focusing their attention on how do they
steal code signing certificates from
legitimate companies so if you work for
company XYZ and you aren't protecting
your code signing private keys
sufficiently and a hacker stills those
keys they're gonna be able to sign
malware in your company's name in my
case
research study about two years ago and
they'd found that 22 and a half million
insistence of malware were signed with
either stolen or forged code signing
certificates so again think about this
if there's a piece of malware floating
around the internet and it's signed with
your company's code signing credentials
what's that going to mean to your
company which your CEO going to think
about that so you know keep this in mind
that that if your company is doing code
signing that you really need to focus on
how do you protect those keys so and the
rest of the time that I have I just
wanted to do a couple of couple of
things I'm gonna go through a quick code
signing refresher I do find many many of
the people that I talked to they they
are aware of code signing but they
aren't really aware of the details of it
I'm going to talk about the challenges
that likely your organization is having
and then I'm going to finally give you
some best practices on how you can
improve things
so first what is code signing it's
really just a technique that allows
someone to add a digital signature to
computer executables and when we talk
about computer executables we mean
anything from the software applications
that that your employees install OS
images disk images containers firmware
drivers you name it if it's a piece of
code and execute on something then
that's a piece of code that potentially
can be signed digitally signed and that
signature is going to show you two
things it's going to show your consumers
two things one is it verifies your your
identity your company's identity and two
it verifies and ensures that no one has
modified your software since you signed
it so you know let's say you put out a
software update a hacker if it's been
properly signed a hacker can't install
malware or attach malware to it because
then the digital signature will no
longer match and the operating system
will reject it
so think about co-signing as a birth
certificate for the software so just
like with with our human birth
certificates code signing certificate in
key is extremely vital to protecting the
identity of the software that your
business consumes as well as creates so
when we think about who signs code and
this is part of the problem that the
businesses have it's kind of across the
board if you think about who's actually
writing the code it's going to be the
software developers and if you're like
most of the businesses that I talked to
they they have hundreds or thousands of
software developers spread around the
world so you have lots of development
going on where they're they're the ones
responsible for signing signing their
software you have build engineers you
maybe people don't even do it it's done
by automated scripts that's being driven
by is something like Jenkins or in
another DevOps kind of platform but code
signing you know could be done by the
developers or the people associated with
the software development there are other
companies that recognize the
[Music]
significance of the risk around
code-signing and therefore they restrict
code-signing to just the PKI team or the
InfoSec team so I know one company where
they have a literally it's a locked room
with one key that one or two people have
access to and when they need to have
signed a piece of code they take they
unlock that room they take a USB in with
the code on it that's where their
private keys are and then they they
perform the code signing operation and
that's how it gets done and when we have
to ask a question where does it get
signed and again this is going to be
part of the problem one of the
challenges that that that you likely are
experiencing is that if your software
developers are doing it it's gonna be
signed on their laptops or their build
servers or maybe it's a web service that
they're using to build their software or
it's done in the cloud and if the PKI
teams doing it it's like likely to be in
some secure lab or on a secured computer
with very limited people access and so
we've got to think about this from terms
of pros and cons obviously the pro for
when the developers do it is that it's
extremely fast and I don't know if you
hear this from your developers if you
talk to them but that's what drives them
they they're being pressured to get out
new software updates more quickly than
they've ever been done before you know
used to be that we would measure
software updates by once per year and
then it got down to once per quarter and
then once per month and now it's not
uncommon that software developers are
being asked that push out releases once
a day or several times a day so if you
have to if they have to rely on a single
point a PKI team it's going to be very
slow for them and it's going to cause
problems so that's why they want to do
it themselves but the problem with this
approach is that the keys aren't secure
if you have keys that are being stored
on a developer's laptop or a server or
in the cloud they're gonna be very
unsafe and accessible by potential
hackers then if you look on the other
side obviously if you have a single
point of signing it's going to be
extremely
but it's gonna be also very slow and
that that often doesn't work for today's
business so let's talk about some of the
risks and challenges around code signing
this is a great read so if you wanted to
find out more about code signing in the
risk around it I would suggest that you
read this very short report from sands
Institute and basically it's all about
how hackers have now pivoted in their
attack vectors to where they're now
attacking the code signing system itself
so if you have developers with code
signing keys on their laptops hackers
are going to be searching around your
network trying to find those private
keys on laptops if there is a lack of
process within your organization the
hackers going to try to exploit that
lack of process and one of the the great
quotes from this article is that it's
this one that just showed popped up it
is not an exaggeration to consider
private code signing keys as the keys to
the business's kingdom so let's think
about this for a minute
if you have a TLS certificate that's
going to have a limited lifetime and
it's going to be assigned to a
particular IP so it's if it's stolen and
it can do limited damage but with a code
signing certificate in key if the key is
released that can be used to sign any
kind of software and it's going to look
like it comes from your business and if
your business is in the business of
producing software that's going to be a
direct hit on your reputation that now
people are thinking that your business
is producing malware the other thing
about code signing keys is that when you
sign a piece of software if it's
time-stamped that piece of software is
going to be valid the the code signing
signature is going to be valid pretty
much indefinitely
as long as that timestamp is still valid
so that means that even if you have a
breach and hackers have stolen your
private code signing keys and you've
tried to revoke those those certificates
if they've already signed the software
it's not going to matter because that
software is out there on the internet
forever effectively and it's going to
have your company's name associated with
it so very very
from a security standpoint to not really
guard those private codes hunting keys
with everything that you have so
particular talents first one is around
private key sprawl and unprotected
private keys and this is really you know
the issue where error we have to think
about where those keys actually bein
stored you know is it on some developers
laptop is it on a build server it's on a
web server and there's a great example
of what bad can happen if you don't
store these things properly and I'll go
back to that Zeus example basically this
is what happened to them they had a web
update server that pushed out their
driver updates to all their customers
and was done automatically those updates
were signed with a Zeus's code signing
keys and all the operating systems you
know assume that you know if they were
being pushed out with a valid digitally
signed update that that would just go
ahead and get installed and we see this
all the time with their computers and
laptops what happened is that for
whatever reason Azusa decided to keep
private code signing keys on this update
server and it was probably for
convenience you know that they were
rushing to get some update out and and
some developer just assumed that hey
let's just put the key here and then I
don't have to be moving software back
and forth between my build environment
and in the update server so they they
stored at least two private code signing
keys on this server and some hackers
were had broken in because the server is
connected to the Internet and they were
looking around and they found those
private code signing keys and they also
found the updates that asus had put
together and so what they did is they
just added the malware to the Aces
update they rescind it with the valid
legitimate key from aces and then what
happens that got pushed out to their
customers computers who thought that it
was a valid update because it was signed
with a valid key and it impacted about a
million computers worldwide so again you
can see that by not protecting these
keys you really open up a extreme risk
for
hackers dealing with your software
so the impact to Asus was lost revenue
you can see it in their stock price when
this came out they lost market share it
was a hit on their reputation because
now there their customers were saying
can we really trust what Asus puts out
and depending on you know who they serve
what what industries there might have
been some regulatory fines as well so
what are some of the other challenges
around code signing the next one is lack
of policy enforcement and I see this a
lot you know that I'll be talking to an
info SEC team and I'll ask them about
their codes on your policies and they'll
say oh we have a you know we we've got
very strict policies and you know we
don't women will have any concerns and
they'll show me a 30 page document that
describes that and then I'll ask the
question well how do you enforce it and
that's where things break down if they
don't have a way to enforce that with
the development teams then they don't
really have a policy they just have a
written document then there's also the
problem around global visibility you
know that if you're on an fo SEC team
that's responsible for the security of
your company and you have developers
spread around the world how do you know
what they're actually doing you know are
they following the policies that you put
in place are they using the right kinds
of code signing keys are they following
the right kinds of code signing policies
and practices you really need to have
that visibility if you don't that's
gonna mean that your company is at risk
for an incident happening like it did
was with the Ukrainian company or or
aces and then finally you have rogue
software development teams and I put
rogue here in in quotes but their focus
is not on security and their focus is on
getting updates out as quickly as
possible security is just something they
have to do and I know that you've
probably have heard this before so if
you have a policy in place that that
slows them down or it's inconvenient or
makes them do different things that they
aren't normally used to doing they're
gonna try to find ways to work around
this and we see this happening all the
time with with the companies that we
talk to
so what are the things that you can do
so I you know this sounds kind of sounds
kind of bleak but but there are some
some steps that you can take to make
this better
the first thing that you need to do is
think about co-signing as a process and
it's different from a TLS certificate or
another kind of PKI in that it's a
process that involves people so it's the
people that use it it involves things so
it's the certificate code signing
certificates the code Society in private
keys and it's the activities so it's
it's the build process it's the signing
process and if any one of these things
has has a failure or weakness then your
entire codes on your process is going to
be weak so think about trying to solve
this from a process perspective and it
needs to be a secure process so how can
you secure that process first and
foremost you need to have secure storage
so you know it is not acceptable to have
a private code signing key on someone's
laptop desktop machine a build server a
web server that's just going to cause
problems so those keys have to be stored
in a central location and that that
sounds obvious but the reason that it
doesn't happen is that when when we do
move those in to a central location then
it becomes inconvenient for developers
and then they go rogue and and they find
ways to get around it you next you need
to have the enterprise visibility so
even if you have development teams
around the world you really need to know
exactly who's signing code what
certificates were used where the private
keys at who did the signing who approved
the signing and that leads us to number
three here process control and and it's
really important especially for for code
signing credentials that are used to
sign very highly critical software that
your company produces or even software
that your company relies on is to know
who actually has access to use that key
under what circumstances can they use
that key who needs to approve the use of
that key if your process doesn't have a
couple of approvers that are required to
the approve the usage of code signing
key you got a broken process that's
that's gonna eventually lead to some
some pretty significant damage and then
when we talk about process we have to
think about automation has to be easy to
do
so if you require you know two approvers
to use every code signing key that needs
to be automated there needs to be a way
that people can actually follow your
policies through an automated fashion if
you require that every piece of internal
code that use gets code sign you have to
provide a very automated way of making
sure those kites code signing
certificates to get issued and and
eventually rotated and revoked and
finally you have to have intelligence
around what's going on in your company
you need to be able to show compliance
if you do have these code signing
policies that you know that everyone's
following them you need to have this
ability to be able to detect risky
trends let's go back to you know a
development team that uses an automated
build server and that build server signs
code once every day at 2 p.m. but if you
start noticing that certificate being
used at 2 a.m. that's a trend that then
indicates some risk it's out of the
ordinary and this all has to be done to
where it's developer friendly I just go
back to you know rogue software
development teams there if there's a way
for them to work around what what you
need to have done they will if it's not
easy for them so and when we talk about
it being easy for them and he needs to
not slow them down it needs to work with
their existing tools and processes and
it doesn't require for them to have PKI
experience because they they often do
not have that and the last thing I just
want to leave you with is if you wanted
to read more about best practices there
is this great piece from NIST
that's a security consideration it's for
code signing so if you wanted to look at
how you can improve the the code signing
situation at your company this this
article would definitely be helpful
there and I just want to thank you all
for your time this has been really nice
to be able to participate in this and
I'm happy to answer any questions
hey so this is about um if you want to
go into slack and go and connect there's
been some questions popping up if you
want to go and glance at those and maybe
have some conversations I'm going to
keep us on schedule or try to keep us on
schedule I know
I was I ran over a little bit and you
got started a little bit late so I was
trying to cut you off and let you have
all the time that you needed for your
presentation but I know it's important
to keep us on schedule so if you want to
go into slack and ask any some questions
and maybe give them some comments about
his presentation we really appreciate
you showing up today and getting up
early I'm presenting at besides Atlanta
it's very helpful and important to us
and we appreciate your time ok great
thank you you're right the first comment
here from Franco Sonia is not a panacea
particularly in the supply chain is
predominantly open source but this is
this is what you can use code signing
for it and in that particular situation
is that presumably your development
organization working with your
organization when they start to use open
source software they run it through
whatever tests and security tests that
that youth you deem is necessary and
required
and once you've deemed this particular
piece of open source software and it's
you know source code then sign it so
that you know that no one on your team
or in your organization can actually
modify that if they aren't supposed to
and so we have customers that are
signing you know multiple aspects you
know they're if they're getting source
code in from a third party they sign
that when they receive it after they run
it through their tests if they're using
libraries for third party after they run
their tests they sign it so that they
know it at no point does that get get
changed or modified by either a
malicious employee or a third party
that's broken into your network but yes
I agree it's it's not a not a solve all
but but definitely it can go a long way
to helping prevent the problem that
Maersk had and even a Zeus I mean a Zeus
is a great example where they just
literally did not protect their keys and
can I get the name of the article that
you recommend again it's I mentioned two
one was a NIST article on security
considerations then the other article
was from the SANS Institute about
code-signing security concerns but thank
you very much I know I am over now so if
you have other questions feel free to
reach out to me either through slack or
Twitter or or my email address okay
we appreciate it thank you