so hey everyone I'm Nico I'm gonna be
doing the talk from zero to red team
we're gonna be talking about what a red
team is and when we need one and when I
should put my computer in do you know
sister so the first thing we'll talk
about Oh hold on and let me share my
screen that's about me all right can you
guys see the presentation yes yep okay
great all right so a little about me
before we get started
Nico my name is Nico I'm on the red team
at Deloitte I'm based in San Diego
California
before coming to Deloitte I worked at
several companies Accenture PwC ResMed
an active network I'm also an adjunct
professor specializing in ethical
hacking and information assurance at
several universities here in San Diego I
got my undergraduate degree in political
science from UC San Diego and my grad
degree in information security from the
University of London is anybody who
knows me will tell you I hate coffee and
I much prefer Red Bull you can follow me
on twitter at eco Behar then my LinkedIn
address is at the bottom of the slide
here so first thing we need to do is we
need to map the attack surface and so in
order to do that we need to understand
what our assets are so in today's day
and age assets can come in a lot of
different shapes and sizes so I was
shown in the beautiful stock photograph
here we have phones laptops mice we can
have IOT devices we can have operational
technology devices medical devices we
can have ICS devices anything really
with an operating system or a network
connection can be considered an asset
and we first thing we have to do before
we actually go and form a red team or
Commissioner red team is we have to
determine our assets so first type of
asset we're going to look at our
hardware assets so there's a few
different types we have endpoints and in
that category we have laptops desktops
and terminals then we also have servers
in that category we have file servers
databases and hypervisors among others
then we have Network Devices which
include routers switches access points
firewalls and hubs we also have mobile
assets so smart phones tablets and
points of sale and then operational
technology or high-end IOT so any
network enabled devices any ICS devices
any sensors any medical devices and we
want to collect certain data points from
our Hardware assets so we'll want to
collect the serial number we'll want to
collect the model number we'll want to
look at the manufacturer we'll want to
look at the warranty and the hardware
specifications this is important because
different Hardware types can have unique
vulnerabilities like firmware
vulnerabilities architecture
vulnerabilities and hardware
vulnerabilities next we want to look at
software assets so there's several
different types of software that we want
to look at first we'll want to look at
operating systems so for example Unix
Linux Microsoft Mac Android iOS among
others then we have productivity
software so we're talking about word
processors spreadsheet software slide
deck software any email clients any
calendar software another type of
software is a driver and that's a piece
of software that allows the operating
system to interact with the hardware own
host then we have other third-party
software so video editing software CAD
software
visual design software any data
visualization software any IDE etc so
what kind of data do we want to collect
about these assets while we want to
collect first application name then the
version number who's the vendor of the
application is the application supported
right so a little side story here I was
recently at a client and they were
running a patching system that was not
supported for the past three years and
could not patch Windows 10 so it's very
important to find out if the software
that you're running is supported and
updates are still provided for it
we also want to look at any dependencies
so maybe it has some library the
software will have some libraries that
it runs on or some codecs that need to
be installed so we want to make sure
we're looking at those as well and the
reason that this matters is because
different applications can introduce
various vulnerabilities in different
parts of the application or the
underlying libraries runtimes or
dependencies and those are all that are
just the two different types and now
let's put it together
so now we can see which vulnerabilities
are in the environment so the hardware
asset information will help monitor for
vulnerabilities that affect the hardware
and equipment in the environment the
software asset information is going to
help monitor for vulnerabilities that
affect applications running in the
environment so now we can look at vendor
advisories to see if there's any
vulnerabilities that have been disclosed
we can do the same with mailing lists we
can look at community forums and
discussion boards and we can look at any
update feeds for many of our security
products that we have so this matters
because monitoring the environment and
the appropriate information sources
allows for identification and analysis
of new vulnerabilities that are present
in the environment and in step zero on
our journey to a red team all right
so now we'll look at the next step which
is vulnerability management so some
objectives and activities we're going to
scan assets for vulnerabilities and
misconfigurations
so we can do this with a commercial
solution like necess or we can use an
open source solution like open bass or
we can build our own solution we want to
make sure that we're monitoring and
analyzing threats and vulnerabilities
reported in real time to respond to
security incidents right so we want to
look at any threats new threats and new
vulnerabilities that are being released
through whatever mechanisms were using
to get those whether that be a threat
intelligence feed or through community
intelligent sharing network we want to
make sure that we're using that
information to respond to security
incidents that may present themselves in
our environment we want to make sure
that we're maintaining our scanning
tools and we're reviewing the latest
rules and configurations that are to be
used we want to make sure that they line
up with our environment and that they're
not going to take anything down we also
want to use the software asset
information to help monitor for
vulnerabilities that affect applications
that are running in our environment so
we're doing this but how do we actually
determine if we're performing as we
should be well first thing we want to do
is we want to consider the risk and
prioritize the activity so this is very
important because every organization is
different and so every organization's
risk is going to be different so they're
going to be measuring and differently
and they're going to be looking at
different vulnerabilities because every
organization has different unique risks
that are posed to them and so they
should approach that appropriately after
we've considered the risk and prioritize
the activity we can also look at the
percentage of organizationally deemed
critical systems scan per quarter so of
the systems that are the most
to us so for example let's say we have a
bottling company somebody that bottle
soda right one of their most critical
systems would be the system that runs
the the bottling machine the one that
actually files the bottles through the
factory and they get filled with this
soda right so that's gonna be a very
that's going to be a critical system so
how many of the systems with that
criticality that are very very important
throughout the organization have been
examined this quarter another metric we
can look at to see how we're doing is we
can look at the number of
vulnerabilities that have been
enumerated we can also look at the
percentage of systems with no known
severe vulnerabilities we can look at
the percentage of detected
vulnerabilities associated with accepted
risks or non-technical controls so what
we mean by accepted risks is that
sometimes we can get a if we're not able
to patch a vulnerability we can get a
risk exception and then they'll and the
risk is then accepted and they will
allow us to forego applying or that
update or remediating that vulnerability
because somebody has accepted the risk
now we can also another metric we can
look at the percentage of
vulnerabilities associated with known
patches or fixes and how many how many
of those vulnerabilities have been
actually remediated and how many are
still in the environment waiting to be
remediated with the patch available so
the reason that a vulnerability
management matters is because monitoring
our environment and the appropriate
information sources will allow us to
efficiently identify and address new
vulnerabilities that are present in our
environment and this is going to be
considered step one on our journey to a
red team
all right so next we have penetration
testing and this is where we're actually
going to exploit the vulnerabilities so
oftentimes it can start out with a set
of formal documents right and so for
example it could have a statement of
work and a rules of engagement and the
rules of engagement is going to say what
we can and cannot do so we'll oftentimes
refer to the rules of engagement
document to see if something's in scope
so before we start a penetration test
we're gonna look at all the systems for
going to sit down with the client and
we're going to determine the scope and
we're gonna determine their pools of
engagement so they can say okay you can
only test between one time I had it
where it was you can only test between
4:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m. so you have to
be on-site only between 4:00 p.m. and
2:00 a.m. right and so if that's what
the rules of engagement say then that's
the time that you're going to be testing
penetration tests also allow an
organization to discover potential
weaknesses in their environment because
the key difference here between the
penetration tests and the vulnerability
assessment is that in a penetration test
are actually exploiting the
vulnerability whereas in the
vulnerability assessment we're just
checking to see if the vulnerability is
present now that's not to say that we
could potentially exploit it there but
the key difference between the
penetration test and the vulnerability
assessment it's the active exploitation
of vulnerabilities and so this gives us
an opportunity to test our security
controls are the controls that are
looking for exploitation going to detect
that exploitation or are they going to
fail and not be able to detect that
exploitation the penetration test is
ideally going to be a blackbox test that
ideally would be performed by a third
party in order to get an independent
perspective and it can oftentimes be
compliance driven as we know a lot of
regulations like HIPAA Sox among others
they require penetration tests to be
carried out I think every year or
multiple times per year depending on the
regulation
and the security team so oftentimes
gonna know that the penetration test is
going on so how do we measure our
performance in one or conducting
penetration tests how do we know that
they're helping our organization become
more secure well how many
vulnerabilities have we picked up right
did we pick up all the vulnerabilities
that were picked up in the vulnerability
assessment base are we able to identify
the main root cause that can address a
lot of the findings that the penetration
test has brought to light so if we have
a lot of MIS configuration do we know
why everything is misconfigured are we
able to address that so we can fix it if
we have something that's not updated do
we know why it's not updated are we
going to be able to identify the root
cause and then go and fix it and so the
reason that penetration testing matters
is because monitoring it and testing it
is actually going to allow us to see if
we can test our controls and see if we
can actually exploit the vulnerabilities
and it's step two on our journey to the
red tape so now let's get to Red Team
operations and one of the main goals of
teams operations is to look at the
organizational blind box so we're going
to assess the effectiveness of the
organization's cybersecurity program
from a holistic standpoint to include
the monitoring and response capabilities
so the testing is performed and via
tailored scenarios looking at an
organization as a sum of its parts so
we're taking into account physical human
and cyber as well as from the point of
view of a determined attacker so these
are oftentimes the different aspects
that we're going to look at when we're
doing a Red Team engagement right so we
can look at physical entry we can look
at physical access mechanisms access
control mechanisms or also definitely
going to look at the human element right
and a lot of the times we're going to
engage in phishing
all right so I promise pretty pictures
so here come to pick pretty pictures all
right so the bottom line with red
teaming right so real quick some points
of reference based on our client
experience so six days is the average
time to achieve a set objective after
the reconnaissance phase 94% of our
clients we're successfully compromised
during the red teaming engagement 70% of
our clients had very limited
capabilities in detecting or responding
to the breach of their system and their
crown jewels and one day is on average
the time to compromise the first device
and gain initial access to the clients
network after the reconnaissance face so
when we talk about adversarial
simulation or red teaming we're talking
about a realistic approach to security
testing right because we're emulating
our adversaries so it's going to enable
an organization to assess their overall
readiness resiliency and awareness using
a realistic scenario based controlled
events adversarial simulations offerings
go above and beyond for 'nor ability
assessments and penetration testing as
it incorporates all components within
the organization in scope and has a
realistic scenario based approach but
ultimately red team operations allow
organizations to mature their cyber
capabilities and kickstart
transformation programs so as we talked
about on the last slide there's three
core elements that we consider when
we're doing red teaming so the first
thing we're gonna look at is we're gonna
look at physical so we're gonna look at
your buildings we're gonna look at your
desks we're gonna look at the safes
right and we're gonna look at any
physical IT infrastructure the amount of
passwords that I have found on people's
desks I've lost track people leaving
their drawers on lock right a whole
bunch of stuff going on in the physical
element then we have human helmet right
so that represents the employees or
customers the
clients or third parties that bind the
cyber in the physical world together
right so people will oftentimes hold the
door open for you or if you ask them
questions they will give you the answer
even if they're not supposed to right
then we have cyber that represents the
online world the Internet as well as
corporate internets right any cloud
services right and all other computer
networks and devices so some use cases
for adversary simulation right so the
first example we can look at is source
code exfiltration so somebody might
bring in a red team to do source code
exfiltration so they can test from both
a trusted insider and an external threat
agent perspective right so we're going
to do so for example we could do
reconnaissance and find the exposed
repository or we could find it on the
Internet
then after that we could exfiltrate the
code we could also test developer
workstations and develop and deployment
workflows like Jenkins to create target
packages for spearfishing developers
right we could X well we could export
rate through physical means such as USB
another use case would be customer data
exfiltration we could identify where the
technology stores customer data where
the website and CRM the databases the
workstations the software as service
applications and the client services
data is stored then we can test
different exfiltration vectors both
overt and covert and depending on what
we find during the reconnaissance phase
and we can also leverage targeting data
supplied by our reconnaissance phase to
attack eternally facing weaknesses and
misconfigurations we could also
go after a manufacturing and logistics
system first we would identify critical
manufacturing and logistic systems then
we would conduct physical and wireless
security testing at manufacturing plants
then we would test system segmentation
move laterally throughout the network
and then we would test any hardware and
firmware and maybe do some source code
review we can also look at remote update
mechanisms for customer systems right so
we've done a few of those we can test
the authentication mechanisms and we can
see if we can bypass them we can test
the impact of an insider threat to
clients so this is one that I was lucky
enough to have just done unfortunately
it was cancelled but we were doing an
insider threat emulation at a point
where we had to break out of a Citrix
environment we were successful until the
corona virus came along also code
signing services another example so the
first thing we would try to do is
identify key individuals in appropriate
business units and craft targeted spear
phishing emails after they click the
link hopefully we're going to elevate
access to the point that it's possible
to sign malicious code and the final use
case is product or technology testing so
one example would be testing the data
synchronization mechanisms and the
protocol between the company network and
their air-gapped recovery system we
could also test the recovery procedure
and verify the integrity and the
recovery system can't be affected when
performing those procedures so some
benefits of adversarial simulation or
event timing well we're gonna have
extensive technology coverage right so
we're going to test the traditional
attack surface right so network
application and wireless but then we're
also going to look at
non-traditional technologies like ICS
SCADA we can do cloud we can do mobile
we're definitely going to incorporate
threat intelligence we're going to use
multiple threat intelligence sources to
provide insight based on threat sources
so we're going to emulate the threats
that may actually pertain to you so if
you're doing business in China or if
you're business that's heavily relying
on China we could choose to emulate the
TTP's of known Chinese actors we can
test the process effectiveness not just
the technical symptoms right so since we
have a much larger scope we can actually
go and test the entire process right now
we can tie it back to a cybersecurity
process we can recognize that threats
don't respect boundaries right because
during remember I talked about the
penetration test we had the rules of
engagement we do have rules when we're
doing Red Team operations but they're
not there aren't as many rules so we can
more closely emulate a real-world
adversary by reducing the amount of
boundaries that we have to subject
ourselves to we're also going to address
the human factor of cybersecurity right
a lot of penetration tests and
vulnerability assessments aren't going
to assess the human factor but in Red
Team operations advance address or
simulation we're making sure to address
the human factor of cybersecurity we're
going to do social engineering we're
gonna do insider threat and we're going
to do phishing you can also look at
automation and integration between tools
we can look at the alignment to actual
emerging cyber threats not just
compliance requirements so we'll make
sure that we're testing we're testing
systems based on threats that could
actually be posed to them we're not just
going through and doing the OWASP top 10
or the CIS top 20 we're actually going
to look at the environment and see what
is possible in the environment and try
to craft something that is unique
would successfully result in
accomplishing one of our objectives also
we can provide business awareness and
insight because we're going above and
beyond the difficult penetration tests
we're getting to know the different
business processes the different
functions and therefore we can test the
integration between business and IT all
right so I promise maturity model so
here we go so adversarial simulation
uses multiple testing techniques to
achieve value so we're gonna focus on
performing realistic cyber threat based
testing activities with actionable and
value-added results and resulting in
improvements to the client's
capabilities to protect against detect
and respond to cyber attacks so here is
the Red Team maturity model so on the
bottom on the x-axis we have actually
slide to the right the organizational
maturity and the capability to action on
results that they get from one of the
three steps is going to increase on the
y-axis as we move up the y-axis the
analysis and complexity of the test and
the environment are going to go up so we
can see in the first step we have ulnar
ability assessments so here before we
move to the next step we want to make
sure we're doing automated and
vulnerability scans that we have
configuration analysis so we're making
sure everything is configured correctly
and it stays configured correctly we
want to make sure we're integrated with
security operations so everything that
we're doing in a vault in the
vulnerability assessment base and
looking at configuration management
doing all that should be integrated
security operations we should also be
conducting code analysis if we're
writing any software and in addition we
should be manually verifying our the
existence of our vulnerabilities
then once we move to step two we should
be performing manual exploitation
analysis right we should be validating
the existence of our exploits if we have
wireless networks we should be engaging
in wireless security assessments which
would be beginning to venture down the
path of physical and social attack
vectors we should also be looking at
business risk integration in the second
phase and we should also be testing our
detection and response now once we move
into advanced adversary simulation or
red team operations those are going to
be tailored threat driven testing for
your organization
we're going to integrate in the cyber
human and physical aspects of
information security and we're going to
have multiple feedback mechanisms and
integrations with key stakeholders to
make sure to keep them in the loop and
to demonstrate that we're adding value
we're also going to perform deep
exploitation and exfiltration analysis
now when we're ready for a red team
we're going to have scenario based
analysis right so one of the things that
sets red teaming apart is that it's
scenario based so somebody can say hey
ok let's say a soda company comes and
hires to you the soda company it's not
going to come and tell you hey go get
domain admin they're gonna tell you ok
go steal the secret formula for secret
soda pop and also turn the bottling
machine off without anybody noticing so
they'll give they'll give objective and
scenario based that's how that's how the
results are based we want to have
objective and scenario based outcomes
we're also going to start involving our
blue team once we get into the red team
operations maturity level we're going to
want to as I said before engage in
threat actor profiling and emulation so
if your business if your business or
your organization has a lot of exposure
to Russia then we could be asked to
emulate
rushon apt we're also going to do
exfiltration analysis we're gonna see if
you're going to catch us stealing your
stuff so if you're able to see us
stealing your stuff then great and then
if not that's something that is going to
be worked on during this phase of
maturity right that's something we're
gonna be working on since we already
have all of the other stuff in other two
phases like vulnerability scans basic
physical and social attacks exploiting
vulnerabilities that's all in previous
phases we want to be engaging in cyber
war games we want to make sure and we
also want to make sure that we have
consistent and sustained operations that
is the highest level of maturity when
we're doing all of this consistent in a
consistent and sustained fashion so
that's it if you guys have questions I
can take a few I don't know if we have
time to do it here or I can just do it
in slack
I'll go ahead and take a question you
actually I mean we're behind but you
actually kind of kicked us back in okay
yeah I mean anything but if you want to
go into flack
connect the track net on see if there's
oh somebody SP we're sharing your slides
and I don't think they meant like during
this talk I think maybe after so you can
yeah you can reach out to me and I'll
let you know where you can get a copy
they'll be distributed eventually all
right cool
well Nico we appreciate your time today
I know you got up early um so thanks for
doing that and hopefully next time this
all be in person yep thanks thank you