I'm going to put this up and give them
all the credit in the world because this
would not be possible without them and
so especially you know when we think
about the fact that with less than two
weeks notice we decided to go from from
physical to to virtual and so I want to
recognize all of our sponsors 100% of
whom who stayed with us even after we
decided to go virtual so with topple
star I mean Warner media at the Gold
level my home department in my home
college my home department the Kennesaw
State University Department of
Information Systems that is in the
Michael J Cole's College of Business
have stayed with us and have been great
to work with additionally we have Bishop
Fox coal fire genuine parts and NCR at
the crystal level crystal crystal paths
are critical paths and synopsis at the
Silver level errands and you may have
just heard from a couple of their
employees maybe not I don't know I don't
know if they were here in official
capacity or not but allegedly they might
know something about Aaron's next binary
defense we also have Black Hills
information security core alight and
guide point security at the bronze level
we want to thank NCC group for coming in
to help us at that level I also want to
acknowledge some in-kind sponsors
ec-council ransom paid training force
yesterday and some of you took advantage
of that and I've heard really good
things about that yesterday also want to
take a moment to acknowledge a secure
code warrior they stood up and are
conducting I think until four o'clock a
CTF
over in the CTF channel and so that's
been going like gangbusters all day long
a lot of traffic in the slack channel
for that we'd also like to thank the
following individuals and organizations
we're contributing to our raffle prize
effort I want to thank Mike Acosta with
crosshair information technology we want
to thank Joe gray we also want to thank
the good folks at all
sense of security and we also want to
thank the pen tester lab for all of the
things that they contributed to allow us
to have a great giveaway program that's
going on all day if you haven't done it
yet we are a virtual conference and for
the first time ever for us and we have
created a map that would allow you to
drop a pen minute to let us know where
you are
and if you haven't done that already
I've just posted a link to be able to do
that in the channel please take a minute
and drop a pen we are truly if that data
that's in the map is accurate we are
truly global I saw somebody check in
from Australia I've seen some folks
check in from Germany from the EU Greece
you know it's it's just amazing to see
all these folks I also mentioned I did
mention a minute ago that we've got
those giveaways and prizes to check that
out I'm posting the link to the channel
they're here in our Channel you got to
register to win and so for those of you
who are privacy adverse if you want to
win you got to give us real details
unfortunately so we need a real email
address a real telephone number real
mailing ID just to make sure we can get
you whatever it is you win so make sure
that you give us everything there what
somebody just put in Oh face it okay so
you know we've had a lot of good talks
all day long today and some of you been
asking well you know what if I miss one
how can I go about finding it well we're
recording all of them and we are having
them processed by a by a post-production
company
and once they are all processed and
chopped up in radio because we've been
recording all day long and big blocks
once they are chopped up and ready to go
they will be posted in our YouTube
channel and I am posting a link to the
YouTube channel
in our channel here if you would you'll
give us a follow on YouTube because when
we get to 100 or more followers we get
to change to a fancy fancy vanity URL
which will be which would be good for us
it is now a little after 3:30 sorry Jake
I took two minutes of your time so I'm
gonna stop yapping and please allow me
to introduce Jake Williams our next
speaker Jake will be talking about
cybersecurity merger and acquisition due
diligence so let me stop sharing my
screen so that Jake can share his screen
Jake it is all yours buddy take it away
so um well go through over the next half
an hour it's actually less than half an
hour 25 minutes here we're gonna walk
through basically what is cyber security
emanate your diligence why do we do it
how do we do it
and give you a couple of case studies
and then we'll be a wee rock and roll
and so that said let's get in Who am I
I'm not going to belabor this too much
either you know me or you don't and you
can go back and find this anyway I work
with renditions InfoSec out of Augusta
Georgia right down the road from Atlanta
although now that this is a virtual
conference you know we're gonna wear a
international firm we actually have
people permanently in other countries
and you know their countries outside of
the US so boutique information security
consulting firm do a lot of this merger
and acquisition due diligence and want
to basically want to share some of our
experiences with that and why it's
important get your thinking about it as
a possible activity that you may either
want to engage in yourself or engaging
yourselves or certainly at least think
about bringing somebody in to do so
agenda why it matters what are the
techniques for it what are the
challenges around it and Oh buddy are
there some challenges and then we'll
wrap it up basically wrap it up for the
day so you know we talk about why does
cybersecurity due-diligence matter and
I'm not going to not gonna kick somebody
while they're down certainly you know
with the Cova 19 scare you know the
hotel industry has been taking a beating
and Marriott is definitely my case study
here right you may remember last year
Marriott announced a breach and the
breach itself came from Starwood
Starwood is a Sheraton and a bunch of
other brands that Marriott bought and
they literally bought a breach that they
brought on the liabilities with those
assets
right and so we talk about why does
cybersecurity do the due diligence
manner because when an organization's
acquired all the assets get transferred
but of course so do the liabilities and
if you think about how normal due
diligence works and normal M&A due
diligence taking cybersecurity out of it
nobody goes through and buys you don't
like look at paper and they're like we
attest that we have the following number
of buildings and the following state of
these buildings etc nobody does that
that's just ridiculous right and so when
we step back I mean they always send
auditors out to like look at the
condition of the buildings to look at
the physical stock if you're buying a
I'm buying a warehouse for instance
right what is the actual stock on hand
right are the factories in shape if
you're manufacturing massive upgrades
and for some reason the state of
organizations cyber security posture
isn't given the same level of attention
even though we know now as CCPA I'm the
California consumer Privacy Act GDP are
numerous regulate you know basically on
numerous regulations around data and
data security certainly has huge
liabilities there not to mention the
brand damage that can come from
literally buying a breach right so so
this obviously matters a lot of it is
really you know propping that bow or
communicating that value proposition to
chief council chief risk officers right
typically the co-starring chief ops
officer CEOs etc they listen to your
chief risk officers which are typically
attorneys typically lawyers right and
those chief risk officers will
absolutely tell you they don't want to
be involved in something like this and
they'll explain the risk very well it's
a matter of you getting with a CRO to
get it going so what's one of the big
problems that run into heterogeneous
networks every M&A almost every M&A last
two decades has involved heterogeneous
technologies what Active Directory
version are you want and if you can't
answer this question by the way this is
a big one right are you on a functional
level 2008 r2 domain I can't tell you
how often folks come back yeah our
domain controllers are Server 2016 and
I'm like that's not which ad version
Your Honor I think you're telling me
that the version of your server it's
almost like saying which version SSH are
you running right and you're like yeah
I'm on RedHat right well those two
things are both technical terms but they
don't actually mean anything together in
context right
which linux builds do you have do you
have a bunch of Engineers that know
Ubuntu and the other organizations are
acquiring is all red hat which
workstation versions right
what about VPN and remote access
technologies Oh buddy has this been an
issue recently right and we have a lot
of this stuff that isn't considered
pre-acquisition and and we don't look at
how is the newly acquired network going
to be secured in moderate right you may
not be able to and I'll give you a great
example here I'm not pooping on any
vendors I want to be super clear about
that I absolutely not do it I mean maybe
Oracle right but other than Oracle we're
not gonna like beat up on any vendors
right
Oracle deserves it by the way but anyway
let's say you've got CrowdStrike
right and CrowdStrike you know is you're
chosen at big co-write the acquiring
company or that's your chosen EDR right
and crowd starts your josy CrowdStrike
doesn't run on pretty Windows seven
right because it relies on dotnet and if
you've got a bunch of technologies
legacy technologies in your to be
acquired Network obviously we need to
secure those and we need to monitor
those and simultaneously my chosen tool
right can't do it and so this obviously
something I need to consider how I'm
going to how I'm going to bring that
together and how I'm gonna secure if
we're on backdated active directory
versions I can't just join our domains
together right maybe there's a reason
you're on functional level 2008 domain
even though ours is functional level
2016 I may not be it's not as trivial as
as folks like to make it seem so
techniques for cyber security M&A cyber
security M&A do diligence how do we do
it right obviously this is a problem I
had everybody convinced here because it
was easy this is what you do you do
cyber security you don't want to see
this you know see this all fall apart
especially because it's gonna be your
job to go clean it up right I don't
remember who the actual live person is
behind the df' our dfi our janitor
account on twitter but i love a train
dfi are being digital forensics and it's
a response and they refer themselves as
a janitor and I absolutely love it
because we are the ones that end up
cleaning the pile poo when poop hits the
fan all right so we want to make sure
that this doesn't this isn't an issue
that we run into now M&A threat hunting
is different than traditional throughout
hunting in literally every way
traditional throw who uses AI
season baseline deviations and my
friends I am here to tell you that
baselining takes time and it isn't easy
and if you ever try to deploy UVA or
you'ii be a software user environment
baseline analytics or sorry behavior
analytics with minimal false positives
you know this can't be done right
there's no such thing as minimal false
positives of this there's less false
positives but was less mean right
minimal okay right doesn't happen
baselines are hard to generate under the
best of circumstances but the reality is
that when I'm hopping in to a network
where I'm trying to temporarily monitor
and temporarily threat hunt around this
network it's just not gonna happen then
I'm gonna be able to go generate these
baselines or I would love to do it I
just can't right secondarily I need in
order to hunt I'm gonna usually need to
go deploy software like endpoint agents
sorry and then I need a central server
or any firewall rules to allow these
communications this is not something
that's trivial to accomplish right again
super trivial when you build it out as
part of a larger program I said super
trivial then this thing is trivial
threat hunting but it's easier when you
build it as part of a larger program but
doing it temporarily right for the
purpose of evaluating risk in this
network to be purchased maybe right it
is a super difficult challenge right so
again we lack baselines we lack systems
for hunting iOS C's on endpoints IOC
scanning systems aren't easy to deploy
we could try to build baselines but that
gets cost prohibitive these are
pre-purchase investigations this is
trying to determine do we actually want
to complete the sale now usually they've
already determined a price or at least a
tentative price but but again there's
not a big interest undertaking huge
cybersecurity projects just to determine
whether or not that valuation that price
of the organization holds and so what
about tooling right you cannot count on
the organization's having their own
drawing typically M&A is you have a big
Co trying to purchase small Co and and
by the way there's another third party
here called spin Co because very often
when big Co by small Co they're buying
it for a specific piece in spinning off
the rest it is something that they have
evaluated that is of interest to them
and the rest of it Jenner interesting or
profitable to them the rest is generally
not there to spin that off and so this
is another place where I can't count on
this smaller Co having its own cooling
even then
I may be asked to look at very specific
areas of the network
ideally remain code right so it's a
small code the piece of it that's
remaining versus pin code they don't
really care so much about right because
literally they're going to buy a either
buy it and spin-off the chunk or only
buy the chunk of it as it's being spa
right getting buy-in for installing
agent based products is problematic and
honestly most vendors don't license
their stuff for this anyway right so
even going to a lot of your vendors to
be like hey I I need to buy ten thousand
agents or a thousand agents and even for
thirty days and don't look at you like
you're nuts you're absent I'm buying it
like that the vendors that will work
with you typically it's cost prohibitive
it's not very flexible right so this is
this is very difficult it's gonna rely
on my tooling because I can't count on I
really can't count on the organization
having their own so what do we do take
nothing else away from this talk these
are the techniques that we use right and
at a very high level and I'm short on
time so we're not gonna be able to dive
into each one of these in like super
detail all right but I'll walk through
and these slides are gonna be available
afterwards and good right so we're gonna
start by reviewing security practices I
want to know at a minimum what do you
have on paper how do you work
is there a SEM and if not how our logs
monitor if you tell me that your system
admins are going to reviewing logs for
security events I'm calling baloney
the first thing I want to do ain't
calling baloney depending where you come
from north or south sometimes that's
calling shenanigans whatever right
bottom line I'm calling shenanigans I
want to know how are your logs being
monitored right and if you tell me your
system admins are tell me their system
admins are monitoring those logs they
were doing log review no problem right I
pull a couple of system admins in the
room do some interviews and I just asked
what are you looking for in the logs and
usually I hear words like hackers and
I'm like what does a hacker look like I
want you to tell it to me like you tell
it to my mom all right
my mom is horrible attacks you can bring
a phone from 30 feet just by looking at
it that's the level of explanation I
want system admins generally can't
provide it this is not a knock on them
but it does help us evaluate the truth
of the statements right when they say
yes we have a log review program I'm
able to go back to my constituent and
say this is what that really meant right
we reviewed their log review program and
Wow
does it hurt right we want to know about
oddball unit
Cicero's because these are huge support
issues if you've gots coordinate all
right legacy systems again a lot of my
security platforms cannot run on these
legacy systems so simultaneously my most
vulnerable the population right the most
vulnerable things in the population
unfortunately we can't get good
monitoring across attackers know this
they will spend their time embedding
themselves there and as a result you
need to spend time hunting their network
traffic after an IDs right you need to
install Network apps and collect network
traffic run an IDs done right I'm not
gonna spend too much time on this
because there's not that much about it
but you're gonna have to bring your own
taps period because almost nobody has
them at these smaller company levels
never traffic capture I don't wanna
identify unmanaged endpoints the
environment I want to look at
business-to-business VPNs they are a
huge source of risk for organizations
the big takeaway here
go grab Andy Andy Greenberg wrote a
great book called sandworm go get a copy
of it it's freaking awesome and he walks
through the not Pecha attacks and
sandworms and learns about a lot more
than not Pecha but it's outstanding
outstanding talk there and he even
touches on the business-to-business VPN
side because that is a huge part of how
not Pecha spread for those b2b VPNs then
we do vulnerability scanning and i want
to do some of my own bone scans right i
want to see what's what we're looking at
here what is the overall security
posture of the network right now there's
a lot of the there's a lot of extra
stuff that we can do here there's a lot
of additional things that we can do for
instance looking to see even if
something's fully patched today i can do
some quick forensics and it's super
quick forensics because they have the
tooling port on host to tell when did
you get serious about patching because i
want to know if you just threw a new
coat of paint right or forgive the term
here lipstick on a pig right i need to
know that because that's gonna tell me i
see a question the chat there it's andy
greenberg sandworm is the name of the
book hit it on amazon anyway we want to
know if somebody just put lipstick on a
pig and kept rolling right on so a
triple threat hunting this is another
thing that we do look i can't touch all
the hosts here i don't have that kind of
time it's not a regular threat hunting
ever
and so threat honey is easiest to start
with on the network and that's gonna
help me vector into where to go collect
endpoint data now there are some
high-value targets we collect endpoint
data from anyway memory forensics is the
tip top end of that to go hunt down
those memory residence rats alright so
you can think about this like the base
of a pyramid or network threat coming
across everything we are then moving an
endpoint data on a very limited number
of hosts and then memory forensics on
onesie twosie
right bad that kind of thing so again
start with a network move up the stack
moving for residual risk from breaches a
huge percent of breaches repeat after me
breaches are not completely remediated
routinely horrible horrible horrible
right so threat hunting what I want to
look at here is one I want to identify
residual malware but I also want to go
in and look at the regulatory liability
for improperly recorded breaches this is
a huge one for us because we have seen
repeatedly or an organization either out
of ignorance or malice does not report a
breach to the appropriate regulatory
authorities and guess what when you buy
that organization you bought that
liability too and if they forgot to
report or didn't report or whatever
right you now are stuck with it you need
to go review that yourself and determine
with your chief counsel do you think
this needs to be done is this something
that hadn't have been reported to the
regulatory authority that's something
it's absolutely critical to understand
so Sakho an M&A challenges right look
the organization under evaluation they
have an incentive to be less than
completely forthcoming about their cyber
hygiene now by law they absolutely have
to write in the agreements they
absolutely have to communicate clearly
with you but oh brother the people
filling out those pay phone out that M&A
paperwork they are being truthful to the
best of their knowledge I'm air quoting
here right I'll tell you that what
appears to be deceived in most cases an
extension of existing communication
problems between line workers and
management right if you go into any
organization today forget one that's
under M&A any organization today and you
ask management how their cybersecurity
about good and then you go to your
practitioners right how's your cyber
skirt like horrible kind of thing right
they know where the bodies are buried go
talk to your text right I'll tell you
another thing is that a lot of folks
reduced
prior to M&A they try to basically
adjust their profit wash sheet and what
they'll do here is I'll try to cut cost
that comes in the form of software it
comes to the form of services comes in
the form of staff and again at the end
of the day the results here are
predictable InfoSec and ITR cost centers
not profit centers and you can run with
technical debt for a while whatever a
while is before it catches up to you you
want to know if that's been done you
want to understand the impact of that
poor asset inventory another big issue
here all organizations not just M&A have
issues asset inventory but I will tell
you this is a big one for us there's
another reason that we bring in those
Network caps and start looking
east-west I don't just want to scan
endpoints and subnets identified by IT I
want to go find my own and we do a lot
of router config review we do a lot of
firewall configuration review this helps
us find other subnets we do a lot of
passive traffic monitoring those network
taps and again we have to bring our own
now if you're thinking like hey this is
an easy thing to get going I can tell
you that we have in calculus of money a
rendition tied up in property that is at
different network caps and pivot boxes
and servers that we can send you can't
send somebody a half rack of equipment
and be like hey find power space and
cooling for this you have to find
portable equipment as well as have your
own taps and your software licenses and
it is just maddening the amount of money
you have to put into this on the front
end so I just want to throw out here
like on the poor asset inventory side it
is really hard to get this done in the
best of times it is crazy hard to do
this when you're trying to drop or
perish it into an organization and do it
for a very temporary time and then
network visibility right again is huge
for us we don't have you know a V or
endpoint protection systems in some
cases or it's just antivirus knows we
don't have a good SEM with our net flow
we got EDR this can be super super
difficult to get over right again we
need to come in and figure out how we
can enable the organization or enable us
in the context of the organization to
threat hunt around those merger and
acquisition pieces right so again that
the bad news my friends is you end up
having to bring your own beer of the
barbecue right this is a this really is
if you want to do this right and you can
do this without doing all right don't
get me wrong you can still do a little
bit of work but to get the best value
out of this
you're gonna have to bring your own
tools and to bring your own licenses
your hardware etc and there's a lot of
considerations that are different again
like I mentioned you know if I'm
deploying to an organization normally
I'm bringing a rack you know basically
rack mounting units here right I'm doing
this I can't bring rack Mountain units
right I have to bring things that are
easy on power space and cooling I have
to bring network apps you know again all
kinds of stuff that you would think an
organization might already have that
they do not I just I'll just throw it
out there you can't count on having it
that that's probably the big one for us
is achieving that visibility enough so
that we can provide in the state of the
network back to our constituent so war
stories right let's get some war stories
going here right Michael Bay moments for
the win this one was awesome all right
this is that we forgot about the VMS
right not the BMS I had multiple
analysts correct me air quotes correct
me on the report right where they're
like hey if you could stop capitalizing
S&V ends that would be awesome I'm like
it would be but I'm not talking about
VMs I'm talking about freaking VMs and
if you don't know what VMs is you are in
good company because a lot of analysts
today don't either
this is literally like backing up into
the wayback machine right I see some
comments there Lola Wolvie MS exactly
right so our scanning scope is limited
due to ICS devices this is a huge one
this is a big ICS network we only found
this due to on-site interviews and data
center business I literally walked into
a data center and there were yes Andy we
are absolutely officially old there is
no question there no question right so I
walk in and there's an alpha server
actually to alpha servers sitting one of
them has the lid off of it I'm sitting
in the corner of this data center and
I'm like oh hey guys you know not too
good at taking the trash out they're
like oh that's our parts server right
parts server right and it used to be and
I kid you not
it used to be their staging server and
now they only have a dev and a prod they
no longer have a staging server because
they can't get parts for these and they
literally have to pull the staging
server out of production right so this
is huge by the way right VMs does not
run an emulator as a VM not not the way
they needed to run my friend
unfortunately right so the organization
repeatedly tried to move off the legacy
EMS servers they failed each time right
this is actually in an alpha you talk
about an emulator we're talking about
alpha chip here right so this if you
don't know what alpha is drop back it's
Dec alpha they had failed multiple times
here seven million dollar expense right
over three failed attempts you'd better
believe a hundred percent this is a risk
to the organization was not disclosed
I'm just gonna tell you this is yeah
somebody's like this YC nineties
motherboard selling for dollars on eBay
heck yes right absolutely
saga the BBB VPNs initially I was told
there were none none eventually we found
or quickly found five always-on VPNs
with no filtering wide-open right and
I'm not gonna say target here but I am
alright target you may remember right
was a supply chain attack that the
target compromised came in through the
basic came in through an HVAC vendor
huge problem here once but mara and his
VPN connections it was clear the
confidential data was being
systematically siphoned from the
organization's ERP system from a remote
site right this is a huge huge issue no
threat hunting alone I want to be clear
if I go to IOC sweeps I don't find this
right we only found this because we're
doing good network monitoring again I'm
not saying that you only do threat honey
or only do network monitoring this is a
you have to do it all you have to bring
a lot of stuff together here it's not
easy it's not always cheap but man do we
I can tell you consistently we save
organizations more in there I will tell
you consistently we save organizations
way more their valuation than the cost
of the actual assessment by the way the
cost of the assessment is borne by
typically borne by the company to be
acquired and if they have made material
misrepresentations in their material
misrepresentations in their basically
their questionnaires and their
disclosures typically you know there's
no refund around if the organization
decides to pull out so this is a
no-brainer for big co if you structure
this correctly it's free to you and only
reduces the value right my final one
here is the sure we were mediated very
intake the org said they experienced one
major instant ransomware in the previous
36 month 36 months and I went in and did
on-site interviews the staff and by the
way if you don't know how to interview
people slash interrogate take a class on
this or find somebody from former
who knows this and has been trained in
this but I will tell you your best
tactic in in you know basically doing
these interrogations slash interviews is
silence just go silent and they will
review they will absolutely provide you
data and it's awesome bottom line they
fail to remediate we found about other
apt intrusions and done so this is where
I'm out
as far as wrap it up these are my
conclusion bullets I don't really have
time for a lot of questions here because
you know I'm running right up to the end
of my time here but look seriously I
want to thank you know thank everybody
here who helped put besides Atlanta
together and everybody who attended
thanks much I'll be posting a copy these
slides hit me a malware Jake on Twitter
and I'll post a I post a copy there as
well as the link in the chat Thanks and
Andy I'll kick it back over to you my
friend