it is it is my time to once again
recognize our sponsors and we put up our
slide deck here of our sponsors because
without them as I've said multiple times
throughout the day without our sponsors
on board none of this would have been
possible today so I want to take a few
minutes to acknowledge our sponsors at
our various levels diamond level Warner
media at the gold level my home college
the Kennesaw State University Michael J
Cole's College of Business along with my
home department the Cole's College
Department of Information Systems in
addition to them we have Bishop Fox coal
fire genuine parts company and NCR and
we are very thankful for all of their
support at the Gold level at the crystal
level we have critical past security and
synopsis and we are very grateful for
their sponsorship at the at the crystal
level at the Silver level a few sponsors
here we've got I got a reading off list
I'm getting tired sorry Erin's binary
defense Black Hills Information Security
Cora light and guide point security and
we are very thankful for their
sponsorship at the Silver level at the
bronze level the NCC group thank you
very much for your sponsorship at that
level
I also want to acknowledge some in-kind
sponsors got a couple of them EC counsel
provided a great training opportunity
yesterday that some of you took
advantage of and also we want to thank
and acknowledge secure code warriors our
secure code warrior sorry they have been
running a coding CTF all day long in a
separate track and I've been kind of
keeping an eye on that a little bit and
they've been banging away at that stuff
all day long and it looks like it's nip
and tuck is that who's going to end up
taking the top three places where
they've got some type of prizes over
there I'm not sure exactly what they are
but they're giving some prizes away
their next want to thank some
individuals and organizations for
contributing to our our giveaway
process that we've been going through
most today that Joette has been doing a
wonderful job of over there in the
giveaway channel I want to acknowledge
Mike Costa and crosshair
information-technology want to
acknowledge Jo gray we also want to
acknowledge offensive security as well
as the pen tester lab for all the things
that they've contributed to us to be
able to give away to you various points
in time throughout the day this is a
virtual global conference for the first
time ever and as a result we are curious
about where you are and so I'm going to
stop sharing that for a minute and so if
you haven't done so already please go
drop a pin in the map that you can find
at the URL that I'm about to place here
in the channel because we want to know
where you are we know where you're
coming from and what part of the world
you're hanging out in lately so if you
wouldn't mind drop a pin there and let
us know where you are also I mentioned
previously we've been giving away things
all afternoon
joette has been handling that over in
this channel and I'm going to put that
in here and just to remind you again
that keep an eye on that there is a
sign-up form that you need to put your
information in on - to be eligible to
win and for those of you who are privacy
concerned I get it but if you want to
get stuff sent to you we need to know
who you are and how to get ahold of you
so we need you to punch in real
information real mailing address real
email address and a real cell phone
number for any of that to happen also
we've been having people ask us all day
long hey I missed a talk where can I
find it well we're recording all of them
and we have a professional
post-production process in place and
once those videos those talks have been
run through post-production we're going
to make them available in our YouTube
channel and so people have been asking
where is the YouTube channel
well it's right
here for you I'm posting it in the
channel we're asking that everybody go
out and subscribe to that because I
found out a few minutes ago that once we
hit 100 subscribers we get to have a
fancy vanity URL so the closer you can
help us get to 100 the better off we are
and we appreciate that um let's see here
I think that that's about all I've got
so I'm gonna stop yapping grab my piece
of paper and introduce our next two
speakers we have with us Jeremy Brooks
and Stuart Lane and they will be talking
with us about automated web application
and API discovery and other things that
sounds simple but are actually difficult
and with that I will turn it over to
those two nice to them and I will stop
talking good afternoon everyone
thanks for spending some time hanging
out with us
my name is Jeremy Brooks I'm a developer
for the last 20 years that sort of
switched over net to app sec and focused
on app sec for probably the last five
plus years working on different things
now I'm running a application security
program at a Fortune 1000 retailer here
today with co-worker mine Stuart let him
do is everyone yep I'm Stuart Lane I'm
an application security engineer I work
with Jeremy I'm also a student at
Kennesaw State University majoring in
information security insurance and
graduating this may so let's do well
yeah go else so we get right into it so
the challenge that we're presenting is
to find and scan every application and
API in your organization NIST has
developed five functions which
constitutes a strong cybersecurity
program and a lot of people focus on the
protect part but you can only protect
your applications if you know where they
are so we focused our efforts on
identify which enables us to understand
what type of risk is possible within
specific environment in our organization
basically if you don't know about it you
can't assign a risk to it
so we're not going to talk about how to
set up best incest that's for another
talk we're specifically talking about
before you go into that stuff how do you
find those applications and the
challenge with this is that absolute
teams don't have a great discovery
process or it's a it's a passive process
there are new there are new apps and
Lacey web apps that maybe no one knows
about in M API endpoints they propose a
completely different challenge because
they're difficult to find Beryl it's
like go find all your web apps well okay
but how are we going to do that and
that's where teams usually fall back
into an old-school onboarding model so
here's what a typical old onboarding
process looks like that a knapsack team
may have Smee set up this is a prime
example of what a waterfall method is in
dev teams just don't do waterfall
anymore if you try to implement this in
an agile development model it would be
perceived as a gate and developers won't
follow it and figure out a way to bypass
this process leaving you wondering why
no one is filling out the four they
created and even if you can get a dev
team to do this the data that given to
you only works really if it's new
development and that information is also
becomes out-of-date as soon as it's
handed off to you so our approach
basically how do you you know you still
want to be involved with the dev team so
you want to know what they're working on
and security is still important even in
an agile development process this
requires a mind shift and an
understanding of how new software flows
on the dev development teams and you
have to have some idea of how to hook
into those different points into the
pipeline so we're going from a passive
to an active search for applications and
then based off the end
that's bill we identify risk factors and
that's specific to our organization that
we're going to talk about later on and
based off of the risk factors in the
inventory we track changes and we create
alerts based off of those changes yep
that's great so before we dive into the
methodology will kind of give you our
thought process as we were building this
this process out and how we sort of
thought about how we're gonna tackle
this problem and basically we went back
to their steel sea and we thought about
you know what what does it look like in
the environment when news when software
is being built and being tested and
being deployed what what's going on what
kind of activity so there's repositories
being created there's commits flow into
repositories if it's you know if they're
actually doing an agile or lean you know
there should be a CI CD pipeline so
there should be projects being created
there should be DNS entries for these
web apps right I mean they they're gonna
have names and URLs that people can
visit so there should be DNS records
there should be infrastructure being set
up and if they have a proper pipeline
they're probably going to have a dev
environment a QA testing environment and
then a production environment so our
thought process was we should go look
for signs of life you know we should go
look at sources of truth to figure out
where software is and that's kind of the
foundational thought behind our behind
our pipeline so this is what our
pipeline actually looks like at a very
high level we're looking at we're doing
DNS enumeration so we're collecting lots
of host names that may be running web
applications may not we're doing web
host discovery on those we're doing API
discovery which is basically going a
little bit further it's web host
discovery is kind of just checking
see if there's something at common web
ports and does it look webby right does
it speak HTTP API discovery is looking
for REST API then we're doing risk
factor identification and what we're
trying to determine there is do we
really care about this application
beyond just knowing that it exists you
know we're gonna necessarily scan
everything your new full penetration
test we we need to look and make a
determination on how deep do we need to
go and then we're generating alerts on
all this stuff so we're not having to
manually go and constantly look for
these things we're getting feedback from
the system so we'll look at each piece
of this the DNS enumeration it's pretty
basic but we're looking at sources of
truth right so the first place to look
is to look at your DNS servers and look
at the zones so we have a system that is
trusted by the master DNS server and it
can do zone transfers and that gets us a
lot of Records back and we're
specifically looking at a records
quality records and see names and using
those to build fully qualified domain
names if you're using Azure DNS or AWS
is route 53 you can enumerate DNS
through their REST API we're actually
using Azure DNS so we just go through
all the zones using the azure DNS zone
API and then we pull all the records and
we look for those a records and cname
records so that gets us the big bulk of
the host names in addition to that we
also run some make some tools that look
at external data sources so a mass and
find domain or the two specific tools we
use all the tools I'm going to talk
about by the way or open source these
tools give us
view of shadow IT so don't know if you
saw the Bishop Fox presentation they
kind of touched on this and we're doing
something kind of similar because you
might have found all your DNS records
but there could be some application out
there or some app that somebody stood up
that's still linked to your domain and
this is a good these two tools are a
great way to find out where those are
and Adam to your inventory so once we've
built that list at this point all we
have are host names we don't know what's
running on those we need really in our
cinema web applications so we need to go
look for the ones that looked webby so
you could use nmap or curl or roll your
own thing that goes out and hits various
ports I came across a tool called HTT
probe which is a little go program it's
it's pretty fast and it really gets the
job done so it's very nice you just feed
it a list of host names and it spits out
a list of web hosts with the port and
scheme attached perfect that's exactly
what we need the other thing that you
can do so if you're not having good luck
with with doing like the convincing your
sis admins to allow your server to do
zone transfers or you're not figuring
out where to get the axe you know you're
not getting access to your cloud-based
DNS system look at your continuous
deployment tools because those have to
push that application out somewhere and
so in the configuration there's going to
be a host name of where that application
lives so that could be a good place to
do we're not at the point of where you
feel like we need to do that data mining
but it's another place to look so at
this point now we've kind of whittled it
down to we've got a big list of web
hosts where we suspect web applications
are running we would
also like to know within those
applications where are our api's so most
developers if they're building new api's
they're probably not using soap so it
was kind of cool back in the day because
you can trust that there would be a
wisdom endpoint which pretty much
described every every endpoint for the
API so you're once you found the wisdom
of Don rest is a little more complicated
because it's it's kind of wild wild west
there is a new relatively new it's been
out for a few years now but fairly
widely adopted let's just call it the de
facto standard for REST API I'm it
started life is swagger
some people still client swagger it was
rebranded a couple years ago is open API
but you'll still use see those terms
kind of intermixed if you're not
familiar with it you can go check out
the swagger to i/o site but it's
basically a way to describe your REST
API in a machine readable way so it'll
be either a JSON object or a Gamal
object and that's what we're looking for
so our strategy is to take the list of
web hosts that we found and go visit
some of the common endpoints where we
know our developers push out api's and
we look for a JSON or gamal document on
the other end of that that's that's a
pretty good way to do it it's not
bulletproof but if somebody has a better
way I'd like to hear it but that works
well in our environment because we know
something so you have to know a little
bit about how your developers build
their api's you might have a different
list of common locations and one point I
don't think we made clear is none of
this changes your relationship with the
developers by the way you still need to
have good communication but this lets
you go out and and fish instead of
sitting by waiting for developers to
come to you another good place to look
if you use in Azure xapi eye Management
Services or AWS API gateway again you
can just go data-mine that and you can
just enumerate all of the
api's and when developers configure
their api's 300 ease tools through as
your AWS you basically get open API doc
for free you just need to go and find
all the find all the resources and go
visit the end point that gives you the
open API doc and the other cool thing
about swagger or open API where is a lot
of tools support it so postman you can
just drop an open API doc in the postman
and it generates a test suite for you
or there's a plugin for burp there's a
plugin for his app a lot of commercial
scanners have built-in support where you
can just feed them document alright and
then finally risk factor identification
so these are the high level risk factors
we're looking for these kind of give us
a quick view of how deep we want to go
again you might have different risk
factors but these are the ones that we
kind of agreed on internally that are
signals of that we need to go deeper so
is that our login page is it using is it
configured to use weak TLS which
understand that's not an application
issue but we found that applications
that are running on a server configured
with weak TLS tend to have other
problems so it's a signal for us if it
supports HTTP with a width and it
doesn't redirect to HTTPS so in other
words I can visit HCP website HTTPS
website and basically at the same
content that's a signal that there's a
that there's some risk they're outdated
or old sites again with this enumeration
we're probably going to find some legacy
stuff that's not part of the pipeline
that nobody's looking at so we want to
be able to identify those kind of legacy
older sites and then risky keywords so
that's what that's about is going into
the looking at the response or looking
at
you're get repositories and looking for
words that you might be specific to your
environment so for our environment we're
really concerned with applications that
touch payments or applications that deal
with sensitive PII so we're looking for
applications that have keywords that
seem to indicate that they're doing this
and then the last one which we haven't
fully cracked yet although I'm super
interested to look deeper into the smog
cloud which Bishop Fox talked about this
morning is is it an external versus
internal we sort of intuitive based on
where we discovered it if we find it
through like a mass or find domain we
kind of put it in the external bucket if
we find it through one of our internal
DNS servers we put it in an internal
that's not always correct there because
we have some things that are internal
that still somehow leaked external but
it's still a pretty good a pretty good
indicator so kind of touched on this
stuff but I baller is is good for
finding login pages or old-looking sites
so this is a Bishop Fox tool that they
published back in the fall really easy
to use just take just use Chrome
headless feed it your lit your your list
of web hosts generate the screenshots
feed in iBomber and then let eyeball or
do the classification for you so they've
got like four different classifiers
right now we're just looking at login
pages and old-looking sites if you're
familiar with SSL labs which is hosted
by paws you might like to look at test
SSL dot sh it's open source free version
of that that you can run on your own
hosts you don't have to worry about you
know getting API throttled or you can
you can tune it it really is a Swiss
Army knife of TLS checks we kind of we
do the the fast version that just looks
for critical issues and we report those
as risk factors
and repository activity cells talking
about risky keywords that's what we're
looking for those new repositories we
actually alert on that because if
somebody creates a new repository
usually the name of the repository has a
good clue of what it does and if nothing
else it's a chance to go engage with the
developers and say hey we noticed you
created a new repo called do super
sensitive thing with customer data let's
talk about it and you can also if you're
using an on-prem version you can use a
tool like talisman or get secrets and
look for hard-coded secrets we're not
there yet reason bitbucket cloud which
doesn't have hooks so we're actually
trying to build something that basically
monitors for changes so we can't do the
blocking but we can do the reporting but
if you've got an on-prem solution for
repositories you can use one of these so
that's that's our full pipeline I see
the questions piling up in slack so I'll
get to those in just a second
what I wanted to talk to you about a
little bit was outcomes so we we've been
able to successfully implement a lot of
this pipeline and so we've we've moved
past the passive discovery now we go out
and find stuff we stop developers come
to us we still have open lines of
communication but we're just as likely
to find something new that that they
haven't told us about as we are to have
them come by so it gives us a chance to
start the conversation
the really big benefit of this is we
have a basically continuously up-to-date
application inventory we can have you
know we're just constantly building this
this thing runs all the time it
basically runs and when it's done it
just starts up again so it's it just
never ends we're able to use those
identifiers that I've pointed out as as
risk factors so we attach that to the
finding and we can say it kind of gives
us a quick
and on on whether we need to go deeper
into the site and we're sending all
these alerts to a slack channel that we
monitor and that our developers can
monitor - so we're getting good
visibility on all these things and I'll
give you a little teaser so we built
this out with some of those up to source
tools that talked about but we also
wrote some proprietary code because this
is something that you know we built for
our team at work it's it's proprietary
to our employer so I can't just post
this stuff up to github and say have at
it but I'll show you real quick how we
built it and I'll give you some better
news right after this so it's just an
example of one of the slack alerts so
here we you know two new API is
discovered in Azure two new live web
hosts were discovered and some new
bitbucket repositories and we can go
look at each one of those and see you
know what the what they look like what
the risk factors were we built it out as
a REST API so we have our own swagger
page and we have just a cron job
basically that just runs it on repeat so
like I said the bad news is I can't just
take this and post it but what I'm doing
right now is I'm gonna build out and it
just starting like this is literally
fresh as of this week and I published it
up to my github so there is a app set
discovery repo in my github and you're
welcome to go check it out like I said
it's really raw but I do have I have
implemented some a significant part of
the pipeline and you can if nothing else
use it as a example of how to use some
of those tools but I'm gonna continue
building it out it'd be awesome if you
want to collaborate on it totally down
with that if you just want to pull it
down and maybe try to use it to
bootstrap something in your organization
that'd be awesome too but that wraps it
up but Stuart did you have anything else
I kind of
yes no yeah I mean you know better risk
factor identification the the goal you
know is to its decide if the site's
working worth taking people look at
right so in our organization we have
over two thousand applications so based
on a risk factors we might not we might
engage and we might not but it's good to
know it's good to know that these
applications exist in general so I mean
that's really what we're looking at
there but I know it was great I think
that it was good Jeremy good all right
let has any questions we can insert yeah
there's some good questions all right so
here's one it says how would you do API
discovery in an environment where
documentation is outdated or not even
done at all so yeah I mean that this is
a good model for that it really what you
need to do is look for pattern so even
if you don't know where everything is is
if you know where some stuff is you
probably have a pattern that you could
follow so if you're developers aren't
sticking their API is under you know a
slash API endpoint they're probably
doing something similar if nothing else
you can start looking through source
code repositories and look for those
patterns and then build those out into
your automation unfortunately there's
not you know there's no magic I mean
api's are tough and it's just because
they're not well especially REST API is
because discoverability is a very tricky
with them there's there's there's
nothing to crawl right it's not like a
standard website where you pointed at
the root page and you get back links and
forms and stuff that you can then start
crawling if you go visit the root page
of an API you're just as likely to get a
blank pages to anything else but if
they're using some standards like
swagger or open API you can look for
those swagger Doc's or open API Doc's
and use that as your documentation if
and then you said for web host discovery
would you recommend a network perimeter
scan for applications communicating
through firewalls b2b or b2c yeah that
would be a cool that would actually be a
really cool feature
I think you're talking about like
looking at your firewall logs and seeing
basically you won't you want to build
your own caste be kind of thing right
you could do that I think you'd have to
figure out you know if you use and it's
gonna depend on what kind of firewall
using but you know like powers I know
they have blogs and you can pull those
out if as long as it's like an
enterprise firewall there's probably an
API and there's probably logs that you
can pull out and and data mine those for
for b2b and b2c communication ok cool so
it looks like we're getting the hook
yeah
I'll answer the rest of the questions in
the slack Channel thanks guys I will
post the slides and thanks for your
attention and have a great rest of the
conference