[Music]
[Applause]
so thank you again roadside for having
me again I guess I didn't screw up too
bad last time because I was reinvented
again I apologize I don't speak
Portuguese but I didn't know some of the
things were saying about me anyway said
this is sorry I was pregnant tone down
the New York accent this topic is
obviously titled mistakes for me and to
talk about out of my experiences in all
the time that I've worked security what
I found really works to make a healthy
security you were redundant and security
as a security person
running a security program and then also
what doesn't yeah so this is the
obligatory slide about why you might be
interested what I have to say about this
subject area I've been working in
security for about 15 or 16 years at
this point I've kind of stopped keeping
track but I've worked on a lot of
different security spaces and a lot of
different industries so when I first
started that I was actually working for
the US military that will try to keep
American politics out of this - a
wonderful research finding bogeys for
the government essentially then I sort
of pivoted into the financial space
first kind of bridging the gap between
the US government and finance by working
for I don't know how many people here
are familiar with the Federal Reserve
Bank but it's sort of the organization
that surprises
probably not go into the toilet doing a
lot of application security a lot of
advisory a lot of you know letting
people know the best way to do things to
make sure that our economy is being
destroyed by bad people after that I
decided I wanted to make some point make
some money
if that's in earth so I worked for first
Nasdaq which is one of the main stock
exchanges in the US and they also have
stock exchanges in other parts of the
country as well again I do an
application security but I was also the
lead of the security program there so I
was doing a lot of running around
telling people you know we don't want
the stock exchange to crash how can you
prevent that to happen a brief while I
worked for a actually bank event trading
house Anita do you have a Citibank in
Brazil yo they're everywhere you can't
avoid them mostly making sure that their
ATMs on such are getting broken into but
again
of guidance in terms of looking at how
they were building things figuring out
what were the best recommendations in
terms of you know you can't be running a
really really old version of a they
didn't have a luminescent soul there but
please don't run a really old version of
iOS on your systems so on and so forth
and then all the sudden that kind of
money shift gears and that's kind of how
I landed in sort of the start of SP
space I will so I found a seed bank I
started working for tumblr I apologize
it's not my fault they took the adult
content of the tumblr okay that happened
a long time after I left that I know who
you in that decision so I'm just gonna
lay that out there whether Tom where I
was more of the security engineer like
handsome new keyboard writing the code
to one of the big things we did was made
sure that every single part of toddler
was being served overage yes or to kill
us she protects the user environment too
users a waddle stuff since tumblr is a
platform that's been consumed not just
the US over the world you can imagine if
you're in a country that maybe looks
down on female perspective nipples I
don't they people could have their
privacy invaded and so it wonder one of
the big things we did was get so a
tumblr where this year - it's basically
like okay here's you know all over the
deck sort of looking at pictures of tags
pictures of I don't know
cool videos and whatnot but that other
one has it with her own private sites
and the dashboard is protected against
was served over an encrypted
communication of people's private sites
if he went to a Laurie accountant or
calm it wasn't and so I learned a big
initiative there to make sure that every
single aspect of tumblr was being served
over no severe silence
after that I decided shift tracks a
little bit I just went to work for a
start-up but it was compliant and
healthy whatever health is a company
that tries to aggregate and consume and
provide people who wanted to research on
cancer with a lot of data that people
would may not be able to get access to
so they're taking information from
doctors about but say what okay I did
this sort of treatment I gave them this
kind of drugs I gave them this kind of
authority I do these types of surgeries
here's what's worked here
what didn't here's information
development what these people do in
terms of okay did they have any
pre-existing health conditions that
might have contributed to their problems
I just can't imagine that's a very very
set up data to need to protect cancer is
a very sensitive thing you don't want
that one fall into the wrong hands
because people are not going to have a
lot of confidence in you if you're
letting the world know my gosh this
person has leukemia or
breast cancer
and this actually monetize mathletes a
Citibank and as that are the financial
stuff is that there's a lot of
regulatory stuff that also ties it to
this not just sort of the ethical or the
moral implication we should protect this
data because people are trusting us with
it or you know we have a responsibility
to do so but also if we violate a law
that tells us that we have to protect
things in a certain way that could
actually thank throughout a smaller
company or you don't want to be in the
terms of the financial company you don't
want to be our page of The Wall Street
Journal because somebody forgot
something close report on the firewall
or you know has simple injection or
what's not just talking about the
classic yet so that I didn't do
something that I guess it's a little bit
more in line with tumblr but I went to
work for Spotify and I guess the reason
that I have this leg is also the fact
that I want to highlight the fact that
there are a lot of different red balls
risks associated risks and things that
you need to be worried about and all of
these organizations since father
how many people here in Spotify everyone
you know Brazil is actually one of our
most enthusiastic what I found of
consumers and that's awesome thank you
for isn't my stock prices but you can
make that looking at Citibank as the Fed
that the military at you and say okay
security is really scary if there's a
breach there right you know you could
screw the economy would screw up the way
people make money in case of the
military you could put people who are
fighting a war at risk with Spotify
people might not think you might be like
oh what's the big deal but there's a lot
of different people we need to protect
can you imagine how embarrassing it
would be and I'm not going to do one
particular artist but think about your
favorite artist that's and imagine how
embarrassing it would be for that and if
they're alcohol that was like super
hyped of the playing everyone's waiting
for it got these or if somebody broke
into their accounts and uploaded a track
that was super offensive and had just
completely made them look bad or maybe
somebody changes their album icon to a
picture of somebody's but I don't know
like people are not going to want to be
an artist like the Spotify platform if
we don't make them confident that they
can trust us with the stuff that they
want to keep secret the other side of it
is the consumer and this is true for a
lot of and I'm just using the places
that I worked at is work that has
specific examples but this is true of a
lot of places
why would I do Spotify if I feel like
somebody is going to be constantly you
know hacked into my account I have to
reset my password
there actually is you can imagine a lot
of people want stuff for free premium
accounts are really really attractive
things that people want
okay that I forget what the price of
that is sorry that my favorite email for
free but people don't want to leave that
2015 20 whenever his dollars there's
actually a black market who are getting
these multi premium accounts and
reselling them so and that's just
looking at the risks to the users and
there is it's typically sumers we'll
talk a little bit more about some of the
other threats but I guess the point that
I wanted to make with the slide is I've
been in all of these different scenarios
where there's a lot of things to worry
about and I've noticed tracks I've
noticed I think a lot of the question
that comes on and if you're a big
follower of InfoSec Twitter you probably
see this as well as people are still
scratching their heads that wondering
why take security more seriously why
aren't people what what are we doing
wrong to make security something that
people don't want to participate in
something that people don't want to
interact with and that's why
I'm going to give four examples of where
I've seen a common thread of how people
in different organizations and how
people I should say organizations labor
security programs do things that make
people not receptive technology that the
new security efficiently the mistake
number one and actually this is this is
a really great timing for this
particular slide because I saw yesterday
that somebody did a poll like I don't
know if it was RSA or some other
security conference where somebody puts
an article that said that people who
were security people were more
comfortable walking into a bathroom a
public bathroom with no socks or shoes
on than using public Wi-Fi and you can
understand the reaction to that right
it's like you're a security practitioner
area you're not comfortable using public
Wi-Fi like you don't know any use a VPN
and install patches
we lock down your stuff but the security
culture of paranoia is a really big
thing I don't know in Brazil you have
there's there's two kind of things that
we use in America what is the the
Chicken Little the sky is falling and a
thing or the boy that cried wolf but
would you make everything an emergency
and when you would make everything seem
like holy crap everything's on fire you
need to react to this right away people
get overwhelmed people kind of feel like
almost desensitized to the fact that you
know the things that you're raising are
report
so really and we'll get you how to
overcome that stuff but the culture of
paranoia where everything is an
emergency that means nothing somewhere
in the state I'm sure that there are
some people in this room how have been
in buildings where the fire alarm is
possibly going off as they're testing it
and you're like it's probably another
fire drill but when there's actually a
fire okay-
don't
but snake number two that I see a sort
of visible hospitality I don't know if
anybody's actually watched this movie
I've never watched it but you know but
everyone wants a sequel right like
there's this attitude of you know we're
all really proud of being a hacker is
cool it's awesome like you can find like
manipulate the system and maybe do
things that you don't want to do but
this mentality of one the gotcha you
doesn't make people like you it doesn't
really make people receptive to to what
you want them to to make them want to
cooperate with you the other thing is
that when you walk in the room they
should look at you as somebody who wants
to help not somebody who is going to be
elevated and now that's a lot of a lot
of times I see that sort of perspective
with security picture and a lot of
organizations where you come in who like
oh god Security's here I'm in trouble
I'm stressed out I don't like it again
people want to cooperate with you it's
not learning to make people listen to
you and to ever make people want to come
to you if they need hope for something
the mistake number three and this is
sort of two-tiered is lack of
transparency I think of a lot of
organizations a lot of security
companies people don't really know what
security actually does it's sort of
almost like a black box where they say
hey I hope this thing you look at it
come back with you have a with a list of
stuff to fix you don't really know why
that you don't really know what these
sort of rationality is behind that the
other thing is sort of how do I engage
with security when should I be agent
security what's what biggest food
security offer me so that I can make my
stuff better a lot of times witness oh
yeah we're security give us a request
we'll review it will tell you if it's
good or if it's bad and sent you on your
way I think this is a really big one and
this is one of the things that I think
makes people avoidance for participating
if they see it as something that holds
them back it's easy said that they see
it as something that takes them more
time and that kind of ties me to the
previous slide where okay I gave you a
review you say these things are bad but
I go back and fix them I send it to you
again you go back to tell me some other
things are bad you don't really
understand you're basically especially
if they're working in a rapid paced
environment something that you thought
would take you two weeks maybe takes a
month now nobody likes that it's going
to make you frustrated and also you're
basically kind of being like hey your
baby's ugly alright or like even a new
onesie and I put a bow on it second
[Music]
security should not be pulling back your
organization from doing stuff because if
it is that people are probably just
going to try to work around you there's
this average it's better to ask for
forgiveness than ask for permission
security is seen as a problem that a lot
of times this is what occurs so what are
some ways to get around these things
that maybe people will not want to deal
with us what makes people think that
security is either a bunch of jerks or
holding us back or just something that
they don't even comprehend the first one
in this pysics of the culture of
paranoia is being honest about what
people should be scared about and the
weight of that scared regularly I went
down the street today I didn't pass
because I wanted to buy a company I
probably announce that wrong so I use
the company ETM a lot of but the reward
for me from these of the public ATM was
higher than the rest of getting my debit
card
skinny's whatever
understand that if people under together
threats that they know how to behave
properly to them they know how to
respond better and they're not
constantly scared they're not like in
this constant state of I want to know
what to do I don't know how to move they
can actually action on what's nevel okay
maybe you risk this versus worth reward
in the situation or maybe the threat is
really really bad and I can't do this
this is sort of this is the one I'm kind
of a screwball bulk out there be
somebody that they can look to that ask
questions do don't be someone who's just
going around in like no sorry you're
done what the heck why are you doing it
like that are you serious you're not
using unauthorized queries what the heck
is wrong with you be a friend someone
that if they don't know the answer it's
okay for you to ask be someone who when
you're working on reviewing whatever
they are working on you can basically
sit down with them and say hey tell me
why you decided to do it that way rather
than being like why did you do it that
way
also just have everything documented
like if you have at other places we
either have the confluence page or wiki
I know a lot of people are you saying so
posted stack overflows have places where
people can actually look up stuff and
understand you know like to take action
for themselves I mean we're not the only
people who like to sit down and figure
things out for themselves like that
wonderful filters a lot of Architects
have the same sort of mentality if you
instead of feeding like going to mom or
dad and I have a cookie mom and dad go
to the park if they can look and see oh
ok that's a good way to do things
I'll do that they're gonna feel more
empowered they're not going to feel the
air glued or scared or anxious things
that come after them to get yell at them
because they'll have some sort of
self-control and some sort of again
education and empowerment so that they
can say
here's the thing that told me to do it
this way that's why I get this way this
also saves us a lot of time 2 or 6
o'clock we need a lot of time but it
also like this is great for us as
security because you just you don't get
people well nobody told me not to do it
that way so great they say well yeah we
did right there when we put both of us
the other thing and this kind of ties
back into these that last shot slide is
if you can yield out of your security
program so that people can take
ownership over their own security then
that makes things it's going to one see
a lot of work as security but it's also
going to be making them feel like
Security's not evolved that and what do
I mean by that well there's a lot of
different things you can do and it's not
just have a good documentation
how about different source code scanners
that can find you know hanging from
funner abilities so that they when they
actually to ask you to do a book review
you're not finding a bunch of really
easy to pick stuff but you're finding
the more serious more permanent problems
maybe have aways in their configurations
and AWS GCP whatever using even bare
metal will say hey I notice that you
haven't updated for what particular
third-party plug-in or you have
configured your server properly or maybe
to outer and say hey I notice that there
was a problem is this okay let's see us
work and it makes them feel like they're
just asked me to you for every little
thing it makes it more of a not
securities here and there here and there
like it's more like an equal
relationship
so I think they have like five minutes
left but so I kind of breezed through
this the one thing that I wanted to also
say is that there is never going to be
one size fits all approach the security
depending on where you work depending on
that things you need to be worried about
you may need to be a little bit more
strict or any sometimes you could be a
little bit more flexible if you are
subject to think display sarbanes-oxley
GCP HIPPA and yet they're really going
to have to put your foot down because
that means that the ball is going to
come after you or it's soon or you're
just have every bad news in the press
and nobody wants to have to deal with
that so again you know your mileage may
vary
getting there needs to be to adapt to
your organization's working style where
I work now it's very rapid if there's a
culture that allows people to feel
quickly and then recover quickly places
where it's a stock exchange or event
it's probably not going to work you
really need to find a ways kind of
implement the fun
tools of let's play make security a
hoping organization and the organization
within the parameters of what's going to
be well received within your
organization's culture and the way they
do things and this is sort of repetitive
but security is better you see when you
present yourself as hey I want to help
you learn I want to help you learn how
to make things better I want to make it
so that when you quote something about
coming back to you or when it when you
move out of a server or deploy a
firewall I come back to you and I'm
constantly telling you things to fix I
want you to have the knowledge in your
brain so that you can get a break from
to start I think I love the most is when
I sit down with a developer and showed
them how to exploit the vulnerability
and they're like wait this makes sense
oh I have a hacker now like our mascot
would take away just don't get her like
I get that feeling all the time when
when I pack into something I just keep
it to myself like there's been times
when I pop servers at companies I've
worked for and I'm like II lose a big
man on campus
whoo oh but keep that suit yourself
don't be a jerk don't grow but people's
mistakes in their nose and it doesn't
work for cats it doesn't work for dogs
make crap on your rug it doesn't work
for developers or engineers or
architects
[Applause]
[Music]
you