[Music]
[Applause]
she also didn't told told some of my
affiliations I wear a lot of different
apps but what I tried to do as as a side
to my professional endeavors is provide
a lot of free information out to the
global security community to protect
networks because not everybody can
before lots of expensive security
products particularly consumers you when
you go home you know friends and family
I'm sure may ask you how do I protect
myself and you're like well install
antivirus and then don't put on even
things an email so I try to provide some
information to help make that some of
that work a graph I like to use and most
of my talks to kind of explain my
perspective on things this is from
virustotal and it's a graph of how many
unique malware samples are submitted to
virustotal every day and the orange line
is they have 300 thousand unique samples
submitted on May 20th that I did know
one through reverse-engineer all that
there's a whole lot of information out
but that's what we can detect today the
steering number is between the orange
and green line because that's a number
of malware samples that we don't detect
that are still delicious but we know an
awful lot about a threat as security
professionals we often struggle with
information overload we have too much
information and we don't know what's
important most not we struggle with ways
to make use of that and that's what this
talk is one way to make use of this at a
fairly low cost price another thing
that's on my mind is one of the features
of technology particularly American
technology companies are finding more
and more ways to get information about
us and this is a fairly large book it's
about as big as a Bible but goes through
a lot of information on Facebook and
Google the Internet of Things companies
are creating more and more ways to get
information about us in our private
lives to sell us stuff and that is
something that I would like to reduce
I'm sure that many of you would also
because we like to just be private in
our private lives I don't know if I were
the care if anybody knows what kind of
diapers I live
my kids I just don't really want people
mining everything that I do and creating
some profile for me well we have these
devices that are listening into our
homes right this is an Amazon electric
Alexa that's been in the news last week
I believe and one of the things that
Amazon wants to do is have this device
listening to people speaking even
without giving it it's way quicker so we
pre voice profiles and do all sorts of
interesting things that Amazon wants to
do data science on and bear in mind one
of Amazon's biggest companies or
contracts is the United States
Department of Defense so they were also
a defense contractor that are you
leveraging some of the technologies of
voice recognition and facial recognition
for military applications but these
devices are in our homes listening to
what we do so there's two particular
threats that I'm concerned about I
assume many of you are concerned the
first is cybercrime I'm not really
worried about me clicking on stuff I
have tons of malware on my laptop that's
because I were at first engineering but
I had young kids I have six kids who
like climbing games
I might find a laptop they find some new
malicious garbage that they downloaded
under the guise of some made some game
there's not much to compromise for
children but it's designed to get
towards me and my wife our finances but
also minimizing the amount of
information that's just leaked about me
every day as I go about my business in
the United States and I assume in other
countries is a big debate about
monitoring DNS words in terms of the
host things you go to as you go out
during the internet and Internet service
providers want to use that information
to create marketing profiles well I can
tell them awful lot about somebody based
off of what those names they're going to
and about
business I could tell they work for I
could tell what kind of companies they
shot with the frequent there might be
you know personal information or adult
web surfing that they're doing they
might not want flagged in a profile so
lots of information that be protected
against but all of this requires DNS the
world and it's actually relatively
amazing DNS was written in 1980 before
there was a web browser before people
were still using dial-up modems before
any of the technologies that were
invented you know were invented in what
we know as the Internet today there was
DNS and it basically works the same way
it did in 1980 and it takes names and
turn them into numbers it's
decentralized we
establish domain rights to various
organizations and countries the system
or less works works at a global scale it
has since the 1980s but since we use it
now we're also Gusev almost every
malware config out there will use a DNS
name to reach out to something and all
of the ad tracking and surveillance that
goes on also uses DNS to reach out to
send information if those things didn't
work they didn't resolve than those
services wouldn't run which is an
essence of this talk is using DNS to
protect
against our against those threats to
privacy they're out there but it's just
transparent thing that all of us use
every day that makes the internet work
that many people don't even think about
even in even in corporate in corporate
environments right even IOT devices that
you can modify you can't modify an
Amazon Alexa but it uses TMS and you can
modify how the responses to that DNS
query that makes to get it to be more
preferential things as a relatively
brief overview I'm sure many of you know
what DNS is but it's a hierarchical
system you go to your resolve where you
say I want to go to www.google.com it
queries the root servers where it's Dom
if it's not - where's google.com and
then it goes to Google so where does
www-what the important thing about this
craft is the most
or device down there is the users
primary DNS server of resolver if you
control that you control every device on
a network
criminals have known this world well
over a decade that if they modified DNS
to you know pick a bank website then
instead of going to the bank you think
you're going to then you're going to
some criminals website we can do this
also to for more beneficial results I'm
going to block lookups for fishing
domains or malware domains or pets by
default when most people use DNS and the
home environments and even in small
business environments they use whatever
their internet service provider gives
them they plug in their router it gets a
DNS setting with a DHCP and everybody
ignores probably the only exception to
this rule is how many people use 8.8.8.8
for DNS
and that's noon but yeah there's clouds
there also right you have Google and now
you have a cloud right how many people
use 99.99 that's the only open resolver
that actually blocks malicious traffic
clouds where in google old sensor quad 9
but we'll get to that in a minute but by
March people just don't think about it
you know you can bypass it you can set
it on your devices I could set whatever
DNS setting on my Google how many people
don't think Google is paying attention
to what their query so provides a fairly
solid and responsive DNS service it
works to resolve hostnames
they just happen to use that information
also the same is true for Internet
service providers or any other entity
you know you know with the exception of
blog nines and we'll talk about that
right I said if you control you on the
DNS resolver you can control where that
information goes I need to keep it all
quite a bit we want to expose it if you
want to and you can block whatever you
want to because is yours
one aspect of DNS that allows this is
called response policy tones this is
built into the DNS protocol and it's
basically a special zone you put into
your DNS server and I'll show you
examples of this in a minute it says if
you're looking for a specific record it
will return a different response than
what the authoritative nameserver wants
so instead of going to bad site.com you
could get an ex domain it just says I
don't know anything about that
it could redirect them to a different IP
address but it's already built in to
bind in the one that you can stall with
after death or rpm you could use it
right out of the box it's also supported
in Active Directory
you can modify or blacklist certain
requests over DNS there are four
different indicator types that response
policy zones can block or or detect one
one is the specific thing that your
query or a wildfire person you're
looking for WWE will calm you could
redirect that somewhere else you can be
startup google.com you want to block an
entire domain or startup PW if you want
to block the entire nation of Palau
which is actually not a bad thing to do
because that that top-level domain is
run by basically a criminal organisation
so there's a whole lot of abusive
domains in palau you can block based off
the idea dressed it for as well stupid
alright we know lots of IP addresses are
malicious there's lots of twists out
there we'll talk about that in a second
and DMS also requires authoritative
servers so google.com has authoritative
nameservers responsible for telling
people query resources under Google you
can blacklist specific main servers that
you think they're malicious
research that I'm doing for my PhD but
we won't go into that here what you can
do you can return an X domain which is
the DNS code for saying this doesn't
exist
you can return metadata you shouldn't
point it to something else so in a
corporate environment you can point into
a sinkhole if you wanted to to get some
notification hey this machine is
infected with malware and then they see
a webpage pop up saying you've done
something bad stop doing that or take
the machine in between so lots of
various things with that that you want
right one of the things that I do it at
home
they can be redirected to something that
says dad knows what you're doing stopped
this basically looks like a DNS zone
zone it's all based off of text while
states got its own syntax but not overly
complicated you have a list of those
names over here there's a long Part C
name and then dot says it returns an X
domain
you start out or you put a fairly simple
to configure so it's all a for loop
basically that I've got a list of IP
addresses I've got a list of bad host
names I hear it all through that and I
attached the header up on top that has
some various time-to-live values in a
series of the same things true with IP
addresses except it's done in Reverse
notation because in DNS IP addresses are
reversed because of the hierarchy
involved but you can also do net blocks
so in this case you're blocking five
decade 37.0 on that pole
there's lots of entire networks that we
know or that Spamhaus and anti-spam
company publishes lists of just bad
Netflix is by spammers and scammers that
you could populate into there and start
blocking entire bulletproof hosting
happens you can do the same thing with
name service you see the same thing here
where it's as rpz - nsv name and NSIP
where you've got the host name in there
and then you've got again the reverse IP
address which if you do my Netflix it's
fairly simple text-based way to
configure it the trick is of course well
one problem that I got at least with my
own kids is we have a smart TV at home
because you can't currently buy in the
United States just normal televisions
anymore so they're like watching YouTube
videos
videos that a five-year-old should be
watching you can't really do that on a
smart TV because there's no cook there's
nothing to contract with but on using
dns settings because the Smart TV just
uses DNS I'm one of them and it does
whatever the network tells it to do well
Google and YouTube and Ben and others
have created ways to in DNS force
various safe search things to prevent an
adult material inappropriate things for
minors and you see an example in there
with Google we can redirect Google
searches to it state search or for
YouTube they have two different versions
of restricting which tech moderate
because there's three different settings
there and you do the same thing to thing
where you just do a cname of wwe.com to
restrict at Gamescom you do it at BMS
I've never touched a smart to you yet oh
the network just tells it you're only
allowed to go here and then all of a
sudden they can't see whatever if not
just YouTube videos static you know they
can get out there so it's one critical
use case it's at least good for my kids
because that I said there is a catch
right the configuration the tools have
been there they've been there for some
time not a lot of people use them
because you have to find the data now
the good news is there's lots of data
out there we'll go over that a couple of
slides but there's dozens of many lists
out there with malicious host names and
domain names I produced one that's about
a million domain names
there's hundreds of IP address IP lists
most of those are actually free for
consumers and not free for businesses so
there's lots of people neutral lots of
great information and give it away but
nobody really helps to enable a way to
make
some of these are documented some of
them or not right there is some who
wants the data and there might be some
white posting and curation you have to
do it we've implemented because as with
anything free right you make up for the
free but by having to make sure that the
data is clean but if in your home or
small business odds are if you're
blocking some website innocently in
Ukraine you're probably not going to
access it anyway so those are really
matter but there is lots of data out
there to be have you just need to make
sure that you're not blocking stuff
that's important to you this was an
example of a curated feed from Steven
Black repository that you see the link
there but he separates up data in
various classes right if you want to
block all the malicious code that the
beautified posters Edward now where you
see other cover lists on there if you
want to block safe news if you want to
on social networks if you want to block
pornography or gambling or all of the
above you can pick and choose which link
in there and start
so the data is fairly usable and about
forty to fifty thousand domain names not
a lot but good enough start to get
started and blockbuster a number of
things and these are updated on a daily
basis so its domains get taken down or
suspended there's a change but this one
lacks watts adware for instance the
various pervasive but there's lots of
data out there these slides will be
available to you to write all this down
but this is just a partial list from one
website the number of abusive this means
there are and some of them you know
slice and dice depending on however you
want there's lots of day as I've said at
the beginning of his talk we're not over
loss for data were to loss of tools to
make it useful and do something
interesting things with
but one thing I want to make a point of
is making your own dating and making
your own list they're making that
available to others is that often
threats you see may not be the same
threats that I see different countries
to see different things
[Music]
so nobody who really has a truly global
perspective things that happen here
take whatever you see whatever you care
about block and create open resources
there's always a need for more people
doing that in curating all those lists
I've showed you on the previous titles
done for volunteer work right nobody
gets paid to do that and all the empty
ad tracking and surveillance stuff is
almost all volunteer effort take
somebody who's sitting there thinking
about how Google and Amazon and Facebook
is trying to attract today
so it's not overly complicated it just
takes time and effort and as security
professionals I argue that we have some
duty to broader society to help make
life better for people beyond just
so certainly creating feeds of data I
think it's important I'll talk about a
couple of my experiences of crazy
trading feet there's two main sources of
genes that are known to creating one
based on domain generation a dta is
basically a mathematical formula that
takes some input and then turns it into
a list of domain names
now we're started using this around 2012
2011 because we got to be better about
taking down demands and getting domain
suspended so they coded these DJs and
malware so that whenever the malware
started it would say I'm going to go
query these list of a thousand domains
they would register two or three of them
News has allowed me to reverse-engineer
that figure out what domains are going
to use in a given week try to resolve
any of that and put it into feet so as
you see at the bottom of slide is two
domain names used by tiny bender which
is banking approach so it's fairly easy
it was fairly easy
what's the hard what you see from the
command in essence the entirety of what
my future generated on is running that
one command parallel throwing a bunch of
domains into asynchronous VMs and
putting it into a text file to then
parse it into into feeds from there it's
not overly complicated
and that's something I've done six years
ago want to use all over the place and
then I've said from there a great list
of domains an IP addresses in main
servers that are used by 11,000 some odd
organizations all over the world for
free and it cost me about a hundred
dollars a month and Amazon charges of
creating something that's a million
domains which
if you're interested in freaking out how
to reverse engineer DJ's there are a
couple of github repositories that I
have linked down there but Johanna's
Bader is a swiss switzerland researcher
an academic and he does a lot of work
and describes how we reverse engineers a
bunch of DJ's if you're interested in
that as a resource you can check out
this blog but those two github
repositories have a lot of DJ's scripts
implemented in Python that will start
generating lists domains I've done the
same from our confits like malware is
mounters like software which has
configuration items one of those
configuration items is where it wants to
talk to the main well there's ways to
statically reverse-engineer now we're
very fast
on the slide where I can give it an
example of dark comic or NJ Iraq or
nanopore or pick your family of malware
and then get out all the configuration
item from from that and then populate a
feed with so I've got a list of usually
dynamic DNS host names that are used by
malware or remote access tools so
[Music]
this is what it looks like at the output
it's fairly simple with it there's no
dynamic aspect to it it just parses out
the file itself and rips out the config
from just a file so if they've got
copies of malware you can run these
decoders against it and in this case
it's a dark comic that's got a DNS name
zero six zero five whatever as many of
you know dynamic DNS providers tend to
be heavily favored by there's lots of
other data in there that's useful for
other reasons but but for DNS I can
probably walk that I know I can block
that because nothing ever legitimately
use it going back to write all of us see
lots of things in our own email folders
and antivirus or web access logs and
forever whatever as an example one area
of my research is the various sextortion
that points damage that people
that has been going out the past six
eight months where you've been you know
it says you've been going to naughty
places on the internet send me however
much in bit point those Bitcoin wallets
are immensely useful and the same is
true for ransom it's not you can't use
it a dmx but creating feeds of that
helps track the people behind that down
and the same is true for dns saying oh
I've seen this game with this URL and
this this domain name I'm creating feeds
of that to broader society one helps us
all protect each other's to it
in order to make this work you've got
feeds of data but running by maybe
sphere to some people right it's
certainly not something you probably
could go to your parents to do another
easy open source project that really
does make easy use of this data runs on
a Raspberry Pi fairly simple was
installing the glow that instructions
here fairly quickly and then it's just a
question of just adding weights to
whatever domains you want to block by
default it was a project born at
tracking and surveillance so out of the
box configuration will block the various
forms of ad tracking and surveillance
that goes on of how people monetize
their websites but blocks things and
wipe those things and you can block the
whitelist anything you want so you can
put in as many or many feeds of data
that makes to
but the best part of that is if you're
running your own resolver its right
meaning it's not the queries on your ISP
you know they'll be routed to the
authoritative nameserver google will
know that you're looking at cool calm
but they won't know that you're looking
because this is how easy to install
install raspy order nee of the operating
systems represented there have you run
that one proscriptions one of which is
to set the password for the admin
interface but you run curl and it just
works fairly fairly simple install you
can run a docker you can run it wherever
you want
there is one additional stuff because it
is a DNS resolver you've got to tell
your devices to use that instead of
whatever the guy has provided default
dates so on my network right I've got an
access point behind the router I did
company and by default it says okay use
this name server here's your IP address
I simply point it to an internal IP
address corresponding to my raspberry pi
then all of the devices on my network
and magically start query the raspberry
pi instead of my ISP for DNS words
including the IRT devices including all
of the various things because everything
uses DMS and everything uses DHCP to
figure out its network settings so this
works on everything fairly quickly even
those even those devices that you can't
otherwise modify because there's no
access to them the trick is many access
points and home routers to make that
difficult of non-intuitive
I have dd-wrt on my home access points
that's fairly simple right but if you're
using the cable access access point and
access router you might not even be able
to access access that device or
difficulty point that's my video DWR
team
it breaks everything at home bricks my
kids and my wife can't get two metrics
from YouTube I'd be hearing about it
right now I'm a no place to fix it for
them the good news is this device has
never broken in months
still it's still running there's no
issues but if there is that you have to
figure out a way to bypass it either
bypass it on a per device basis or log
back into the answers point and change
things every now and then you know the
things that I don't want my kids to see
kit block for me because I'm a security
researcher sometimes I go places I'd
rather my kids not go to so I've got to
bypass DNS traffic to keep doing my work
at home or use the VPN and if the local
machine statically configures its own
DNS server then I will bypass the
firewall and there'll be no protection
time almost nothing does that
does that is my own laptop when I get
exclusively pay to do it with all the
IOT devices for whatever reason just use
whatever the network provides them which
is somewhat surprising I think that
surprised that they didn't just use
themselves with DNS servers to capture
more information here's what the media
dashboard looks like gives you query
volumes and lets you kind of know what's
going on this one is the one provided by
them are provided by biologists there
are 17,000 queries in the last hour
one thousand one box 6.5 percent of the
queries of what responses and what types
of queries are going this can be very
interesting for people are kind of
curious about what their devices are
doing especially if you have a lot of
smart devices at home is to get idea
what's going on with the traffic that
they're generating they don't really
make it easy to see what you're doing
this device is cooling over one of the
other benefits things this does because
DNS the DMX Bible doesn't run full RPC
it runs DNS mask which basically
operates as a for you know block some
things and then forward request of
whatever it doesn't know about you can
sip where queries are forwarded to
so you see several examples right Google
is in their cloud sweater with cloud
ones is in their quad 95.9 is in there
you could do this over DNS over TLS our
DNS over HTTP with a little extra work
so that no one can even sniff your DNS
traffic because Dan asked by default is
unencrypted over UDP port 53 right well
if it's DNS over HTTP HTTPS well then
all the fuss the only one would ever see
is that you're sending to your web
traffic to
and no one except the person serving the
request would see it now the important
advantage of quad 9 in addition to me
the only one that I should say quad nice
and open dns will lock malicious stuff
quad knowledge is the only one that
keeps your queries from those queries of
the data that I provide them so despite
quad Knights having some measure of
disability into what you were you they
don't provide that to any third parties
so you can maintain a degree of privacy
then having list is a simple simple
feature of just putting going to block
list or whitelist and just put the URL
in there whatever lift you want to have
the system itself is pretty smart in
terms of figuring out exactly what it
wants to block over a variety of formats
so I just picked out to the top one I
think is our domains which just lists
domains and the other one is the bottom
servers host file and you see that IP
address or host name in figures
what you actually want to walk so it's
not very strict in terms of data which
is good let's do the whole bottom
protection but it doesn't have any
capability of blocking my P addresses
and it does need to be local or if
anybody
or for a small business either but it's
not really able to enterprise deployment
because so what I do at home that's
running so early right but in some more
details of what I've noticed right in
terms of capacity the Raspberry Pi it's
pretty neat device but it is constrained
in terms of resources on the PI roll I
can block about 2 million entries those
names in domains
1 million entries because you're running
a full resolve where it has to keep cash
that keeps a lot more things than memory
versus doing the real-time lookup of
sending to something blocked or not so
there's there's definitely resource
constraints in terms of what you can
block so primarily on the first device
running RPC I focus on bad networks and
IP addresses and then focus on all the
privacy stuff in the firewall with big
lists of domains and then quad 9 to pick
up anything else so provides some pretty
decent relatively robust protection at
least for my family but if it stops
95% of criminal stuff and my kids are my
wife cooking on something stupid I'll
take that as a win and like I said I run
this over at DNS over HTTP on that last
link so my ISP can't see
I've been running this for a few months
now I do travel internationally and I'm
kind of the only tech support for my
family so things break I get angry calls
my name yet my wife's phone is broken
the better phone's problem not the
network but it has interrupted there's
been no hangouts my cable service has
gone down you know a couple of times but
these devices are relatively recent and
they just run for a long time it's flash
storage so eventually
the answer it's fairly stable and could
work for a small business I don't know
if I would trust like that a major
Enterprise to this major enterprise okay
I'm gonna use actual server hardware for
DMS but if your small officer can't
afford lots of stuff this can provide
you a whole lot of protection in a
fairly low cost point and all the data
is already out there three you just may
have to wipe those things every now and
then
Britany twice I think my first set up
there were a couple of things that I had
the right list because just applications
wouldn't work because of how they were
tiny to add tracking network so I'm one
by one case I could say okay this could
this could work so I've got a white list
is and you can do that entry by entry in
the pyro interface in fact if you look
at pretty log you just a you see the
queries in real time you can just click
white list and it will wipe this
whatever the underlying query was so
it's fairly simple with some tuning that
took me about an hour I haven't touched
the white list in months
it's still working and all people save
starts and that stuff operates on smart
TVs and iPads and other devices it's
that I don't
so what are the things like I said
prepping this talk that I gave thought
is discussions I've had you know over
over the years is there's been you know
with the advent of the Facebook's image
emails of the world saying oh don't run
your own email server don't run your DNS
server it's too complicated you don't
have the time to superior you know we'll
do all of that for you and oh by the way
loom I know all this stuff about
profiles and sell out to the highest
pitch there hasn't been a compromise of
the mail server in ten years even though
it counts guest usernames and passwords
but nobody has compromised post six or
accident right
you know vibe is secure basically out of
the box especially if you're running out
on the inside of the network you know
the whole concept of the internet was to
allow you know people to interconnect
their own devices and figure stuff out
and make things work and as time has
gone on
right DNS is an example I've mentioned
to external DNS providers everybody
knows those there are hundreds of them
out there that everybody knows Google
and CloudFlare is at the best market the
other thing is they provide no security
my Google and CloudFlare cloud for it
particularly like saying we don't
believe in censorship I'm ok with
blocking ransomware and not considering
that censorship I think we can we can
deal with blocking criminals and not go
down the slippery slope
[Music]
the privacy at the same time in the last
point because this is a talk about DNS
is DNS over HTTP is relatively new
development over last year by clouds are
by the rule that in the coming months
they want a mandate in the browser which
means by default you're going to be
giving all of your DNS queries to them
and nobody's going to be able to have
any visibility except them including to
protect yourself right this is a bad
idea because it's giving the browser's
inclusion with Google to the world full
access to information while not
providing any real protection and just
monetizing I don't know where that's
going to end up they said in the next
two versions of chromium
whatever web browser you use and see if
it's mandated in your DNS queries to
some place in the last point to go to
what I'm talk there's lots of people are
creating data but we need more lots of
this is volunteer work because you know
big companies will do this but then they
sell the product to be enterprises but
if you want to protect families or small
businesses or people who have had a lot
of money who rely on three tools to do
that and free information you data so
certainly there are a lot of projects
out there that help even if you're not
creating a feat operating sensors so
that feeds can be created one is a do
shield one where the sans internet storm
center it's basically it's a Raspberry
Pi honeypot that sits on an external
network and just listens to all of the
traffic that comes through honey bee bee
is another example of a raspberry pi
into the round honey box to go with
brute force attacks out there
our web servers or SSH and Ron failed to
man you could also contribute that data
to abuse IP to help protect the system
for DNS lists that takes work in terms
of ad tracking is just to see where
things are clearly to do that but
certainly we need more people helping to
curate those lists and get more
information about bad stuff seeing on
the left but certainly whatever you do
[Music]
you