it's been a long time
in our community where i think ics or ot
or whatever we want to call it by
is kind of pushing the corner a bit or
oh that's that other stuff or is that
even a thing or that's an add-on to this
other thing and it's like dude the
enterprise is the add-on to the ics
and so it's just been wonderful over the
last 16 years to see our community grow
to become the community that it is where
we get thousands of people
lining up to to come to the conference
to share their insights
it's just really really beautiful and i
will i will say this as i
kick off there are plenty of still loud
voices in the community any given time
that don't peddle hope that talk more
about tearing down people and building
them up
and one of the things that always just
makes me so excited about the sands
community and the people that come to it
is these are folks time and time again
that'll go work the 12
to 15 hour shifts out in the substations
and real lines and similar
and still come and talk about hope and
growing the community and educating
going and talking to students and
similar so just be
that part of the community because
that's what makes it beautiful so
i'm gonna kind of click into the next
slide here um so for my keynote
i'm gonna be talking about the ics
security and review uh i'm gonna put on
my drago's hat
hold on uh especially just with the
background there we go
boom now i'm over at dragos all right so
the the beautiful thing about getting to
be at sands is is i get to be an
instructor and course author at sands
and i still get to
i do my company over at dragos with a
bunch of wonderful folks
um and so i'll do a proper introduction
now and kind of get into what this topic
is going to be
and kind of the lessons learned and the
data and why
um we do these kind of year in review
reports um so as i mentioned
in my sans capacity over as an
instructor and course author
uh in my dragos capacity i'm the ceo and
co-founder over there
we're a company that um has technology
for like monitoring and doing visibility
and detection in these ics environments
but one of the things that kind of makes
us particularly unique
is the way we think about making our
technology is about having really really
good people on staff
and those folks are going out doing
instant response engagements hunting
threats
uh architecture assessments with folks
we have an intel team that tracks those
threats and tries to understand what
they are
and and i you know when i started my
career i started
the national security agency side of the
house and built out the us government's
mission looking at industrial threats
and at that time it was a big question
of is that real
is there a real thing of threats that
are explicitly interested in ics or
developing capabilities or insights and
lessons learned like is that is that
real
and as we built that mission set it was
obvious that yes
there's a lot and the challenges we were
facing
was that we were always collecting in
the normal places that we were looking
for enterprise threats
and it wasn't until we started adapting
our collection getting into substation
networks and manufacturing lines and
similar
that we started collecting in the right
places to find uh those ics threats
and so to see the evolution of the
community for where i would say even up
until 2014
2013 or so like even the mention of
ics cyber attacks or uh hey
these things can take down
infrastructure to be overly classified
in the government
side nowadays we're having broad
discussions with the community about
hey how how can we get ahead of these
things and let's not freak out
it's not about a phishing email it's
going to take down the power grid like
that's not how that works
but yeah let's stay ahead of this
because these are low frequency high
impact events and when you're talking
about things that can impact not only
reliability and operations with safety
it's worth paying attention to and
getting right so when
when i was coming into the ics security
community when i first started
everything was anecdotal it was somebody
spoke at a conference and said hey i
i got some secrets or i know a guy or i
saw some things
and it just wasn't too helpful uh in my
opinion
to really start understanding trends and
broader insights
and and how can we start getting ahead
of these problems instead of just
somebody's opinion um and so what we did
is starting to create these year in
review reports and then about four years
ago or four years ago is when we started
them
which was to say let's take all of our
insights that our services team our
intel team that we're seeing out in the
field
let's have a data driven view
non-marketing not pitching anything in
the reports just
here is what we're seeing from our
perspective
that's data driven on the community and
where the community is today
and and so it was really our attempt to
give back to the community these
insights and make them accessible to you
all so you can go draw your own
conclusions
and think about the problems that we
have and and again kind of invest
in our community and make sure that we
get this done correctly
so let's jump right into kind of the
broad
themes as we look back against 2020
these were some of the headlines you
would have seen
and some of the discussions that were
taking place this isn't the
incident response and inside you know
baseball kind of stuff this was all very
public
eckins started off the year where it was
the first time
that we saw ransomware explicitly take
an awareness for ics
you know computer processes and similar
and you know this is something i've
always
always talked about for a while now that
a lot of activity we see against
industrial sites is state driven
so adversaries that are state actors
targeting industrial systems and one of
the realities
of industrial is it's very political you
know going after
energy systems or manufacturing and
things like that it can be
you know going after critical
infrastructure is very state driven
either espionage or potential for
conflict kind of scenarios and there's a
lot of value in that to states
but at the same time there are all these
cyber criminals and non-state actors and
similar
and one of the things that we've kind of
been watching is
when you look at the complexity of
really causing
impact in industrial it's not easy it's
easy to break in somewhere
there might be a lot of security
challenges but you can't take your it
mindset and look at the ics and go oh
there's a vulnerability in a windows 7
system therefore it's bad no
can you use that to cause impact you
know you have to look at that
very closely and and what we've what
we've
kind of been watching is that the level
of effort required to cause
impact and cause scalability is so high
that the investment required is for
states but what we're seeing now
in the community it's kind of you know
you can call it digital transformation
you can call it hyper connectivity we
start seeing common operating platforms
you start seeing more open standards and
a lot of this are driving a lot of value
but it's also lowering the barrier to
entry lowering that complexity
where non-state actors and criminals can
start taking a closer look at our
community
because there's scalability and
investment and return on investment they
can make
and i i don't want to get carried away a
data point is not a trend
but ekkins represents an interesting
data point
of an ics specific or ics aware
ransomware and wondering if we're going
to see more of that
throughout the year we also saw like
miter attack for ics release which i was
just
extraordinarily thrilled about again i
want to move away from anecdotal
stuff and i want to move more towards
what's the data
and there's a lot of value in saying
here's what we've learned from
attacks and intrusions before here are
the common tactics and techniques of our
adversaries
get off of chasing every single
indicator i want to know that this ip
address or that digital hash
that's not scalable it can be useful but
it's not scalable
getting into how are they operating you
know how are they achieving effect
what's the style of their attacks that's
very very useful
and it is scalable and it's something we
can take a close look at and have a
complain
excuse me a compendium of knowledge that
is driven off of exactly what the
threats have done
there's a lot of value in doing
consequence driven analysis
what is the art of the possible in our
industrial plants regardless of who or
what attacks it
what can be done there's a lot of value
in getting in there and looking at it
from that lens and a lot of good
engineering work going into that to
reduce some of the risk
of what's even possible in our
facilities but there's a lot of art of
possible
so to also know and pair it up with
what's the ground truth reality
what are the adversaries actually doing
not all 10
000 things they could do but what are
the 100 things they're actually
accomplishing and doing
there's also a lot of value in that to
help in things like prioritization
and again we started seeing lots and
lots of different ransomware effects
very targeted intrusions and
transmission system operators in europe
eckan started popping up again in
multiple facilities by may
the ripple 20 vulnerabilities got a lot
of conversations going
the i think the impact was lesser than
people realize it's very
hard to use the vulnerabilities in a
reliable way in industrial environments
however the point that it accentuated
was a good point that many have been
making in the community for a while
which is we don't really know what's in
a lot of our products
and you might see a vulnerability for
one vendor
but five other vendors may use the same
coding library or similar
where they all have the same
vulnerability but only that one issued
the advisory because that was the one
that got told
and so this topic of like software build
materials or s-bom or like what's in
our products is an incredibly important
topic that we'll just continue to hear
about in the supply chain security
discussions
um i was pretty sad to see adversaries
targeting pharmaceutical companies
during a global pandemic um
it it makes sense actually as much as we
want to yell about it it makes sense
that a state actor would try to steal
the recipe and the intellectual property
associated with new and emerging
vaccines
their own intelligence community
stealing things to help their people in
terms of manufacturing and copying that
you know we can get upset about that but
to some understanding that's what
intelligence services do i can
understand that
it was the adversaries that were looking
to potentially
target and disrupt those processes or
manipulate or use misinformation
to destroy the public confidence in the
vaccines those are the ones that were
just extraordinarily over the line that
we were seeing a lot of
and then we're just seeing a consistent
trend of just more and more
vulnerabilities
what i thought was particularly
interesting and this is
one that is something to watch is the
u.s treasury came out and sanctioned the
russian lab for the crisis malware
trice is also known as triton that was
the malicious software leveraged in
2017. it was the first ever cyber attack
to explicitly try to kill people
at a petrochemical facility in saudi
arabia and
what i enjoyed about that is it wasn't a
name and shame strategy to throw their
names up on a wild wild west post or
whatever it was an ofac
sanction from the treasury and from
those for those of you that aren't
familiar with
um the sanction process and ofac
sanctioned
from from the treasury it basically puts
you on the same level of isis
and it says you're dead internationally
like nobody's gonna do business with you
nobody can go and visit you nobody can
you know any banking sector that's
related to you hands off
it is an extraordinarily powerful
sanction and
and it was the first ever sanction that
we saw as a relate
as it relates to an ics attack and i
thought that was interesting and they
explicitly called out in the sanction
the fact that the reason they cared so
much was because it was ics
and because it was that targeting and
when we get national level buy-in
and amplification that there's something
special about ics
and maybe we shouldn't be targeting that
um that that's a great thing for our
community
and it's not going to solve the problems
it's not like adversaries you're like oh
okay
but it's the start of a dialogue between
states that i think is useful
and we'll talk some more about the
solarwinds stuff throughout the
conference and i'll mention uh
some points here today as well but but
we also saw
a large growth in threat activity
and and this gets so many different
opinions about threat intelligence and
threat activity and
and i try to keep it professional but i
will say it is always interesting
uh people's perspectives on what intel
is and isn't
and how many folks that have no
experience in intel at all or happy to
tell you everything about why intel is
wrong
and here's my perspective if you like
the idea of
learning from an attack or learning from
an intrusion and sharing those insights
that's all intel is
it's not magic secret sauce you should
absolutely do your security audits you
should absolutely invest in all the
other parts of the business before
you're going and
you know layering on intel but intel is
that kind of
secret sauce on top if you will at five
percent of
hey let's make sure the things we're
doing are right for where we want to go
and let's make sure that once we get to
a defensible place
that we're informing our defenders to
help move the defensible to a defendant
state
let's figure out how to incorporate
intelligence to understand those lessons
learned
it's not about taking a feed and rolling
it across your data it's about watching
trends and understanding
how you're going to prioritize your
limited investments and when we look at
ics threats how we think about it is not
just the threats
that are developing capabilities today
not just the ones that are taking down
you know power sector in ukraine or
similar
instead we look at it from any any
threat
that is explicitly targeting ics we want
to know the ones that are
hitting the enterprise right now but
they have engineering documents and
they're going after
just the accounts and people on the
operation side of the house
or when they get in they're stealing out
engineering drawings
and hmi screenshots and things like that
we want to know the adversaries that are
explicitly interested in them
so that we can help prioritize it for
the defenders
the goal isn't to say here's one macro
group that represents all threat
activity ever it's to say hey you've got
limited time and effort
if you care about these types of
problems here's an understanding
explicit to that
and as i mentioned kind of when you look
at the trend
in the threat landscape for years we
didn't have a lot of insights
and there was a lot of cases that dealt
with ics if you look back in 2010 and 11
the apt-1 reports that came out
fantastic reports looking at china
breaking into different sites around the
world
there was a lot of ics stuff in there
but not explicitly called ics
and the community wasn't at a place
culturally even
to be able to get into those industrial
environments and see anything but we
were seeing
intellectual property getting x-filled
out of manufacturing environments we
were seeing
engineering drawings and and scada work
getting pulled out so we knew it was
happening but we didn't have the
collection to say anything
and so what i normally tell people is
don't freak out about the threats it's
not oh my gosh everything's getting
worse
it's as we collect more we're seeing
more
and we're getting a better picture of
what's actually happening and what we're
seeing is some of those threats
are learning about ics and then
developing capabilities and doing
disruptive attacks
what we see is some are the early stages
of their learning
and we want to track their evolution but
maybe they will get to attacks maybe
they won't
and so you kind of follow that hurricane
path if you will
and one of the things that we highlight
in the report was that the threat
activity is growing
at a three sort of three times
um the rate of growth and what what that
would mean to us is
if we haven't seen a group in over a
year
any intrusions related to them we would
deprecate them saying hey
we we we're not tracking these these are
kind of inactive groups
but what we're looking for is how fast
are new groups appearing
versus how fast are groups deprecating
and we would hope for a one
ratio you'd accept kind of a one to nine
of like one new group comes in one group
drops off
what we're seeing is for every one group
that drops off three groups appear
that's not a great trend so it's
something to watch i'm not saying it's
alarming and all that it's just
showing that around the world more and
more state actors
and non-state actors now are becoming
interested and focused
and capable in ics at the same time that
our community is becoming more
hyper-connected and accessible
a lot of people talk about it ot
convergence i usually talk about kind of
that digital transformation with that
threat convergence
that's the intersection that i'm
watching that i think is interesting
that i think we need to stay ahead of
because a lot of the security efforts in
industrial
for big companies can take a three to
five year journey
and we're in a three to five year window
of hyper-connected common environments
with
adversaries developing their insights so
again not alarming
not freak out but hey we need to pay
attention to this and we need to get
ahead of it
um so as we dig into kind of what those
groups are
from this past year there was four that
we kind of i'm brought to
the discussion um one is actually one
you're probably already familiar with
um to some degree but we we sliced it up
a little bit more to be
um kind of the things that we thought
were interesting to ics so
fireeye track sand worm they do a
fantastic job in doing so
and san worm has been involved in a lot
of different activities you know
everything from ukraine 2015 to
the olympics in pyongyang in south korea
um but the uh reality
of um sandworm is it's
it's a definition i think a lot of
people look at these intel names as a
name
that's that team that's one-to-one ratio
with that team
you know these names are really
definitions and i don't know and you
don't know what the definition
to that team is of sandworm the ins and
outs of it
what you do know is that good people are
tracking a team and briefing you on
updates about what that activity is
doing
so as we looked at san worm and the
things that we were tracking related to
it
it hit a lot of ics stuff it had a lot
of non-ics stuff
as we started focusing just specifically
on the ics portions of it
um last year the us government and the
nsa actually came out and said hey
here's some interesting activity uh with
this xm campaign
relating like basically uh mail headers
and they said this is something we
attribute to the gru the russians
military sort of intelligence unit and
it overlaps very broadly with sand worm
and so we took a look at that
and it was something unique and it was
unique intrusions and it was unique data
it was a really good job
and from a government sharing
perspective and we were able to use that
data to then go find additional
intrusions and work with utilities
that we're seeing unique intrusions and
we were able to pull this together to
say look
it's not just like there's this one
broad sandworm team to us to others
that's fine
to us there's a lot of non-i.t stuff
there's a lot of i.t
stuff they focus on there's kind of the
actual team that develops malicious
capabilities like the develop the crash
override malware and ukraine 2016 that's
somebody we track as electrum but what
comma site is to us
is the team that's actually going and
breaking down the doors they're the
access team
they get in place and then someone else
comes in and moves in
and we and it's easy to think about gru
or russia and say that's them
but the reality is they have their own
development shops they have their own
allies they have
government labs that work with them et
cetera so this idea that one
threat name represents like one team
sitting in the basement somewhere is
always been off in my opinion
there's a whole supply chain that they
have hacker for hires
exploit developers lab researchers etc
the focus is how can you take the
intrusions and the activity
and focus it to a level the defenders
can use it not
look at me i'm an intel analyst i can
track all the cool things but how do you
piece it together of this is what you
mr utility care about this is what you
miss is manufacturing you care about
um that that's the stuff that we try to
do and with comma site was really
cool and interesting um to see the
access development team the team that
goes in before someone else comes in
so the main thing to focus on here is if
you were to see comma site related
activity
the takeaway is you can't just assume
that activity is related reconnaissance
this is one of the few teams that if you
see them you should be prioritizing the
detections and response efforts against
that type of activity
because they have demonstrated both the
capability and intent
to line up the team that then comes in
to do the destructive attacks
or i should say disruptive
skype night was another really
interesting one um this was interesting
for a couple of reasons
i'm not getting into attribution on this
don't really care to i don't think
that's the value
but i thought this was just a really
good work so cisco's talos team
identified the original poet rap malware
they did a fantastic job diving through
that
we took those insights kind of expanded
it out went and found a bunch of other
intrusions
and found some unique targeting and the
targeting that was particularly
interesting to watch here was that the
um the stipe night team is explicitly
targeting
wind generation resources and azure
jaiban we're not targeting anything else
that we can see from our collection
not going after anything else and the
interesting thing about that wind
generation capacity is there is no
operational wind generation capacity in
azure drive on nothing's up and running
there's multiple projects there's
multiple uh facilities getting built
but they don't have a wind generation
capability today
in izerjaiban they want one terribly bad
and they want one because as we
understand it they would love to not be
dependent on russian natural gas or
other fuel sources
and energy between states has always
been hyper competitive
and so for eiser jaiban to be able to be
more energy independent is a national
security goal for them
and styme knight is specifically going
after all of the companies involved in
that
the construction companies the the
companies making the wind turbines the
companies that are going to be operating
it
they're getting a foothold early on
before even the operational capacity
turns on
um in that country and either gibon
has had a really interesting year where
there's also
um you know darn near armed conflict
between them and armenia
and you've got you know i'm not going to
expound too much here but you've got
uh saudi arabian resources coming in to
support eiser javon
and helping build out energy assets
aizer jaiban has made
um sort of different trade agreements
with ukraine to provide
uh wind energy resources back and forth
between ukraine and then armenia has
more
sided with russia if you will and the
idea of having
energy dependence not being dependent on
russian fuel is
is an interesting geopolitical topic to
watch
so again i'm not trying to describe
attribution or saying anything like that
it's what what i think we're observing
here what i would assess we're observing
are the early stages of trying to get a
foothold in their energy entered
independence and that could have broad
strategic impacts
um for what's going on in eiser triban
now for all of you and the rest of the
world
i think it speaks more to a strategic
level it's not use these indicators and
go look for these things
but how are they doing that how are they
accomplishing it
how are they planning on their targeting
what are they looking for that's all
stuff that can absolutely be useful to
you
you may never have stype knight come
after you but if we can talk about the
tradecraft the ttps the tactics and
techniques that they leverage
this is stuff then that you can pick up
and defend yourself against any other
team that uses those same type of ttps
um so so all in all pretty useful there
another one that was interesting that
targeted a lot of japanese taiwanese and
us electric utilities
um was talonnite now a huge huge kudos
to the proofpoint team
um they picked up some of the initial
phishing emails going out in the
community and wrote a fantastic blog on
it that i put down there in the bottom
i had some really cool insights that
they developed and they'd actually
flagged
this email as well and we went and um
worked with the number utilities got
some additional information found some
additional intrusions pivot you know
went and found
this email loaded up in virustotal
pivoted it off of there found additional
intrusions and started making this
broader
view into the ics specific portion of it
now again it's not it's not saying these
folks are leveraging exploits and
vulnerabilities in ics
that's not the point it's saying this
group is explicitly
targeting utilities so it's not hitting
banks and other things
and the ways they're doing it is
explicitly going after the engineering
side of the house
even the theming of their phishing
emails and similar it's all about
getting to like
uh you know engineering surveyors and
their license renewals and anything they
can do
to get to the engineers and operators
that gives an
example and an assessment of motivation
on the adversary to be targeting in
the industrial side of the house and
therefore
as we care about that um it ends up
being something a little bit more
prioritized for us to go take a look at
again anybody working a utility or
manufacturer oil and gas company
etcetera you've got 10 000 things to
look at in a day
this is not about saying oh my gosh
we've discovered something that's going
to solve everything
it's about saying out of the 10 000
things you have here's three
that are really interesting on
industrial side of operations if that's
what's interesting to you
um and so the the focus there
and the consistency of this team to
target us utilities and try to get
access and they have had successful
access before and we've worked a number
of cases with their clients to
to make sure they can get ahead of any
sort of ics specific access
um those are a cause to watch this team
and to see how it evolves
and this could be a team that falls off
in a year and we learn some things we
share to the community
it could be a team that continues to
develop their insights over the next
couple years
so that's kind of again that hurricane
path i was talking about following
um another cool one that we saw was
vanadite um the
all the names we come up with by the way
are just made-up names it's all it's all
uh
industrial minerals everybody has their
own naming convention for us we just use
industrial minerals because we're not
trying to say like it's china it's
russia we're
we're trying to say here's something you
should focus on the the interesting
thing with this
group is the us government has already
come out and said this is related
has said that the broader context is
related to the chinese government
um so it's been interesting from their
attribution to say they care about it
what we saw and what we were able to
find
is that this group specifically is
targeting the
kind of the virtual private servers and
the remote access
into industrial sites and at first when
we saw this
and we saw a number of intrusions
targeting you know virtual private
servers and
uh kind of vulnerabilities that had come
out like one day before
against you know firewalls and remote
access points
and similar we didn't even know if it
was ics at first it was like well this
is interesting you could leverage this
to get ics but
i don't know that they are then we
started seeing the focus
picking up explicitly on those systems
that were related to
um infrastructure community especially
oil and gas
and manufacturing getting hit a lot we
started saying okay well if you're
hitting oil and gas and manufacturing
maybe there's kind of the the desire to
get into the operations environment
and then consistently with you know
feedback from our customers they were
seeing
um targeting of those remote appliances
that were explicitly
um the access points into industrial
systems
and this is a you know a good
observation for most people where
i think for years there was an
expectation
that ics was segmented and off the
internet or at least highly segmented or
you had to go through the enterprise to
get there so a lot of companies
prioritize their defenses and the
enterprise networks
made sense if you believed your stuff
was segmented and only could be accessed
from the enterprise
what we found time and time again over
the years is that actually integrators
original equipment manufacturers even
just the necessity of doing operations
in general
have set up lots of remote connections
and set up a lot of connectivity
and you don't have to go through the
enterprise to get there or you have to
go through somebody else's enterprise to
get there
and so these remote access points and
these um
capabilities to get in directly to the
ics by bypassing
all of those other systems is a lot of
value to the adversary and it's
definitely something you should be
prioritizing because we see
adversaries like van dyke explicitly
targeting those and getting access to
those systems
so when we look at the activity groups
we've already tracked you know this year
we focused a lot on kind of the new
folks
um the the existing groups out there
that we track are still active many of
them are
um we see them picking up you know
different vulnerabilities going off the
energy sector
um we see a lot of interesting water
hole
intrusions uh specifically themed on
like project and engineering sites and
integrators
see a lot of targeting of integrators to
get access to broad
sets of industrial environments um so
there's still a lot of activity going on
we're focusing on the new to educate on
the new um but i should note that
that many of those groups are still
active so make sure you're good with
those
um i think it's always a thing in our
community we're going to focus on kind
of what's the latest
even though we might not have actually
applied the lessons learned from the
last couple of years
there's still companies i know that
haven't applied you know instant
response plans for what a ukraine
scenario might look like
you know those are good places to start
um so then as we transition from the
threats and we start thinking about like
what's the true state of vulnerabilities
you know i i think the thing about
vulnerabilities that i find interesting
is if you're an i.t security coming into
ics security
and you look at the plant and its
operations right off the bat
you think oh wow these old
unpatched systems ah so many
vulnerabilities almost you wanna take a
shower right you walk in you're like
you're using windows xp still
what um and and i think that's really
not the point
and it's not a great way to approach the
industrial operations in
it security you're largely dealing with
system
and data security protect the system
protect the data
in industrial control system security
you're largely dealing with system of
systems
security sure i've got access to an hmi
but what is that going to allow me to do
uh in the environment how do i make the
lights blink how do i you know
cause an overpressure event how do i
cause these systems to work together to
do something
additionally in enterprise you deal with
a lot of high
frequency low impact events a lot of
stuff happening lots of scans lots of
emails etc
not too many of them are going to bring
down your company in ics we deal with
low frequency high impact events we see
things less often
but when we do it could be the
fundamental like intellectual property
that keeps your business in
in uh as a business it can be safety
related it could be operations and
national security related
they're big events so to me a focus
an over focus on vulnerabilities is not
the way to think about it it's more
about
uh how can i understand what's in my
environment how can i get in a better
security posture how can i start looking
for the behaviors or the threats i care
about
how do i look for exploitation of the
vulnerabilities i care about not just
patching
because patching isn't always accessible
but that's not to say that
vulnerabilities aren't important
but when you look at the state of
vulnerabilities it's pretty bad
and so over the past four years we've
been highlighting that the
vulnerabilities
are not the same value as they are in
the enterprise because they often
have errors they often lack a lot of
context
and many times the patches don't even
actually fix the vulnerabilities
and so we wanted to have real data to
support that and so generally speaking
we find most of the vulnerabilities are
kind of deep within the ics
network and control elements and similar
those ones bordering the enterprise that
give
access to the ics are definitely a good
place to start
with your vulnerability patching inside
the ics i want to get kind of east-west
traffic analysis start understanding how
things are communicating
worry about native functionality because
it's not about malware dropping in and
doing something
it's about an adversary abusing native
functionality in those environments and
how to do that
but getting access is a big pouring
point of the
story so focus on the bordering the
enterprise ones to start with
then look at the impact your cvss the
scores around these things are not gonna
be the best way to view it from an
operations perspective
the the way to view it from an
operations perspective is what can you
do with this vulnerability
we found in 2020 that
36 of the vulnerabilities caused both a
loss of view
and a loss of control if you were to
take advantage of them well that's a
good place to start looking at those
much more than the ones that didn't have
loss of view or control the 62 percent
so maybe about 62 of the vulnerabilities
were kind of the bottom of the
pile for you and then you should figure
out if they really make sense for you
we also found that the vulnerability
data is just wrong time and time again
in 2019 it was 30 but in 2020 43
of the advisories that came out for
vulnerabilities were wrong
had the incorrect data either cvss was
wrong the vulnerability was wrong
sometimes it was the wrong software or
hardware
entirely and so the point i'm saying is
not
don't patch i know a couple of you are
leaving this presentation going going to
your security staff saying rob lee said
don't patch no that's not what i'm
saying
what i'm saying is if you want to take a
risk-based approach to patching
the data needs massively cleaned up with
a lot of context added to it because
it's missing an ics where you might have
it in the enterprise
the last thing we want to be doing is
bothering operation staff
to go do something more than they're
already doing on data that's wrong or
irrelevant
we also found that when it when it came
to the advisories a lot of them were
missing
any sort of context or action and we
found that 26 percent of advisories
didn't have a patch when they were
announced at all hey there's a
vulnerability
that sucks good luck that's not very
awesome i mean it's good to tell us
about the vulnerability so we can
monitor or do something about it
but if patching and segmentation is your
main strategy
you're obviously being left out in the
cold a little bit
we we further found that um you know
kind of as we saw that evolution
that 64 of the advisories
had no practical mitigation advice you
know and 61
also had no alternative mitigation so it
was basically patch
or don't and there wasn't you know hey
you can restrict this port or you can do
these other actions and many of our
industrial environments you just
simply can't patch it's okay don't beat
up your operator so the fact that
patching has taken down more power sites
than russia china and iran combined
um so let's figure out how to do it
correctly with the right data
and then you know if we're going to
patch
make sure that we we plan it but if we
can't patch
have alternate guidance what else can we
do what can we do at a firewall level to
take care of ourselves
and so the the way that we think about
it is actually
a standard developed over at cert cc
where they look at it as a never next
now forget the cvss
forget the those other kind of contexts
on the dragon's intel team what they do
is they sit down they look at it from
are there threats actively exploiting it
is the vulnerability posing operational
issues
or is it wrong or is it not that useful
or is the vulnerability just giving you
native functionality
features that are already present in the
system you don't need a vulnerability to
get the password that's already hard
coded into it that doesn't make sense
um and so we put everything into that
kind of this never next now
um and the idea of course is to take a
lot of things off people's plate
uh in 2020 30 of the vulnerabilities
fell into a never category
unless you were just flush with
resources there's no reason to take a
look at them
63 fell into the next hey your next
opportunity next time the plants down
for maintenance next time you're in
there
take a look at these 63 percent only
seven percent of vulnerabilities were
worth
causing a fit over saying like we really
need to take advantage of this now
threats are actively going after this
or it has so much impact that we just
really need to be aware of it
and so getting into a state with
vulnerabilities where you're a partner
to operations
and not coming in with your checklist
saying why haven't you patched all of
these things
is going to be a thing that's culturally
good but it's also backed by data of the
right thing to do from a security
perspective
um and additionally like when we talk
about the vulnerabilities again kind of
as we
we try to modify the vulnerabilities we
look at taking those incorrect data
and we look at trying to add additional
context to it hey the cvss is wrong it's
actually higher than you think because
the way that we do it in ics here's a
specific guidance on how to
mitigate this or like block things to
the port level here's context of the
operational impact
you know this is what we do this is not
to say just go get our stuff
this is to say this is what we do to
help our clients this is the kind of
stuff you should be doing as a security
team
if you're going to go help your
operations staff i see too many security
teams that throw a csv over the plant
personnel that says
here's a list of the vulnerabilities on
the equipment go tell us if you haven't
what you're doing about it
you could provide a lot more value the
operations by telling them hey here's
the ones we actually care about
here's the mitigations that you can take
if you don't patch
please let us know if you have this and
if you need any help again it's all
about collaboration and approaching them
as partners
from a engagement perspective and kind
of instant response and assessments and
red teaming and similar and what are
what our team was doing out in the year
um what we saw is that most companies
have extremely limited visibility or
collection or logging or insights in
their ics
and and there's a little bit of bias
with this number where
obviously clients that come to us to
start their journey
you wouldn't expect them to have done a
ton of visibility things they often come
to us for
visibility and helping them understand
what's going on
and so from a security professional
perspective this one might seem a little
obvious
but it's actually a very important stat
outside the security practitioner
community
most of your ceos and board of directors
have an expectation that a lot of things
have happened in industrial security
usually they think all the compliance
work they've done is related to all the
security work that should have been done
or they think that they're just in a
really good place anyways where
most facilities out there have taken a
patch and segment
strategy that's their strategy and so
showing the broader community outside of
practitioners
that actually broadly speaking you know
in our
cases in our collection 90 of the
facilities 90
of the customers we go into don't have
any collection of visibility
that is an eye-opening stat if you ever
want to be good with resilience
if you ever want to talk about instant
response you need that visibility and
collection
up front we've we've done a number of
instant response cases just the last two
months
where we're going and talking the client
saying look you have no logging
you have no data you have no sequence of
event logs on the system you have no
uh network monitoring you have nothing i
don't know what you want us to do
like you're such in a not good place
that the best we can do
is help make sure you're not still under
attack
uh or still going through an incident
and you need to go and do all these
different architectural invisibility
kind of things
we also see just again a lot of poor
security perimeters
that's not a stat to say you're doing a
bad job that's a stat to say if your
entire strategy is segmented
uh that those segmentation strategies
aren't solid
and it's a poor strategy in my opinion
um we also saw a nice increase where
people
last year 100 of the people that came to
us that said that they had an air gap
had
multiple routable connections we have
far less people
after that stat went out claiming to
have air gaps but we did find
more segmented environments not
necessarily truly air-gapped
but as people are getting in there they
are trying to put more focus on that
and we also found that a hundred percent
of our instant response um engagements
had shared credentials from i t to ot
often times in it active directory
doing active directory and domain
controller work in the operation side of
the house
and uh that is a highway of death that
ransomware operator
hit the it side go right to the plant
side not not a great time
so that's a good one to get ahead of the
other thing
as we start rolling down and i'll go
over into the break just a little here
um on the solar wind side we saw so many
people call us saying hey don't activate
the
the instant response retainers we're
good we don't have solar winds
that like a day later would be like oh
crap we have solar winds
and what they were finding is that
either plant personnel bought solarwinds
and didn't tell them
or they had it but they didn't have an
accurate inventory
or integrators and service providers
were using it in their environments
anyways
or in some cases it was white labeled
into vendor security stacks
where they didn't say solarwinds in the
box it said like you know vendor name
security solution and it was actually
solarwinds
and the reality is if you looked for the
technical indicators of the initial
intrusion
related to solarwinds it was compromised
software if you look for the initial
indicators
and you had the logs and data it was
really really simple to say hey we saw
it but we didn't see any follow-on
activity we're okay
if you didn't have the logs and the data
what was a simple like
two hour check then was a you have no
idea
if there was external connections if you
missed that initial data
if they came in it was a tier one kind
of top tier you know team
they burrow in and you have very little
chance of finding them unless you do
extraordinarily deep skilled hunting in
that environment
and and what the public i don't think
fully captured is there's a
ton of industrial facilities that were
compromised
not had vulnerable software they were
compromised because it was compromised
software
all across the world through things like
maintenance links
with the vendors as well as directly in
their environments
with none of that visibility and logging
therefore most the community has no idea
if there was follow-on activity in their
ics
or not that's not a great place to be in
um
it's okay to try to talk about
prevention but everybody focuses on
prevention how would we prevent the next
one i don't care
on the next one i don't care about
preventing it what i care about is
instead of
having a multi-month or multi-year long
process to try to figure out if we're
screwed
let's have a two-day process and with
the right you know
forensic capabilities the right
monitoring the right visibility et
cetera
you can be more resilient by having a
better detection and response strategy
why we push detection response a lot
because we've over focused historically
on prevention
and prevention eventually fails another
interesting one is that
a number of teams felt very confident in
their ability to detect like a red team
activity
um what we found in 2020 is that 85
of our clients um had completely
ineffective abilities to detect
the dragos red team on getting to their
crown jewels
so not just like we could break into the
ics but like we could modify
uh a safety system or we could actually
get down into your uh
most sensitive control elements and so
that's not a shame on the security team
that is a
hey you may not have as effective
detections as you think
and when we do see people that roll out
detection response strategies a lot of
it is host-based logging or like a sim
work
and that's it's an okay place to start
or it's an okay place to have
but again you really want to get network
telemetry to understand especially these
systems that are largely
not able to have endpoints and a lot
with functionality and a system of
system design
where people are abusing native
functionality more than they need new
exploits or malware
you want to be able to see how the
systems behave and come together and so
forth
and so it's definitely an area for
improvement because again i can't harp
on it enough
if your entire strategy is segment and
patch or maybe deploy antivirus
it's a very preventative focus strategy
you need to also bring up your detection
response
i'm in a good case study of that this
one was a really cool one um what we
found
is uh this was a locomotive i i gotta
say that the rail industry
just so many good folks i'm really
stepping up to do a lot of good security
work
i think they've got an awesome
opportunity to uh do some fantastic
things in the community and bring their
insights and share them i've seen the
real industry move this past couple
years more than
last decade and what we found that we're
able to do
on a locomotive is actually modify
the logic directly on controllers in
such a way
that when the engineering workstation
plugs into it the controllers auto
execute the code and the engineer
workstation auto executes code
and we were able to modify the logic in
such a way that it propagated malicious
logic automatically
across the locomotive as engineer
workstations were getting plugged in and
similar
and the propagation from an engineer
workstation to controller
of malicious logic is something you've
probably heard about before there's a
2010 case study on doing something very
similar in a
nuclear facility somewhere and being
able to see
that that same tactic on different
systems in different ways in different
industries is still effective
um is a great place and to start and
that's why i talk about like learning
the lessons from intel
it's not about i need an indicator and i
need to know who's attacking my system
it's no here's a viable attack path that
we've seen before
we're going to teach you about that you
should go apply it to your systems
too often i see companies go oh we're
not in the nuclear sector
and we don't use that vendor therefore
we're good
no does that tactic still work does that
technique still work does it
work apply to your systems and your
environment take a look at it let's
learn from each other let's learn from
these attacks
especially since it's low frequency high
impact we can take a look at the things
we see and really dig into them as case
studies and stay on top of that so what
an awesome opportunity to to go in and
teach people different things and again
to see whole industries kind of uh
get ahead of it so as we boil this all
down as i end my presentation
and as we we get through all of our
lessons learned throughout the year
it boiled down to us for these top five
recommendations
you know i i like the 20 critical
controls and things like that but i just
think it's too much
i i think the expectation that you need
to do everything in your ics security
portfolio that you're doing in your
enterprise security is wrong there's
four or five things that if you do well
in industrial
you've got a world-class industrial
security program we don't need to copy
and paste
everything over most things aren't even
effective to copy and paste over
but increasing ot network visibility by
far
you can't see it can't protect it i know
everyone says that but it's true but
more importantly it's it's
validate the prevention you think you
have validate the segmentation you think
you have
understand and be able to get to a
detection program to see the malicious
behaviors in your environment what
you're dealing with
um there's so much value that comes from
visibility seeing failing network cards
and you know
battery packs on plc's that are failing
there's operations value in doing that
um the second is identifying and
prioritizing crown jewels you have a lot
of stuff in your industrial environments
you can't do
everything and some things aren't worth
every security effort that you're doing
you know the wellhead that's generating
a thousand dollars a day
is not the same value as the refinery
generating a thousand dollar
a million dollars an hour and so figure
out your assets that make most sense
but then in those assets what are the
crown jewels the safety system the
engineer workstation
the the system that i can modify the
most control with
the domain controller that happens to
have access to everything figure out
your crown jewels and start there
definitely boost your instant response
capabilities we find time and time again
that companies think they have an
instant response plan but there's like a
paragraph
for the ics inside the enterprise or
it's something like call the plant
manager
and then the plant people are like who
the hell are you and what are you
calling us for
um go figure out an ics specific part of
that strategy and go train
go get like a tabled up exercise go do a
tabletop exercise on
realistic injects with your operation
staff and your security staff
pound for pound best training and
culture you know kind of bridge you can
provide
validate the network segmentation again
i don't think network segmentation
is the best strategy but most of you
historically have depended on it so go
validate it because
we're finding that 80 plus percent of
the time it's off
so these are good stats to go to your
your execs or others and say hey
we're probably in the 80 percentile you
know what the community is let's take a
look at this
and then lastly if you're able separate
that it ot credential management
uh specifically the adaptive directory
stuff as well that's rough
try to get ahead of that the best you
can so i just want to say thank you all
of the report and all the data
associated with us at downdragons.com
y ir so you're in review which like i
said we try to make all this transparent
and out to the community for you all to
use appreciate you hanging in there