and I went very badly the lesson as a
software developer that day and that was
awesome but if you fast forward a few
years from them a tiny camera without
pen tester and then I have a visual
sources you can see the trace and then I
secured it for some time no idea if she
doesn't ask any more questions so she
doesn't recognize no with that
information technology please allow me
to do the about the slides which the
sole purpose of is devoting our students
my ideas put the rest of the talk so
this is me sometimes this is me act when
you do that and I'm gonna
and I
[Music]
I'm totally obsessed with this they
called our office who here was that i
wasa feeding on once they made you have
it on top there in the city and so
obsessed then I hope to the birds all
over the world that are obsessed with
the security of software and we have
meetings and because we want and I'm so
obsessed that I hope around the chapter
in the city and is third a project
called this I have like this crazy but I
wanted to
right now you want something that you
secure if you want I want the easy
waiting whatever way you were gonna do
the thing to be the secure way I want to
be hard to do something with no hurts do
that can make security teams feel a
little bit insecure I really like um so
what do you what do developers do
sometimes sometimes they're like let's
ask the security team for a couple
instead I'm going to write my basics
before including its wasted secure this
sounds like that's what like you don't
want that
can we talk about resign and they're
just like I talk to you after he's gone
[Music]
they just clean the important things to
do this is a basically okay so they -
really under typically I was just like
the biggest problem for me is a scary
person because like the developers know
the answers about their apps and I need
you so what do you people do you need to
elephant
well we send them automated reports like
reports from automated scanners or
whatever and we send them false
positives sometimes sometimes we don't
get usable security advice who cares
heard of NIST
it's like a standard in America so in
Canada is a better call the item is -
you threw around it's like a snare word
and I feel I've had security teams where
they you know the Java developer writes
us and we're like
we do it and they send them a link
doing this because that's what you
basically just did like they asked you
some helpful in might just turn right so
and sometimes you're seeing gait like
they're slowing down security and
sometimes you'll be in a project and I'm
acquirements your physical safety kind
of security like and as we saw in the
very first guide sometimes they can be a
little insensitive would tell you the
results of their security testing and
make you feel a little bit and I wrote
this full talk because two years ago or
a year and a half ago my dad said honey
it's 2016
why can't we make software by now can
you just this is the reason why like if
we can't reach other sites looking into
it and so all these things make people
feel insecure and halfway through their
jobs
and when I looked into it today the
social scientists of one things was for
a million years when you feel insecure
about your jobs
it leads to predictably bad behavior so
like my research session I was like
but they're predictably bad behavior is
deviant behavior do you want people to
be eating some of those these processes
that you just made for them to follow
that's not good right people feel
insecure and they have moral
disengagement you don't want people are
feeling a bit flexible with their morals
who might not be very pleased with you
handling sensitive data that does not
sound ideal we have reduced job
involvement people who are not going to
stay late to fix that last thing or just
search that last part of functionality
to make sure they have complete test
coverage and then you have a weird one
organizational citizenship so this is
positive workplace activity that you do
I'm going to explain it with an analogy
though which is that when I read that
dies right way so imagine you're in the
kitchen you are by yourself no one else
was there you realize you're the only
one and you were pouring coffee and you
spill a little bit on the counter so if
you have an organizational citizenship
behavior the first thing I do is go grab
my paper tell them you'll wipe it out
and if you feel very invested in the
workplace this is a place that you
respect you feel curl it if there's
water
my life ain't like chemicals on my hand
but if you poor organizational behavior
what you are going to do is you're gonna
make the company because that's the
other guy's fault etc and that person is
not gonna have fantastic coat the person
is not going to be a great security team
member and if you have these two teams
fighting against each other all the time
does bad behavior in my opinion it's
part of the reason we end up women it's
good software this is my hypothesis of
the whole talk and I hope you agree with
me because the rest of talks just how we
can solve this problem because that's
the part I consider interesting of every
talk like here's this bug I found but
here's what I can do so let's just talk
about solutions yes
simple awaits them did you or gonna
appreciate that so let's talk about what
we could do so on the next slide and I'm
gonna have words
and I know the first thing everyone does
when I see words
they read the words because I used to
only have words on my slides i stoled
that it was not acceptable
no people had picked it so it's kind of
half words but I'm going to get it with
you don't have to rush ahead which kind
of you want okay so here's the plan I've
made it to clear plan and we're just
going to dissect the plan for us to talk
with ideas so we're gonna support our
diversity and our security team and the
Resta fight with processes training
resources so they have all the things
they need to get their job done and well
and know they do it well and then we're
going to initiate and maintain culture
change sounds easy right there I have
like over 20 ideas a penny conversion so
let's start with per sentence I have
that places where one please had to do
21 separate steps to get approval to run
one scan Oh sometimes they have you have
people four levels above me in the
organization so to prove something I did
a sperm every day work they'd have two
copies
ask them told me to do this boring
things calling me I'm just kidding but
processes like that don't work right
it's really hard to get things done and
it's really discouraging for employees
if they do all of these things really
fast the person you want to talk to is
like the person's database and make
impacting rate so this is available in
processes that work that number one
thing I think you should do I think
people should get an ADD section
including this baby baby incentive ok so
application security or OPSEC as I call
it for short it's the security of
software so in apps like team would be
the part of your degree attainment
actually understands how to make secure
software if you don't have one and
you're working a big enterprise I feel
that you need one right like if you were
going to set up with four people you're
not gonna have enough sex in it but if
you work at a place like where I work we
have a whole bunch of those things if
you were going to be enterprise
Department if you have a 400 developers
you should have some outside people
people dedicated to making sure their
software is secure
and that's whether they're doing quarter
views are 32 developers we have security
or they're adding automated security
tests like negative unit tests to your
demo pipeline these people should be all
over your developers and helping them
make secure acts every day if you need
the Verizon pre-trip work but you should
totally read the summary and the past
two years in the number one cause of
breaches is in secure software great and
it weighs 26 percent one year and then
is authority the other year if you look
at your budget for software you better
if you look at your budget for security
a huge percentage at 25 to 40 percent is
not okay it's AB SEC so you can serve
next I have job for that hot SEC team
you just hired the first thing you want
to do is you want to start loaning them
it's people doing giant projects and
some people does the partnership and
that's where basically this person will
follow the sdlc
with your team and every time they
and you a security this person handled
said they might go back into the
security team even get the person that
knows the answer to that thing they
might brainstorm with you and look over
your design with you and help you solve
problems but rather than you going to
various different groups within the
security team or there's one person who
can help you and you should not assign
those person to 25 different projects so
they become a huge bottom line because
there's a bunch of little work they need
to do I would say three projects Cisco
three big projects that time but this
this is how I got introduced the apps I
connect and now the partner should not
before fixing so this is make me right
then we should say security earlier
sometimes known as pushing left for
money Security's that as part of your
systemic cycle rate if you're trying to
make software and you don't have any
actual security steps as part of making
your software like if you have a project
with a really take timeline and you have
no time dedicated I need to create
activities do you think they're going to
happen probably not right now it's going
to feel like a big code review or
anything like that it has their time to
do it you want to insist though be late
have no flame security and really
you need to plan this so if you can that
steps like if it is fine to your system
development lifecycle this will really
help and another thing that we can do is
break security activities into smaller
pieces I have worked up a lot of places
where they're like oh I need to do a
secure border of you so everyone might
code freeze for three weeks when I go do
this or maybe up it will be back to you
but like four or five weeks with results
it's not super realistic anymore they
with people doing DevOps in a general
and sprinting the security team actually
needs to sprint to and we knew those by
doing the smaller security activities so
if you're going to do static code
analysis you don't have to scan the
entire crew page you can just scan the
new feature rate if it's again just the
person change or for each sprint so that
your developers do you could scan for
just cross-site scripting let's say one
time and then the next time just
injection vulnerabilities and just go
like that and cut up
nobody's in pieces and they just handed
a whole bunch of bugs that are the exact
same everything is just like being in
the loo with my favorite name I don't
want a salad with you results what I do
I do it in production I think we should
never ever send results from a security
tool to developers that we have not read
and ensured that everything is not false
positive everything needs to be a true
positive that's in there positive you
are ruining all trust that they ever had
on a security team because you you have
a webmix here you have a scanner you
have all these tools and background to
go look for this
well the developer doesn't have those
things and they're like the security
person who told me there's ten things
wrong when I've been chasing that one of
them for like three weeks I can't find
anything and when they realize that
you've handed them before it's
positively wasted days and days and days
of through time from now on every result
assignment was in question and when he
validated will be impressed the melody
but I know that some scanners have
apparently
that's a salad a it's not what I mean I
mean like the man really testing to make
sure but it's actually there because
there might have tons in the toilet
sometimes much false positives that's
just the way life is and there's both
negatives what's that by training when I
talk about training that don't mean
don't click on this one or general IT
security awareness training I mean if
you are a coder I mean they you would
have secure coding training or if you
are an architect like you design
applications you design systems threat
modeling training or secure design
training great like you want to make
sure that people get the training
something I should know how to do what
they're doing because I don't know how
it is in suis M by Annoying North
America when you go to university or
college for computer science they don't
teach you to security like there might
be ones last but it's cursory or lame
makes another apparent like you know
must have 10 you don't learn how to see
what I see inputs really well like these
are basic things
No so okay so first off you don't have
to know everything see how this guy's
rest it's because he needs to know
everything before I was in security as a
developer and sometimes I forget that
when we were feeling like that but you
can actually you can I don't know the
answer but that's fun that you can do
that and you can ask for training right
like if there's a thing that you do all
day and you're like you know what
things are changing I want to brush up
on this there's not always money for
community I know this but there's tons
of free stuff on the internet now like
when the internet was just beginning we
have where's my Twain have to look
through like pages and pages and pages
are just like a brand of things that
nothing to do is what you look for that
was almost all the corner but now you
can be like I wouldn't normally quite
impressive scripting in my app what do i
do / - this and I'm like network in the
bit that some people trying to have this
excited right so don't feel like you
need to know everything that's the first
step second step what if we keep
security listens to everyone in my team
right what if we
[Music]
yes what if there are free-living am i
trying to call giving free training to
the Coker's last month and we had a
hundred people come came and we just
showed them how to hack apps like let's
spend three hours just punching this hot
and cold man in the face
we used to tell everyone how freaking
the bank and everyone was like I'm gonna
run back I can do this
please don't get fired because about
only like tons of developers came in and
people want to know this you teach them
this a lot I'll be excited about it
another thing I would have to say is
don't stop I was talking to some people
once and they're like we gave this to
public first training and they still
rate grab me act like when 2012 you
think you've had some employee turnover
so please don't stop job Club is a
really good way to learn new things but
when I suggest this I'm not really
necessary
this week I learned about incident
management because a really bad incident
happened and I always not supposed to be
involved Meyers on his phone call for
some of the reasons and then I went and
looked at the thing I'm like hey I can
read that and they're like what I'm like
I'm a nerd
I had the bestest obfuscated code it
looks like SQL injection and then I was
created to but it got me super addicted
to security so a way that you can
convince the teams to work a little
better together is if you win funny each
other to do job shadowing it sounds
crazy but it's really amazing and it's a
great way to record to the security team
cases um resources a lot of people tell
me the relationship we have the best
intentions but we have like one a
knapsack person and one 2,000 developers
or we have this great team of security
people but none of them have had any
training and also
the tools and we don't want people to
like try to get it so expression blood
from a stone like let's make it possible
so the first resource I would want to
get to developers would be a weather
security standard what is that it's a
good 8 to 10 page document about how you
make a secure app like what this
community actually wants from you I'm
not just answers we just throw them if
you follow these ten pages worth of
ideas if you're gonna do a file cheers
through systems we're going to look for
it like we expect you haven't done like
this and then we write it in developer
rewards so instead of saying your
session should be your sessions where
they should be as ephemeral that's a
security word that's non-developer word
and it's a fake it means don't give it
to them for a vague requirement because
you're gonna get a vague results you
want to say you know after five minutes
of idle time session IDs expire or 15
minutes or whatever it is that you want
really be super specific and then you'll
have a little bit jobs that look like
that and then when you go to test you
take this thing that you just made it
and attest to it right like so many
places they don't have no guidance for
developers of what they want this is the
number one thing you just remember
anything from this from the top please
remember this very nice when you made
this very tender don't make it a link to
mist don't make it 300 page long in
sales French
that's you copied from like the Oh
awesome security testing guide where the
application security verification
standard or anything like that
make it eight cents to de cobre it's
like I want you to add all the external
apps to be HTTPS only that's it don't
care how you accomplish it you want to
force it on the server that's cool and a
thirty hitters that's cool I don't care
or these days of security headers we
want if you are gonna have these
security headers and want reasons
radiant 90s you're gonna sign off on the
risk another thing I've seen their word
summer months and I was like we need
security standard and she said we have
one and I'm like grades I was on the dev
team for eight months you should go to
someone's desk we walked around from
desk to desk to desk to desk
and no one heard of this never
so then she's like behind us in your
link and then four days later she's a
catfight I'm like so you don't have web
apps and like you paid for one but you
don't have one and they eventually found
it the consultant I copied and pasted
that lost top ten in the sands 20
persons 25 into a document
literally like that's enough on this
slide okay so I'm giving tools to people
so that they can do their jobs and so
they can do my job because there's
always way more of them than there are
with me I read somewhere once and I gave
everyone's that so that is the big blue
circle with the lightning through it
it's free it's from Allah and it's
asking
it's not gonna find everything that's
wrong with your app but is gonna think
the easiest to find stuff and I told all
the developers I want you to fix all
those things before it comes to me
because I'm going to be worse and if I
find things that that could've found I
am going to come to your desk and doing
this is once you teach them how to use
it safely to make sure that there's no
messes it's just such a good deal and a
lot of these are free like I know that
we couldn't afford the licenses to some
of the really expensive tools for like
your entire development scheme but you
can certainly give them the open-source
free ones rather than a mystery to come
up with like more advanced tools perhaps
and I also want to note that just
because something's free does not mean
it's not awesome there's a really
amazing open-source tools that will
always be able to toolkit ok so who's
paying as someone who was a consultant
someone who's been in a plea and someone
who very briefly was a see so it's being
manager sucks you know consultants cause
of money Tools cost money licenses to
have all that cost money but when you
add all of the Apple
cheaper than a breach no matter what
it's all cheaper if you took 30% of your
security budget starting and then an
adequate 30% and started doing not suck
and then you don't have a breach in the
next five years definitely still saved
money you know that sounds crazy but
look at how expensive their breaches
I think they're two million dollars on
average and that's including the baby
which is for like nothing where the
important happened that's crazy like
companies go under because of this all
the time so if your boss is like
hesitant to sign just remind us on that
breach take advantage of free stuff just
because it's free doesn't mean it's not
good you have a chapter about lost in
the city you can ask if your company can
host them and then you tell the first to
go
that's that's a part of how I got put as
well I joined up a lot and I figured if
I collagen your neck could help them
think which talks they're going to have
the things I wanted to learn so that was
awesome
it should only encourage you if you're
interested
outside to join these guys because
mostly everything's free but also
because these are the experts this is
the only non biased data that you can
get up there that's on this topic ok so
the next thing is culture change which
can be heard but also it's a name ray
because if you do all of these things
culture should already be changing that
you want to do things to make sure it
stays that way you want to stop stop
blaming each other for so far
if you're gonna have so appreciate you
have an incident or something that
happens we should have a post-mortem I'm
sure you all do that where you get
together after the dust has settled and
talk about how this happened and it
should never be that it was Alice's
fault or Bob's fault
it should be what safeguard was missing
that allowed this person to do that
what process was birthday did we not
teach them they say was this not clearly
labeled so they didn't know that they
should have done this with it right when
we stop blaming people
these are somewhere and I managed
and we did this is beautiful so no
blaming in our new culture we also know
that people save face right we never
like whenever possible let people save
face don't rub people's noses in a
mistake I think oh this thing happened
and then just move on I've seen a lot of
cases where it's like Obama now is like
this again to work here another thing we
can do is we can co-locate the security
team and the developers on the same
floor or any same building as have
social defense to
which might sound like a bit of all
those who are gardening but yes we've
only heard to someone's face if you or
if you're waiting for the code for teas
if you drink tea and then you know
you're waiting with someone else you get
to know them later it's a lot more
difficult to be to be rude but if you I
noticed a lot of us in modern days we
work remotely but if you can co-locate
it's much much better I have seen it
where the security team is almost to
their one side because they're doing -
sensitive things and love Allah but it
can really make the developers and I
I've heard it's a lot easier to be a
jerk in email then window this place
okay so this is a message for the
conference organizers it really liked
the keynote this morning because it was
not negative that's good
please don't look he knows about
absolutely are so many IT security
conferences I go to and
so everything's worse let me tell you
about those problems never gonna do it
just get worse that's discouraging I
feel like people should be up here
because they have ideas of how things
can get better and how we can fix things
and we still need to talk about problems
I can't pretend they're not there but
it's you know I feel should be like
let's go into battle together because
that's what we're doing great
I mean I was saying during her job that
she's in the military and in military
and those motors there's like people
doing cyber because that is where we are
fighting wars now and we were defending
like our companies money we're defending
our own money
we're defending our critical
infrastructure we're defending our
democracy and so I don't think we should
be discouraging anyone that works in IT
security because we have enough
discouragement for bad hackers okay so
this next one I think we should lead by
example so we're going to go back to
work probably on Monday and then you can
forget some
right or you can think about them in
unboxing them instead do you want it to
you can think of some of these ideas and
see if any of them may helpful okay like
maybe there's some processes that can be
improved you could talk to your boss a
bit more if you're a supervisor you
could set an example with your team you
know accepting unprofessional you made
it set an example by holding yourself to
a higher technical standard great
there's there's a lot of things that
I've mentioned all through this talk but
that everyone has mentioned I've been
told this talk and that people will
continue to mention until I think we
finished at 7:30 tonight or 8:00 right
so I encourage you to hopefully whether
there's anything physical notes or
mental notes trying to remember these
things and when you do you're saying an
example everyone else in my office will
see and hopefully over time we can start
changing our cultures the better with
that I'm going to review the claim and
then say one more thing okay so okay so
we are going to enable our security and
developer teams by giving them processes
and training and resources that they
need
the jobs back and then we're going to
initiate and maintain the culture change
exactly our jobs are to enable so quick
here we have works in security yeah okay
so who here doesn't work in security
everyone else have our business or
organization to get whatever third where
did you dine securely that's our whole
job if we're in their way right and I
would like you to take it upon yourself
to remember that when you're making
security decisions in the future like
the biggest complaint that I hear from
everyone ever about working with
security is the answer was no instead of
you know what if we do that's pretty
high risk
can we brainstorm a better way that
maybe like we can do this but it's more
secure but you still get them where you
need to get done and so I am appealing
to you that you consider some of these
ideas you try to remember it's our job
to enable everyone to do you think
securely is not ever a job to stop
what's happening in general with
business or organization or or whatever
it is we're doing our jobs to enable and
with that I'd like to thank you
[Applause]
any of these flights aren't there but
when it's slightly different pictures so
if you want to take a picture you may
want to take a picture of this and also
give away some things for free if you
want to try a catcher for free like that
whole bunch of stickers at the back of a
cute and I will sell five communities
these are made of maple syrup for years
hurting maple syrup that's right these
are made only I'm to decide there's no
sugar etiquette our cheese deliciousness
and so you take like a whole bucket and
melt it down to get
[Music]
okay
so certainly if you would make release
to have a potluck celebrate like
celebrate all your wins right if they've
a security test the first time I've ever
really needed high fives when you know
when I was a consultant at one point I
gave a whole bunch them high fives and I
was like nice considering that you like
would give like little kids like a thing
like you won we'd like stickers and
stuff they're like literally were
shocked you did it and those things are
cheesy like celebrating women's also and
a huge fan of talking clearly but I
didn't use the speak I used to be hosts
so when I raise a developer
million years and just at least once a
month sometimes twice a month I'd have
someone come in and just teach us their
stuff I want to know and then I joined
[Music]
somewhere and we need a security
policemen and when we would have all
sounds like pencil the pencil grounds
and and they security placemats and then
we liked to say it's about security like
a crossword puzzle what security thing
it sounds super cheesy like people use
them like they were all taken home so
like it's working
if recommended once again food for what
the university level one only one oh
it's what you want I would say because
it's free because it's also it's got all
these things like workshop I do 20 30
minutes and everyone's having stuff it's
so much easier and that's always the one
I I see if it was just there also
because it's a free single for that I
spent money on it if you don't end up
getting into it
thank you there were more questions
there's one here and there's one over
there
it's a parental mr. bardington breach it
cost do you have a good
that window is closed I don't remember
but if you read the verse and I'm from
the city where like everyone remembers
fashioning medicine
[Music]
so me doing this is one of the ways we
get more people doing on set also okay
so the queue sang how do we get more
people in the field of application
security so I tend to join us and I
think the best way to find outside
people to make them yourself
that's that's what I've been doing our
networks it's an expensive proposition
also I feel like what if universities
topless or something universities and so
the university in my school is I don't
have a PhD so they're firm that like a
real person
in academia I went to college
we have degree and so there can be an
adjunct professor so I believe they said
it would be four thousand Canadian
dollars per year which is like three
thousand American dollars no per
semester and they're like
[Music]
but they like communicate so late my
diploma in college I work two jobs and I
graduate always now but people like to
find like hundred thousand twenty
thousand going to universities like
North America is very expensive
especially in America and then to have
them not to do security and they're like
oh we don't have to cover it with
something imagine imagine sorry most
brands almost over sir imagine is the
electrician's went to school and then
they taught them when they switch a
light switch we just twist the two wires
and then just shove that you might
they're like oh that's electrician was
topless great thank you so much
[Music]
all right so know you guys are probably
getting a little bit tired but have no
fear because it's time to drink coffee
and eat so yeah it takes to be from a
back spot and fix a puppy eat some bugs
and stuff today it's gonna be stuff like
this door I believe I'll check hopefully
you
[Music]
okay let's get started
help me welcome okay thanks guys for
attending my pocket only one track quits
my second year here love being here look
at the crew the organizers thanks for
happening sure title my cops called
finessing fake firmware security for
Friday fun I'm not even joking I spent
all morning
bug hunting thankful for where end comes
some bugs a portable some things are
going to be in detailed some things are
not going to have a good balance of
effective defense pointing out some some
snake oil puck books and things that are
going on the embedded in hyperspace so
my name is Eric Guzman also known as I
am from Los Angeles recently published a
book up here back in November of 2017 I
don't want to miss this next point in my
talk last year I love pizza and every
single place that someone recommended
last week to go check out the pizza I
went and checked out disappointed I have
[Music]
so I am the chapter leaders from Los
Angeles
I am the co-organizers for abside
California so if anybody would like to
come to LA I mean it's hotter clear that
it is in LA right now
January feel free to ping me involved in
a boss and top security line sex agrees
I have a project leader for the embedded
application security project also a
contributor for the IOT project and
we're going to have some new
documentation coming out for both the
IOT and the internet check currently I'm
with the digital Sciences as well love
to teach definitely ask questions
afterwards I'll be around until Sunday
[Music]
let's get started by the month ten Kurt
state Mel for more security it's going
to point out three different industry
verticals we'll talk about medical
medicals getting better overall
definitely had a lot of regulatory and
lobbyists behind medical firmware and
medical security medical device security
even hospitals as well hospital medical
device deployment security but it's
still pretty bad it's a work in progress
right you know connecting medical
devices to the Internet to the network
or to be networked it's something that's
new I'm automotive it's definitely still
you know learning the security kind of
cultures a lot of different changes
going on from product meeting the car
not reaching the Internet and now it's
exposed to many different interfaces so
you know the kind of embracing of street
culture is occurring now age of bug
bounties between sin to research and if
you can't fix the news there's a lot
going on with an automotive
[Music]
themselves telematic unit's obd2
aftermarket products there's a lot going
on but again before it was mostly based
upon obscure this is the access to
physical system of the vehicle and the
security of that getting access to the
polls were wire to to Smith buses and so
forth so automotive business is
definitely an interesting space and
again it's a place that I kind of have
lived in testing wise with it from the
suppliers going inside as well but this
one was talked a little bit towards the
consumer aspect total mess I had my last
slide
Papa Exodus used to leak security over
at leases for a short period of time and
I know you know the growing pains of
trying to push a culture of security
with no incentive to do so
you know developers have any type of
security coding experience never have
their applications facing I'm good to go
whether it's you see whether it's Lewis
C++ PHP ASP all the kind of event
languages of use they've never they've
never had any type of web facing
products you know there's low margins
and not a lot of incentives it's
definitely you know there's definitely
reasons why the consumer space still has
terrible security
one of the ideas or reasons that appears
lack of regulatory compliance there's no
requirements attached securities
features hotel people get you know
compromise every day which is fine for
me long as you know the catching update
cycle all those absolutely absolutely
which is getting better for the major
manufacturers and it also created a new
sector market where we have these these
devices now being deployed in line to
network or inside your home network to
monitor your devices to monitor
potential threats within your home
network so it's a creep that's kind of
society vertical that we're gonna talk
about on the bid but basically comes to
do horror right we're going to forget it
you know o days from infecting your
devices from your your endpoints your
Mac OS or Windows boxes but you know
there's really no proof we'll get to
some of those claims because in the end
security is hard multiple you know
everybody's responsibility there's
different aspects first let me talk
about embedded and IP as far as
interfaces different entry points
you know everybody kind of tries to go
the complex way right they want to put
these nice new shiny jumps for free
works to handle all the client side and
protections but you know the basics of
you know access control and it may be
you know easier companies like that so I
was talking about some of the big
problems here or within I guess you know
the consumer space and even you know the
new horizon
verticals with these I would see kind of
security hub that promise you know you
the world to get like I said was taking
you from things that they have never
even seen so generally as security
professional I see it actually blue and
you know some of the big companies out
there there are so many products some
what some are doing their due-diligence
and these performing the basics of what
do you see we should be performing at
from the hardware aspect from the
firmware aspect needed mobile but they
also include you know with these
products they're kind of great Intel
things right but they're basically using
your home network at that wrecking town
to cipher and categorize all all the new
data and send it off to you know their
Big Data Platform whatever it is and use
it as families or they all have their
own sparks pretty tough need some of
them you subscribe to some of our bill
too but more and more data points
everyone's heard about the Alexa you
know voice recording send it off to your
your contacts but in this case you know
we're talking about this product there's
the lack of let's say transparency with
regards to you know what it's bill to it
what's the kind of bill materialism of
the devices what's what's the software
framework that it's running on would
sneak you know platform real-time
operation citizen Linux how long was it
in the updated onesie and applied
there's nothing like that you know to
kind of gain to cleanliness or you know
the livelihood
or sort of the product itself look
there's some things where you know the
marketing team takes it and runs with it
and in this case it's these products
that again are selling you with promises
to protect you from whatever it may be
but they're you know not telling you why
and they're basically using kind of a
security type of explanation with that
but we're going to go through and kind
of take apart devices and I guess our
own research coming to one of the last
points here there's no certifications or
activation writing like how how secure
or how how could it be guaranteed or
what level of security can it be I guess
aware of and I think they're working on
that right now so a medical for sure
kind of like the nutritional facts in a
way and the retiring room is for medical
and in the states with the FDA to have
it both materials possible materials so
libraries all the frameworks use all the
versions of them and so it's a good
that's a good way to you know every
other nation verticals and I think even
in China they're requiring software
build materials which is surprising but
still something that they're doing and
another problem for security and
embedded teams you have the margins you
have a device that about the cost of
public dollars and yet to support it for
10 15 years
structure there's not a lot of incentive
to put a TPM or a security chip inside
of a device for secure boot or for any
type of security to store any company
credentials and access Keys API keys so
you usually find a lot of expose secrets
and from our hard coding
unfortunately hopefully we learn from
that and usually if there's a kind of
type of like hardware hardware speech a
few ones that it's probably not probably
not secure meaning it's not verifying
five former images it's not validating
the integrity data or firmware itself
it's not
I'd say the communication the transport
security is probably not doing well
either because maybe the pipe key is
housed within the client so anything
that's private let's say a certificate
and signed by CA and it's hard coded to
a piece of armor you're gonna have to
reissue that certificate otherwise
masquerade as your domain and malicious
content which has happened for a big
device manufacturer and again some of
these devices as well they're never
updated some of them may never be even
connected to the Internet and sometime I
think the GPS the mobility and
connectivity requirements for suppliers
and things like that is to provide
updates for a certain number of years
yeah some sort of OTA function which
again opens up another attack
potentially so problems problems that's
all fine you know we can deal with
problems just a matter of progress but
who's taking advantage of these these
problems and you know the lack of
security and devices are
and creator's malicious users
nation-states who are taking advantage
of you know these vulnerable
small small just home office devices
these consumer devices that have or use
the same kind of basic code base just to
kind of go through let's say you know
one of the main ones one of the main a
four in one skiers right I'm sure most
people here for Brian correct and right
biggest thing about where I was not just
to be honest it was is actually release
of source code of grind source code so
now you know you have super influx and
all these how to that's being
created and just targeting certain
devices that you know the botnet
creators are choosing you know we have
different examples here
pochamma record bottom or they could
join to botnets that are either a zombie
is something killing all the services
that are running that are vulnerable
Rickard bot totally zeros out a
partition of the device and Bridget so
you have to manually reset that device
to defaults which is time for a
consequence X and you also have the
other ones that are taking advantage out
we're gonna put execution water
abilities or command injection
vulnerabilities I won't speak towards
all these but as far as like the you
know and then threat landscape everyone
probably get a blue border and crack the
BK to these kind of proving protocols
that but fuzz tested thought to be
security are now evolving we have even
you know CPU architecture
vulnerabilities that are affecting the
underlying platform of the device itself
so arm for example affected by spectrum
different arm families of the cortex-m
cortex a which is iPhones and his
microcontrollers so vehicles in ours for
real-time up real-time
so could be a number needs to be medical
he also vehicles it could be Russian
control systems but as far as the
development of these botnets and like I
said using mariah template moving
forward there now evolving to not only
change the targets but also change the
the architecture itself so art is a cpu
architecture that was the first botnet
that's been created targeting that
certain architecture then we have some
other ICS frameworks but they're not
even where I could say but what's
happened a lot less been going on as
opposed to you know pre 2017 or it was
mostly just you know CSRF botnets that
are taking advantage of changing you
know Tina's configurations or or admin
page configurations and things like that
now they're actually getting access
shall access to advice and spreading
throughout a local network and infecting
other devices as well and speaking to
each other blocking out other botnets
format app and the kind of steps to to
develop a botnet payload is not it's not
it's not too complex this is something
that I gave a training yesterday we went
through some of this here but we
basically basically extract the firmware
file system you know over the folder
structure is figure out what the
architecture is of the your target
device whatever they D and took the arm
it could be bits which are probably the
most common so once you figure out the
architecture and on the end eNOS it's
just way the computer and the hardware
understanding bytes and bits and things
like that that's how you know Richard
your payloads according to your
architecture quarter to your device so
the payload should have you know some
communication towards either your situ
environment your command control or your
other devices that are going to be
attacked for p2p peer-to-peer
communication so once you create that go
ahead and build that went across
compiler body using appended Bilson
build systems such as build root is
common yeah please another one these are
free as well build up your appeal own
that has your communication configured
and whatever kind of experts you have
within your payloads obviously you want
to test it the an emulation your the
device itself you know and then build it
into your variety code according to you
know whatever ports that target device
listening on whatever banner you're
looking for again with mirai's you know
target hook template for you know
botnets like super super easy it's out
of the way and it's not this little
little to no effort almost like I said
you know simple simplest seven steps or
there's something that can easily be
done especially so with no experience
who wants to you know malicious software
or test you know test certain situations
or could be used for read to me actually
you know to you know keep it throughout
a network who's laterally whatever it
may be and basically developers for
these botnets are thinking that you know
the whole Internet's going to be doomed
because ok so easy everything's being
affected I think there's over like three
hundred four hundred thousand devices
two different botnets we're gonna screw
Sarai whether that's for Tommy
anybody anybody ever played altarpieces
before old school but what they're doing
as far as their developers for these
five axes they're targeting you know
whatever has a high screen time and
that's something that you would do as a
pen tester you know you're assessing a
device and assessing the network you
want to target you know whatever has the
biggest payout in this case you can
target you know the supply chain of
public devices created and the middleman
who creates the you know the base staff
local code system operating system in
this case that would be the original
design manufacture the podium otherwise
known as supplier or a white labeling
who built code and then sells it off to
you know different OEMs and this is
common for you know almost you know
every industry vertical basically you
know whoever can develop piece of
software faster than the gatehouse
I mean it's cheaper or maybe you're
outsourcing to India China Taiwan with
everybody that supplier has you know
their code base their services running
their configurations their debug you
know backdoor code you know with a
number of different types of devices
that are soldiers
oh yes so in this case we have John line
here who was responsible for variety
ship their code and sold it to a number
of different NPR IP cameras doorbells
routers whatever you can think whatever
you can think of you need to jump I sold
it to him that's you know
the bass note of Mariah what we've yet
to see is the suppliers and different
games to vertical Ajit offense medical
or even on a motive in this case where
you have a major supplier for ten units
telematics systems or the platforms for
telematics those two an X for example
and that propagate out you know to a
number of different types of vehicles
but it's common to see you know a ton of
different Oh a manufacturer using QX
typically creations but if there's a
piece of dead code that has hard-coded
credentials that has a backdoor whatever
it may be that's left over from the ODN
and Owen doesn't have a code to review
that that blackbox binary it's dirty
ship and that's the way it's going to be
and again flashing some of these
products and devices it may never happen
and you can never force it and there's
so many different variables you know in
the event you want to force an update
let's say for an OTA use case of their
car you lose connectivity expensive four
cohan's a lot of different use cases so
again very very easy to figure out what
the who the supplier is and that could
be through the constants and then
targeting with that specific supplier
looking for those wonderful devices to
to attack them and compromise and
essentially botnet and some basic kind
of for rectification that lidge's again
we talked about recons figuring out you
know who that supplier is what the
products are and then obviously you have
to get these firmware to review to
analyze to again target your
architecture that in dienes you talked
about build your payload you know try to
find some vulnerabilities within the
software stack and execute you know
with emulating a familiar in the
firmware performing dynamic analysis
runtime analysis and so forth so that's
generally you know what you know kind of
malware developer for IOT botnet so even
pen testers not what ever made me go and
perform some research on your free time
such as you know this morning
70 to 130 something that I did you know
we gathered any number of information
from from the web let's say you can't
find the firmware you know via forums
yeah support what I you know what could
be a good good use of recon is
subdomains something we take over issue
you to see archive you know our clash
sites that have legacy firmware you can
see I've been lucky and pulled firmware
for some certain number of vehicles near
archived sites that were once you know
passive detected and are not anymore
so things to keep in mind kind of
different methods you can use usually
say that the software methods don't work
where you can't get asked to faraway
over you can't get reached out or
anything like that well you're probably
gonna try to go with a hardware method
and try to pull the firmware even
through either through hardware whether
the URJ tag SPI or just miss the buses
and test points that are left and every
piece of hardware because there has to
be test points for manufacturing there's
no question about it
it's just a matter you know security
controls from the manufacturing side you
know what they're placing as far as
username or password or some sort of
security teacher or tenant a tempering
technique for hardware hardware wise and
you know are there any being you know
which holds for firmware again I talked
about you know secure booth integrity
things like that during startup
verifying whether
legitimate from the manufacturer
themselves and some tools but I think
these are probably the main tools to get
started these into analyzing keys in the
firmware definitely good walk right
before a gridlock before its installed
on Kelly Linux still being actively
worked on take a look at github
I had my place commit probably within
the week so there's other newer tools
and most of them are python-based right
Benelux Python for more analysis
Chilton's Python that helps with the
automation of emulating our firm work so
we can test and not have hardware that
way we don't have to buy something it's
kind of that's how we can try the
product and test out the products before
we actually I don't you know next year
device already have racks literally
backs in my office in my house but then
I've common so if I can emulate
by all means I will you can use a good
for where else it's toolkit for that and
that's actually a wrapper for firma dine
which is another rabbit from ki-moon
this is basically a virtual machine type
of the platform for butcher machines and
peddling binaries for certain platforms
which are as far as you know when you
want to analyze the possible contents
let's say you extract the file system
you see that as the pin dead let's see
user SP and things like that you can
point for water to automate some of the
analysis for you are these parts for
parse it for you for a hard-coded
password
private keys it's basically a batch
script that Craig Smith wrote he's the
guy who responsible for the car
Hypertime book so it's a good tool it's
a free tool essentially modular as well
and again some of these tools which have
been what we're not around like three
years ago
so and there's even more tools than just
giving you a few here the last but not
easy for more analysis comparison
toolkit is another type of a tool but we
see we can drag and drop your doubt that
I emptied that bin back TX whatever your
firmware is and they'll do automated
analysis for you so thankfully
University over in Germany has been
working on on this Pacific tool for for
drones and military for their own
purposes but again another free tool but
just keep in mind the amount of
resources and needs I don't know if
anybody has an extra 16 core 64 you
wrinkling around but what I usually do
is and go to sleep wake up see what's
going on see you know do the next day
again otherwise it'll consume around but
it's similar to the mobile security
space with mobile security I love free
Python tools as well support for mobile
security framework literally literally
drag and drop the engine back for
example a web application so our tools
are evolving they're free we have you
know more in able to do research more in
able to to validate verify and check
with the manufactures are claiming it's
fun it's fun to find issues also fun to
mix Asian business usually the point is
to discover these files but also have
them fix them hopefully they're open to
it usually they are
the culture shifting in the industry as
a whole
oh we can't see that but this is the web
UI for for my renounces American toolkit
but it categorizes even using ancient
past where we've had big walk in there
by default and extracts your file system
for you an automated way so I would
definitely check it out if you want to
get into something for more analysis
like I said you don't have to know
anything you know we use the tool but
there's time coverage coverage issues
obviously it's not going to look for you
know specific things related to energy
vertical it's only looking for you know
certain certain streams certain
expressionist things like that so many
analysis is definitely you know a must
but with free tools you know it's easier
to to help again promote research and to
learn and expose people who should be
you know sharing what what licensing is
useful if you're using GPL to publish
your source code okay this is a kind of
controversial topic right
publishes their their source code if
you're using GPL I know over at Linksys
you know we basically didn't publish on
our support site we had up someone's
like random debug for the WTC example
but basically this device is a semantic
and corporal Clark home router is what
it is so it's supposed to secure your
local network and it's using a version
of open wrt and again they're called out
for not you know releasing their source
code by certain licensing we get
controversial but it's cool right cuz
we're all happy recently to configure it
out
seriously who's a rather that was just
mentioning has to ship prevention system
it has deep packet inspection so it's
basically looking at all your traffic
it's one of those like well it is it is
symmetric so it's like you know they
have life poverty so they really want
your whole life basically in your house
so they're gonna look through all your
traffic there you have your social for
the people who do have my flock services
but the idea is you know again to secure
your entire kind of personal identity
and your traffic and your your devices
there are two devices and personal
devices from attacks and from they seat
back doors so let's do during research
which I know this company company in
addition some some good research on this
product specifically I spent some time
they're pulling down the front we're
shifting 13 we see what I can find
but as far as the research research is
concerning actually done their due
diligence and you know invested in a
secure hardware platform or with a chip
that has a secure element and a half
glass cube ooh I've enabled through and
they also have a ticket each X and they
verify their chains which we can you
should be right at the promise of the
world but at the end of the day they
didn't do some basic things like I've
seen you literally done with the latest
firmware just with this curl request all
it's looking for is if it's coming from
this host which is pretty funny but it
ended up being there's a remote code
execution plan injection via bluetooth
to get access to the firmware but the
end of the day continue have other
products out there so we had to talk
about the northern core router so the
routers like cleat locks again they
either go in line with your router or
they literally listen passively and King
box with Peaks on blue succour and has
their own similar gradient our semantics
has their own intelligence their Peaks
thing box has their own which is a
digital fence probably not as common
it's a heavy H beam iOS really kind of
equatorial networking all the divisive
thing Network
I guess the kind of cool thing did this
release all these devices I'm going to
find
at least last year or within the last
year so this one release in August late
August last year but the cool thing is
that it expands your external IP space
and closes up ports and sends you report
safety reports on what's hoping oh it's
closed so when you think about you can
key the vulnerabilities of you know
piercing your firewall access control
their sugar your NAT basically can help
you with you know from that aspect but
it's not something that's been popped
open yet I was trying to make the firm
earlier didn't have no luck but we keep
trying to probably just buy the device
and pop it open but offender box anybody
heard this one before
similar thing plugs into your network
Bennie visited some of some additional
research here first with a defendant but
he says web filtering for malicious
sites kind of you know was with like DNS
as an example and there's any type of
fishing or anything like that potential
malicious sites of a redirect you to
kind of a splash page but again this is
one of those ones that claims to
identify backdoors claims to identify
vulnerabilities and software and
different versions of vulnerabilities in
software which was debunked and proven
not to basically what the penny did was
put a vulnerable camera command
injections at publish CDs on the network
for over a week no alerts
nothing happened and along those same
lines
this device is supposed to do a
vulnerability assessment supposed to
actively probe and perform a number of
different tests doesn't see how it
doesn't say what type of message using a
third-party
whatever maybe but basically they
weren't doing anything we buddy do is we
can put that camera put another horrible
idea device and then exploit the non
reported bug is zero day within dealing
a dealing product and box with anything
so forget one of those things were you
know you're behind products you know
secure be more aware identify potential
threats and get promising you the world
it's definitely not you know the route
to go doing your due diligence as a
manufacturing they see the marketing
team running with it the funny thing
though is they had a back door
the back door is a hard coat with a
hard-coded SSH SSH access for their
support team once you reboot the device
which it's carefully should never never
do that never never do that that wasn't
any right checking if they're walking or
like talking it and they definitely are
totally bugs product is not what it
claims to be
they have vibration too but I hear it's
all of the same you know development
production builds a lot of comments it
comes to code comments and code here's
some of the common ones you have that
gears armor which is powered by
bitdefender box you know we're doing
what they're supposed to be doing we're
not I guess been working together
partnering I think it's supposed to do
that blown a really good session we're
talking about here you know promising
you scan it you know all your devices
and that
access you know it's interesting to me
these claims are gonna prove it you know
and then give the DNS sheep's browsing
with malicious sites and I still love
the zero day exploits because obviously
you can protect exerting exploits
so again hoped around this I spent some
time yesterday right before trainee
class that I expected and right away
accompli a private key server key end up
finding multiple pipe keys and I found
multiple certificates hard-coded
certificates user backdoor talents but
yeah you warned that this this specific
device doesn't even have the the arm to
make your armor I was looking at it and
it's not even released if isn't advice
you know be kidding me to give it on
device it might not be great you know
securable network but yeah um some hard
coding web service credentials make uses
really updated access patching access
they're not even access to so this is
like 2011 but yeah I didn't try to
access yeah I just thought if they had
there we basically we have a lot of bad
things again hard coding secrets on the
client-side meaning whether that's the
firmware whether that's a mobile app
whether that's amazing that the clunky
knows us easier has control over unless
it's protected by a hardware chip you
know element
it's never good at you we have AI
protection since I was hacking away
earlier
this idea of pro and classic where you
have basically IPS enable in line with
network traffic again all of these
devices are within in line with in your
they could be year in line within your
traffic so plugged in directly from your
router actually from your voting to your
router you're connecting of their Wi-Fi
whatever maybe or just passively
listening on the network but again
another one it does web filtering of DNS
filtering and the the probe it has a
switch and le the classic does not but
it's based on Trend Micro so yeah big
defender Trend Micro partnering up this
is good though right at least there's
some sort of like they're trying to
build it into a product trying to build
into consumer devices where then there's
absolutely nothing or was absolutely
nothing a few years ago so at least
there's you know some sort of security
issues that are being built in but again
they're more data points that they're
pulling from you as consumers your
devices what you're doing what you're
watching sound their data to third
parties and not even protecting the
communication between you know their
devices to their cloud infrastructure
so yeah they have anybody have these
Asus devices router security assessment
checks for vulnerabilities but again I
was looking through piece of programs
today this morning actually through a
number of devices that have this feature
enabled for Pro and again identify a
number of different
putting URLs the PGI keys that is when
looking to get into the portal but the
funniest one I found was a ec2 instance
for a developer to the URL recent
instance but for a number of different
private certificates that well within
the firmware as well as over like 54
Nikes that were hard-coded into firmware
so it's talking to third parties that
you may not even know about but coming
back to this this you are out there
obviously my first you know reaction if
I see something
ec2 Amazon and the plug-in into the URL
ceiling again and I got someone's actual
real network they were actually
connected there was like five times if I
say this is network no username or
password so I you know take a look at
what a protection had to offer
I thought I'd get that don't worry you
know little screenshot they have their
private security assessment obviously
there's some danger here this is only
one instance I found multiple instances
of the same occurrence with different
URLs for different firm languages so
it's scary and again for firmware you
can't delete from work from someone's a
workstation or if someone's device
itself it's going to be there forever
basically and people are looking for
that when dealing is not passed with
protecting their legacy and firmware
images although they're not very strong
there's one type of you know defense but
once I saw once I saw that my putting
TRL's
and plug them in I was good I was like
you know this is exactly what I need you
know to figure out you know some of the
point of some of the secrets some of the
issues figure out what this product
actually has to offer which is not much
unfortunately yeah it's returning within
the first few years again all of them
really they're all learning
unfortunately we're all learning with
them so there's more again I'm gonna
report some of the bugs that I found
earlier today but switching over to
another type of consumer advice which is
a vehicle is the Audi and Volkswagen
research that that happened two months
ago now where they selectively went
through and enumerated basically
vehicles that had the most attack
surface Wi-Fi USB different types of
head units and what they did was exploit
a vulnerability within the Wi-Fi David I
guess when you're connected locally and
I shall access to the platform to the
head unit in this case is running a
real-time operating system Q and X and
so you know q2 next seven seven eight
above 17 a bomb has loads of security
features in this case again vehicle that
was just purchased which is what they
did it wasn't fully updated you know
exploit and the research bullet is fully
up there by the way
but yeah qxo real-time operating systems
are not bulletproof if you happen to
look into you know the differences
between embedded Linux and
systems underlying technology what's our
how to communicate is this completely
different but you can still open up
attack surfaces within real time
operating systems as you could with
embedded Linux such as using POSIX
utilities like cat breath whatever maybe
for command injection as an example
which is which is which is what happened
here so that tell me and we'll go to the
latest one here's W research yeah
multiple remote code execution these
guys this is crazy work not only went
through they also took apart the
telematics device itself and the first
engineering both of the front wires for
the head as well as the telematics unit
so then and also have multiple remote
code execution locally plugging into USB
as well as Bluetooth I think there's
another method so they have I think
three or four ways to get remote the
execution to your good rule just crazy
but again another cold old device oath
to a next version 6.5 good research
super detail they ever released all the
details as far as you know what they did
have a calendar
the tools they use the given obviously
the manufactures that chance to fix it I
think proposed to me fix next year so
more research try previously automotive
research was almost sheindlin's before
you know from you know the morning
perspective stone Adam
we weren't enabled we didn't have enough
cool their expertise maybe and even for
Q and X as an example real-time
operating systems they are commercial
license days so you have to be a
developer with them or a partner one
thing with the company I know it's user
tools know their underlying technology
the development of the platform as
opposed to embedded Linux we have full
access to all the built tools and
libraries and frameworks so hakuna tips
and license it's I guess you could say
it would be more obscurity because love
will have access but now the more
research is more more access now you can
see that BMWs run a Pentium seller so
flinch that's right who's the one of kit
cooks in the kitchen when it comes to
any of it advice any product that you're
assessing and again we're talking about
you know whether they're the IOT device
and I guess the vehicle is the
technology device but it's probably you
know I think over 60 60 70 or 80 you
know different microcontrollers and you
see using a vehicle different vehicle
networks in this case even vm w they're
running Ethernet so they plugged in USB
to Ethernet IP address for like a debug
interface again
Vibha testing always seems to eat the
trend and it's about finding the sifting
through and seeing
you get the same access as as a
developer basically now he needs just
one issue one bug one problem you know
within you know the development of the
product itself so in this case we found
that issue the same thing it's a kind of
defense-in-depth
approach what you should be happy
anybody no drink so I'm going to close
off with the proactive things
manufacturers should you do is putting
down to the basics routing dead code
potential backdoors working on access
management identity access management I
know a big fee mobility and identity
within mobility so keeping that fluid
throughout vehicle networks as well as
as well as the cloud infrastructure same
thing goes for IOT devices as well you
know they have we have different
developers responsible for different
aspects of the product starting to shut
down according to current function
whatever it may be they get a lot of
coops in the kitchen is how I referenced
earlier you know it's hard to you know
kind of bring together one crawling with
mice a lot of different code bases a lot
of different styles a lot of different
backgrounds different partners and
suppliers all within the development
supply chain defense-in-depth is is
something that you want to shoot for
hardware hardware wise firmware wise
wireless wise it's Bluetooth Wi-Fi again
as an example vehicles of a huge
protectiveness that they didn't have
before
and now you know code that was once
expected not to be exposed in phoenix
close and being exploited and will
continue to be and it's on the bathroom
it's just matte matter of fixing the
issues working on the maturity is the
culture of
you know of research and those
researchers and enabling encouraging you
know people like us to you know keep
finding bugs especially when you have
enough you know resources tools and
hopefully you know the knowledge is
required to to start testing and
especially for manufacture together
continues testing you definitely need
testing and testing you know usually
there's silo box right about some
developers are you know focused on one
specific feature others are focused on
you know firmware update as an example
and you know I know many people guys and
talk to tell max guys and vice versa you
know they're like two guys with guys but
creating that culture within a company
gonna get anomaly frog boat being any
industry vertical and enforce some sort
of continuous security pretty testing
with a venue through source going
through dynamic testing we have again
for consumer for arm and it's a ton of
tools to emulate again we don't want to
buy or have to so definitely make you
suppose and last but not least like that
was really totally just getting just get
lots of the sauce find some fights with
other types of issues get into it put
some music on it for your girl put your
hair in a ponytail you know figure it
out and you know again have fun with
gold and go free kingi at any time I
would definitely love to help anybody's
research project I love finding bugs
see how there are any questions several
it seems my bad
to be honest what you say like stars on
the show shining examples of different
levels right
I think cementing did a good job
they did a good job too and share
firmware was secured in a way that you
can't siloed your own software they've
had secure food and even in memory the
memory was configuration where it did
even together not common and they
invested from the beginning so they
actually designed with a secure platform
as opposed to you know a lower margin
cheaper device with no chip to store you
know secrets or anything like that or
for secure memory
and I think it's just you know they're
selling those devices right all these
devices that I talked about the Box the
dissented there are on the c5 about 200
to 250
I think everyone's looking only the
first year I sister promising waiting
too much and this is like any other
security cloud right
and zero day seeing the machine learning
and hopefully hopefully we'll see we'll
see a turn again there's a lot of
guidance in documentation around how to
security codes over web even correctly
philosopher cases to verification
standard same thing for mobile there's a
participant security verification
standard for mobile embedded embedded
project and there's a ton of benchmarks
for platform security it's on a certain
commercial based platform a real time
operating system Arkansas with the
bedroom that's definitely something that
specific but it sounds bad just the
claims that they're making marketing
lines are not lining up one-to-one and
we're having to you know kind of go
through and verify validate hey you know
this XYZ what they're saying is that
true and also who you know why is my
device talking to you know a number of
different IPS I know you know for
example of the third-party stuff I may
not be aware of and they're not my
friend about the transparently it's very
much marketing gauge feedback you know
it's just imagine kind of Kosovo effect
you know keep it good by secure but but
your network security devices but it's
the false claims but hopefully we'll see
if that gets better as far as you know
they stopped marketing 0 defense and
also enforcing some you know active
defense through you know I
that's all your data if you're going to
do a product even your data stuff
somewhere else
I don't know device you're gonna have
issues and vulnerabilities this is a
matter of you know how fast the
manufacturer responds I think lad Lee
you know the manufacture is aside from
the team which has been research we've
all patched the issues in Baqubah I'm
gonna send some to Asus but they all
have the pros and cons really it's just
a matter of you know coke ability the
usage and again if you're sending all
your data through one device you know
it's again that whole situation that you
want to get any protection you have to
give your social you know are you
details to get secure you know make the
best judgment if you can and if you have
the opportunity to you know perform some
research on the device before I'd
recommend that but I wouldn't have the
specific vendor I think it's just you
know arms race and a matter of you know
how fast you know they're fixing issues
that are discovered by researchers and
their culture and I think for let's say
rather is a thesis and dealing they got
this left hand really hard by the FTC
over in states they got sued forgotten
there's twenty thousand twenty thousand
dollars or something
have to depend test for 20 years which
has never happened before but because
they were false marketing marketing that
easy easy to secure equality 565 secure
by default but you know now regular
regulatory you know body are kind of
getting involved to win you know it is
affecting privacy and safety now
[Music]
unfortunately we know that time for
questions right now but ready to find
out later great
thank you so much
[Applause]
so the next dog is gonna be about five
minutes
[Music]
No
does it turn you
let's go them
all right the next talks have started
about two minutes so these devices
alright guys we're just about ready to
start so please get back to you
[Music]
okay so please join me welcoming solar
son
[Applause]
all right hello everyone
there we are
well good afternoon Sonia and I just
want to say thank you very much for
coming to this talk so it's great to be
in Sweden this is my first time and the
first time presenting this material as
well so hopefully everything will go
well so here's what to expect and this
is kind of a suggestion of things you
might cover so we'll start with an
introduction and background and then
we'll go into memory analysis academic
analysis like we do acquisition and then
how do we pivot and do better analysis
into web intelligence and now I can say
this is a best-case scenario that's what
most of our let's wait my hands a little
bit and when it's time to stop never I'm
at a time on the coast again in the back
and something I always include is the
live demonstration family because I do
like demos and I really like doing like
Devils what is also extremely scary
because always whenever you're at your
house you're in your lab you know you
work on software everything works
perfectly as soon as you get on stage
you want to do a demo stuff crashes now
if it happens I'm sorry
Alpine fix very clever and it's not well
we'll move on to the next slide I give
up what to see and I just recently
looked at Johnson
and another higher priority
responsibilities until I'm able to turn
back and how do you better respond to
compromise how do you keep anyone from
occurring teacher no it's a software
engineering software development and
degrees okay so let's talk about memory
forensics now one thing I believe is
that a forensic machine forensics memory
is kind of the hardest thing to really
grasp in my opinion and one of the
reasons is it's hard to kind of search
and understand what's really going on
and then clearly without the right tools
without the right knowledge to know what
exactly you're looking at but one thing
to understand is that if we can perfect
how do we look at memory on a computer
machine then we can actually be able to
solve and extract more malware that's
able to hide in our antivirus and other
detection mechanisms and one thing to
understand is that every single process
everything that's going to run on that
computer or there's an embedded device
whether it's a cell phone whatever using
everything must at one point four verse
memory Mazz of you know how to look at
memory let me have some fun
respect indicators artifacts and now
have a better way of protecting our
emissions in the future so here are some
artifacts that we can actually capture
and analyze from memory processes
running policies are one of the texts
and grab these modules and bring it
directly to be a hard drive analogy
better analysis on those and running
systems process heaps the memory of a
particular program what is it thinking
what is loaded inside perhaps with an
encryption key you can extract that from
memory caching support password
unencrypted decrypted binaries so
nowadays whenever we're looking at
malware analysis we first engineering
the good networks which is now the more
almost all of them are going to encrypt
itself somehow and also have anti
debugging techniques and type the
virtual machine understanding so it
makes it really hard to really know how
am I going to analyze this machine but
if you know at what point to extract
that module from memory go back to your
computer now perhaps we can find that
unencrypted binary and then I can do
better analysis on files drivers handles
which programs are already open all
inclusive into stored in memory web
browsing activity and socket connections
a few more things that we can extract
from Emily doing Charles I canvases this
I really really love because this is
kind of
we're doing our threat intelligence to
see like what's actually happening and
what does the information behind the
domains that were seeing your console
activity so whenever I am on the
terminal typing in information sometimes
that console data is stored in memory
and it can be stored in memory for
multiple days if you know which and
every time to look at like a hibernation
file or please if I know what to look
for then I can extract and see you all
perhaps out of that malware execute
itself what commands gonna send itself
to run like the efficiency or if it's
ransomware or come on what keys are
going to use to encrypt a complete
machine sometimes you can expect so
crash thumbs and if we get the blue
screen hopefully but usually and
whatever I am Windows of course very
annoying usually this hard computer
system anyway it's actually trying to
save an image of memory on to the host
machine so to kind of extract that to
see well what else was wondering what
could have been the precipice of that
computer system in the hardware device
information registry hashes keys now
there are two main types of memory
analysis online and offline if I say
online I just mean we're looking at a
live system like if I'm doing analysis
on this computer it's running like now
this is the live analysis a live
acquisition because it's gone and now
you're offline analysis is for a dead
system isn't as off perhaps a crash
maybe I know this computer has been
compromised with malware so I extract on
the harddrive and I'll send it over its
other people to analyze yeah that's a
dead system there are different ways to
look at memory on both instances and
after extracting memory for looking at
the memory there are a few locations to
look for so if it's a live system I'm
going for a volatile Rama if the system
is off I can
hibernation file incident that exact
duplicate of the memory of this
classmate on that sale on to the
computer scene
I think the crash comes from the blue
screen of death I can also look at the
page file plus a lot fun if you're the
locations to find those positions now
the difficulties but anyways memory is
kind of actually this earlier for one
the information changes constantly so
you kind of have to know what am I going
to look what I'm going to scan on this
actual memory system parsing and
understanding the structure is also a
bit difficult because on the host
machine you're familiar with browsing
from one file to the other double-click
here there but memory does not
necessarily have that type of browsing
capability because mint strictly for the
operating system the firmware to run
whatever it means and unload modules
that are running in the computer
unloaded into memory and let things run
just fine without the user knowing
that's why it's a bit more difficult to
understand how they go for memory except
if we have the right tools and we'll go
through the right souls in the following
slide then we'll know exactly how to now
if we start with when we have position
lamas together an online online system
now there are many many many tools that
exist out there
I'm just keeping a small list of the
most of my views that work really really
really well especially the long so I can
daisy-chain or write a wrapper around so
I can now automate across an entire
enterprise so to start off with we have
a dumpling dumpling works really well
that's I'm going to be one of the tools
that will demo in this presentation
Manion hasn't told called memorize that
you can use as a command-line tool that
understand
founders to send then it can do an
entire dump of like memory when p.m.
that's an older tool but still works
very very very good and it's need from
belkasoft ram caption men and men into
redline xk imager and holistic forensics
now if we look at these delta software
and capture ran into redline ftk imager
osf forensics and there's another one
magnet ram capture also released the
slides so hopefully whenever you get the
slide you see that i have a lot of even
slightly and that's because for each
tool and i definitely talk about here i
actually show you the instructions to
download that tool and then the
instruction counts around because
unfortunately it's not that
straightforward one school to another
which is why i did this study to see how
do we do this in have already step
actually community to make your analysis
much easier and faster and then
honorable mentions these word tools
might use but i did not necessarily like
all that well but they still a morgan if
you like s response HBGary ask them the
reason i do not give this HP area is
because it has a 32-bit and a 64-bit
they're 30 to make this free to support
it and i really got any money
sounds like that one man tech that when
I couldn't had part of trouble finding
san has an entire six and they have an
entire set framework that works level if
you want to establish and
/ - you seem to handle on your analysis
and even p.m. dump alder told a man like
Katie that's under sysinternals
very very nice using sis internal tools
however this one was like punks I'm not
even looking at this one anymore cuz I
try to run it it was not straightforward
you need other dependency requirements
lovely
it does work I noticed were to the past
but since was more difficult to
establish on the analysis like no I'm
not gonna use it we will use these other
tools that are open source and free
image acquisition oh sorry one thing to
mention is that I do the same thing in
multiple tools because the worse today
what happens tomorrow when that tool is
deprecated what happens when the company
realized that oh this is a really good
tool which you start charging for now
and I have to pay money and they know I
just go back to your other free tools in
these parts for free because it's free
now if we look at acquiring memory and
so on this is just one of the tools and
that will demo and then that's the wait
if the actual ones download on this tool
so what dump you launch it you can
prompt with the Ministry of this we can
also just EE UN your administrator
credentials and then you press Y that's
all you have to do dump it does the rest
to dump an entire image of brand
everything that's going on at the
present state like computers so here's
another screenshot of what it looks like
as it runs and when it's finished you'll
have two fonts one of the document your
memory dump file that's going to be as
large as the RAM on the new machine and
then a JSON file the JSON file gives you
meta do that
the computer gene like the computer
systems name and leaders time and other
data if you look at the notes in this
slide gives you an example of whenever I
ran this on my Windows 7 machine and
then your administrator so this comes up
it says you want to run we press yes and
then it says the race now this might
take some time and so as it's going we
will come back to it but that's it now
we're able to dump the entire memories
into this one single dump file and then
we can analyze some further you can send
it off to a gate additional memory
analysis that additional similar to what
we mentioned earlier and it's the only
other one that we have it was the magnet
Ram come capture so that's a GUI tool
all of these are user interface tools
and these ones to man my command line it
knows about offline acquisition of
memory so there are a few places that
you can look for one is that hibernation
file so the last time that the computer
system wasn't happening
perhaps it's been gone for a while it
goes into sleep it's been sleeping for a
while it was into hibernation then you
can actually extract this entire Kaiba
nation file to analyze what was
happening at that present time before I
went to sleep
that's just instruction how you enable
high dimension fun now here I included
another helper tool because if you are
trying to extract a hibernation file on
the current machine like this computer
has a hibernation following hydrated in
the past I want to distract the
hibernation follow you like a copy or
something windows will not allow you to
do that
by default but what some searching and
some coffee and some expletives they
would found the actual tool that can
actually allow you to just copy that and
now understanding the hydration file is
a compressed file so I'll first have to
decompress that hydration column and
then we can do analysis asking for
another place that we can extract memory
is the windows page file so the windows
please well this one is a bit different
at along to understand so the page file
happens whenever a process or a more
memory is needed than the actual DRAM
that is present on the host operating
system that's running at the current
time
well that extra blocks information
between ram and then the hard drive so
to each process it's seamless that it
has infinite ram what really was
happening as the operating system is
handling
context switching between ram volatile
memory and then using your hard drive
space to offset and have additional RAM
for you but a difficult thing about
analyzing the page file is it's not a
continuous memory dump as like the
hydration final order permanent system
Ram because it's pieces
anytime a nominal processing his extra
RAM then pieces of that process is now
scoring too hard but one more thing you
can do is you can on operating a
separate tool called Xavier I just
programmed it like two hours but Xavier
will allow you to enter in my redheads
expressions to see each nice tracks like
URLs domains ECP's on different types of
keys from that page file itself but you
can just run the normal strings on the
page and see what's coming in you
usually have to say something I've made
that clicks and perhaps Francis what
happened because if I look now these two
files were created and one of them
should be a dumb file and yellow should
be yeah these are actually the outputs I
just expected to press something and
finish it so we can have but this this
memory image has been saving this
virtual machine and then supported by
fire
so then we're going to analyze what we
actually have now there are different
tools that exist to now allow us to
analyze the memory sample so firstly
acquire we do a dump of memory now it's
analyzing extract processes what socket
connection
just at the time perhaps their DLLs what
malware samples can be done directly
from memory that's why we go into the
analysis portion of our investigation
now they're different to recall that's a
really really good tool recall in fact
came out first before volatility some
volatility is like a brother to recall
except recall runs for my experience
worked really really well on like a unix
linux system there's just multiple pipe
run files but I come over the standalone
executable so that they convened these
between the right wrappers around that
totally enterprising across an entire
honestly so we'll do our analysis using
volatility but other tools that you can
use is main dancer redline that too is a
great great tool to run it's a user
interface if you like Louise that's
perfect to me I'm like command line I
like everything in black of my text so I
don't use this one but you can
especially if you're just getting
started use YouTube and you'll see how
people are setting it up how to
establish it on the machine
sense if framework to mention earlier
educate imager can be used both to
extract a memory image and also to
analyze what's going on under and then
we will do our analysis with volatility
so here we go with volatility there are
some pros and cons of them so one is a
very very special reached investigation
framework it's open source even make
changes to it you can see the
I said and scrolling and now I love so
there's no and now it does not perform
the actual acquisition for you so I
believe we can do that memory
acquisition and debt analysis the
volatility doesn't so you have to
already have a separate tool to acquire
the memory dump and now how much you
have the dump then you can use
volatility on to carry on your analysis
so it's not a one-stop shop but once you
have that done you can carry on
everything else with and then it's not
that intuitive if you're just starting
so without like a few cartoons or
demos I'll sing it online it's not that
initial it's not your first program to
start with if I'm honest but what should
you understand then you're really
comfortable and everything I think we're
going to do a demo so here's actually
some steps in which I say let's
configure our computer machine to
understand some things onto something
that only is my profile so we need to
understand the profile that we're using
for volatility so there are different
operating systems that are running some
also they need to know how to like
living within the kernel your list of
all of your programs running is
different based on each operating system
is different based on the service Mac
which is a slight variation on each
offering system as well so you have to
know the specific profile think you can
both atoms molecules so that's why I
thought these commands into trying to
help us acquiring it which we need
everything's new so let's go ahead and
just so here I am in our machine if I
launch command prompt and then the first
thing I was like system info so I just
do system in Claude when I type out
information onto my desktop I'm working
don't we just want to help us out so
let's get one like operation system so
I'm in Windows we can say oh is that
text and then it's do the same thing but
kind of a minute exactly what we're
looking for and so that was a separate
command and then I put captions value
obviously this 200s value and then if I
want to sign it so that's just one of
them outputs that we have this really
really simple it just allows you to see
yes for sure I'm in windows 7
environment and their service packages
I'm now on this
so on this computer this terminal
Ida system impulsive system info gives
me more information kind of everything
that happen on my computer system I'm so
I can see its hostname Windows version
once again and then also the patches and
the hot fixes so a few years ago with
fighting continents and I really loved
grabbing a system info because then I'll
write how I understand patches so I can
kind of stay on the computer I'm even
more so I'm this is also just and WIC
again is not that nice here but you can
find out well whatever's come later
let's focus on business I guess I least
me understand we're in Windows 7 64 ok
so what I would do at this point is I
would copy off my dumb files and then my
helper class here and then system info
and we'll I'm something else I did not
show
with volatility for us to know like
natural plugins that we wants to run on
if you launch from a command prompt
volatility that's eight and then once
abroad this should show its help file
I'm going to gives you like a text file
scroll and see things differently now
these are all the supported plugins for
volatility and then it gives you an
explanation on here's what companies do
and now without recommends I'm one of
the best ways to become proficient at
this type of analysis it's the
confidence to do it on your own look
that each command running and they see
the output and say all is this helpful
for me or not
nice just like the basic in the actual
plugins that you like to help you in
your analysis in the future so in
particular I will look my chair for like
the clipboard was actually in the
clipboard whether the user control seat
that's stored in memory command line
what was in the command line and command
line understand what was actually what
programs ran and then what information
is still written resident in memory and
that we can analyze connections and cons
can so these work really nicely for
Windows 16 and this pretty much tells
you the actual sophism in connection
had opened previously and then also the
program have brand establishing that
connection witness news nets can to help
us find out what's on console i'm see
the history in the console like let me
press down on what's there have some
good ones let's see what files were
opened and at which process had handled
to that file so you can see if there's a
program that's enumerating the entire
computer machine then usually have a lot
of handles or you can see has changes at
angle which pile is occurring
hash them Lourdes so if you want to grab
the hash dump of a particular file try
this try ash down so you can get those
hashes and then even ask Google in it
and when it's time that 75 might
actually come up to something here's
like a match and for that the keys that
could be used to constitute it in other
places you just lose meaning has to dump
a particular memory from a specific
process or just look at memories things
[Music]
so this gives us the running policies
that were on an impromptu this is I mean
the first why did this happen - I didn't
know you can actually extract all these
things so would prompt them yeah I can
instrument the plug and drop them I can
get
like the specific process hiking and
then I get that same motto from memory
onto the computer now you can grab that
into reverse engineering on that or you
can upload them to other place like
virustotal
you can google this me5 and C program
okay so the first thing we'll take a
look at if we run so we ran late - HD
see all the models are clickable the
info
okay so in the infobar remember I was
speaking before and that we have to
understand the profile of each machine
that were analyzing so this tells us all
the profiles are clickable for this
current volatility sample so makes an
operating system like we are going to
use Windows 7 with the windows 7 service
pack 1 64-bit somewhat moving and
copiers and I was in the specific
profile that allows all swords need to
know how do i do extract various
artifacts from in any other additional
address based information at the bottom
and then the plugins that we saw before
and now something that's also there it's
all totally works both on Windows and
Linux so now we have a couple help or
clouds created let's start to do some
analysis well the first one to do is
commands in so let's see what commands
could have been run and then what
information was you out from that
process for my mind
mr. volatility and then when the - f we
give the path to the memory dump so
again I expected it from the personal
mission as we named in memory
windows in the
and so now possibly is running its
liquid through the entire memory sample
and then whatever it finds is going to
store on to the host machine here now
sometimes like it might take a while
especially in based on how large that
memory image or the memory not look at
commands can does the file that was
created this is everything that was
scored from man winning four different
commands on the run and you can actually
see that these were the commands that I
run I ran right before the window so we
had a skill when I had went through
twelve running again annoying this
pop-up so I killed it and you can
actually see the commands lighting up to
kill
our grounds of situation and system info
so this is really nice I'm just I'm
surprised of all this information is
still remnant in memory even after
you've closed those programs I've closed
upon so some of these things still
linger on that's why it's less important
to understand how do I do this so I can
do better analysis on my computer
because whenever you're doing forensics
you know the system might be compromised
you never really known what was this
initial infection infection attack or
you never really know what vomitings
it's using so you have to go and find
the clues
[Music]
so now what we're seeing is a particular
process and then the command line
executions to start that process so
again this is really nice
for the way you think about starting a
particular program or you can starting a
malware so if you don't always know what
was your initial IP address or the
domain then you know mal was trying to
reach out to how was it started
encryption key steps for ransomware
attacks whichever country
[Music]
so if we do the network Stan then
hopefully this will tell us the actual
sockets that were established is it
still running at the time of the memory
down hasn't closed at this time and then
the process that was responsible for
each connection right now what we're
seeing as the offsetting memory and that
we have this is important to know the
offset so he's going to go back and dump
a specific memory section this is
awesome that you use to answer any for
your memory compliment
so it's glorious lovely that's just
right there for you
okay the protocol is a TCP or UDP type
of protocol the interface IP address of
the host machine and whenever something
was running and then the foreign threats
that are connected constitute and then
the owner so this is the actual parent
process that was responsible for each
connection so similar to your next act
but if you don't have nothing to invest
that or this black hydration whatever
looking at I didn't go back and time and
see what was running at the instance of
this man and one of the things I would
do is I would extract like these foreign
addresses and I'll throw it into our
threats
system to see like our disconnection is
good because perhaps you can find them
yes so for the interest of time I should
have not seen here this exact
unconsciousness that was running system
main and then the process ID so if you
use the process ID that's what's the
information important for when
everyone's actually dumped that module I
erected from memories now we can do
further analysis now understand whenever
you are really reverse engineering as a
malware sample and the office where at
least decent body that malware that an
hour is going to be encrypted that now
is also going to be virtual machine the
winner however you can get it to run on
a real solid machine freeze machine dump
gram now perhaps you can be successful
at dumping the decrypted module directly
from memory that's why this is a really
important really useful that's good so
if we look on this process list I will
just choose anyone who's like let's say
Chrome for these things okay like this
one so this processing fee is 9 3 6 now
let's go over let's go back to our
volatility instance and let's use the
command prompt then use - key for the
process ID and wells of 96 thank you 6
[Music]
and then the link to talk about the
network as I said I really love right
now looking at the connections URLs the
main things that are tight because now I
can add that tells this machine and then
we can find out additional artifacts or
the actual malicious actors behind their
doing so let's take a moment really
really something a fine print alders one
of the things that I'm kind of annoyed
with other people who are spoken
unthreatened son is not here today but
other companies and clearly they don't
this one like threat leader or just
nonsense for you to pay them a lot of
money so one of the dhole is to talk
about initially whenever we define Greg
Collins based on my definition from the
book of Solomon one thing I don't just
want dump some leader out there that's
not threaten talent and something some
thing is that your threat intelligence
is not synonymous with your threat data
now to understand multiple definitions
do exist but mine that I want to talk
about with Renzo means is that is a
collection of relative information
extracted from data sources one or
multiple data sources that can be used
to instigate some sort of action so it's
intelligence when I can do an action
from it if I'm looking at a lot of
people I have like maybe some image
recognition so the faces that I have
that's your data but what do I do with
those images well I've just found a
person on the terrorist list
FBI or whatever company would just found
someone that we need to investigate
further we need to tell that person
follow them from there that's
intelligence that invokes some sort of
action so that's kind of what we're
looking for whenever we create a threat
intelligence environment here and I
talked about that it has a new paradigm
in there security because it's actually
completely different and the way we've
done security in the past so previously
when we talk about and network security
internet security host machine security
you mainly have a signature based
detection and then your statistical
anomaly based detection looking at kind
of heuristics or variations on baseline
well the trends held is the climate
change the nomenclature to see like how
do I actually understand if this is an
attack or this is not my sentiment and
so I looked at a signature and also I'm
rather looking like indicators and
artifacts and now what correlations do
we create to really tell us one more
time this is have to continue what we
have um so one thing to understand what
understanding can you create indicators
of compromise from malicious people is
to know that people are generally
creatures of habit so I kind of have two
main postulates to understand that kind
of helps us understand how do we develop
this threat intelligence and so for one
the anatomy of a computer attack button
and I mean how do I go about attacking
compute machine look let me ask them
during your hacker kissing scenes
okay good good answer sometimes and with
permission from everyone right
so if I were to say what are your steps
to attack a computer let's say if you
have a computer that you want to attack
like what are your steps
what are your methodology that's correct
so we do some sort of honest enumeration
perhaps I'm doing license understanding
on the system to see the whole mobility
and then we're trying to exploit it
right we're trying to penetrate the
Machine and after you penetrate we do
whatever we want to do steal destroy
pillage whatever paralyze commit to some
of the machine and then hopefully we can
do some sort of stealth and resistance
right to try and hide our present so you
correct it so that's generally kind of
our main methodology for computer issues
that's good however i postulate that the
attack methodology is actually changed a
little bit because in the network system
that i'm in charge or i was in charge of
protecting in looking at an entire
enterprise you will not find anything
from the outside if you're trying to
scan our computer machines you want that
we have really really really good final
all different types of architectures are
working to protect that enterprise but
yet our computers are still being
compromising malware that's because your
attackers have changed the methodology
so here you can have your main five
steps as before for constant standing
penetration whenever else we need evade
detection my team access but on this
side we then have different ways of
staging the attack will put our text out
there that allow the people to come to
us they could like / download the
Trojans Rachel's here she's going to
talk about social engineering to come on
really excite
that's all so these are all the ways
that I can use to actually exploit the
computer machine but understanding your
techniques can now allow me to profile
view and Know Who am I actually going to
go after an attack and another imposter
that I have on attackers is there are
only three ways on the attackers actions
good even mediocre semi good there are
only the first there were probably too
lazy they're using recycle tools
something somebody else's re-written I
really signature to detect it now my
antivirus comes up well they're too
greedy
there was a take too much information
too fast or they were under skill they
just enough understand this exploit if I
launch it on the main server that server
goes now that people know that that
system has been company so why are these
things important it's important because
if I can understand your common
methodologies then I can be really
successful at profiling you to
understand your new domains renew on
websites that you have created tomorrow
I can detect them to or I could attack
them even before anyone says Sina
because I know what I'm looking for
it's a looking for three minutes
okay all right there I'll be fast okay
okay so here is real quick something to
make sure that we can expect from every
single domain and that's how we look at
the name servers and that belong to each
system that is responding resources to
use we can also correlate this is no
location excellent idea but I'm
determined
five computers that are attacking
where are they coming from perhaps it's
another state like a really you know
evil country out that you can use your
imagination
and then really I want mine a lot of us
who wears data the registration data
that if you can know the registration
they know these behind some domains then
I can actually find who you are and when
you use the same methodology to register
new denise tomorrow attack me I can also
find this was kind of like bane of my
existence by person fun I'm to
protecting entire enterprise machines
the conflict of virus comfortable world
wasn't a machine ten years ago but one
of the things that was so good about
this comfortable work was this one of
the first like revolution in current
affairs in which it deployed like one of
your first ways of seeing each case the
domain generating now good news so
before the conflict before your DJ's
whenever I have a Malibu sample and with
heart all the domains on this now that
was going to reach out to so if I
reversed into an example if I see the
domains of the sweet yell to I simply
block all black hole with the main I
seek the domain so now that can control
the center and then if I'm looking
across the entire enterprise I can see
all the people that are trying to go
there and I found a compromise machine
so the con figure on the daily basis
that bad boys one single sample can
generate up to fifty thousand different
domain one sample your sample that your
computers compromise with is different
than your sample so that means other
they will generate
fifty-thousand you will generate another
50,000 yo generate another 50,000 sold
already can have like a million domains
underwater animals previously will just
block as many as we could
whenever our block list gets full we
delete the old ones and we had the new
which was a bad way of looking at things
instead if we known exactly what to mine
we know exactly which type of indicators
to look for then I can actually discover
who are the real people that will for
responsible face types of attacks two
minutes left to get so I would like to
introduce you to accelerate so those
responsible for doing a lot of attacks
not attack a lot of analysis and
correlations to various sites out there
to bring in additional data for us to
analyze now when I first created Stalin
right critics out there back in 2013 and
then when I submitted it to a three
conferences saying hey I think we're
onto something new with Excalibur and I
was like what I guess it's too soon well
actually table Excalibur for three years
looks like I'm going to leave this right
now I will try to see you in three years
last year 2017 that's a sticker
conference I was like this is 2017
perhaps it's time to talk about foreign
television so the new developer was born
now
in the morning in the morning so they
said given these domain sets just random
domains out there we have found the
actual attackers that are responsible
for all these domains here are the
people and the I guess the artifacts
that indicators of compromise such that
these in the future
compromise with this particular
intrusion and then so then I took their
exact malware random domain I threw it
into Excalibur Excalibur go do and let's
see which will come up with so I'll show
you I'm going to
so if I really Salander this is
available election millet this person is
not available yet on Sunday when I'm
finally home back to the US you will
have this new version that the old
version is still up there since last
years I've been developing so just real
quick
I'm voting thing actually including
sense that the other people said I'm
adding it to Excalibur and I will say
it's down but you find the linkages and
let's see how good you are compared to
the entire company in which they are
finding the indicators because if I at
least look at the stuff of the
indicators then now we know tomorrow if
that same person uses the same
techniques to establish new domains then
we fountain so whenever you launch of
salary you're going to have like various
files so if you want to know like and
where this each connection that's coming
to you on your network when every month
it's Albert give it files to analyze you
can click on each one and then you can
kind of see all of its data if I had
more on blank food IP addresses and also
geolocation which is not standard but
now let's go to your main indicators
okay I'm sorry using a mouse because
whatever that might be but how do you
correlate indications together this is
kind of policy so Broglie
I like various decision trees and so
based on this decision tree you as the
person to see Excalibur said this is a
particulate indicator you need to be
cognizant of so if you accept this you
can then publish to the Excalibur
intrusion detection system that all
on Sunday so you can have a better an
optimum context but for instance if we
look at I'm so look at this tweet I
think we mentioned was like the entire
company and this Isabella in the future
okay because I know there are links to
previous badness in the past so one
doesn't meet you
but one thing to come to this now so
surprised I've not seen oh I did not see
it in their report so isabella has like
a 3% representation which is pretty sick
even those only three that's actually
showing that there's a person everybody
else
[Music]
[Applause]
great thank you
right so uh just some quick information
feel you probably plenty of going back
to Stockholm at some point but actually
with basically that still works let's
apply your fun so it could be a place to
crash alright so it's almost like to get
from something to make them go ahead to
wake over to you
[Music]
[Applause]
do
Hey all right let's we're getting really
close to beer and so I will let there's
gonna be one talk after me so I'll try
to speed it up so you guys get some more
time okay so I'm gonna talk about
breaking policies and specifications and
the thing is I basically have one story
I'm gonna talk about and then I'm gonna
talk to cause problem I've been
identifying which is not really related
to the story but I guess that there are
similar things in it after this there's
also sequence so I'm gonna give away a
secret last year I did a talk here I
also gave away modification about old
hacking tool but now this is just an
experimental tool to find a specific
thing but I will talk about that later
so my name is Franz Rossum I've been
talking here two years this is the third
time I do a lot of life hacking events
so I actually get invited to two events
going out and have a specific company
and then we compete with other habits so
it's like a game but you also help a
company maybe else went and cookie
that's team Sweden and we want so hard
that was our only purpose with the whole
trip so the idea I'm going to talk about
first is it's a story about let's
encrypt and how I killed one of their
specifications they're really definitive
but the story begins with a totally
different thing
I was sitting a day in January ninth of
Jerry generally actually on the night I
was happy a company that you might know
I'll get up.get lab is our open source
source code the first control system
web-based basically and they had they
had like responsible snow sure you able
to pack them and I was invited to take a
look at the code the thing was what I
started to look at was not application
itself where you run it locally and you
have a bureau instance instead of
looking on the specific cloud service
they use it like a compact get Lancome
is a bit different from that app and the
difference was something called github
pages if you don't know what Hitler
pages is it's basically like different
pages it's a same thing but the cool
thing is basically you're able to the
website and you you can point your
domain to that website and you can serve
like on top stock example only conserve
your documentation that documentation is
in Atlanta so it's immersion teacher
when I started looking at it if you saw
my my two other talks I'm talking about
like subdomain take or be able to take
over domains because they don't use any
domain validation this was the case for
each connection they did not use that
the domain validation
that was the first fun trick so that
means that if someone pointed
to eat lab you could go in and say this
is my domain and you concern whatever
you want it on the fee the way you saw
that was basically the sideshow place
ahora fort and if you went to them mm to
me and I wanted to tell them that but
the thing is how do you tell them that
they're making their customers humble
like how do you do that
so I thought what if I take over I keep
that up come to me
wait there only two that would be pretty
cool right
you're breaking your own site because of
your vulnerable system so I tested out
like calm and that actually work they
didn't black place their own domain and
everything is this was like perfect
recipe for me to actually find something
but Thomas didn't result in anything so
I couldn't do anything with just that
one so I had to find the domain that
they were using but what's also pointing
to too dependent so the goal was
basically find this somewhere it's
supposed to be someone the cool thing
was I didn't have to move that much
because that one redirected very
properly from HTTP it redirected to
don't stop with lemon what they did here
was basically realizing okay is common
but we're gonna put them on top so we
couldn't make a redirect however if you
went with HTTPS you would see a port for
this was interesting so I went to top
doctor it Lancome and it worked so I had
it I actually had the HTTPS one so I was
like super excited and that meant that
going
yes he would serve my compliments that
so I went there and then they don't
worry I got this
invalid certificate consolation this is
so close and my attack report to them
would it be as fun if I go and say to
them yeah you need to tell people press
advance
you can't do that so I was like how can
I get a certificate for Atlanta thing is
when you actually get input boxes like
upload your domain here or your
certificate here with your private key
and we reserve that for your remaining
awesome that is super great so I was
like okay so if I put like out did you
know about let you quit let it rip is
like a automated way to get certificates
so I thought to myself let's approach
that secret quit this purpose basically
I can put a file on that main and
validate that lets you triggers that I
own the website so if you don't know
that secret probably all you do it's
like free certificates for everybody
they're trying to automate it it's built
by a nonprofit organization and there's
like you see like a bunch of
organizations founding this infinite
security they have to take now there's
like ten less methods the way to get a
certificate and which is decided on the
browser forum see a browser for so they
came up with ten ACMA and the internet
security group decided that only three
of them is a valid for automation at me
it's like automated management
certificate engine whatever it is like
that automation can only use these three
master plans and they RSVP
and CSS ni0 so my first project was I
never published to teacher 1 basically
what it does is it connects to a
specific URL and it has a challenge in
memory on URL and if it's responds with
another challenge in the file it knows
it's contaminated so I was like this is
perfect I can actually create a
repository called the dot well-known
ticket lab I can create a directory
called at the challenge and then I can
create a file with the first challenge
with the content of the second challenge
everything is also right but do you
remember HTTP didn't work turns out that
the HTTP server 1 specification was
changed from from the beginning in the
beginning a that should try both port 80
and 443 but there was a lot of mineral
at least with the actual thing I was
mentioning that HTTP redirected to a
totally different website because it was
like exotic so they had to decide that
port 80 needs to be open that's the only
way you're gonna get the certificate so
could use that one which was sad and
would have been perfect and very easy
way to actually get tickets but it
doesn't work so next up was DNS 0 1 the
NSM 1 means that you need to add a txt
record to your DNS and if you can't do
that which I couldn't there's no way to
use that one so then I saw the more
interesting one called TLS SMI
the interesting part was that it was
pretty hard to find like you can't go to
let's encrypt a tweet like that a
documentation on how it works because
they only they wrote like a RFC like
IETF has published a draft on how it is
I mean nothing is like decided on almost
everything is like draft based so I had
to read those drafts which was like it's
like green specifications is maybe not
something you doing on a Friday night
but I did and I was chatting with a
friend during the time and slack and I
started reading it and I'm like this is
I actually wrote it like this is week
and I sent you the link tonight if this
is true this is completely up and
he said what what do you mean and like
that's a like a common discussion about
like I'm thinking so much about saying
nobody else is like what what the hell
are you doing so I was trying to explain
to him in simple words what I read from
specification I didn't know if this was
true but I try to like simplify it so
the holidays I want to verify example
right
so I say hello mr. lives in crickets or
missus I don't know and I want to be
able to validate example calm what
happens is that let's encrypt says okay
that's fine but could you on the IP
address of example of common serve me
certificate if you ask me about this
weird main column XYZ document of
invalid and I ask you for that domain
can you assert a certificate that you
made yourself handwritten certificate
okay I can anything is I will now
connect to example and I will ask not
for example of comma likes to ask hello
server name indication is basically the
wait
this is the main I'm interested and you
will say can you please serve me a
certificate for X Y C tomato demand and
then I'm stopping like hey wait a minute
don't you have example of calm in the
discussion you're really connected I
need you don't do anything else no it's
fine oh so I was like okay so if I want
to certificate for one domain the only
thing I need to care about the
validation process is activate of the
anomaly so I actually took out one of
those domains that you need to serve a
certificate for and I tried it in get up
get up sorry and he said no the domain
must be between one and sixty-three
Canterlot no there's no idea to do this
but I get a certificate so I'm like
forget it luck there was something else
there that was pretty interesting so
what I did was I took this like it's a
pretty long domain right it's like I
don't know exactly how long it is but
it's like about my parents right so I
went to two other cloud providers I know
of called the narrow ruin a SS blood
froze
both of them are like supporting you to
upload your own certificates which were
also so basically I just paste the name
that we don't leave out the domain and
like to see he stayed maybe we're black
listing it because if you can have that
domain on that basis
next to them and get the certificate for
that invalid I think to me I had worked
super interesting so I was like I need
to test this and I need to test this in
production but I need to validate that
this actually works now I just added a
domain like I didn't like actually
approached one of the domains so the
target I had was find a crew company
that everybody knows our King and one of
their domain should point to either
group or in the West out front because
since let's people commit to that they
will actually reach one of these but
then I will add this a queen Valley to
see if if we will actually connect to my
own app with the Aqua Valley with my
self signed certificate and therefore
pass the verification so I went to a
friend of mine in Canada working for a
big ecommerce company I will not mention
baby but it's a company that I should
not have a certificate I don't I went to
name the light I don't know if this is
gonna work but you guys have a specific
domain that I could actually test if
this works on could I issue a
certificate for this one like I know
this is a weird question but you can
like yeah yeah we don't care about an
executable list like these are the ones
qualifying for free shooting
certificates any like yeah take that one
it's like nobody cares turns off TV and
people bitch
this is Heroku and I'm but my challenge
is to serve a certificate for disability
so what I think was there's a function
of the source tools to actually issue
certificates using this method in fact
there were some apps one concert was
built by DF that totally supported this
specific recipe but I didn't want to use
one of these things I wanted to
understand exactly how it works
so I rebuilt one of them and this was
just to make the self signed certificate
myself for the specific domain so here
you can see I'm actually inserting
notice something with the only important
part is in the Sun so that's why I can
put all my passwords like diagonal notes
like what the C and I put the domain
they actually want which was an
interesting thing because the CM they
don't care about it like you can upload
a certificate to learn from the Guru ku
with as many domains as you like it
doesn't matter it matter what matters
then is that you actually in your app
add the domain so you can have a
certificate and kind of make sense right
if you have a bunch of songs subject the
political sort of names in your
certificate that you don't use for your
group you still want to upload a
certificate that has their my songs but
that shouldn't mean they should be
certain right so the C in here didn't
matter good right there doesn't matter
but the thing is I wanted to create the
Southside certificate and what happened
when I grabbed this one I actually got
out that X Y C the key for what it
wanted me to validate so I have a
certificate and I added it to my
and I went in and I had that the don't
activate not invalid made and I was
waiting because this doesn't take like
seconds it takes like minute
and so I was sitting here waiting and I
was like that would be fun
we find like doing myself a little tea
servers so I actually wrote like a batch
script that was like a if you testing
every time and as soon as I see this one
I actually use like saying and it says
like let's see yeah and I was sitting
there and suddenly I increase the
baltimore microtubule summit
you brought and another holy and
the next step i did was basically just i
just sent one slack message I said this
picnic do and he answered me
holy like this is this is not good
and he was like can I have done
something to prevent this from happening
I'm like yeah you just stopped using
here a good first stop using powerful
and I did the same thing on our domain
the same company was also using our
telephone so I could like use the same
company to just approachable and I saw
this and I'm like oh this is okay and
the time I can actually see when I sent
the report it's like yeah five minutes
to 2:00 a.m. Wednesday or something and
I wrote the whole report like this is
the way I assure to certificates they're
not mine but I was able to do it because
this is how shared hosting works and
they
one hour and 40 minutes and then they
said yeah we need this is actually a
valid problem and then they put up like
we're shuffling this verification method
down and then due to this message it
turns out on Hacker News and they're
like what the hell people I what the
and they starting like discussion
discussing always like what did people
actually do what happened here and I
went to bed I actually went with that
and this was like before I just like
closed the computer and like I try to
sleep I woke up in the morning I had
four mates from lesson 15 and they're
like yeah we're pushing this today it's
going to go out to the power and I'm
like holy and like what do you want
me to say what do you want to mention
your name I'm like yeah sure do it and
like 15 minutes later like imagine like
this is we're talking about the time
period of six or seven hours between me
reporting and then going out to say that
this guy just emails us and yeah we put
it out like we black like put this black
hole over there certification method in
a black hole and we're gonna see how
we're gonna change this so I was super
stressed because now they went out with
all the information but I really wanted
to tell my story
so I just hammered down on the blog post
really fast like this is how I got this
certificates I also would actually went
to a ruku AWS and sent them a report
like this is
that is going out now this is a blog
post while we get it out I don't care
you doesn't matter if there be a
verification method is gone so it
doesn't matter and they came back to me
in like oh you were the friends they
were mentioning how that kinda make
sense they also paid money which was
amazing that was not the intention with
reporting to them so the basic it paid
me for telling them I'm gonna blog about
them the cool thing after this was net
secret like fiddle around with it
they have like a pretty open discussion
on how they were supposed to do in the
future with this verification but the
fun part was that they had a new
specification called TLS as a 9:02 but
the problem was that that one was just
as broken as this one like that one did
not solve it it solves another problem
but not this kind of problem and that
one never saw the day of light because
they came out and said we will sunset
both these members completely we will
never use bar by TSS neiser 1 & 5 ITSs a
nicer to me
the funny thing was after this everybody
was waiting for something by let's
encrypt called wildcard certificates
what part certificates was basically
like one of the first reasons a lot of
big companies did not use net exactly
the mean basically we could not get a
star on example.com certificate
bilateral crypt and they were announcing
to do this in February and they actually
went out let secret have never broke in
at that point in their whole existence
of two and a half years three years
because of me this is the recent
application of TLS this and I actually
delayed the vote while partisan people
were upset most with
companies had decided that we're gonna
move over to to watch motor starts for
that equipment so they never renewed
their their existing wiper sets which
meant but they were like that's perfect
temporary it's awesome and then I play
green the night no it's gonna be a
couple of weeks we don't know so I think
this explains why I got a bunch of
flowers from all the certificates or
forties when this happens they're like
thank you everybody pull apart
certificates on Twitter people like yes
this would be the first day of the wild
card but they will just delay no no me
take and a friend of mine goes off I'm
like yeah that's right also the bearer
of bad news
the cool thing is they will probably get
the lot better so that's that's
basically the let's encrypt story
there's some there's some fun stories
also regarding about the verification
methods but I don't have time to
actually comedies the next thing I'm
going to talk about is something else
regarding policies and specifications I
haven't seen that much information he
posted about this so this is a very and
I wouldn't say it's unknown it's just
that some people have not been talking
about this and as much as people should
because this thing is broken broken as
hell and it's so easy to do wrong the
whole idea with upload policies it's
basically like we now use cloud storage
instead of actually putting files on
your server it's also but the problem
has always been you need to get define
first someone uploads the file you get
defined but you want to use this
external file storage that s3 buckets on
Google Cloud or on Amazon so you
basically get the file and that you
trance
we we just double the time I had to take
so much time to difference large files
it's a mess so they come up without
thing we're basically they sign the
policy server side they sign it with
their secret key the policy says once
I'm allowed to be unloaded to this
market and what happened is as soon as
you do that you can upload on client
side directly to the it's awesome it
goes really fast and you don't need to
think about like transferring a file
double double the time the problem it's
it's super easy to do wrong and the
thing is every time you talk with pen
testers are like what is the feature you
start looking at first everybody
fundable always violent you're gonna
shell you name it you don't get it but
it's not natural and you everything is
good right so this is like awesome
we can now isolate our are our files on
a sandbox domain they can't get to us
and this turns out to actually don't be
great so the thing is I'm not good
policy looks like this it's basically
you're posting directly to unprotect
works exactly the same way both with a a
SS and they're clapping in this post
request you have the file content a file
name and you have basics before in coded
policy the policy looks something like
this it's basically saying like when
should it expire what's the conditions
on the file that you're allowed to
upload so it says what pockets tell you
about this - and what should the finding
start with or contain or it's like what
should the fightin be or you can have
this loose thing like it's at least
gonna start with this disk you can also
say that access control
lair if it should be publicly read by
anybody or if it should be private then
you need to sign the URL to see it and
you can also like to have the content
type start with something and also you
can specify that the length of the
company this policy I would say every
lineament is vulnerable to some form of
protein policy it's so easy to be wrong
first of all if you have starts with the
key meaning the training and it does not
contain a path separator you can
actually add host files on the root of
the packet some like but the thing is
one of the criteria to install the
service worker is that you can put files
in the root folder of the domain
installing a service worker on a sandbox
domain it's just as bad because you can
have a service worker but he has
actually way to talk about this on
safety last year you can actually have a
service worker or the old little brother
of service workers called appcache that
that if you visit they sandbox domain
and you visit my file i will install a
service worker or an app cache in your
browser so anytime you download anything
from the sandbox domain that URL itself
it's a silent attack to harvest
information and you can actually service
workers are a bit of an upgrade then
attach attach you can say don't expire
at all basically which is crazy service
workers has like a built-in refreshing
timeout however if you have that worker
still on the side and
it can just be newly something so having
ties in your root folder of your pocket
don't do it at all
another issue with this is that if you
have start with and the key and that key
basically contains nothing or contains
the same value for all your users they
can basically replace any other file so
you can modify other people's documents
because that's the policy you can just
break the Boston right whatever I want
on any any file you are out of this on
this bucket which is awesome - attacking
changing images to something completely
another issue is like the compiler if
you have an empty content type you can
of course like this should be a text
HTML trying to make sense so you can
depending on the front of this position
you could have basically an XSS and
remember the XSS is not as bad here as
that we need to install a service worker
on a - the other thing is you don't need
to have an empty content type to bypass
it because if you provide it first with
a pilot countin type image JPEG you can
provide it with a Z like imitates and
then a semi
text HTML and it will serve as text hmm
so the whole thing with starts with
content type basically means whatever
come to fight people there's another way
to upload they tied to into these
buckets one solution is called AWS STS
and STS is basically an idea it's moving
slowly across okay it says generates
temporary credentials client-side that
sounds weird but the whole thing is is
basically you create the I am role in
your in your organization and then with
the same thing relief so the policy can
make you generate it on your skis and
you can then use those aww skis to make
authenticated requests every time you
see this they have my f3 : star or easy
to improve on star which is like the
worst thing ever that means that when
you generate these tokens with that
policy you basically can database tokens
to take over all their servers so the
whole idea the whole room fake is
basically you're pointing with the token
token to desk s Amazon AWS and in the
return to get the temper that's for Edom
yes and you can use AWS CLI to basically
just like this is
in my environment right now give you all
the recipe buckets and then you just
keep get all this it's because of this
broken policy we actually imported this
asking Sweden for one of the companies
and they're like okay you've got all our
source code you can read all the source
code you can replace our other IDs and
all the media people have uploaded is
now accessible by we actually did a
finalist thing on one of these buckets
and the credentials expired before we
could list all the problem is when
people are the leader so I saw an
example like this basically this was
pointing to let's say it was a ticketing
system where you could upload images
just saying I'm not saying but just say
that so you're pointing is to the ticket
system and first your JavaScript said
hello I want to upload a file called
images slash test int and I told this to
the ticketing system and they sent back
like a sign URL this site URL basically
gave a good access to the file
I was asking to interpret but the
problem was as I mentioned we could
override any other file that we had and
the site URL also allows I can read the
documents so that mean that you had
private files I could say please give me
Polish number one you sent me a cycling
and I would just take that image and
they paid a bunch of money with that
because that was like all their files
was in this
our site ok this is so bad and they were
changing it basically adding a bunch of
prefixes depending on who you loneliness
so nobody was sharing the same context
of the files so the whole thing with
building your own logic around this is
proved in almost every time the code for
me in this investigation most has been
to preach the fruit of the pocket
because if you have a signed link to the
root folder of the bucket you get the
finest tip if you get the finest thing
you know all the files that's in there
and then you can just make another
request to a file you know existed and
then it doesn't matter if they are
private because if you get a signed link
you can just download it anyway so the
goal is to reach the root or basically
reach someone else's file and I've seen
so many scary examples so this is
example is basically like they have that
image and you provided a key and we're
back to the nineties guys and girls we
like into a passenger personal choose
them they would normalize the URL and
then give me a sign normalized URL for
ESP bombers so remember like back in the
old days like please download public / /
/ / / / DTC password we're back this is
the same thing again basically I will
have access to all the object I can see
on that object I can list them and I can
just download everything we're back
same thing another another service they
were basically asking like okay do you
want to s3 URL signature cool the thing
was they were fiddling with you around
they were taking parts of it back and
forth so and
with this payload and that gave me the
root access of the pocket the pocket
plane was example - you can see they
have a double slash there if a macabre
slash before pocket it's not counted as
a key and you can get all the info in in
everything
my favorite one was actually I looked at
it's two years ago this is not a new
issue
nobody's talked about it but it's not a
new issue so the whole logic of this
side I see my PS now like I don't want
that sign it but the thing is basically
you said I wanna put a fire and it said
okay give me the key and I gave up /
it's a cookie and basically it created
something and I was super weird so you
basically had a key and that is three
key so the random key I cooked was xx 11
and then I said the SV key is / he came
back to me I create that you're late now
that meant that going to secure
example.com / 5 stop my random key xx 11
would redirect me to assign URL for the
root pocket and this was the first time
I found this so I didn't know how bad it
was and I wanted to see how much they
have in the bucket this is a high-heeled
company they had one bucket they call
the conflict there was the company name
not as real Amazon it was a fun to play
with everything they had in the whole
company everything was in that bucket I
never got the whole finally I I have a
file that is 2 gigabytes large with
justify elect I kept it for some reason
I don't know I'm still looking
like you should perhaps these these are
still public response and so this is
still very much yeah I got to find this
leak but I could never see the whole
thing
so who'll access to all the objects I've
reported it to a bunch of companies and
they're like okay this is actually an
issue this last company I mentioned that
was two years ago and they just like
this is one of the worst things we could
ever like see so they paid me like fifty
thousand dollars as ugly and ten
thousand dollars as a bonus just because
they were like this is such a mess but
now you're thinking what happened with
kidnap that is the question what I did
was basically top telling them about
this domain they didn't do anything more
than just fixing this but what happened
was I had friend call it overflowed and
a couple of weeks after the let secret
thing he actually published this I could
actually use Atlanta to harvest
I could add any domain I want in the
whole world and anytime they want to use
key club and use this thing they will
now be served under my control
so he found the way it mask wanted me to
just add everything to this which is no
the nicest food to show that was
basically weighted so they actually shut
the whole it lab pages down and the
domain verification one of the first
companies in
the history of this domain verification
thing that actually like yeah we're
gonna fix this I thought that I was able
to do it by having them at sorry that
they were wonderful no no no they were
focusing more on their customers so that
was the way I actually was able to take
a full account takeover on github just
because I was able to take this to me I
didn't even need to say to them that I
couldn't get the certificate issue
because also I didn't want to get this
big issue because that would look bad
only by telling them they were like okay
this is a critical thing we should
probably wait I'm actually done thank
you very much
excellent question no one more time
Cooper a stream off
you