[Music]
not
oh
[Music]
a
oh
[Music]
or not
oh
[Music]
hello we are starting one is the sixth
edition we will return to the house we are
manizales the people are arriving
registering are putting of
rosettes several stickers we already have
the coffee everything is prepared for you
start the first speaker and we offer
with this open of pure pure here in
this weekend very happy that
be the event at the university of
manizales the house of the community of
community founders
USA are university professors
in this conference because I teach the
computing and these are these
types of hacker conferences is very
important so that
we have more knowledge of how
hackers are doing to penetrate
the systems and type of social ingenuity
What are you doing to be able to teach?
enough how to defend yourself
buy in your perfect great
It is a very nice public and in general I
like dragon philosophy
very friendly people
the public is following you
latin america my name is asia pastor and
not also to do Latin America and does
some days we run through someone
colonies for the prevention of dragon
charter in our
international conference
so we've had a great time now
we are in this about to give our
unexpected first chat look at her
also discovering that it has been missing like this
that we hope that good with a little bit of
nerves but we hope you like this
talk about child safety yes
they like to stay where we are going
give after lunch which is like the
second part of I tea you a little more
spicy my name is josé pino about
IT security investment
internationally I am also
event sponsor for any
stuff
Well basically space has been
great really was what I
always expected in all events
because the meeting has always been a
Colombian showcase for people
talented in computer security
both Latin American and local and
Well, for my part, I invite you in the
close to marcón and it is a pleasure to be
sharing with all of you how are you
How are you, a good block of Peru is formed
am
Has anyone had this topic for a long time?
time the truth did not come to manizales
many several years ago tests that dean
is one of the 25 after in 2009
and ago and craters there are avenues and
manizales has grown a lot the movement in
his second decision too
the event has grown in universities
I am very happy because it feels like
there is let's say that more participation
It is important to have more awareness
as to
safe to be safe and
to make sure
marten well I'm Mexican I don't come from
switzerland work for dream lar
technologies in Switzerland and I came to present
a chat called rap sporting and
basically we are going to find the
servers from bad hackers and what
let's find where they are at
internet and sometimes we can
disable and well is what comes
he is having a great time in manizales
very nice and good dragon is already a
event you already have
a reputation the community already has
many years my name is
Max I come from Peru but currently lives
in buenos aires this conference of
2015 of my fourth time I'm coming
so the truth is that I have a love
especially for the
knowledge that is shared my talk
specifically talk about issues of
exploitation of vulnerabilities in wii
in windows on how were all found
those vulnerabilities without de wilde and
like us a cork I was able to perform
the exploits and tell a little what is the
impact of these exploits and how
work so that people can
understand like this
may be vulnerable not only
users but also companies and what
measures can be taken to avoid falling into
these things that maybe they can bring
economic and business damage
hello my name is eduardo snail de la
Panama City I am the director
executive of the eye community foundation
a non-profit organization that
is dedicated to training professionals in
cybersecurity in the city
this is my third event to work for
me this is a very good experience
because it has allowed me to know
professional research in
cybersecurity area that are presented
in the best conferences in the world
I have also had the continues to do
networking
know
professional speakers who have a
similar interest as mine and above all
the work that Jaime and Jacobo do and
all team exhaust to do
feel foreigners and
nationals as a family is something that
It has a lot of value. I invite you to
actively participate in the community
from aragón heart and come to today at
conference thank you very much the luxury of
luxury very good super technical conference
very good I take a lot of things
to investigate and to learn and to
further develop security secure
well we finished the conference we are
all destroyed a long work of
the whole team thanks to all the people
who came to all the sponsors
university manizales mayor me with fa
dragon will make all the people who come from
Other parts of the U.S. Paraguay
peru panama everyone thank you very much
but we look forward to next year here in
manizales open cities very well
very tired but very happy
exceeded all expectations
we had among the super happy of
all talks all content
that we have for you were very
good in fact I don't know if we had
said before but we received more than 103
papers and of all those we receive from
all the 20 received we take out 12 for
show the best research
computer security in spanish
so we are very let's say we are
very happy with everything that was achieved and
prepared for next year towards the
next edition
[Music]
very good morning late that night
depending on the time and place
who are watching this broadcast my
name is jaime restrepo and you
will be here not by mistake but because
they are watching the heart security dragon
conference on its second day on the day of
yesterday was quite interesting we were
very very good content of very good
very varied quality and that was felt
for the love they have expressed to us
you on all social networks
this presentation is more than all one and
are the instructions basically for
that they learn to enjoy the event
mainly because I know that many
of you arrived today for
recommendation from a friend or relative
or colleague who was yesterday and told them
they depend on this event that is very
well this one arrives or not and they don't know much
of what is being seen to cassiers
so the institutions for that
we are tired most events
online true but
this is our last one with 100% online
because we are going to the next edition
have face-to-face
possibly in the city of manizales
in a hybrid format what does it mean
although there is a possibility that
let's charge input into the electro
in person we are going to stream
keep 100% online and free this
Well, because we have seen that you have
highly appreciated all the efforts
it is being done by when
we are doing these transmissions and
because we know that there are people who know
connects from cuba to venezuela
other countries that possibly if not
outside because we broadcast live on
internet for free could not
access this content
as I am yesterday for the speakers and
for the organizers and for everyone in
general it is important that they make us
feel the love on social networks now
we have seen how effective it is
this and we have seen how the same
explain
respond to posts thank you
that what is making them arrive is
very important that we do it with him
hashtag dragon hardcore why yes
you do not know or did not find out the
yesterday we managed to be a trend
only in the city where we are
allowing but at the national level in the
section for you on twitter and this
It was only possible thanks to everyone
support that you gave us apart from
that this morning we woke up with that
put and cool that is a company
specialized in all that networking issue
social because he began to follow in the
trending topic the drawn hardcore and we
releases a series of statistics
interesting here for example we see the
people who have been participating more
from yesterday to today
Let's hope that this top is getting more and more
varied and more and more people appear
for this we have a kit
survival or press actually the
first we have is the number 2 is
for the possibility to download more or
less than 800 megabytes that has videos
Let's say a lot of content and the number
2 which is the same as number 1 but
without the videos then they have
templates by paul for you
can make their own posts
they have the talks the summaries
speakers the social networks of the
you explain well they have everything
they need so they can continue
supporting and sending love
speakers from here
we also saw that many creative people
it occurred to him to take memes from the event and
which we quite liked there are some very
interesting those that we are going to
laugh a lot
some came out related to the
occasional talks by some of the speakers
others more generic then the truth
we achieved a lot they can be doing
Some of us are going to ask for contests
better of better said without if they make you laugh
to the three spades because we have a channel
internally and that they themselves choose which
It is the best meme to date there are very
good ones
So don't stop, don't stop sending your
publications
we have the space in general we are
broadcasting on multiple channels
mainly on youtube but also
we are on facebook on twitter and on
twitch then so we don't know
go back to where they were
Given the questions, we are going to have
a centralized channel that we are using
since yesterday is to leave point m is
the questions that you send your
ask there and we will
we transmit to the speaker so that he can
go on screen we also have a
bidirectional channel that is
driscoll and find it at this url there
they can write and well we are going to have
people let's say pending what
you say the ctf started the day of
yesterday at 9 in the morning today is
tomorrow enrique has sent us the
current status of the fao that this is the
top 6 there is more than always is more
participating in the ctf we can see how
countries like Spain Ecuador
I do not recognize the other way because they are
pronouncing true this top surely
will vary throughout the day or
the days because this is etc to be
until Sunday at 12 at night and
We will announce the award on Tuesday
on instagram in a live
ready we also have the calendar
What do you want me to be warning?
regardless of the time zone
are driving you can enter here and by
calendar process in your goal calendar and
The same system will notify you that
It is already giving more at what moment are the
certificates have not asked
many remember that in these
moments can already generate certificates
of all previous decisions how
they are going to do it they can follow this manual
it's there take a screenshot
send let's say scanner with your phone
whatever
but at the end of the transmission well
we are going to have the possibility that
generated in the certificate of this edition
I can't leave without first thanking
all needle work equipment
that he has put on the shirt so that
be everything, go ahead to all of us
explain why if the content that
they provide as this would not be
possible to all of you are behind
screen supporting publishing
participating and listening and seeing
all the content we have for
you do x what is the company
in charge of the transmission that everything has
I've been flawless with them for a long time
many years we are working with
them and they continue to be very good and
very professional and we couldn't leave
one side our sponsor we have a web
to be an American consulting firm
specializes in security issues
offensive computing but that is not there
antivirus manufacturer that has been
supporting this year and it is thanks to whom
you can have in the raffles that
we are doing for the different
spaces we have football and for many
best plugin for boot suite out there
in the market we have created maga
hacking a Uruguayan consultancy but what
has a presence in several countries
latin america
we have the pit bones a platform
of the group that is looking to earn a
space in this new
football world and we have to work
education that today has this
promotion for 10 people with
70 percent discounts on your diploma
and we have loreto martínez with the
following talk in the centered
circuit with schematics like these
what's up uncle how long is my pleasure
be with you as always and many
thanks to the organization for counting
with me one more year and well then
ready for the latter finally online
in real time but that the following
whether they are in person to you and so be to
lorenzo let's do our tenth
decision it is incredible that they have already
Ten years have passed since the first dragon
hardcore and well let's try
do it as it should be a celebration of
accounts with the public
tell us, thank you very much, well, nothing
I come to talk about the same thing
vary as always and that's why I put it
I'm going to give a talk at the dragon
hardcore if I'm going to talk about expertise
forensic computer I'm going to talk about
incident response is one is two
cases I'm going to go a little fast because already
we have eaten ten minutes and it says
I have for a little while you already know me
lorenzo martinez the director of
security me my contact details
you have my email for whatever you want
Lorenza steals dotcom security I don't use
things in between for me to write
you write there and period
and my twitter wait for what you want
display mer as always the cases that
I am going to expose they are true they are things
that have happened to me that have happened to
me or the team
surely we have done here in
in any case, of course,
hidden to the original idea of ​​fact
Every time I give this change talk
certain data, let's say the content, that is
from the point of view of professions
things etcetera to make it a little more
complicated and the only exposure
purpose it has is academic
to say what it is about here is
count I did this like this and that's how it came out and
we got to this content to this to this
result doing this like this
that's the goal nothing more
from the first case as I say
there are two is one of pure expertise
pure computer forensics in this case is
the one you see because as they are from
important forensic artifacts
hard drive file system
you are going to see what I mean or how not
make an expert opinion
contrary to what he did now you are going to see a
pretty good botch basically is
I put in background of the case as if
It is about a person who was my
client was a person who worked in
a company and was fired because while
low for kobe for example it could be
for other things but let's put for
kobe
Of course, to all this, someone who is going to
start doing the job you did
this person this was a lawyer
he's going to get down to it and he's in
the corporate computer according to the
company has been used
and doing personal work have been
found information according to the
company in which good thing is
person
Let's say that the in would run in a
series of personal works and has
billed elsewhere
the client tells me man me years ago
yes it is true that he did something else
thing but the information that they are
raising this company
I was not on the computer at the
corporate computer that I used
but it was on a hard drive of mine
personal that was in the drawer of my
table then of course if the company has
accessed the drawer seen a hard drive
has connected it has looked inside and has
Having said what is here, well, if he
hard drive is personal you can't
do that and have filed to dismiss
to this person by paying zero euros without
compensation and an expert report
expert report made by the other
part
prove the existence of a series
of files on the corporate computer
and he says I made the expert report that they have
been created or processed since that
computer is based on what
extract, analyze and conclude that expert
he says he has enough information
to conclude that the information that
I was on the corporate computer of
this company from this assigned company
to this person was made by in that
computer since it was assigned to this
worker that my client asks me
He tells me look, read the expert report of
adverse the opposite
look to see
what evidence do you have to acquire
inside what there is and analyze it and
look at it because I am sure that
that was not there because I know what
what was there and what was not
and on the other hand of course you have to
identify whether the evidence that has
presented the opposites are
compatible with what my
clients to isolate the expertise of the
contrary and the evidences extracted and
analyzed are compatible with what
my client is saying
ok then the first thing i do is
read me the expert report of the opponent
I see that very formally they have
run a notary in spain for example
It is not like in Colombia in which what
the expert says mass and points to is so
And it's over, but in Spain an expert
computer from or has been brought by
one party does not have to public
in this case they are taken to a notary and the
notary let all a series of
facts carried out by the expert
does the expert and what does he say that it is being
the notary says so in his notarial deed and
the expert in his report says that since
They tell you that there was a series of files
who were on the computer today
he arrives and takes out two hard drives that he has
in a bag and takes two hard drives
in scoring in the new ones I know very well
the expert directly starts the
that person's computer plugs one in
of those hard drives, formatting them is
there also connect the other hard drive
also format it from that windows
and they give you access with the user of this
person who says they had the
user's password was in a
post-it or on a sheet and I don't know if below
keyboard in a drawer behind the
monitor or glued to the monitor or not if in
somewhere had the password
they connect with a user like i should
format those hard drives and the expert
arrives and looks for certain files and
drags them right into one of those
hard drives as some were in a
site the ones the company tells you no
they were at the desk others were
I don't know where others were in another
location drags them a disc and
then how to repeat that again because it was
a little bit of a pain in the ass what it does is
open one of those disks and from there
disk drags everything to the other copy
hit the other
go crowned with evidence don't go
acquisition of evidence that can
make my father who is not an expert
computer forensic or copied
directly with the clear windows and
then it arrives disconnects the two disks
hard and tells the notary good to see
that I put them here back come one
for you not for me any is for
Well, it is after this that the notary grabs
one presents it signs it with a seal
from the notary all very well and the expert
he takes another record home a day
Following this, the computer
format directly as they tell me and
it is assigned by worker because there was
to continue working with the access that
the corporate information that had the
important gold because if you format it and
they do not pay attention I do not know there is something a little
strange but now total that the expert
league and with the order with the hard disk
that he has that he has taken him back to
copy to your computer this got it out in
based on various screenshots in
which efe it is seen that the date is at
day after going to do the
acquisition and based on that
and its files copied from windows
obviously
analyzes and concludes that indeed
that information has been created and or
processed from this computer
amazing for any connoisseur who is
seeing this except the expert that
did this job look what an aberration
come to this walesa because simply
based on analyzing the files and now and
have been made on that computer have not
could be copied put there and
directly
to be at I do not deny existence but
man from there to use creation and
treatment there is a difference but
to all this the notary when he goes there
it was to put it at 12 in the morning
when he went to draw up the minutes of the
notary records hello being
12 in the morning I start to see what
this time ago
what do I do I'm going to make one
acquisition of these evidences I have the
report of the other uncle in which I become
crosses when I read it and on the other hand
I see what I can do
then the judge allows me to go to the
company and the only thing I can and they let me
do is a visual inspection of the
computer I go with the client that
distinctively this may be my
computer or not I don't know you can also
say what you want is also true
but the company tells me that this is the
computer lead me to all this there was a
attorney for the other party my client is
a computer scientist from the company who
Lets see what's there and I what I do
It's the least I can do because
Obviously I can't overdo it
what i do booted the computer up and
i think i can do it
connected a flash drive to the machine in the
which one told the computer scientist look at this
It only has one tool called
fck worth mind that is a tool
forensic that allows you without access to the
files worth without manually accessing
each thing allows me to see how a
file system inside
playing her master fighter iv is
say an internal forensic artifact of a
own ntfs file system
sheep with this what interests me is
see the date of creation of the emt
because because you are going to tell me the date of
formatting those drives yes
indeed it coincides that they had been
formatted the day after
the expert would have gone with him no such
to all this I say okay well this is it
that i have seen initially
one of the things that they tell me and tell me
my client is that there in the files
that appear on that disk that I copied is
this expert there are files that were
were created in years long before
when this pc existed, that is, it is impossible
that I have done or tried or otherwise
least created that file with this
computer because the hardware did not exist
of this computer when that was made
file therefore what I do is
also look in the profile of the
windows device manager
the hardware that hardware is there and I see that
It is an intel i5 of tenth I invented it
generation and a graphics card in the
to be
whatever model it is then what do I do next
give me a look at the date of that and based
to creation date from hardware
I can say no on that computer I don't know
did because this processor is from this
year and these files were created in
a much earlier date therefore this
What is this person saying here?
false worth of
a forensic image of the drive
computer there is no expert in his day
I copy the files, bloated, I don't know
it occurred to make a forensic image of the
disc save it before a notary as
I would correspond as any expert
would normally occur to him to say
each in two things one in expert did not have
no [ __ ] idea option 1 or the expert and it was
required to simply make copy
of files and perhaps proposed to the
better not to make a picture and leave one
real image made but on record
notary was not there and maybe the other
part said it's not going to make this
way me if they ask me so
I will do but left a written record
that I recommend doing it from another
So why do I make an image at
disk with the files entrusted by the
another expert to plug it in are many and
copy them to an image as God intended
a cold image and on that image
work to all this believe
a performance certificate mine of course
there was a notary at that time what
I did was write a document that
compel all witnesses to the party
contrary and mine and I all
we sign that act, they are written with
what happens if someone has to
make a statement that I have
done something wrong put it there why
I do this to heal myself in health if I
later
I have a problem because the other party
says that you exceeded the firm I know
what and why you did not put this by
video course I wrote and everyone
I agreed that what I had
done was the bare minimum
they agreed to allow me to do
this that no one was opposed to what I
did with this saved me that no one
I can blame like everyone else
we sign and we all have a copy of
each of those acts that is the same
in all cases, because here we
we all protect it is no longer about what
I lied about something, okay, it's about that
you guarantee me that they can't
to say that I have done something different from
what is here because we have all
signed this here is always the truth
in front
that I find myself as a result of
analysis of the forensic image that I
I take from the hard drive that was left
stored in the company sealed by the
notary I find a single partition
normal formatted with a system
ntfs files and whose creation date
from the mcc that is when it is formatted
that file system is in date and
time of the minutes approx 4 up to here well
here and this part is kind of hard to watch
and to understand but well let's
try
When we talk about analyzing a system
of ntfs files we are going to meet
two games of four time we are
different relative to each file or
every directory that is on the system
of files some of which are of type s
iii or standard information and others that
they are of type of cn or fire main are called
us those that are of type s iii and are in
both cases are four are I'm going to
focus only on the type s and they are
those manageable through the api
windows through a set time or
bedtime so that when there is a
action on a file is altered
update the time stand of that file and
depending on what it is depending on what
to be done a timestamp is updated u
other st at a time istanbul when you
create a file the date of the newly
created the 4 timestamp are equal and the
date create the date you have is the
that you have the creation date of the
switch ok if you modify the content of
that file is a text file
which text element inside and I give it to
save five minutes after having done it
created that of creation is maintained and the
of modification and is changed to five
minutes later, that is, when it has
saved that content last
access is a bit random because
Really
can this windows configured what
normal for it to be disabled
access time update ok
a registration law that is read in the tc
s 16th the chs is something something like that no
I remember right now how it is but come on
the movie is in that particular one
never update between quotes and
in this theme time what shows us what
that changed that is what when
update is the last time it has
changed for example that has been
changed the permissions of a file
that an attribute of the
file has been done hidden has been done
read-only
or have been given permissions at the level of
does the is so that the user can
agree to listen and I say this because
formless
now well when you believe when you
copies a file that is on a system
from ntfs files to other systems
files in tps this case what happens
is that the creation date of the new
file on the external hard drive is the
of the date and time of the copy when
produces bag however the same thing happens
with the access to be in a windows 10
weeks are believed to be those of the moment
what is done is to collect say can
for a file to be created and accessed
in 2015 but if I copied it now in
2022 to another site the new file whose
more evident content and which original
ok going to have in the new system
files that the date of he that decree
and the access time will be the ones from now
however those of modification time and
those of mfc mod time are going to be the
originals that I had at the time
all right
ok then having this
behavior in the head and this varies
Windows 10 from certain
Windows 10 versions onwards and
backwards this is a bit complex lo
I admit but this case came out as
it came out because it was
of fine thread, that is, it was a surgeon
you are going to see
the client who reads as he takes out the
information that I get from that let's say
of the interpretation that I do tells me
is that some of the files that I
they are saying if they were on the pc but
Others that they are telling me are
the ones that were on my hard drive that I
I had it in an expensive drawer, a client
I have to do with this face that is me
may be telling the truth or not i
just in case
smith and no good well that's what I
the client is saying I can't
trust what the client is but if
I have to interpret the evidence and
see if your demo is supported
with what you put because it may be
miguel bosé or that he hires me but
It can also be a person who
is telling the truth i find
I find that really those
folders and files inside
who were on the computer according to me
says the client in what has copied the
proficient
is what has to happen the crisis john
tenniel access time are always the same
/ in each file and are between the time
start dale of the cta that the end of
the action of the clear expert the time that
it takes to copy a thing a site without
however the immortal s and the snt more
time' are the originals that had good
this is expected and normal
what I am however those
folders that according to the client were not
in the computer
I see that the same in the spectrum start
before the normal style however the mod
time is the original the original that
actually had the file when it is
person
what was on the hard drive
original yes since that record has
copied to another like the mortal and the mst
deadly are carried and kept with the
original would remain but the heretic
we are so careful it is shown that it is of the
same day of the action of the expert but
four hours before the notarial deed says
which stated that the company
they descended from the computer when it arrived
the expert and notary
Well, it can be warm that it wears
on 20 days and really blast
five minutes before it goes up don't you dare
no one has looked at the events no one has
looked at absolutely no artifacts
of this person's system or user
of this computer to be able to see if
have you done something with that computer or not
it really just got cold
the existence of a listen
what happens is that it is
finding me the mf we have time with a
modification four hours before is
perfectly compatible with that a
administrator user has logged in
to the machine has copied the files
on that person's desk or in a
directory to which that other user
had access and when you get into
a
directory that is not yours even if you are
administrator tells you windows hey what
know that you do not have permission to enter
here but as you are administrator
you want that is the one to give it to you yes for
favor and automatically generates a cl
which does an update of the mst
mortal
could also make there
changed all to readonly and read
writing or that were not hidden at all
hidden but the way they go
which is not exactly four hours
before, but minutes change and
seconds I see this in the master is missing
and I'm going to say that there has been a process of
do is this test the is empirically
walesa i took another computer of mine i made a
test create about 60 media access
take out the emt and indeed the
behavior was this at the level
emergent therefore empirically
I could tell that it was compatible with what
that leaves all this good and the
computer itself
what it has is that the report
contrary expert says that from the
the files were created on its own computer
says it is impossible okay because first
It's impossible for me to prove it because
the creation date of everything i
I have really is the date of creation
of the copy, that is to say, I do not have the
original I have the copy if I had made
this guy a previously image well
well but it is that when I have gone there
Well, let's see it exactly when you went
but it was formatted I have
carried the dates of the creation of the
emt and I see that they are the next day
of the dismissal therefore he is not here no
there has been a lot, no, that is, it hasn't
there was a possibility that I do that
acquisition in order to demonstrate a
thing to the other not
there is no disk image therefore
as a disk image is not even
have brought forensic artifacts from
user ellen tauscher dot give ni los
recent nor the jungles to giuseppe the
punctuate neither the keys nor anything at all
nothing has been taken or preserved
neither among other things
the other part can say is that I
keep that computer there motionless to me
It costs me money, it's a computer, they're worth it.
the invention two thousand euros thousand five hundred
euro
I can not have it, there is to have a soul
of god that you can make an image of
disk and leave an image of the disk in
another site is okay or you can get the
hard drive what I did was look for the
hard drive model that came with that
computer and saw how much it cost on amazon
and onion look for 50 euros you have a
hard drive the same, that is, for 50
euros you could have preserved the
audience and you didn't feel like it
then it is clear what I see in the
computer is what it is besides that the
concrete hardware
what does that computer have is newer than
when those other files were created
ok and i can prove it ok
On the other hand, the expert report in
christian way was crap was
very bad but very bad savor all the
procedure was very wrong I already said that his
requirement was to find information
documents and data that allow to conclude
objectively that in said
computer equipment have been made
professional activities that are
unfair competition and uncle based on
that argues it
on the other hand it says that it is required
so that they copy all the files but
you have not copied the files you have done
a copy of only a few folders
those of tyson client there and that's it
then he concludes that he has taken
professional activity outside the company
from a year well before hardware
basic processor more card the good
is that they may have changed this
It is no longer the same computer, it is worth what
but it is also that the way to test
that this user has done it is not to see
the existence of files that can
have been there or not and I have you
they may have planted there that is in my
opinion what they have done with those who have not
they were on the computer according to my client
and really the client me when they see it
It's that Miguel Bosé is making me
but it is that really later the
evidences because they gave him the reason
you know what and it is that as an expert I do not
I'm here to agree with my client
I am here to see if the evidence of
viewer that my expert says that my client
He tells the truth, I am for that, not for
something else then
So of course when you see this it says
Well, that you have everything done, it is
one side several very serious the artifice
has not preserved anything negligence or
failures in the analysis the analysis was
painful and you can not say that it is the
user activity has dealt with those
files when you haven't even parsed
user activity does not exist for
that I can see it if it's true no longer
there is a form of contradictory because
there really is no divide
the one that would have once we are time
updated four hours before
the expert arrives and the notary can
make me understand also that they have
searched for an expert sufficiently
well let's leave the limited
knowledge
so that really
when I got there there would be the files
and grappos yes yes yes they have created this
here but as white and as many
you can tell they were there but they weren't
you can say that they have created them bar
treated there because it is not true then
Apart from that, it is not possible to test whether
they created not from the dice because we
User artifacts have been made
of that user who demonstrates that
indeed it has opened them although it is
There are those above who demonstrate
what changes have you even made to them
that you have agreed to be content that we
admire nothing regret
for this finish a game and ended in
a final traded at the gate
for good with my client they paid him I think
that everything I asked my client
gave a contrary report before
enter that god this is going to break us in
two and it really hurts that I was going with
you win because it is that he because when already
I mean when something
professionally it is badly done and it is
so badly done is that it really is a
shame what some people do
that is, there really is the harmed
is the other company that in quotes
because I think that part of having done
things at hand also had the company
but what I am fairly clear is
that the expert is what he had to
make wings something else though because that
it was not done that way that was not done
well, this was a case of expert opinion
with me to my client because he was right
initially it seemed to me that I was
counting a strange movie but no no
it was true what he said and then he
Second case I called him catch me if you can
this is very curious because it is good
from a company that calls me and tells me
who have an active hack on the
moment the client was really
terrified he told me that they printed him
stuff on company printers
Ok, well, it was a real company.
they were with the whole company stopped
because of course things were printed on them
the printers saying see you
I'm listening
there was something that implied that
they knew the people inside or whatever
like very directed
but a company every time I count it
I say that it is from a different sector than
I am going to say that he was from that sector of the
roulette, well, what was done in the sector
food for example or industry
medieval is that I want to give me what
I am not going to tell you which sectors
the story is that the company
I was standing, they tell me what was happening
strange things sometimes had something to do
another poltergeist
and that about three months ago before
they called me to call me already with
all for I suggest in a denial of
web service
they left messages through the
company contact form
English but it was an English as we say
in spain english beach english
Juan Villar's beach shoes click well then
such a thing as very
wrong is like I think it was wrong
fact is english bet worth later
You will see why I no longer believe that the
person who wrote that
wrote badly or spoke so bad English
really, they even let him
messages in which they referred to a
person from within the company
direct, which implied that
there was something that wasn't, that is, it was someone
who knew there
then the messages also said that
had we have access to your servers
we will do what we want
etcetera as they printed them with which
they said hey I'm seeing you they arrived
they had to turn off the cameras
that the client had in the sap company
I was scared alive and you are going to see the
barbarity that was this but of course
when you see this it says where
I start not good well I what
I always recommend starting
for what we know we know
well that on one hand they have left me
messages in a contact mailbox in a
web of contacts initially but by
other part the last ones that I have
that they print things for me by my printers
therefore and they say that it also has
access to the cameras because I don't know
so what we do today in the
cameras keep those of something not a bit
I have to look hear the printers how
are printed because there are some servers of
impression we will look to see if it has
there have been print jobs there are no
that nothing is saved
it is seen that the person is bad
theoretically knows the person
commissioned here in the company by the
messages that we say then already
The only thing that remains is for the moment we will go
against the web server that is not because
be the only thing exposed to the internet
only but because it is also worth
that the evil one has had access against him
it is there here it is presented to the hand and
greeting I'm going to say rejection please
very good yesterday bad looking at the server
web this was a good linux machine
Well we started to get evidence of that
linux machine
looking at the vast user history
admin it is seen that there was all the activity
of commands in which things are seen
that if they are suspicious that if they are
malicious is not the dates on which
who sent the messages to the
company but at all times there is a
lots of things the most manager and a
linux by default and depending on the
distribution does not save
at the date and time when it is typed
a command when it has been executed
something then what we do for
identify when something has been executed
or at least limit the times is
search for those commands you generated in
a file or generate an entry of
those of some kind and we know this was
on this date therefore what I would do
then it will be from now on and
whatever comes before is going to be from here to
ago identified several points in which
which can I assign a time date
executing a command can
decide
when or in what time ranges has
past these commands and look in the
connections that have been if there has been
there have been connections because this only
will remain when there has been a base
it is worth either in the local or because
the attacker has connected directly
by ssh for example the machine or has
sent a shell and then executed a
max there will be registered for me
bass history something if not this is not going to
pass there may be form of execution
remote command on machines that do not
are recorded in the history but
here was everything recorded that was seen was
would see the creation of a directory
hidden
hide a directory in linux that is
as easy as calling it with a period
in front of this there is no need to do anything
master for this and inside was the
jeep download with and grow is
tell those close that it is a free project
that what he does is requires something
interesting is a username and password
domain and what it does is inject
mimicry ok on windows machines to go
pulling credentials from memory
users of a domain well a stiller
of remote credentials in this case ok
very very interesting
well we found that obviously that
He has not done it with anyone from the company
for purposes
normal not dare legitimate and reproduction
but there it is seen that there is evil
I find more of these from the
admin user I feel good
copy of a file or a web path
curious because it also asks you here if
you have to place it on it to steal
www to director, that is, he has followed the
manual well as I say as a curiosity
execution of the tool requires a
domain and a user that is to say that who
run that has to have a user
domain or know a user of
domain to be able to do it is to say that
there has to be a chat there has to be
a preview of before having stolen or
got somewhere
domain username and sucre password
for him
As I was saying when this happened, well, in
based on command execution
we identify with the file system
based on the creation and modification of
files in when things have happened
on the other hand a very curious thing
reading the story under 52 girls who
there were other history there were 13 create create
clear screen
options that's weird no this is weird
find that there is to create every so little
time option or not someone is you
looking from behind and you don't want to be seen
see what is coming up on the screen
but no option 2 you have a touch I'm not going
directly modified describes how
you see the screen
option option 2 on the other hand of
commands that are uncommon in the
execution as thor and world top is for
talking to another user is worth three
sessions the same is to send a message
to all users who are
connected in all the sessions there are
among other things you can see a happy new year goal
new or similar are worth exactly the same
It was at the end of the year or at the beginning and
see a goal happy new year seriously but
Seriously in Spanish this but who you
is attacking trunk a professional a
[ __ ] troll
where it is clear I think the attacker
I was there entertained because there was
accessed a machine and then
felt like
the beggining
This man was loved more than him
president rivals himself new
total body that we keep looking at
keep looking and interesting file
where there have been connections not the out
love point at the point the first thing you see
free brute force attempts
public that is to say by ssh that is to say that
be that here is exposed to the internet
we consult with the client and take it
before this exhibition it is good that is not
well but well let's see who it is
know from which addresses and pérez have
connected up to here everything from
a specific date date xx and now and
and i won't say when
a password change was observed
user admin called the customer today on
client has usually changed the
user's password on that date if
It sounds like I did it because things were already happening
rare we dropped the entire network
So I have sanctioned myself for
if so and how is this answer
Internet I changed the password
then the perfect good customer
immediately afterwards I begin to see attempts
manual failed authentication
initially they look okay or it looks when
I try it is failed manually and
when it's brute force when it's force
brute you see that everything happens very fast in the
same minute second when manual
there is a time between when someone writes
or type a something not then
asking we see that this was the
plateau than ip addresses that
failed attempts are recorded
come from IP addresses that according to me
says the client
the company
eye
or know that it is someone who has a pc
initially engaged in rank
company wireless
hours later the same pattern is observed
but now in brute force mode and at full
host is worth that yes from an ip
of the range of the wool of the internal network
Wi-Fi no longer ranges well and
curiously the next day there is a
satisfactory access to the first bone
that is to say without brute force and without any
nothing from range ip address
wifi from yesterday let's go to the same
day from the from the ip that there was
failed attempts the day before the day
next enter the first bear is
someone who already knows that password
some way but I don't see that here
there has been a full access access since
any of those ip is therefore what
must have gotten it another way
well ok and that is the wifi range is
someone who has access to Wi-Fi or a
pc that is tight on the bus
Well, listen to how they work here
whose ip addresses is this limit
fixed on this ip of the wifi network that
you have the pda the network plan in another I can
say that it is the client because here everything
works for htc ok with the tascas
and the servers work through the tv
well, well, how can you not do it to me?
say I'm going to go to the servers
hcp what do you have to see if there are logs I'm leaving
to the wifi network store the http there is the
corporate firewall we connect
we look there are no hot
there is no gray there is nothing that allows me
identify here in burning you
would allocate a bad idea through
from the mac he took out the hyper looking for the mac
in the company
obviously not good total that from
from there I say good and in the wool in the
land who gives you the one from hcp that's him
control controller I'm going to look and
there are no logs well there are no wait no
there is the order of hcp ok but but in the
domain controller one events
of my companions
this job in this case
we work a lot several colleagues
the time I say will be required urgently
and it was quite complicated but we were
pulling the ball you will see cut
and notices an event that is the
5800 7 on the domain controller
looking for this that during the range of
time that brute force lasted is worth
Look, you saw a message like this, no
It is this evidently of lack that I did
in the last 4 and 12 hours
there has been a connection to this sunday
controller from client machines whose
ip addresses are not the ones
correspond to the IP addresses of the
company
be alone that says and tells you towards
below this has been saved
printed and customer addresses and
I tell you and the hosting has remained in the
barfile debut netlog dot lo
well and only here that this message
it's taken from google and my is really
in my case it was not a connection it was 186
connections against domaine control
It is worth seeing as a team and specifically
it was a single ip address that looked
in a file that looks like
this one is worth you are going to see it now that
obviously not this one is also
removed google original image
and it is seen that it says it is to this file you
tells the date and time that we were
helped connect against the domain
controller and here only one appeared
wifi range ip address that is not
of the domain and a hotmail
and here is something that I have not told you
said and it is that in this company that
belonged to the random sector I knew
a person from the systems department
who worked in this company was not my
friend was not someone who left
way with him but I knew him from life
total that you are not going to imagine who
it was the ip and square name waiting for the
wifi range but whose corning was it if
of the person I knew in the
company download here I already stayed a
little hearing [ __ ] that everything points to
this person from the department of
systems as I explained this to the
client since explain I call the
client I tell him look we have reached
this point and of course it is not all points
that the people I know in this
company is his pc it doesn't have to be him
it could be the compromised computer
may have a problem in
computer and indeed there is someone
who pulls the strings from his computer and
is setting up all this mess is
possible, well, what I propose
to my client who is who to me
hire and pay me is
The first thing is take a notary to the
company to guarantee
worker so you can't say that
someone has modified the content of your
computer and that it is charging the
dead to this person be directly
hey look this is what it is and
directly from his hands you tear the
pc and what is it taken by the notary
it was the notary took the pc and up to date
Next
well this person also appeared
the company and I proposed
thinking that today it may happen that there is
been this person or not the one I want
have a meeting with this person with
my acquaintance and good I would like to see you hear
and he got a confession from him, what I did
that I arrived was to hey I want I have a
agreement with the company that they are not going to
dismiss nothing will happen but for
Please, if it was you, then confess what
say it there is no problem these people
they are good people they are good people they are
willing to forgive him is a person
young and good maybe the young
we do the [ __ ] many times or what
we have done this not so much but good
but those campilla people
Well, yes, in the end the guy gave me
said that it had not been that this was
I put miguel bosé back and that this
It is the fruit of a conspiracy but total that
that it was not then that sure that
someone was screwing up life and
He denied everything because I gave him the opportunity
that if it had been him he said so
that not total and that I did I went to
the notary before a notary acquire a
disk image of your computer and I
I safely brought me to the laboratory and
We analyze well analyzing that
contents
We are already beginning to see curious things
first there were actions of anti
forensics on one side and there wasn't much
trace just before the date on which
I start to do the research
of course obviously this person who
They know, wait, we have
hired securities to see if we
can you help with this by very well
things in life just from that
day from there to back there is almost no
information on the computer of this
person not another interesting thing is that
from the date I am hired
there were no attacks there were no things for
printers do not turn off things are going
the complete network did not fall there was not
attacks on the web server with the bird and
suddenly there were also executions of the
ccleaner program that as you know works
to clean things that have been in the
actions machine do not activity
and according to this person he justified his
responsible for the use of money if not
you know it's [ __ ] bad it's because it does
let the computer go very fast because
the windows is corrupted and goes away
filling with [ __ ] and degrading
he's right the man is that I'm a
powerful computer the hard drive that was
ss of the installation of was a windows
10 that had been installed less ago
of a year therefore it does not add up to me that
the degradation of the machine has been
big enough to get to this point
you had to run this kleenex
as if you had a hard drive
old hard drive and not that that
was very slow and indeed
it would be convenient to do it that way
done it looks like the ccleaner
installed it three days before the last
execution of tgn and executed it all
the days for the end of the month that is to say that
all this that uncle told me and
cheering up but it's 2
It doesn't look like it
well total that man and here we have
I have a video of the guy
this already solved the problem and
that now comes for that reason
review this that will give exactly
the same because it will not be possible
find more but there is a file that is
the consortium history dot txtr that lo
that saves inside the user of this
person
was the commands executed in power se
makes you have at least in this
non-clean version that is what it looked like
you saw scripting in python up to here
all good would be installation of the module
for me as for connections
interestingly ssh is to say to do
brute force for example by ssh well
quietly for me that you're going
testing no ideas and program in pay with
request to make web requests this
is not actually binding
an egg of executions of
clear
once again the touch is worth or not
had to see things on the screen that
They didn't add up or just what's wrong
when he's powers he's a screen on
blue and when you execute something and it
you execute wrong you get something in red
What leaves you blind is that with glasses
sun to read it and not let you
blind so if someone passes by
behind and sees it because indeed it can
give rise to that say what the hell
is this guy doing that he doesn't have to
do this then hence the clear in
mode to brutes on your pc many clear
on linux machine with lots of
clearly illegitimate activity and
catty and many clear ya tie for
behavior though I know
what else but then let's start
analyze and remove the artifacts
user forensics that must be removed
a user to see their activity that
we get out of here attempts are seen
event of 30 thousand 803 samba and when
client fails to map a drive
obviously when you don't know one
password of something you try to access it
beast for something is going to give you this
error and you are left on the pc side in the
client side I'm not going to do this
in the jungles access to resources
shared
where you have navigated at the systems level
of files this person this user
had literally tried to enter and in
reality had entered all that
shared that the whole company had
all the ips were seen one by one attempt
barraza dollar bars get before the cde today
dollar did not look good in some cases
and it looked like this shows us the folders
or shared resources for which you have
entered a person does not show me what
There is, but well, that is, he has entered
sites in which they try after
your user this is no longer an activity
normal of a normal user
on dates and times of use of the
printer to print the famous see you
Is it me or do these things happen, okay, there was
a user session started there is a
prefect that demonstrates that the break is
executed maybe download using the
I don't have navigation but I do have it
in the execution of break and previ you know
what is a browser that has a google
chrome below is worth bazán chromium and
the installation of the cec liner or surprise
right there not around on those dates
looking at the link this is seen in the same
master is missing and usb secure erased here
looks over writing and name change
of files from the cache or from the
navigation in this case of google chrome
that is to say that you have tried that you have gone to
delete otherwise
I have the 10 minutes that you used
Jaime I say it because I didn't take them off
that I have calculated for an hour
acclaimed in case you leave me 10 minutes
with sorry but you don't need then
as I say
to try to identify
let's say the ip address that had the
machine we see that in the software
installed has teamviewer ok
machine can be accessed by teamviewer
or use teamviewer to access
to other teams there is a file that
is the local teamviewer that when
starts the service what it does is
save record on one line this will
never does this if I'm not mistaken
keeps record of the ip that has to
we meet
calculating the difference between you and
the real time in this case Spanish
we found that the ip that had this
machine at a time that started the
teamviewer service was out of range
wifi that we had seen as attempts to
brute force access to web server
who were at the out point of love
linux server on the other hand has the
food installed when you use put it
and it serves to connect you for example by
ssh among other things to be like this to
systems
as a user artifact they keep us in
the inside of a fingerprint that
uniquely identifies the certificate
from an ssh server which disconnected
and its correspondent with an address
ip this what is it for me is it for
the one for what is it good for putin so that
if you connect to 1926 811 by
example and that 11 has a certificate
different from useful life that eye that I the
that I have saved here is different than
the end the first certificate that is me
showing the current connection so
so much you can be the victim of a
man in the middle attack not then
for that it is saved initially but at
me for forensic purposes it serves me for
know which servers you have connected to
that user because it is an artifact of
interior user be about to give in a
certain moment is worth or at least
from that user
among others we see the web server
directly through the hyperprivate from
inside and be careful a server is xy
who was in the company to all this
I ask the client and this server yes
What's the time? Let's do it.
in control on file servers
normal in a company or one's own
Web server
says hey and the service drop is
so of course we really had to
restart the whole set and yeah and we had to
do things because indeed
there were certain moments when
which the whole company fell
it was tastier when they started
these attacks and give you access to is x y
we connect alexis and of course here he
Trias is different, that is, there is no, I do not have
a tool to do this but
we remove those files that we
save information in this case games
at the out point you can see it
eyes because a physical that yes you
guard the glass of xx and that guards the
date and time of execution
command that saves the
with that it shows me connections
from the ip of the wifi range of the pc this
that I have told you forgive me it is not here or
maybe it obviously saves the date
and time of connection from an ip and in the
next file that I will show you is
the resemblance to bash history saves us
the date and time of execution of each
command by dante m ahead of me but what
important is that here I have the
connection from wifi range the ip that
you lie in wifi range on the date on
which was born to fight web server that is
that it has been from that ip that I also know
that pc had it because teamviewer me
is saying it and why am I watching
that malicious activity calls
quite focused indeed
and on the other hand I see connections in
different to see two blocks of
connections from the hyper range of the
lnd the same pc of that person of mine
known at the date that he was also
confirmed by titles to that at the end
indeed it is seen that these times
had connected in two different ranges
from dates to this is x y in the bar bar
I know the point what is where I
they put things away looking through the ranks
of dates I meet is
there are some things that are a bit
you miss an ls to see things that are there
that route very well and inside that there is
when it is heard I will be root the same there is not
nothing and that's why the guy arrive and execute
sudo su but crumbs and now root
sudoku will lead you to ruth again no
he is already accustomed to
connect to a specific machine
with a non-privileged user and does a
sudoku to serve ok clear screen
nuclear man finally what things no longer
I missed him well but if he is going
reading down does not
absolutely nothing useful in this
machine and what it does and when it already
we see the world the top creating we say
well let's see the investigation goes
stupendously it is clear that the
execution is the same person based on
comma running looking at the other
time range
the second of the connections the second
of these connections with the ip of the range
land and look here it seems that it has been
documented a little fact good
I want to do evil here I don't know very well
what but I [ __ ] on the [ __ ] and I go and
So what does he see, he says, well, I'm going
to execute those commands as well as with
rare characters not these characters
really what they do is a way not
try to run a delegation
service based on the execution of a
lot of come from let's say consumption
by maximum number of the process and that makes
currently on some linux machines
that are not configured correctly than the
machine collapse ipec good as not
it worked says to see if it is necessary
putting a sh or after it doesn't work either
wait I put a max in front to see
later they don't let him give and he has
more this the same does not hear you have the look at
be if it has no because when executing the ch
ball power interactive and selfa ssh goes
To be
sh the ones who have this I don't know what anymore
to do but I'll see you I'm bored
wait and be the root seats and am
root save anything not and for
see the crux of the user with which
is connected by as questions of their
sons ruth and you are logged in as root
totally good god that the guy tries
delete the murban which is a directory
hard
good thing it is generated every time at startup
store important information
server and to return to
regenerate I have to go out again
wanted to make the mother come back
restart no but hey you can live
without it hears and the machines that there were
here that were not open runs there will be
done something inside some machine
virtual is playing now already as we have
that we can look at all this we are going to
To die
Well, the client indicates that here in addition
of the production machines that were
there were lab machines watching
we see that there is a machine for root and
leaving the [ __ ] that can see here well
looking at the modification dates of
the vm files of each of this machine
parrot we see that the dates are
previous are several months previous
I will have installed it I don't know but I don't know
has used because if it had torn off
and your right to use that goes up medical
the medical achievement modification date
it would be later it would not be of a moment
for more current however looking at the one
configuration file for that country and
from that to roth this here my partner
Miguel who has a special radar for
these things went to look at this and says
is that it is configured so that the
boot either from iso from iso
from the parrot cd that is downloaded
inside the filesystem of the xx y
Thus
normal that the
files disks is booted for is
configured to boot in mode
like and what happens in las vegas stays
In Las Vegas you pay for it and the records don't
are modified does not change anything and is
quite complicated to tinker that without
embargo
the logs of that virtual machine if I
save the vm logs save vale del
s xvii and wear of that machine for each
machine is generating a log and there
is logged when started and
when he stopped looking, it was seen that
coincides that the machine started ok in
dates in which there was brute force
to the web server with the ip of gallant that is
this machine had an ip were
shone against the lnd and the hcp
he gave an ip of the lnd and from there his
brute force afternoon minutes
then until the day after the
same lack why then why
probably the system administrator
he said so he changed his password
take eses
and well in this case it was very cool and
As a conclusion, I am only going to leave
this video
[Music]
there are men yes no
and well and he was not invincible in the end
man believed himself invincible because he had
made a difference because he was a great
hacker and really the truth is that
well the case was complicated
I admit, but in the end, well, in
pulling the thread and maybe we had a lot
good luck finding the net logo file
point the people who led us to the ones
It had to come to us and as I say in my
talk ends just tell you
to those of you who are in Spain
we have now occupy a hakim plan
ethical
face-to-face and online in real time only
Can it be done for people in Spain?
I'm sorry people and friends who are
in Latin America but for a matter of
streaming we can't do it any other way
way for there to be quality in what
in what we are offering are
formations that are given by daniel
echeverría drags that too
participate in this event and it is a plan of
ethical garden in which it is ethical
we try to teach how to do things
but also do not apply in cases
like the one I told you in the part
not bad but good because to help
identify faults that may have
your companies or others that
hire our hacking teams
and nothing more
up to here thanks a lot for everything
do you have my contact information if there is
questions that base the organization
quickly and if I don't answer them on twitter
to save thank you very much for your
participation is really very
interesting the chat the chat of this
game in fact they are saying that
we have another hour for
the outcome of the story is already
we saw it but who want more than
finishing version 10
next year
is that when it was a question no
there are many questions but there are some in
particular that they have many votes
So let's start with those and
Guillermo says in reference to the
first case it is not possible to have the
performance creation attributes
ntfs so that it is undetectable
that if it can be modified, man, have
can be modified is that here you have to
keep two things in mind the activity
natural is worth and the power to modify it
you can only modify the s and the
fn cannot be modified, it is worth the xxi
with a windows api call
accept you modify the one of that time of the
m time and modifies it without any problem
I mean, this can be done, okay, but I
what I do here is spend in the
natural behavior of something and if the
another expert is starting from one thing
well, that thing is starting from
you know that's the story
or through the operator tells us frame the
ordering in the stay in menu
windows server 2008 r2 how could
apply computer forensics after
that the service has been compromised
well you have to sit down and look at it
done if we are talking about
ns poisoning when you create one
entry of ns in a zone will generate a
series of files at the physical level once
more here who gives it to you in what it would be
the system artifacts
files the strong master and bag I
I insist I am always very heavy with this
the analysis of a file system is
there are many points of advantage to know
scan a file system well
ntfs the master fire table the love file and
the journal interpret well that is
wonderful, that is, it really contributes
a quantity of information for good or
for bad that allows you to understand what has
past is worth in many cases I go
we try very hard to try
explain this
we have many more questions but come on
with the last one that has more votes
comes from martir de argentina says which ones
These are the tools that you recommend the most.
for computer forensics and what it looks like
should never be overlooked
time to review an expert opinion
It is a very difficult question to answer
one in a minute but basically
tool that I consider important
for me I recommend you for the phase of
trias the acquisition of evidence
winter jacks is a tool that I have
made by me is free and I know that the
Do you know Jaime that we have talked about her?
on some occasion the same until used
and for analysis because there are many
In the end I used all the ones
almost one hundred percent are
free m that they give you to gut
a mcte ntfs what to be to gut
the logo and the journal interpret that and
reaper for example to identify for
get content run version of all
the different
record airs for 66 there are lots
from link to be one of fort discovery
to analyze files the nk ms svd
casts for the flames
and do a windows course
in the chat they are putting the networks
Lorenzo's social networks so that they can
ask the other questions and we
let's paste to paste in the internal chat
all the questions left
missing in case you can take the time
to respond in networks
would be generated by all and I answer them
one by one I don't have
a lorenzo pp or the public so that you
say goodbye and we can continue with the
programming, well, nothing, thanks a lot
all my thanks organization a hug
huge jaime as always a truth
sky álvaro outraged see you
thank you then we continue with our
programming
we enter the circuit and conference
Next we have Luis Miguel
angel in the one from colombia and in talking to us
a bit of how not to give papaya in
internet you have to do a little
explanation of what it is to give
papaya because it is a term like very
colloquial very Colombian but
It is practically like the prize that you
perform certain
malicious activities of cleanly
then left louis with the public
Luis will be right
hello jaime pérez how are you doing they look good on me
outstanding and the perfect sound if the
perfect sound
then with the public so that
share screen and why not
listening to it is worth thanking you very much
everyone says thank you
let's share the screen here
a second
Yo
he is not letting me share see something
not yet luis what do you want while you
you coordinate the theme of the machine there
we can go
giving some parish announcements
such as the theme of
certificates
on my screen
pablo confirm if suddenly luis has
screen sharing permissions
while I already have it here and the
skill ready for
not only close for the announced
all parishioners who eat in the clouds
remember is that the certificates both
of this as of the previous editions
dragon hart security conference se
they can do in dragon hard with point or
heretic get into the archive section and
there is a platform where
allows you to see all the videos of the
past editions and they have to
visualize all as if they were one
class and at the end of that class they are going to
be able to generate the certificate
attendance
totally free of the different
events since our last nine
editions
So Luis has already been able to share
screen let him through with the
public louis this is being seen in the
screen
Gilberto already see it ready they do not appear in
the corner to the right the images of
The perfects
ok good thank you very much first
place to thank work for the
invitation really that is an emotion
very great to be able to participate in this
event I give lectures talks but
As my children used to say, this is another level.
I mean, these are the big leagues
So I'm very happy to be able to
speak and carry like this message of
reflection and if before beginning what
jaime said
the term papaya is a very
colloquial very colombia means that's how it is
how to expose how to risk how to give
chance of something happening
context of something human after
obviously we adapted it to cyber papaya
it means like in that digital environment
if we are exposing others and
we are over exposing information yes
we are screwing up that it is another
term that can be used here
and well, it's basically the topic, yes.
realize and know techniques not so
advanced to put the part of the network
It's like that if there's something I've wanted to say
I will always say it like this
talk about many the discrimination what
we are going to learn here it is educational for
please don't please don't
repeat
I know that all of us who have life
digital in one way or another we have
done we are doing it or we are going to
to do so is that they are all
guests are in the company if they are in
their home if they are in college yes
are those who are following this
call all the people because the
idea is that this charles for everything everything
have a digital life every day
people who in one way or another
we have precision internet living
days since we were little we are already getting into
the kids on the internet the grandparents to
As a result of the pandemic, many people have already
learned to handle many more
tools and the idea is that the
digital security as it is a matter of
everyone then calls in the company to
the people of services to the secretariat
to the manager and as we saw yesterday in some
Talk then and they also call someone who
another page director that you put the
escape something
then, well, let's start my name
is luis miguel angel zepeda
am
passionate about research
safety culture culture and
digital coexistence I have a degree in
electronics the pedagogical university of
Bogota Colombia
I live in zipaquirá I am transmitting to you
from zipaquira colombia
for 25 years passionate about everyone
these topics I have been a teacher is invited
as a speaker in multiple forums
I participate in media etc. and I am an author
of three books on this subject
digital security trying to bring the
message to the person on the street
common person to people who
Well, we talked to that one so that that one
famous phrase that technology me
run over and you can know we're in
full quarter of the 21st century and not
we can afford the luxury of being
thinking even of voting that ball there
are those responsible for our
security and our privacy then
how do they get that message across
to all
What do I propose for today's work?
there are three key moments the first is
of reflection let's see if it really
What I am saying is true if it is not
cart but two and it will be yes and when
something like that will be that yes yes it is all that
we are falling in that age matters
no matter the knowledge no matter if
I'm an expert, it doesn't matter, it concerns us
if we are going to reflect with some
images later we will
recognize is that knowledge that all
one way or another we have to see
how to talk start this is already part
digital culture
and in the end we are going to talk about action
What are we going to do or what have we already talked about?
a lot thing then what is it
I propose that any being
human who is against in life
digital can have a
healthy and safe coexistence in the network
So let's start with reflection
technology runs over me I said it and I
all my colleagues will excuse me here
experts who have passed in this first
day because it starts not at all
people who are connected who know
that this definition is very clear but
for many people on a day-to-day basis
common this is what happens
we carry the message in safety
digital at such high levels that
are servile to those of us who follow
many speakers that we see there are some
textbooks is tera but for the
ordinary person faces this
something is that this is the complex was not
TRUE
So I propose to change that face
that he is on this other side a bit
more friendly
and understand this message safety
digital that I think can reach us
everyone to digital security is action
that we are going to do this to prevent
serve those words that are in
capital letters do not forget what actions we are going
to do to prevent is the risk that
exists against the various threats in
the network because there are threats that maybe
we can't share but we can
minimize the risk and it is something that I
I try about it
So that's what we're talking about
of the human being the human being is key
then being the one who ultimately has
to take that action so let's talk about
technology so I work in 'the and so
I have my WhatsApp as configured
to make it more secure as you set
this team so that things don't happen
So as human beings we have a
important paper with strata little words
judgments and decisions
and that's basically I'll think about it
day by day each one of us
regardless of what we do in the
digital life and the logic of changing
all are based on judgments and decisions and
This has a lot to do with engineering.
social how are we going to see what what
judgments and what decisions we are making
It will be that if we are screwing up
You will see that if we are giving ourselves papaya
Well, let's start by looking at these images.
please the people who are there in the chat
I'm not in let others than me
I know that there are already several that I will be there
let's hope it's more entertaining
the exercise but let's look at these
publications in a normal day-to-day
anyone has a portal hand
that we want it in the networks we see here
a photo of the boy if arthritis is
important to highlight national talent
So that there are no leaks, true in Mexico
and it appears that she is an expert in physics
quantum this boy turns out to be in
another post
there is also the boy for a battery
more because he died he is looking for the
fight him as in rest the pass
of Spain and the famous phrases of
social engineering with those who seek
hook people as it is not
footballer or singer then everything
We go out and if we have to support why not
go player because you do not give to christ that
in the shield of the because of the
footballer between let's share share
contributing the likes etc we see it there
how many times has it been shared on and from
teacher and oh surprise we see the same
boy who is now
harvard is in ecuador because the degree
hardware is mathematical indeed since
is always multifaceted and the most
recent here in colombia we have the
gem is that it turns out that nothing more or
nothing less than I hope is familiar to you
some former president and with the problem of
the register there is the detail as
I would say cantinflas and then the fraud and
let's attack and like so not in
let's share decent etc
Well, we'll see the mystery and now
everyone will know there because that famous physicist
relative of a former president person who
He has passed away because he is an actor
spanish porn movies
and we already share
we made a judgment based on that noise
that is managed and that intervenes a lot in
my social life and that can be used
to socially destabilize
congest networks unnecessarily
even to outline because well with
all those comments that go
becoming someone the networks because why not
go doing some things we no longer have
of course those two girls are not from the
registrar nor are they the companions of
harvard let's move on to the next see in
this moment another photo of another character
Do not say anything
We see that a student is called alias and that
they can love and numbers than the one who put
here the bomb a few years ago in the
police school
terrible terrorist let's share why
we can't leave that and punish
here I also did and it turns out that the same
It's international lit the cathedral of
notre dame
no no it can't be let's share it in
comments etcetera and in the latter the
I kidnap these girls that if someone already
saw matica will understand that these are the
matilda's girls but we don't see why
because even though the world moves
with the attention economy
pay attention true the idea is
take the person to move that
human being move it an amount
feelings emotions to make a
judgment and make a decision
share etc. for example this from
girls lost boys are shared se
share many messages of this child
they are lost please and they are children who
have been lost for ten years and still
They are still lost and they keep looking, it is more
and there are many who have already found them but
so how do you manage these on the one hand
the famous grenades of likes by another
side can be profiled or on the other side
then you can get a message to
these children who have been lost
telling them that it does not appear is a
very poor family the police do not do al
government does not help but we create
an account to support this family there is
it's there you can make your payments it's like
we realize this has some
connotations a little more more more
Beyond what it seems, well, I think
that they will have already seen a lot who will know
who who we are we talk we are u2
of the euro play that in case those
messages make fun of everything on his channel
What have I done here that there is another amount
of things not and coronavirus with senators
and senators who have said the number of
things and he makes fun of this but let's think
also in something like the famous
digital reputation term he is a
famous person has created an identity
digital with which you can share and
take advantage of that but what if those
same messages that were a while ago
moment out for any of us
for the internal we are barely average
known how it affects our lives
if we have not created a good identity and
That's where I'm going with the topic of the
coexistence what do I do in the networks yes
you have to start paying attention to
all the little things we're seeing
to reflect but it is not only that
Let's look at this other message, not free
I won the lottery and well many
know this famous message that came to
cell phones and there are people who have told me
Said is that I use the cell phone flechita
because these smartphones these teams
these are the internet that many arrive
things I feel I use a little arrow better and
it turns out that the little arrows that arrive
texting and how i think he is
being clear in the talk is not itself
technology is relative easier is
relatively easy you want it to be
human convincing that person in
special to a group of people
specials of a certain cetera in a
exposure is sent a text message
where do they say you won this prize car
silver calls already calling one of those
numbers as most know sounds
fanfare little special music
We congratulate and adherence and applause
they create the whole atmosphere
of confidence or those words and then nothing
He says ready, have the pesos but
we need to verify as a reload to
this number and as we have already discussed
even in chats and people have
Where are those refills going?
prisons and that serves so that
then a lot of whiskey is being made
that I had discussed it yesterday with him
that the little call the uncle spoke to me
who is sick and who is not
ran over who meditated money well everything
this comes out in prisons but we are
Sponsoring those cell phone refills
Obviously, it is talk that has been
lost and people say oops it's not me
they hacked the password and one that
makes me think about my hacked
password specialized software that
here all the but if the people who
they have spoken to many know many
of these other tools and how to do
edited this kind of stuff but the
ordinary people stay in space
It doesn't happen to me that's very movie
fresh hollywood no problem
let's look at this image this is from hawaii la
agency is in green emergencies
famous photo with the post-it with the super
password because what is it for
very robust password but it stayed at
discovered come and that does not happen only there and
that's supposedly this time it was a
news that is to this agency launched a
message to all hawaii to get active and
a missile on the way and a collective panic
and then this person had to go out
yes it was not yes octopus press the button no
it was but the matter goes further
password
[Music]
and if you are turned by a company
you will find many teams like this
so why put password in
last and they will have it there to the mark
more complex assets of that password
can be used for many and many
services of many applications because
we are lazy to do more cons is
certain
I found this other one out there I hope
that is false true
He talks about I have a card and what
chicanear in networks because it is the
modality in díaz will bet who we are
and then there appears the back number
because everyone asks me
back number
true and then we have the audacity
because it is like that to say they hacked me
true they hacked me when we don't give each other
note that we are hacking ourselves
we give a lot of continued in papaya
the same as what I was talking about a moment ago
from euroempleo he is a well-known character
but what happens when there is a message that
Mass becomes mass and we turn it
we believe because it is san whatsapp san
facebook and what is said is true and
it can happen these cases as
as so serious but it is understandable we are
human beings have our
vulnerabilities our shortcomings
evolutionarily we are like that
but they have also sold us some
ideas that is what I expose too
in my talk with those who sometimes don't
we can stray us down the road we
lead to the dark side where not
we should be the first of those are
four that I like to talk about
first time we thought that technology
it is and it will be and it will solve everything and we
we disconnect as human beings
true what he said now then
we believe in something because it simply is
on the internet and we think what is there
it's true true
we trust one hundred percent in a tweet
of safety and we wash our hands and
we forget about the rest if we don't
We realize that we have to balance the
technology helps us is true a long time ago
time a lecturer an I don't know what
country was said that famous phrase of the
power of technology not technology
if you don't have powers in some other
but when we are like zombies there is
connected by clicking 11 at night
midnight sharing doing we put
the back uses them we go down because
Well, the brain is going to the factory, no.
works like this then it's time to take
control and be the ones
we decide how our life
technology is going to help us and what
controls
the second a security incident
it only affects me nothing happens to me
They hacked and emailed but I'm a book
open no problem investigate
what they want then that's just for
me but we do not realize that it runs the
looted for impersonation
indian sometimes people don't fall for
account is to use the name to imagine
send emails to boss to friends
seeing money etc
the day besides that sometimes they are the
emails that are linked to the accounts
principals of various services as a
incident does not only affect me we have
to understand that with me there is a family
and since 2020 we realized the
pandemic and isolation that in the
home, many things were no longer focused
can one run to pei to ask for help
to a student to the professor systems no
everything was fine the place and everyone
we had to be of you to share that
make video calls than birthday
than games in entertainment everything
focused on the home therefore neither
following can begin to affect that
first environment children grandparents family
wife headquarters but precisely what
spoke as a result of that isolation as
now hybrid work or is it still
work home etc. well the companies
also commits is a fact and more
if I am lending my my equipment if he
equipment that I use I lend it to my son
He gave him to enter pelis plus
torrents install some tournament if it is the
fresh company team that is the most
fast all we're risking
without realizing if then I am not
only i am affecting my first
home environment business environment my
next level security can be given and
on a social level if it is something serious that
affect the reputation of the company
affect the reputation of the household
personally to friends then a
security incident not only affects you
you carry many people
third in the network everything is virtual to see
is beyond in a pun
something that I have proposed in my talk yes
the virtual little word was put in guaymas
now yes but to see virtual the brain
this processes it in a way outside the
Words have that power and virtual the
brain does not understand as not real if it is
plus the royal academy in its third
meaning says virtual not real
fourth that is below refers to all
digital media and see it but
So when you've seen it before
without a brain I made this more real and that's why
things happen on the internet is that it is
seen write as you can do and
undo and nothing happens development and
killed nobody nothing nobody will catch me in
Navarre, but as we saw in the
previous talk is not like that
2 my proposal is to change that for the
virtual life for digital true or not
face-to-face and let's talk about a real world
which is both digital and
digital if to me in the day to day I go for
They rob me on the street and they don't go, I don't
I want 300 thousand pesos
And if I go to Facebook and it turns out that a guy
He arrived from Europe and he is asking me for 300
thousand pesos to remove merchandise from
customs because they are 300 thousand real pesos
two virtual ones are that you spend implan
then the real world the real thing
composed of its two environments and between
discussions with experts who talks looks
disconnect from the internet to be able
live in real life
the internet was not daily and real
ready then this is a proposal
that we begin to understand that beyond
engage in philosophical debates about the
virtuality is understanding what is real and what
what happens on the internet they do to all of us
in a real way
and finally in this part we are not
important for cybercriminals
Well, managers don't miss that
that happens to me health has a sign already
we have seen in previous talks there are
organized groups in the first place there
groups organized worldwide
they look every day to see that those fit
famous mail theft messages from
desire that they turn on servera but many
people sometimes stay on that plan
He quoted that not only that is where it happens
in other countries russia finland china
Brazil, that is, here that does not reach us
dissect like in bollywood movie
and they forget that to read is not to be
organized crime as it is a
cybercriminal closer than it seems
I don't know if you saw that that movie about this
actor is called from my heaven it turns out
who was the friendly neighbor who wasn't
so friendly
does not mean please avoid
go out to fight with the lost but
sometimes we are too confident
we lend our equipment at the right hand and
sinister
we use the neighbor's equipment the neighbor
to do Chinese homework
girl and we don't realize it so much
exhibition that we are having there what
such that there is a capture program of the
neighbor's keyboard how can it happen in
a good internet cafe or cafe whatever you call it
why because if we have a lot
confidence we think that it cannot be that
someone knows about these things when today
nowadays on youtube they exist as a support
how to install a keylogger to capture
the keyboard how to fake the webcam
how to capture the camera a number of
things that cybercriminals like
they said yesterday they have the motivation
because it is the motivation to deceive us
our children to ourselves
I envy the amount of very human things
So my question is what is the
motivation of you people
as normal as it is in his day to
day thinking that the responsibility of
digital security belongs to third parties and does not
we take charge also help
a little bit in that in that treatment of
our of our digital life then
with these four points it is but she
it is a little lighter harder
previous we believed as that little
reflection of what is how we are
embarking on the network and that many times
It's not our fault that what we have
to start making those bases
Let us now move on to that recognition that
there is already a reflection and we could give ourselves
that reflecting with more examples but
We now integrate some basic things
that go beyond thinking that it is a
engineering master's course
people who are experts from
here are things that handle them very well
for the uninitiated there will be things
to begin to understand and you have to
start with engineering story
social who have talked about it a lot yesterday
there were quite a few interesting talks from
elisabeth because martín exhibits it in
excellent grass and it is that in engineering
social that is is the famous art of
deceit and directly attacks the being
human
like how people can be
easily meat towards someone will say or me
What he has said is that since they exist
those social networks today is from the
cause as if before the internet no
nothing will happen and no one is fooling us true
well let me tell you that the deception
has existed for a long time
a lot and here are some examples
we have in this first image that
you see this lady here
she said in 1700 something she gave birth
rabbits with them as well as it sounds gave to
light with them
after convention convinced people
that it was true because because the lady
contacted an eminent doctor and had him
believe or preceded his wiles true
to make him believe that indeed
the doctor was giving birth with them
believed him men we are talking about
until now there were little things that could be
and more in those places so remote and
separated because the doctor believed him and was
the voice for the people and the peoples
surrounding this doctor we could
compare it today with social networks
they did not believe this doctor as well as
we believe everything he says
felipe everything that appears happens to everything
what they share with us without thinking about it
times
nowadays this channel but let's see obviously
We are not going to believe that you do me to the
rabbits but nowadays they are another type of
things like me yes how are we going to continue
seeing the image in the center are one of
the first social experiments
back in 1950 a radio station that
said there was a town in england
that was had a tree that gave
spaghetti because people believed him
began to arrive in a massive way to that
little town and it means money talk
economy
We can also daily and well
then they came out it is and it is not that
we wanted to see how easy it was to cheat
people and this at the beginning of the
20th century the last image you see there
with a statue had to do with the theme
of religion, which is one of the themes
also quite quite that quite
moved remember that we can we can
use topics like religion like sports
as a policy to generate an amount
persuasion profiling things
manipulation etc, well, there are these people
they said if we found a statue
of a giant as some say
religious stories but it was a hoax
of a person who wanted revenge
then we are human beings we are
muddy we are believing but
So what we are is how deceit is
today, for example, not to mention here
we have this image this girl
I want us to think, I don't know if it has been
reached the text ok but they ask me
I want us to review here first the
forms the typical photos that call the
attention to the channel my god
she is sick
look at the phrase please pray for me for
Please, let's start with some phrases
widely used social engineering yoga in the
cancer is to say a cool battle
You have five seconds to see beyond the
text this is like this from the and you find out
of becomes that the person on the part
there if I have the seconds and if I know
They realize in the messages that from here
475 responses to date worldwide
supporting this girl that pour such
center has shared more than 29 thousand fish
three hundred and fifty-odd thousand already
comment for a number of things
terrible spelling but that's it
another topic where we do share
share more we share two or three yes
it was analyzed s of that girl we see
really who no longer looks so
sick miraculously healed and thank you
to god but facebook later it happened
account that it was a false profile are those
famous profiles that are created to make
the famous farms of likes where well
the line of conversation and each that
we share that because you will say why
web I can not share that solidarity
if solidarity is very important but
nowadays it has to be more proactive and
Let's stop momentarily and review for what
minus the comments that someone will say
that's false let's not go crazy
sharing giving to her because
we are on the one hand filling the
pockets of cybercriminals but for
other side we are also giving a lot
screen leaving data that can be
very useful for profiling if I know the
comments there are several people who
support these causes because more in a
Easier center to send emails
send messages in front of them
and I said it, all this serves to outline
how is it shaping up at the moment and what
the experts know the experts
that while we are talking here I don't know
they are profiling all those of one u
another way we have a digital life is
they go and look in our
needs is that I am next to
I work more my girlfriend left me I'm alone
blah blah blah what emotions in young people
for the program of the day loneliness
minors is a subject that engages
a lot and the two cybercriminals do not know
the ignorance that's why my invitation
to which any person
it is your responsibility to learn the basics
as a student why are you doing here
they will have is precisely that to carry that
knowledge to those who use to those who
sanz keep learning day by day because
digital security is everyone's business
and well a number of things that with
those who seek in each one
people how to get where everything is
This is obviously on the networks
social a while ago a while ago
about 30 years ago for her what was he like
subject the subject of age I want to find out the
life of this gentleman who is the director of
you are either the managing director or you are
than daughters or sons, well, one
truck take pictures with binoculars
what time does it leave at what time does it arrive where
He went to have coffee, right, you have to
school that friends have today
well, that's on the net, it's much more
simple much easier and it is that
we share everything we are
sharing
our intimate moments of life that
is the term of over xavi is the envelope
to have information and look that this
it goes a little beyond the technical
intimate moments of life is the
intimate term I didn't like those very much
terms because then we lose the year
when we are not clear there is a video
that I have in my intimate channel
means you should not have any
Registration
that's simple
if you already have a photo if you already have your
videos and you wrote a text is already one
It is not intimate, it is not private or what
private public aeronautical then it is
the invitation for you that is intimate
because it remembers if there is a record of
something that is intimate for you is already private
and you can lose seen the plans
vacation we go to cartagena and
all the photos of the tickets in the
cloud plane can be done with
this you can do many things for
example the thieves decided the
home is alone welcome but also
you can impersonation as we saw yesterday in
a serial talk that the person who
was is the accounting is traveling
[Music]
no one can make us a few calls
life is that today had been
fully this occasion and to you
they know how the whole story is to achieve
persuade and manipulate states
states of guasave that we place in
Social networks are a source of
very big information and excuse me in
the özil experts and all this but
look at the successes that it is in some
moments this
you can find an amount is
because we are placing everything I am
sad my girlfriend told me I'm without
work and that can be very useful for
that profiling answers to the
questions are created tests in some
good services this is a little example
common but for us to understand
I want to hack so-and-so's social network
this service and I forgot the
password then to the question
secret the service sector and the typical
question is difficult pet name
baa1 to instagram and if it is filu like
moving if lula inserting cell phone and
sleeping finlay stomach because
we are over exposing the information
insult defame here send
exactly has to do with everything
theme of coexistence
I want to talk about this in terms of not
I am referring to all freedom of
expression because it is a right that
we have but sometimes we get out of hand and
according to a freedom of aggression
and we are many many the example for
other generations not the same as we create
destability also serves to outline
if I see that you are a person who is is
quite alive when spoken in
good politics out there it can be the
business
compromising photographs not only
I'm talking about the photo in a bikini or what?
encourages when walking things but
also the photo of the entrance what
leaves enters the house the license plate of the car
or the famous photo of the post I'm not with
my cup in front of my computer and my
job with the pósito
password we return to the same
financial information we have because
is posting that kind of stuff
intimacy of the children of happened
march in you we are happy as parents
posting the photo in chipping of two
years dating in the shower
and nothing happens when we understand that there is
markets
but jumps at the level of the flesh where
can this type of images but also
That child is going to grow up to see those I was going to
growing up is going to be 13 14 years old stress
internet do not forget despite the right
of good but he sneaks in because of Arian he removed and
what will happen when the friends of
little boy find it to be well hair
ticos well cyberbullying sponsor by
their parents then let's keep in mind
these examples because there are many more with
manipulation can be having these
data the process begins to persuade
and manipulate persuaded in the part
pretty or in today's part
mail that says look we detect that there is
something but we are going to help you person is
the famous message on the call of d
I am loved is being monitored by
your safety thanks to those personal
to later manage to manipulate, that is,
to think to make the person drink
that decision that is not the best
but then
what are the techniques there are many
techniques this theme the dense because here
we could stay talking about biases
cognitive of all biases
thought logistics is brothers
confirmation area bias
amount of things that is how we work
human beings that is, there is no other
if we work and take advantage of that and
evolutionarily biases exist for
in theory it is the easiest way for us but
we have seen it in advertising we have
seen in the 'news we've seen it in
social engineering that the matter can be
get out of hand we talk about you
we are not talking about ruiz is another term
also that it is used a lot at the time of
make decisions then how to do that
people go the other way
they said in the least appropriate way and
we find many do not reciprocate
towards my mind I am someone but
we if that's how we work divert the
systems thinking through
systems thinking is that we
bring to a moment I like this
exercise face-to-face talks
we are talking and moment to another says
for god's sake it's shaking and I'm going out
running and behind me to a quantity
people
the same you will say no but mark that the
Mirandés was yes but it would be like
logical to stop all this for a moment
you are what you seek that over time
that trust can be generated
we create everything that appears there everything
tell us everything else that has happened
during that time and let's trust that
that is to say, all this leads to that
we are vulnerable as human beings
it is a fact we are vulnerable and we must
understand that when digital matter
we refer to devices that also
they are vulnerable true it fails him that
they can enter the malware etc. but
as human beings we are in charge
that all these devices are
less vulnerable already according to a suite of
security either with learning that
we are seeing and other things but it is
that that that set not human beings
devices and the device is
vulnerable as a human being i am
vulnerable
I am vulnerable and I can do my
device is too then
we have to be aware of
balance balance those two things
of size
malware
in devices then appears the
malware for years we talk about viruses every
are more and more publishing virus viruses and ago
years it was the fault of the computer virus
it was slow it's a virus has run
It's a virus, come in, it's going to hide those
videos because nowadays malware encompasses
many more things we are not talking about trojans
speaking of using us we speak for example
the famous ramson web that is to say the
hijacking of information to know now
maybe he made me a little screen that we
let it pass or they actually deciphered
the data and you cannot recover it and
even worse after finishing selling
who knows where then from here to think
in that and many of these
each day they are more sophisticated and more
complex
we have the drawings that capture the
center image keyboard and it is not
complex even i had a demo
face-to-face is to download a drawing that
interest we find it and promptly
Second team is what I need to do
a university job or you are taking
if it is my girlfriend my mind I have confidence
use the practical was already here place the
antivirus warning like crazy which ones
sirens of the quiet submarine
antivirus is a false positive and there it is
distar and then after if I have
talk he bought filiberto this is what
What is the digital or will not arrive the
plain text that is to say as it is to my house
to my mail we have places we have
trojans animating flesh trojans
andina activate the webcam at the level of
activate the microphone that many listen to
cell phones
so that's how to comply
we also have the fish and difficult
They have already made it difficult today, these are correct
that they do not want so we can fall
here this is real is that it is an account
mine that rather I have it there for
let them attack what they want where
I have won prizes that you see there
where the registry office
quoted 20 thousand times never where I have a
embargo in a court where they had
purpose we are in on the trick
statements here be careful the
banks describe then you give because
if it is true that the bank still
wait hold
because well I'm not going to fall into this without
However, obviously some look
because art is true and here we go
wasting the year however it is not
bite the heat as the motto says by
Where does all this come from?
emails that we already placed to see and it is the
mail is still the largest source
Where does all this kind of deception come from?
where we can download malware where
can legally df asking for the data
not necessarily bad but about
exposing data
where we find malicious pages
We see pages that just enter and
be able to happen something with the announcements the
next ad here system
applications not updated we have a
side of 20 years ago and we are not
updating it looks like three
Business
update one of 200 when we pay
windows
perez you have to do
browser extensions to
watch the video then let's install this
plugin and finally remote access and that
widely used remote access software
very legal but sometimes we can
cheat with other kinds of things or are we
giving excess and more nowadays because
as a dose with the work of the video etc
whatsapp messaging apps
telegram we have to know that it can be done
also send in any of the
messages that can be seen some cannot
I'm talking about the technical part of
security I'm talking about what look
Here I send you this link, click on it
there is famous usb and we found the
usb and we put laundry or some
employee who is going to unload things
we have seen there are also with the and sainz
jr always now the electric ones
more deceptions we find this true goes
beyond the technical 10 to which I
I go with the talk
Let's realize that this is everyday
Anyone
NASA sets the date May 6, the date ends
world the world ends three times
brother hour half weirder no
they capitalized and suddenly I right now
passing September the end of the
world if not the collison collider
that it will be a black hole will
be an asteroid normally and we believe
that always to profile for
destabilize to finish last
selling food from the future of the end or
the sad news like this we see
a lot especially when downloaded
certain kind of sad movies and games
news like so you have to install
a plugin to be able to see the ham or the
famous person who died, he did not die and
martin or please
everyone calm down because what we do
That is what sometimes calls that tension there
and like that and we are lazy what is it
we have to do there so let's do
let's compare let's go and check in a
information medium or whether digital will be
that is true but please never
we created the first instance in this by
more striking than appear
because it is usually false but let's see
what I was saying right now we are in
time tax returns here at
Colombia the day and good in other countries
leave from tax addresses
but this is very level change
several countries where you already look at it you have not
paid taxes next or last
it is that it is this circular what it is
that of occasional profit and comma quote
download here on the trojan or the famous
photo fine tour a photo fine and one
anguished like so many photos I go
to download the file after me
I agree that I don't have a car but anyway
download it because it was that they took my
photo and next to another car we put together
all the stories because we are beings
humans and we are engaging a
device that as we see that it is
compromising not us and how
we saw is contributing to all
so what to do then you have to call
I know that laziness remains
five minutes a month also took
those five laziness but then you have to
make the call put there are no music
but cybercriminals know we are
lazy and that it is much easier to do
useful to put on a check you have to
do never click on these things
More Adidas Influencers Hoaxes About
everything for young people free tennis
we keep dropping the messaging with
whatsapp for example the action
whatsapp is as simple as
lend me your phone you don't have it
william you don't have a password this is
very technical and well, the clone there
we have on the computer on another cell phone
a browser can explore both
no problem the famous message in
life is to change cell phones and without
blame digital with the photo and ops without
fault digit 1 but you can't pass this
because I'm activating a new
single ticket costs one hundred
and the messenger who are people who
they come from other countries and they mature
I meditate on this type of thing and we are done
ending apps that also do
an amount I want to see with a life
times assumed as a mean of 100 years
we are giving a quantity of information or
a little flashlight that what i should do
is to turn on the lights and have more but yes
We analyze the permissions ago
calls send to that trick month so that
With the coronavirus and more stonecutters there are
What to do first to be taken care of
legal although we know that place tour
lets go of many things but for what
least not an act in any of these
other things if that happens with adults
image of monkeys to our children
age to everything you face when
I'm talking about judgments and decisions and
we don't have them clear as an adult
Imagine an 89-year-old boy with a
life and also active having to take
decisions on a daily basis
Biologically he still can't take it anymore
that we
It is a genre from the technical point of view, yes, but
as a decision maker
has to discern between what is real
and what is fiction between the good and the
bad etc is complete and this goes to
you talk someday and the news
trends there are already some talks
so they can see the stress better
He has already talked about this whole subject of allot and
the internet of things the clock that its
customers smart TVs the
blog theme change nfts with all the
new scams brewing
falsification of pages like pencil etc
artificial intelligence a famous face
if we believe a photo because it is
he got into the photo let's imagine
with a video shot grace to do
then to finish you have to
thinking about prevention is this because it is and
prevent but what is prevention
prevention is paying attention to training here
during this door talks we have given
many credits during the other
talks of walkers one more technical
but we have talked about many things and
daily we see many of those who
They say that there because if not what will
pass we will have to talk about
certain protection that they exist and must be
talk about restitution of rights has
to see if there are backups that
when we could have stayed here
that prevention are three little things that he left
no responsibility is greater than
another my message
I always say these three things
responsibility we have to be
responsible for our old lady not to throw away
the ball is that it is the dt and it is not that
we don't have to be responsible
knowledge that what we are talking about
if the fungus learned and the famous
common sense excuse me jaime
excuse me yesterday also to alejandro that
they talked about the adult they talked about
dragonball but here he used it a long time ago
knight of the zodiac because he spoke
the seventh sense must be awakened
common sense that we all have asleep
but how do we realize that it is
failing the sense as it does not serve by itself
only common sense is dynamic does
a few years we thought that feeling like
tells us that the keys must have eight
digit winds today we have to
think keys must be a lot
older than we should have a second
true third factor authentication
but if we are sharing the key
under a bridge this is non-digital
when is the bridge please stop
and think for a moment about life we ​​already see
this to digital life and we have the
daring to fight the one in the taxi that almost
we are run over by exchange en off when for
favor is our responsibility or the
usb no photo shoot what if
we found him knows the cb on the floor
Well, I could go on about more things.
I simply leave these readings more
recommended require learning because
Well, the celebrities we live in thought
that television is a way to
start of the hacker world there are many of
the interesting seriously what it calls
hatton with social engineering we can
having a library for any
staff who can learn some
little things some not very technical and yes
He wants to get into a topic a little more
strong understand the nature of being
Human, well, Daniel Kahneman is from
think fast think of space we
talk about the two brains it takes
decisions and think about it
intuitively or the reflection of
that is very good and sant control new
what is called noise how does it affect in
our decisions in the newspaper by
Also if you want to see the art of
leg but what is there one that I
I recommend that you love the art of deception
what is explaining the art of war
applied in decision making
I leave this last image for you
let's reflect I think it says synthesize
all the talk there is nothing to do with
responsibility
knowledge and common sense I hope
you liked the talk thank you very much
by your attention
thanks to all the people thanks to
So thanks to the community for all the
support and good
to you louis thank you very much we have
obviously some questions we are going to
go for those who have more
likes in the question system that
we have designed and the first question
is anonymous and says that techniques and
tactics and procedures used
for the expression of false news
well I guess there are many people
what are you hearing notice me techniques
so what is there to do
first it depends where they come from
news and be a facebook-like network
let's check the messages there are people who
they don't talk anymore it's that it's clear it's
spacious came out a while ago it's just that
we are lazy to carry out the messages
second usually a fake news
is in a medium a social network
then let's verify that news with
other media such as a newspaper or
velinas digital newspaper in the
hiring what makes us
need to contrast verify and it is not
complex is simply entering others
media and check if that is real because
I access the news up to date and there are some
that impact and the false news depends
of the moment, that is, right now, Qatar is coming and
there will be a lot of news right now we are
in time see here in colombia
tax return and there is a lot
News
recently one also came out of edict of
an attack deletes you have to verify that
kinds of things through other means
let's not stay with the pretty photo with
the alert sign as the words of
urgent loosening time etc.
because that's what you're looking for
that there is another that is said that if he had
the possibility of sending you a fragment of
video for people over 60
so they don't screw up on the internet
that I would send this to him, they are going to cut it and
then send by whatsapp everywhere
then think about the message and with this
answer we say goodbye well then the
I really think that people more
since 2020 we have noticed this
trend as older people
they are commenting more and more because
Well now the birthdays with the
grandparents is between blue and let's
get together and we're just like
There were almost seven cameras in Bogotá
another in other countries and all celebrating
the birthday of the grandparents of what you
cousin here they know how to do it
I think that more than grandparents is
having young children is ours
responsibility to help them yes
because because they are yes or we are not
as a son I have to be aware of
my parents I am something of this and I am not
easy knowing that my mom until
share the all interest in whatsapp
how is waiting then i have to
be every day saying eye yes
you get this if so if you
grandparents ask their children to help their
grandchildren is more integrated is of all that
we talk about this is so not because it is the
it is up to them that they depend
we can guide them and they can
enjoy your digital life than erc
locals and they have to do it to me and today
day is demanding it towards the world
luís then in public so that you
you neglect not without first thanking him for
your participation
thank you very much for the content
They just gave away and then to the public
it's all yours it's worth a lot thank you
all the people who accompanied us
did not accompany thanks for listening and
Well, take this message from
reflection to each of your homes in
their companies so we can live
a safe and healthy life thank you
well let's continue with our
schedule next guest is coming
his name is omar from mexico and he is going to us
talk about safety issues
he controls directly in football
taking advantage of their rewards program
public then in this way we give
continuation I imagine that omar is already
there present what else take how are you
hello hello can you hear me
we hear perfect
hello a pleasure first of all so many years
in dragon and see how
let's say as a spectator and now finally
as a speaker an honor to be here is a
honor for us to listen to you omar y
we know that your presentation is very
expected and different groups
specialized in walking then no
In order not to delay, I'll leave you the subject
with the public share screen and
thank you very much for your participation
you thank you for what they tell me yes
the screen is seen
and we are already seeing on your screen
well first of all
the talk is called recognition
fast and a local feeling
even in the google bp program that
It's basically the program
google rewards a brief
biography my name is omar espino
known in networks as el espino I'm from
mexico for the
morning
Work as
infrastructure security manager no
I know if we are going tracks a US company
that you have to have to in mexico
I'm going grones
and that I really like everything it has
what to do with unix and linux in the
terminals or all type systems
I like linux a lot before it was
and back in developer and it was also
motionless to see it but right now it is
security issue that does not end by
the day at night is a researcher of
independent diplomatic security and
I am also a book counter for
people who are watching us who are not
you know it's a book counter
basically a person who is dedicated to
look for faults in companies that offer
mainly rewards programs
coin the money in the reward but
there is also another type of reward
I have my personal blog or the hawthorn
dotcom my twitter is today month came and
some brief milestones
and published in the blog of chema alonso
informal already has enough time
I did a minute on how to run seal the
hay sx in the bow bears just called
saw and gave him what he posted on his blog and
I have been recognized thinking the way
some companies like facebook google
apple microsoft
twitter among others
good very good finally I'm recently
this year he published a book basically is
a compilation of failures that I have
found at
throughout my time that I have carried
my book counter career and what
important or special about this book
is that it is in Spanish regularly almost
all the information is in english
So that's why I was encouraged because several
thinking and they ask if he had something
in Spanish because they knew it was in
Mexico then there is the book
available on amazon is called bug bounty
in Spanish it is in digital and it is in the
but in my blog there are also the
links to
to buy the book
very well although the agenda of this
talk is first an introduction of
what is the bug bounty motivations yes
that and then I'm going to share my
methodology
In a simplified way, what happened?
to find this kind of bugs
which
includes as the
Let's say the visualization of the
overall organization
names of their domains
visual identification a little strong
gross and web scraping and then already
specifically the steps
followed
to find a bug that I put
relevant to google
things that come after
you find a bug
and then also the lessons learned
of all this let's say experiment process
that at the end questions and answers
aesthetic
before starting this information is
for educational purposes only
professionals and in this case my dragon
jarni and I take responsibility for
of the use of this information
very good first the introduction
because he is looking for what is behind
of the idea of ​​being a singer in the
Personally, the challenge motivates me a lot.
that many who are here with us
the challenge is one of the main things
it is very fun to understand how
computers communicate and depending
the processes or intentions that
have can good to have your results
sometimes unexpected so I think it's
something that we share many who are
exist in this conference that
probably is
share that that with me and in addition to
all that because there are profits
money involved but it
main thing for me is the challenge and that
it all seems very funny very funny
this about how to manipulate computers
to get where expected
ok hey
Broadly speaking, the methodology
used or what you are using is
first as the discovery of
organization in global or simply
fetch
the scope of the program or the rules of the
program but the mind is called
bug bounty program rules
[Applause]
after that we will choose a domain
in which we are going to do our
tests and also a main network in
this case is a sn
I will elaborate a little more in detail
next the following slides true
but basically that's it first we have
a domain to which we are going to try to
look for subdomain or let's try
see that your domains has the domain
principal
that if he is alive he is domain to say
I have a list of x number domains
and check if the domain is
answering and it's worth it and continue
inquiring
then you have to make a notice
visual identification which is basically
take screenshots decade
of each subdomain that we find that
is alive and from there
already with one
look more reduced we could already do
brute force or power attacks is
phil is on the domains side of the
net side
what we can do is identify what
network blocks has the organization a
port scanning
same as domains see if alive
which live which ports are live or what
ports are responding and already starting
from there
identify the services that are
they are running on this sports link and
once we found
all these patterns can be re-
repeat the process let's not say that
we found an interesting subdomain
we could replicate and revisit this
methodology again and throw it away
for this particular case of the failure
that I am going to talk to you specifically about if
I say part 1 of the methodology
I probably see it like this in two parts
not the domains part and the
network
in this case only
uses the part of the domains
per se
but well let's focus now yes
in what would become a branch
google rewards
to take him as an example and show them the
glitch that was quite interesting
the google reward program google
it's called google
brp pues vulnerability we work program
basically they pay you from 100 to
31 thousand 367 dollars depending on the
impact of vulnerability that
you have found and it is accessed with this
url is not cut sends you directly to
or program rules
basically the program
[Music]
consists of three domains
main that is the one of google.com
youtube.com and blogger.com even though
there are only three of google is a company
very old and therefore has has
many a domain in fact never
I never eat
How do you say no, I haven't done all the
job of doing all the discovery
of all goods because it is a sea of
information
and for the network blocks, that is, of the sl
they are around 9 million ip
basically the s in that are the blocks
network that the google company registers
on the internet as belonging to their
services and their and their networks and then
yes yes it is enough information it is not
exaggerated let's say and overwhelming all the
how it was made
the amount of
to do or objects that google has
to test not then the question the
first question is where to start
where to start then I'm going to
share how was my
reasoning first as is google
My idea was, well, I'm going to take google.com
is what you are most familiar with
and from there I would start with a
aggressive methodology to call it
a certain guy let's give a name to
greece cause i mean i'm gonna
be like there is trying this
interaction directly with the
google servers
save some time too
I was analyzing
and certain environments that are usually
deploy in companies such as
example
by dot google.com from google.com
development point google.com stay in
admin alpha beta local test etc.
people who are familiar with the
software development or
infrastructures will know that they are that they are
sub are words that often use
for non-environment subdomains
of production then I had already seen
quite the dépor google.com on the internet
like that suddenly and he was the one who called me the
attention then to cut the let's say
to focus and shorten more to the sight
the one that selects was the sport
because it sounds more corporate and for
therefore they are what they use the
people internally is not
basically what i did was
do a brute force attack with
a tool seen more works and more
estate
combined with the word list of a
liar called ya ya dix this one ya dix
he is a super master of recognition
well-known bounty hunter
and what happened is that he
together with all the dictionaries of
tools similar to ls
and that they were public for example
d
the next tv etc. a number of
tools that have their lists
dictionaries and all together
complete all lists all
words related to discovery
of energy that found the with a single
file and made it public on the host and
is this the height of txt 2
basically with that he was attacked
brute force all combinations
what can there be for word point the
dotcom let's say asterisk dot
google.com.uk dotcom
Y
they were around 22
million requests in
three minutes or so all this with
A server
relatively small is a pps of 2
gigabytes of ram and a cpu
[Applause]
[Music]
and it was quite the many fast ones, no
same the
It is important to think about how you use the
methodology, tools and
let's say and the
commands and everyone don't worry right now
do not think about this I am going to share
anyway the rendering
something important and tell each other the focus of
the talk is that previously before
use his gross and more goods he used
other tools calling dyn
goods to provide and buster these
tools with the same dictionary
what is golf txt lasts around
30 minutes then what I started to
search was therefore some tools that
they were or that they were that they had
more the same as 6
features but achieves a little more
fast that's how I say
as I told you
because you are the combination of
ns and de resource dictionaries
gene numbering tools
starting well that's the first
let's say the first part of the
discovery of their domains that was
the aggressive one now there is also a way to
get those subdomains so
passive
there is a seeker named adam
probably most of here know
that they give but for those who do not know
basically jordan is like the brother
lesser bad cousin a bad cousin
from google is a search engine that
current, that is, it is constantly
showing services published in
internet and concert intros you can
getting information is enough
interesting we will be talking more
up there in the following spots
basically passively you with a
filter in sudan or in his mike that
It's basically a very useful tool.
similar but blue
you can add 2 point scl filter
and the subdomain we are looking for is
the one we select from cutting
google.com or even the host name
and that will show you servers
and probably with its sub domains of
that contains this this sub domínguez and
not
there is also
another search engine similar to the one called
binary dot i
or even on github too that is if
we put in github in addition and in combine
and in the subdomain as it can
return information related to that
domain and its domains
let's say linked to this without domain no
there is another tool that is also
a certificate search engine that is the
cis
here is the filter same as the one
presentation will be shared but the
The idea is that it be a part, there is also the
sense tool
There is another tool called
rr.ee sh that is a place is a website
where are they say
where certificates of
a lot of many websites then with
this point of sh
Google is also mastered to perform
many related domains today
because they were obtained by
certificates
and one of my favorites is
like hacking hackers to hack their
hacks
eventually if there is someone who is
looking for his domains to go and about everything
from google will come across a list of
rand or a steal when wonderful is
another before very very good
and the link it hot' has all the
numbering that they own many
programs have them public in hip hop
then we can also take the list
from random robbie and add her to
our list of what we got in
all these then processes and many
sometimes there is work that is already done
by us for example in this case
we probably have more
domains but a large part of the
other kids are from where random robin
then it is also interesting to search
in github sometimes it can give you give
information is not that interesting or
work that someone already did because like
they see that together with certain
certain subdomains and it should be noted that
all this passive part, that is, all
the searchers or adam senn if be you lo
i mean random robbie
that information that is obtained without without
have contact with
the servers directly but
passively calls the aggressive part
it is literally testing
combinations one by one in the post
to see what comes back to us
ok at the end all the results
combined and creates a file that is
call by dot google.com diagonal or
txt
What does everyone have there?
institution all the result of all
is from all this exercise
As I mentioned there is also a part
that is from the network is this part of the
network no no was not used in this bug
but i think it's worth it
mention it and what would you have done if
was looking for the network blocks of
d
of Google
there are still two ways passive aggressive
in the aggressive way basically
registration of nextel corp google.com
we obtain
his
idea
basically it's like the network block no
we can we don't have domain
We already have the block and for example with
menem we can
Well, I had position 80, not everything is going
the block in this case was two thousand
591 host
Seeing that we have certain flags for
that for us to say that it is fast that
act fast not with a high king with that
be aggressive that avoid the pin and that's
2,591 houses
they are in two minutes only port chat
and
[Applause]
and how the talk increased is the
idea of ​​revisiting the ruling but also
go see how I inherited tools
and when doing it with more scale
with the same let's say similar
configurations not like the raid for
10,000 the same port the same block
the amount of scan host in 10
seconds
that is, if they realize 2 minutes 6
seconds is one yes is one quite
difference that's a difference
considerable
but there is a very important workshop
more scan is 10 times faster than the
sea ​​that is, there is no doubt but
but but but that is without more without more
scales very fast and in the mab it is very
good for fingerprint what is it
what do we know or do we have
is the port scanner for
fingerprinting and for all then what
What did I try to do instead of having one?
decision of one or the other
first with more scan
Scanned all the ports of the
blocks you have because it will be very
quickly and now that I detect that they are
live the ports now you can
be recognition with
with the motto and scan again then
this already gives you speed and also gives you
consistency there
and gives you greater precision in what is
the ping to the front
at once
in addition to the aggressive part
you can also with the part you can
do passively with equal jordan
it keeps filters than the ones you can
directly add blocker then net
two points
and you can even add sn to it like so
is mentioning the sn
when a company is very large
google or facebook level for example
the
they register network blocks
let's say they have to go to an organization
to register the network blocks that
they are going to be public and that they are going to be
acquaintances of use of this company
so these angels have have
id have an idea on this
the case of google is that 15 16 9
then something that has done though is
very powerful is that you can add in the
idea is in and it will return all
host for all servers that have
that correspond to that being and then to
that's the then it's something it's a point
which I think is very familiar to us but
large companies often have sn
registered and therefore you could
get all network blocks
they have that aysén
and in this case assume that all those
shows will belong to google then
I mean, for example, in this sn only in this
from sn because he also has multiple
memberships of nine million hosts
then many nine million sounds
games but now imagine that instead
to search all over the internet now alone
We have to look for the millions, it won't go away
making smaller the
Let's say the sight that we are auditing
binary which is another similar joan has
they have very similar filters that
you can put the net in sight and nobody
les sl and adds and at the same time equals and
sense and if it's a little different don't
let's say from the filter exactly can
return post d
d
of health
and as I also commented a while ago there are
information that is sometimes already ready
for us or already
already this
the information that is already ready by
example the
most of
well there are many lists that are
public as what are the for which
ports that are most used the 100
most used ports 2000 more ports
used the
the 10,000 most used ports or the
services other than sql
ssh apache check there are lists that already
they have those ports
filtered for calling it another way
we can enter the list of
10,000 top ports in more scan and instead
to scan the 65,000 ports that
they have all the computers we would put
the success of scanning only those of the
top 100 is 2000 the top 10 thousand
there is even a lot of information that if
we found x open port there is already one
cbs promo who say not to be the
port x to run networks and cover x
assigned vulnerability or eg
has a default password that are
or the classic ftp not the 21 that has
anonymous login and if you have it then if not
it is disabled as ftp is
etc. but they are various forms of what
What could be done if you want to audit
the network is not but how do I tell you about this
no this is not in the bug flow
that we are like revisiting
but hey, returning the error to the
failure what
we were looking for we no longer have our
txt list of all subdomains of
cord google.com
and what we did was pass him a
tool called http that
basically that tool tells you if
the host responds something not the subdomain
answer something no basically it is literal
and pass that list try it and it will
answer this one is alive and this one says so
which was a new list from that
after there
we use
eyewitness which is like eyewitness
basically it is to take screenshots of
of the hosts that are alive as
As you can see here the list is already
calls proof basically on what
resulted from testing the domains in
general and then see which ones are alive and
then take a screenshot of the ones
they are alive
ok if recapitulating well then
we have the color list google.com
diagonal that was what we took from
our passive aggressive knowledge
that is, all the tools and the
search engines that we used and we got
about 12,000 house after that
We test if it is live from those shows
of its 12 thousand only thousand were
alive
and after that we go to the
visual display to identification
visual forgiveness of
of those 20 10 thousand 23
thousand 23 sorry then those who are
alive all returned written by
certain html files not from the server
very good once you have to run
there is that witness tool that is
the one who takes screenshots must have a
small graphical interface you can't
run on any static server and
gives you a mini summary of
what
that he answered for example here they are
there are four statuses there are four and
4 1 40,403 answered on http 11 that
4,044 answered that they have value and
you can others who have errors etc.
then
after having them let's say the
screenshot itself
there was one that caught my attention a lot
spring world.com management
Google com
because it caught my attention because it said
work and only
basically
pure pure work accounts could
use that server
so i said ok i'm going to focus on
this first point by point google.com and
In addition, it was publicly accessible
most one redirected to a login
google business and this one not then
what I did what I did was with a
brothel or is it called super basic http
I saw that how he behaved and to what extent
I was heading and what I noticed is that
scream world.com dot google.com what
redirected
espn.com that is, he took away the core and
then he was heading closer dot.com
which was this image but here was this
this domain in the middle that for what is
It made me weird, that is, the end was that
it was not that it was not hidden under a
login and what and what was accessible
publicly not
I wanted to focus later on this single
corp
to see what he did after the return
So from there I went to the part of the
of brute force so to speak
basically it was taking the dictionary that
from jaric the type of cyst and being
testing brute force combinations
in this domain in this its owner
for that the tool that uses be
a tool called w
it's like the web
fuster officer
basically quite parsed with a
filter is a tool that allows you
be sending information
hit a certain application
and allows you to review the let's say the
result or the answer of this one
combination you invented not in this
case what I did was literally both
million words of ya dix las
I was combining
and his brute force and combining in this
subdomain to see if it found anything
this lasted about an hour with 18
minutes when using double euros
[Applause]
later I found out about this tool that
pop pffff flame
of I am then it is supposed or what I know
sold
as sold is tools that is the
which is like a
be much faster and even this is
inspired by double buffaz that's the one
I used but it's a lot a lot a lot
faster happens even if you don't know
realize the syntax is very similar
but the difference is that this one is
written in go and double in fossa is in
python then interpret say is
compiled then in quotes
should be so much faster
after doing the same test
try same dictionary two million
lasted 18 minutes in infusion 2 million
of words then an hour 20
less than 20 minutes
and
and there buying that pop is four times
faster than double post
all those tools
that they are faster or that I am going like
making the comparison the fast ones are not
use them the first time of the flow
Let's say once I met the ones that
I knew the other tools that I visited
this this error and then and I went back to
document as the entire process and there
It was when I did the tests
weather
and at the end of all this of all this
process of all this
let's say two tests
I only found I found a
interesting directory than the diagonal
that's it
and
okay
once we navigate to the first
dot google.com diagonal already
was not heading yet
to an internal google triangle of
fact that it is possible to see what prot says
dot.com and certain common data or
internal no not true true
memory and cpu information and monitoring
from the core network
once I got there I no longer wanted
follow up
let's say brute force or something
could affect this server because it
I saw that it was something important
So there I stopped and what I did was
move on to the web scraping part that
basically it is
in the source code of the page
sample by say the html search search
information or filtered by the tool
that I use is called javier's ht track
basically what roche does is that
makes a clone of the web page so
recursive on your computer pass works
everything even if you have hyperlinks like
those who are seen here well are like
it navigates the hyperlink and
Download what's inside
hyperlink and if there are more hyperlinks
inside the pages too
download all that let's tell you what
all content on this website
they put it, download it in a folder and
after that use grep from the
terminal is normal for
to do this
leaked not with seven brought the
literal url and how it will be called
discharge background
the let's say the html and javascript code
of the page
and in the end I made a group of the file
the same inside the background the file the same
for those who already have a certain time
doing tests and that they know that
probably that parameter does exist
may be vulnerable to cross leg
or what was the inclusion
local feil discovery
but it's like almost certainly going to
it could be that there will be a problem because
literally it is usually that they give him the
path of the file you want what you want
this one that they load or the server
then at the end of that it was again
another group on the results to see
if there was some atmosphere or barber
and this url came out
basically he is pointing at her
proxy file send to those who have
some time using linux you know that in
that in this file well they find
all environment variables
of being running everything I did
was grabbing all that link line
sail
after getting the line and navigating
to google chrome paste lic and
indeed all the variables are
environment of that server
there in plain text before I get excited
I thought I'd better leave it is a file of 6
static no that is not a t exists
literally there that they left or not to be and what
what i did was change the file path
does not have the file for the same
[Music]
and check with the pro version which is the
file that tells you the version of
linux is fighting and loading then there
It was when I already said no, I'm already doing
and if it's something important it worked and that's it
it is verified that it was not that it was not
something calculated because then they can be
upload files
changing the route from here to the fire
and
in the end being honest and try to
escalate this in the remote code but no
could
the server was very protected very
I was like very card in hoisted of a certain
so that I couldn't load things that weren't
may of the prop and for example the
variables of
environment they had nothing that I
could you give me access to the german server
internal or for example the own brawn
diagonal efe which is sometimes used for
climb
the session was not accessible so accessible
the beaches of seychelles
nor the logs either, that is, look for logs of
http to see if you can that I saw it not the
you can't really silos and i tried but
after all, it was something important and
I decided to report it
then pass the recap of this
failure came first
In a global form
we say a discovery of
organization and the first thing was to see the
scope of the program which is very
important or know what rules the
program because regularly if not
follow the rules of the program do not suit you
to pay it then it is important to continue
the rules to stay out of trouble
and know what we have to review
after that we took a
subdomain in this case was by dot
google.com after there what we did
was that of the discovery of his
domains aggressively and aggressively
passive and at the end was the
display
with screenshots of what was alive and
of what was left after that
was what what was brute force
to see that
what word could someone give us
directory or something important with the
the goal list txt and in the end no
got key as directory
internal
after that we lowered all that
application we made a local copy with
this track to make the escape
and at the end filter serious
with the same file
and then already result in profits
after all this what result of
this failure
First of all, as I told you, well
the truth is that I had a lot of fun if it's being
such a large organization if anything
considerable amount of time
invest and for the same reason I try to find
tools that go very fast
to try to pass the stages
from one stage to another faster no
back then back then stay
ranking 62 worldwide in google and
Right now I eat at 100 and fair 105 104
flights and it is then that at level in the
in the range 62 and 20 and 13 thousand
dollars obviously very good very good
incentive and
and let's say google is a team that
knows that they know when something is
important and let's not say they don't walk no
try to hide or try to
fix things but pay and so they
when when they know it's something
important they take it very seriously and
that's why they are usually rewarded
quite quite high the
something also important here goes
mention that they gave me the reward
higher than was considered as
remote code execution
even though I couldn't do the
remote game execution what happens is
let the google team them
internally
they were able to execute remote code that is
They were able to escalate this bug and how
you already know that it is possible that it was a matter
of time that someone could
have remote mail run on this
server that's why they take it as you
they pay how to put impact for saying it
so it's pretty pretty good no because
in other programs
Latino experiences that if you are not
able to demonstrate x x this impact or
how critical it is they minimize and treat it
to pay less and already and here in google
once this is the opposite of them
They help you to scale as much as possible
you can and after that you already have
the proper reward not to the failure that
by contrast
ok once I'm there we find a
failure and many people then go to
another thing
usually
Well, yes, that is, this same error
They want to look at other companies, I do.
than a part of the process that you add in
All my process is something that I call it
the duck test maybe someone already
you hear not necessarily something from
security but but I liked I liked the
idea to add it what is the test the
pate, that is, if something looks like a duck, nothing
like a duck and quacks like a duck
so they are probably part that is
the yard test
So what was I thinking of?
that is, I said that he has this fault
on their servers
they do not deploy servers
one by one they do it on a scale or
automated so i said ok yeah
have a mistake
probably that mistake if edu se
deployed in a systematic way because in
other parts then basically what
I did was get in done dan told us the
seeker is the
google's younger brother and put the
filters of what was the flame background
and the google organization
basically i told all the servers
that you find that they have the
java east directory and that
belong to google damaris and for me
surprise there were six of those six one is
the one that I had already reported
there was another that was not accessible
help bandos and the other 44 sorry
I returned to report as I mean as
result were three other failures
valid and 14 that was duplicated because
apparently it was I don't know if it was the same
server or did it have to do with a server
which deploys another but only that is
just by thinking about that google
probably deployed more servers
the same as the ones I found and with certain
fingerprints in sudan i was able to get from
return which public servants
they had that information that in fact this
this is outdated i already found
still but compared 33 more with the same
problems with variations
but yes, that is, it is very important
revisit our failures and it is something
something I have not seen that people
comment a lot but this type can happen
of things, that is, if you already know
specifically the behavior of a
server you vulnerable
you can use sudan
Well, filter in a certain way so that you
return servers very similar as
a pad
and well after all that
lessons learned from all this
exercise
for me it is to keep the basics never
underestimate the basic weights if
realize we are talking about tools
simple configurations
tools but I did not put much emphasis
because it is not so important in itself
tools or saint for me what
important is the analysis and for the
people who are just starting
I recommend that you focus on the
bone analysis
what we want to do is the
I can talk in six steps right now or
whatever we were doing first
is to see the program 'rewards and your
global reach
second list your domains
after numerous goods see which ones
are alive of those which are alive
take screenshots of those writing shots
to make a visual review and the one who
seems interesting to make the web is
traffic be download this page
complete and to filter the to see if
we found something important in there and not
there is no tool in between
well sometimes maybe tomorrow they will release something
better than four or something better than the
however something better than more are and
it will simply be to exchange the
tool in the step that we are lo
important are the steps but there are times
What are you saying, no, well, I like this one better.
this sea birthing tool
screenshots
and it's valid, you just move it and the
you change and adjust your methodology because
with the methodology is a is something
separate to what is the tools
[Music]
but already speaking of tools something
important is that the tools
they have settings you can't
put the time out for example of saray
witness where you can decide how much
you want me to wait to take the
writer if the server does not respond the
by default it has seven seconds I think
but in my case I always add that
the second answer me yes no yes no
answered the second that follows but that
It is fully configurable, thanks.
to your preferences yes or if you know that
there are servers that can last 30
seconds to answer because you can
ring and since 30 seconds have passed if you
you go on to the next one but it's something I know
can configure then it is important
just copy and paste the tools
but see the configurations you have
to know how you can
let's say how you can adjust for what
you are looking for nothing else is to be
professional many times there is a lot
frustration and as I comment
programs sometimes do not give us the
answers that we want but
It's just like, well, that's how it is, that is, yes
you have if you want to be a professional
you have to accept as a professional that is
polite to wait then
discipline is constancy is very
very important
daily even a little for this I go
to address this issue but daily although
be a little there that we are documenting
or follow the people who are involved
or be reading because yes yes it is
important as soon as that discipline is done
is what gives you results
Another thing is that you don't have to give yourself so much
hurry many times we are very
accelerated and especially not
we started this takes a long time
fact could cancer is bored to
some people
but if patience patience patience
I give you an example is la and microsoft
I think they are already more agile in their
response times but in its time
12 years ago
They answered me after 16 months or more
less then since I reported until
to get the profit was 16 months
in each one then it is something that
you have to be very patient another
important thing is to avoid bon outs or
or burn out or overload can be
say that there are times that the ruling does not
you cannot raise it, that is, by more than
try yes to search and do no
you can climb it happened to me with him with him
from yahoo i found an ex 1x ss in a
mobile application and report it to me
mark with a formative
and I knew that I could do it, which I couldn't
informative, well, yes, I knew this.
it can climb but i lasted like 23 days
wanting and could not until I decided
release it and that I will not continue with my
life and one day eight months later I
came the idea how to exploit it and
I barely did it and that was because I read
more things because I went on with my life and
I just said that I can't do it
right now and after months only the
answer and I was able to continue the escalation and
it was paid and everything out there is the blog
come from yahoo
in my page
another very important thing is to learn
English more than anything for communication
almost all companies receive their
reports in English and the information that
it's good
is usually in English every time or little by little
There are few things in Spanish but the
The reality is that in almost all areas
the good information is in
English is not important if you demand it is
complicated it was very complicated for me
but but with practice and with the idea
that it is one more tool then
may
you can see it like this social knowing english is
a tool more than more than another
stuff
another important thing in being reading reading
read
to what I am going to recommend not to
to overwhelm I know it sounds very cliché
that we fight and that now with that
we are going to learn it but sometimes you have
ten books that have come out in your
youth or in your bookshelf and you don't even know
how to start what I did was read a
thing a day or a blog post a day is a
goal that I started a rap pill ago
moon 2015 then to read one thing at
day sounds something that is to see relatively
simple I do not open more times and drink coffee
for example you can do with your coffee
and it is a habit that I promise you will
change a lot, that is, they are going to learn
too much although it sounds very very fat that
I made that purpose in 2015 or so
less right now we are at 222 let's say 7
desserts are like two thousand days more than
2000 days not then since that day I have
read one thing a day at least
security and it's already like seven years
as more than 2,000 days to mean
that there are more than two thousand things that I read
it was seen then the could sound like
start reading on the fact day before
someone computer or security blog
I'm not sure the older ones know
they will remember the day is called
I don't know if it was because of that but I would have
a lot of sense because if with one
day then then do then until get
lots of information and change and change your
your knowledge exponentially
As I was telling you, patience is so
important this is 16 months and wait
right now the programs are more
nimble but still at least it's a
month three weeks of waiting and at the end of
that to repeat everything we saw
can repeat and throw identify things
that we want to change and start over
and well for my part it would be everything and many
Thanks for the opportunity, I'm attentive.
for your questions and
here in the
they left the talk yes of course man
thank you very much for your presentation
the truth is that very interesting
how you use this methodology
to find this kind of problems
indeed we have several questions
We are going to try to solve at least two
of them
and the rest of the steps by internal
so that if you can answer them in your
social media
there is one that talks a lot about your book
where can you find it if you go
to raffle someone who is good in general
So we can summarize several questions in
that
ok well you can find the book in
amazon is called one has spanish and
anyway i have it on my blog too
in nine months pino dotcom in
any link from my blog are the
links to the book something important is that
This is in Spanish and English at
At first I took it out in Spanish because it was
the idea because there was almost nothing in
Spanish and there were people who asked me
in English so I have it published in
the two and the raffle I think that if one
digital one digital there if you can
pass a list of those who
they attended the conference or something like that and
we make one that is a selection of
this random
and by doing this on your own social network
twitter are you going to put something related to
your book we send people to
to give it a retweet and the people who
make retweet of that publication they raffle
free, do you think it's going I'll remember later
a little later I do it this time
well
there is another question then specifically
about what you found that if the
three other failures also paid you
like rc yes yes all faults los
they will find they will pay them as you are but
as they were not in the domain of
Google com
the impact and the
Let's say
economic gain but if everyone
they paid the same pass was the same
issue
the last bullet you want the rich as
the main phase for the success of the
group not
it can be but hey it's a very part
important and probably the
principal
but for example there are others
researchers that their focus is that
they are going to
to say the case of this one from google.com
they go to google.com directly and not
They get out of there and start testing.
based on a google search for
example or google filters and it goes away
live a day let's say to the bull for
the horns' is not the application itself
that is his approach in this case and for me
personally if the recognition is
one of the most important phases but I have
been trying to change that that
let's say mentality and try to search
stuff
directly in a fact application
there is an example of a bug that
I found on google+ the one that basically
It's like a programming idea with
a linux shell that google has
gives it to you for free for having your account
from google and for example in this case
particular was no does not say anything
acknowledgment then directly in this
app i stayed in this app
three days until I found something that
the one that can make her vulnerable
It depends, it depends, but in general, yes.
of the first things or when one
Recognition has just begun
the most important
I think the important thing is that I don't know
get stuck in the stage of
recognition because I believe that a lot
people become experts treat
automate tries to filter and at the end
this is just the tip
of the air to find something that
catch your eye and start looking
failures if it only makes a record they will never go to you
to pay nothing if you find no fault with
he recognizes himself tara to win then
like they don't get stuck in rich
in but if it is very important of course
correct totally agree good a
see I have the public for you
say goodbye and we can continue with the
event schedule that many
thank you all suffered the conference
and as Jaime mentioned we are going to give a
digital book
in a moment more since busy month the
things I will publish and I will carve
work and it's going to be done let's say the
raffle among the retweets of this life and
many thanks for everything
active thank you very much continuing
then with our programming
next we have mateo martínez
he comes from uruguay and he is going to talk to us a
little about security issues
which is located in the dependencies 220
shows ah but Martin in his
professional reconstruction of the
computer security that has already been
in various editions of our event
when it is in person when it is done
online and the truth is that it is a
nice for us to have him back
Theo are you open
and this in jaime nothing to do is mine a
Nice to be able to participate again in a
give you a lecture that
I adore I congratulate you now what to explain
for the benefit but at the time that
who have done as a community what they have
done as a company what you are doing
as conferences is something that now that
came to admire so congratulations
no mind thanks back for for
allow me to participate that part for me
are or are not really so many
thanks to my crisis' actions
get active march thank you
well he continued with the filtration to
less than subjects of thanks from
affiliations will never be enough
when they are doing I think everyone
professionals vicious if ever
we saw news develop well
expert insights motivated us to learn
some theme and lara that yes share
since the piety edition was criticized with
denounce phrases for me it is also
an honor always a pleasure every time with
the whitest hair jaime so it is
It really shows that years have passed
since the prediction we were all
with even darker hair after
receiving sponsors so that
the effort wanting the events is
extremely important but you have to
thank the sponsors who do
and allow others to take too
the shape the size of professionalism
that they have so that each of them does not
and me when I saw on the website of
the sponsors in this that I liked
show that he appears so humble there
below that the two creators are the
motivators all this in being on top of
everyone so make that big task
as as a company one knows what
collaborate as a community and entered into
the conference and obviously the
sponsors that make this possible
my part stopped thinking a little my
biography for those who don't know me
don't you martínez I'm working on
a thousand people and ways to do it no
I have a long way to go
still no more computer television and
computer engineers and with some
market certifications of how it's done
and between the iso standards I am a teacher in the
monterrey tec in utrecht florida as
in paraguay nor tested and in the
ort university uruguay diploma
help security that is just that
daily coordinates situations a
industry in Uruguay and with that the
founder of two companies create more
hacking I come from Colombia that's the
place in uruguay that you saw some topics
anti that explains that to us only as
plantation after I think they have
talked a lot but always without topics
to work professional ethics is what
What makes us today professionals
this let's say this more than anything to
those who are starting out in there is a
road
extremely
interesting in terms of security with
which work on this issue of ethics
good morals they manage to do professionals
considerable in and I think that doing the
difference in the market so
work on these issues
just from behavioral issues watching the
respect to have patience really
part and what professionals do today in
seriously and now check out the introduction and
I'm going to talk a little about what they are
dependencies in particular to have their
sensors I like this image a lot
general but it is a drawing that explains
almost all the problems we have in
day we always have legacy projects or
projects that we have created in another
moment put five or six years ago
those pieces the software we want
to say that he has many problems
many bugs and ropey is something since
zero well to make it clean but no
have problems so that he does not bring us
no complications and what do we do
we take pieces we always use pieces
that's that castle we had
full of bugs and our new project
always start with community problems
and others later that we add in the
subject of copy and paste really being
unlikely we could survive with
control is controlled and from there
some additional extra but it is a
fabulous tool there are some very
interesting how to cocker and paste from
stack overflow as villar message from
mistake I also recommend them so that
are starting on the subject and then
If the problem is the time you have
Defender I am with though something that
Collaborate helps us to make the software
faster develop
and well these types of names
applications with some dependencies
well every time does follow even this
resource of bookstores or part of the
project as part of the efficiency that
we have the problem happens with these
values ​​not that 85% the components are
outdated good inclusions
updated more than four years with what
which
let you see those components extremely
vulnerable in many times without a
follow-up of the same with which it is
a timely and attack well and
obviously must work on security
after this we add a
problem that is good there is
tools today that allow
or databases that allow us
investigate when a cb arises when
an apathy 9 appears in a dependency
Now I'm going to dig a little deeper into that.
but the truth is that since I came out a
ally is that it is until the same
it has its cd and its encoding its
identity the only one happens not that is and in the
case of 9 for example 50 54 days in
average good for it to be published
this is good if we compare it with what
it can take development of an exploit
in front of a new unit we talk about days
we talk about weeks we talk about hours
leaves an exposure and dental at risk
very wide ok then sometimes
we talked about that for more than a month well
then the risk where the
exploit and yet it is not on cd or not
is the public the authority as such
with an identifier and many
tools what they do is go and search
these in this database to define
if he is vulnerable, not since we speak
is for simplicity of recognition
men that is to say well there is some seen
there is some basis there is something and maybe
after
in the community is discovered the
which opens a very wide window before
what the tools will put vs.
what can be achieved by a researcher or a
analyst or air through god given today
who is looking for tools in attack
So where are we in the day and
the international context that also
always interesting in this context
and there I always appear in the
current situation we must talk about the
situation with ukraine without a doubt well that
began to see how two sides and Ukraine
with his
cyber army of which he sought an interest in
global level and we began to skate
begins to make attacks not in what is
infrastructure of russia russia for its
party for years attacking ukraine
from electoral issues to issues of
critical infrastructure good and good
clean everything in that situation
affected sales to suppliers and affected
already to different organizations and he in
service nation themes saying guy
of aspects of attack is inclusive has
fact that some hosting providers
For example, they were in cities like
this mass have had to change their
equipment and then for the
more regional situations not the issue of
costa rica have paralyzed the government in
crisis situation have issues such as
of the app its themes of attacks to
companies triplings for this
keep moving forward
we see more and more viral attacks themes
like the one from the uber where sometimes
Not clear how to respond to
attacks on how to respond to the press
how you respond to situations sometimes
things that happened a couple of years ago and
I know also writing like it was a
functionality is not a file not the
great phrase we have on the matter
just from incident reports
regularities after then too
regional on the run in mercadolibre
What more than obviously visiting the
pandemic remote work led to
also the use of these houses have
be affected well and in taking advantage of
all those who were also with the
same controls that had the
organizations and that ends up being good
hoaxes and scams
and within the text it is impossible not to talk about
for six than a unit too
dependencies that made us all run
in the complete market had to be
search good which providers using
the gay doctor and in what products that
we use that project how to start
to tell the different brands well
with our suppliers or in our
behind networks where it was then by law
And how did we mitigate this?
be able to make some kind of improvement to
remedy the unit well whereupon a
good review that had everything in check
the market that good based on the other of
smoke that showed this other to me not
I find it interesting that he explains a
little that cause day and it is not
exactly the case of the king mushroom but
yes for many glories we use no
we have a great project
solution to internal commercial as
be and we have a small dependency
opensource that maintains it to someone
since some year well
and how is this example and in 2003 there is
in the fridge to a single person who
manages and maintains that bookstore that
becomes critical our platform is
that small pillar that separates a reason
who makes the whole fall down is lost
platform then a little iron
it ends up being to say well let's work
on that little pine forest that is there
abandoned and you can see the different
perspectives on one side to give you
security in the organization for topics
from bach band and as well speaking well
It is also a place to attend and work
Now it is to demonstrate a small case and
obviously from the tasks side of
If you don't think so, that will also help us
work and analyze what the other has
good side then of what is current and
from bs cops well today it begins
work in legalized environments than in
which these little blocks too
each one of those blocks that brings us
dependencies do not strangle ities and
we talk about solutions of course
third-party component microservices
infrastructure as a service
the truth that we began to add
leaders of energies and each one has
some kind of constant dependency
being within this concept
in the efes will arrive as soon as possible
software development security
it becomes important to work and add what
theme of piluso bookstores well and
dependencies then today the elect of
dobbs teams wanted a change
cultural generate a transformation
speed a job what was had on
cascade investigations but
It also requires automating