good morning everybody uh welcome to
b-sides boulder 2021
um well i
i'm going to you know expect a bit more
enthusiasm from y'all next year um
so you know we are planning on doing an
in-person event next year but first
i just kind of want to talk about the
great
event that we have planned for this year
um uh you know before
you know we get into schedules or any of
that i
just want to say thank you to uh
volunteers
um uh stephen kennedy and dan mackin for
uh all your help uh today um
you know throughout the day uh hopefully
um uh and want to
give a shout out to all of our sponsors
without whom
you know none of this would happen first
you know i want to
say a big thank you to rule 4 for being
our leading sponsor again this year
second year in a row uh
thanks for everything uh you do
um kaspersky again is
uh a sponsor for the second year in a
row uh we also
picked up uh elastic um and
uh sands as sponsors this year so thank
you
uh to all of that uh to all of you guys
um
for having faith in us and you know uh
letting us
uh do this um this event and
uh really you know allowing us to bring
such great content to you from you know
great people inside of our
inside of our community so and of course
thank you to all of you who are here
you know watching the stream i know that
you know
i'm may not be the one that you came to
see but
uh there are a number of great talks
um that are uh going to be happening
today
um the schedule
is uh on
the besides boulder.com website
i know it was a little bit fuzzy on the
um on the feed earlier but uh we'll just
run through
that real quick so right now we're doing
the opening
as you can you know hopefully can tell
um
at 9 30 we'll start with our first with
our keynote
uh love your love your cyber life uh
wear your
bra um by uh karen warsaw
uh then you know this year uh
one of the feedback things that we got
um from last year
the ways to improve was to lengthen the
brakes in between last year we had
little five-minute breaks which in some
cases
bled over and didn't allow enough time
for
you know people to actually get up and
get
you know more coffee or or whatever so
this year we've linked in those
uh breaks to 10 minutes
so so that should be able to help you
and i just got uh
notified that i said besides folder.com
i think uh it's actually besides
boulder.org sorry about that
uh please um go check out the
full schedule there um uh we do have
uh talks you know all the way until
uh five o'clock uh where we will be
doing the closing we have a one hour
lunch
uh starting at noon uh well
uh 12 15 excuse me uh
so take take time get outside
you know stretch your legs um grab lunch
uh
chat in the the general or social chats
you know
get to know uh some other people in the
community
um and you know but come back uh by
uh 120 where we have another talk
uh starting at that time
if at any time you have to step away and
you know you're like man but i really
wanted to see
a victory lap to the end of the world um
you can watch some of these
well you can watch most of these talks
uh after
um after the event um we'll
send out you know much like we did last
year
on twitter you know the the channel that
you can see those you can always go to
the besides boulder
uh youtube channel and they will be um
listed there as well
uh let's see what else we have giveaways
today
um those will be given away
at randall uh in
the um in the discord channel if you are
not in the discord channel please join
the discord channel
the uh link is somewhere on the
frame underneath me i believe
i don't know if it's over here over here
but uh it's somewhere there
and you can also get there
if you attended last year it's the same
link um
to that discord channel so but i will be
we will be doing uh giveaways that
um will be announced in the discord
channel uh so
i'm not saying you must be present to
win but in
most cases it is definitely helpful if
you are present to win
um um some some
of those giveaways we do have ideas on
how we're giving away
uh most of them but there may be one or
two words just like hmm
you know random roll of the die you get
the
giveaway so if you're um
in uh discord it very likely will not be
during lunch you know maybe at the end
of lunch you know time frame but
we do want to allow everybody time to
get outside and
step away from the screen enjoy a little
bit of sun anyway
uh let's see what else we have this
secure code warriors tournament
if you jump into the discord you see the
scw tournament
channel head in there
it's a great coding tournament i have
not
done it myself and i really want to i've
seen
the idea and you know it sounds uh
sounds amazing and i
totally would be doing it today but
um i'm i'm kind of
helping out um with some of this stuff
so
unfortunately not going to be able to
make it today but there will be
winners announced uh in the closing uh
uh remarks uh for the secure uh secure
code
warriors tournament so jump in there
i think that starts
at around 10 30 but there are more
details
in that channel so please jump in there
there's i think um youtube video on how
to get started
um and
they'll certainly have a lot more
instructions in there for you so you can
do that uh we always
you know uh appreciate your feedback um
you know for each of the uh of the talks
uh for each of the speakers you know uh
i know as a speaker myself uh in other
um other events
i enjoy getting feedback um you know
ways to improve
uh you know things that you know oh hey
that that was great you know those
those kind of things uh so we will have
surveys um
i will send out a link to those
throughout the day
inside the general channel
please take time to fill those out we do
have a section
in there where you can fill out you know
uh general
um general feedback for the conference
so if it's not directly related to one
of the talks you can still fill
that out and we'd love to um we'd love
to get that
feedback and you know see what we can do
better for next year
uh we do have um moderators uh
moderating these channels um so please
follow the rules
the rules are pretty simple you know
uh let's see if we can uh
make it as as nice as possible um don't
uh don't be a jerk just you know we're
we're all here together to get to
know some some new content to get to
know each other
last year we had no issues um i'm not
really expecting that we're going to
have any issues this year
because you know this is such a great
group of people so
again thank you guys for uh for joining
um the the
discord and interacting with other
people
that actually means a lot to all of us
um
so i i want to point out something
you see i got oh look at that we have
a shirt we have shirts guys um we
weren't originally going to have shirts
but
you know i was uh sitting talking with
um with one of our sponsors rule 4
and they're like hey what are we doing
for shirts this year and i said well
i think we kind of made the decision
that we were not really going to do
shirts this year due to some of the
logistics
and rule 4 stepped up and said dude
let us do the shirts we'll get those
shirts
so now we have shirts they're amazing
they have the logos on the back um
and you know this nice
besides boulder logo on the front
how do you get your shirt um i will be
after
this uh after i stop talking uh i will
be dropping a link
inside the general channel the shirts
are first come first served um we
already had them ordered
uh and they will be shipped out
shortly uh after um
you know early you know next week so
hopefully we get them
uh into all of your hands you know very
quickly afterwards but
you know again a huge shout out to rule
four for
um um for taking on
the shirts uh this year
let's see dropping out the oh
they are first come first served uh on
the form we have
um two sections for sizes
uh two sections for sizes and
um uh one you know is just in case
we um you know run out of that size and
say our first come first serve you know
add your second selection
we uh are asking that you only fill out
one form
we're generally only going to be sending
one shirt um
to each person so um but
uh that's that's all i have to say
on that for now getting a few
uh messages about yeah i i
almost came on here saying who's this
guy yeah
uh the beard is gone this year um
it was a nice uh a nice fun
um i guess experiment i'd never
uh grown a beard and you know was super
happy with it
uh but um it came time that uh
i figured i'd go ahead and you know uh
shed the the winter fur i guess
and you know uh just in time for summer
so uh but
2022 we are i'm not making any promises
on a beard uh for 2022 that was not
what the intention that was not the
segway 2022
will have an event in person um
uh uh
we you know are not sure exactly
date or time or you know location yet
but we will be
um uh having an in-person conference
this will be
a first for the b-sides boulder um
event and we are super
super excited about that um you know
uh again
you know fill out those surveys we
will appreciate any of those the the
feedback
um and you know we'll implement some of
that stuff
for you know even next year so
let's see i talked about i said thank
you to
um our great volunteers again stephen
and dan um uh
our let's see our sponsors
again thank you guys so much for um for
spending time
uh with us today i know you know on a
saturday it's not always the greatest
but
you know it's nice to get together with
um
really a bunch of friends so thank you
for you know being very friendly with us
uh i do expect maybe one or two
um issues today but
um we'll work to uh
clear clean those up super quick uh just
bear with us i
i say i expect them i don't really but
you know figure if i say
i do then you know that's that's the way
it goes
uh that is um
really all that i have uh today
to to talk to you about um
we have about uh let's see
15 minutes left uh until
uh the the first um
until our keynote um
i'm happy to you know just sit here and
you know just chat for you know another
five minutes
um if you know if anybody wants to talk
about stuff uh um but other than that
uh you know thanks again everybody
for for joining us
hold on i did see let's see what kind of
power tool
yeah power tools um
power tools in order to get uh get rid
of
the beard uh
it took you know um
i had to go to home depot really and get
a gas
trimmer um for that because i tried with
the
the uh electric trimmer and it just like
it got all bound up and stuff so i
need did definitely needed the gas
trimmer for that
um i i would have preferred a battery
operated
but you know the the gas trimmer just
had a little bit more
power uh let's see what can i do to get
involved oh
great question um what can i do to get
involved with 2022
please reach out to us you can either
reach out to us
via our um our email address uh
info besides boulder.org.org
or reach out to us you know on
twitter reach out to us at discord today
you know
certainly we'll need um
a little bit more assistance next year
as we will be in person and we need a
lot of smiling faces
that will help you know greet and and
make sure everybody is
uh feeling comfortable and um
and you know enjoying the event
uh this is sponsored by
harry's razors now no uh
no harry's razors today
um
that really let's see uh that is all i
got
guys um we have again 20 or
13 now minutes 12 and a half
minutes until uh the keynote so
please um go ahead
and you know grab a drink grab some more
coffee um
take a quick break and you know head
back and meet us back here
at uh 9 30.
and we will see y'all then