good morning it's uh my pleasure to
welcome karen worstel
karen is a serial assisto for iconic
companies across industry sectors and
the silicon valley technology leader
her keynote presentation is titled love
your cyber life wear your bra
and provides recommendations for a
successful career in cyber security
all yours karen great hey thank you so
much for
inviting me to speak to you this morning
i have multiple cameras here so i'm
going to
take a minute to kind of get adjusted to
uh where i'm looking because i want to
be
looking at you um i'm i'm very grateful
to have the opportunity to be here today
and i hope
um you'll get a lot out of this and
as we come to the end of the
presentation if you have any thoughts or
questions i'd be happy to answer
any questions that you have so
many years ago i stood in the produce
section
at the local market looking for apples
apples apples apples where were the
affordable apples
because you see i had a two-year-old and
a five-year-old
and i had 13 dollars in my pocket to
last me for the next two weeks
49 cent per pound apples which seems
like such a bargain today
they were completely out of reach and
in desperation i swallowed what was
left of my pride and i went to the
produce manager to ask him
if he had any apples that he had pulled
from the shelf that he'd be willing to
sell to me for a discount
and it was so it's so vivid in my mind
right now
remembering that still
small voice of inner wisdom that i could
hear
that said there has to be a better way
than this
and you can do this
so about that same time my biggest ally
my
big geeky hacker brother michael
he came over to my house and across my
kitchen table
he spread out a trs-80 model one
computer with a serial number of six
and said to me sister
you need to learn to code
well i'm a 98 percent
left-brained creative i studied music
performance
and i did that until my early 20s i
thought when i was young i would grow up
and design ball gowns for barbie dolls
i designed and sewed all my own clothes
all the way through college
and i had managed to get undergraduate
degrees in chemistry and biology through
sheer will and hard work
but still this whoring blinking
machine intimidated me i was sure that
if i did something
wrong typed in something wrong it would
go up in smoke so i finally sat at that
keyboard and tentatively
typed in the words h-e-l-l-o
hit enter and nothing bad happened
that blinking nine inch monitor with
that
amber cursor it just kept blinking at me
and all the various ribbons and cables
and components
just sat there so
with michael's help i learned to program
and go beyond playing games i started
programming in visual basic
and then i taught myself a programming
language called fourth
and i loved programming and i found out
i was really good at it
so when the local graduate school opened
up a program
in computer science for a master's
degree
that's when i heard that voice again and
it said
you can do this
so have you ever had that experience
when you had kind of that heartfelt
inspiration about something that you
knew could happen something that you
knew you could do
and then your head starts all kinds of
noise
some people call it imposter syndrome
for me
my head got super noisy and it sounded
like this
i thought you wanted to be a good mother
don't forget you have a two-year-old and
a three-year-old
by the way you have zero money
and you suck at math
which i kind of do so to make a long
story shorter i applied
i got in two years later i graduated
from university with my master's degree
in computer science
my first job happened before i finished
my thesis
as a security analyst and 15 years later
i left my job as the chief information
security officer at microsoft
to start my own cyber security
consultancy and share my lessons learned
and experiences toward a more inclusive
work culture where everyone
has voice and an impact
so you may think this is an
extraordinary journey from a broke mom
of toddlers to a chief information
security officer with of multiple
iconic brands like microsoft at t
russell investments
but what i know for sure is that just
like all of you
this journey happened one ordinary day
at a time
it took an unshakeable belief in that
still
small voice that carried me through it
all
and it took up showing up every day
even when things got tough and as i look
back on it
it took a lot of allyship
starting with my big brother michael
people who believed in me and held me up
people who made it possible for me to go
even
further to go to university as a broke
mom of toddlers
and to help make sure my kids were cared
for
that path to the top of my profession in
large part
happened because of three things that
i'm going to talk to you about today
whenever it got tough these three things
helped me
they helped me by reminding me
it can be better than this and you can
do this
so today i'm here to share with you
those three things because
tech can be far better than it is
now and i believe with all my heart that
it is within your power and mine
to make it so you see
tech suffers from a lack of diversity
it's a la
and a lack of inclusion and a lack of
equity
30 years ago when i got my master's
degree women were 34
of the computing workforce today that
number is far
south of the 23 percent that it
officially hit
in 2016 when the aauw
published its report on women in stem
called why so few
every area of stem over the last 30
years
has shown growth in diversity and
inclusion
except computing and the huge question
for me
when i learned that fact was why
part of my path to that understanding
inc
you know it includes what seems like a
huge detour
but in hindsight now it makes perfect
sense because
at the time that that report came out i
was a chaplain
i had just completed 2 000 hours of
clinically supervised
training in pastoral care in addition to
another master's degree
and i was serving as the palliative care
fellow at the va hospital in portland
throughout my time as a chaplain one of
the things
that i noticed was that i had seen
firsthand
the similarities between the distress in
people
in the tech sector and distress
of families and patients in crisis and
there's a principle in chaplaincy called
the principle of proximity and what that
basically says
is that the chaplain does not sit in her
foxhole
or her or i'm sorry the chaplain does
not sit in her field tent
waiting for the front line to come and
make an appointment
she goes and sits with the front line in
the foxhole
and my foxhole is in tech
my still small voice said to me again
tech is your foxhole
it can be better than this you can do
this and so i left
made the decision at that time when i
learned this information
about parity inequity and inclusion
in tech and left the chaplaincy and came
back to tech
and i returned with a big hairy
audacious goal to create a more
inclusive work environment
and to reverse the trend of women and
under
underrepresented groups leaving tech in
my lifetime
so these facts are current i'll give you
a few facts and then we're going to dive
into the three things
six percent of partner level pay in big
tech goes to women
this pattern carries across all of tech
in a meal a meloo that author emily
chain calls
brotopia it's a symptom of a culture
that doesn't value the voices of people
who are different than the decision
makers at the top
life cycle processes in hr are designed
unfortunately to reinforce
the existing dominant culture and you
if you have differences must fit
in i do an exercise in all of my
workshops that sounds like this
it's it's kind of designed to make
everyone feel equally uncomfortable
right at the beginning and break the ice
but i have
everyone walk around the room three
times the first time we walk around the
room
we walk around the room as ourselves the
second time people walk
around the room i ask them to do so
by embodying the energy that is the
opposite of what they
embodied when they walked around the
room the first time
and the third time we walk around the
room we're not supposed to walk around
the room as
anything and be completely neutral
and when we debrief when this is over
the feedback that i always get
with every single group is that walking
around the room
the first time as ourselves feels great
the second time we walk around the room
everyone spends about 30 to 50 percent
of their
energy trying to figure out who they're
supposed to be
and the third time they walk around the
room people use
the language like all the energy went
out of the room
we looked like zombies time slowed down
and my answer to that is welcome to
corporate
america because you see
we don't create an environment where
people can bring
all of their variety and all of their
rainbow
and all of their diversity into the
workplace
and shine and create
the kind of work environment where
creativity and innovation really thrives
what we do is we create a corporate
blender where everyone comes in with all
of their variety
we put you all in because to fit you
must
blend to bland beige
right so
let's get to why we're going to talk
about what we're going to talk about
today
because here's the truth when we
lift one up all rise
so when we embrace the benefit of
inclusion
in the cyber business it's equivalent to
promoting
creativity innovation and diversity of
thought that will help us
in this asymmetric war that we're
fighting right now
and that's eating our lunch so this is
our foxhole we're in it together
it matters for all of us in cyber
security because creating a workplace
where everyone has a voice is the right
thing to do
and because we cannot begin to address
the challenges that we
face in cyber today with when our
community is disengaged out of
frustration
for the next little bit i'm going to
show these three pillars that you can do
right now
every day and that will make a
difference
three things belief resilience
and allyship and yes
that spells bra
in case you wondered where that came
from the first pillar
in the difference that you can make is
belief when megan came to
our two-day intensive that we do she was
a senior software engineer
and her experience led her to believe
that it was best to
fly under the radar she was frustrated
that
although she was considered a high
potential employee
she did not receive the visibility
opportunities or compensation that her
work deserved
and after our two-day intensive this is
what she wrote
i have a renewed sense of self-awareness
and confidence
and i've learned that my professional
self-worth listen to this very important
is in no way dependent
on what i am able to accomplish how
productive i am
or how others perceive me i've also
learned that the true value in making
genuine connection is with is making
genuine connection with the people that
i work with
and that i don't need to do it all on my
own
and get by on mere merit and solid work
ethic
i'm much more likely to ask questions
contribute in meetings and admit that i
don't understand something and talk to
people
about my work experience and how things
are going with me
i'm a lot more confident in my skill set
and i'm better at reading
my own emotional state and attempting to
read others
i'm much more comfortable with reaching
out to people
those are megan's words when we believe
we can make a difference
we do this was not something that we did
to fix
megan she already had all of the ability
to make this happen
it just took a little bit of a reset the
mindset
reset that happened with megan was
almost instantaneous
she influenced her she went on to
influence her leadership
she helped shift the culture got
visibility
got a promotion and a degree of
assurance
that was incredibly self-satisfying for
her career
the power of belief to make a difference
is a hope that comes deep
from your own inner wisdom just like
the inner wisdom that spoke to me at
that very beginning of that journey
unlocking that power of that belief
comes from knowing how to listen
to that inner voice and believing it
so why don't we do this all the time
because most of the time we as cyber
people
are all up in our heads we deal with
systems and data and facts and metrics
and when you're in your head it's very
hard to pay attention
to that still small voice believing in
the difference you will make
begins with knowing your inner self your
in and knowing
that your unique inner wisdom is
powerful
listen to it make room every day for
what i call the download
and setting aside the to-do list and the
head
noise and just listen
so what is your inner voice saying to
you right now
besides when is she going to finish her
i invite you to take a moment and listen
and record
a voice note on your smartphone
when this talk is over and capture that
get accustomed to listening to your own
smooth voice the voice of your heart and
capture
that each time without judgment and
without all the noise from your head
it is it telling it is telling you
something important
and at the end of the week with all of
these notes you've captured review them
do you see a pattern
do use any particular message really
stand out
so that's all i have to say about belief
let's move on to the next topic
in our three points the r in bra
stands for resilience
resilience is basically the ability to
get up
one more time than you've been knocked
down in its simplest form
it's easy to say and it takes being
brave
it takes courage it takes knowing
yourself
well enough that you don't believe the
fake news that your own
inner your own head tells you about what
other people think of you
this is the antidote to imposter
syndrome by the way
it means not succumbing to imposter
syndrome it means
that feeling it means overcoming that
feeling that once people find out who
you really are they won't support you
anymore
resilience takes knowing the warning
signs of burnout
of knowing when you are just surviving
and not thriving
it takes courage to take time
for self-care for fueling your brain and
your body
in the best possible way and resilience
is the courage to say at the end of each
day
i will try again tomorrow
in our five day online challenge called
that we call flame proof
which is another word for personal
resilience i
walk you through the five steps that
could change your life
and not only help you but help your team
a rock star senior engineer recently did
the program and
wrote this to me just yesterday
i was stuck in a vicious burnout funk
and miss warstell's flame proof your
career reignited and energized my
motivation to focus on priorities and
goals
in my professional and personal life
considering the insightful lectures
combined with exercises that elicit
self-exploration
i highly recommend the course the
journey allowed me to develop the skills
necessary to evaluate my needs and
desires
such that i could identify and realize
career ambitions in a healthy fashion
and while ensuring i took care of myself
and my family
i was thrilled to hear that so for
anyone interested in more info on that
um please dm me on linkedin and even if
you're not interested
in the course that's fine i will please
dm me
on linkedin following the presentation i
would love to hear from you and connect
there
let's talk just a little bit more about
burnout for a minute
do you know the number one no i always
ask this of cyber people
do you know the number one sign of
burnout in an organization
it's cynicism right
cynical jokes in cyber security by the
way are the best but
cynicism is born from a wounded place
cynicism comes from life experience that
was traumatic or deeply disappointing
and we all have that
for many people cynicism is
the protective mechanism that's not
rational
but it goes like this if i expect that
people
are self-serving self-interested and
incompetent
i won't ever be sucker-punched by
trusting
someone who will only let me down
that's cynicism
have you ever heard that in your
organization
let me tell you this
the big problem with cynicism
is that it's contagious
cynicism its impact on organization is
like pouring gasoline on a campfire in a
bone-dry grass line
grassland during a chinook wind we are
most often willing to believe the
negative
and not shift perspective to look for
the positive
i have an exercise i call turn it and
turn it and
the next time you see something that
seems very much out of character
ask yourself this question what's up
with that don't get mad get curious
take the decision and turn it around and
examine every possible
angle of it so that you can understand
why the decision was made
the way it was all right quickly let's
talk about allyship i know i'm running
out of time here so i just took a look
at the clock
ally ship is the third component in bra
allyship but and uh uh and at the rsa
conference in 2018 we used b and ally as
our hashtag
it actually trended and and i thought
this was really pretty incredible
until somebody turned around and say you
know you can read that multiple ways
and i was like uh
right so i don't know if you see it
but we're talking about be an ally not
the other ways that you can read
that hashtag allyship is a new term and
a lot of meaning is poured into it by
different people
and you may not agree with some of it
here's how i use allyship very quickly
when a very well-known first century
jewish teacher walked the earth he was
asked the question what is the most
important law for us to keep
i'll paraphrase it like this the most
important law
law is to love the creator with all
you've got and the second most
important law is just like it and that
is to love your neighbor as yourself
so the attributes are of the creator
that we
all could we all possess and can
practice every day our mercy
graciousness
slow to anger kindness truthfulness
being forgiving compassionate and
just
that my friends is allyship
i want you to fill your cup with these
attributes
that you possess so that
you have the opportunity to share them
with the people around you
and on those days when it doesn't work
ask yourself
what's up with that
you know there is there's so much more i
could share with you i'd be happy to
connect with you more on linkedin i want
to just give a couple minutes here for
any questions that you may have
we are have just finished talking about
belief allyship
belief resilience and allyship
ask yourself what it would be like to
live in a world like that
it's possible if we all
we're our bra every day
if you find yourself struggling remember
there's a lot of resources to help you
with this
wear your bra every day imagine it
dream it do it
you can do this thanks for your time
do we have any questions i'm not quite
sure what we do next
thanks karen um let's see
i've been monitoring i didn't see any
questions so far
but uh if uh folks
in general want to post questions for
the ama
please feel free to do so now and i can
read them to karen
uh so we have a question from aaron
what should we be looking for in someone
who isn't reaching out
that needs help
well what should you be looking for in
someone who needs help
and they're not reaching out and um i i
would say
um well you've already seen something
because you believe they need help
and they're not reaching out um and your
allyship in that situation is one i
think of kindness right
so when you can reach out to someone and
say hey
i just want to check in with you how
it's how's it going this just happened
to me
a couple of days ago because i had a tip
that someone really needed to hear
a word of kindness and they were at a
conference actually
and i texted them and said how's it
going
and i didn't hear back so i picked up
the phone and called them
and just said hey i've been thinking
about you and i really want to chat
how's it going
and so you can you know don't ever be
afraid
i think we all kind of have this
nervousness that we're poking our face
into something where we don't belong um
but you be brave you know the worst
thing that can happen is they
ask us to go away um
at least you've done your kindness part
to reach out i hope that helps
be sure to damn me on linkedin too if
you have any questions following up from
this i'll be
happy to answer anything that i get in
the next week or so
uh see we have another question from
slammer uh
do you have methods to rescue those that
have burnt out and left the community
wow um so
in the five-day online course and i'm
not here
trying to push that but one of the
things that i
emphasize in that is the one of the
reasons we burn out and i've been there
twice
so i'm kind of a slow learner sometimes
i guess
but um that one of the things that's
very helpful
is to know what you want and to be
willing to set the boundaries
around that that will help you make sure
that that happens
and to show to know in a in a very clear
way
that you're working every single week on
something that contributes to those
goals of yours that are very important
so as an example one of the goals that i
set for myself and it was an
important one for me to set and be very
explicit about
because i was always so busy working
which was
i would i create um
amazing experiences and memories with my
family and my loved ones
that means that every week i take time
uh if not every day but it's usually not
every day
um to do something about that goal
right even if it's making a great dinner
or whatever it's something that i'm
doing and i can tell myself at the end
of every week that i am working on the
things that are important to me
there's a lot more about that um in the
course but that's
one of the ways to do it is to know what
you want
and make sure that you're setting
boundaries that make sure that you can
do them
thanks see we have another question from
aaron
um yes what can we do to create a more
inclusive community
for underrepresented individuals
wow thank you for asking that question
um we have so much work to do
um tech is not tech is a place where
we're moving at a very very fast rate
and in order to move very quickly what
we tend to do is self-select people who
are like
us who think like us who make decisions
like us and
we have to be willing to be patient
for a process where communications of
diverse
ways of communicating whether a person
is neurodiverse or ethnically diverse or
gender diverse
how do we listen to them
how do we seek to understand because
it takes time to do that you will 100
percent
always get better solutions and better
decisions
if you take that time but it's
frustrating for us i think the number
one thing we can all do is learn
to slow down just a little bit i i
always kind of
use the phrase you know slow is smooth
and smooth as fast
take the time to be slow because you'll
go much faster in the long run
thank you i think we might have one more
question
uh oh we do
uh how can a company be more inclusive
to parents
i love that question um so
not just parents but also people who are
caring for elders
right because i did that five times
while i was in cyber security
um and uh i'm about to go back into
cyber security again for the first time
without children or
grown-ups to take care of um
having on-site child care wow like
if i had a way if if i had to go into
the office how i could have
um child care now in work from home
we've really highlighted how hard it is
for people who
are caring for family members at home
to be able to concentrate and focus and
i think we just
we fundamentally have to change the way
we think about the workplace and
um having those conversations those are
fairly brave conversations to have
um i think people are going to be a
little bit afraid that they'll be seen
as asking for special accommodations or
whatever but
um you know start if it's not happening
in your workplace already start the
conversation
and and and let's be really clear
about how hard work from home has been
for anyone who is it's been hard for
everybody
in different ways but for family members
it's been particularly difficult
and we lost we lost 10 percent
of the women in the tech workforce
due to work from home during the
pandemic
it set us back it set us back
dramatically
in terms of any kind of progress towards
equity in the workplace
because so many people had to drop out
it's
i think the thing right now is just to
make sure that the conversation doesn't
doesn't go silent about how important it
is for us to make sure that we value
families
um extended families and you know every
variety of family
while we're trying to all make a great
tech workplace
thank you for asking the question
okay still i see a little bit more
activity in the channel so i'll see if
there's another question coming
huh we do have another question uh so
this is from punk coder
uh how do we bring along management that
are not fully on track
with dei oh yeah
i i don't have a great answer for that
um and if you just take a look at what's
happening
at uh some of the
big tech firms right now well even
this has been going on for for decades
but the
the um the culture does not favor
diversity equity and inclusion just as i
talked about and
some companies are making a difference
intel is a good one vmware is a good one
right there's companies that are really
working on it for those companies that
are not
there is cultural shift that needs to be
happening and the only way that's going
to really really change
is when the message is coming down from
the top
it's very hard to do culture change from
the bottom or from anywhere in the
middle
so my suggestion is
it's conversation it has to be really
brave conversation if you've got
individuals who they may have a blind
spot let me give you some hope with that
i had two managers one time this wasn't
about diversity equity and inclusion but
i had two
managers both of them women directors in
my organization
who needed to me to hear something they
had to say to me
because i was interfering in their jobs
in a way that was making it hard for
them to lead their organization
i was blind to this they sat down one
day and they said we have to talk to you
and they very bravely kind of laid it on
the line is like this is what you're
really really good at we want you to do
more of that we want you to stop
doing this because it's making our jobs
hard
and i was blown away by
their courage and
um and we were able to work out that
difference because they were truly
speaking to my blind spot
so you kind of have to gauge the person
if this is
something where they just it's a belief
system
and they bel they actually don't believe
in dei
then you're going to have a harder time
because
poking at somebody's belief systems is
is a
very difficult thing to do but if you
have someone
who just has a blind spot and you can
shed some light on that i think that's a
very good thing to do
i hope that helps it's hard when that
that's the case
and i guess i have a brief follow-up to
that um
do you think uh how do you think the
approach for di
like can that look different at
different companies
well yeah i think
when you when you say dei it means
different things to different people
right and having an a
at the end of the day here's what i
found most helpful about dei
at a high level when intel made the
decision
that they were their internal workforce
was going to reflect their customer base
and demographics
they got very intentional about how they
were going to
um rebalance their workforce
and one of the things that they found
as they were doing that and this is
where our phrase about when we lift one
all rise
comes from is from the intel experience
because when intel did that
what one of the things that happened was
you know they had 50 say they have 50
white men in the organization and what
they found
was for the first time in the
organization their voice was being heard
the big benefit of inclusion
is not that we're hitting certain
numbers
the benefit of inclusion is that
everybody's voice gets heard no matter
who they are and there isn't
a weight given to somebody because
of a particular class gender
whatever that might be that they're and
we don't really have
meritocracy we haven't achieved that
i think we even have a podcast out there
called meritocracy is dead
but but the truth of it is is that if
you can
uh this is the practice that has to
start with each one of us and this is
why on our podcast we talk about making
the workplace
making the tech workplace better from
the inside out the inside is here
we all can do a piece and the way we can
do the piece
is to make sure that we learn how
to help other voices be heard
and you know dei
is driven by lots of different motives
and lots of different pieces of the
organization
it's going to be different things in
different places but at the end of the
day
it is how do we show up in my book
allyship
dei shows up as how do we show up with
kindness mercy graciousness
being slow being patient right being
just
being compassionate how do we show up
with that every day how do we fill
our own cup so that we're able to fill
other people's cup
um every single day with the way
we come to work i think that's how we're
going to get there
to be honest grassroots thank you so
much that was
that was yeah those were this is a great
discussion
well thank you thank you so much for
having me i'm really
grateful to have the chance to be here
and um please please please connect with
me
on linkedin i would love to hear from
you
thank you very much thanks