hi everyone this is extracting all the
azure passwords and i'm carl fossen
so a little bit of background on myself
here uh practice director at netspy i've
been with the company for about 10 years
now during that time i've worn a number
of different hats including pen tester
social engineer password cracker uh
currently cloud enthusiast i lead up our
cloud pen testing team out of our
portland oregon office along with being
a cloud enthusiast who works in a number
of different clouds primarily azure but
also aws gcp and a handful of other
different clouds that we end up running
into i'm also a bit of a cloud
enthusiast as a private pilot my wife
and i like to spend time flying around
the oregon area
in 79 piper warrior which is kind of a
fun plane to fly
outside of that i've spent about the
last year or so here working on
penetration testing azure for ethical
hackers with david okioti
it's a book that's going to be published
on pact publishing in october
and uh it's a fun book to write and
contains a lot of information that we're
actually going to be talking about today
in regards to
extracting azure passwords
you can find any code examples for tools
that i work on out of the netspy github
i also like to blog on the netspy blog
and you can find me on twitter at
kfossen
so today we're going to learn about
extracting credentials out of microsoft
azure but before we get into that we
should really baseline on
what azure is just so that everybody's
got common terminology to understand and
understand how the platform itself works
we'll just go over some basics here real
quick
so uh at its core azure is the cloud
provider from microsoft so it's a lot of
microsoft services that are integrated
within the overall microsoft ecosystem
and everything's being brought up into
the cloud so things that you've
traditionally seen on premise like
virtual machines applications
anything that you know hosts an
application or interacts with data
somehow is now being moved into the
cloud so we're going to talk about a
number of those services today
during the talk but here's just a
handful of kind of common services that
we run into in the azure cloud
so one thing to keep in mind with the
azure cloud is that at certain role
levels and we'll talk about how roles
are applied in an azure tenant
but at certain role levels passwords are
everywhere there's clear text passwords
that can be pulled out of individual
services and today we're going to talk
about different ways that we can pull
those out of those services
so uh to understand an azure tenant we
need to kind of understand what items
are comprising that tenant so the azure
active directory tenant or azure ad
tenant is the core of identity for azure
cloud so
as that core you have security
principles which you can think of as
users and those users are assigned roles
so the principles themselves can be made
up of your more traditional users
carl netspy.com something like that or
guest users where we could say carl
gmail.com where that's an external user
to that tenant that's been invited to be
a part of that azure active directory
tenant
so uh those are more traditional users
typically assigned to
specific profiles and daily use accounts
there's managed identities that can be
either system assigned which means it's
tied to a direct resource or user
assigned meaning it's created within a
subscription and can be assigned to
multiple different resources if need be
these manage identities are identities
that are tied to a specific resource so
let's say a virtual machine or an app
services application where that specific
resource needs to access something in
the azure tenant and uses that managed
identity to access that there's a number
of different ways that we can get
authentication for that managed identity
primarily through uh requesting tokens
but those identities are typically used
within the azure active directory tenant
to access other items within a
subscription
and
that's a security principle that could
have a role
there are service principles that not to
be confused with security principles but
service principles are typically
referred to as application accounts so
you can see things like enterprise
applications that may have what are
called app registrations that are
considered service principles these both
can be assigned roles within the azure
active directory tenant and we can use
credentials from these service
principles to authenticate to the tenant
so
a lot of different types of security
principles here at the core we just need
to understand that a security principle
can have a specific role in a tenant and
that role dictates what we're able to
access
so at
the
subscription management group type of
level those roles that are being applied
are typically owner contributor reader
kind of as the three primary items that
we're seeing owner being somebody that
is able to
assign resources
specific
applications of roles so as an owner i
could assign somebody reader rights to a
specific resource group or resource or
subscription at contributor we have
rights to modify individual resources
that are in the platform
the owner also has these rights as well
and they're able to make changes to any
of those resources
the least interesting of these is reader
which is something that we're actually
granted quite often during an azure pen
test where we have read-only access
we're not allowed to make any changes to
any resources we can't assign any rights
to any resources to any of the security
principles
it's literally just you can read
information about these resources so
pretty straightforward on the reader
there are additional kind of special
roles that can be applied at multiple
different levels here uh
a lot of these are really service
service specific or application specific
uh depending on the needs of the
[Music]
service principle or security principle
that needs access to something maybe
it's log analytics contributor and that
user needs specific access to log
analytics resources that's more of a
service application specific role that
might be applied here
and these roles can be applied at a
number of different levels so at the
highest level the management group where
there are containers of individual
subscriptions that might be under a
management group all the way down to
individual resources so somebody could
technically have reader on an individual
resource and it's the only resource in
the overall subscription or management
group that they have access to
so a number of different ways that we
can apply these one thing to note here
is that these roles are at what we would
say the subscription level as compared
to
the azure active directory tenant level
so on the previous slide here we talked
about the azure ad tenant being the core
of the identity that has a whole set of
different roles that are applied at the
tenant level versus the individual
subscriptions or management groups for
today's talk we're actually just going
to be focusing on we'll say subscription
level contributor and we'll talk about
that in the next slide here but we can
assume that uh we as an attacker have
contributor
on the specific subscription that we're
working with here now
some people will say yeah but that's
that's basically admin on the
subscription in some ways people are
correct in saying that a contributor
does have rights to make modifications
to any of the resources that are in that
subscription but for the most part we're
seeing developers engineers anybody
that's doing anything on a day-to-day
basis in the platform having the
contributor role for the subscription
so in a way yeah you are basically admin
i think it's more on par with local
admin on your own workstation or shared
local admin across multiple workstations
on a traditional active directory
environment
but you know with contributor we do have
some power here and as i mentioned
before we'll use that power to extract
credentials out of here
there are other roles that we could talk
about today that do have access to some
of these either application specific
credentials or individual services that
we can extract credentials from
we don't really have time to dive into
every single one of these uh we'll
mention a couple of these as we go
throughout here but just keep in mind
that
contributor by itself isn't the only
credential or role that you might need
or have access to that allows you to get
access to credentials there are other
options out there as well
so first things first let's talk about
how we manually access credentials we
can go service by service and utilize
either the portal cli powershell
commandlets anything like that to do
one-off collections so we could go to a
storage account like we have in the
screenshot here
and take a look at the key that's
associated with that storage account
that's fine but as a pen tester i want
to be efficient
i really want to spend more of my time
focusing on you know exploiting the
vulnerabilities and diving deeper into
the environment versus just manually
going out and getting credentials so
what we want to do is automate this
process
and conveniently that's what we've done
with get ac passwords so get ac
passwords is a powershell function
that's used to automate the collection
of any passwords that are stored within
the azure cloud it's part of the
microburst tool set and it's tool that i
wrote to really just automate that whole
process
you know in the past we would more
passively just gather credentials
through configurations that we would go
through the portal
there are some active
tasks that we'll talk about that the get
a z passwords function actually
automates for us so that we don't have
to manually do these attacks every
single time so it really helps automate
this whole process and what would
normally take
we'll say about an hour to go through an
entire subscription and get all of the
credentials out service by service it
can do that in a matter of minutes so
very convenient for us from an attacking
standpoint and allows us to audit any of
the credentials we have access to
so can be found on the netspy github
under the microburst repo
and we'll be talking about a little bit
more today
so the first of these services that
we're going to talk about
under the azure umbrella here is key
vaults so pretty simply key vaults store
keys
it's a service for storing credentials
be it keys secrets certificates we've
seen all sorts of different things that
get put into key vaults as a way to
protect that within the azure
infrastructure now
there are additional protections that
you can apply
to the individual keys themselves we'll
talk about that in the access policies
but for the most part key vaults are
really just used to store sensitive
information and retrieve it
as a specific
service principle or security principle
in the azure tenant
so uh
dumping the credentials from the key
vault service manually we can just go
through the portal or utilize
cli or powershell command let's anything
like that to query the individual
secrets keys certificates anything like
that from the key vaults themselves
within the portal this is really simple
we can see here that we were able to
access the super secret password secret
and if we hit the show secret value
there it's a password value and we'd be
able to return that directly in the
portal like i said this is not the most
convenient way to gather all of these
credentials so we like to automate that
with the get ac passwords
but you know from the portal it's
actually really easy to get these
credentials out
that is if you have rights to read those
credentials so as i mentioned there are
additional policies that you can apply
to key vaults to restrict the access to
the secret data that's being stored
within the key vault
this is done through something called an
access policy and access policies are
tied to individual
principles as we can see here as the
select principle we can select
individual security principles that we
apply
the key vault permissions to so this
could be list get create modify anything
like that and that's per individual type
of
permissions so this is key secret
certificate we can modify this
individually to allow somebody to get
and list these specific keys secrets and
certificates as needed this is a really
handy thing within azure to limit the
scope of who has rights to access the
key vault keys however
anyone that has rights to modify
be it contributor or
key vault contributor permissions on the
key vault
they would have rights to modify these
access policies so we as an attacker if
we have contributor level rights on that
key vault we are actually able to modify
these access policies to give ourselves
access we'll talk about that in a second
there is one additional restriction i
want to talk about here and it does
apply to some of the other services but
we don't really need to extend it is
the private endpoint connections so what
you can do with key vaults is you can
restrict access to the key vault to a
private endpoint or individual virtual
networks or just selected networks that
you want to restrict access to the vault
for which is a great control to put in
place i prevent somebody from the
internet going and talking to your key
vault to pull down keys and secrets
if you're utilizing uh private endpoint
connections that really gives you an
extra step ahead against any attackers
that get access to a principal that
might have rights to read
the actual credentials here now from a
contributor level attacker's perspective
here we could technically change this
from private endpoints over to all
networks but that would be a pretty
major state change and you know if i'm
working in a client environment i don't
want to expose their key vault out to
the internet and potentially allow
somebody to gain access to that so not
something that we would really recommend
doing but
from an attacker standpoint that is
something that they might consider
so from a get a z passwords perspective
we're going to utilize the az powershell
modules to automate the whole process of
identifying all the key vaults and then
gathering all of the key vault keys
secrets certificates out of that
and for each of the key vaults that are
in a subscription we'll take a look at
the current access policy that we talked
about on the previous slide here to see
if our current user has the ability to
get or list
the keys secrets anything like that out
of the key vault if we don't have access
to that what we'll do is snapshot that
access policy
modify it to add our specific user and
then extract everything that we need to
extract out of the key vault
then once we've dumped everything out of
there we'll go ahead and return that
access policy back to its original state
kind of a sneaky trick but it's actually
really handy if we have contributor
rights to modify these things as if
we're trying to access keys that we
don't have access to that might actually
cause more alerts than just changing the
access policy temporarily to give
ourselves access to those keys and
secrets
so next up we'll talk about app services
and app services is kind of a larger
umbrella for the overall hosting of web
applications apis function
logic apps all of these kind of have
their own little
elements within them but overall they
kind of work the same under app services
the app services umbrella everything has
configurations for the service itself
these configurations include things like
connection strings for connecting to
databases uh
any
passwords used to upload uh code for the
app service so you know if you think a
traditional iis web application moving
that up to the cloud
you need to be able to access that app
service up in the cloud in order to do
that and upload files
you can either use ftp
there's a web management portal as well
we're able to pull those credentials
we'll see that on the next slide
additionally there's access to just the
source code itself
function app files we're actually
finding quite frequently people will
hard code credentials into those
likewise with logic apps we might be
able to extract credentials out of those
and then just the app services
configuration service where we can apply
the same configuration across multiple
different app services and just maintain
that same configuration that's going to
store things like connection strings and
potentially have stuff that we can pull
out of there
so from a get a z passwords perspective
we're actually just going to be pulling
out things from get published profile
here but doing this manually within the
portal we can see that there's a link
within the app services application to
get a published profile and while i've
redacted all of the passwords that are
in here we can see in the text file here
that we've got usernames and passwords
for web deployments for ftp deployments
and database connection strings that
might be in there
this is a just a nice handy one-off if
you happen to get access to the portal
and want to quickly get credentials for
app services the getting published
profiles actually
pretty straightforward and a quick way
to get a couple of credentials there
so to
automate that we'll talk about how we're
going to pull those out with get ac
passwords did mention the ftp and web
management credentials one thing i did
want to note about this is that if you
browse to the actual forward slash basic
auth endpoint for the scm which is the
kudu environment for managing these app
services environments
you can just use the username and
password that was pulled out from the
settings here on the previous page this
is really handy for persistence as you
can keep those credentials and i don't
frequently see people rolling those
credentials over so if we get access to
those settings and those credentials we
could potentially maintain access
through this kudu environment through
this basic auth endpoint here
on the scm so you can see netspy.scm
azure websites.net and if we
authenticate against that basic auth
endpoint that allows us to maintain
access to kudu which is
there's a web shell there there's file
browsing there's all sorts of different
ways that we can persist in that app
services environment uh quick thanks to
mcomi uh who does storm spotter he's the
one who initially pointed me
to this kind of interesting bypass here
so uh one thing to note we talked about
managed identities and you know how
those are used in azure active directory
tenant
app services are frequently configured
with managed identities and those
managed identities are used to allow
access to key vaults so we talked about
key vault access policies
these managed identities would be added
to the access policy for the key vault
in order to read keys secret
certificates anything that you might
need within an azure app services
application
so from
an attacker's perspective if we're able
to get control over an app services
application we can generate a token for
that managed identity and have that
scope to
the management apis and the key vault
apis and use that
to go ahead and
take the rest apis to pull out all of
the key vault contents we do have a
couple of automation scripts within
microburst to automate that whole
process with the get a z key vault keys
rest and secrets rest so that you can
pull out all of those key vault contents
that we talked about in the previous set
of slides here
so something to keep in mind if you get
access to a managed identity in app
services
so now with that detour out of the way
here let's talk about how we automate
that uh really it's just getting each of
the az web apps or app services apps and
piping that into getting the published
profile this is really straightforward
it's just a couple of lines powershell
and then we'll parse the json output
that comes back with those publishing
profiles to get those credentials out
for the output
next up we've got automation accounts
and this is one of my favorite parts of
the overall uh
get a z passwords presentation here
i'm a big fan of automation accounts
there's a lot of different things that
we can do with these and a lot of
interesting things that end up getting
stored here
so from a service perspective automation
accounts are meant to run serverless
code up in azure to automate your
day-to-day tasks so management of
systems management of your active
directory tenant just really managing
all of the things that you need to
manage without having that running on
somebody's desktop you've got your
serverless environment where you could
schedule these runbook uh code books to
just run whenever you need them so if
you need to shut down all of the virtual
machines you know during a certain
window
you can automate that with automation
accounts it's super convenient uh run
book codes typically in python or
powershell and it's just a nice easy
lightweight scripting environment to run
serverless code so the platform itself
stores credentials for the automation
accounts
in credential variables i can also
accidentally have those included in the
source code itself for the run books
there's also run as accounts
that can be used within the runbooks so
you can think of that almost like a
managed identity
automation accounts are moving towards
using managed identities it's kind of an
in-progress thing i think it's still
technically in preview
but that's going to eventually replace
these run as accounts and we'll talk
about how we can use these run as
accounts
uh
there is something important to note
here with the run as accounts if you're
going to use those in an automation
account
by default those are set as a
contributor on the subscription so if
we're able to extract the credentials
for that run as account we'll have
contributor rights in that subscription
but typically you need contributor in
order to extract those anyways so we'll
talk about that a little bit more in a
second here
additionally you can also access key
vaults from automation accounts kind of
like how we talked about
the
app services accessing key vaults with
tokens there's similar things that we
can do with either run as accounts or
additional credentials that are supplied
to the automation account the bottom
line is typically we see key vaults
being accessed from automation accounts
to pull in secret data let's say there's
a
shared password or a key that's being
shared across things that need to be
automated that might need to be pulled
from a key vault first into the
automation account run book and we might
be able to abuse that run book to then
get access to the key
so uh for the clear text credentials
themselves that get stored in a runbook
this is really easy to audit if you've
got portal access and just use the view
within the portal here we can view the
source code for the runbook and
potentially pull out clear text
credentials
it's really simple you can read the code
they're right there
it happens more often than you'd like to
admit but
something to look out for there
additionally if we want to pull out the
platform level passwords or any of the
run as credentials we need to run a
custom run book to extract those so the
run book being powershell code here that
we're looking at and we won't go line by
line here but essentially what we're
doing is we're casting the available
credentials in this case there's a test
credential we can also see in the
sidebar there's a carl credential stored
there
but what we can do is cast that
credential out to a variable and write
that out in the output additionally we
can take the runes certificate by
getting the individual certificate
itself from the environment and then
casting that out to a base64 string
which we could then copy out and save
elsewhere
so in order to do that we would use
what's called the test pane so we can
see here just above the code there's a
little box that says test pane and this
is the view that we're going to look at
here so in the test pane you can
run your automation account run book and
that will output any of those stored
credentials output that run as
certificate here that we can copy off of
here
and this does not get logged as the jobs
within the automation account now you
might be looking at this and going oh
yeah there's there's clear text
credentials that are being returned back
to the screen i hope these aren't being
logged anywhere
if you're running this as an actual job
yes that would happen but if you're
running this in the test pane here this
never ends up in any of the logs all
that you see in the logs is that the
run book was saved and that the test
pane job was run but
the actual output never comes back there
so it is kind of a stealthier way to get
these credentials manually but it's also
not the most uh
it's uh
you know
it's a little slow to go through all of
this i've spent more time than i'd like
to admit waiting for automation runbooks
to complete so
you know automating this through get ac
passwords is much faster
so speaking of when we do that we want
to encrypt all of that output so
when we're
potentially outputting clear text
credentials that might you know contain
actual credential data here we don't
want somebody with reader level access
to be able to read the output of these
jobs and potentially get access to data
that they shouldn't have access to so we
can see on the left here the before and
on the right the after
of what our encryption method looks like
so what we utilize is a certificate that
gets uploaded with the run book and we
keep the private key on the get az
password side so that we're able to
decrypt everything on our end here but
we'll encrypt all of that output
in that output pane here and then clean
up after ourselves after everything's
done so that nobody can actually decrypt
that output that is put out into the
jobs output here this is just a much
cleaner way of getting output back from
the automation account itself and it
protects everybody from accidentally
exposing passwords
so something to kind of keep in mind as
we're utilizing automation accounts and
getting credentials out of there
so like we talked about with the app
services and getting access to key
vaults
there were some issues with runes
accounts being able to read key vaults
and some permissions related items that
microsoft addressed with the cve back in
2019 but we put together a
run book
automation script called get a z key
vaults automation within microburst to
help automate that whole process of
extracting credentials from a key vault
utilizing automation account run books
that could be a whole other talk in
terms of kind of how all of that gets
orchestrated within the runbook itself
but just something to kind of keep in
mind if you get access to an automation
account and want to access
an attached key vault there are tools in
microburst that you might be able to use
there to automate that process
so uh getting all of these credentials
out with get ac passwords we've talked
about all of this kind of as a whole but
for each automation account we basically
list out any available credentials run
as accounts we're going to upload a
malicious run book i say it's malicious
but we're the ones running it it's just
going to be extracting credentials here
would you randomly name these so if you
happen to find evidence of a randomly
named run book in your subscription
something like 15 characters long upper
and lower case letters
that may indicate get a z passwords was
run in that automation account
but once we upload and run that run book
that will extract those credentials
encrypt everything on the fly and
decrypt those credentials client-side
once we pull the output from the
automation account job
then we'll go ahead and clean up those
automation run books after we've
completed everything
one important to note
thing to note here if you're going to
run git ac passwords is do not use ctrl
c while that function is running
particularly
during the automation account phase if
you control c while an automation
account runbook is still running that
will leave that resident uh randomly
named runbook up in
the automation account and we don't want
to leave anything behind and that may
potentially uh you know just
leave behind indicators of compromise
anything like that so you want to make
sure that you clean up any kind of
orphaned run books that end up there if
you control c while uh the function's
running for get ac passwords
so for storage accounts uh
storage accounts are pretty
straightforward they store things it's
file storage in the azure cloud you can
think of it as kind of like aws s3 for
those that are a little bit more
well-versed in aws
but for the azure platform now unlike
aws s3 the storage accounts in azure
also have
different file storage types so we have
blob table queue file all of those are
different ways of storing either data or
just files flat files anything like that
we're really going to be focusing on
keys that can be used to access any of
those different types of storage items
here
but in general storage accounts store
files
you can think of it that way and in
order to access these we have keys we
took a look at this earlier at the very
beginning of how you would be able to
extract keys out of a storage account on
the very first couple of slides here
talking about
getting the keys for individual storage
accounts from the portal
additionally you could go through
available files in things like file
services or blob storage where there
might be clear text credentials in
a configuration file anything like that
that's not really an easy thing to
automate so we don't automate pulling
down credential files or anything like
that with get ac passwords but as a pen
tester you might want to keep in mind
reviewing individual files once you get
to a point of contributor or storage
account contributor in an azure
subscription
we do frequently find configuration
files that are hanging out in storage
accounts which lead to other credentials
but for our purposes here we're really
going to focus on getting these storage
account keys
these can be used with
the storage account explorer
there's a number of different ways that
we can use these keys to get access to
the actual uh storage accounts
themselves and view some of those files
and persist potentially in that storage
account environment
one of these ways is with cloud shell
files so as i mentioned we can get
access to those keys access the
associated file shares for any cloud
shell file shares
typically these are going to start with
the letter cs and then some random
letters and numbers generated after that
these are file shares that are created
to run your cloud shell environment so
if you've ever used the azure portal
before and more specifically use the
cloud shell environment underneath that
you would have seen when you created the
cloud shell environment an option to
either select an existing storage
account or create a new storage account
typically when you create the new
storage account it creates that cs
prefixed file share storage account
within your subscription to store all of
these uh what i have seen in the past is
that uh
depending on the environment multiple
people might share the same cloud
cloud shell storage uh for each of their
different cloud shells this is
potentially really dangerous as anyone
who has contributor rights on that
storage account has rights to modify
those file systems
so if i as a user am using cloud shell
that's going to store uh
an img file which is an ext2 file system
up in a cloud console folder up in the
file shares what we can do as an
attacker is pull that img file down
mount that on a linux system
and either review any files so let's say
i store configuration scripts up in my
cloud shell environment that have
credentials in them
an attacker could potentially get access
to those additionally you can modify any
of these startup files for things like
bash or powershell to automatically run
commands when somebody logs into cloud
shell so as an attacker we download the
file mount the file system modify the
startup files to say add our user as an
owner on a subscription or
do some other types of malicious
commands here we re-upload that img file
up to the file share and the next time
that
victim user opens up their cloud shell
environment that executes those commands
in that victim's cloud shell this can be
potentially pretty dangerous uh you know
if i'm able to poison the cloud shell
account of a global administrator
account that would be an easy way for me
to escalate privileges
so uh we detailed all of this in a
netspy blog here that i've linked down
at the bottom but definitely something
to keep in mind uh we typically just
recommend don't use cloud shell
if you're going to use cloud shell make
sure you're locking down those file
shares to limit any potential exposure
there
so
dumping those storage accounts is really
really simple we just get a list of the
storage accounts and then for each
storage account we get the storage
account key i could probably cut this
down to like a two
maybe in powershell uh you could maybe
even just do a one-liner of get that and
pipeline it into the get storage account
key but really really simple uh super
easy to automate and it's really easy
for us from a persistence perspective
next up we've got azure container
registries so for those that are not
familiar with azure container registries
or acrs as i'm going to refer to them
going forward here
they are a
repository for any container images that
you might want to use either in azure
services like container instances or
azure kubernetes or aks which we'll talk
about next
but it's a service for storing all of
these images for any of those services
or potentially publicly exposing azure
registries so that
other people can get access to images
maybe intentionally you want to
have a docker image available for
somebody to use
that's what that service is for
so the passwords themselves can either
be found in container images what we
frequently see is service principle
credentials like we talked about way
back beginning might be stored in these
container images themselves
if you've got a kubernetes cluster and
don't want to deal with pulling secrets
down into these individual containers as
they get spun up it may just be easier
to bake in those credentials into the
container images this is not a good
practice but we frequently see this
happening so as an attacker we
frequently pull down those container
images and extract credentials out of
them
really only requires reader level
credentials
in that azure subscription to pull those
images down but we'll talk about that in
the next slide here
additionally there's uh container
registry admin credentials that can be
exported for persistence it's not a
guarantee that those will be in the
subscription but we can see here in the
portal that these are enabled for the
netspy container registry which is now
since gone but for demo purposes we
created one here that we had an admin
user enabled for
additionally you know talked about the
container images and how those are
quite often storing credentials in the
images themselves
uh
from a attacker's standpoint we just
pull the images down run the images with
whatever their base shell is do a print
env see what their environmental
variables are see what local files are
available there we'll frequently find
application configuration files
uh web.config files anything like that
that frequently extort or store clear
text credentials so definitely something
to look out for if you're pen testing
azure container registries
from a get a z passwords perspective
we really just care about getting those
admin credentials that we showed at the
bottom of this slide right here so that
just gets a list of all of the container
registries and then pulls any available
admin credentials for the container
registry itself much like storage
accounts this is really really simple
potentially could be a one-liner if you
really wanted to cut the code down a
little bit but a very simple way to
potentially get credentials out of the
platform once you're at contributor
level
so uh as a
service that is supported by acr's azure
kubernetes service is
just kubernetes clusters in the cloud so
if you want to run kubernetes up in
azure azure kubernetes is probably your
best bet
there are multiple different ways that
you could potentially do that with
virtual machines and other things but we
don't need to get into that here what
i'm frequently seeing in azure
environments is the aks service being
used to run clusters
so the passwords themselves are
frequently found in
the cluster vms themselves we'll talk
about how service principal credentials
and managed identities are utilized
there
uh additionally there's admin
credentials that can be exported for
persistence for managing the cluster
itself so these are the cube config file
uh credentials that we can export to use
locally to
manage the kubernetes
cluster potentially remotely depending
on how things are configured
for the virtual machines themselves the
service principles or manage identity
tokens you have to choose one or the
other when you set up that aks cluster
and uh the service principal credentials
end up getting stored in clear text in
an azure.json file and manage identity
tokens we have to generate those every
time but we'll talk about how we do that
in a minute
so if we have portal access for
something and want to just quick
generate
the kube config files via cloud shell
you can just use the azcli uh within
cloud shell to add the aks cluster
credentials into your current system uh
one thing to look out for if you do get
access to cloud shell files like we
talked about earlier with storage
accounts is looking out for kube config
files in those img files those can get
stored there and they can last for a
while so you might be able to pull live
kubernetes credentials out of those
cloud shell files
super convenient from an attacker's
standpoint
but for more of a manual export here if
we add those kubernetes credentials here
and then just cat out the coop config
file here we can just copy that out of
cloud shell and grab that at that time
you can also use dash admin to specify
as a cluster admin versus a regular
cluster user
not a huge difference there are
minor differences there i'd recommend
using dash admin if you're going to go
this route but
besides point
we automate this with get ac passwords
by grabbing both the regular admin and
the regular user credentials as part of
this whole process but in general we get
a list of all of the clusters we
generate a token to use with the rest
apis this is the one spot where
excuse me where we typically differ a
little bit
from the standard powershell commandlets
here we're going to use some of the rest
apis which is just a little bit
different than kind of the standard
tools that we're going to use in get ac
passwords but
using that token we're going to pull
down the different cluster admin and
cluster user credentials in the kube
config format
if the cluster itself is set up with a
service principle we're going to
invoke the azvms s
vm run command oh it's a mouthful there
basically it's a virtual machine scale
set that's supporting that cluster and
that's able to expand and contract and
you know spin up different node pools
anything like that for aks
what we want to do with that virtual
machine scale set is cut out that
azure.json file that stores that service
principle credential alternatively if
it's managed identity instead of cutting
out that file we'll just make a request
out to the metadata service and pull
back that metadata token
and get access to any tokens that we
need there for the managed identity
so for the demo here i'm going to use a
video that i recorded from a sample
environment here but this is running get
a z passwords you can see here at the
top that i've imported the microburst
module we're going to run git az
passwords with modify policies as yes
and export certificates as yes meaning
we're going to
export any of the certificates that are
available in physical format into an
individual file so we can see we wrote
out democert.pfx
additionally for any access policies we
will modify those in line here to give
ourselves access to any of the key
vaults keys secrets certificates
anything like that as we need them
so i do have this
pretty sped up here we have a 10x speed
here but i'd say in general for an
average subscription usually just takes
a handful and say maybe five minutes at
the most to export all of those
credentials
so we can see here there was a pfx file
that was created and an authenticate as
ps1 file here which we can potentially
use to authenticate as a run as account
and we can see all of these credentials
that we outputted to out grid view
this is a handy way to export all of
these credentials i'd also recommend
just using export csv instead to have
everything out to a csv you could just
copy everything out of here instead
that's a little bit different but we can
see in the output here things like aks
service principle here we can see the
client secret that was attached to
that service principle along with access
keys cosmos db which didn't even talk
about
storage accounts all sorts of different
stuff that gets output there
so real quick here we'll just talk about
a privilege escalation that we were able
to identify in azure utilizing to get az
passwords
function here but basically what we were
able to do was use git az passwords to
get the run as
account for an automation account
via the log analytics contributor role
previously the log analytics contributor
role allowed star permissions on all
automation accounts which allowed us to
then
export any automation account run as
certificates
and go through that process of getting
the run as account which is a full
contributor
on the subscription by default and
having that run as account we're then
able to escalate our privileges it's a
mild privilege escalation
log analytics contributor did have a
fair number of
you know rights in that role itself and
escalating up to contributor was just a
small jump up to full contributor but it
was technically a privilege escalation
microsoft recently addressed this in
august they actually removed the
automation account star permissions they
temporarily had a disclaimer here saying
that it did allow for the privilege
escalation here but they recently
cleaned that up
so a quick thanks here uh for our
microburst contributors here jake josh
thomas uh they've all helped contribute
to microburst and add things to uh
the platform here
uh
the slide uh design assistance here from
sofia netspy she was responsible for the
microburst with the uh knife there for
attacking the cloud and mentioned mcomi
here already for the kind of basic auth
login hack so thanks for that
and our last slide here just a couple of
different links to include here
for netspy github the blog and some of
the specific blogs that we talked about
today
so you can find me on twitter at kfossen
and feel free to reach out with any
questions
let me know if there was anything i can
help clarify here otherwise thanks