okay man how are you ken
hey i'm doing good i'm here
you made it
yeah my isp fell over a few minutes
before the talk was due to start bad day
okay no problem no problem
so your talk is amazing i think that i
don't i'm not going to to present you or
something like that
i let you present yourself on the talk
and everything uh i really want to thank
you very much for being here in
particular space in akubari this is like
our second year uh
we took a lot of effort to prepare all
these stocks here so
thank you so much for being here
um sorry for this swap of the talks
we save you
and it was amazing
uh well ken uh this is your stage
have fun and okay
we are
all eyes and ears okay good so i've got
a talk today uh that's based on about
the last three years of research where
we've had the privilege of having access
to a number of airplanes and being able
to spend time doing security research so
let me share
my slide deck and let's get started
shall we uh it's one of the most fun
things i've done for a very long time
but what i want to do is really look at
what's the reality what's the hype what
do we know so hopefully you can see my
slide deck there who are we well first
of all i'm a pilot uh i'm not a very
good pilot though but i have colleagues
who are also pilots some private pilots
some commercial pilots so we have a
current boeing 747 pilot on our team and
that's been really helpful because it
helps us understand how commercial
aviation works whereas my knowledge is
mostly private aviation
we have a lot of people on the team we
spend a lot of time working on planes
that's us on the right in 747 we'll talk
about that in a minute
one really important point from me
is that we have to be super responsible
even more responsible than any other
industry perhaps outside healthcare
because disclosure in aviation is
complicated and difficult and one of the
challenges about that is the media
doesn't really understand the separate
domains on board an aircraft it's going
to take a long time to get
vulnerabilities fixed because aircraft
is certified you can't just apply a
patch it has to go through testing it
has to be approved it has to be rolled
out through a complex ecosystem you
can't hack the plane from the infra
entertainment system it doesn't work
like that uh domains so the primary
domain the one that's most interesting
to us is the aircraft control domain
that's bit that has all the controls the
uppy downey lefty righty engines and
things
you have the aisd which is for cabin
crew particularly which contains
communication protocols for passenger
systems and then you have the bit that
we've all experienced so the passenger
and information entertainment so
in-flight inflate entertainment and
services domain that's where there's
some fun stuff to be found as well but
these domains are separate the acd does
not touch the aisd
there's also a lot of connections out
there so this is where things get quite
interesting a lot of data goes to and
from airplanes now and that started to
expand the attack surface somewhat so in
the past where you had to physically be
in an airplane
they're an increasing number of vectors
to remotely compromise an airplane but
there are many many layers of security
and defense in the way
be very careful what anyone says about
vulnerabilities in airplanes in the
media
the media gets very excited and there
have been a lot of stories that did a
lot of damage not all of which were
based upon fact
but what's changed well
all of a sudden
maybe a little bit of silver lining from
the coronavirus pandemic is that a lot
of older aeroplanes have been retired
and the breakers yards
the boneyards are backed up they have
too much work on
so we had a really interesting
opportunity to work with a breakers yard
where they would bring a plane in and it
would be sat there for months and months
before they could get to parting it out
and breaking it up and we arranged to
have access to these aeroplanes we could
power them up we could light the engines
we could put ground power on and we
could do pen testing on real aeroplanes
without any fear of causing problems for
those aeroplanes in the future because
they were going to be scrapped
now
there are some big caveats uh get bench
power for avionics is dangerous these
things work at 400 volts very high amps
you run the risk of powering these
things and blowing yourself up you can
throw yourself across the room some
older components use crts with large
power capacitors inside them make sure
you've discharged everything before you
touch anything and take good electrical
safety precautions
you will find unusual protocols so the
most common protocol you'll find will be
um
aaron 329
sorry 429 which is a very old protocol
it's quite easy to work with you can
decode it using a picoscope but decoding
is one thing injecting is another thing
altogether it's not easy uh in the
boeing triple seven you'll find uh our
inc 629 which is a different protocol
very hard and expensive to decode but as
we go towards the 787 uh the boeing um
uh and sorry various uh later air buses
you'll find in the abs a350 you'll find
aaron 664 which is an ethernet based
protocol interesting
what we're starting to find is
components are becoming available but
they're all very old so if you jump on
ebay you'll find some components being
parted out but they're all 10 15 20
years old anything that's still
certified and flyable is expensive but
there's fun stuff to be done so you can
jump in the cockpit of an old plane
power it up and start decoding traffic
and that's us working on airbus a320 a
little while ago
now what goes wrong well
sometimes it's surprising things so
there's uh an operator in the usa raven
there they were subject to ransomware
attack it looks like their maintenance
logs was encrypted and the backups
you cannot dispatch a plane into flight
if you cannot prove it as airworthy
which is why your maintenance logs are
really really important
no maintenance log because it's been
ransomed you don't fly
sadly that airline seems to have gone
bankrupt in the last year which is a
real shame other crazy things you'll
find
an electronic flight back they're
increasingly being used to save paper
it's fundamentally a tablet an ipad or
an android tablet electronic flight bag
used for lots of functions that i'll
talk about in a lot more detail in a few
minutes
but an efb
application crashed this is i think
2015. american airlines lost access to
the electronic flight bag apps with
which you could not depart you couldn't
get the charts up to tell you how to
take off and land and as a result the
efbs didn't work and thousands of
flights did not go that day it turned
out to be a corruption issue to do with
a duplicate chart for washington
national ronald reagan airport
another example this is much more recent
this was last year so southwest their
weather app on the electronic flight
bags failed not clear why but the
weather wasn't delivered and
1415 flights did not move they're all
delayed
you cannot just go on yahoo and get the
weather for a flight you have to have
very specific types of weather for an
aircraft to fly and land
other crazy things i'll go into this in
a lot more detail in a few minutes other
challenges around electronic flight bags
include the calculations you do for
takeoff and landing you might not be
aware that very few airplanes take off
with full power for reasons of carbon
dioxide saving engine wear and
efficiency you use a reduced power in
almost all takeoffs
there are consequences because those
calculations are done on the electronic
flight bag fortunately i believe there's
only been one fatal accident this is in
2004 from a 747 200
by mk airlines and through a
miscalculation in the electronic
calculations from the flight back the
uh pilots didn't put on enough power
they were tired they didn't recognize it
they went off the runway and sadly the
airplane crash caught fire more common
you see tail strikes happen where pilots
make miscalculations they over rotate
because they haven't got enough power
and they trash the back of the plane
that can be very dangerous too as well
other errors now when you start getting
access to planes you're going to find
lots of old stuff you'll be very
surprised how old some of the
technologies are in there but even so
you have to be careful this is a retired
747 that we were working on we had
access to the in-flight entertainment
system and flight attendants panel so
we're all over the um aisd
even so even though this plane was
retired some of the systems it talked to
were still live for other airplanes on
the fleet so be careful
don't spook the media into around
publishing very scary stories that upset
people but to give you an example of how
bad things can do it can be this is a
747 we were working on it last flew in
april 2020 we were working on it in june
2020 and on there we found the aisd
cabin management terminal so that's the
bit that the crew use for managing the
in-flight entertainment system and all
sorts of other things like meals and
messaging to the ground was running
windows nc service pack for
amazingly old it was quite fun actually
we'd uh i don't know about you i've
forgotten how to hack nt so we actually
had to go through a process of reminding
ourselves and come up with a viable
attack that's on our blog you can go and
read the full story of how we did this
successfully but yeah sometimes you find
very very old things
you'll also find floppy disks on planes
from time to time but she got with me
this is a navigational database from
boeing 747 that's in the cockpit you'll
find her updated over floppy disk which
is kind of cool you'll find pc cards in
the avionics bays the thing on the right
there that is a quick access recorder
uses a pc card uh fortunately this one
had an adapter to take it to cf so
compact flash and from that we could
download and extract the quick access
recorded data which was all the faults
on the plane and management logging
you'll also find some stuff you'll be
familiar with so you do find ethernet
but typically not on the uh control
domain you'll tend to find ethernet on
the
in-flight entertainment system and the
similar and you'll find crazy stuff so
that is the operating system disk it's a
solid state disk for
a reasonably recent uh cabin management
system i need to go back and get an
image of that disk before they take the
plane apart be fun to see what's there
where things get interesting is when we
start to see uh passion to wi-fi
some examples from the flight attendants
panel here the attendance panel is in
the galley in the in the accessible part
of the
cabin
obviously if you are messing around with
this i expect the crew to come and have
a very stern word with you and also bear
in mind that other passengers are likely
to take extreme exception to you
interfering with anything in the
airplane so don't do this without
permission please
what we discovered we could tamper with
the wi-fi we could get onto the backbone
network for the in-flight entertainment
system and we could knock things out
worst case so the ife stops working
people get annoyed because they can't
see movies but hey
basic learning we've reported these
vulnerabilities they've been fixed one
really fun one though are a 747 that was
23 years old its ife had been updated it
was only about three or four years old
we discovered when it lands it uploads
the latest movies uh from an amazon s3
bucket when the weight goes onto the
wheels of the undercarriage it enables a
wireless access point that connects to
ground systems and pulls the media for
the movies we discovered that the s3
bucket was read white and of course
managed to extract the credentials for
that from the in-flight entertainment
system
uh actually the vendor involved in this
was extremely cool they uh took our
report very quickly got the credentials
changed and changed the way that they
authentic authenticated to this system
it was great really really cool vendor
not like some vendors we've worked with
in aviation
also on the cabin management terminal we
discovered we could access a number of
plain text protocols and we could access
the input entertainment system and
potentially push new media so
what would you do does it really matter
maybe you could push some i don't know
pornography pretty unpleasant make for a
bad press story or perhaps more worrying
is put up a video showing the plane's
been hijacked that would really spook
the passengers would it spook passions
into doing something dangerous perhaps
so that's the biggest worry to me
typically the uplinks for the passenger
wifis uh
whilst they're vsat over the oceans over
the land they're typically a downward
facing lte or 4g downward link
we were looking at the router for it we
discovered credentials and guess what
they were written on the door of the
cupboard that the wi-fi router sat in so
that was pretty bad i'm sure they can do
better
in general what do we find well you find
a lot of old systems on planes you find
very old protocols and components you're
going to find very old hardware lots of
exposed physical interfaces but
physical security controls do work
if you're just messing around with
systems on a plane that's being used
you're going to get arrested
if it's not the cabin crew that um come
and um apprehend you it's going to be
another passenger i'd be very upset if
someone was
trying to hack a plane
the next step one of the projects we
want to look at is actually getting the
vsat terminal adapter out of the
overhead space in the 747 that's my
colleague dave who's up in the passenger
cabin in the roof and up there on a tray
is the terminal for the vsat no sign of
any ethernet it's all eric 429 but we're
going to get hold of that shortly and
see what we can do in terms of hardware
reverse engineering on the vsat that'll
be really interesting
now i've talked about electronic flight
bags these are an area of extreme
interest to me right now
what we discover is actually really
weak standards for uh
pilots using these devices many airlines
actively encourage the pilots to use
their efb tablets as a personal device
too i'm not sure about that we hear lots
of stories about doing personal email
watching netflix
browsing pornography and other really
unsavory things on a critical device
that's really important so
there are two types of efb broadly
there's a portable so that's one the
pilot takes home so an ipad or an
android tablet and an installed efb
which is physically bolted into the
airplane there are some halfway houses
so on the a350 there's a halfway that's
kind of sort of installed uh and there
are some others as well but
our primary interest is in portable efbs
because they leave the airplane
installed the fbs are protected behind
the cockpit door much much harder to get
access
so we spent time looking at performance
calculators and as i mentioned a moment
ago this is when you add power it tells
you how much power based on your weight
the runway length the wind your engines
all sorts of things temperatures and
that will then calculate how much power
you need to apply on your engines to
take off safely
there are multiple inputs and the
electronic flight back does this and
calculates it for you
typically on airbus with what's called a
flex temp calculation
on boeings and others it's called the
d-rate calculation and your d rate on a
737 might range from about 57 percent up
to about
90 something it's very rare you use 100
power
now a lot of that data comes from an api
a lot of those calculations are done
locally on the device we have found
vulnerabilities in electronic flight
back apps that would allow one to tamper
with the calculation data you'd need a
degree of privilege to the device
but you could compromise the way the
calculations are made and the way that
the data is handled a lot of the data is
stored locally for example runway
lengths if you could tamp with that you
can cause an incorrect um d-rate or flex
temp calculation to be performed what
the efb does is it outputs
power requirements and v-speeds now v1
is the speed at which the airplane can
safely stop while still on the runway
vr is the rotation speed so that's the
one where you pull back the columns and
the plane starts to rotate v2 is the
take-off safety speed at which you can
take off safely uh with only one engine
now the gap between v1 and v2 i can tell
you as a pilot is quite a scary place
because you can't stop but you can't
take off anyway
incorrect v-speeds could be produced so
the pilot rotates too early or too late
too early you create a tail strike too
late you run the risk of taking off too
low and potentially infringing safety
heights as you take off on landing if
you can tamper with landing performance
calculations you run the risk of the
pilot having the wrong braking settings
and sliding off the end of the runway or
doing too much braking and you end up
causing excess tyre wear or potentially
bursting a tyre
we have found worse vulnerabilities on
installed efbs but we accept that risks
are mitigated because they're in the
cockpit uh we've found trivially
exploitable vulnerabilities uh you could
uh break out of these uh in the cockpit
you could also they're also exposed
ports and the approach to security for
many is to put a sticker over it saying
don't use it which isn't good
there are lots more things that an efb
does they contain a lot of
passenger information and lots more i
won't go into that but there's lots more
to be done and there's lots more covered
on our blog
one of the main problems i have is it's
taking time for the aviation industry to
catch up and truly understand cyber
security
security has been baked into aircraft
design very early stage but
unfortunately not all the aviation
organizations are have the same
approaches to cyber security
we found four separate vulnerabilities
in electronic flight bags
uh three of them um
have had variable responses to
disclosure including one who said that
fixing the vulnerability would be a a
feature update however one vendor was
amazing took it very seriously fixed it
very quickly and we think they're
amazing very variable approach to
security and integrating and interfacing
with researchers
sometimes we also see approaches to efbs
getting things wrong
a common lock down for an ipad for
example on the ground a corporate device
is to use something like face id or
similar
yeah
if you get the lock down wrong you're
going to cause safety problems and a
great example of this is using or
mandating face id to unlock your ipad
because pilots like wearing mirrored
sunglasses they don't work very well for
face id
we also have problems uh in an emergency
situation your pilot may have been
depressurizing the pilot needs to put on
an oxygen mask in order not to pass out
so they can do an emergency
descent and face id doesn't work very
well very well when you've got an oxygen
mask on that's really important because
on that electronic flight bag is your
emergency
or electronic quick reference handbook
and that tells you how to deal with an
instant typically a depressurization and
crash descent
is done from memory but you have to then
cross check using your eqrh
but you can't unlock it because you've
got a face mask on great so there's a
lot of thought required and we put a lot
of good advice for airlines and
operators thinking about how to lock
down their efb safely
there's also big challenges around
regulation so we've advised various
regulators about how they could improve
cyber security but there are differences
between the european regulator the faa
and the us and the uk regulated the caa
there are differences in the way that
regulation is done some are very
prescriptive some are not
other stuff we do we've done a lot of
work on a cars which is the text-based
over rf
protocol that sends data to planes tcas
that's the collision avoidance system
that stops planes crashing into each
other in the sky and lots of other stuff
too
some interesting research done by
another organization looked at the
potential of spoofing the instrument
landing system now we have an airbus
a320 simulator here which we do a lot of
replays and recreations of instance to
see how they work and a good example
this is taking the work that was done by
others and showing the real impacts of
this you can see here the instrument
landing system crosshairs are aligned on
the left-hand display on the primary
flight display or pfd
we look at the window we're in cloud
obviously it's an instrument landing so
we can't see anything but we're aligned
on the
on the approach however when we pop out
of the cloud you see the crosshairs are
still centered but actually we're about
400 meters to the west of san
francisco's runway 27 left so actually
if we carry on to do a category 3
approach which is where the plane auto
lands you run the risk of ditching in
the ocean now
practically this is difficult there's a
lot of rf power required and it's more
likely that what the pilot will see will
be the navigation flags flipping and out
as they get raked signals the pilot will
then use other sources of information to
land
tcat spoofing is quite interesting this
is how you stop planes crashing into
each other their transponders will
interrogate each other and if they
detect a collision potential they'll
give each other avoiding actions a
resolution advisory or ra one plane will
climb the other plane will descend
however some really cool research that
was backed up by avsec oxford another
aviation research group showed that you
could cause planes particularly certain
air buses which will fly the resolution
advisory under autopilot to actually
create
uncommanded climbs in the sense
including um up and down which is really
interesting again technically
challenging to reproduce because you've
got to do it at altitude which probably
means you've got to be on board one of
the planes with some large rf gear but
still interesting that there is
potential to produce um bogus alerts
my advice for everybody is be careful
don't go hacking planes without explicit
permission
there have been all sorts of cases where
researchers have been playing with the
in-flight entertainment system and going
too far
that is illegal don't do it get
permission there are breakers yards
around if you're
lucky you find the right people at the
right time maybe have to pay a little
bit money we usually have to pay for the
jet fuel to power the airplane it's not
cheap costs us four to five hundred
dollars an hour
or we can get ground power a bit cheaper
but it costs money to do to power the
systems up
don't fall for media hype the aircraft
control domain is separate from the rest
of the in-flight entertainment systems
you can't hack the plane from the cabin
certainly not in the way that's been
described by some
there's also certification out there so
you can't expect an aviation
manufacturer simply to patch a plane it
takes a lot of time to approve this
buy your own kit you can get it on ebay
it's old and bear in mind that technical
debt is a major problem too but there's
lots to do and it's really exciting
place and i would strongly recommend
anyone get involved in the aviation
village the aerospace village at defcon
is really cool we'll be there this year
with our simulators demonstrating lots
of cool stuff you can do and lots of
hardware we'll take as well lots more
reading on our blog that's a small
section of it and there's my details if
you want to follow or ask more questions
offline please
anyway i hope you enjoyed it thanks for
listening
ken absolutely amazing the talk was
incredible a lot of information a lot of
stuff
and the last important thing
and maybe the most important thing is
not to
to do illegal things without permission
but we are entering now to the q a
section um
maybe there will be some questions maybe
not
um
i want to ask you first of all before
the questions that are going to pop up
in the chat um
how was this this process of of checking
the security of an airplane of studying
the security of an airplane uh in it was
like something like research you did it
like uh shots for job
how you started with this
yeah so we got started uh about three
and a half years ago
uh one of my colleagues uh we were
driving past a boneyard
for airplanes and uh we rang them and
said hey can we come play and we're like
okay
um
a real surprise
uh they had some planes that they hadn't
taken apart yet
they put power to them and let us play
and we were blown away it's great um we
bought some components from them uh
we've got all sorts of fun things in
fact you can probably see behind me this
is part of a320 over here i've got some
some more components too
so yeah it's it's a great relationship
we've done it at our own cost uh to
really try and drive the industry
forward uh we do do now paid work in
aviation so we've been asked to test all
sorts of things by arab operators uh and
airports but yeah we were doing this for
our own interest and our own fun
amazing
um something that is this interesting
about this is like um the technology
evolves and we have a lot of information
and software and computers
in the
aerospace industry so we have
so much uh to learn about it and we have
so much to learn
in in our space security so
for us that we are you know like we have
our differences uh
to united states or
or you know
or england so
how do you feel like
this um
aerospace security industry
uh is is evolving and and how
and what will be um
a cool
thing to to the people that is watching
this talk
to learn
like he like in career path in in case
they really want to start doing some
security
uh
audits or something testing or some kind
of of security staff inner space so so
what would be your advice
for the people that's watching us
and
yeah industry has come along a long way
in two years um you might remember
boeing had a run-in with io active two
years ago now maybe a bit more
that no one ended up looking good at the
end of but actually bearing have come a
long way they've engaged with the
aerospace village they've come to come
to
to help support the village as well
which is really cool
two years ago rsa they brought an
electronic flight back with them and
demonstrated it it was super cool and
they've also invited us and other
village members to
their factories we've seen a lot of
their cyber security offerings which is
cool
the industry used to be really close to
external research but that's changing uh
boeing has led the way there they've
been amazingly cool and done a great job
of opening up to engage with researchers
i think industry more broadly has a long
way to go we've been very surprised at
the
very dated response to cyber security
and research uh by some but many others
are improving ways to get involved is
you need to understand the protocols
involved so you need to learn eric 49
eric 9 and 664
there's a lot of learning to be done
there
you don't just pen test a plane
one of the challenges being is you can't
predict how some of the unusual
protocols and systems will respond
so i'd strongly recommend that anything
you do is passive do not do anything
active on a plane ever you don't know
how the system is going to respond so be
careful
okay again so we are finished our time
now i really want to thank you so much
for being here
for this crazy switch of the talks and
i'm trying to make the best of
of this
casualties here so i really want to
thank you thank you very much for being
here in particular space in a
cooperation i hope
uh in case we have some q a
um
i mean some questions uh we i we are
going to to forward to you in some way
cool thank you okay thank you so much
see you