hey everyone welcome to my talk today on
how to do code review the offensive
security way
so the first thing that you need to do
when you're doing code review is
obtaining the source code this can often
prove difficult because of some source
code some source code being restricted
behind the sales process or just being
generally difficult to get your hands on
so one of the first techniques that i
want to get into is obtaining the source
code through cloud marketplaces
these days we're fortunate enough to
have many vendors list their software on
cloud marketplaces like aws azure and
gcp in many cases trial licenses are
available which lets us access software
that would typically be gated by an
enterprise sales process
so this is pretty valuable because we
can leverage these marketplace offerings
to obtain the source code for enterprise
software
personally i have used cloud
marketplaces to gain access to source
code multiple times where it's typically
behind some sort of sales process or is
really difficult to get access to
so here's an example
there was this piece of software called
teradissi pcoip manager
and it was something that facebook were
running so you can see in this
screenshot
there's a subdomain under fb.com where i
identify that they are running pcoip
connection manager
now
typically it's not so easy to get access
to the source code
or the software
what i found was it was available on
aws's marketplace like you can see in
the screenshot below
what this let me do was simply spin up
an instance of teradc pcip manager on
aws's marketplace and then obtain the
source code to do source code analysis
another method of obtaining the source
code is container image registries
so similar to cloud marketplaces you'd
be surprised at some of the enterprise
software which you can find pre-built
docker containers for images for so if
you go to hub.docker.com and you search
for the software that you're interested
in reverse engineering you'll often find
something that is already on docker hub
and can be used to reverse engineer the
software
if there's an image available you can
simply spin up a docker container using
that image and gain shell access to that
container then you can obtain all of the
source code once you're inside the
container whether that's war files jar
files or php files for further analysis
so this technique i've been pretty
successful with as well i've often found
that there's enterprise software that
typically requires a license that's
pre-built
as a docker image and posted on docker
hub
this is something that often you will
find on docker hub because of you know
whatever reason someone is trying to do
devops for their company and they've
pushed these images to docker hub for
convenience but ultimately it's useful
because you don't need to
be able to get a copy of that software
or even spin up the infrastructure you
can simply pull down the docker image
and start up a docker container
containing that software
so here's the little meme around docker
hub you can see that um in the first
window there's uh adobe experience
manager you can contact sales to get
access to the software but alternatively
you can just get it on docker hub
there's a container for adobe experience
manager that was updated only two months
ago on docker hub so sometimes you can
really defeat the whole sales process
and the whole gated software approach
where it's possible to get access to the
software without going through a sales
process through something like docker
hop
another
unfortunate way of getting
access to source code is actually
contacting sales
now this is one of the more high
friction high reward approaches because
typically contacting sales is not
something that is an enjoyable
experience from my experience and often
it is a long lengthy process where you
need to explain to them why you want the
software and why you are someone they
should consider to give a trial or
something like that so if the only
possible way is to get access to the
software by contacting sales
this might still be a viable solution
it also means that if that's the only
way to get access to the software that
it probably hasn't had many people
looking at the software's source code in
the past due to how difficult it is to
get
while this option is the has the highest
friction involved if you can convince
sales to give you a trial copy of the
software it's pretty likely that you're
going to be able to own the crap out of
it
this is my least favorite route of
getting access to the software because
who really wants to talk to sales but
historically speaking this has had the
highest rewards when it comes to finding
critical vulnerabilities
another approach to obtaining the
software is through freelancing websites
so um this is an example where i went on
fiverr.com and i asked someone on fiverr
if they had experience with the software
called websphere webspherecommerce i
asked them i said do you have experience
with this do you have access to the
installation files so that and can
download them if you can i'd be happy to
pay you to install them on a server and
upload the files for me this is
surprisingly surprisingly a pretty
effective technique because there are a
lot of professionals on fiverr on
freelancer and other freelancing
websites that have access to software
that you typically don't they often have
credentials for ibm or for vmware or
whatever website that has a gated
download process so you can often go to
these
freelancing websites and ask someone or
pay someone to install a piece of
software that's typically difficult to
get
so you can see that this ad was related
to someone offering to install software
related to websphere tomcat jboss
wildfly and i just asked them i said hey
do you have access to a copy of
websphere commerce i'd be interested in
buying that off you so this is another
approach you can take to obtaining
software
another technique is obtaining source
code through github
now github has a way of searching for
files that's pretty effective so if
you've identified a unique file name in
your software like for example here that
we've got install cmstep1.aspx
then on github i could search file name
and that file name to see if there are
any hits and this can be pretty
effective when you're looking for net or
java code bases because you can often
find the jar files or the aspx files and
the dll files for the software that
you're looking for
a lot of people post their entire web
route on github for some reason a lot of
people post a lot of sensitive
information and software on github so
this is a really good uh really good way
of discovering software that you
typically don't get don't have access to
and lastly one other way of obtaining
software is chaining vulnerabilities
so
when you can leverage other
vulnerabilities to obtain the source
code for the application
some of the challenges include not
knowing all of the local file locations
of the source code and sometimes this
isn't something that's allowed by vendor
or bug bounty programs
often local file disclosure is one of
the easiest ways to for an attacker to
read the source code from underlying
systems
external entity injection can also lead
to local file disclosure and this is
potentially another way to read the
source code and obviously remote command
execution will let you read the source
code and execute as you can execute
arbitrary commands
on net systems particularly you can
download the dll files from the bin
folder and then decompile them to
c-sharp source code there are some good
blog posts on the internet about how you
can do this and how you can
essentially enumerate the dll files that
you need to download
so now that we've talked a little bit
about
obtaining the software um
one of the other things that i want to
go through is some of the source code
analysis that needs to be done on the
server side in order to discover
vulnerabilities now remember this entire
presentation is about
source code analysis in an offensive
security way what i find really
difficult with approaching targets from
a completely black box perspective is
number one you don't have access to the
source code so that should have been
addressed by the first section of this
presentation now in this section of the
presentation i want to go through a
little bit about what sort of
vulnerabilities you can look for and
what what the result of source code
analysis can look like when you are
successful
so here's an example from teradici pcoip
manager
this was a vulnerability that i
submitted to facebook a couple of years
ago
can you spot the vulnerability in this
snippet of code
well the vulnerability actually lies
where it says random.next bytes
in this section
what it's actually doing is it's using
java.util.random
and that is essentially an insecure
random function in java this means that
an attacker can potentially crack the
seed and then predict future sessions
that are being made on teradici pcoip
manager
this wouldn't have been super obvious to
you if you just looked at this source
code and didn't have much knowledge
about java or how random uh how the
random util works in java but this is
why it's really important to have a good
base understanding of each programming
language you are attempting to audit
because there are going to be
vulnerabilities that are nuanced and
require a little bit more attention in
order to discover
so as i said earlier this is insecure
randomness the sessions were generated
by java.util.org instead of secure
random due to this the sessions have an
incredibly weak seed that can be
determined allowing the attacker to
predict future seeds
future session ids
this can be of critical impact because
attackers can generate valid future
sessions by knowing the seed value
facebook paid four thousand dollars for
this vulnerability in 2018.
here's another example from terror to
see pcoip manager
you can see in this servlet it is
accepting a post request and as a part
of the post request it's parsing some
xml
you can see that it tries to sanitize
the xml however ultimately
it gets parsed by pars xml input
the pass xml input function essentially
creates a document and passes the xml
without any other modifications
if you can spot the vulnerability here
essentially
it's not the presence of something that
indicates the vulnerability it's
actually the lack of something that
indicates the vulnerability
typically when you
parse xml in java
and when you have a document that you
use a document builder for or sacs or
something like that to parse the xml
you need to explicitly specify not to
expand entities and explicitly specify
that dtds are not allowed in this case
that hasn't happened and essentially
what's happening is the xml is being
parsed directly without any
modifications or settings or
configuration items
and it leads to external entity
injection
so this is what the poc looks like
essentially you post to a specific
endpoint and then you include an xml
input that contains your dtd that this
will ultimately exploit
the when the xml is paused it will reach
out to your dtd and then once that
is done it will then evaluate your dtd's
contents this leads to things like local
file disclosure and server side request
forgery
so no protections were in place within
the source code to protect from external
entity expansion
through the ftp server trick it was
possible to obtain the full contents of
files from this from the file system and
directory listing was possible as well
turn the c pcoip manager was at was and
still is hosted on facebook's
infrastructure this particular bug led
to a bounty of five thousand five
hundred dollars
another bug that i want to quickly go
through today is an employee management
system zero day i can't really disclose
the vendor as i've reported the bug to
their bug bounty and it's not allowed to
disclose who they are however they
produce a software that a lot of
companies use to manage payslips and
other employee related data this source
code was obtained through a friend of
mine however it's definitely not
something that was easily obtainable on
the internet
i discovered an xss0d through xml
injection unfortunately i could not
escalate it to
xxe so here's the example of source code
which i was looking at and you can see
that it essentially takes in a few
parameters and passes it to the system
tree command function
when the system tree command function is
uh
initialized it uses these parameters
that it took in the first snippet of
code and it replaces a bunch of xml on
the local file system before evalua
before returning the xml to the user
you can see that the delphi guid is a
user input from the previous piece of
code that i showed and over here you can
see that in the xml it replaces a
variable in the xml with the contents of
the user input delphi guid
so what you could do is essentially
provide a delphi guide that injects a c
data
xml element which contains arbitrary
html now the reason this works is
because the content type returned by
this endpoint is text
html
so that's why this xss vulnerability
works you can inject a delphi guid which
has
c data xml element and ultimately that c
data xml element is evaluated as text
html leading to cross-site scripting
this was reflected across that scripting
so lastly i just want to leave uh some
tips for code reviewers now in the
previous section i just showed you some
examples of what code review looks like
and what you can discover through source
code analysis
these are examples of source code
analysis through the offensive security
lens um often i didn't have access to
the source code i had to figure out a
way to get access to the source code and
ultimately i always ultimately
discovered vulnerabilities within the
things that i was looking at after
spending a bunch of time on it
so before i wrap up this presentation i
just want to give a few tips for people
who are getting into source code review
and people who may be a bit more
experienced with source code review
for novice code reviewers so beginners
um what i suggest is you identify all
the sources and syncs the sources are
where data is being input and the syncs
are where data and ends up being
processed um spend time doing recon on
the code base so for example identifying
all the routes so the web.xml file the
application.xml file the routes.rb file
depending on what language it is there's
going to be a different way to define
the different routes and controllers for
the application i suggest that you
discover these and you go through them
in depth and you understand how the
sources and sinks work
next i would map out these routes to the
server-side functionality and make a
note of all the inputs for each of these
routes be thorough with it it's totally
worth it if you can understand where all
the user input is coming from and where
it is going that is going to help you in
your vulnerability discovery process and
your source code analysis process
and lastly go through a server-side flow
from a http request from the source to
point to the point in code where it's
being processed the sync repeat this
process for all the other places in the
attack surface for all other attack
surface
so these are some of the tips that i
would like to provide to beginner code
reviewers and i think these are
practical trip tips that they can employ
in order to become better at code review
ultimately code review is really based
on experience and it's based on the
ability to understand how a programming
language works but also how the code
base works and each code base is
different
in this presentation i
what i can't really tell you is how to
become a really great source code
reviewer i can just give you tips on how
to become more experienced at source
code review which will ultimately lead
to you being able to discover more
vulnerabilities when you do source code
review and my biggest takeaway when it
comes to source code review is the more
time you spend reviewing different code
bases more patterns become familiar to
you and you can start understanding how
people structure their code bases and
how certain things operate like
controllers and views and models and
things like that on different
applications
often applications are completely
different to each other every time you
approach a new code base it's completely
different so what really helps is having
the experience of doing source code
review in the past on previous code
bases that helps in the future
for more experienced code reviewers what
i would suggest is to understand the
interoperation within the software and
to make sure that you map out the
potential attack surface thoroughly
reviewing all the dependencies that are
being used is also really important
because you can audit these dependencies
for security issues and you can take the
concepts of syncs even further sometimes
you have to get your hands dirty and
fuzz binaries like for example there's
mean vulnerabilities and binaries like
image image magic and that's just the
dependency of a product so sometimes you
have to go deeper than just what the
initial source code is if it's depending
on certain things like image magic or
exif tool for example then you might
need to start auditing some of those
binaries as well if you want to try and
find vulnerabilities within those syncs
another thing is not to make assumptions
even for standard libraries so always
read the documentation and code to fully
understand how the functionality is
being provided and sometimes
even if it's a standard library read
through the source code of that standard
library function so you can understand
exactly how it's operating sometimes
this will shock you and you'll find
there's some behavior that you didn't
that was not something you expected even
in the standard library
another thing is ensuring that you're
covering all attack surface so all
internally and externally exposed ports
protocols and services when considering
attack chains so what do i mean by this
essentially let's say you had a target
that
you were doing some source code review
for and there was a reader's server and
readers was being used then you need to
also consider all of the possible attack
vectors that involve the reader's server
as well when you do all of your source
code analysis so understand the
interoperation between the different
services and internally externally
exposed ports and protocols when you're
doing your source code analysis
and lastly make an effort towards
chaining the vulnerabilities for impact
so if there's a white list for an ssrf
do not stop there attempt to exploit
this white list
for things like open redirects to
achieve an unbounded ssrf so this is
something that i often do when i do
source code analysis i find
vulnerabilities that they they think
they're protected against the
vulnerability class but under closer
analysis and deeper inspection you find
that you can bypass the protections they
have put in place
and lastly gain a deep understanding
about the application on its stack by
reading the documentation thoroughly
i cannot stress how important this is
each framework and each application can
have its quirks and can be different
sometimes by understanding these nuances
within these applications and frameworks
you will find really good
vulnerabilities due to those nuances
so that's all that's all i have today
but i really appreciate you taking the
time to watch my presentation
thanks so much for coming