hi
uh okay so this is the talk
uh colonel
pawning with ebpf a love story or hockey
and cardinal
i'm the lead security researcher at
grapple
i focus on vulnerability research
exploit development reverse engineering
and offensive security
tools and techniques
we use this research to improve
detection in defense
and
if you're interested i release new
research exploits and blog posts on my
twitter and github
i speak english spanish italian and i'm
learning chinese
i'm going to give the presentation
presentation in english
for
for simplicity but if you would like to
uh ask questions
perfect is
so that's about me
um
so let's do a little primer on what ebpf
exactly is so originally
ebpf
stands for extended berkeley packet
filter
and it was originally just berkeley
packet filter and it was created to do
packet filtering directly in the kernel
was later
recoded and redesigned into extended
ebpf
and
simply what it does is it allows you to
run kernel code without loading a local
kernel module
basically a driver
why is it used
it
it's better because developers don't
need to know how to develop kernel code
so
there's a subsection of developers that
only write kernel code and
it kind of
is its own separate thing
um and
maybe intimidating to some developers or
don't want to bother with it it's easier
to write ebpf programs and there's some
performance advantages to run things
directly in the kernel
modern hardware is now kind of
designed to
optimize asynchronous programming
and
so there's performance increases and
it's a safe way
safe way to run kernel code presumably
what is it used for uh
many things you can use it to trade for
tracing debugging
instrumentation such as like hooking
syscalls to see
what comes out of them and of course
packet capture filtering which was the
original intended use
um even writing root kits it's actually
kind of fun and interesting to write
root kits with for ebpf there was a
couple of
uh really interesting def con talks
about
using ebpf to write root kits
presuming that you have root access to
begin with
it's a nice feature
one other thing
somebody asked me
recently
what are like modern use cases of ebpf
i think netflix has
started to use eppf
in there
to run their programs directly in the
kernel
and
quite recently sysmon for linux has been
released and i believe
they are using evpf
um
although i haven't gotten a chance to
look at their source code so those are
some like
concrete examples of how evpf is used in
current
modern use technology
so how does it work
so first the developer begins by writing
an ebpf program in a higher level
language um
usually in a
simplified version of c
or python
there are
you know competing tool chains
that are coming out um probably the most
popular is bcc
which will compile
the higher level
program into bytecode
and the bytecode is a simple instruction
set it's very similar to x86
um it utilizes 12 registers one stack
register and one auxiliary for strategy
checks and it has an implicit program
counter
so once the bytecode is compiled the
user mode application will load the
bytecode in the kernel using a ebpf
syscall so it'll have the
you know some buffer
with the bytecode instructions and it
will pass that buffer into
um the kernel using a bpf cisco
at that point um the ebpf verifier will
perform checks on the bytecode and make
sure it's safe
and if the checks are
passed the byte code is
uh jit compiled into the native
instruction set depending on the
architecture
um
that's running
or
this depends on a kernel configuration
so
if the kernel configuration specifies
that ebpf should be jit compiled it'll
be j-compiled if not then the ebpf
interpreter
will
run
interpret and run the
um at each specific time it's supposed
to run but usually the default is to
compile um that's usually enabled in in
most um linux distributions
um
okay so after that uh the application
will attach the program to a hook point
um
where upon
an event the program will run it's event
based execution
in particular we're kind of interested
in where
unprivileged users are allowed to run
evf programs
and whether they are or not depends on
the assist control knob unprivileged ppf
disabled
um
privileged users are limited to where
their program can hook so
they can't really hook uh
syscalls or
anywhere they want they
they're mostly limited to
a socket that the user itself owns
and to interact with the ebpf program
the application
can interact with it giving input or
receiving output with ebpf maths and
helper functions
um so this is kind of how uh
uh asynchronous
programming model
uh will come in so
the current of the ebpf program will run
in the kernel
will do its thing and the user mode
program
at its leisure can check in and get
results
or give uh change its input
to uh
the program
when it sees
fit but the kernel program will run
independently
um so a little bit more about evpf maps
which is how the user mode application
will interact with the program
it's a generic key value store with an
arbitrary data structure some examples
are arrays
stacks cues
very simple data structures that are
available and it's defined
by five attributes type
key size which is the value of the
key value store
the value size the size of the value the
max entry
basically defines the size of the map
and map flags which
give you the ability to
change a little bit about how the map
behaves
this is a diagram that my colleague
andrea
helped me create
as you can see it's divided between user
space and kernel space
the tool chain
compiles the ebpf program to bite code
in user space
the process that will actually do the
loading
has the bytecode and some buffer which
will pass it
via ebpfciscall into the verifier
the verifier will check it
if it passes will jit compile it
then the
user
user mode application will attach it to
a hook point
and the ebpf jit runner or the
interpreter will actually run the native
or interpreted instructions upon some
event
depending on the on the um
hook point
and so the user
space
application process
can interact with the program
using uh again evp of syscalls
um
to
change and receive values in the map
so we'll do i o with the ebf program in
the kernel
so the interesting thing is so we're
looking at this from a perspective of
uh
me which i am an exploit developer
the most interesting thing to me is
what is the attack surface
how can we look at
and prod the weak points in this
technology if you're allowing
unprivileged users who run code in the
kernel
even though you
are sandboxing and giving severe
limitations
there has to be some
[Music]
place where you can try to find
vulnerabilities
the first one that um
seemed obvious to me when i first
started looking at this
um was the ebpf verifier which is the
thing that actually analyzes
the program that you're trying to load
in the kernel and determines whether
it's safe or not
so you can use vulnerabilities in the
verifier code to trick the kernel into
loading unsafe bytecode
and they usually present as arithmetic
and logic errors another one um is in
the ebpf jet compiler itself
um
mistakes in how
the evpf by code is compiled into the
native architecture
uh assembly language
um
and i will get into examples of each of
these
um in a minute
and as well as
separate from the actual evpf code is
using ebf programs as an exploit
primitive so even though there's not
vulnerabilities in ebef itself ebpf
can be used
to leverage other exploits in the linux
kernel
as a primitive i will also
um
give an example of one that's happened
before in recent time within the last
couple of months too
um so attacks how has evpf been used in
modern exploits so
in particular in the ebpf verifier cve
2021-3490
um
using register brown tracking to trick
the verifier into thinking register
contains a constant value of 0 to gain a
kernel read write primitive
in the case of the ebpf jet compiler
our recent vulnerability the jig
compiler inaccurately calculated branch
displacements so this was used to hijack
control flow
um
of the program so it passed all the evpf
verifier attacks
but the way the bike code was compiled
what um
there was a
a mistake in it so
even though the program
was supposed to branch to another place
in the
assembly it
went to another so the uh
the verifier didn't account for
jumping to further down and so then you
could
trick the verifier into thinking
something was happening when it wasn't
um
and using ebpf as an exploit primitive
a great example of this was qualis
using um cv 2021
support uh 39909 sequoia which is just a
memory corruption vulnerability and file
system
um and they actually use this to
overwrite ebpf by code that already made
it past the verifier check so it was
like
technically correct
um
or a valid ebpf program but like it was
later overwritten
to
other instruction set or other
instructions
um
when that happened
uh they were able to gain a read write
primitive
because it made it past the the verifier
step and
other memory corruption vulnerability
overwrote that
so the ebpf verifier enforces these
general rules
no back edges loops are unreachable
obstructions
no pointer comparisons and
the only pointer arithmetic that's
allowed is with scalar registers and in
this case scalar registers are defined
as registers that do not contain a
pointer
so like a
a scalar value
and pointers cannot point outside of the
bounds of an evpf map which is like a
predefined
area of memory that you use to do i o
with a user space application
and pointers can't be stored in a map or
as a return value
because that would leak kernel memory
addresses
and that's not allowed particularly if
it's an unprivileged user
um so one of the important aspects of
the ebpf verifier is range tracking
so the verifier will track the bounds
for each register in each execution path
and it has 64-bit and 32-bit hundred
pounds for counterparts for each so
it'll attack
the minimum unsigned integer value the
maximum maximum inside integer value
um and the same for signed
it also will
store information
in a
field called a structure called var off
which is a t num structure that contains
information about
which of the bits of the register are
known or unknown during static analysis
um so if you can kind of imagine
through various
flows of logic you can kind of
gleam information about like
what are the
constraints of what the value of some
constant
register
um and so then those are updated in this
structure called var off which is tnm
structure that i'll cover
shortly
so it contains two 64
bit fields mask and value
both can be interpreted as big vectors
if a bit is set in mask the value of
that bit is unknown
and if the bit isn't set then the value
is known and the known value is
contained in the value field
an example is if we have a register
where the lower 32 bits are known to be
one and the upper 32 bits are known
then far off for the upper 32 bits
will all be set because they're all
unknown and the lower 32 bits will be
set to
equal to 3.
um
so
uh the lower 32 bits of mask are all on
set because we know all of the 32 bits
of the the lower 32 bits
another thing that ebpf firefighter does
is
alu sanutation which supplements the
static range tracking um
so we have some idea of what is going to
happen during static analysis but it's
patching in instructions to do dynamic
checks during execution
uh to make sure that the actual during
run time the values of this register
stay within what
the verifier thinks
they're going to be
um so an alu limit represents the
maximum absolute value that could be
added or subtracted to a pointer before
crossing the bounds of a map so getting
into memory that um
they shouldn't be getting into
and so how the limit is calculated has
changed over time so very recently
it's been drastically changed um one
interesting thing is is that uh this
vulnerability cve 2020 27171
basically rendered alu sanitation
useless for a very long time and it went
unnoticed even though
there were several
public evpf exploits that leveraged
leveraged it and
no one really noticed that alu
sanitation
did wasn't working um until
may of this year so just a few months
ago
okay so now i'm going to cover cve 2021
which is the
vulnerability that i exploited to
do
privilege escalation
on many uh distributions of linux
i thought it was kind of interesting
because it wasn't an arithmetic error or
like a bounce competing error it was
actually a logic bug
um
the way that it worked was the value of
far off wasn't updated after 32-bit and
xor
and or instructions if the upper 32-bits
of the registers were unknown
um
this allowed the track bounds of the
destination register of that operation
to become invalid or corrupted
so here is
a screenshot of the offending code
and the comment here is that if you
assume
um
if the source and destination register
values are known
then don't update
the um
the destination register
um and the problem here is is that um
how source known and destination known
are computed in the 32-pip case
um only compares
um
the 32-bit register however
it says here assuming scalar 64 min max
will be called so it's safe to skip
updating
scalar 64 min max will only update the
registers if the entire 64-bits are
known
in this case only the lower 32 bits are
so
once you compute the new bounds
they become corrupted because
they didn't become updated after this
operation
so how do we trigger this bug
we need to prepare two registers
uh one register the first one
all 64 bits are known
and the register is equal to
this value
um
so bar of rf.mask
is
0 because we know all 64 bits and bar of
dot value is equal to
the actual value of the register
and
r2 the lower 32 bits are known and equal
to 1 and the upper 32 bits are known so
the upper 32 bits of far off dot mask
are all set
and the lower 32 bits are equal to the
actual value which is one
so to trigger this bug we perform an and
operation on the two registers
and the destination register should be
the one with the unknown
uh upper 32 bits
so
this is the
the instruction the bpf and instruction
and the destination register is we're
going to call it the exploit register
the result is corrupting 32-bit bounds
when you see the the minimum value is
equal to one and the maximum value is
equal to zero so we know that these are
corrupted because the minimum value is
greater than the maximum value
and the true value of the register at
runtime
will be zero during our exploit
um so the verifier will check all paths
for execution
and some are removed for optimization
for example jump conditional paths are
trimmed by checking minimum
maximum bounds so if you can imagine
um if you have like a greater than or
equal to operation you can kind of
eliminate
uh
a lot of those paths if you kind if you
already have
information about the bounds
of the register and what their possible
values can be
so this is just a quick screenshot of
the function
it will just k uh
just looking at the case of greater than
or equal to
um so it's just looking at the u32
minimum value
and if it is
it returns true and if not it returns
false
so in that case
if the branch is not taken we can just
like completely eliminate it
so i was able to use this bug without
doing anything else just other than
triggering it to
cause dos
so remember the value of our exploit
register will be zero at runtime
so if we do a 32-bit
uh
register comparison conditional
um
the program counter will jump five
instructions if the lower 32-bits of the
exploit register is greater than or
equal to one
even though the value of the register
will be zero
since we have corrupted bounds meaning
that the minimum value is equal to one
[Music]
the verify will think that the program
is going to evaluate to true every
single time even though in this case
it's going to evaluate false
this will allow us to put whatever
instructions we want in the false path
and the verifier
won't reject us it won't check to see if
that path is safe or if we're following
the rules during that path
unfortunately
um the verifier will patch
the the dead branch
path thinking well it's not going to be
taken anyway so we can just patch these
instructions with whatever and it
actually patches the instruction for the
jump back
one instruction
so if this path is hit it will keep
jumping back one instruction
and
cause an into the loop because it keeps
jumping back one evaluating the
conditional jumping back on back one
over and over and over again
so we can cause a dos by launching many
instances of the exploit and lock up all
of the available kernel threads
depending on
how many are available
and
you know hardware conditions
okay so that we were able to cause a dos
um
now we want to actually leverage the bug
for lpe
we need to create a primitive
to create um to be able to do
out-of-bound read writes
and ultimately arbitrary rewrite
so if we add if we do an operation to
add one
to the exploit register that will add
one to both of our bounds
so the register had a random value of
one are zero initially now it'll be one
uh so the bounds are updated for each
branch after a conditional jump
and we can use this to manipulate the
bounds of a register
with all of the bits unknown so this is
a new register
that we're going to use
to manipulate our exploit register the
one that leverage the bug
and the true branch of this instruction
so jump
if less than or equal
if the register is less than or equal to
then the lower 32 bits of the register
must be less than or equal to 1.
um so even though the
the least significant bit is unknown um
its bounds are
between zero and one the verifier knows
this
so our exploit register has a minimum
value of two and a maximum value of one
those are the corrupted bounds
uh if we add it to our construction
constructed register that we just made
that has a minimum value of zero and a
maximum value of one
we add those together the verifier will
add those bounds to create the new
bounds
um
our exploit register now has a minimum
value of two
and a maximum value of two as well so
since the min and max bounds are the
same it will update
the registered knowing that it must have
a constant value of 2
even though
it's actually 1 during the runtime case
so all that's left to do is to perform a
simple and operation
we know that uh ending two and one
will result in zero and the verifier of
course knows this two
um but in actuality
we're ending one and one
so
we have a value of one where the
verifier
thinks it's
um zero
so verifier thinks it's zero we actually
have a runtime value of one
so now we have a register that we can
multiply add subtract whatever but the
verifier thinks that
the value is zero so we can use it to do
pointer arithmetic and
access memory that's outside the bounds
that we're limited to
okay so the first thing we need to do is
create an information link
uh this is actually easy we don't need
to
use our register primitive at all we can
just uh use the bug itself
um
if you look at the if conditional
so if the register is known
and
the
minimum value is greater than the
maximum value which is in the case of
this bug because the bounds are
corrupted and the minimum value is
greater than the maximum value it kind
of knows okay something got messed up
here
marks the register unknown
but if you actually happen to have
um
a pointer in that register
uh
marking the register unknown
means that now you can store
the value of that register in a map
remember that you're not allowed to
store pointers to maps
in an ebpf map because user space has
access to it so you would be leaking
kernel memory
but in this case
since the register is marked as unknown
um
the verifier doesn't know that there's
an actual kernel pointer there so we can
get our information leak just by
leveraging the bug and not doing
anything fancy
um and so we get our initial information
link to break kslr
so an evpf map
um as i said earlier this is what user
space uses to interact with the ebbf
current uh program running in the kernel
has a is represented by a bpf map
structure which has various fields
the ones are in of interest are going to
be ops and btf which are the first and
last one that we see here on the screen
um okay so from there we have an info
oblique how do we achieve arbitrary read
so as i said before a
bpf map is represented by a bpf map
structure
which
the last field that we saw on the screen
is a struct vtf
if we set the field
of map
btf as the address we want to read
uh we're able to get a four byte read
primitive at an arbitrary address
if you see here
um
uh this is like a snippet of what gets
executed executed
uh
when you call the btf
obj get info fd command using ebpf
helper functions
so
btf underscore id
gets dereference uh dereferences the
memory at map btf id
so
if you overwrite what's at btf
field it will dereference an arbitrary
address and memory
so that's our
our read primitive
our right primitive is going to be
um a little different so
btf ops
um
if you remember
a bpf map
has the first struck uh first field is
ops which is like a table of
map operations that you can do when you
call
helper functions
so if we overwrite this table we can
we have
control over the program counter by
overwriting
the function addresses
in the structure
however
the way that these helper functions are
called the first argument is always
going to be a pointer to a bpf maps
structure itself
so
we're
really better off changing the type of
using the map operations
functions itself because it knows how to
interpret
uh
that pointer instead of like
i don't know using some other
completely different
um
kernel function which
is not going to know how to handle the
first
parameter as an ebpf map and will
cause probably cause problems
um
so the way we do this is we first want
to change the type of map from an array
to a stack the reason is is because
we're able to call map push element
which is only available
if the type of the ebpf map is a stack
type stat it has the data structure of a
stack
and then because we have out of bounds
read writes in the evpf map structure
itself
um
we can overwrite this with
uh an arraymap function
called map get next key
um so this gives us control over the
actual parameters that get passed to
this function
um so even though we are able to call
map gets next key by leaving
the map the type map as array which we
originally did
we wouldn't have control over the key
parameters
but if we change it to map get next key
we can because we have control over the
flag parameter
and we can see here
the flac parameter
we are able to actually overwrite
what's pointed to as next
our next key which is the last parameter
uh supposed to be flags as index plus
one
so we get an arbitrary right primitive
in that way
so we're able to
arbitrarily
arbitrarily read 4 bytes
and
arbitrarily write 4 bytes
so
uh that gives us enough to do lp
um
it's pretty straightforward from here
uh
we use the arbitrary read primitive to
find the current thread's tax rack
address um and get the address of the
credential structure we overwrite
the id to zero
um
i kind of glossed over this a little bit
but there is code to do
everything
on my github
um
and if we have time
i'll do a demo which i think we can
uh
here and so this is the demo of
the
actual exploit happening
and you can kind of see the steps that i
just covered
and there you go
so that happened
okay
um so if you're interested in the code
it's there
um and so let's talk about new
mitigations
oh sorry
sorry the next youtube video played all
right let's talk about new mitigations
and ale sanitation that kind of prevent
this type of attack from happening now
which they're very recently introduced
like
it's not something that has been really
just
discussed at length
previously the alu limit and if you
remember it's a way to do dynamic checks
during runtime um
not static so it's like checking to see
hey we thought during static analysis
this register was supposed to be between
these values
uh let's check to see if that's actually
true
um the way that it's computed is
different so before it depended on the
position of the map register um so if
you had some
uh pointer to a map
um and the verifier knew okay we just
added
you know 100 bytes to it so we're 100
bytes into the map we can only go 100
bytes more if the map size is 200
this is different it's using the bounds
of the offset register so we're adding
the value of this register that is
supposed to be between zero and one or
zero and it's supposed to just be the
value of zero
it's going to use
um
the bounds of the offset register now
which is much more effective because
if you find some vulnerability in the
verifier
where it doesn't actually calculate
the bounds of the offset register
you can just keep vlog
keep triggering that vulnerability over
and over and basically get unlimited
uh amounts of
um
out of bounds but now it's using the
bounds of the offer set register so if
we thought that the offset register was
supposed to be between the values
remember originally of zero and zero
because if the verifier thought the
register was supposed to be zero if the
offset register isn't zero
then the operation is going to be nulled
it's not going to happen
um so it will totally kill
um
this type of
uh exploit strategy
additionally not only uh
not only it does it apply to
um
situations where the offset register
uh
the offset register bounds but if the
offset register is known to be constant
it will
it will patch the actual instruction
uh to use the constant value instead of
using a register at all
so if it knows the register is supposed
to be zero the instruction will go from
add
this register to this other register
it will go from that to adding zero to
the edge of the register so it
completely removes
uh the dynamic part of it so it'll just
add the immediate value of zero to the
register instead of the other register
because we don't trust what's actually
in the register anymore and this was
done to respect uh speculative attacks
but it also serves as a purpose to
kill uh exploit
um exploits using verifying or verifier
vulnerabilities not that they're
completely dead but it really does
hinder them so if that makes sense
instead of adding register 1 to register
2 if you know that the value of register
2 is 0 the instruction now becomes
add register 1 to 0. so
no chance of fooling
there
so can we still exploit the ebpf
verifier
it's more difficult but not impossible
there could be vulnerabilities in how
the patching code actually calculates
the bounds
the evpr verifier code is very complex
and how it computes paths and where to
patch
um which paths are speculative and which
are not you can trick them into thinking
well we don't need to actually patch
this path
um there's error you can find
vulnerabilities in errors when computing
the leu alu limit
um
and if you can't find any
vulnerabilities there there's always the
vulnerabilities in the jit compiler
which people have started to attack now
um
and there's possibilities in every
architecture because every
uh architecture is going to have its own
compiler and as uh i talked about
earlier
um
there was the vulnerability that i
talked about earlier there was uh
errors in how branch uh
branch uh jumps were calculated and so
that was just for x8464
x86 64. um but there's still a whole
other slew of architectures that there's
probably vulnerabilities in
how things are jib compiled so those are
places to look
um and future medications for better
security just my personal
recommendations
throughout the process of this research
verify our vulnerabilities can still
triply cause
trivially caused denial of service
um
so just as an experiment i decided to re
unpatch the
patch for
the vulnerability that we just exploited
um to see if i could still cause dos and
you can and the reason is is because
dead branches are patched with a jump
back one instruction
um which will cause an infinite loop and
lock up a kernel hood if you
were to patch those dead branches with
exit instructions instead
um
then the program would just terminate
and and free up that threat instead of
causing it to execute insolently
and uh another future mitigation that i
would recommend personally
is the ebpf bytecode buffer to be marked
read only
during and after verification
um
until jit compilation is complete
um so this would prevent uh evp from
being used in an exploit primitive for
other memory corruption vulnerabilities
like we saw and um
the qualis
exploit where they
were able to use a memory corruption
vulnerability to overwrite an ebpf
program buffer with new instructions
after it had been
verified by the verifier
we still would need some way to in um to
incorporate bite patching so if you uh
mark the buffer as read only um
you're not able to like
do dynamic patching to it um so you
would need like at the end to be able to
consolidate like what new instructions
or what instructions you want to
overwrite and patch with to the
read-only buffer but
you know
i think it's still probably possible
and there's a solution to that and
until then
ebpf
is a really good candidate to use as
an exploit primitive even if you find a
vulnerability that is in completely
different
part of the kernel
okay so now it's time for questions um
my blog post is at grapplesecurity.com
which gets into more in depth about each
part of the exploit process you can
follow me on twitter uh my handle is the
same uh twitter github and email
um
and yeah that's all i have
thank you