hello and welcome to a presentation
about the aerospace village badge design
my name is dan allen and i have the
twitch handle at cyber test pilot
how to pcb i am completely self-taught
i
wanted to get into pcb design and i
found the youtube series uh by sean
himmel
sponsored by digikey it's a 10 part
keycad
video series and it walks you through a
very logical
progression from zero to hero
how to pcb from start to finish
where you can actually get something
fabricated and hold it in your hand that
you have designed i found that video
series fantastically helpful
and from there just launched my
inquisitive
mind to continue learning and see what i
can do in the space
along those lines
the free open source software tools that
i found and utilized throughout this
project
inkscape as a svg
editor for all the graphics
uh keycad the pcb manufacturing you know
software
files
i found a module svg2 mod this is very
helpful module to take the vector
graphic
files that inkscape would make and then
convert them to the keycad
module footprints that would then be
necessary so it's kind of like go
between inkscape and keycad where you
can join art and
engineering kind of at the same time
it's a command line script
and does the conversion for you
i use the arduino ide i stuck with the
micro controller the attiny 85 it was a
stock i was familiar with
in terms of purchase tools to actually
program my controller
and the sparkfun avr tiny programmer
retails for sixteen dollars
and then the icsp pogo adapter retails
for 12 dollars little kit you can get
from sparkfun
the two hardware components utilize to
actually program the micro controller
so we started at the aerospace village
from just an initial concept a top-down
view of an aircraft
you can see that we had initially uh the
designs for an adsb dipole antenna
coming out the wings we knew we wanted
an integral antenna that was tuned to
the 1090 megahertz frequency to be used
as a receiving device for
adsb messages
and then we had this kind of an
additional idea to have additional wire
leads being able to come out that can be
cut tuned to different frequencies
lengths to adjust for the frequencies
and so that we can have a mechanism to
have additional connections at that
point
so
from this initial concept design we have
to actually turn this into some
engineering and make some trade spaces
and concessions to actually get into
something that we can actually
manufacture
so the initial concept morphed into this
two engine top-down view of a 787
aircraft a boeing 787
you can see here that the dipole
antennas have been moved to be more
aligned with fuselage this is just a
practical length
extension where we can get that
perpendicular
or parallel rather dipole antenna setup
as it ran the entire length of the
fuselage
and then from a top-down view like let's
make it fun and aesthetically pleasing
let's add the anti-collision lights and
some navigation lights as well as some
flight deck lighting uh and then we use
the engines as an opportunity for the
sma connectors this is really fun
because
dimensionally it could kind of work out
where we scale the engine back from the
actual drawing and then kind of use the
additional space of the sma connector to
kind of protrude forward as the engine
cowling that was kind of a fun way to
play
the actual characteristic shapes of an
aircraft with actual components
that we're going to need to make the
badge functional
so this idea needs to get mapped to a
schematic
so here in this box here we've got the
uh a t tiny 85 it's pretty
uh
small form factor and also relatively
inexpensive microcontroller
and had this efficient amount of pin
outs that we needed for this project
down here in the lower left corner we've
got a switch
and connection to a battery so that we
can turn power on and off to the device
uh we've got a breakout here for i2c and
then ground and power so that we can
interact with the microcontroller
external
or easier
and then we've got the icsp connection
here so it's easy to program the
microcontroller
and then the two sma connectors here and
here so engine
on the left engine on the right
and then the remaining components are
simply the resistors and reverse mount
leds
that we use to achieve the lighting
effects
as we move on we need to make the parts
fit this is kind of an interesting trade
space
in my limited experience designing pcbs
you've got an idea of what you want
things to do and how you want them to
operate
but you have a form factor that's
limiting and you need to
make sure all the components fit
and
can be compatible with one another
real quickly
as we make the parts fit and this is
something that i learned in the design
process
it's good to have an understanding of
how you want to take the graphic uh but
eventually it has to be moved to the
keycad
footprint module and so knowing the
processes and steps that you have to go
through to get to the end state it is
helpful to take just a quick second and
walk through
the tool that we use to make that uh
inkscape to key cat format and that is
the svg
ii
mod
so if we go here this module that i
found online exactly as it states
converts inkscape svg drawings to kicad
keycap footprint
module files
command line tool
give it the input svg that we will
design in inkscape
and then export as we need to
i draw your attention to this because of
the layering
what they're talking about here what
svg2 mod is looking for is a specific
set of named layers in the inkscape file
this is helpful so that we can start to
organize
how we want the
inkscape files
to
uh be organized
so as we make the parts fit we'll jump
over to the inkscape file itself
these named layers are matching uh what
we want the svg to mod
we'll be able to pick up those named
layers and then export them to the
correct keycad
module footprint so
in pcb land thinking in layers
there's essentially four
color opportunities that you get to pick
from
there's the color of the copper layer
silver
typically
in color
there's the
solder paste color that you get to pick
most often that's green but depending on
the manufacturers that you go with you
can make it blue blue was the chosen
color for the final
version of the badge um in addition to
that on top of the
solder paste color you get typically
either a color white or black that's
called the silk screen
layer we got white
with this particular manufacturer
and then the other kind of fourth
uh perhaps neglected color is actually
the substrate color so if you could see
through the board it's the color that is
in the middle
uh so it's kind of a translucent almost
yellowish color but there's
opportunities to use that as a fourth
color
thinking in terms of layers
now we have an opportunity to outline
that in inkscape
and with svg2 mod in place or with an
understanding of how it works the first
layer we have selected here is the edge
cuts
i'm going to turn on the front copper
layer
here you'll see that
this is our
dipole antenna if you can see the value
up here it's
65.173 millimeters in length
and there's an equal one on this side as
well and that is to
be tuned specifically to the adsb
frequency of 1090 megahertz
interestingly enough the
um
length overall length of the badge was
more or less dictated by the length of
this dipole antenna
we squeezed as much as we could right
there
and equally similarly at the top so this
is a design consideration constraint
this is one of our bounding dimensions
is to make sure that we have sufficient
length for the antenna
for the navigation lights uh i found
through experience that using a copper
pore indicated by the entirety of the
black really kind of help to highlight
or isolate the light that we want to
shine through from the reverse mount led
it was kind of a nice little aesthetic
trick
you'll notice this black box here
and that is when it's combined with the
mask you'll see as i toggle them
the aerospace village logo
indicating that with the mask here
we would get no
uh
because um copper would not be copper
will be poured there but solder screen
mask
would copper will be poured in the
entirety of the black circle
but then solder screen mask the blue
will be absent where the black is here
now so we get the logo to shine through
in the same color as our copper pore
which was silver and then
draw your attention to
the flight deck lighting so the mask
this would go through to the substrate
and then because we also in the copper
pore here's the copper where black is
copper will be
and where the mask is solder paste will
not be this is kind of an idiom to get
used to
uh and it's even confusing as i vocalize
it
um
copper layer is where material will go
and then in the mask layer its wool
material will be um absent
when you put those together you're
actually going to get a um
a through layer all the way which is
exactly what we want because we want to
reverse
uh mount reverse light this flight deck
lighting and then also
the navigation lights
that are present on both edges of the
wing
the last decorative layer and this is a
little more straightforward to think
through is the silk screen
so this is just exactly where you want
the color white
to be printed
is where it will go and so in this
instance we've got silk screen
really helping us outline and sell the
shape of leading edge flaps trailing
edge flaps vertical stabilizer
horizontal stabilizer
over wing doors
just
exterior doors and so this
layer
is the silk screen
this svg2 i'm sorry this inkscape is
saved as an svg file and then run
through the svg2 mod
converter and at this point now we have
a keycad
file format that can be used and
imported into
the
next set of steps
prior to
moving things into to
kicad
uh i did want to kind of do an
operational
check verification that sizing of
components would still work for me it
was easier to print on a one-to-one
ratio and then just draw in with pencil
this is a
rough draft drawing of an idea that i
had as we're getting closer to the
progressive you know final stage
form factor i wanted to really make sure
that the sma connectors as roughly
measured would aesthetically look
correct
in terms of
replacement of the engine cowlings i
wanted to make sure that the battery
could be sufficiently hidden with the
retainer clip that hence the battery
in the middle of the graphic
my small representation of where the
microcontroller approximately will go
and then just kind of holding up some of
the reverse mount leds that i had chosen
like will these work out on that edge of
the wingtip
again one of the constraints was the
length of the overall uh adsb internal
antenna
once that was set to the minimum that it
could possibly be do i have sufficient
space to still sell the idea of
navigation lights here and then
anti-collision lights
here with sufficient space for battery
and power switch
so
this was a helpful step to make sure
that
conceptually physically the parts were
going to be compatible
with that work done we're ready to start
going into the
kycad
viewer
and
here
we've got the kicad program running i've
got just the edge cuts selected here as
our rough shape outline
we can turn on the front copper so you
recall from the inkscape
some of this will look very familiar
what we have now is additional wire
traces to connect the dipole antennas
uh footprints for the sma connectors
and
we can continue adding layers we can see
the back copper layer
at the grounding
for the
coin cell battery
we can start to get some of the
there in the back copper layer the green
we've got our no fill zone so our
reverse mount led is going to shine
through just that window
so to give us the kind of a clear focus
concise
version of what an anti-collision or a
navigation light rather would look like
out on the end
similar on the other wing and then we've
got
through hole leds these are white
leds for the strobe lights
and then we've got a similar kind of
layout reverse mount on the back copper
pore a light for the flight deck
lighting
with an understanding that the light
will as it's diffused will kind of
really go out and cover the entirety of
this window outlined by the front copper
pore
all of these things are working together
for us add to that the silk screen
layer
the back silk screen layer
and we are starting to get a badge that
has all of the components
lined up and we are getting very very
close to
fabrication
something i like in the keycad
viewer and i found this very helpful
is the
badge 3d viewer
or it's just the 3d viewer but in our
case this is the badge now and so
this was helpful to view
uh
set the blue color so i can see the
final form factor you can start to see
that the
silver is coming through for the bad
aerospace logo village
we've got our hole cut out here for the
anti-collision light we rotate this
all the components are fitting
we've got reverse
mount leds
uh the microcontroller with the
isp breakout for programming we've got
the switch
and
everything is
nearing completion at this point
so we have the kycad layers
we uh
bundle up the files uh from kican
they're called the gerber files you
bundle up the zip files you send them
off to the manufacturer
uh you wait number days weeks and then
you get your first version back
always a nail biter to see if it
actually works the first time
in this case pleasantly surprised
version one worked
it was incomplete
in that it didn't have initially like a
battery switch it or
the
external antenna connectors and this was
just kind of in the interest of a
compressed
timeline to make everything work uh some
of those initial considerations have
just been like foregone like let's get
something working this did have the
internal antenna
i did connect it
uh wire it up everything worked there
were no
shorts
um
but now in the redesigned version too
we've switched to the blue color the
final form factor we've added the
terminal connectors for the external
wires
here
if you can see these these are spring
loaded so that you can load a wire up
onto either side
and then it's wired now to one of the
sma
connectors
on the back
uh
showing it's got the switch
and another
the design consideration i wanted
everything to be
to the extent possible surface mount to
keep kind of all the business end on the
back end of the badge or the battery
um
and all the other components are the one
concession i made and this was
intentional was the through hole uh
components for the spring loaded antenna
connectors and that was just to provide
a mechanical
uh advantage so that these things can
are fairly rigid i was concerned that
with the surface mount component if
something got tugged on it the whole
component could come off
through hole kind of solidified that so
it's still on the
on the back side of the badge it's still
fairly concise
and then the front of course the top is
a clean badge the only exception is like
the connections or the sma
as they're a side mount component they
have a mechanical top and bottom part
which is fine
in case there's any again mechanical
tugging on there
so prototype version two
we had it wired it up hooked it up to an
rtl sdr
dongle
uh ran the dump 1090 and
lo and behold adsb and traffic in my
local area was being captured and picked
up i was like this is amazing this is
really fun again for a first time
badge manufacturing process uh new to
the industry new to the concept of even
doing it myself like something i had
designed was working to
effectively pick up aircraft it was the
antenna
but it was also aesthetically an
airplane so it's kind of iconic in that
sense
and that was a lot of fun and very
rewarding
it's working so we've got the navigation
lights on
the strobe lights are pulsing that was
fun to program kind of just from my
experience watching aircraft at night
the
approximate uh pulse cycle of how ni
collision lights work
so that was a fun little event to
code up on the microcontroller
and then the really super cool version
is at night where you really get the
highlight of the navigation lights and
then of course you really get the the
selling of the anti-collision lights
so
questions if you are at all interested
in making this for yourself the entire
thing has been
posted to my av badge 2020 github repo
[Music]
in here
we can
see the entirety uh all the components
all uh everything that i've gone through
is stored in this repo
so the pictures that you've just seen
kit assembly instructions programming
with the
arduino we even had a contributor add a
lanyard modification so you can
wear the badge easy enough with a chain
or a rope of some sort
all the files are here if you want to
modify it
make recommendations
pull requests certainly
advised requested please do so if you
want to make this better
in terms of
kycad if you're interested in making
this if you don't want to go through the
whole hassle of
redesigning everything yourself you are
more than welcome to grab this aerospace
badge version 2
dot zip if you take this zip file and
send it to the
pcb manufacturer of your choice
they will be happy to manufacture a pcb
just exactly as we've walked through
and then in terms of the parts list
we've got the entirety
of the uh
this is the uh
parts all the parts the csv
and then the bom
um
that may not load that's the xls so
github's not going to show me that but
you can download that
we made all the purchases from
digikey so all the part numbers and
links are referenced relative to ggk
great resource to
get all of the obscure individual
components for the
badge
and
uh approximate digikey purchase price
for all the bombs about 13 and then
again depending on your pcb manufacturer
you probably get five badges just pcb
probably delivered your door for
anywhere in the ballpark of like 10 to
15 dollars at the low end it might take
a month to get but
it's available
but
that is a walkthrough of the aerospace
village badge
presented at defcon
safe mode
thanks
so that's it
well thank you for
for being here uh the talk was amazing
um
we have a lot of of of different
projects here in the airspace and we
really love to see how the batch of
of the bilat was done so amazing
we are now in the q a
we have uh in the right
the the the questions of the people that
is watching the talk so in case we have
anything here
we can read it and just answer it
okay thank you very much
okay done
um
[Music]
i will have a question for you
how much time uh
you've been designing the pcb
batch
that's a great question so i consider
myself like i'm still learning uh i feel
like if i
with years of experience i could
probably
do that
uh same badge like recreate it probably
in like a 15 to 20 hour you know kind of
timeline but given that i was still
learning how to do it like exploring and
iterating through it probably that badge
took every bit of like 80 hours like
when you add up you know hand drawings
to
what is the microcontroller i'm going to
pick
uh to like coding it up
it gets pretty involved it ends up being
spread out over multiple weeks
wow great and how much iterations do you
have in the pcb i mean how how many
times you send it to
to
to make
to make the pcb and
need to making a game
yeah so i like again from trial and
error um the that badge was i think the
fifth pcb that like i had ever done
myself so like
in previous iterations it was just me
tinkering with the whole idea of
manufacturing and design of a pcb
when the aerospace village needed a
volunteer to make a badge like all right
let's i've got a skill set let's bring
it and help out um
that said i we were under a time crunch
so i knew that i couldn't have a whole
lot of iterations with the manufacturer
because it takes about uh the
manufacturer i was using about 10 days
to come back from manufacturing to mail
back to my house
so
um
i did like a whole bunch of work to make
sure
version one was good
um and then sent off version two as a
low batch but i was expecting and hoping
you know fingers crossed that version 2
was going to work
it did um and so then we took like i
think i ordered 10
for version 2 and then we went up to
full volume
for the order
once and as soon as i i was watching the
mail so as soon as the board got there
it was like my afternoon i had to do
this thing right now to make sure it
works so that in like an hour i can you
know commit the order to the bigger
number oh that's great
um i think that that we don't have so
much question now but i have one more i
think that with this question we can end
um so we have time to
to have the following talk um dan uh you
explained a little bit in in your talk
about how this idea uh grow up in in the
village um it was like a necessity it
was something like a challenge and how
it started this project
yeah so the aerospace village i think
you know had started initially at the
defcon conference
uh and the defcon conference has a big
badge life you know following
and so the aerospace village uh
initially was just the aviation village
and then as it relaunched you know for
year two it was the aerospace village
and it was getting bigger and it was uh
getting more name recognition more
branding like hey from the volunteer
corps like we should have a badge like
like all the other villages like we
should have a badge
and uh i was hungry i was like yeah like
this is like a good volunteer thing that
i can you know go sink myself my teeth
into
and uh help help the village out and i
kept asking like hey guys like i want to
help i want to help like where's the
team where's the team and they're like
there was ideas
um but not necessarily like
the capacity or capability for people to
do it so i was like all right i've done
this my free time you know at small
scale like let's just grow up let's go
do it and so a lot of fun but it was
great
a lot of people enjoy it
it's such a thrill too like to be at the
conference or to like have someone
wearing it and you're like oh my
goodness like i did that like that's
cool that's like a super rewarding okay
well done thank you so much for being
here in ecuador in part on space it was
great to have you
thank you so much to showing this crazy
idea
to show us how the pcb was designed
for sure we we will have some question
for you later i i'm sure about that
so i
i will share with you by email email or
maybe
at the
i don't know
any other way uh so thank you so much
for being here
yes thank you very much for having me
okay bye man