hello everybody my name is lucas and i'm
android malware and security researcher
at eset today i would like to share with
you our research about vulnerabilities
discard in android style career
if you thought that social media knows
everything about you you were right
however today i will tell you that there
are apps that know even more would you
like to know more
have you ever been feeling like spied
upon have you ever encountered strange
behavior of a smartphone have you ever
had a feeling that you know that
somebody knows but you don't know how
they know
they might know because they installed
stalker software in your smartphone
so what is stalk aware
simply put it's spying app
stalker needs to have physical access to
device
install the application
allow all the necessary permissions and
based on these permissions we can tell
what are the capabilities of the
software afterwards stalker wear is
hidden from the victim's view and it
might impersonate system applications
such as settings
where these apps could be downloaded
from
besides shady websites apparently they
were available even on google play store
imposing as a kit or employees price
resulting in fact that it wasn't that
difficult to install them whatsoever
precisely eight apps found on play store
were installed over 140 000 times
so the number speaks for itself
based on our data from our android
client devices as you can see in the
slides now
these apps have become more and more
popular in the last couple of years in
2019 we detected five times more
installs as in a previous year
last year detection increased up to 48
we see the popularity still on the rise
so
how can we make sure no one is looking
over our shoulder this problem has been
discussed and luckily for us it has been
sold how
by using manually or by using manual or
static analysis using trustworthy
security software that detects informs
and removes our uninvited cast however
its enormous popularity made us wonder
and worry about one more problem
who else might be watching
since stalkerware gathers more private
data about their victims than any other
app you have installed in your
smartphone right now
and i'm talking about the privacy and
security of victim information that
might be at risk since such software can
access
almost all the sensitive user data
when we picked one of the most popular
social media application and its
permissions to compare with style cover
it is
important to say that when social media
requests
a permission um there's option to allow
the permission either one time or during
using the application
contrary stalker where in order to work
properly all the permissions needs to be
checked as a result
the stalker has full access all the time
let's take a look
the phone on the right belongs to the
attacker
the attacker is not a stalker it's a
person that misuses security issues
found in stalker
victim and stalker are not aware of the
attacker or these actions
the phone on the left belongs to victim
the attacker sends text message to
victim
the victim receives a text message
text message is then processed by
stalker wear and it would trigger a
phone call
back to the attacker instantly opening
microphone spying opportunities without
a victim knowledge
please pay attention to upcoming slides
where we will deep dive and share with
you your research we'll focus on
security issues discovered in these apps
and then we will close all that with
responsible disclosure to affected
vendors
first thing first
question questions but from my big
question where from we gathered this uh
the applications the first one is from a
github it's talk about indicators of
compromise at that time there was around
um stalkerware apps then the list of the
top most popular detected style cover on
our site
paid advertisement pr articles top
google search because of that we
gathered information about
mobile stock aware vendors
mobile stalker is debated divided into
two main platforms
we focused only on android
and the reason is simple the market
share and the easiness
of site loading apps on android
comparing to ios device
when stalker
wants to install stalker where an ios
device he need the device needs to be
either jailbroken or he needs to already
have icloud credentials and there's one
more reason why we focused on android
from all the analyzed vendors
all of them provided solution for
android but only 37
for ios as well
so what we did what was our plan i wish
to analyze 86 or these 86 android style
cover vendors which were represented by
86 different android style cover apps
we went through
manual static and dynamic analysis to
observe its behavior capabilities
also we would like to state a fact that
this was not a full penetration test
we focus on privacy and security issues
actual impact on their clients victims
or company however the matter is really
serious
there are some limitations i would like
to go through them first because we
haven't paid for any of the software we
didn't want to support them we were
limited by the provided functionality of
apps and the full accessibility of admin
panel that is responsible for sending
commands receiving data storing them
still
we were able to fully test statically
and dynamically 72 apps 14 were limited
to static analysis only
what we are finding our results from 86
apps we found security issues with
serious impact in 67 percent of them
33 percent were bid out serious security
or privacy issue discovered
all together we identified 158
exploitable issues in these apps
now let's jump into particular problems
again
even because of the limitations we were
able to find
158 problems
there were different ones such as leak
on the network of the personal
information out of the victim on the
smartphone leak on the server
possibility to frame a victim
remotely control smartphone through text
message open directory leaks possibility
take to take over account
live stream from smartphone without any
authentication
and others i prepared two more video
demonstrations i will go through them
briefly
now let's go through the
the most serious issues discovered
let's start with http leak
what is this all about
22 stalker web apps use an unsecured
http protocol without additional
encryption of the data
um
to communicate with the admin panel and
let me explain that when stalker
first time installs stalker where in a
victim's smartphone he needs to either
create an account or log in
and for that
stockholder used the http protocol
because of that the attacker on the same
network using man-in-the-middle attack
could intercept the communication and
steal the credentials because of that it
could access the admin panel of the
stalker to remotely control smartphone
of the vector
besides credentials stall cover could
also download additional binaries
or modules or updates of themselves
which are bunny binary files executed by
style cover again attacker on the same
network could replace these binaries for
the malicious one and
trigger
remote code execution for these binaries
there was no integrity check
the most common issue
was
leak on the network of all the extracted
data from smartphones such as text
messages
phone call logs
gallery screenshots and camera phone
call um recordings etc
these were leaks on the network now
we'll move to the leaks on the
smartphone
leak of the personally identifiable
information of the victim what is this
about
when install cover processes all the
commands from the server
it needs to store the data somewhere
many of the style cover apps would store
these data on external shared media
where other apps installed on a
smartphone with them read the right
storage permission
for android below 10 could access these
files without additional permission
or any other permission
in one case stalker aware would store
admin token on the shared media and
because of that any third-party app
could steal the token excess admin panel
and then control smartphone of the
victim
some of the style covers provided key
logger functionality meaning they could
lock all user input from all apps these
key logs were not protected
and accessible to other applications
and they could lock synthetic
information
from other applications such as paypal
financial banking applications
including the passwords and the result
the takeover is possibility take over
other accounts of the user not just
stock aware
most frequently seen in device leak was
unprotectedly storing and extracting
data such as recording phone calls taken
photos screenshots and in some cases in
some apps
also calendar events browsing history
contact list phone number and received
text messages
from the league on the network through a
leak on the device let's move to the
link on the server
user data leaks through open directories
there are available data such as
weakness photos recorded calls details
about them such as names
physical addresses text messages social
media messages email addresses these
data were accessible without any
authentication for anyone
during analysis we discovered and tested
that manipulating with victims data
wasn't a problem at all
many apps used for pairing device and
the server account
unique device id such as ebay number or
android id instead of using server
generated token
however these device ids are easily
obtainable
by other apps installed on a smartphone
there are two impacts or two
malicious cases the first one if
stalkerware
uses http protocol to communicate with
the server it's possible for the
attacker on the same network to forge
data being uploaded from smartphone to
server such as text messages to create
custom one text messages photos
to frame a person to make her life a
little bit more difficult or even
blackmail her
second case scenario of the impact is
third-party apps could get the device
ids and then based on the ids upload
custom and fabricated data to the server
on behalf of the victim
in case there is no internet connection
some of the apps provided ability to
received sms commands however not all of
them verify if commands
are received from stalker and because of
that or someone else and because of that
anyone could
remotely
control victim's device by sending text
message but there are two things
necessary the first one are commands
for the attacker to know
these are available on the website of
the stalkerware the second is a phone
number of the victim
for that either attacker already knows
the phone number of the victim or it can
be extracted by a third-party
application
i prepared a video demonstration the
phone on the right belongs to the
attacker four on the left belongs to two
victim
the attacker sends text message to
the victim receives text message stalker
wearer wouldn't process that
and it would trigger
sharing
exact the gps location back to the
attacker or to whoever sent a text
message
of course gps needs to be enabled on the
victim's smartphone
let's continue with our
ability to start arbitrary components
because of unprotected exported
components defined in android manifest
it is possible to trigger restricted
stall cover functionality
as a result
any application installed on the device
could through stalkerware app without
proper permission or any other
permission take pictures
record calls record surrounding audio
take screenshots wipe data enable
disable gps reboot smartphone etc and
afterwards access these data since they
are stored on external again shared
media
what happens when spying ends this
this is a photo taken by a stalker wreck
of my ceiling
while it was lying next to me
unfortunately it is still stored and
accessible on the server even though the
stalker in this case me
removes data logs
on the link's smartphone
and removes full account
besides my photos are on the server
still stored my text messages
and my call logs
in other cases of stalker where data are
not removed immediately when requested
by stalker but rather it takes 90 extra
days to be deleted
let's continue with hard coded secrets
this is not
about the token or password as you might
expect
rather just server links that are
responsible
to trigger live stream from particular
device where stall cover is installed
what's this about
in app there are hard-coded links three
links that could through server trigger
live stream from particular device
the only thing that is necessary is
device id
however these device ids
are stored on external shared media
by stalkerwear and because of that they
are accessible to other apps installed
on a smartphone with them read write
storage permission
i prepared the video demonstration for
that
where on the left side we have
smartphone on the victim where the style
cover is already installed and then we
have three windows the top one is our
notepad that contains three links
and we appended device id that were
found in application browser and the vlc
where we now try to watch a stream
however this is not accessible right now
first thing we need to do is to make two
get requests to server and if the server
returns through
it means that it would enable a live
stream from a smartphone without any
authentication to ever request them
victim can't see anything happening on
the smartphone
so these were the the most um
prevalent security issues discovered in
the stalker web apps
after we identified them
we reported them to affected vendors
we follow 90-day disclosure practice
by contacting affected vendor up to
three times we contacted the stalker
vendors through either email or creating
a support ticket through their website
in two case cases we could not reach the
vendor
without the results of the fixing issues
from
all the affected vendors 10 of them
fix the issues within a 90-day
disclosure period
12 of the vendors
replied back
to to our request and promised us to fix
them but the fix the patch was not
delivered within a 90 days
of the affected vendors did not reply
back
or fixed the problem
because of that we decided not to
publish a full list of the vendors the
applications and connect them with
particular problem security
vulnerabilities
now before summary let's go quickly to a
compromise scenario and a couple of
prevention tips
so when stalker wants to install style
co-wear and a victim smartphone
needs to have he needs to have physical
access to device which means it needs to
know a pin or pattern to unlock a device
and then install side load the
application allow all the necessary
permissions and then stalker where is
hidden from the victim's view
what
the victim can do before that to
um
prevent that happening
make sure to have enabled lock screen uh
either you spin a password or a pattern
and if you believe someone knows your
pin or got access to your device make
sure to download install and then scan
your smartphone with a trustworthy
security software that will
automatically detect detect stalker
where and gives option to remove it
compromise sign
so this might tell if you have installed
stall curve in your device
there is a higher
battery drains faster since there's a
lot of
communication on the smartphone and a
lot of tasks being done
um higher internet consumption again
there is communication being being done
between the server and the smartphone
gps wi-fi or mobile data might be
enabled or disabled by itself without
user interaction
there might be a suspicious
persistent notification a notification
bar most of the time is invisible
but there is some something something
there you will notice that
photos screenshots all your recordings
stored in your smartphone even though
they were not done by the user
and there might be or you might have
received questionable text messages
which means
they might be a
sms commands sent from the admin
so
to summarize number of used detected
based on our data android's talk aware
has been increasing in the last couple
of years
style cover apps gather store transfer
transmit
a lot of personal information of the of
the victim
many of them have security issues and as
you saw we discovered 158 of them
unfortunately their vendors don't really
care about fixing fixing them
saying something about 78
did not even reply back not to fix them
we would like to appeal to anyone who
might be thinking of using such software
to reconsider that using stalkerware to
spy on your spouses it's not just
unethical but it also reveals private
and intimate information about them but
also about those who install it and want
to spy on their close ones
thank you very much for your attention
enjoy more talks to come