thanks
this is a joint presentation of some
work done collectively by L català
cisco and juniper and the history of
this work starts at a nana and wash
there was a security involved and
someone had mentioned that
they would md5 authenticate their bgp
peering sessions if there was a way to
update keys without bouncing the bgp
session well
I remember that comment
later on
there was another nanog i think in
seattle where
talked about how many people were
actually md5 authenticating BGP and
surprisingly small number of people were
actually authenticating well how does
that work another customer reminded us
that we needed something better as far
as authenticating BGP peering and for
that matter all tcp tcp based routing
protocols so this work came out of this
acha the motivation
not enough operators
cating current practice RFC 2385
local operator requirements
and
basically there are a couple reasons why
they aren't using it one is CPU
utilization apologize for the first
bullet there to these slides before it's
a joint presentation it's not so much in
an issue for Juniper or Cisco or alcatel
because forwarding and control
processors are separated so CPU
utilization
so much so much an issue he management
it is an issue
there is no way to refresh the
md5 key without bouncing the bgp session
correctly and the other thing that's an
issue is the cryptography is weak there
are many well-known attack 25
so we need we knew we needed to come up
with something better than RFC 2385 the
question is what would it be would we do
something in the application and the
transport layer or in the network
we could have done it in the protocols
on something
authentication and bgp something an ldp
at msdp in fact pgp used to have an
authentication mechanism inside of it
that was recently deprecated because
used it we could have used TLS again
authenticating at the application layer
and we decided against that because
although it would authenticate the BGP
payload would bother people well it
would authenticate the BGP the TCP
payload it wouldn't authenticate the TCP
control information so we would still be
vulnerable to things like blind
insertion attacks where the reset bit is
set so we decided not to authenticate at
the application layer our two choices
were to do it at the transport layer
with yet another TCP option or to do it
with a hike ipsec and we decided to go
the transport layer route and we'll talk
about why in a little bit but before we
talk about why we made that decision
let's talk about the solution we came up
with
the solution is characterized by a TCP
authentication option the option has in
it a message authentication code and a
number the number identifies one of many
keys that could have been used to
generate the Mac now where do these many
keys come from on both systems to
sending and receiving system we manually
configure a keychain a keychain is a
list of keys the sending system decides
which key to use based on time it
generates the Mac it generates the TCP
option that has the neck and the key
identifier in it sends it to the
receiving system it has the same key
chain looks for the appropriate key does
the
another characteristic is we can use
some stronger cryptography rather than
using md5 to authenticate you can use H
max shell 196 CMAC aes-128 96 for that
matter we can use any authentication
algorithm but these are the two that
most recommend it
this is a look at the new tcp option
like a neat ECT option that starts with
a kind and a length the t NK bits we'll
talk about in a little bit the
algorithm ID tells you what algorithm we
use to generate the Mac the key ID tells
you which key off the keychain we use to
generate the Mac
so a look at the key chain keychain
contains up to 64 keys each Key has an
identifier and authentication algorithm
a shared secret and a start time and an
end time actually to be more accurate it
has a start time and an end time both
for receiving and transmitting and those
don't have to be the same typically the
end time for receiving will specify a
wider window than the end time for
transmitting and that way we deal with
clock skew when the sending and
receiving systems have their clocks set
a little differently
so
let's take a closer look at how the
authentication scheme works
the sending systems first job he has a
tcp segment he wants to send out first
thing he has to do is identify the
active key on its on its key chain it
does that based on time
ok
a little closer to the mic okay it
identifies the act of key based on time
basically it's looking for a key whose
start times less than the current time
and end time greater than the current
time if there are no candidate keys at
all the sending system discards the
outbound bakit if there are multiple
candidates it selects the key with the
most recent start time for sending
having selected the active key it
calculates a Mac it calculates the Mac
over the TCP pseudo header TCP header
and TCP payload and by default that
includes the TCP options except of
course for the option that is
calculating then it assumes that the mac
is 0 going back to the T bit it's
possible that you don't want to include
the options because you have some middle
box on the line if you set the tee bit
that means that the options are not
included
any out sending system formats the
enhanced authentication option and sends
it out now the receiving system gets it
first thing it does is look at the key
identifier on the option make sure it
has that key if it doesn't it throws the
packet away next thing it does is make
sure that the key is not expired if it's
expired it throws it away if it's if it
has the key and it's not expired it
calculates the matok if the mount get
calculates is equal to the mat gets
received and it accepts the packet
otherwise it declares an authentication
error in the case of an authentication
error the receiving system discards the
Datagram logs and it doesn't send any
indicator to the originator that's very
important also it does it doesn't play
with any of the counters in TCP if the
packet does not pass authentication
okay here we have a couple of
configuration examples one from juniper
another from alcatel and we have another
Francisco but unfortunately I don't have
it on this slide deck so we'll update
the slide deck before it's posted to the
web page in any event that's the
presentation before I open the floor to
questions I'd like to ask a couple
questions of the audience how many of
you are authenticating ibgp sessions now
and how many are not well so the
majority are actually authenticating now
um how many of you
are interested in a better way to update
keys okay that's the same girl okay open
the floor to questions now
not at all
not one Russ Bundy are you planning on
taking this work into the ietf so it
gets published through that process yes
it's already been introduced to the DC
p.m. working group was presented at our
piece Atkins ag2 we're waiting for some
feedback to see if we can progress the
work any further but also appreciate any
support you could give us on the side
working group mailing list ok thanks
hi Jay hi Ron were there any simpler
proposals
the there were literally this was
designed for the IETF there were no
alternative proposals other than the
ones that we put up in the first slide
and rejected ourselves this seems pretty
meeting
Steve velvet Columbia University no
longer security ad the idea two things
one and I know the questions come up on
the sack list you tell me more about why
you're rejecting I can i pee sexes that
does all this it really does far more
which is deliver does what you're asking
for two why not tie the algorithm to the
key get it out of the header it won't be
as for ID or something else okay I'll
answer the first question the second
question first since it's easier
actually the algorithm could be taken
out of the key and put in
well actually let me clarify the
question you asking why the algorithm is
in the TCP option as per Wyatt's and the
key is what wise and why isn't the DCP
options set of associated with the key
okay actually that's the kind of comment
that we're looking for in the ITF we
argued both ways whether it should be in
the option or not and I'm kind of up in
the air as to whether it wants to be or
not one argument for putting it there is
it's a very quick way to check without
actually calculating a Mac so you can
throw away some some attack packets
before you've actually calculated a Mac
but personally I'm not married to that
idea the second question is actually the
more interesting one why not use Ike and
here you're talking about Ike with just
authentication of course nobody they
should just idle perceive
here and out that most other people do a
grave loot there's probably no need for
confidentiality we talked about that and
there were a couple possibilities one is
to just just use IPSec with pre-shared
keys but then you have the same problem
of having to roll up roll over the keys
you need some way to either negotiate
keys once you've done that you need some
way to authenticate as it turns out
those are all probably good ideas what
we would like to do is do this in a
first phase to have just a way to do
manual key rollovers in a second phase
people will talk about things like how
you'll negotiate a key for one time use
my question I like be set Ori
using including pre-shared key mode for
I do I will negotiate a key and
authenticated get summer session okay if
you needed appreciate if you were to use
pre-shared key mode for right you'd need
something like this to roll over the
pre-shared key in the first place
because there are many people with
access to the router
that
this is a large topic that's probably
about to brew on the sack mailing list
there was some activity on that this
weekend
is there
I think you made the right choices and
thank you thanks
very green Francisco the answer Steve's
question and maybe or the Randy's
question why is this a little bit more
complicated it's because of the being
able to have multiple keys and rolling
over I mean you know we've had NB 5 out
there for years and we kind of some of
you guys both networks out there we've
had their keys the same key for like 10
years because you can't change them out
without dropping off sessions so I think
the one of the dominant themes is to
have a way where you can have in OC 768
sessions and have a hitless rollover
about the key which I didn't allow that
I mean looking into it we couldn't find
a way what we can get that done on the
bike so this is going to be from IETF
because this originally started with the
question business going to begin to the
IETF think the question is this isn't
the way that people have been thinking
about doing IETF this is very much an
operational operator giving sort of
requirement which is having that fit
let's roll over of the key
thanks
jaron watch itt America Jerry hi so I'm
just gonna ask my question in public you
you already know it so how do I go in
take my internal ibgp session and roll
the key from existing md5 infrastructure
to this without making the nanog mailing
list ok we we need a solution to that
problem and look forward to version 5 of
the draft
yes Bora killed for broadcom the comment
about Ike being able to not roll over
cheese without without a kit is kind of
incorrect if you did I could be one that
the ipsec assay is that you would use
are not coupled to the I guess I so in
fact you can lose your I kisses have
your IP sagesse Ricky or I can say and
that in the meantime we establish your
IP succession so that I this is what I
CLE one I kleeto unfortunately couple
these together but I don't quite
understand in this environment while
we're so hung up on pre-shared key
because just like you're exchanging Keys
across if you were exchanging
certificates between two service
providers or within the same source
water which to me is a non-issue then I
should be able to suffice because with
Ike every time you do have a new session
you regenerate the keys so maybe I'll
participate in the mailing list and kind
of discuss this further there I agree
with Steve's comment here that you're
basically doing a lot of the stuff that
I can I protect us all over again
nothing wrong with that is just that
maybe we should try to reuse some of
what we have okay
perak so here's here's a so in changing
the keys you got to think of it this way
and a lot of you who run networks and
advantage 75 you know this light so what
you want to prevent is a Colo meet this
column meets are a pain in the butt so I
want to set my key you know here's my
new key my okies working here's my new
key that's send the email message over
to Jared and say hey Jared I didn't
reset my keys and Jared's not even a
look at it you know it looks very easy
meal I'll look at it next week and I
finally look at it and said okay I'm go
ahead and set the key here's a new key
and it rolls over and there's no hit and
nobody knows about so you got to look at
not only how do you roll over keys on
like OC 768 when you can't afford like
you know a half a second otherwise the
customers see it you're also got to
realize how people operate their
networks and work with it in a system
that you know works how they work and
everybody squeeze the time and things
like that so that's where some of the
constraints were running running into
with this and why this is shape out to
be different so we encourage people to
participate I think sag is the IETF form
where this is being conversed about
right now
there that's a good place to join up at
least for this time period of this
discussion
looks like it thank you very much
you