and from as you can tell from the last
two talks still popular however for as
much as people like to talk about d das
nobody really likes to talk about what
you as an organization or what your
organization clients can do if your
targeted by one and there's very few
resources that exist within the
community or in the government that can
help you figure out what to do if you
are in fact targeted by a DDoS attack so
what I hope to do today is give you an
idea of what you can do if you are
targeted err what you can tell your
clients to do and the only way that you
can properly really defend yourself or
take legal action in the future against
this is by collecting proper information
okay so the United States Secret Service
reports that less than 0.1 percent of du
das attacks in an arrest 0.1 percent
that's not a very good number and you
also have to take into consideration
that this is only the number that is
actually reported which min ed Dossett a
aren't even reported to the authorities
and this is also the only the attacks
which fall within the US Secret
Service's jurisdiction now this number
might not shock or scare a lot of you
out there many people tend to think of d
das as a non serious crime that doesn't
really have any victims but it does and
so I want to run over some of the last
numbers with you just to prove you know
how this does really hurt company's
first example is one major US
corporation lost over two million
dollars in a 20-hour outage and this is
a corporation to that doesn't even
depend on the internet for generation of
its core revenue in offshore gambling
company lost Nesta mated four million
dollars in just three days an online
payment processor lost four thousand
dollars in under 72 hours and a
canadian-based online retailer
lost twenty thousand dollars per day and
they had downtime periodic downtime over
three weeks and just to quantify this to
this is all on US dollars and so you
know I hope that these numbers you know
do impact you this is quite a bit of
money here that people are losing as a
result of DDoS and this doesn't even
take into account to kind of the
indirect losses from a DDoS attack which
are things like damage to the brand name
the money spent on bandwidth bills who
are the money spent to actually mitigate
the attack just to go back to the
canadian online retailer i just
mentioned they spent sixteen thousand
dollars in bandwidth bills fifty-five
thousand dollars on a hardware
mitigation device which ultimately
failed for them they spent over ten
thousand dollars on data center moves
they got kicked out of three different
data centers do the ddos attack because
often when these tax come in to data
center they'll knock all the data
centers clients offline not just the
client at the targeting they also spent
twenty thousand dollars on their
existing itune contain security
consultants and then another six
thousand dollars on adidas on another
dude awesome negation service which
failed to and didn't end up properly and
mitigating the attack so now the
question is what what can you do about
this you know well if this was if
somebody came in and stole this type of
money from your company or extorted it
you could easily go to your police local
police station and tell them and they
would investigate it and arrest those
responsible however if you go to your
local police and tell them that you're
under a ddos attack they're going to
have no clue what it is and even if you
go to your local FBI field office and
they happen to have a division of
cybercrime you're not going to get a
response very fast and when you do get
one it's kind of negligible how good
it's going to be and this is because
cybercrime is a relatively new area for
law enforcement and it's not really
staffed with knowledgeable people who
can investigate these cotton crimes so
the question is really now how can you
help yourself
and you can help yourself best by
collecting basic information that you
can give to the authorities to help them
and also this information will help you
go to other knowledgeable resources on
the internet and get help so the first
thing obviously that you have to do is
get a packet capture and the best source
of course for this packet capture is the
machine that's on our attack however if
the machines under attack it's probably
not going to be available over the
network kind of the fun caveat so what
you hope for then is that you know you
should either have the device on console
or you're going to need to get the
information from an upstream device a
fibertap aamir port whatever and you
need to take this site well your teeth
to be dumb you need to remember a couple
important options on this lower case n
that's so TCP dump doesn't resolve the
host names and you give yourself
secondary DNS flood if you also need to
use dash lowercase s 0 that's to send
the snap link to catch the entire length
of the packet and this is so you can
look over the payload of the attack a
payload of the packet later and you also
need to use the dash capital C option so
you can limit your dump file your pcap
files 25 megabytes surrender and the
reason why you want to make them a
smaller size is so they're easier to
open and like protocol analyzed program
like ethereal or whatever you're using
later if you make them too big it's
going to be problem and when you first
fall under attack you want to take about
three or four of these packet captures
and about a 15-minute period and for the
duration of the attack you should be
taking a small packet capture about
every three or four hours and this is so
you can just get a nice bod view of the
attack and can determine if it has
changed at any point in time also so now
what you're going to do from these
packet captures is you know playing back
you're going to want to determine the
type of the attack which is something i
don't really have time to go over in
this presentation but if you can't
figure out what type of attack it is
there's always people out there who can
help you so i suggest that you get help
and next thing you're what going to want
to do is obtained a complete
of lists of source ID resource IP
addresses as possible and those source
IP addresses sending you the malicious
traffic that's what comprises the botnet
obviously and to do this you're going to
want to just generate like a larger
probably tcp down plain text file then
you can use awk or whatever other
scripting fancy thing you want to to get
a list of addresses that go to the IP
port combination that's under attack and
we're also going to want to save any and
all visual material related to this to
the attack that's all bandwidth graphs
floated a pack up per second graphs just
anything to demonstrate you know kind of
the size the volume of the attack and
one of the most important pieces of
information that people routinely
overlook is any communication from the
attacker a lot of times even something
as simple as like a chat log from a
customer service where they're getting
warning of the attack a lot of time
attackers like to go and threaten with
the forehand either by email or
contacting someone in customer service
you need to save this because this can
be really critical and identifying the
attacker later and also there's a point
that I left off the slides here and this
is something you'll want to go to your
management to get and it's the actual
loss figures like how much this attack
is costing you for downtime either per
hour or per day and the reason why this
is critical is that at least in the US I
know it's a little different in the UK
it's under like the computer misuse act
in the US and center section 18 of some
law but you have to substantiate damages
over five thousand dollars at least for
any like hacking or DDoS attack before
you can take any legal action against
whoever's doing it so you need to have a
way definitely to substantiate your
losses okay now all this sounds really
easy to talk at all this is really easy
to talk about but it's not necessarily
so easy to do and what you need to do is
you need to have a plan if you or any of
your clients come under a ddos attack
it's a very stressful stressful
situation you're going to be dealing
with angry customers you're going to
have freaked out management you're going
to have
stressed out engineers and every company
has to really come up with a plan that
works for them but i can give you kind
of some pointers of how to put to get up
how to put one together you need to have
a like a point person or team already
pre-designated to collect the
information that I've just mentioned on
a du das attack you need to have a point
person or team assigned to deal with the
customer calls because there's going to
be a lot of them you need to have a pre
prepared statement to give your
customers or business partners because a
lot of companies don't like to actively
acknowledge that they've kind of come
under ddos that's something you need to
decide beforehand and yeah I think
that's about it also for you or any of
your clients good monitoring doesn't
have to be expensive you don't have to
have like an arbor box you know you can
easily put a fiber or gig e card into a
little 1u rackmount box and you can
mirror traffic off of a border router a
good note for this is that you're going
to want to limit it to 100 re limit at
200 megabits a second or lower anything
more than that and you get a lot of
traffic in it's probably going to kill
the box if you try to run TCP dump on it
so you don't necessarily have to get all
the traffic you just want to get a good
sampling of it the other thing is too is
that a graphing is obviously something
that is one of the first things deployed
and set up in a network but a large
attack can often knock all your your
graphing systems offline but remember
that you can always retrieve this data
from an upstream provider all you have
to do is ask and be nice they'll give it
to you okay so now the next step that
we're going to take here is like you've
already got your basic information you
might be asking why can't I just go give
this to the FBI no and walk away well
you can but they're not going to move
very fast and if your site or your
client site is still down you might as
well go the extra mile because a lot of
times if you provide the your law
enforcement with extra
a data they'll make that much more I
mean your case looks that much better
and they're much more willing to go out
there and investigate it for you so what
you want to do now is actually track
down the bot net source code that's
being used and to do this you're going
to want to use your list of source IP
addresses the first thing you want to
look for is a network that you already
have a contact with you know if you have
a friend at a network it's going to be
much easier to work with them than
anybody else if you don't have if you
don't see anything anyone in there that
you recognize you're going to want to
look for either reputable us hosting
company or reputable you hosting company
I'm you're going to need to approach the
network through the abuse contact give
them as much information as possible on
how the machine you know on how the host
that you picked out how it's involved in
the attack how you determine that it was
involved in the attack you're going to
want to be really calm patient and
persistent because a lot of abuse
contacts there initially answered by
knock people and knock personnel aren't
going to necessarily know what you're
talking about so it might take you a
while to work your way to an engineer
who's actually willing to help you once
you've actually found it an engineer who
does understand what you're talking
about and who is willing to help you you
obviously want to be you know really
nice to them and the information you're
going to try to get off the infected
machine netstat TCP dumps who's
currently logged in web blogs access
logs of course whether or not you get
this information is really dependent on
the hosting facilities policy and the
owner of the machine but getting this
information isn't necessarily critical
that your goal here is to actually find
the source code so your key thing is
just to provide help and support to
whatever engineer you're working with to
find that source code on the machine
this process can take anywhere from
hours to weeks literally and even at
Prolexic when we have a huge contact
list established just for this purpose
and sometimes it's still difficult even
for us to do it so obviously once you
actually get the source code the bonnet
source code
you want to save this oh and one of the
things i forgot to mention earlier
that's very very critical is you really
need to save all of your information to
a central location in the early days of
Prolexic we didn't have a central
repository for all of our information
that we collected and as a side effect
of that some of the early data on the
first attacks we got is lost and we can
ever get it back so don't make that same
mistake everything you get put it in a
central spot and keep it there because
especially under stressful situation
things get lost you'll never find him
again okay so now that you have the
source code you're going to want to
examine the source code obviously
scripts are the easiest look at them you
know what's going on however most bot
code is compiled code and so it's not
that easy so you're going to want to
unpack the exe run strings on it usually
what you get ad is a lot of gibberish
okay like what does this mean you look
at it in context do DIA impact exe you
go through what you're looking for is
any sort of identifying markers list
bars who wrote the code a lot of times
people will put their nicknames in there
they'll put group names sometimes leave
their real name you never know what
you're automatically looking for is the
IP address and the port of the
commanding the control server usually it
will be in there in plain text so you
want to get that out the worst case
scenario is that you can't find any
information that you understand yet and
the reason why I say yet is that a lot
of this information depends on context
and so just because you can't put it in
the proper context right now doesn't
mean you won't be able to later I won't
be able to with some other piece of
information that you get so once you've
actually looked at the source code you
want to write yourself kind of a nice
little summary pick out all the key
information and then you're going to
want to save that to a central location
along with the source code itself okay
so now that you actually have the IP
address and port hopefully of the
controlling server you either got this
from the source code or you can also get
it from
the connection table of one of the
infected host machines that's been
attacking you and what you're going to
want to do is verify this so that means
you're either going to tell that to the
IP port combination or connect with an
IRC client to the command and control
server and I'm assuming that most of you
know what an IRC you know server answers
like so you'll be able to recognize it
now the process for cotton for getting
this I receiver IRC server shutdown is
very similar to the process that you
took to locate order to get your the
information off your infected host
you're going to need to go through the
abuse contact words hosted you're going
to need to be calm patient persistent
again and explain the situation it's
going to take you a while to get to
somebody who even knows what you're
talking about and even when you do get
to somebody that you're talking about
most people are very reluctant to just
disconnect a machine from their network
based upon what you're saying that oh
this is can this is controlling you know
a huge attack against me most people
won't believe you so if you haven't got
law enforcement involved yet now is the
perfect time to do so because they can
often help you they will get FBI will
get warrants to get machine set shut
down and and seized but you know you
this is something that it's not a quick
process FBI doesn't get warrants within
an hour this takes some time so you have
to be very patient now I've mentioned
kind of several times that abuse
contacts are difficult to deal with
especially when it comes to DDoS you
know slow process people are very
reluctant to believe what you have to
say and I think this raises a really
good question of how to improve
awareness of this in the community and
how to get legitimate requests answered
in a timely fashion or forwarded to
someone who knows and can answer them I
don't have a good answer I'm just
throwing this out there is a question
okay all right so for this next part
this is actually finding the attack or
the person who is responsible for maybe
writing the code or at least launching
the attack against you and this is where
I have to issue a big huge
disclaimer if you don't know what you're
doing if you don't know how to hide your
identity well your location well don't
attempt this most attackers or angry ex
employees they could be possibly
affiliated with organized crime unless
you really know how to hide who you are
don't go after them they find out who
you are you're just as likely you're
totally likely to have them turn on you
and that won't be pleasant thing so
first thing you want to do is you know
review all the information you have so
far you know kind of maybe get a feel
for who this person is so then you need
to contact the attacker and you usually
do this on the IRC server that he's
already sitting on any information that
you get out of him you obviously want to
save and log all these conversations
because they're going to be very useful
for later there's a big caveat here
though and that's that any conversations
that occur on a private IRC server
aren't admissible in court usually
that's why these conversations occur on
a public IRC server it's much for the
better it's really it's really horrible
to get to a point where you actually
have somebody that you're going to
persecute for one of these attacks and
your key evidence is something that
can't even be used so public servers
good private servers bad hopefully the
information that the attacker gives to
you will help you piece together the
attack from a high level and kind of put
together you know what's going on what
his motivations are perhaps where he is
in the world however this really isn't
very easy most attackers are highly
motivated and highly skilled individuals
it's usually a matter of waiting for
them to slip up all right so I've been
talking about this whole time resources
you can go to either with law
enforcement or resources in the
community here are the resources that i
am referring to your local FBI field
office most of them will have a division
of cybercrime those that don't will
refer you to the next largest city that
does have a division of cybercrime
Department of Homeland Security I really
haven't worked with them much so I can't
give you my input I just know that they
do handle cases like this cert you can
certainly send your information to them
I've
were actually received any help from
them that you can send it to them the
guys that come we are absolutely great
if they have the time and the means they
will absolutely help you they will help
you to identify types of attacks you
know if they have it even within their
power they will help you to mitigate
them if you're in Europe the NH TCU has
a cybercrime division and I think that
that's now been changed to where
cybercrime actually resides in the local
field offices like it does with FBI one
of the resources that I find most
helpful is loco US Secret Service
there's some my favorite to work with on
this they have a division of electronic
crimes and yes your local US Secret
Service Service office does have this
and then a new resource that engineers
at Prolexic are working at putting
together is ddos DB org and what's going
to be on there is how to identify or
recognize you know different types of
attacks you know basic descriptions what
is d das all my notes and this
presentation from today will be on there
and hopefully soon will either get to
release part or all of our internal
attack database to the public and I'm
hoping that this will encourage other
people to put their attack information
there so we can kind of build a way to
like identify our profile botnets and
hopefully it will become a central
repository for that kind of information
all right now to kind of go through how
this whole data collection forensic
process works I want to go through two
case studies with you and the first one
is the success story and it involves the
tracking of an attack series named x3m
one st or exe he was responsible for
hundreds of extortion based DDoS attacks
we documented all the information on him
tracked him for months it eventually led
to a successful rest here's kind of a
high overview of had a tact function the
attacker basically hid behind four
levels of hacked servers to conceal his
identity and the bonnet was comprised of
you know mix of general machines on the
internet
exploited by a variety of different
methods and obviously all malicious
traffic was then directed at the current
attack target one of my co-workers was
actually the tracker on this case and
exe Nia's group only talked on private
IRC servers so you can see the problem
here none of the information we collect
it from them could ever be used to build
a case against them however one day exe
made the mistake of connecting from his
home computer under a domain actually
registered to his real name at his real
address this was the slip-up we had been
waiting for so as soon as we got this
turned it over to the nht see you and
that information combined with a lot of
information from other sources led to a
successful rest just a few months later
so that is actually exe AKA ivan being
arrested in russia and the next attack
is a lot more interesting in my opinion
and this these series of tax or named
peak lagrima or abba and where you can
really pronounce that however you want
to mount a real word the interesting
thing about this attack is that for its
zombies the infected hosts this guy
targeted linux machine specifically Red
Hat Linux machines and the difference
between the Linux machines like this and
kind of your average home user boxes
that they hit him they sit on much
higher bandwidth connections and the
exploit that he used to infect the
infected machines was mostly a common
cross-site scripting vulnerability and
PHP in which you take the query string
and you insert it right as an include
file or executed on the machine without
doing any validity checking but he was
pretty crafty he also used it my SQL
injection he used holes in popular
control panel cold like cpanel and holes
in a lot of the popular shopping carts
to recruit machines he also actively
browsed the O'Day list and she could
adapt his code I mean basically when I
saw in under an hour for any to exploit
so he was creative blow guy um same it's
the same basic scenario here he hid
himself behind multiple layers you know
big botnet
tax a single target everybody kind of
knows how that works the result of
having such powerful buzz having such a
powerful botnet was a syn flood that
spiked over 10 gigabits per second
problem with a flood like this is that
it knocked a lot of our upstream
providers offline and also got a snow
around null routed outbound on a lot of
the other larger telco networks just due
to the amount of outbound traffic to our
network people having so many infected
hosts on their network that it causes I
about flood for them which is always fun
on this particular case I was the
tracker I had a lot of interesting
conversations with this guy I learned
that he was being paid by an employer he
wouldn't mentioned to me and I learned
that he had done this actually multiple
times before for other employers and
unfortunately what happened with this
guy was that he eventually disappeared
but before that I was able to also get
out of him that he English was a second
language he always logged in from hack
university servers and also that he was
attacking other sites about six other
sites that happened to sell the same
product as the client that we were
protecting and when I actually went to
our clients and told them this not only
were they not surprised but they said it
made perfect sense they'd actually been
threatened via the phone over phone
several times by competitor trying to
force them out of business so once we
kind of put all this together oh yeah
that and the fact that this attack
occurred right before Christmas and over
Christmas which is the busiest time for
any retailer so this kind of goes to put
together the picture that this was
corporate sabotage I spoke with abba for
weeks he never really gave up anything
about himself this guy was probably the
one of the most professional I've ever
dealt with which would go with the fact
that he said that he's been doing this
for quite a while it became really
difficult to obtain further information
because he was always logged in from
either China or Japan those countries
can be a bit difficult to work with
especially China
and so the end result was that I turned
over all the information to the FBI and
let them pursue the case further so
everything that I brought up today I
think leaves us some big kind of issues
to address in the community and that's
better abuse contacts maybe one
specifically for d das we also don't
have any centralized repository
specifically for ddos profiling like we
do for worms and viruses I mean I'm
hoping you'd ask doobie org my head in
this direction I don't know I realize
that this information gathering is
extremely intensive but it's very worth
it you know not only to you but to
others also no wedding IP space due to
large amounts of outbound malicious
traffic is not a good option anymore if
this happens probably your network needs
to be cleaned up a little bit the shoe
other please i want to make your one is
that you shut down recursive sore open
recursive DNS servers on your network
the others that everybody out there and
instigate some stricter spoofing rules
and bottom line is that deed haces
everybody's problems so i want to get
everyone involved in solving it and
that's it so thank you very much for
listening
Matt PTAC yahoo one tip for people if
you are likely to be a victim of DDoS
attacks it's very useful to have a dsl
connection or of some other connection
totally unrelated to your normal up
streams that you can use for sending
email looking up who is records doing
other contacting even just dns lookups
because it really really sucks when you
can't get to the rest of the internet
and you're trying to debug these things
well said hi Mike use links um comment
about the nht see you and what's
happened to the nht see you and that
they've been rolled up into an
organization called the Serious
Organised Crime Agency or soccer and
there's a genuine concern in the UK and
the nht see you have been really helpful
in the past but there's a genuine
concern that some of the e crime stuff
is going to fall down the gap because
it's like well level one sort of petty
crime go to your local plod soccer is
far more interested in sort of level 3
organized crime drug rackets and things
like that and sort of extortion and
hacking and Andy dose is like kind of
well it's not as bad as the drug guys so
it falls down the gap is a second-rate
thing for them and there's a genuine
concern about that so I think that's a
case of watch this space with that
because I certainly the nht see you were
approachable and and then had a lot of
Industry outreach where is sort of
soccer a far more sort of arms reach
dark and shady types you know if I can
say that about law enforcement okay hi
Bill Woodcock um I wonder if you could
spend a little bit more time on the
issue of the public versus private IRC
servers and what obviously we know the
technical distinction but what the legal
distinction is between public and
private there and why conversations that
you yourself are involved in are not
admissible if that's what you were
saying yes
ok so the distinction between public and
private IRC server right a private IRC
server is any IRC server that's run by a
group or individual that is not publicly
accessible that's restricted only to
group I'm not sure why this definition
exists but it does private IRC server is
also if it's running on a hacked machine
that's a private IRC server it's a box
owned by somebody else I'm not exactly
sure why technically according to the
law this is not allowed this is what you
know I've been told by the FBI and I've
also experienced this fact that some of
my stuff won't be admitted into
investigations because of this a public
IRC servers basically defined as an IRC
server who anybody can connect to and so
that's you know f net doll net you know
any publicly accessible one those
conversations are perfectly okay i'm not
sure why the ones on a private like
private box are or aren't but i just
know that they your app to david
regarding the contents of the
conversation is admissible though I'm
sorry could you repeat that what you
assert about the contents of the
conversation is admissible go mmm the
cop I mean you can whatever you get from
it you could admit but it's only hearsay
you can't since you can't admit the
actual conversation it's not fact it's
just you know if you learned something
from it it's here saying can I mean it
can definitely help you but it's just
not actually admissible in a court right
Anton capella 5 9's data I just have a
question for you what does Prolexic
recommend when customers are attempting
a bit of the forensics you talked about
earlier when it's likely that the tools
you you would use to kind of figure out
what happened to the host the tools
themselves could be back door door
exchanged for ones which hide the fact
that anything happened how does proxy
how do you recommend customers deal with
that kind of stuff I guess they don't
get your butt well first that way said
nuts that output and that kind of stuff
and I've found that many machines we've
dealt with are very well rooted if you
will
and they'd even change that's that or
the output of such oh you mean like if
somebody's actually rooted the machine
in there I'm changing the data on it
absolutely okay um well in that case I
guess I'm just hoping that whoever
you're working with can kind of help you
to determine to if the machine has been
rooted like that sure I mean if you're I
mean chances are gonna be dealing with
you know if I call you i'm gonna be
dealing with you and you're gonna know i
mean if we start looking at that box and
you know between the two of us we ought
to be figured out if it's been routed
sure is i'm thinking for like likes a
colocation customer people i don't have
access to directly is there is there any
kind of network level stuff I'm trying
you're working with or doing yeah not I
mean not really that's where you know
like colocation clients and boxes you
don't have access to that's where it
gets tricky I mean you you know your
information is only as good as the
source you're getting it from so sure
hey yeah that's just you know advise
your clients on better security that's
all I can say good good last two
questions and I think these two guys
whoa okay John's gonna walk away the one
in one on the other side all right jin
kim ngan feel um about the ODA
miscibility has evidence about
conversations on some public servers
what if the server is located outside of
the united states does it affect that's
if the server is located outside the
United States I think it's fine as long
as it's publicly accessible server I see
and how about a private conversation
instead of some public conversation on
some channel for something like that uh
yeah yeah it doesn't matter private
message chat whatever as long as it's on
a public IRC server it's fine yeah thank
you hi Lou easy for micronics um to
address Tony's question i would suggest
maybe mirroring the switch port that the
server is on oh yeah it would be able to
capture all the traffic from a machine
that the Hope has not been hacked
already yeah yeah that's actually yeah
that's actually a perfect suggestion
right there so yeah perfect
okay okay one last one that's it Rob
seized from clue trust quick question
what is the incidence that you are
seeing of both encrypted communications
and multiple CNC servers and you know
distributed where if you take out one
everyone just costs to another one oh
yeah that's actually huge disclaimer i
forgot to issue about all of this this
is actually only unfortunately this
information collection procedure is
unfortunately only for the absolute
easiest case scenario and that's where
you're dealing with an attack a non
spoofed attacked that is actually
controlled by a centralized command and
control server whether we done it
distributed or not a lot of these
attacks function both peer-to-peer and
through proxy servers in a case you run
into one of those you're going to have
to go to an expert there's basically
nothing you can do yourself or at least
that I can tell you right now in 30
minutes I like to make a comment and
store Phillips from New metra I worked
on several of these cases the one thing
you talk about with private public
channels you want to just ask me
afterwards yeah I wanna make a paypal
account via there's also the security
buff this afternoon and this is a
perfect place to continue discussions
like this so thank you very much thank
you