as bill said my name is Vince fuller
I've been doing this internet operation
stuff since before the dawn of time
Jason fortunately is a little younger
and who's not doing this quite a lot but
he seems to be coming these things
become becoming cynical just as rapidly
as possible anyway what we're going to
talk about is some thoughts we have on
ipv6 and actually more importantly the
subject of multihoming and scalability
thereof for the Internet in the feud I'm
going to talk about some of the history
behind how we got to where we are today
also going to talk about some conceptual
things some of you may have seen some
discussion on the architecture discuss
list or on PP ml or on a no-go a number
of other places over the last year or so
where people have talked about the
concept of locator and infant ID as
distinct from what we now think of as
addresses I'm going to talk a little
about why this is important why you
might want to think about this and
wonder if the community needs to think
about this going forward look at what
the situations today with IP version 4
and I 86 and why it kind of mingles
these two concepts together and why
that's a problem and then sort of look
at where we think multi-homing will go
and we're routing scalability will go if
current trends continue finally we'll
going to solicit some interest from this
this group and from others in the
community for whether we should do some
work on an alternative direction for the
Internet routing system okay reef
history of time paraphrase a famous book
title this is kind of how we got here
sometime during the late 80s or so we
started to see wide-scale
commercialization of the internet that
led to the exponential growth that we
all love know and love that created all
the jobs for all the got all of you
folks sitting here in the room today and
keep us all nice well well paid and
comfortable unfortunately the growth
sort of started putting some stresses on
what had originally been a fairly small
network design that was never expected
to go to to become a ubiquitous global
infrastructure the way it is today this
recognition of this growth and some
disturbing trend started in the late 80s
and there were a number of approaches
that were taken to try to deal with
first was an edict that came down that
tcp/ip would be replaced by the OSI
protocol stack particular TP for oversea
LNS you've probably never even heard of
this bit of gobbledygook because it
never went anywhere there was something
of a revolution against the
self-proclaimed leaders of the internet
community at the time and that level
proposal was defeated again and then the
early again then in the early 90s there
was a small group of people that got
together to try to solve this problem
some of some pretty smart brains looked
at this I happen to be long to take
notes don't really fall into that
category but they identified three
problems that were looming for internet
growth and stifling their of the first
was running out of class b networks
something that we don't even talk about
anymore because that problem was
actually solved you know originally
there were three types of network sizes
/ 8 / 16 / 24 s what we call them today
and the most popular one was the Class B
because just like with Goldilocks and
the three bears no it was one was too
big one was too small and the third was
just about right so everyone wanted that
that problem was solved but the other
two problems you know ongoing explosive
growth well that one was sort of
deferred it was it was dampened our time
but now it seems to be coming back to
bite us and the eventual exhaustion of
the 32-bit address space was not really
a critical problem in 1992 but it's
starting to become a real possibility
today the result of the road group was
two efforts one a short-term effort that
in that evolved into what we call cider
today and the other was a long-term
effort that has sort of turned into ipv6
for whatever that's worth there's a
whole gory description of this process
at this kind of obscure looking URL that
I found by doing a google search and for
those who are interested in internet
history I encourage reading it following
the adoption and deployment of cider
which was a rather politically painful
experience that some of us had to endure
there was a solicitation for IP next
year
region protocol sack December 1993 RFC
1550 subsequent RFC's described what the
technical criteria were supposed to be
for selecting this and a thousand
blossoms bloomed in the form of
different proposals from people ranging
from to bow which essentially was
reimplemented tcp / CL NF style
addressing to something other things
that were more innovative like pip which
was sort of roughly analogous to mpls or
other source routing techniques and
Nimrod which was actually sort of a
architectural description of how you
would deal with this problem at a higher
level without really looking at the
details of how you'd implement the
protocols a lot of discussion a lot of
flaming back and forth a lot of you know
heated arguments and anger towards other
evil factions in the in the community
the choice basically came down to
politics rather than technical merit
when I think back on these times sort of
that the image that immediately comes to
mind is that of one of these talking
barbie dolls that my little sister had
back in the late 70s when you pulled the
string on the back and Barbie doll said
something but one of the things the
Barbie doll said which is entirely
non-pc today was math is hard let's go
shopping that's kind of that's kind of
summarizes what happened with the whole
ipv6 decision process solving
multihoming looking at difficult
problems was hard so people decided to
design packet headers instead because
that was easier more fun you got to
attach your name to a standards track
RFC so it was really cool anyway because
of this process a lot of things got lost
in the shuffle variable the concept of
aerial length addresses was discarded
decoupling of transport network layer
addresses was considered problematic for
several reasons so it was discarded and
most importantly and most fundamentally
clear separation of endpoint ID and
locator was either ignored because it
was people didn't understand the concept
or because again it was hard and we
wanted to go shopping instead and then
this of course led to some issues with
route aggregation and abstraction which
we sort of kind of shuffled under the
rug
the guise of let's just do cider from
now on in fairness these are hard
problems they were hard then they're
hard now but if we don't solve them
we're going to have some pretty serious
scaling issues that we have seen for the
past 15 years with ipv4 kind of
suppressed and solved in a short-term
way but we're going to see in much much
bigger context going forward if the
internet does become as ubiquitous and
wide scale as we expect it to anyway
stepping back and talking conceptual a
little bit just wanted sex few brief
words about what the whole concept of
endpoint ID and locator are again some
of you may have seen some of this
discussion and I don't have much time so
I'm going to make this quick endpoint ID
is by the name of one endpoint in
protocol exchange could be a process
could be a machine something that
terminates a TCP session at one end to
another end point at the other end the
analogous thing in the real world is a
name like Dave Meyer or bill Woodcock
it's who is involved in the
communication you can think of a domain
name is sort of being a human readable
version of an endpoint ID although dunno
main names can also be kind of abused
for other purposes endpoint IDs have a
number of desirable properties
persistence you know once you have set
up a connection between two end point I
DS you don't have to you don't change
the endpoint IDs so a session can stay
you know up forever as long as the two
machines are up and as long as there's
communication that needs to occur it's
nice if they can be administrative lee
assigned because they tend to be
assigned to organizations and by
organizations to their sub parts so the
hierarchy for endpoint ids is generally
a long organizational or logic a
grouping of you know similar
organizations rather than anything
having to do with network topology ids
are ideally entirely portable they stay
the same even if our organization moves
from one part of the planet to another
or if it changes the number of the
number and set of providers that it's
using and they're globally unique that's
one area where they'll analogy with the
analogy with human names kind of breaks
down but a human name is a
you know human identity is more than
just their name my name is sort of a
shorthand the other concept is locators
locator is essentially states where a
device or process is located in the
network the source and address the
source and destination addresses that
you use in routing and forwarding today
well those are locators the real villain
a legate here is a street address which
can be specified to fairly high
precision but doesn't have to be once
you're far enough away from the
destination where all the all of the
more specific information kind of looks
the same to you for want the the
hierarchy associated with locators is is
generally along topological lines
ideally it is completely along
topological lines in other words numbers
speak street city state country or in
the case of the historical phone system
prefix and area code I realized that has
all changed since then actually there
are some things to be learned about
Internet address portability from the
network from the phone number
portability experiments the last decade
or so locators have a have a number of
desirable properties that aren't aren't
really the same as those of identifiers
xand herein is where we get into some
issues again the hierarchical assignment
is according to the network topology to
use a fancy mathematical word it's
isomorphic dynamic transparently
numbering is possible without disrupting
any transport layer sessions in general
locators are expected to be unique when
they're fully specified but you can
reduce the precision of what a locator
covers to reduce the amount of state and
thus improve the scaling of the writing
system I'm variable length address or
one way of doing this that again the
internet architecture did not follow and
less specific prefixes are the way we
kind of deal with this today you have a
/ 32 that specifies an exact IP address
and you can summarize that up at various
levels by shortening the prefix in the
routing system on the reload world
analogy here is that you don't need to
know the exact street address in
Australia if you're traveling toward
from San Jose or to follow the song you
don't need to know the exact address of
the Convention Center in San Jose if you
know the way to San Jose locators are
possibly applied to traffic without
the end systems really know what's going
you'll know what's going on so there can
be a little bit of smoke and mirrors
that sort of is like NAT but you don't
really break the sacred end-to-end
principle which tends to get a lot of
people up in arms when you do why do you
why do you care about this why should
anyone care about this why should anyone
stop reading their email long enough to
listen for five minutes in ipv6 and ipv4
there are only addresses which try to
serve the purpose of both endpoints and
locators and as when someone tries to
serve two masters they usually don't do
a very good job of either this means
that they don't have the desirable
properties of either assignments
organizations are painful because use of
locators constrains them to be
topological in other words the so-called
provider based addressing which really
isn't mean provider based addressing is
really topological addressing to make
the routing system scale but because
providers dictate well they build the
topology the assignment 10 tends to be
along the same lines exceptions to
topological assignments create
additional global routing state this is
a problem this is why multi-homing is
such a big issue this is one of the one
of the main reasons why their routing
table has grown to 180,000 plus globally
visible prefixes today even though
topologically the network really isn't
that complicated remembering is hard
dhcp doesn't really do everything for
you changing addresses disrupt sessions
this is actually a kind of an
interesting key point that was missed in
the design of ipv6 that by embedding all
of the full IP address in the TCP header
you basically make it very difficult to
change addresses and do any kind of
remembering without disrupting sessions
third other issues we cut n occation is
used source based filtering you know
makes makes it difficult to do
remembering there's a whole raft of
reasons why remembering it's difficult
when you're commingling locators and
address locators and identifiers and
basically the fundamental issue is that
you can't make the net you can't make
the routing scale for large numbers of
proto provider independent or
topologically independent addresses aka
multi-home sites
again why do we care well right now look
particularly looking at the ipv6
forwarding table you probably don't care
because the reporting table is a few
hundred entries it doesn't really invest
but that's true of any prototype network
in a lab or in an early adopter stage
where you haven't started to see a
serious growth curve if it does really
get adopted and you don't solve this
problem you're going to have you're
going to have a lot of you're going to
have routing state growth state that
growth of routing state that becomes
rather ugly rather quickly the larger
ipv6 address space gives you a lot more
potential for more specifics and other
things to make the routing table bigger
today by doing that you're effectively
implementing a ID locator split it's not
a very clean or very elegant matter mint
method of doing it but effectively what
you get with with nats if you get rid of
the Nats which is what all the ipv6
proponents would like you to think is
nirvana suddenly all this hiding of
state goes away and you get even more
growth of the routing state again the
scale of the ipv6 network is tiny and
even the scale of the ipv4 network is
relatively small compared to where it
could go in the future if we start
thinking about personal area networks
multi homes individual residences things
of that sort the scale the network gets
gets you know orders of magnitude larger
than it is today then the bottom line is
that recreating the routing swamp with
ipv6 and much longer dresses it's
probably not a very good idea it's
either somewhere between not a very good
idea to disastrous on the on the scale
of what will happen to the routing
system and the people that have to
manage the routing system unfortunately
this problem again you know it's a hard
problem and we'd rather go shopping it's
been ignored for the last 10 plus years
and not only has it been ignored for
10-plus years but the concepts behind
this have actually been known for a lot
longer than that probably on the order
of 30 or 40 years given at some of the
papers in the additional reading section
date back to the 60s can ipv6 be fixed
and what's this thing they might have
heard of called GSE basically GSE was
away proposed by a smart guy named Mike
Odell back in 1997 to take the existing
v6 protocol stack and addressing
architecture and retrofit in a method of
doing endpoint ID versus locator
splitting basically takes the ipv6
address splits it in half uses half of
it for routing uses the other half for
endpoint ID again with a nice google
search you can find a reference to the
document that he wrote in 1997 it's
actually pretty interesting reading and
I highly recommend it the problem with
doing GSE is that you have to make a few
changes in particular when I mentioned
that code me that using the the
addresses directly in the TCP header
makes it really hard to remember things
well when you do GSC you essentially
have to fix this problem you have to go
back and making compatible changes to
TCP and to UDP so you don't do that
anymore the whole point of this is to
allow for the routing system to modify
the routing goop to use a technical term
on packets in flight and arbitrarily
according to the routing system without
having to touch the identifier portion
and without the host having to know
about any of the magic that's going on
behind the curtain again we want to keep
the locator system isomorphic to the
network topology do you see benefits
excuse the goal of locator split looky
locator ID split while keeping most of
ipv6 for those who think esox a
wonderful valuable thing this is a
benefit it allows or facilitates scale
the multi-homing by allowing a different
routing information to be assigned to
multiple paths to an end system in some
respects it's similar to the way that
shim six works in this here and that
there are multiple addresses associated
with endpoints but the host don't need
to know about that so it reduces a lot
of the complexity and some issues with
the hosts again unlike some six it does
not require some of the transport layer
of complexity for doing address
detection and such and to deal with
multiple addresses remembering can be
fast and transparent two hosts with no
need need to detect failure of unusable
dresses issues problems open with issues
with GSC well again they're incompatible
changes needed to TCP and UDP back in
1997 there was no installed base of ipv6
and they were seen as plenty of
time for transition well some people
would argue that today there is a huge
installed base of ipv6 that would be
that would be severely impacted by any
change to the protocols therefore
protocol changes are impossible but
looking forward the number of installed
host is actually pretty tiny compared to
where it's what it's going to be in 5 10
20 years here at some purists would
argue that there's a violation of the
end n principle there are perceived
security weaknesses in particular
because n point IDs can be used to route
traffic to host independent of the
routing system this opens the door for a
new class of of well what is seen is a
new class of attacks on hosts that
actually turn out to be a tax that
already exists that just aren't that
common steve elven sitting in the back
says thats problem can be worked worked
around and I trust his knowledge of
security for more than my own mapping of
n point I d2m point ID + routing
information may add complexity of the
DNS depending on how it's done this is
all something that needs to be looked at
and yeah there are probably submissions
here that need to be resolved traffic
engineering which is kind of the popular
subject and one of the reasons people
hate IM 6 in this community is was not
considered in the original design for
GSE so there would have to be some work
on that it may may involve doing traffic
engineering somewhat differently than
it's done with ipv4 today but pretty
much any scalable implementation of
routing is going to have that property
then the biggest problem is that nobody
is looking at this the draft is expired
it was basically killed by IETF politics
some years ago one thing to notice that
GSD is not the only approach it's just
one again the goal of GSU is to keep as
much of ipv6 as possible biased but with
still retrofitting in the end point ID
locator separation there are other ways
of skinning this particular cat such
Nimrod being kind of the classical
consent the architectural approach to
doing full separation but Nimrod is not
entirely specified all these proposals
have issues associated with them but the
biggest issue is that none of them are
being pursued okay what about this gym
sick stuff we've probably heard of it's
about three years old basically involves
getting multiple
dresses to all that multi home systems
and hiding this all behind a shim that
it's not that makes it look to the host
as if there's just a single address
there's all kinds of I'm kind of running
out of time so i won't go into details
and the details are available elsewhere
in much better technical description
there's all kinds of a complexity
involved and there's all kinds of issues
involved in how you hide the fact hide
hide what's going on from tcp how you
make it all work when addresses come and
go when links fail etc there are some
issues with Jim 6 nobody seemed to like
it that's the biggest issue and
different people like it dislike it for
different reasons service providers
don't like it because you can't do
traffic engineering hosting providers
don't like it because it adds more state
to their servers and insights don't like
it because they still really don't get
provider independent addresses which is
what they want so they still have to
renumber in some cases well shim 6 solve
your problems well judging from the
feedback we got the last nanog doesn't
seem like it but I'd be happy to be
convinced otherwise what if nothing
happens what if we don't do anything
about this problem I've done a little
thinking about this and I launched a
little bit of a discussion on couple
mailing lists few months back that takes
a few assumptions about ipv6 internet
growth going forward and guess is that
some of the growth trends and then ask
some questions about where we think
things are going to go Jason actually
has some detailed numerica gestions of
this based on some even more sketchy
assumptions but it kind of gives you an
idea of what we think might happen
what's the worst case what do vendors
have to what do vendors have to expect
to build on what to excuse me providers
have to expect to deploy and how quickly
a few assumptions behind this I don't
agree with all of them but their
assumptions that kind of are looking at
what we could do without changing a
whole lot of the current direction first
assumption is that ipv4 of ipv6 will you
be deployed in parallel tidy v4 and will
be widely adopted there's some reason to
think this might happen there's some
reason to think that might not happen
but if it is the way forward as dictated
by the IETF and company then I guess it
has to happen in the short term ipv4
will be the put
protocol and we'll continue to use
indefinitely this is kind of important
because it means that you need to carry
both ipv6 and ipv4 routing state for the
indefinite future routing state growth
particularly that for multi homesite
will continue to tonight sites will
continue to grow at a greater than
linear rate in other words exponential
or quadratic up to or beyond address
exhaustion what i mean by beyond address
exhaustion is that as the ipv4 address
space runs out it will get increasingly
divided up into smaller and smaller
pieces hot hidden behind nats but
increasingly smaller prefixes will then
start being routed uniquely as as as
they become different part as they
become topologically diverse parts of
the network it's a consequence of this
routers in the in the default free zone
quote-unquote will need to maintain full
routing and forwarding tables for both
ipv4 and v6 tables between to grow and
there will be significant churn over
time going forward few more assumptions
prefix assignments will be large enough
to allow most if not all organizations
to aggregate all of their resident or
single prefix this means this is
actually a good thing about ipv6 means
you won't have providers that have 20
prefixes that have to be 20 different
routes because they couldn't get a big
enough block initially I don't think Jim
six has been a significant adoption
beyond residences are extremely small
businesses extremely small organizations
and ipv6 ipv4 style multi humming will
therefore be what we do going forward
for ipv6 am i running out of time yeah I
need to I'll just going to do this
bla-la-la more multihoming traffic
ingeniero be ipv4 style other things
like a s hop count won't significantly
reduce state because they're too hard
and they're to their knobs that are just
too difficult to implement and just
point solutions questions to worry about
is how much routing state growth is due
to organizations need multiple previous
this is one of the things that ipv6 will
fix will the number of prefixes and the
growth rate tend to decrease towards
towards the number of a esas in a
perfect world if every organization had
exactly one prefix the number of
prefixes would match number of asses
traditionally in IP IP v4 weld world the
ratio of prefix de s is about six to one
what it will be with ipv6 12 12 21
something else probably not one to one
how much growth is due the unintentional
more specifics which can be avoided with
an intelligent deployment and design how
much of it is due to intentional more
specifics such as traffic engineering
these things are also going to happen
with ipv6 because we really don't have
another way to do traffic engineering
and other stupid pet tricks in the
internet today what's the turn rate in
other words how fast is your CPU have to
be to deal with all these updates and
withdraws what happened and then one of
the questions that Jeff asked is what
happens if we add more state to the
routing system so that you know for
security and such so that the cpus are
even more heavily loaded jeff did a
projection of this and a report on this
back of apricot and then again I guess
that I ETF grow that kind of looked at
some of these numbers they're kind of
disturbing I won't go through all of
them in detail but it's starting to look
quadratic or exponential again and
that's bad because it's really hard to
keep up with growth rates or exponential
even if you start out with a small
number of objects the classic example is
taking a penny and doubling it every day
but they know the month you remain there
or a billionaire well we're going to
have millions or billions of prefixes if
we keep if we keep doing things
exponentially Jason actually going to
give Jason a few minutes here to go over
his analysis that's ok bill if we take
another 5-10 minutes and then I'll do a
quick summary at the end all right so
let me try and kind of run through this
really quickly I don't really want to
talk about when v6 adoption is going to
happen go ahead and debate that the
Assumption basically is that v6
widespread adoption will happen and what
more the routing table look like what it
does in other words what does it mean to
make a long-term commitment to do d
aggregation and ipv6 the way in which I
do this is I look at the v4 routing
table and try and project what the v6
routing table would look like and in the
v4 routing table I try to identify three
different types of routes aggregates d
aggregates that are because you've got
to non-continuous blocks you got us last
24 you grew out of it you got a second /
24 and D aggregates that are for traffic
engineering for example you have us last
20 and you break it up into multiple /
24 s 40 e
and the numbers I'm basing this on is
the Tony Bates cider report where it
says the number of prefixes and the
number of sight or aggregates that that
could easily be reduced down to if you
take the difference of these two numbers
you can assume that these are all of the
intentional d aggregates that are used
for traffic engineering in this case
around 61 k so what would the routing
table look like assuming we were doing
dual stack and it was widespread
adoption you start off with your 180 k v
for internet routes you add to that your
new ipv6 routes you have to have 100 get
piraeus there's 21 k active a esas in
the routing systems that's another 21 k
you not to that you're intentional ipv6
d aggregates which we measured from the
Tony Bates I no report to me around 61 k
so that's your internet routing table on
top of that you have to add your
internal more specifics for a Tier one
isp that's somewhere between 50 and 150
k and your v6 internal more specifics
which we projected to be somewhere
between 40 and 120 k and this adds up to
a fairly large number today 530 k routes
which is not easily done in all boxes
that need to focus in hardware in order
to be able to forward six million
packets per second there are the things
that this interpolation doesn't account
for it does not account for a single is
that currently has multiple non
contiguous networks but if they were
given a single contiguous network would
still make multiple announcements for
example a single autonomous system that
is to Stubb's that connects to an
upstream in two different locations
using two different / 24 s if they got a
/ 23 they would still announce to / 24 s
it also doesn't account for all of the a
esas that have justice last 24 make a
single announcement in the v6 world if
we give them a / 48 or / 56 is it likely
that they will try to put more specifics
into the routing table because they can
but in the v4 world this last 24 is the
smallest typically the smallest routable
space so they can't divide that up any
smaller
the third thing it doesn't account for
is people that have multiple Matt
addresses and they're hiding a service
behind one or more NAT addresses in the
v6 world it seems unlikely that knot is
going to be useful because of the number
of addresses you have so if they're
using that for a TD mechanism they're
likely to need something else and and
lastly the big one which is a huge
unknown is all of the new v6 only
networks that are likely to pop up you
know whether we're talking about China
or cell phones or coffee makers or
toasters or are fit IDs there are a lot
of people that think that because there
are a lot of addresses in v6 that we
need to put an address on everything and
that could have some impact so just go
through a couple Graf's real quickly the
first one you see here is you're on the
top is your V for routing table in red
there's some projections the best fit
looks to be quadratic the purple line
below it is the intentional d aggregates
its projection also seems to be
quadratic and much steeper if you add
the this is the number of active a esas
which seems to be fairly linear if you
add the two of those together your
active a esas and intentional more
specifics you get a projection of what
the v6 routing table is likely to look
like I also looked at internal more
specifics for v4 there's two lines here
the top one it seems you're around 150 k
mark the bottom one is if you're around
the 50k mark this is based on the growth
of internal more specifics at unit and
their projections are quadratic when you
add it all together you get some fairly
large numbers so if you're looking at
safe for a five-year number on the low
side we're looking at 650 k on the high
side 1 million routes at the 10-year
number 1.1 million on the low side 1.8
million on the high side there was some
discussion on PP ml about you know are
these numbers ridiculous and what are
some other methodologies to look at this
and Marshall eubanks had some
interesting comments about the number of
multi-home small businesses that might
be likely to happen in the you
he found a number of 1.2 million
companies with 10 or more employees if
these are all likely to be multihomed
and you make the assumption that the
u.s. is one-fifth of the global economy
that suggests about 6 million multi-home
businesses if they're all announcing
just one aggregate into the Internet
routing table that's 6 million
additional routes if instead we think
that they're going to advertise more
specifics for traffic engineering if
they're going to do maybe eight per
business like they do in v4 then it's a
much larger number 48 million if it's
maybe more like four if you take out all
of the non-contiguous non-overlapping
space then you're still talking about 48
million it's kind of an interesting
number this is one of yours i think is
nosy yeah yeah yeah so the short of my
conclusion is basically want to make
sure that we understand what it means to
commit to the long long term routing
table growth is this a problem we really
want to sign up for it you want to
continue to ask our vendors to build
boxes big enough and we need to build
them big enough long enough for us to be
able to test them deploy them and have
them live in the network for some time
five years is the magic number in our
network so the question really is is
this the problem we want to have or do
we want to find an architectural
solution 1 1 comment on it before I hit
the last conclusion slide is that as a
vendor you know this is actually a
really good scenario back in the late
90s people were having to turn over the
networks and buy any routers every three
years and just go cleaned up that's why
it became one of the largest growing
companies during that period of time so
from a vendor perspective you know bring
on the growth but from a long term user
perspective and community perspective it
probably isn't really the best approach
anyway in conclusion is there a real
problem here or we just a bunch of
chicken littles running around looking
at the sky falling does this problem
need to be socialized elsewhere not only
in nanog in the other operational
communities but other places where
solutions might be sought tried this in
the IETF the IBI hga is actively hostile
toward this work because ipv6 is the
one way and shin six is the way to get
there nanog ripe apricot there's been a
little bit of effort to socialize there
is if this talks all about I'm sure we
go to the ITU that's been the enemy of
the internet community for all these
years your favorite router vendors
research community other suggestions
we're open to hear it again there's been
some discussion earlier on the
architecture discuss list on P pml-n a
little bit on nanog and if you're
interested in actually working on this
problem or in following what's going on
I created an alias that is for right now
just a contact point to solicit interest
so i encourage you to send mail to this
alias if you're interested in this
subject a bunch of recommended reading
i'll leave it here in the presentation
you can go through it later i guess we
have what one or two minutes for
questions or so we're ten minutes
overtime right now into the lightning
talks there is a supposed to be one hour
of lightning talks and then a half-hour
break so at this point if we're going to
do all the Lightning talks we're ten
minutes into break right now since of
the room do we want five minutes of
questions so we'd have five minutes
worth of people asking these five
minutes of people okay so
alright let's let's do let's do the next
three or four three or four questions
really fast questions and we're running
into break now more hopefully it will be
lightning striking even the sky that
thief yeah I'm Steve elleven uh Columbia
University couple clarifications and you
I've liked locator ID separation since
literally 1986 a lot of these things
were seriously discussing the I PNG
Directorate I was a member of the issue
is that there was no really well form
fully worked out proposal for how to do
it yep we had advice for people like
Vince surfer said we tried this way back
when and it was a lot harder than it
seemed my comments on security at you
with authentication right not denial of
service where there's still some open
issues so it's it's a lot harder than
seems it's a good idea we want to go
there but it's a lot harder than it
seems and I agree completely the only
reason i invoked your name in that
context was that when we discussed this
on the mailing list you said that there
were no fundamentally insurmountable
issues here that still might take but
there and they're absolutely needs to be
more work on this because none of this
stuff is thought out beyond the
conceptual stage at this point yeah it
was not quite as much ignorance of the
issue in the eye PNG director it is
people might have gotten your precious
my point okay we really did consider it
thanks for the clarification Randy Randy
bush and I IJ we've been discussing this
for a little while Melvin and you know I
flip back one slide you know so weird my
tongue Quixote slide up on the sunscreen
where do we talk about it's a moot
question we've talked about it
everywhere the problem is the people who
need to do the work need to do the work
and they're all burned down because of
the denial and because of the stone
walling at IETF etc so we the operators
wearing other hats are going to pay for
this and be caught in the long run v6 is
barely deployed thank you Ilan's Iran
for using up a hundred million addresses
without announcing them
the internet so you're not polluting and
you're actually saving and and the
talons credit I think that his
application for ipv6 is a perfect one
because that doesn't require any
detailed routing it doesn't require any
global state it's a private network
essentially right now um but is there
really any where viable to go from your
voice just still beating our heads
against the brick wall well the question
is should we bother or should we just
resign ourselves to dealing with
exponential I to the right I system
we've been bothering for a while and
unsuccessfully I'm perfectly happy to go
home and and count all the routers that
you have to buy every three years well
luckily I'm closer to retirement in most
folks this is true Alan it's a question
but to have been asking couple people
for 4 last few years now and never
already got an answer is there a
mathematical model but look at the
different routing protocols and bgp in
particular and that says watches or is
where a maximum limit in the number of
rods before this thing can simply not
converge there are that's a good
question i know that there had been some
analysis of that back when there were
problems with the rate of updates and
withdraws in the network there was some
NSFNET work done along those lines by
ICANN craig lebovitz did some of the
analysis it's a it's a moving it's a
moving question because it's based
somewhat on cpu speed it's based on
propagation time let's just imagine a
perfect network I don't see you enter
let's imagine a perfect network with
zero timer for propagation and infinite
cpu speed okay just perfect network and
it's come on a question for the research
community could somebody come with a
model but we tell me this where is the
sky is this guy at 1 million wat is this
guy a 10 million watts is there's no
limit but what that's an information
that would be really really important if
you want to have an answer to your
question but is is it okay to go to this
let's get the cutting table go that
sounds like a fine research topic and I
okay we've got to cut the lines off this
point so we'll take the last three that
are at the mics I Jared I'm up here
mostly because Ted is forcing me sort of
is that I said
so what alternatives do we have for bgp
or what are we doing to replace that in
the long term for the question about bgp
well if we have the existing NRI prefix
length model right how are we supposed
to get away from that to something else
that's a good question the problem isn't
really bgp it's the amount of state
you're carrying around and inventing a
new protocol isn't going to change that
impending a new way of propagating
information doesn't change that you need
to really look at how you're designing
the routing system how you're doing your
aggregation and help how completely you
can be isomorphic to the topology yeah I
don't know the I think those two are
potentially actually more interrelated
right and again the point of this is to
determine if there's if there's interest
in actually working on a solution and in
getting a community of interest together
for doing that I think there's interest
but I think Randy point on the operator
bernau is significant and the challenges
that faced with dealing with the IETF
and other things in the past have read
and the question is can we do something
outside the IETF among the vendors the
users and the providers they're gonna
have to live with this problem and
should we bother if you're interested
sendmail the madness yeah I already have
but I think I think it's going to be
hard to try and get a significant number
of people involved I agree with you Tony
Tony hain Cisco um a couple points that
I wanted to make to your talk the issue
about India and is really about identity
preservation of identity between the
endpoints is really what that's all
about and modifying it in middle
modifies identity right first if it
argues we're splitting if endpoint IDs
and cola and locators are commingled
into addresses then certainly that is
true that argues for the split at the
same time all of your security
infrastructure is built around that
overload and assumes that the security
can know what the identity is by looking
at the same locator that's that's a
problem and then the other issue that I
wanted to make raise was Mike Adele was
also responsible for one of the other
parts of this problem right he was the
one who set the bar that says honey Tony
were 15 minutes all right I just at this
point just just let me there's like my
sentence this arguments been going on
for what ten years now I'm not arguing
against him I'm trying to help the rest
of the room understand the context
right and Mike was also the one that
said if you're going to play and be a
serious player in the game there is one
global default free zone back to your
point part of what we need to talk about
is does that particular assumption make
sense and that's that's part of the
discussion we need to have is a single
default free zones does that make sense
we can certainly take it up on the
various mailing lists to talk about
architecture discuss would be a great
place to discuss this and I encourage em
I encourage male 2 I PMH interest at
external at syscom last question there
actually it's more of a statement than a
question there there's a fundamental
disconnect here that is existed for
about as long as the ipv6 and its
current form has existed and that is the
rough consensus and loot and working
code disconnect and we've been talking
about all sorts of interesting ways to
do decoupling of locators and endpoint
enta fires and nobody nobody is sending
working code well and until that time
it's it's flailing around yes and and
the point the point of this of this
mailing list is to trying to rectify
that problem the fact that the the
domain name where the man list is
located ends in da Cisco com suggests
that there actually may be some people
that are interested in prototyping some
working code over this where where is
the version identifier field for the
IETF and how do we increment it
implementation details