real estate is very expensive that makes
sense however most of the data center
that we have in the United States is we
have it in like in a somewhat suburban
area so the real estate is not as high
too cool that place servers for instance
takes about 3000 watt per per blade
servers and that is if you put about
three or four of those you can you can
get up there 10kw 12 15 kW rapidly to
cool that and with our current
infrastructure it's almost impossible to
call that so the next step is we're
going to have to bring a chilled water
system to call that cabinet which a lot
of the vendors are starting to go to
their route so it is a very difficult
for us because when you start using a
chilled water system in an open
colocation space and you mix up with the
other other colocation low density power
cabinets it's very hard to mix it up so
are you saying actually take I have a
chilled water plane tonight you take
chilled water put it through coils in an
individual cabinet have a fan running
that's correct so basically it's a
recycle within the cabinet so so when
you have a coil it's probably you know
it's going to sit in the back back to
the heat the hot aisle mm-hmm the back
side of the cabinet so all the heat will
go through that coil and then recycle it
back to the front side so in order to do
that you have to have a really an
enclosed space if you do that an open
space and you mix it with the other air
it does not is not an efficient system
or are you you guys concerned at all
about having lots of water flowing
around and through well of it this
equipments day 20 years ago when I was
working on a lot of the IBM facility
they used to have all this chilled water
system and nobody wanted that chilled
water into in their racks and cabinets
but as the technology's changing like
what he said going to play servers and
we can get up to 20 kW / cabinet that's
definitely an issue and we have no way
up okay I
I would disagree you up no way out what
I'm actually disagree that you you have
no way out there are okay is that better
okay i would actually disagree there are
several ways of doing that using
different facilities and also sort of
changing how you look at the delivery of
that air and also the question that i
would ask is how thermally efficient are
those rooms in the first place I I would
love to bring you on a tour of some of
our data centers and we'll let you sweat
behind some servers for a while oh no I
understand that the servers are running
hot i'm not i'm not denying that what
I'm saying is is that if you walk into
most customer data centers I've been
into which is in the hundreds most of
time there may be only operating at
about seventy percent efficiency of the
area that they have capacity to actually
deliver if you've got tile cutouts in
the back of a server where you've got
cables and that's a four foot you know
four inch by 8 inch opening you're
losing a lot of air there as opposed to
using something like closed cell foam
using something like a bristle system to
don't allow that air to escape so you're
actually getting more volume at the
location where you actually need to
deliver that air alright so I've got a
hundred and twenty thousand square foot
floor plate one of five floors rights
and I have to go and deliver that with
the sperrit clients talking 500 clients
I've got guys with you know you know
several GS ours in their space you know
twenty junipers tons of server Sun boxes
HP boxes IBM z800 blades every wacky
thing you can imagine and every
engineering religion you can imagine to
try and engineer and and do the cooling
on that with all these variables it's
it's it's almost impossible and it's a
rack environment up to several thousand
square feet and some you know carriers
drawing average of you know 40 watts of
square foot we love them we hug them we
kiss them they're great and then we got
these you know hosting guy comes in and
they you know they want to do 400 watts
a square foot and and we blink at them
and say no and they think we're crazy
and then we have to spread them out and
do all kinds of crazy stuff it's it's a
really difficult thing we're facing
right now and you know most of us are
pushing it to the limit but it's
something they all have to face I can
tell you one thing by the way in
regressing we were back on this one I
want to say something will welcome
liquid cooling I call dielectric spray
liquid on chips whatever it takes
because I in my opinion it's not about
power I think we can all get the power
in from the utilities now most of us put
our data centers generally in the right
locations to get those you know the big
13 to feeds or whatever in from utility
the issue is moving air or somehow
getting that stuff cool down and either
we vent it out or liquids or whatever
but that that's the issue it's really
more cooling oh no cooling is definitely
the biggest problem the issue that that
I would raise is one of the problems is
how you're thinking about the space and
that is that you're dealing with it in
watts per square foot as opposed to
dealing with it in the specific
requirements of the rack which is what
it eventually boils down to anyway and
if you have a method of doing that at
least you have a mechanism by which you
can actually charge the customer based
on the amount of heat that they're
generating I believe that what you've
done is you've lowered the cost to the
port to the customer but then you've
driven the cost of us has the IDC
providers where now we have to pass that
cost on to customers in some form of
either bigger space on charging for
other services but if you can
rationalize that to them that's actually
allowing you to make the same if not
more money right yeah it's a thing is
when you have like 20 kW 15 KW / cabinet
you try to cool their with a current
infrastructure and even if you open up
that tile underneath you can only bring
so many CFM per tile there's no way you
can call that unless you go with the
chilled water system um what about what
I actually would disagree with that you
can also do that by taking is one of the
biggest problems we have with air
cooling is at some point within the
height of that rack what ends up
happening is the air basically bleeds
through your generating so much air
being pulled through machines at either
the bottom or the top of the rack
depending on where you initially
delivering the air that the machines at
either end of that spectrum are getting
basically they're not getting any air so
have you actually considered using air
systems to actually go from the bottom
and from the top because now you're
you're not necessarily you know starving
out for error one of those two locations
and you wouldn't necessarily have to do
that with water well
only thing i can tell you you have to
come out of data and feel that we will
having a hard time cooling like even
seven or eight thousand watts per
cabinet those are hard to cope without a
chilled Odysseys okay because i've got
one in menlo park and we're doing 12 no
problem and that's only with single
delivery under the floor okay let's go
do some questions from the audience
Randy um grande bouche i J I'm going to
put as hot stuffy in there as I can cool
because I want the power that's life ok
now the problems the cooling over three
four thousand KW per square meter with
current air cooling you're at the limit
because people walking into the pop will
get blown over physically the wind
tunnel colocation affect the chances of
me putting water in my rack are rather
small you know actually we learned to
take out the sprinkler systems right I'm
we have dry actions frankly surgeons how
many folks here well we want dry action
cooling yeah how many folks here would
be willing to have water flowing through
their racks come on everybody
participate who would be willing to have
water flowing through the racks how many
people here would say that's a
deal-breaker for me to have water
flowing through my racks I think the
people who said yes have water on their
brains yeah well alright what about
glycol look every scared of that what
about dielectric liquids on your chips
there's better ways to get airflow
through the rack ok you can side feed
them and blow across them etc I'm going
to sacrifice the square feet no matter
what ok but the fact is that most of
your facilities today can't even have
held 3kw per square meter I think any
bills which aren't doing that today are
unrealistic and I would like to know
which of the provide which of the build
provide
are actually providing three to four KW
per meter okay that that's 300 to 400
per square foot approximately I suspect
the answers none but what would anyone
like to take that I have I have some
cabinets at nota and I'll give Akamai
part of the hottest customer out there
kudos on this where they have one
cabinet are several cabinets running
about 386 watts of square foot at
seventy-five percent breaker load all
day long and the reason I can cool that
they have a very big hot aisle behind
them and so they're spaced out and
they're around a lot of carriers who are
running at about 40 watts of square foot
which is wonderful and great that's the
only reason we can do it I think Patrick
Gilmore told me before that we're
actually there there dentist cabinets
anywhere at that at that kind of wattage
per square foot load your facility for
3k per square meter cool give me I'm
spaced out too I'm gonna have to pay for
it give me 500 million I'll do it no
you're put your problem raising your
capital is somebody putting racks in
there it's my problem to pay for the
cost so you can continue to have your
rice bowl filled okay but the reality is
that i'm gonna burn as hot as I can
because I want to move those stupid
little electrons okay and I want you to
give me a facility that can take as much
as you can without blowing me off my
feet when I walk into it and give me and
raise the plenum higher and start
talking about you know cooling is coming
up air coming up the side of the rack
and crossing it mm-hmm currently we are
Equinix is building a like for KW /
cabinet in the future we're already
planning on it we're building on you
know going for in 2007 it takes about
close to you know close to year and a
half
get a start on it is about one a cabinet
is 2 square meters essentially because
you have to walk down the aisle so
that's 2kw so anyways so he's going
forward with building that day listen
and going for we actually are starting
to separate high-density users medium
density users and low tensile users so
that's what we're going forward I and I
i think that's that's a wave of the
future is building you know high power
density pods let's go to the back center
aisle hello my name is Derek wise from G
and I we recently went through this with
our data center in san francisco we
deployed a thousand and eight IBM
bladecenter in a 12 cabinet environment
we're currently taking up 2,500 square
feet we have a ping-pong table and i
think a soda machine and some other
things in the adjacent cage we left
empty I think to two to three hundred
square foot per I mean watts per square
foot is insignificant for us we need
somewhere between two and 2,500 I mean
2,500 watts per square foot delivered on
the floor to get the space requirements
down to the actual amount we're
currently we have to pass you can you
try to speak a little more to the mic
did you say 2500 square less per square
foot 2500 per square foot if we were
delivering the same cabinet space that
you do you typically blow over to about
2,000 per cabinet 2,000 watts per
captain correct and that equates to
about eight servers we get about 80 for
servers right now / cabinets so you can
do the math it's about 20,000 watts per
cabinet that we're able to liver in
power that we're able to deliver an
equipment right now that's 336 cores a
process or power / cabinet that we're
actually installing today how are you
able to cool 20 kilowatts per rack by
buying a 2500 square-foot cage and put
in a cabinet there I kept their I
cabinet there and that's currently the
solution that we have today we don't
like it we'd like to see some kind of
direct cooling environments that are
available for us I'm currently paying
for it anyway I'm paying for a hundred
cabinets and have 12 installed and
that's
that's how we pay for the so how much
this cost us we're already dealing with
it today but I'm still netting
efficiency so I know we pick on our
hardware providers pretty hard but I
want to kind of give em a little bit of
kudo I still get three percent better
efficiency out of my math numbers every
single month than it would if I'd put 80
for one year pizza box servers in place
and attempted to cool and pay for the
environment that way so there is some
benefit from taking the bladecenter
environments and if our data centers can
figure out a way to keep up with us then
I think we can also keep the space
requirements a little smaller and maybe
give ourselves another percentile to of
net gain a little business happening
here you know building from 100 and 100
watts square foot so what most everybody
built around 2000 2001 and yeah great
we're spreading down cannibalizing
getting to 200 watts of square foot or
more is great but when you when you
start saying i want to go to 200 watts a
square foot baseline or 400 watts of
square foot baseline it's not a linear
curve it doesn't just you know just oh
we just tack on some extra costs its
exponential it's it's obscene I all
kinds of new technologies have to put in
place massive generators oh and by the
way it's a fun thing generator lead time
right now for a nice 2 megawatt diesel
engine it's up to a year up to a year
for one generator so we can build all
those raised floor or non raised floor
do all the overhead get all waiting and
we sit there and twiddle our thumbs for
six months waiting for hopefully our
generators to get delivered and and I
guarantee all of us have you know
combined probably have about 40
generators in order you know and then it
take on anybody enterprise all the
government everything else it's it's you
know it is an exponential increase so
you know where randy says great pass on
those costs and I want more you know
more power and more cooling you just
make it happen I can't wait to see the
budget trauma when we start passing on
those costs because we're going to have
to it is what it is the only thing that
I'm proposing is let let our demand
generate some ingenuity I'm not
suggesting you have an answer right now
that you're not deploying suggesting
think about it as much as you can we're
currently paying for there's a better
way to do it someone's going to figure
it out a minute and the internet
industry in general as short-sighted we
don't put enough in place to start with
or we don't really see how significant
this growth can be 22 million blade
servers going to install the United
States this year and who's going to cool
where they going to be located and how
are you going to handle that demand when
it comes up you're going to have
mountains and mountains of empty
colocation space you know I suggest my
comment we actually had a trial in this
we actually the math calculations the
power sums ended all the drawings for
our environment and how we're gonna have
stagger out equipment based on the
facility that got us to 200 watts per
square foot and it was still a very
significant burden from a amount of
square footage space we had to take down
to make it happen okay bill there's one
other dimension to this problem that I
think is worth pointing out which is
when when you build a brand new data
center the expected life is not just a
couple of years generally in the 10 20
30 50 year type of time frame so it I
mean it I'd like to sort of shift to the
other side of the the table there and
talk a little bit about what kind of
projections those of you who
manufactures hardware see for the power
consumption towards the future do you
believe it will continue on literally
and grow in terms of how much you need
do you think it will flatten out because
those of us who are looking towards you
know two to five years in the future
have two neat have to find out some kind
of measure of what we should be
constructing towards so I opened it up
to you guys so from from from a
technology point of view until we have
the next great quantum leap coming CMOS
I guess with less big help to us and we
don't know what that next great quantum
leap is we're going to be struggling
incrementally to keep the power to
control so I see it continue to grow and
and the linear the things that can help
but so the things that it can help
mitigate that a little bit I think Randy
mentioned a few things I mean we are
fairly inefficient in terms of our
cooling architecture right the amount of
air that we can get through we're forced
to make bends in the in the air paths
and for example the Sierras one we're
about twenty percent of our power goes
to the fans right just a power the damn
fans so that that can be that can be a
mitigation the other thing is that just
spreading out spreading out the
equipment you know as gross as it might
seem that that is a mitigation
gentleman said he's already facing his
stuff out let's true in the router space
as well as well as the data center space
and so you know the advent some of the
vendors to do multi chassis systems for
the large large routers well maybe the
lead to lease do that and how about sun
and juniper do you guys see the power
consumption continuing to grow linearly
flatten out or so i believe is my
colleague pointed out it's going to
continue to grow and it's exasperated by
the addition of features and
functionalities we continue to push wire
speed performance and increase the
connection density as we go up to 40 gig
connections and that begins to take on
some light in the market all of that's
going to contribute to the addition of
heat within the systems we've got more
gates providing that functionality
that's required pushing it at higher
speeds and i do think we are beginning
to approach the physics limits of
current process technologies so i
basically concur with what you're saying
there cisco and juniper agreed please
note the date and time well it is you
know it is 6606 anyway i mean the other
question that i would ask is if you look
since you're talking about a 20 year
sort of shelf life for your data center
if you were to go back and look at what
data centers were generating from a
power standpoint 20 years ago it was
actually about five to 10 watts of
square foot so if you look at going from
five let's say you go in 10 watts a
square foot even to you know a hundred
times and sing go 2,000 watts a square
foot we actually have greatly increased
the amount of work that can be done by
well over a factor of a thousand since
then so I mean if you want a 20 year
lifespan on your data center I guess the
one question I would ask which is do you
expect over that 20 years from machines
to be able to do the same amount of work
they were doing 20 years ago or a
thousand times because one of the
problems we have now is as you start to
draw when you're drawing a wide and you
double that to two wats it's not really
a huge deal when you're drawing you know
5,000 why
the next time you double that that's
10,000 watts 20,000 watts 40,000 watts
so there's an element of geometric
progression that's going on in terms of
the power usage so that's the other
thing too which is if you've got a data
center you want for 20 years how much
more work do you want to be able to do
within that 20 year time frame just to
make a statement that people can throw
back in my face ten years from now I
want to say that no one will ever need
more than 20 kilowatts per rack let's
write it through a 640k right um can I
make a statement that he's wrong today
whoo-hoo so actually I'd like to say one
more thing to address your question I'm
not entirely sure that it's going to be
and i know i mean history shows that yes
the progression is up and to the right
as far as power is concerned but as as
some of the guys have indicated we're
running into some roadblocks and one of
those things is it when you get to these
you know 100 million gate a6 that you're
just packing so much density and so much
power into ones in one spot it actually
becomes extremely difficult just to
actually sink that power out into the
system and so with those limits you may
actually see some hiccups where it may
not be linear just because you reach a
point where we'd like to add more
density but we just actually can't do
because that point source of heat is
just too much and as we've seen in like
laptops on the Pentium and stuff like
that you run into these these tremendous
problems of actually getting that heat
from that point source out into the
system Patrick all right Patrick for
mock my for the cola vendors anybody
putting a Colo in McMurdo base I'm just
wondering if that would be a good place
can you say that again this week oh it
was a bad joke I asked if anybody was
putting a Colo in the South Pole as a I
don't know as a brighter light is a spot
of hope as the hottest Colo in terremark
which i will give kudos to is the
densest best cold cola we have on the
planet and that's saying quite a bit
because we're in 2,500 locations we are
actually finding that we don't need more
power we are coming to less power this
is not true I'm sure for some people in
the audience but are we are running into
a problem where we have trouble getting
enough spindles
and the processors are getting faster in
dual core and drawing less power at the
same time so in the last six months we
have actually found that we can go from
40 amp stay at 40 amps Iraq which is
very low for us and we couldn't even
fill the rack but that's what most kolos
could provide and still not have to Bay
empty racks so that we could call them
and we're now able to fill them at 40
amps Iraq with servers and spindles and
things like that it says this was not
true six months or before so I don't
know if everyone is seeing this but
we're actually very happy that our power
consumption is going down not up and
we're getting more bits more CPU more
everything out of the same number of
amps volts watts so it's not all doom
and gloom of course you know a year from
now we'll need more power but in the
meantime for the next 12 months you guys
are lucky briefly I mean the fact that
John is talking about CMT or you know
chip multi multiple cores on a chip that
is really a pretty big sort of leap
right now that can save actually a fair
amount of power and I do work for Sun
and if you go and check out our Niagara
systems you will see that the workload
that they do relative to the power they
draw is actually considerably larger
versus the amount of power so whether
it's us or anybody else in soon chip
multi-threading or multi-core chips that
is a way to look at to really be able to
save some power because all of the other
ancillary pieces are there's actually a
fair amount of power there if you really
look at a machine about only fifty
percent of the power is actually being
used by the actual processor the other
fifty percent is being taken up by all
the other ancillary things you need it
to actually run the system RS rob c
strim um so bill started to sort of
danced around this question and kind of
back into it we've certainly seen this
happen before with data centers I
remember may East mark three with
additional Libra challengers sort of
wedged and wherever they could possibly
get one the question is if one were to
build a data center 24 kilowatts per
square meter or 4,000 watts per square
foot or what
is considered the state of the art right
now how long is that premium space
versus no longer state of the art so you
have to sell it at a discount is it even
possible to do a data center with a
20-year life expectancy these days
obviously it's possible to sell it for
see how some value of colo 10-15 years
for now but the question is is the run
rate Steve enough on the increase of
power requirements that that's just a
number that we're completely fooling
ourselves with and if you're if you're
SEC compliance people won't let you
answer that that's fine too look this is
all future thinking theory and what's
going to happen from a business sense
but we're we're all of us you know we
three all of internet exchanges and we
have lots of telcos and ISPs and none of
them are running at the kind of density
it's really it's a really displacement
of server infrastructure that's causing
the greatest heat or if somebody happens
have 20 GS ours at a row you know that
can be pretty rough too or crs ones or
what have you or a big junipers or
whatever it is the I think what you're
going to start to see is a separation of
environment the ISPs and carriers aren't
going to want to build in more fiber and
redeploy this infrastructure gets a
little tougher to redeploy they're going
to want to have an exchange point server
is P environment where all the carriers
voice guys wipe whatever the heck it is
is all sitting and you'll see a separate
either modular data center in a campus
environment or in a multi-story building
built specifically for server as a
server floor and you try and isolate
that stuff now as far as the future goes
20 years from now you know that it will
it be obsolete maybe who knows I think
all of us have we're all for-profit
companies that we're going to you know
battle like crazy to keep building to
satisfy our customers and as we fill up
our space will will you know find a lot
next door or a lot down the road or in
another city and closest to the cheapest
power to acquire which is a big thing
right now to from the utilities and and
build it we're in business we're gonna
keep doing it to satisfy you guys and
keep it up keep the internet working
joel crouse go from viata a question
about the hardware vendors not the
server space because processors are now
becoming more efficient what are what's
coming in in network equipment can you
shut down part of a fabric can you shut
down half a line card if all the ports
aren't in use or do these things exist
now or are you thinking about them what
can you talk about yeah we certainly
have detectives it's kind of interesting
we had a bunch of service providers come
we we ask that that question and the I
guess the answer is if you make it
automatic so I don't have to worry about
it and nobody nobody ever has to
configure it will consider it but did
the response in general was pretty
negative so we have considered
techniques like that I just would remind
in terms of the bandwidth demand growth
right now it's it's the from a router
perspective anyway and I think there's
an analogy also to the CPU side the
exponential growth technology not only
is not keeping up with it but it's going
to sits plateauing so all these various
you know multi-threaded ideas having
turning off idle idle portions of the
logic that aren't being used those are
all great ideas and there are all great
incremental improvements but they're
they're kind of like one time things
that we can we can try to do it in order
to mitigate over the next few years but
the slope of the curve is not effective
unless we do either do better technology
the other the other thing to think about
is maybe we need to just accept the fact
that we need more space there's a
trade-off between space and power in
terms of the density right power density
so
so today will bleed crs-1 also has high
speed low speed fans so we are doing
things like high speed low speed fans so
that we can reduce the power required
under nominal conditions and only kick
up when there's thermal extremes in the
environment we're also looking at and
have had similar conversations with
customers with regards to acceptability
of shutting down subsystems within the
system and it's typically been viewed
with a little bit of a skeptical eye in
terms of as long as it comes on exactly
when I want it to exactly when I need it
to but I don't want to have a protection
circuit that's delayed and coming up
because you're in a suppressive state
things like that back to also your
comment with regards having hot spots in
the system I think that's that's also
very valid point in terms of the density
of the packages that we're putting into
these systems today are pushing us in
terms of being able to just design heat
sinks that can that can sink that into
the enclosure itself and get that out of
a geographic hot spot within the system
we do need we do need to look at all of
the incremental changes and additions
that we can but we also have to be
mindful as a vendor of the reliability
requirements and the other time
requirements of our customers so there's
also been some concern expressed in
terms of thermal cycling certain
portions of the system and having hot
and cold regions within within the
platform itself and what would that do
in terms of aging and long-term
characterization of the equipment so
those are some of the concerns that
we've heard for doing mitigation steps
like what didn't ask about yeah just
said what the one final thing on that to
address your question is that we've also
talked to customers about this and given
suggestions as to what we could do and
one of the issues we run into is that in
order to do a lot of these features
where you turn down or you turn off
portions of the design and then turn it
back on is it usually have some sort of
latency involved with that where the
circuit has to wake up and you have to
essentially maybe buffer packet or
whatever that may be and in a lot of
cases people are sensitive very
sensitive to latency as well as to you
know jitter and the latency where you
may have low latency in one application
and then
suddenly the latency increases I had
effects software a lot of different
software applications so yes we've had a
request for that but the pushback has
been fairly fairly large from a lot of a
lot of other sources I think it was
first okay go right ahead thanks to the
gentleman over there um my first
question is to the colocation vendors
win willpower I'm one will heat our BTUs
be a component of the charging and to
the server vendors when will be to use
and the patent the heat generated from
the systems be a one of the elements
that people make decisions about it
sounds like it sounds it sounds like to
me that there's no market for your
problem okay the vendors aren't able to
sell on this particular issue and the
I'm not charged for it ok so we're today
I enters the idc's you guys charging
based on heat load no we're not really
charged we're charging customer actually
with charging custom a capacity without
capacity hmm so not by the helo is that
something you guys anticipate doing at
some point in the future power what
hours parts agree yeah i think you know
our costs are based on delivering space
and delivering power and delivering
cooling and something people which you
mentioned a little bit was cooling
overhead i don't think people pay
attention that it's a percentage of our
cost of actually delivering the space
it's wrapped into the cost that you pay
us per square foot and for your power
circuits so we have our costs from
utilities in general have gone up in
some states by thirty and forty percent
because of our wonderful Middle Eastern
oil market so all of that is driving
other things as well which is making it
more expensive not only our ability to
build and deliver it but all that now if
any of you happy to propose a BTU cost
factor they can charge you I'm happy to
do it it's more money for us right
because we're not doing it now so it
might make it easier I don't know
okay and are you guys seeing in your
rfps now that folks are putting in you
know heat generation limits or
requirements of any kind is is this
something you guys are starting to see a
lot of our customers have kind of hard
limits due to legacy legacy buildings
right so what we're I mean and the way
we've kind of approach it as kind of a
syllabus is may seem silly but building
smaller systems with less slots is one
way to approach it so not directly the
dimensions you're asking about but we
haven't had people inquire about power
efficiency for the routers in terms of
gigabits per kilowatt for example as a
way of measuring system capacity for
comparison sake the other thing also is
a lot of Education when you look at
total cost of ownership for any device
whether it's a switch as server what
have you that total cost is dependent
not only on the hardware software
support costs but also the power costs
and you're getting devices now you can
go and buy a server for seven hundred
dollars and at eight cents a kilowatt
hour which is sort of pretty close to
what we pay in this area for example
it's actually going to cost you more
over the course of a year to power and
cool that box than it will be for the
cost of the box so that's extremely
interesting Lane Patterson Equinix quick
question to the vendors I think an
interesting point might be a t6 40 if
you were to redesign that today what
fraction of the power budget would it
require compared to the existing model
and if you project that ahead to the
next generation of stuff that you build
what I hear is people saying hey I can
do for X the density and speed and
throughput with only thirty forty
percent more power how much
of that decision making goes into your
next generation of hey I have to come up
with something that I can fit in the
same power footprint as my last gen so
in terms of developing product
requirements to meet those kinds of
requests we are seeing definitely
requests for holding the line on power
density but we're also seeing requests
for increases in throughput and capacity
so I don't think it's practical for me
to be able to go forward to my customers
and promised a doubling of capacity and
holding holding power consumption flat
but we're definitely working towards
trying to reduce overall system capacity
through whatever mitigation steps we can
take in the course of the design so I
guess what I'm what I want to leave you
with is it is not an afterthought it is
being factored into requirements and
being being synthesized into the
engineering process from the ground up
as we're going forward I guess I would
just just reiterate that we're at a
point now going before in the future
without we have to you know there's
probably a set of tricks in our bags
that we haven't used yet so we can
probably hold you know we can hold the
line somewhat over the maybe a
generation or two and that's what we'll
do and you know going forward beyond
that I think we have to maybe think
about alternative architectures for pops
reverse the racks in liquid nitrogen you
guys get that stuff ready and will you
know lowered in the tanks and lot of
maintenance I'll throw out one question
I have kind of the audience is that you
know in terms of there is somewhat a
there is a space versus cooling
efficiency trade-off that we can make to
you know to some degree so would it you
know why don't we build pops that are
you know in cheaper locations and
backhaul more stuff
yeah that's why you back call it that I
will the trying hi jared montz NTT
America 52 backhaul more stuff I have
the challenge of right now I'm seeing
individual customer growth that is
rather huge you know the numbers as far
as customer growth that I've heard
earlier today seemed about right for
traffic and right now no vendors are
providing interfaces greater than 40 gig
right now and not in the foreseeable
future certainly not in at least the
next two years am I going to be able to
do anything faster than that based on
rough estimates and timelines that I've
heard and so back hauling stuff means
that you're aggregating more stuff in a
single location you need faster link
speeds in those locations as a result of
that to be able to deal with that so
that's not really an option in fact it's
really more of what about any lengths
well I'm sorry wavelengths ah there's
significant problems as you may know
with any sort of hashing algorithms to
balance stuff across multiple
wavelengths so five individual customers
coming to me in delivering 10 gigs of
traffic to me in a location and they're
going to be doubling that every year for
the next several years how am I going to
be handling that over long distances
local distances and such if the fastest
interface speed I can get is 4x that
internally and this is significant
engineering challenge that I think we're
all really facing and the the as the the
media companies continue to do what
they've been doing recently which is
saying hey we can make money selling TV
shows on the Internet in the past six
months and stuff like that and sell
movies and whatnot I think it's really
going to be a significant thing and we
may see past the 2x of growth for a
little while as people start to get the
faster file services into their home and
everything else and it's without any
sort of faster capacity out of the the
vendors for the individual link speeds
this is a huge challenge and this really
has me personally actually somewhat
scared about what we're going to be
doing about this to solve it in long
term
okay we'll just be taking questions from
the people who are standing up right now
actually since we're almost out of time
for here avi Friedman I talked to a lot
of people who are looking to do storage
video streaming usenet news things that
are very very disk intensive interested
that rack a bowl I don't know whether
rackable systems was invited but I see a
lie to them a lot for people who are
looking for very dense disk solutions
and i also have a question for sun
regarding the coming thumper product 48
discs for you you know sort of no matter
how many processors you have in it looks
like it starts to generate a lot of heat
another so first question is what is the
heat profile of a rack full of those
second question is is there any work to
do something like a for you hundred
ninety-six laptop disk box does heat
really come into it for people who are
basically saying I need I ops or you
know I just need so many terabytes of
storage per rack unit I can't give you a
specific answer on that because those
products well they showed up in
Jonathan's blog they haven't actually
shipped yet I can tell you that that
area is being looked into I think the
other thing that we're looking at
whether it's from you know a a blade box
full of disks or a blade box full of
processors there are going to be certain
limitations that we're going to tell
people and it's going to pretty much be
if you want to put this in you've got to
sort of show us that you have the
capacity in the location you're going to
put it in to cool it or thank you yawn
yawn good night that's one of the other
things that you know taking there's a
responsibility that we have to make sure
that we can give you accurate power
information on you know that type of
work the other responsibilities is also
to the people who are installing it to
make sure that they're installing in a
location where it can meet the
requirements of the box that it has and
I think that's one of the areas where
historically a lot of vendors including
Sun have really sort of dropped the ball
which is letting people go and install
stuff
in areas where they couldn't
realistically support it particularly
from a thermal standpoint and that does
cause failures we know that if you're
running stuff very very hot it will
decrease the the mean time between
failure so I think that's one of the
other things that we're working on now
and I know some of the other vendors are
as well Randy nope okay after the right
yeah I'd like to just suggest that this
is phil for my as Prime Phil Rosenthal
the worst offenders in terms of hardware
really are not the people that are on
the panel in fact they're pretty good
all things considered that's why they
showed up exactly and I'd like to point
out to the audience that they really
should be putting pressure on the
vendors that are producing these 1u
servers that if you look at the profile
of where the power is going greater than
fifty percent of the power is going
towards the processors and I don't know
about everyone else's but for us if you
look at a server say for example at Dell
1650 from five years ago versus Adele
1850 today they're doing similar
bandwidth because the customers have the
similar needs we have more of them and
the processor time they're sitting at
ninety percent idle on both of them so
do we really need these bigger faster
more power hungry processors in greater
density for our bottom of the lines
servers that you can buy today I really
think that that's not the case and
vendors really need to start offering
more power-efficient you know losing
laptop processors instead of Zeon's and
also I'd like to point out what patrick
said that they're reaching a plateau in
terms of disk density I know for a fact
that a lot of the vendors were buying
from are going to start distributing
servers using smaller miniaturized I
mean basically laptop drives but with
higher performance spindles so you're
going to see greater density for that
coming very soon that and there wasn't
really a question just wanted to make a
statement excellent come there is one
area this is true for you know basically
all the vendors that are working on it
which is the area of virtualization and
that you know it the biggest issue there
from a particularly from power and
cooling standpoint which is the point
that the gentleman made which is most
those machines are only doing about
they're not idle ninety percent of the
time so I guess one of the other
questions is if you could actually get
your machines to actually be in use
eighty percent of the time and that
workload that they're doing would you
need nearly as many of them generating
sucking nearly as much power in
generating nearly as much heat show of
hands anybody I think well one thing we
see in the market now particularly the
hosting market is that there's really a
widespread adoption of virtualization
you know I think a lot of the dedicated
hosting market in particular is you know
except for the higher-end managed
hosting the the I'm gonna rent a dell
box market is starting to rapidly go by
the wayside in favor of virtualized
private servers I mean so that's
definitely being seen in the marketplace
and I'd like to make another comment on
that vendors what we have seen that I
think what I I kind of like what they
did is that we have seen our Neutral
corners dropped quite a bit because of a
lot of the servers now this stage they
require 208 volt instead of 120 volt
that eliminates the neutral phase that
the generator less heat to the data
centers were so there is something that
you guys did really well who Randy on my
left I've got a large crew singing I
want my p2p yeah I'll virtualize yeah
I'm squeezing it down but I got more of
them so I'm still going to have max heat
in the rack I'm talking intimately with
the router vendors and some of the
server vendors they're working real hard
to do what they can but when I go to the
colo vendors in two thousand went to the
newest facility in the Redlands had to
with this is technology that's now six
years old we weren't even using the
latest stuff we were trying to install
then we had to leave one third of the
facility empty we were going to open a
bistro in it bill you tell me you're
designing for 50
years you're not designing for today I'm
trying to tell you I need three to 4k
per square meter today and other people
who are trying to stick blade servers in
our twice that and that's not tomorrow
that's today okay one last comment or
question Tim alesio with the new mantra
to what extent and I'd like to hear this
from both sides opinions on both sides
so what extent you think standardization
of things like let's say using larger
more efficient power supplies or
standardizing cabinets so you get a
better airflow or you can reduce having
to have internal cooling fans which also
are going to suck power to what extent
do you think that can help mitigate this
problem and are there any efforts in in
that area going on right now start with
the hardware guys so I think that
actually could be very helpful i know
that there are some efforts on the if
you go into like the I Triple E meetings
there's some efforts on the physical
layer side to to look into power
reduction but whenever you standardize
something generally that you get the
economies of scale you get the more
reach of research and development
investment and we've seen that if we
look at our products and i look at the
standardized products that go into our
design versus and non standardized
products in general just the economies
of scale and the amount of investment
that goes into you get a much more
efficient product i think the one thing
that might help would be I mean I think
we're we're working towards it's at
least in the kind of the telecom router
area you're working too kind of old
standards so I think in you and a new
standard that that redefines what a rack
really means maybe something that looks
at what air flow architectures really
mean I think that that would be a big
help the the other stuff the other stuff
yeah we can get the more dollars we get
into a particular area we can we can do
a better job of optimizing but
I think you know we're kind of hamstrung
again by technology I keep harping on
that subject so standardization along
the lines of things you're talking about
mechanicals air flow systems things like
that would go a great deal towards
helping the situation within the context
of a system in and of itself I think
we're always going to see optimized
designs for specific products internal
to the system but the enclosures the
physicals and the outside plant from the
router's perspective it would help a
good deal if there were if there was
something that resembled design
guidelines or a target to shoot towards
and there again you'd be working on top
of economies of scale that colleagues
have spoke to there is a lot of
standardization that's going on you know
from nobody's trying to use you know
multi-speed fans and use them when you
need them and stuff like that the
biggest change I think you're going to
see is that now there are sort of three
organizations right now spec which is
actually working on a power benchmark
the echo forum which is being driven by
the EPA they're actually looking at an
energy trying to trying to actually
create an energy star metric for servers
Energy Star blade servers yes at some
point I mean this is one thing that
we're working on right now and then also
what's called the Green Grid and so what
you're going to start to see as these
benchmarks start to come out and
customers really start to ask for it
which is all the vendors whether it's at
server vendors and storage vendors the
network vendors one of the things that
they're going to be able to compete on
is how much work are you doing given how
much power are you sucking and how much
heat are you generating and that's
actually probably the single biggest
thing that the users you are end-user
customers and all the people who you
know by this in the industry can
actually do which is make us compete on
how efficiently we use power and
generate heat because then you're going
to decide
your dollars who's gonna win and when it
comes down to you know who's going to
make money doing this and if I can
create a more efficient power
utilization server at a given load than
my competitor and you're actually going
to buy it that motivates me to find
other reasons to do it but to say I'm
not you know you could save all the
power you want but I'm still not going
to buy your product well that sort of
tells us guess what you're not willing
to pay for power efficiency so part of
it is you have to tell us and you also
have to vote with your dollars as it
were it's nice to have metrics that you
can measure to help compete but I'm
thinking specifically are the vendors
talking to each other about ways that
they can do things in common ways so
that they'll they can be more
inefficient inefficient if they're
working together a data center if there
are adjacent to each other data center
let's say or they want to interact with
what the carrier's I mean I'm sorry what
the facilities might have built the one
thing that has happened which is ashray
the American Association of hitting
refrigeration engineering has come out
with a spec that sort of says okay you
know machines name be cold front to back
and fans need to be variable speed and
stuff like that and so at least that is
one small area that you have a lot of
enders now they're trying to build
machines that at least meet those specs
I don't I don't think personally that's
just my own personal opinion you're
going to actually see vendors wanting to
work together I mean I certainly don't
want to tell you know HP how to build
cooler machines that draw less power
because that's a competitive advantage
for me there are going to be some
standards but in terms of things that we
really think are a leap forward say some
stuff that we did with no chip
multithreading we don't want to make
that publicly available and give it to
my competitor because that's way I can
make money I can differentiate myself in
the market very briefly just to wind
things up this has been an excellent
panel I like each of the folks on the
panel on both sides in 30 seconds or
less to give one thing that they would
like to see the folks at the other table
to help the situation just to sort of
wine things out so let's start start at
the end well I think basically from on
the data center side we are we request
for vendors to as a say design more
efficient power supplies more efficient
equipment because at the end of the day
we have to figure out a way of how to
dissipate that heat out of the data
center and that's our biggest challenge
well we've been you know out with
equinix we've been challenged by the
power density and customers a lot of
times they do not understand the
statement of like spreading out the load
they like to put everything in a
condensed mode or compaq smallest cage
as possible we want them to understand
the heat load and able to dissipate that
here you need to understand we need to
distribute this the cabinets spread them
out so that we can cool you guys say
properly you know we're all building
really hot you know there are excuse me
well powered big data centers now i
think i'd like to see all the vendors
come into our IDC's not enterprise data
centers but IDC's which are combination
of enterprises nice peas and hosters and
everything and and start testing their
hardware in a real world environment
let's work on thermodynamics and flu
dynamic issues and bring it into our
data centers we all have labs will put
in the middle of the floor and see if it
melts something or doesn't and you know
we'll put some glycol taps and it will
put some liquid stuff see what happens
and we're happy to do it because it
benefits us and our customers later on
building a data center is a slow-moving
iceberg you know building a server might
be a lot faster it takes a long time to
build a data center so let's work
together on that when you guys are not
using the rag if you're not using a
certain the space use a blanket the
blank so you can isolate the cold aisle
to the hot aisle so it'll help the
airflow much much better that's
interesting how much you think that in
an average facility we're putting a
blank up how much do you think that
or it'll help a lot really it'll really
help a lot right now you got a lot of
leakage going from cold aisle to the hot
oil so if you if you cover that up
you're gonna have a lot better it's
efficient very efficient system that
that's actually the fluid dynamic calm
and I was talking about things what kind
of inspired that you have a seven-foot
42u cabinet and you're and you know the
middle of it is totally empty the air
you know you're in a raised floor
environment the air is going to flow up
through that hole and shoot back and the
top servers are going to run dit in 99
degrees the ones below they're gonna run
to 72 degrees and everything's going
wrong and you're complaining to the
vendor and it causes all kinds of
operational and flow control issues for
us you put blanks in holy cow it all
works and it's much more efficient and
there's less you know cannibalization of
space going on okay hardware guys first
answer that I can tell you on all of our
stuff we actually supply those now and
if you actually go to PG knees website
we actually did some work with them
recently to actually try to measure what
the increased efficiency is if you have
those blanks and it was fairly sizable
the biggest thing I would ask is one is
education not just amongst yourselves
but also to your customers and to please
stop using watts per square foot to
define your data center it is a
fundamentally flawed view of the world
because it's making the assumption that
the heat load is even and across a data
center it never is um if you really
start dealing with it in terms of a per
rack basis that makes it a lot easier to
understand and justify the requirements
that you have so that would be the one
thing that I would ask so for me what
I'd like to actually see and this goes
back to one of the questions out there
is that if the all the IDC groups got
together and if there was some sort of
form or group that could actually work
with us we'd be very happy to do that
one of the issues that we run into a lot
of our customers everybody has different
requirements and we try to you know fit
all these requirements into our design
and it turns out that then we're sort of
basically doing trade offs for all these
requirements and we can't optimize for
any one application but if we had a set
of a general consensus across the board
we could probably do it much more
effectively
I guess for me would be again to get
together I think the last question had a
good suggestion in terms of
standardization or get a group of the
IDC people we need to get some service
providers that do their own facilities
and inventors such as force10 juniper
and cisco and try to strategize on
what's the facility architecture should
look like for the next generation I
think we've been dealing with with
legacy architectures for too long so I'd
hope we'd come up with a an architecture
that would make cooling easier make the
air flow easier that would go a big ways
to to helping us reduce the amount of
power that we consume just in fans for
example today is the vendor when we are
see RFPs from our customers they're all
over the place with regards to what the
requirements for the environmental look
like there maybe that's a little it if I
purpling but they are they're quite
quite diverse in the needs that we see
so it helped a lot to have some common
common standards that standards that
people are shooting towards in terms of
data center designs also to update some
of the nomenclature would help a great
deal as you were describing with regards
to taking a look at the amount of power
for the amount of work required from the
router perspective we look at things in
terms of gigabits per kilowatt consumed
or the reciprocal of that kilowatts per
gig it's necessary so some common
language like that I believe would help
us a lot as well thanks sorry I'd like
to thank the panel for the great work I
like to thank Michael David bread rob
Josh Jay and Brian outstanding job thank
you