without further ado
hold my beer ransomware operators in the
race to the bottom
okay
hello everybody thanks for coming to our
presentation hold my beer ransomware
operators and the race to the bottom
we're just going to give you like a
sneak peek at what dan and i see every
day working on the thread intel team at
kroll
so as an introduction my name is laurie
icono i'm a senior vice president with
kroll cyber risk i manage the day-to-day
of our threat intelligence team
i was formerly a program manager at the
national cyber forensics training
alliance and i also teach cyber crime at
a couple of the local universities
including university of pittsburgh and
robert morris university which is where
i met my co-speaker dan i'll let him
introduce himself
oh hello i'm dan cox i've been with
kroll for about a year and a half now
it's i started off
cyber security at robert morris i went
through their masters in cyber intel and
investigations and that's how i met
laurie and then ended up working at crow
and now do
i do a bunch of ransomware stuff dark
web research
um really just anything that comes
through we kind of do a mix of
everything
um so yeah lots of ocean research and
lots of ransomware research
so what we're going to talk about today
is we're going to cover kind of like we
are here like kind of the current state
of ransomware as we're seeing it working
in an incident response practice we're
going to talk a little bit about how we
got here so some factors that we think
kind of led us to this current state
and then we're going to talk a lot about
what we're learning along the way uh
specifically what we're learning from
some of the thread actor shaming sites
which dan has done a lot of work kind of
drilling into the analysis of those
so
talking about we are here
you can see this navy line on this slide
here this basically represents the
distribution
of threat incident types that we're
seeing in our incident response practice
that navy line is representing
ransomware
and you can see that that is far and
above the other
lines on the chart that's because
except for quarter one uh when we had
microsoft exchange proxy logon uh
ransomware is by far the most frequent
uh threat incident type that we see in
our ransomware cases or in our incident
response cases and it's actually been
like that since august 2019 so it's been
holding steady for about two years uh
prior to that time we would see a lot
more like email compromise a lot more
unauthorized access cases but starting
in august 2019 we started to see
a big rise in the frequency of
ransomware and that has pretty much held
steady since then like i said except for
the little little uh
skewing the results with microsoft
exchange earlier this year
the next thing that we've been seeing a
lot of in our practice is the use of
these what they call double extortion
tactics
so the ransomware groups they're not
just encrypting networks but before they
encrypt the network they're going in
they're exfiltrating data
and then the extortion component at the
end
first of all they're extorting you know
pay us for the decrypter but they're
also saying pay us or we're going to
post that stolen data on one of our
actor-controlled leak sites basically
and these actor-controlled sites these
are basically like the ransomware gangs
will put up their own kind of branded
site where they're posting the victim
data
we are seeing in our
in the ransomware cases we see it crawl
about 86 percent of them right now are
associated with this double extortion
tactic
we did a similar analysis of this about
a year ago
and we were about 40 percent
so the use of this tactic has about more
than doubled in
in a year's time
and you can also see here the growth of
these sites
in 2021
the bars here represent like unique new
sites that we observed during the year
so there was a big spike from q2 to q3
of different groups
adopting this tactic
so i want a little i want to go
into a little bit of flashback here kind
of talk about the ransomware as a
service model
and one of the groups that really
popularized this model was gand crab
ransomware here you can see their
landing page
they were very active from
about january 2018 to may 2019
and this group um they kind of i don't
know that they were the first to use the
service but they definitely like really
popularized it and kind of brought it to
the mainstream
a ransomware as a service is is
essentially a model where the the
ransomware operators kind of like
outsource the distribution of the
ransomware to affiliates
then those affiliates get a a cut of the
ransom proceeds so this helps those
ransomware games kind of force multiply
how many targets they're able to go
after because they're using this huge
network of affiliates to actually
distribute it
when gan crab retired in may 2019 they
made a pretty big post they like a
retirement a
little letter on one of the dark web
forums and they claim that they had made
2 billion u.s dollars in that 18 months
now this is a threat actor this is what
a threat actor is claiming so we don't
know how accurate that 2 billion dollars
is
but we know that it's fair to say that
they made quite a bit of money
in that time so if you remember that
two slides ago i mentioned that it was
august 2019 that kroll started to see so
many ransomware cases in our caseload
so it's very likely that a lot of other
groups at that time a lot of other cyber
criminals saw how profitable this was
and started getting into the ransomware
gang game
the next
kind of flashback here this is the maze
news site
this site was one of the first of the
actor-controlled sites
so may's crew was really the first
ransomware group to
threaten this kind of data publication
and then actually carry out carry it out
and post data
this site went up in may
it was eventually
they eventually retired in november of
last year but the site was quite up for
quite some time hundreds of victims um
you know they would definitely post
after an attack
if people paid the ransom they would
take the data down actually they would
remove it from their site we had
unfortunately some clients that that
happened to and we would see proof that
they did at least delete it from their
site
another one of the groups that quickly
adopted this double extortion method and
and set up an actor-controlled site was
the
rival gang
they set up their site is called happy
blog
so they were the second ones to kind of
get into this method and they kind of
like gave it a lot of personal flavor i
guess i would say
so they would kind of like write these
letters about their victims
kind of trolling their victims
essentially
so we've seen
they've went after a lot of law firms
that had high profile clients so they've
trolled everyone pretty much from like
lady gaga to
donald trump on their site
this summer they're also the first of at
least what we've observed of the
ransomware groups using what we would
call sextortion tactics
they were threatening this one ceo that
if they didn't pay they were going to
basically
post a dick pic
they did not pay and they actually
posted the dick pic
i think my question as a cyber security
professional is why the ceo
of a significant company would have a
dick pic on his work computer
but he did and they found it so that's
the kind of things that these gangs are
going after
so obviously most people in this room
are surely familiar with the cassaya
supply chain attack that happened in
july
rival went on hiatus after that
they came up for a few weeks the end of
september
but now they are
down officially as of monday and last
yesterday there was an article released
that it looks like that was
international law enforcement
cooperation actually bring that site
down so hopefully they've been disrupted
i want to talk a little bit more i know
i've been talking about the exfiltration
and the actor controlled sites there are
other tactics that we've definitely seen
them using
during the negotiation period
one of those tactics is ddos
and i will say we've seen the threat of
ddos be used
so avadon here on the screen avidon and
suncrypt both of those variants threaten
to basically ddos
victims during the negotiation periods
we haven't observed in our caseload that
anyone's actually like had a successful
ddos attack as as during the
negotiations but it's one of those other
things that they're threatening them
one thing that we have observed quite
frequently unfortunately for our clients
is this
tactic of cold calling the victims
the dark side ransomware gang
they kind of were kind of marketing this
on the dark web
earlier this year kind of how
you know we have this call center that
we're using and if you're an affiliate
of ours we'll basically you know have
this this call center will be calling
the contacts of the company to try to
get them to pay the ransom
and we saw a lot of that that happened
to a lot of our clients almost like
within days of that post
going up on the dark web
um another tactic that we've seen them
use is emailing victim clients or
basically like the clients or customers
of the victim organization so you see
here this email from the klopp
ransomware group saying your personal
data has been stolen and will be
published
we've seen them
do this so a couple like i know the maze
team
at one point they were going after
patients at a plastic surgery center
saying we'll share your before pictures
they went we saw them go after
patients for a rehab clinic we'll share
pictures that are related to your drug
use if your clinic doesn't pay the
ransom
and we've also seen another group
actually go after victims of
i wouldn't say victims it was patients
at a celebrity hair club for men
so they were kind of telling them we
were going to show we're going to show
the world that you guys are actually
have hair transplants um so it just kind
of shows you know how low some of these
groups will go and trying to get their
ransom payment
so we can't talk about ransomware in
2021 without mentioning the colonial
pipeline attack
and that was which darkseid was
responsible for
in the wake of that obviously everyone
in this room knows
you know how
devastating ransomware can be but this
kind of brought it into the mainstream
all of a sudden the media was engaged
and obviously there was a lot of law
enforcement law enforcement scrutiny on
some of these forums that had
heretofore been kind of harboring some
of this activity when it comes to the
ransomware as a service ecosphere
so they quickly kind of banned uh some
of this activity on their forums now
since that we've seen you know obviously
it's a ban on a cyber criminal forum so
you know we will use that term lightly
but they definitely shy away from using
the word ransomware because they know
how much attention it attracts um so we
definitely see them using kind of code
words
trying to still accomplish the same
thing
and we've also seen a lot of the
ransomware activity actually transfer
over
to a new forum that came up i think in
like july
a ramp forum
and that one has a little higher bar to
entry probably because they want to
avoid some of the looky-loos that were
coming into the forums in the wake of
colonial pipeline
so some of the other things that we've
seen on the shaming sites since that
time
first of all is that you know we saw
that rise from q2 to q3 and more actors
putting up these actor-controlled sites
where they were dumping data
we've seen a lot of actors pivot to just
exfiltration so they're not even using a
ransomware to encrypt
they're just going into the system
they're stealing the data and then
they're extorting it to try to you know
prevent some kind of data publication uh
we've also seen a lot of doxing on the
site since then
so you know sometimes they get people
get immune sometimes to like okay well
so what my data's dumped um so the
threat actors constantly have to keep
ratcheting it up um so we've seen a lot
of our clients like sensitive data like
plain text passwords has been dumped on
some of these sites
in the past couple of weeks we've also
seen
my
let me see
we've also seen some rhetoric from some
of these groups coming out against
recovery companies so recovery companies
are basically third parties
that some of the victims will use to
kind of help them negotiate with that
threat actor to try to lower the ransom
demands and a lot of times that is
successful and they are able to get a
significant reduction in that ransom
so some of the groups ragnar locker and
grief this is just an example of them
coming out earlier this
i think it was a couple months ago but
they basically come out and said
if you work with a recovery company or
we think you're working with a recovery
company we will just delete all your
data showing they were kind of trying to
play hardball with these groups we
haven't actually seen them do that but
it's just another threat that they have
made
another thing that we have seen as you
can tell this is why we called it hold
my beer because every day when we think
that the ransomware groups can't top
themselves dan and i are messaging each
other the next day that we can't believe
what they did um so this was one where
lock bit ransomware they've been
especially active after uh after the
dark side shutdown
they started soliciting actually for
insiders to help them launch malware
so this uh image here this actually
shows up after a victim has been
encrypted
the wallpaper will say all your files
are encrypted and it will also put up a
little advertisement
saying that if you want to make millions
of dollars you can work with us giving
us passwords
to vpn or rdp to help us get into
networks
so you know we're talking about insiders
and they're going after insiders in our
you know industry in the cyber security
industry probably with that posting but
now that this ransomware landscape is
kind of spread out we've got all these
affiliates we've got all these different
kind of pieces of the pie that are
feeding into a ransomware as a service
operation
that means that there's more likely to
be individuals within that ransomware
supply chain that may be disgruntled and
end up sharing information
so this happened in august this was a
disgruntled affiliate that was
associated with conti
ransomware
he actually dumped basically a training
manual
that's what they give their new
affiliates to help them launch
ransomware and in that training manual
there's a lot of technical details about
the tooling that they use about how they
move through networks that we were able
to share with our
detection and monitoring teams as well
as our forensic examiners for threat
hunting but for the purposes of this
presentation i'm going to focus in on
what we learn
when it comes to exfiltration one of the
things they were told basically is
that's one of the first things they
should do when they're in the network is
start that exfiltration so it kind of
highlights how important that is to them
as a part of these attacks and some of
the things that they were told to look
for are items related to finance
accounting
clients so as we said before they tend
to go after clients and customers um
they're also told that what's especially
important for them to go after our
documentation related to cyber insurance
policies so it's lately that they're
trying to look at a cyber insurance
policy see um you know what they may be
insured for and use that as some kind of
leverage when they go into the
negotiations
i have talked a lot about that
exfiltration piece and then dan's going
to talk a little bit more about those
sites and what actually happens
with the data
okay there we go
oh yeah so looking at the different
actor controlled shaming sites um i
believe last night
the most updated account that we had was
34.
yeah
um there we go i just won't touch this
okay
was that better okay
yeah so last night we had counted that
there were 34 active
actor controlled sites where they're
leaking victim data and threatening to
post
different attacks onto their websites
so there's
on the sites
there's always the large claims of oh we
hacked x company and we stole two
terabytes of data if they don't pay us
in a week we're going to post that data
onto our site
i mean when you actually look at the
sites every day and break them down
you can see that that's not usually the
case with the sites
there is data posted to most of them and
yes it is
normally a large amount of data but
it really depends on the group if
they're going to post that data when
they will post that data how much data
and then actually whenever you get into
trying to retrieve the data
there's a lot of troubles that you run
into with that
so for these different cases
uh what we typically see is the post
will go up about two to three weeks
after the initial attack
and then with that you'll have a
countdown timer that'll start anywhere
from four days to two weeks to a month
that it gives the victim time to
negotiate and decide if they're going to
pay the ransom or not
if they do not pay they'll move on to
leaking screenshots
where like you saw with lori sometimes
they contain plain text passwords
they might be
personal information documents whether
that be passports driver's license of
employees
student records if it was a school
different things like that and that's
all in a push to actually get the victim
to pay the ransom to remove the data
from their site
whenever you go through
most of the different negotiating
companies
one thing that you'll see very common is
that they get the negotiation extended
and usually that just drags it on long
enough so that they can keep working
down the threat actors price
and then after so long though whenever
the countdown does finally expire
they'll release the data either all at
once in one bulk download or it'll come
out in different parts
and we've seen the parts leak anywhere
from over a few days to over a few
months that that data will slowly
trickle out and then eventually that
data will get published onto their site
so for most of our different clients if
data does appear on the sites we do go
out and retrieve that data and just a
few different things that we've noticed
with that
is over tor
the connection is always very slow and
it's very spotty
to say group does actually go out and
post a terabyte onto one of their tour
sites
it's very hard to actually retrieve that
data set and then work with it
you might be looking at a download that
takes up to two weeks
and your normal just person visiting
these sites probably doesn't have the
infrastructure set up and prepared to
download
any random victims data that they see
fit that would take up to two weeks
so then the data might not actually get
published they might get to the
screenshots phase and dumping the proof
and then not actually move forwards with
anything
the different things some of the groups
will post to different third-party sites
like mega
there's send space onedrive that they'll
put the data on to
and with that that actually opens the
door to where we can contact that
provider and then have the data removed
from the site
and then with the groups deleting data
occasionally like we just saw with
reaval where their site was taken down
that takes all the data links off with
it
and then so with that
yes your data may have been posted to
the site
but looking at how long the data will
actually stay live
and how long it's actually maintainable
is a very large statistics that we'll
look into to try and help out some of
our different clients
all right this thing is
let's try this way
nope
okay
so yeah looking across the different
sites there's a bunch of different
statistics that you can pull to actually
analyze the group and it's slightly
different than looking at their actual
attacks
whether that be their
iocs or ttps that they're using on their
attacks
this is slightly different of their ttps
into just their shaming sites
and how that victim data kind of gets
performed and may appear onto the dark
web if they don't pay this ransom
so some of the different things that you
can look at
some of the different things that you
can look at is the actual victims that
make it to the site versus the number of
victims that actually have data
published with that listing
there is the claim data that the threat
actors claim to have xfilled from their
network
and then it's typically much less that
they actually will post to the site um
so we get to kind of see both sides of
that we'll be looking through the
network traffic to look at exfiltration
most of the time what the actors claim
instantly you can rule out that it's a
lot higher than what we saw
but occasionally there will be or you'll
see them next fill maybe a terabyte and
a half and that terabyte in half does
appear onto the site
like i mentioned with using the
third-party providers to host this data
there's different statistics that you
can pull with looking at how long do
those links stay online before the third
party provider would remove those
and then what we've also seen is actors
upload to sites like anan files
where the link will actually expire
after a set period of time
so yes your data may appear onto the
site
but will it still be there in a week in
two weeks once this becomes public
knowledge and actually out there
so with those different statistics
we've kind of provided those to our
clients just to give them an idea of
here's the different timeline that we
expect to see with this group
here's what we expect to see with the
data that does get posted and here's how
long that data is expected to stay
online if it does appear
okay there we go oh
maybe not
okay
as the different groups that we looked
at just for this analysis was black
matter which is the alleged dark side
from the colonial pipeline hack
we have defray 777 who's going by
ransomyxx now they've been around for a
few years now
but more within the past year they've
moved to the shaming site model
hive is a newer variant that we saw at
the beginning of the year
they're pretty nasty
they tend to whenever they get into a
network they'll generate their own
encryption keys
and sometimes we'll notice that the
encryption keys will get put into memory
so that way then if the victim restarts
the computer at all those keys are lost
and decryption would just not be
possible even if they did pay the ransom
we have freeville slash sadena
this is with the cassette attack and
like lori mentioned
they're actually seized right now and
looking for different models to move
i'm in that group actually last week
they were posting about that they
believe their servers were compromised
and then yesterday we found out that the
servers actually were compromised by law
enforcement
and then we looked at vice society
which is suspected to be a hello kitty
spin-off and hello kitty has been around
for
at least two years now they have many
different spin-off variants and each of
their sites
or each of their variants will get their
own shaming site
but typically what we see with those is
they're only online for about a month or
two and then they'll pivot to using a
different name but vice society with
them has been active for about eight to
ten months now
and then we have zing walker which is
suspected variant of matlocker
zing lockers actually has gone down
right now
and
believed to be a new group called
quantum locker
and they've kind of shipped it shifted
their tactics over the different courses
of their variants
but through each variant like we saw
with mount locker they would post a
victim
and then two or three days later
the victim would appear on the next site
which would have been astrologer so the
same exact victim same exact data as
posted
and then we saw them do the same thing
with astro to zinglocker and then now
zinglocker to quantum locker
and then on the right there we just have
a total victim count of what we scraped
this was from i believe about two weeks
ago
for the active victims on each of the
sites
who can show me my water please
the powerpoint is on another level
yeah yeah i know
what is it pressing
why am i doing that i have no idea is it
the clicker
okay oh no it's not that quick is it
this quick
okay if we can get this stay on one
slide there we go
all right so whenever we want to go pull
the statistics
different shaming sites we actually
still had the rival site was still
online this was only a few days before
their operator
stated that their servers were
compromised and shut down their
operations
i mean as you saw on this last slide
they had about 250 victims listed to
their site
but then whenever we moved to
okay there we go so you saw that they
had about 250 victims posted which was
far more than the second
but whenever we look at the actual toted
data that was live on their site there
was only around 40 gigs
which then compared to like zing locker
with 1.3 terabytes where they only had
about 20 victims so you can just see
instantly the giant
kind of variances between the groups on
how much data they would put up per
listing and how many listings would
actually stay active
i mean so whenever we broke that down
for average per victim
i can see with hive where they had
please stay there we go
they had 25 victims listed onto their
site
but only 0.07 gigs of data actually ever
was posted to the site
um and so then if we look at the sites
like blackmatter and zinglocker who are
posting large zip files of several
hundred gigs
down to hive which might post a kilobyte
a few megabytes
there's just a large variance there and
so then knowing that coming into the
actual investigation where from day one
you can say this is what we expect from
this group
um say it's zing locker we're expecting
a lot of data exfiltration whereas hive
we can tell the incident response team
that there may not be as much
exfiltration i mean they still look
around but we're not looking at too much
of a risk to get onto the site
let me try clicking
is that the next one
oh yeah so this is looking at the actual
um victims with that are posted to the
site versus the victims with actual data
onto their posting
so we have zing locker vice society and
defray if you made it onto their site
your data was going to appear onto the
site
compared to variants like reveal
where you only have about a 25 chance if
you get posted to this site
is that actually going to leak
and then moving over to the right side
here the trend that we can see with the
different groups is how long that data
would actually stay live
so revo had about 250 victims
but only 10 percent of their download
links had stayed online and this goes
back to victims ranging back to about
early to mid 2020 was the earliest one
on there up to several days ago before
they were shut down they were still
adding new victims
okay and then so whenever we shift to
i'm looking at how much data that they
claim that they will be posting to their
site from the claimed exfiltration to
how much data actually appears on the
site you can see on the graph on the
left there just how large that shift is
where groups like black matter are
claiming that they have seven terabytes
of information posted to their site
whenever you actually go through the
information there's only about 760
gigabytes on there
this does get to show with defray
over on the left
what they claim is what they've actually
ex-filled so that is a great tool for
our incident response team once the
initial post comes up and they claim
that they have
400 gigs of data we can tell the ir team
you're looking for 400 gigs of
exfiltration somewhere on this network
then if you actually see with the hive
one two
they have very large claims on their
website where some of the groups they
were claiming that they had about 300 to
500 gigs posted onto the site
but whenever we looked at the actual
data available it was only about half a
percent
of their claims so there's very little
data available on the site versus what
they claim to have ex filled
oh
it's just the forward button
back one works fine
um so breaking down where the groups are
hosting these sites uh you can see on
the left with the asterisks those are
the actual third party providers i'd
mentioned that will cooperate and may
actually remove that data from their
site once they notice that it is live
and then if
with the different groups you'll see
them have different file servers so
whether that be it's a section of their
website
that is actually hosting the downloads
or a separate tour apache server
what we noticed with the tour hosted
whether it be the apache or on their
actual site was those were the groups
that had the 100 uptime
and very large amounts of data
compared to your groups like hive would
use sites like mega and the private lab
and only post
maybe a handful of the data that they
claimed and then compared to the actual
other groups where there's several
hundred gigs
there we go
so this is kind of a breakdown of just
all the statistics kind of rolled into
one
can i take that off to turn around
there we go
um so yeah whenever we look at the
different groups
um like you can see with defray vice
society and zing locker if you made it
onto their site you have a hundred
percent chance of that data actually
appearing
compared to looking at like some someone
like black matter
you only have about a 50 chance of that
data appearing
then one of the things that we really
notice with hive was that out of their
25 victims roughly 70 had data posted
but the total data that was actually
posted on the site was only
two gigs
so out of the around 20 victims that had
data posted that only amounted to 2
gigabytes of data which is very very
little for the around 20 victims
compared to with black matter with 26
victims we saw about 760.
um let's see
yeah so just kind of overview of the
different stats um black matter roughly
ten percent of their claim data that was
x field actually gets posted and that
did line up with what we saw with
different black matter cases as far as
their ex-focus and then looking to the
previous dark side cases we had before
they're shut down
one of the just really cool kind of
stats we saw with that was the victims
with data posted for black matter was
rated around 50 percent
that was exactly the same for dark side
so just kind of just a odd ttp
doesn't necessarily mean the groups are
related but just goes on to pile on with
the rest of the information on the
groups
and then like i said with defray
vice society and zing locker who use the
tor hosted sites if that data does
appear on the site it's going to stay on
the site compared to with revo using the
third party sites where most of the time
they're getting taken offline or the
links are actually expiring before the
data is even up for too long
and then just like with any threat
actors that we deal with
i thought it was going to stay
like with any of the threat actors we
deal with even if you do pay this ransom
or your data does not appear onto the
sites there's no really telling where
that data is who has access where it has
been published online
so this was from
one of the chats that we had with one of
the threat actors after they had given
us data that a victim had paid for to
have unlocked
so of course we could easily have
backups but we assure you we do not now
they've kind of been joking manner
whenever we showed the client
these logs they were not too happy about
that with the
actor kind of making a joke that they
still had their data backed up
and the lawyers were kind of iffy about
that going forwards
but as far as the larger groups go
i don't want to say that they're
trustworthy but they do kind of like to
keep their reputation in line
so say a large group like black matter
a victim pays to have their data removed
and that data is spread across the
entire internet
the next victim that comes along with
black matter is likely not to pay
because even if they do pay their data
still may get posted somewhere online
well i work for the last one
yes sir
so obviously the you know best uh
you know cure for ransomware is
prevention um because these actors are
obviously very opportunistic they're
taking advantage of everything they can
do to get into networks um they're also
you know taking advantage of security
vulnerabilities that they observe
um so the biggest you know way to stop
ransomware attack is to prevent it from
actually happening um so these are just
some you know controls that we've
observed in kroll as far as you know
things that people should probably be
doing to have you know increased cyber
resiliency i guess they would say
multi-factor authentication um the
majority unfortunately of our of the
ransomware cases that we see the
majority of those people do not have
multi-factor authentication across the
board maybe they have it at like a part
of their organization but that seems to
be a huge factor for these groups
obviously they go after a vpn so
vulnerable vpns if there is a patch to a
vpn appliance that you're using you
should definitely be updating that
because we do see those actors uh you
know trying to exploit those
open rdp that is another one that they
will try to exploit
we recommend everyone have some kind of
endpoint detection monitoring to like
catch some of this like precursor
malware before it actually goes to a
full ransomware attack um and then we
also suggest that everyone you know have
some kind of a plan uh in the event that
this does happen do you want to talk
about the other ones
yes there's some of them
well just a few different things to go
along with those
in case of an attack does happen
you need to go through your different
backups kind of have plans
have different training into restoring
from the backups
so whenever these ransomware groups come
in they may get into your network
encrypt your backups delete the backups
or just kind of lock you out from those
so having
it's just me whenever i stand up here
so having just a different kind of
awareness and ability to go through that
can definitely save you a lot of money
and time recovering from those
well your access controls constantly
reviewing constantly updating and
managing those
compared to
what you see in a few different cases
where an actor gets onto a network
whether they create an account
escalate privileges onto a account that
was already created
companies not knowing about that that
actor might be on your network for
several months to several years
then with your email hygiene and
security culture
your number one threat is always going
to be the end user at their desk
so kind of just constantly promoting
with those
letting your
different coworkers know what is going
on with the landscape what is popular
right now and then having the actual
controls
built in to back that up so whether that
be an outlook with the reporting
phishing button
whether that be the tagging all external
emails in outlook or even just going
through and teaching your employees
here's what not to do if you believe
that you received a phishing email
and then i just want to touch on like
lori said
with the multi-factor and vpns so even
if you have those implemented we have
seen many cases where those are bypassed
just due to them either being
implemented poorly or improperly or not
patched
one of the largest ones that we see
was a 2018 vpn vulnerability where
actors have gone out and scraped these
credentials and posted them all online
and this has been out for three years
and we're still seeing companies come in
that are still vulnerable to this and
still have the exact plaintext creds
that were leaked for their vpns
and then infrastructure and segmentation
kind of limiting just how the threat
actors can jump around your network and
separating those whether this be they
get into a marketing computer versus one
of your sales people's computers
and then getting into being able to
spread across the entire network
so having the different monitoring
across the endpoints
and then being able to actually identify
and stop this kind of attacks are
critical to you just
not having your company be shut down for
would be two weeks to four weeks during
the entire attack
anything else gonna go with that
does anybody have any questions for us
[Music]
is everybody ready to go for lunch
we can see the boxes back there all
stacked up
awesome thank you everybody
[Applause]