we're going to close out
besides pittsburgh with an awesome talk
by a couple of people that are going to
tap dance and sing like yeah yeah
we're going to make it really difficult
for the camera how to fake friends and
fine people this is
gonna be
awesome take it away
you got you got hands-free i got a
double awesome yeah extra hands all
right so thanks everybody um
this is gonna be how to fake friends and
find people to build a buddy case study
clearly
click click click all right so
this guy's me it's a little bit older
picture before i decided to move and
stop cutting my hair
um i work for a company called attack
research i'm a security consultant at
pentester
um
oh it's mike we're getting some echoes
um both of you and i are prior special
operations forces
though that's spelled wrong it should
have a t on the end uh veterans
my contact info is up there i do not
have twitter because i don't want to um
i also have some
coins and conference swag stuff to give
away if you're interested
yep and then i'm david schloss i also go
by gabe
um
i'm the offensive security lead at
echelon cyber risk
i am a researcher red teamer
professional idiot whatever you want to
call me we have a lot of fun yeah she
gets it
i do have twitter all i do is post memes
and then my linkedin is nothing but uh
red team
tips and tricks
so
hit it away
all right so our our goal today right um
what we want to kind of talk about
is uh
we want you guys to start working in
crowdsource humanitarian efforts
uh 2020 saw this huge boom of people
using the internet go figure right
they're all bored at home uh they
stopped going on to facebook to hit oh
yeah you know that really sucks this
country's having a lot of problems let
me go ahead and hit like and send my
prayers that way
uh so they started helping out in
humanitarian crowdsource efforts
uh in this talk the scope is more
directed towards
those who are under direct threat of
harm
and
those who are being
like that's through like human
trafficking
wrongly persecuted individuals if you're
contacting those individuals through
efforts led like digital dunkirk was
that's what this is going to be talking
about
we also have this really really cool
thing at the bottom it's a cowboy hat
back in our unit when we were still in
the military there was a phrase it was
called don't cowboy it up
basically what that means is i don't
think this is the wild wild west if you
start going crazy and doing things wrong
people can get hurt
and whenever you do see that cowboy hat
if you start messing up that region of
the talk this is where people could
potentially die
uh so that's kind of how drastic this
talk gets into
hit it
cool i've got your obligatory cat meme
because i promised you that i would
so we're going to talk we're going to go
over
what are we talking about what is a sock
puppet um
why you use one when and where to use
them
and then the differences and some
consequences between good and bad
implementations and what happens when
you don't do it right vice when you do
yeah
so uh what's a sock puppet other than
you know something that five-year-olds
make in their kindergarten class
uh a sock puppet basically is a fake
online persona that is used to help mask
your true identity
um from your true identity wait did i
say that right or i say true identity
twice didn't i anyways it's a fake
persona that you put online it's
normally associated with the baddies you
know things like russian misinformation
actors
uh apts uh three-fourths of tinder for
all those who are equally on that
application uh maybe also like half of
linkedin i'm sure you all have the uh
the people who just message you about
jobs that don't exist
ultimately stock puppets are are a way
that can be used in a
offensive
security mindset so when we do things
like social engineering campaigns or red
teams we don't actually use our true
names right i'm not going over to a
client and going hey my name's david
schloss let me inside your building it's
more of like hey
i'm steve rogers i'm here to rescue you
guys let me in
things like that
uh so why does it matter probably right
why do you care
uh why would you want to use a humanita
a sock puppet during a humanitarian
operation
i'm gonna hold on with both hands here
because i think this is really important
for you guys to know the baddies have
the internet right
uh this isn't the days when the taliban
don't know how to
log into google this isn't the days when
boko haram is like oh man i don't i
don't know what facebook is like the
baddies have the internet and literally
everything about you there are companies
out there that know more about you than
three letter agencies and that's that's
the truth
uh which is kind of scary
but for the uh for the really really
cheap price of 0.99 you can learn about
anything so if you want to be
you know there's a there's a
little
cowboy hat there for a reason uh because
this is where people start turning into
stalker mode right like when you start
learning you're like oh man i know where
you live i know where your cousin lives
like you can literally find out
everything about a person uh we've done
that on multiple occasions where we have
to go and find a relative an advantage
of an individual who is in country and
that individuals here in the united
states are their relatives here in the
united states
we could find out everything about that
person get their their their daughter's
name phone number their husband whoever
it may be contact them because we've
lost contact with those individuals
so it's really important to use a sock
puppet and this is why you know the the
baddies do have it
word so this is kind of the big bottom
line picture is that these fake personas
when you use them correctly can keep you
safe super short version of what's nice
and long on the screen they keep you
from being found by the people you're
not trying to be found by as you're
communicating
past and through
their
network capabilities
that was me all right so
where do i start how do i do this um
step one
sorry step negative one before you do
anything
are you ready for this
are you in a head space that you can
tolerate getting involved in this kind
of an operation
um
i didn't do step negative one last time
we got involved in this and it was a bad
decision because i found myself talking
to people that were in a lot of danger
and i was
under a lot of stress anyway i didn't go
well think about whether or not you can
tolerate this kind of activity or not
mentally right that's all your mental
capability
headspace
so then it's cash record how are you
going to fund this
we're going to go through acquiring
temporary service building a fake
persona building your presence for that
persona step four obviously
question marks and then step five
not actually profit it's a go live and
and run your operation start your
communications
are you sure
okay
then you start off with low tech
all right we promised we practiced these
slides i swear yeah like at least once
all right so a question you also have to
ask yourself is how sophisticated is the
hostile entity um
are we trying to avoid people like the
taliban before the fall of kabul where
they don't own the telecom suites they
don't have access to all of the network
stack are we trying to avoid people like
the anti-balaka militia or the farc who
are relatively
low technology capabilities within their
user space
or
are trying to avoid advanced nation
state adversaries
yeah so we like to kind of point out the
difference because this is something
that a lot of new people
tend to
not understand right they think okay
there's some big humanitarian crisis
wrongly persecuted individuals to say
like in china right and then they're
like i want to help those people via
online methods well like obviously
china's really really good at hacking
i'm pretty sure i don't have to tell you
guys that right so they're going to be
able to run the telecom services they're
going to be able to track down who you
are as an individual even if you are
starting to use vpns like we're both we
come from a apt-ish
background right um we understand that
it is very easy to still backtrack ways
through um
i i also put up here the cartels right
we all know how danger danger the
cartels are you don't want to mess with
their money stream they they'll probably
behead you it's kind of terrifying right
but they have people everywhere uh
that's that's something to be aware of
when you start messing around with uh
let's say human trafficking you start
getting into the revenue stream of
criminal organizations that are
closer to home
you have to start worrying about all
right is this going to be a problem for
me
um
and depending on who they are the
retaliation could be higher the cartel
is more likely going to not care if they
go and try to whack you china and russia
probably aren't going to try to murder
you unless you're in like the uk you
know somewhere that's closer to them
uh but
for this talk like that's out of scope
we're not going to talk about anything
about getting into the more advanced
adversarial nation states
seriously be careful with this if you do
ever get invited to
participate in some sort of humanitarian
operation that does include something
that would be found up here including
the taliban after they've taken kabul
then
maybe back out especially if you haven't
done this before
which is why there's a big big cowboy
hat here because that is a high danger
yeah this is
this one's scary
so then you gotta you know really get
down to down to the dirty let's start
like actually building our fake online
persona let's build our sock puppet you
got to think about the first question
what do you want to go cash a card i
think they asked us at defcon 2 which is
really where they take card anymore but
cash is king for most of the part you
have to weigh the pros and cons uh the
pros here really cool it's hard to trace
right uh people aren't really putting
down like tracking numbers on your on
your cards or on your cash uh it's
really cool when you have a lot of it
you feel like you're you know tony
montana
uh and leftover cash can be spent in
singles i'm not you know
saying anything but if you want to go
downstairs you can spend them over in
the
slot machines and whatnot
the cons is is not everyone's going to
accept this uh and there's a there's a
cowboy hat here because i've seen this
happen before uh when you go to buy your
equipment be that like a
a visa gift card or your cell phone
service via cash places like target
and
well actually i only can speak on target
because i've seen it there but uh they
won't accept cash for this kind of
transaction they want a card they want
some way of being able to track it it's
not technically illegal to do this but
it is
it's a gray area people don't like you
to do it uh but i've seen some guys like
try to like fight the cash register
because they're like trying to uphold
their own policy and i'm pretty sure
we've all seen that here in 2020 as
people just go insane or 2021.
um i don't remember what year it is it's
all learned together at this point
but you know just be aware of that and
we're not endorsing anything on the
screen these are just services that you
could use
everybody has their own preferences
but you can get your temporary cards
through things like do not pay or
privacy.com these are
cards that aren't associated to a name
so you can put any sort of name to pay
for your service
and then obviously this visa gift cards
you can buy via your card as well which
is a little weird but that only enables
for more financial tracking if you were
going against a more nation state
cool so now you've got your cash you've
got your card you've made your decision
how you're going to fund this first
thing we're going to do is we're going
to get ourselves a phone number so you
do not want to use your own personal
number we'll talk about why in a little
while it's not a good decision
uh you got physical phones you have
virtual devices physical phones are
obviously easier to do especially for
like lower tech kind of capabilities
people go get a track phone or an atm t
prepaid or i don't care i don't
i'm not paid by any of these guys i
don't care go get whatever find some way
to get a cell phone
um alternately if you've got virtual
devices me i'm lazy i'm a nerd i sat in
my chair i virtualized stuff
i'm not going to walmart i'm not doing
it bluestacks is a tool that we used
it lets you virtualize an android system
and then
burner app was the application that we
used you can pay them like what seven
bucks and they get you a phone number
that works for like two weeks so now i
have a phone number and we're ready to
move
okay
so now now you have your your cash or
card you have your
cell phone service next thing is
building your believable
persona
right all these photos up here aren't
real people that's a disclaimer you know
you can give a name to anybody but
basically you use one of these two links
what we would recommend right
this person does not exist it's actually
really cool if you go ahead and hit
refresh a few times you can see some
very terrifying images of like people
with tentacles out of their eyes it's
really creepy but other times you get
really cool things like uh you know
iranian seth rogen here in the middle um
it's my favorite one yeah
you know like so you get all these like
really cool generated images and if you
use the one that generated photos uh or
generated dot photos they uh they give a
little watermark on the bottom so if
you're good at uh powershell or
powershell
photoshop thank you
sorry i give too many talks on
powershell um then you know you can you
can take the watermark out and and put
it up on your facebook your twitter
whatever it may be
and then the second piece to this whole
story is you have to
build a believable
story of that individual right something
that hasn't really been mentioned yet is
kind of creating this like age of the
person uh if you go out and just build
yourself a sock puppet like five minutes
later you're using that sock puppet in
the wild people are gonna know
it's probably a sock puppet right so you
can build this nice little backstory and
it gives you the ability to remember the
name especially if you're communicating
with people who are under duress in
country where you're helping
so like you you know you go to
fakenamegenerator.com and it's like your
name is now kevin smith you're like oh
that's super easy to remember right or
or something in a sense and it gives you
everything like what your email address
should be what is your password what is
your social security number if you
really have to give something like that
or a credit card number your employment
building these backstories really helps
you remember
who you are in this persona especially
when you're communicating with those
overseas or away from from the domestic
united states
uh i think that's it for this one
but i don't like using those
so
our standard practice is to grab a photo
pick one that you like and then make fun
of the poor guy for five minutes
i mean they're not real
right so you can be you can you can have
a little fun with it right like
so like for this particular guy he looks
like he has like two first names right
like something
like what like chat
chat chat
no yeah so this is something when it's
blown up you can kind of see like where
the ai kind of screws up too yeah what
was mentioned is his ears are not
symmetrical and you're right he kind of
has a little bit of elf ears there right
so down here his caller's messed up i
mean there's artifacts from the from the
generation
this this guy doesn't usually look good
enough to work i don't know he looks
like a like a
i don't know what would you call his
last name
kent kent chet kent that's a hard name
to pronounce
right but you know so our chat here we
got to figure out what what his
occupation is what his age is where he
went to school maybe his job right
because this is stuff that's stuff
that's asked in like your facebook
profile or your twitter or your
uh linkedin right communication methods
that you would have with people overseas
so yeah i don't know he looks like he's
like mid-thirties uh i would say he's
probably in the military but i'm kind of
biased just because that haircut's a
little like military-ish
um
i don't know pick a school what do you
think
not pittsburgh michigan state
count
oh that's actually my hometown that
looks scary
you doing some ocean
all right so he's from sacramento he's
his name's chet wow what a great
probably went probably went to see kay
mcclatchy too
uh out of the military his email would
be something totally ridiculous like
like ultra chat he would have his name
inside of it right he looks like one of
those people who'd probably be
entertained with his own name
um
but i mean you guys get the idea right
like this it's a silly way of like
coming up with a backstory for an
individual that doesn't exist and you
have fun with it because uh this is the
only time you're actually gonna have fun
um
once once you start going live it starts
getting depressing
that's the wrong way is it yeah it is
yeah yeah there we go there we go so
this is awesome
so um
now we got it all done right we built
our persona hopefully you've aged it a
little bit it's not brand new if you
need to have friends on facebook because
you're trying to make it even look even
more believable go on fiverr it's like
twelve dollars to get ten thousand
friends i looked
um it's really cheap actually actually
if you need more followers on on youtube
you can get it there as well but you
wanna start building your actual
communication platform your
online presence
per se right so the first thing you want
to do is you're going to go out and
you're going to find yourself a
privacy based email something like
protonmail private on mail doesn't like
share it out to other people right they
like to say they're secure this is where
all your
information that's going to come in
that's potentially sensitive and what i
mean by sensitive is
when you are communicating with these
individuals overseas you're likely going
to get some pii you know their names
their passport numbers probably some
photos maybe even their country
identification code or number uh there's
a lot of stuff that you don't you know
you wouldn't want your social security
number getting out there so you want
people who are handling this information
here in the states to be handling with
the same sort of discretion
uh that's going to go to your proton
mail
the next thing you're going to do is
you're going to build yourself your
google or your yahoo and that's
kind of important because that's where
all your social media is going to be
built from uh
you know facebook linkedin they like to
pretend and say like oh we don't like
sock puppets you know we're against
stock puppets because misinformation
actors it's just not true
right uh you can build yourself a sock
puppet quite
quite easily
and uh they'll be like okay i guess sure
cool you know add a thousand friends
within five minutes like man yeah i'm
cool with this uh so your gmail you're
out that's gonna go towards your social
media accounts and then the last piece
is really just setting up the social
media accounts using that phone number
that you had uh set up earlier that's
going to go into your facebook and
linkedin because those require a phone
number
i think gmail does too right gmail
definitely does yeah yeah
you used to be able to get away with not
having a phone number now you have to
have one so we had to add like the first
three steps oh you miss your mic
oh this is you
all right so
[Laughter]
shenanigans so
one kind of consideration we tapped on
earlier was whether or not you're
dealing with an advanced adversary or a
lower tech adversary if you are dealing
with somebody who can monitor your
network traffic or is viewing everything
that comes in and out of the country
it's probably a good idea to use some
vpns um
you're definitely going to want to
consider where your operation is
happening for example if you are in
pakistan you want to use vpns to come
out of india because they're not going
to cooperate with each other when it
becomes time for
an investigation if they ask hey who was
this where was this coming from india is
not going to help pakistan they're not
so you want to make sure to consider
where you're coming from and where your
vpn pops are coming out of
this is actually kind of important for
the previous effort i don't know if
anybody remembers or knows about digital
dunkirk like the taliban as they were
taking over kabul right like they were
able to gain more and more control into
the telecommunication networks there
they were already shutting down the cell
service and the um
the internet service on sundown until
sunup but uh slowly but surely they were
capturing telecommunication points and
putting their own
network security people into monitoring
that activity so that's where this kind
of comes in as well
yeah so uh here comes the fun part right
like you've just built your whole
persona you you've you know we've been
building up to this whole point what do
you do now how do you uh how do you
communicate with the people on the
ground you're like i'm ready to help
people yeah
um so here's some things and things not
to do right first and foremost when you
start talking to people overseas like
you're
probably not like prior government
employees right we've we've had team
members who are not
you probably never handled a source
before uh the first and most important
thing to do is validate who this
individual is
right um
you have their information that was
given to you by some ngo or
non-government organization that's
helping people get out of the country or
maybe even somebody who is within the
government and they just need extra help
right
like digital dunkirk uh in this case you
want to validate who you're talking to
don't tell the information that you have
to that individual because then they'll
just be like oh yeah that's me for sure
right have them read you their passport
number have them give you their country
identification code right
be smart about this because it this this
part right here is is what most people
that were unfamiliar with these kind of
techniques or um
helping individuals screwed up on the
most and that caused a lot of a lot of
problems for us later on uh
only use your temporary devices for
communication and i will double hold
onto the mic again because i cannot
reiterate this enough do not use your
home computer or your home phone
right let's say you're looking for
somebody you're trying to track down
somebody and you find their linkedin
right and you're using your fake persona
of gabe
uh to go and look at linkedin's is this
the right individual the photo seems to
match up okay let's try to contact them
through linkedin right you're trying to
get in contact with these individuals in
any way possible
uh if you use your home computer i don't
know you might be logged into still your
account and now your account is showing
up in their
viewpoints right it's another added
point that if that individual gets
captured and some sort of like
investigation or sse is what we call in
the military is done on that individual
they'll find you
right and then they have your
information they have your name they
have your face they know that
individuals talking to americans based
off the conversations on their phone
and you're the only american in their
linkedin presence
who are they going to come and look at
right who are they going to harass
so only use your devices
um
another really important thing and for
any prior govi or military people in the
room pace which is uh a communication
plan primary alternate
contingency
contingency and emergency i just use
this all the time uh and i still can't
remember it
basically what that means is you want to
have different communication methods
with the person that you're talking to
right let's say hey my primary to
talking to you is going to be signal
because i can set these to delete after
five minutes uh and then once these
delete and the end of days has occurred
delete my phone number i'll contact you
eight am your time
your alternate could be all right so
signal's down in country because the
the entity that is chasing you is uh
shutting down signal traffic let's go
ahead and use whatsapp all right
whatsapp doesn't work let's use facebook
messenger let's use
uh
just a phone right let's straight up
call you on your one nine or your plus
one nine or your whatever country code
plus one nine three um
[Music]
you know have have different methods to
communicate with this individual but
also know that these individuals are
probably scared and they're not at the
same level of
of uh
clear-headed thinking as as you're gonna
be on your side behind a computer
uh so create a duress word from that if
they are walking through a potentially
scary location
like a checkpoint with people with guns
and
those people with guns start shooting
which has occurred a few times in our
uh
our efforts
you know have them send hey here's my oh
[ __ ] word right for lack of a better
phrase of it that's the duress word once
they've given you that word they should
know delete your phone number
and
when they remake contact with you you
have to start back from step one
validate who you're talking to
because you don't know that person could
have been captured right that person
could be killed and now somebody else is
using their cell phone they don't know
who they're talking to
uh something like that if they didn't
delete the number which is what happened
a lot of times
then
well whoa don't don't touch that button
just yet but we got one more section to
go yeah then we got the things not to do
this is like the put on your cowboy hat
right and then take it off put it to the
side because we're not using it here put
your cowboy boots down this is where it
gets scary right because this is what
gets people in trouble
don't have an active conversation with
somebody while they're on the move
this was actually a lesson learned from
digital dunkirk
which was really important
the taliban
don't like it when you talk on the phone
in their
checkpoint areas
they'll tell you get off the phone right
particularly if it's in english oh yes
especially if it's in english right
they're like
you know i'm watching you fam
right uh but actually way more
aggressive and probably not something to
joke about uh
an individual was killed in this
instance where they were talking to the
the handler on our side in english a
taliban checkpoint guy heard him
shot the guy didn't even ask questions
just shot him right so don't have an
active conversation
tell him what to do tell him where to go
drop locations but cut it at that leave
it a text if you have to have a
conversation make sure they're in a
secured location where they're not going
to be overheard by other people who
could potentially rat them out
don't group multiple contacts into the
same channel
right
uh you don't know who you're always
talking to people get captured all the
time especially when they're trying to
run out of countries if they're being
persecuted wrongly or
even human trafficking right like you
don't know who is who
and you're only a guy behind the
computer so make sure you're keeping
everybody separate it might take longer
but it's smarter to do it this way
uh do not promise anything this is for
your mental health
right
uh these these operations weigh a ton on
your on your mind especially like coming
from our perspective where we were
actively engaged in these kind of things
as military people and now all we can do
is just passively engage in these kind
of operations where we help out and and
do it on behind a computer on this side
and if you start promising things that's
going to weigh on your head especially
if you can't get that person out right
you're gonna be there going all right
yeah yeah we're gonna we're gonna get
you out of country we're gonna get you
safe if that person gets captured or
killed like
it's not gonna just leave your head of
like oh yeah that's that sucks no you're
gonna be like oh i promise this guy like
it's gonna weigh heavily on your soul so
that's your mental health keep at it
right
and uh of course the last thing is
don't don't forget to do the things in
the to-do section these things are
stressful we get it if you're new at
these kind of operations reach out to
people like us especially if you start
helping in these things because we're
more than willing to help we like opsec
we like having these operations continue
we like to help people
so anything we can do to make sure that
you as a new person in the group can
do it right
you know we're gonna we're gonna stop
we're gonna slow down we'll be like okay
let's let's crawl before we walk let's
walk for a run
those kind of things hit it
this with me again
all right so
obviously there's things to consider
uh traditional step five we've talked
about it a couple times your mental
health's important
i got to stay alive so i can help
i need to take care of me
think about what you're doing before you
commit to something
before you make promises you might not
be able to come through on
um know your limits don't take on too
many contacts right we've talked about
not grouping too many people into a
group conversation part of that happens
because i take on 15 20 25 contacts and
i can't manage all of them at once
don't don't do that to yourself uh we'll
talk about what happens if what can
happen i guess if you do that here in a
little bit
um
yeah um
i got they're too small over here and
then i got to turn around dingus so we
don't plan how you're going to debrief
uh how are you going to decompress from
this
how are you going to mentally remove
yourself from what you've been doing
lately
because again it can be very mentally
and emotionally taxing
and then understand when your
involvement is more of a risk than it is
a benefit there's value added in saying
hey here's a safe location this
checkpoint doesn't exist here's where
you can go here's a safe house
but after a point providing that
information might be more of a risk
because
the traffic's being monitored or
i can't verify that that route's safe
anymore so there it does there may come
a point where you need to go
it's time for me to go away i'm sorry
you're on your own i've done everything
i can i can no longer help it's more
dangerous for you now if i continue
talking to you
yeah there's also a really good story
you guys can look on the news which is
pretty true a group of cowboys at the
the last digital dunkirk they decided
hey we want to keep helping um you know
these are all prior military guys
they're like yeah we want to keep
helping but we want to go back in the
country so they brought a ton of guns
into pakistan
and then tried to fly into afghanistan
like yeah that was really going to work
their bud so uh you know where your risk
becomes more
or where your involvement becomes more
of a risk is this because now the us
government has to be like really dude
now we got to try to get them to bring
you back to the united states so we can
prosecute you here instead of using in a
pakistani jail
um
but you know you we all want to help we
get it but you have to know when to stop
yeah big hat on that one don't don't fly
to pakistan with a plane full of guns
it's a bad idea don't do it it does look
really cool though you know oh yeah we
uh
find a meme for that one yeah okay so um
all right we should have definitely
download one
that's bad okay so here's where it
starts to get kind of depressing but the
memes don't stop so sorry about that
guys this is this is how we defeat humor
in the military as we just make jokes um
but this is where we talk about the
consequences of bad implementation or
your bad implementation of ttps right
uh some of the things that we're going
to talk about here is loss of your
anonymity is that the right way you
pronounce that word anemone and anemone
and then
i can't speak english sorry guys uh
disclosure of privileged information
right uh you don't want their
information get out there just like you
don't want your social security getting
out there uh you can burn multiple
objectives in your operation from from
doing things poorly you can get
harassment from the baddies nobody wants
that and there is potential loss of life
as we've already mentioned before
so uh the risk to you the the one thing
i think is really important is you need
to understand that you are not always
100 disconnected form from your
sock puppet you're not getting the stock
puppet from the government you're not on
in the government's cover program right
the united states administration for
social security isn't giving you a brand
new social security number this is you
uh
and a sophisticated enough actor can
come down to track you via network
tracking financial tracking right if
they really wanted to get back at you
they could find ways of getting back at
you
is that going to happen if you guys
stick to what we've been saying so far
probably probably not right like there's
plenty of people out there that do this
and they don't get caught at all and we
don't even know who they are uh but it's
on you
to not get doxxed just like how it's on
you to not get doxxed in the normal
world if you're out there playing call
of duty and you start trash talking to
14 year old you know you probably should
not do that because he's gonna dox you
you know they don't have any they don't
have any control over that
or their own actions
but what can happen so online harassment
threats uh travel restrictions right if
you start doing this against russia it's
not a friend of russia it's not
necessarily like russia's gonna be out
there like oh yeah hey no i don't like
that there it's just a line of people
are gonna be like yeah you can't come
here you can't come down to uzbekistan
uh which you know for some of us that's
not a problem i don't mind not going
back to afghanistan not gonna lie
uh
and then for all you fed boys and girls
out there your clearance can be put at
risk here uh the fact is if you have
contact with foreign contacts which you
will if you start doing these operations
you have to put in your sf86 for those
who don't know what an sf-86 is it's a
big long paperwork that
that you you have to fill out it takes
like a few days and you hate your life
and you're like this is miserable uh
don't do it right if you if you're
a fed
just you know help out other ways
so now
yeah we uh as you may have noticed when
we missed the meme
uh we we didn't fully update this one
uh yeah you fed girls you guys can get
out get away with this you know like
you'd be good to go they'd be like
particularly egregious is if in the
event that somebody's phone does get
captured and they say hey
this is no longer the person you were
talking to this is
made up name x
uh at say the checkpoint
now you do have to say on your clearance
paperwork yes i have been in direct
contact with members of a terrorist
organization and then you have to deal
with that
yeah if you've never had to negotiate
with the taliban it's a good day it's
gonna suck
yeah
okay
so this isn't a real face this is a made
up one just like all the others
um it's also not a real name but these
are examples of
uh two two examples of what not to do or
what happens if you do it wrong and then
we'll do one good one so rebecca here uh
as a single-aged middle mother found out
through a friend through a friend
through a friend through somebody who
worked uh these kind of operations that
digital dunkirk was ongoing
she wanted to get involved so she did
she contacted through whatever means she
needed to very low technical knowledge
does not know what opsec means
um now that i've said that out loud up
here
not everybody is going to know what
object means opsec is operational
security it's the concept of how you're
going to protect your operation as it's
ongoing
um and since that was the case
we've touched on this before the hostile
entity contact
confiscated words are hard man her
contact's phone they reverse search that
phone number to get her information and
then they started harassing her online
and sending her personal information
back to her because she was using her
personal phone to make contact with our
contacts in country this is why you
don't do that
because you do not want the taliban
saying hey you live at address x and i'm
coming for you and your kid
you don't want that
so this is an example
of what happens if you do
not wait follow the instructions yeah
and something to point out
when you when you kind of make these
mistakes right whether it be
through ignorance or through
uh just bad practice this does take
resources away from the ongoing
operation right we had to take a few
bodies and say hey let's start helping
rebecca here um
lock down her online persona she had
like her facebook like public to
everybody right she could accept
messages from anybody aside from having
her change her phone number we had to
start like working through the list of
okay how can we lock down like your
online social presence so you're not
getting as many like random threats from
uh
the taliban and i mean that is that's
pretty stressful i don't know if any of
you guys have received death threats
before but that kind of sucks especially
as a single mother
right
but
at the end of the day right she got
doxed ducks deduct herself don't don't
do that right it's on you
uh the next example is bobby and this
guy really does kind of look like a
bobby um
but uh the reason we call him bobby is
because bobby is also another uh name
i'm sorry if your name is bobby but you
know it's like your best friend or a
blue falcon
or if you guys don't know what a blue
falcon is it's a guy who pretty much
screws you over in your unit uh don't be
a bobby i'm sorry if your name is bobby
we've kind of singled you out here um
but bobby here he was a prior government
employee he had some moderate technical
knowledge right he wasn't like dom and
i.t but um
he wasn't like a cyber guy he never did
i.t security or anything like that uh
and bobby's biggest mistake was he
didn't know when to say no so
as
in this case digital dunkirk was ongoing
uh
he was like hey man yeah i'll take more
like hey we got we got another 12
families can you take them yeah i'll
take more it ended up being like bobby
had like 50 plus contacts inside his um
his roster of things he needed to take
care of right and so
uh bobby thinking all right let me
streamline this conversation here we
needed to move all these contacts to a
safe house which was a a hotel that we
had paid somebody roughly about like ten
thousand dollars of worth of like
anonymous donations we had people like
the whole day going all right yeah yeah
let's collect some money we we gathered
about ten thousand that was going to
keep our contacts like a whole group i
think it was closer to like a hundred
people say for about like 10 days right
bobby's like oh yeah no that seems cool
i'll just group them all instead of
giving the contact information or the
the movement information each person
individually well this is a problem
right this is a problem because as those
individuals were making their way to the
safe house
one of those group of families got
captured
they got stopped at a checkpoint they
were arrested the phone was searched
the
the individual didn't have time to
delete the information on there and now
you have a
adversary in your group chat who just
scrolls up and goes hey there's a
safe house information here i wonder
what that's all about right none of the
prior information was there i guess he
had given the um
the back story in the private
information or private text there that
they had deleted through signal
uh the only reason we know that there
was an adversary in this group was
because that person started asking
really really weird questions right like
how many people are going to this safe
house uh is this safe house within
this region right which was
semi-controlled by rebels forces at the
time
right they were asking very very
weird jaded questions that
bobby's contacted the time probably
wouldn't have been asking they would
have been like just get us there safe do
it now so when we went to go actually do
the
reauthentication of who they were right
reconfirm who they were uh they couldn't
they couldn't give us any of the
information that was required they
couldn't give us proof of life and in
that jazz and we were able to determine
more than likely this guy got arrested
uh or that contact family got arrested
and um
now the safe house is burned so that's
ten thousand dollars that was thrown out
the window right just like that that's
not like necessarily our money but
that's people who are trying to donate
to a cause to make life better for those
who are being wrongly persecuted in this
case and a lot of these individuals
going to that safe house we're already
on the hit list for the taliban so
that's a that's a bad day especially
when they're like three-fourths of the
way there and you got to go hey run just
i don't care where you go hide right so
don't be bobby bobby's
kind of creepy he also doesn't have like
one side of his glasses uh right so
another ai generated problem broken
glasses bobby yeah don't
sorry bobby if you're out there
all right so we talked about what
happens if you do it wrong unfortunately
the list of things that happen when you
do it right
is real short
it's you don't get doxxed you don't get
threatened your app doesn't get blown
that's pretty much uh pretty much it if
there are small issues they're small
issues it's a family needs to relocate
instead of
80 families need to go to
somewhere i don't know where we i don't
know where to send them
so
your hiccups are small they're
manageable the list's pretty short
which
seems sad but
yeah don't do it wrong don't
don't be dumb
all right so also not a real face i just
thought the black bar was funny and it
kind of looks like one of our buddies
this is an example of a better
implementation
pedro here fake name prior military high
technical knowledge knows about opsec
and knows how to implement it i'm not
saying that because he's prior military
he's better at it
it's just his background
um
so
this guy managed to establish
communications with 50 plus contacts
bunch of people different places kept
them all segregated kept them all
separate didn't group them together
uh multiple successful ops digital
dunkirk was one of them but there's been
several others i don't know who this guy
actually is i know him by a couple of
handles that's it i don't even know who
he is we've worked with him
a couple times we've worked with him a
few times yeah he comes from our same
background so we were able to confirm
who he was through through other
channels but
um
yeah this guy
very very sneaky even amongst the group
good implementation
but as you can see right like not a
whole lot to say there he did good he
did good he got people out that's all
that we care about you don't need to you
want to be famous about doing it yep
bonus step six
burn it down
get rid of your vms delete everything
smash your sims
take i like taking my hard drives out
and shooting at them because i'm a
hillbilly from montana
uh
delete your vms close all those accounts
pet your dog call your therapist
whatever it is you need to do next start
that detox process start your debrief uh
take care of yourself because now
now it's that time
just don't keep anything
don't keep anything it's dumb too you
don't want to use that cell phone
anyways you're probably getting calls
from people you don't want to get calls
from
and i mean you already get enough spam
calls on your home phone why would you
want more spam calls
right think of it that way it might be
tempting to say hey i need to hang on to
this proton mail with some information
in it because what if this guy contacts
me again
then i have us all in all of his
information we're ready to go but you do
not want to do that because you need
them to establish who they are to you
again
phone got captured email got compromised
whatever it is
it's been six hours i don't trust this
number anymore i don't trust this email
and i chose this facebook account prove
to me you are who you are so there is no
real good reason to keep any of the
prior information get rid of it delete
it shut the accounts down
yeah
and so because we're military we like to
sandwich everything so uh now we're
gonna give you a down and dirty review
of what we just exactly talked about
but we have about like a couple minutes
left so just just to go over what we
talked about we talked about no you
should know what a stock puppet is by
now if you don't like come talk to us
afterwards we'll explain it better maybe
probably
um
you should have an idea of when and and
where to use them uh where to start some
silly techniques to build your own stock
puppy if you don't want to use name
generator uh how to use them i already
said that and the inherent risk and
difference and consequences of
of good and bad implementation right
like ultimately if anything that you've
learned today is that by going and
cowboying it up you're gonna screw
somebody else's life up
right there's that potential when you
start working in this
realm
of uh humanitarian operations but with
that we have
any any questions
i i know some of you got some out there
we don't we don't do interpretive dances
though
no we did sorry yeah sorry we didn't
rehearse the tap routine for you
all right well cool if uh if you guys
are too shy come come talk to us
afterwards we'll give you uh
give you some pointers
thanks everyone
awesome awesome talk