I thank you very much we are talking
about the human factor in cybersecurity
and the humans are missing in the room I
guess the people who are sitting in the
back if they can cooperate with me a
little bit and come to the front it'll
be a great great service to whatever we
are going to do so volunteer please all
right so I think we are already running
behind the schedule and I would like to
keep it as tight as I am asked to do
before I call my panelists which also
was a was a bit of a surprise for me
because you know many a people due to
the obvious coronavirus had canceled
their trip so I had to I had to kind of
assemble a panel overnight yeah actually
overnight you are right so let me let me
just invite the panelists here and then
we'll do a small brief on what we are
going to discuss what is this human
factor and then would seek participation
from all of you who are in the room so
please welcome forum Mehta forum is the
head of information security at an APEC
level for PayPal welcome forum my friend
in many ways my mentor - Burgess Cooper
Burgess is the partner for information
security at ey welcome Burgess
[Applause]
you can just bring them up there is a I
have the privilege of again you know
last year also I moderated a panel with
him as a panelist so welcome Manish
Tewari Manish is the group CEO of Bharti
Airtel one of the one of the greatly
surviving tell telcos in India so
welcome please last but not the least I
have Venkatesh Subramanyam
Venkatesh leads the global CEO role at
Olam International so just just look at
the variety of the panel from my extreme
right which is Ola which is an a group
in an agribusiness in agribusiness to a
telco to a FinTech and and end to a one
of the one of the big force in the
advisory and consulting space so you
know before before we go on to crucify
these panelists with with what questions
I have not I have not given them any
preparation so all of them will have a
surprise check on their knowledge so I
was referring to to a slightly dated
research from the University of oh yes
sorry so as we talk you will see you you
will see our friend what sell from me by
doing a mind map which is a live mind
map which means that whatever they are
speaking is going to be projected here
and those who are interested in having
that knowledge later on can please let
us know we'll mail this to you so as I
said that I was referring to a slightly
dated research which happened in 2018 at
the University of Maryland it's an
academic it's an academic paper it's not
a research done by any InfoSec company
or group and you know very just the
abstract part of it I will I will read
for you and it gives a gives a flavor of
how ignorant we are about the human
factor in cyber security domain so it
says that
human factor remains unexplored and
underappreciated in information security
mark these two words unexplored and
underappreciated the mounting
cyberattacks data breaches ransomware
attacks as a result of human enabled
errors in fact are they are 95 percent
of all cyber incidents which are human
enabled 95 percent and whom do we blame
at the end of it is that technology is
not working or the seesaw is bad
research indicates that existing
information security plans do not
account for human factors in risk
management or auditing corporate
executives managers and cyber security
professionals rely extensively on
technology to avert cyber security
incidents and very fallaciously believe
that technology is the key to improving
security defenses even though the
research says otherwise that new
technologies create unintended
consequences nonetheless technology in
induced errors are all human enabled so
you're getting my point you know even if
the technology is foolproof technology
is proven its tested it's done the the
the induction of error in the technology
solution or technology deployment is all
human related so you know another very
startling fact if I if I tell you that
in here 2015 and it's a very very 5-year
five years ago a report indicated that
four or five companies Wells Fargo Bank
of America Citibank and JP Morgan Chase
these four companies put together
invested 1.5 billion dollars in
mitigating emerging and persisting cyber
threats imagine just four companies on
1.5 billion dollars of investment in
cybersecurity wonder who was a
consultant so that you could find out
okay so I think enough of enough of
reading of data from my side however I
would like to now kick-start the
discussion you know some some really
blatant opening thoughts from all of you
starting with you Burgess as to how how
do you evaluate the human factor in
cyber security and where are the weak
links where is the lacunae sure Thanks
so when you said five years ago I saw
you man fine alkanes ago yeah five
Malkin's ago on that note I think when
we say human factor for security most of
us look at plain simple learning
awareness but I would serve rephrase
that more than learning in awareness I
think it's the attitude of that security
guy which counts you know if he's a
headhunter does he really like to hunt
between the eyes if he's a red team or
does he really have the kill to get that
work done between which most others are
not fine or easy happy to settle for the
easiest one if he's a defender you know
will he really be able to safeguard his
whole estate behind in spite of knowing
that there are hundred holes so more
than learning an awareness for me the
most most important part of the human
factor for a cyber researcher or the
people in the audience is your attitude
towards security you really want to hunt
between the eyes you want to really make
an impact or are you just no care and
awareness is good and life will go on
that's my opening lines so wonderful
point that your attitude towards
security will decide how how robust the
cyber security plan quad will they or
seesaw survives the job or not that's
the next discussion yeah because you
know either they are responsible how
many of you work in corporates here show
fans oh my god lot of them so you're
CSIS job depends on depends on how you
perform in the organization and how well
was I saw you know pressure how well
versed are you with the dust with the
you know the errors that humans create
so I will I will quickly move on to
forum you know your initial comments on
on what we are discussing today and as
we move to specific questions sure
you know I think just on the thought and
uh just on the line with that the number
is that you put together on the number
of breaches and and how humans are the
weakest link it is important to
understand how we function and we
haven't you know as a discipline
invested in a pin and truly understand
for example this corona outbreak that is
going on there's been incredible number
of advisories every single doctor
everybody who's worth their money has
said do not wear masks unless you are
sick and in just in this room don't we
see so many people doing exactly what
will actually lead you to be getting
sick if you are not already sick because
now you can attach your face that many
times you're gonna try and remove it put
it somewhere and then put it back on
your face so the idea is that you know
it's very important to understand why we
do what we do and then find from a
corporate perspective ways in which how
we can incentivize the right kind of
behavior or decentralize that kind of
behavior so from a PayPal perspective
again you know we don't think of all
humans is the same or only thinking of
the employees and not thinking of the
developers I broadly I think segment
humans into three categories one is our
customers everybody who is outside and
we think of them as our customers and
what is it that they want to do some of
it some of them are probably in this
room and some of them are attackers some
of them are users but how can we make
sure that the good behavior is
incentivize and bad is not the second of
the builders and what do we do to make
sure the products that we create are the
right kind of products and third are the
operators or the user and as we go
through the the links I'll you know say
how one particular approach may work
really well for a one segment and the it
may not work well for the others but
it's important to not treat everybody in
the same bucket and and the core
principle just you know as Berger said
if attitude is in you know as since we
are doing the mindmap
is one area I think from my perspective
the biggest and the most important
considering cyber as a discipline is to
try and keep it as simple as possible so
simply
in this complex world is extremely
important will be thought about human
factors so yeah good two points here
incentivize the right behavior I don't
know how many companies follow this in
in letter and spirit but I haven't I
haven't really seen incentives being
doled out to further for the for the
good behavior however I have seen yeah
deterrence for the for the bad behavior
which is also a good practice however so
sorry for Manisha your opening comments
so if you're talking about the human
angle which impacts cybersecurity I mean
let's look at it from two perspectives
99.9% of the people in any organization
really understand ITT beside IT security
so I think it is more about how to and
no disrespect the fact is it is not
their core business you know they are
they may be tech savvy but they do not
understand the integration in the
Integra C's of information technology or
or IT security so I think it's about
simplification it's about very simple
and clear and strong messages it's about
human mind which tends to forget things
a little too frequently so it's also
about reminding people at a regular
interval sensitization campaigns should
be run on a regular basis so as to keep
that mind fresh on some of the basic
aspects of cyber security and then I
come to the core element of the actual
cyber warriors which you are supposed to
protect the entire organization now with
the current focus on automation you know
there is a lot of belief that look the
human element why is it important in the
Armed Forces we love to say that look
irrespective of what happens for the
foreseeable future we will always be a
man on a woman behind the machine so
there is nothing called hundred-person
automation as well today I'd like to
share this with you in Bharti Airtel we
have currently over a period of one year
with a lot of effort and dedication of
the team 70% of my security operations
right up to incident response is
automated 70 percent okay now going
forward raising the bar is going to be
very very difficult because you can
reach a benchmark but beyond that
if you have to raise the bar it's a but
we continue to do that but there is a
very very strong team of people you know
working relentlessly the most important
thing for any job and cybersecurity is
no different
is what is the aptitude of the person
yes all right you may have in fact I
will speak to an ex-colleague
this you know just shortly before coming
into this room you may want to do you
know something specifically in
cybersecurity but you have to as as an
individual and as a professional really
understand your own strengths and
limitations or what are your strengths
and what I am where where does your
aptitude take you because eventually
that is not just important for your
individual success it's also a very
important contributing factor for the
success of your team and your
organization so I think that aptitude
part is extremely extremely important so
it's just warming up you know I will I
will include people's participation the
people who are listening their
participation also once once we hear
from Venkatesh first good morning to all
of you so talking about the human factor
usually we say that the human or the
employee is the weakest link in the
organization but if we kind of put it in
a more positive self fashion I would say
that you know the employee can actually
be the greatest strength like now that
you have so I would say that you know
from a human factor it is true I mean
like in a statistics do indicate that
25% like a know of incidents are purely
just because of some employee like
actually making an error right I mean an
employee clicking on a link etc so I
would say that the two aspects that we
as caesars need to focus on is C and we
use this word awareness very often but I
would say that you know if we if we look
at training main training people
to be self-reliant and to be able to
different the organization so I would
say for the employees one aspect I would
emphasize is the amount of training that
you can keep on a repeated fashion and
when I and I mean training where I would
like us to be a little different is that
you know people every all people have
got their jobs right so you are trying
to do an awareness campaign you're
trying to send a newsletter nobody is
going to look at that because they all
have their day jobs so if you can make
that training a little bit more
interesting like through some form of
gamification etc and actually make sure
like you know that that key message that
this what they should and they should
not do if that is kind of deeply imbibed
in them that'll be a great win for you
so training is one aspect and the other
is like you know what some of my other
panelists also spoke is the culture so
the culture is a little different from
training where in like you know is - it
should actually be kind of a second
nature so I mean how do we actually make
sure that you know we reward like in our
cases of good behavior like an of
reporting of incidents of cases like
that and also in cases like Ana where
people are actually trying to hide right
either deliberately or like you know
through a lapse in judgment we have to
actually start taking actions so what we
do not do well today is we just run
these campaigns but there is no
consequence of that so as long as we can
build a consequence mechanism and then
make that as a part of like another
culture I think we will go a long way in
making at least that employee aspect
like and which is considered to be the
weakest link that will become like you
know our greatest strength for the
organization yeah so you know great
great two points coming here from from
what when Katie said is the culture of
the organization needs to be very very
carefully carefully pursued by the
management and
collected in the in the larger ecosystem
also about the training aspect I will
come to that I have a small I have a
small challenge on the training aspect
whether training is the only thing that
that we can provide to humans or we can
cultivate them in some other ways as
well so Burgess you know very
interesting point that I have captured
from the research unfortunately I
couldn't share it with you is that
purpose the researchers and human
factors experts vehemently emphasize
that technology alone will not
ameliorate information security big fat
there for organizations need to leverage
behavioral specialists to examine cyber
security operations from cognitive and
bias viewpoints now my question to you
is not this this was a preface to my
question the question is that you know
what goes in the in the mind of an in
rogue insider or what goes in the mind
of a unethical hacker which which is
which is driving him to you know exploit
the vulnerabilities which is driving him
to do bad stuff making him a bad bad
actor all right I'll answer question in
two ways and thanks for not letting me
know before I think humans have evolved
from the Stone Age
you said Tech is not important in that
in the stories that take was a hammer
and a chisel to rate sophisticated right
they evolved they have adapted okay the
reason is because the human mind is able
to sort of you know keep on withstanding
a challenge and succumb to that that's
woman defenders perspectives now an
attacker or an ethical hacker whatever
we call it always looks at the element
of surprise
yes for him it is of doing something
what is not expected it is of being
where you're not sort of planned to be
and if he has to make an impact on what
he has to prove himself for what I was
trying to do he has to capture that
element of unknowing knowing or be where
you are not expected to be
we're normal defenders will not be able
to utilize his adaptability or
versatility to say okay this guy is a
pattern try and be as different as low
as challenging enough so that the
defenses and that's what I really must
do a red teamers also the same thing
they will try and emulate the best
attacker to think the best thing or the
worst thing G will do so that you bring
your worst we'll do our best and that's
the same game whether you train your red
team on to think like that and protect
the company or a bad guy as you said
does that but the thinking process is
same the attackers advantage ram
children's book what is the attackers
advantage that you can give on the
defenses that he or she has not thought
us attacking on our 25th Christmas Day
know stuff like that so extending this
the same question to you forearm and you
know the behavioral part of it though
that the fear of unknown is that the
maximum fear of unknown originates from
the unknown behavioral aspect of human
beings you know and those human beings
you can bucket in all the three aspects
that you talked about the three
stakeholders which are humans so how to
deal with this nuance of behavioral
changes and how how that that one corner
of mine impacts at that point and
triggers the triggers the attack or
triggers anything mollified so I'll give
you know maybe touch to try and keep
some time left with the other panelists
with very easily I mean a lot of you who
are application security researchers we
were for consistently four quarters
after quarter you know one of the most
attacked website in the world even
though we've been around for twenty
years the kind of the nature the
business that we do makes requires us to
stay online and requires us to be secure
at all times and we were getting you
know on one hand we were acquiring a lot
of companies so our internet footprint
was growing so we started this bug
bounty program about eight years ago
right initially it was very
counterintuitive not only are we not
going to stop people from coming after
us we are going to
to actually reward them to poke holes at
our web sites and you know again now a
lot of you probably participate I mean
every year we pay anywhere between two
to three million dollars and a large
majority of it I'm proud to say our
researchers that come from India but it
is yeah it's really commendable to how
the space has grown that's when I'll go
into the world exactly so you know
that's a very good example of how not
only you know trying to create an
opportunity in a way that people can
learn something and apply the skills in
a more responsible manner and and inform
the organization so that it's not just
for lulz it's not just for some kind of
a street cred but it's actually going to
help the organization do what we want to
do help you what you wanna do in a
matter of fashion tourniquet anyhow you
know from a pure corporate website
corporate network security perspective
so coincidentally human element was also
the team at RSA and predominantly
everybody was talking about insider
threat you know for a company that is
you know available in 200 markets with
56 actual offices around the world
insider threat becomes a big issue when
we have to do businesses in in Russia
and China and Iran in a lot of other
countries where ever you know the
sanctions allow us to do certain things
Mountains the u n-- human viruses is
that the countries you mentioned matches
that true so what we've done is you know
look at the poor aspect of what decides
behavior within it within an enterprise
and we've come to two key elements one
is the identity identity of a user
identity of a device identity of a
system component whatever it is the
other is the system itself and I did and
create a baseline behavior so if you are
a developer at what time you come what
type of access you have what type of
commands you execute what type of code
you upload and over time we create a
profile at not only at an individual
user level but at a country level at the
city level at a function level same
thing for a system if it is a end user
device it's going to have a baseline of
stat sorts and to care
any time we see an anomalous behavior
from that aspect from an insider aspect
on a baseline behavior that is already
established it's going to be
investigated and we find ways of how do
you make sure whether it is a suspicious
one you know quarantine them for some
time or or outright block them and then
investigate further so if you study
history the people the human element
right it's not the people who have been
strongest who survive
now most of the shiquan central pole
right 23 armies try to attack it would
not but the one army who could is the
one was the most versatile just like a
coconut tree you know the strong trees
get up put it in a monsoon but the
coconut free space is flexible so just
being rigid on a security is not the
only way but being adaptable being
learning being situationally aware and
on-the-fly making your defenses Summoner
from attack expect no interesting but
this versatility comes from where you
know who is the who who's the igniting
force that you know we we should become
for ceaseless job to create this as his
host job culture okay I mean not his
only job I chose the management but he
has been the driving force for me I I
have a very specific question for you
you you mentioned that you have
automated 70% of the incident response
within within your organization now you
know when I hope I can you say
correction correction it's not 70% of
incident response I'm saying 70%
security what significant relation on
seeking operations are automated okay
now so I wrecked myself here however you
know even after even after deployment of
automated countermeasures malicious
actor gain actors they gain access to
targeted systems by by exploiting the
human error
human error remains still remains there
completely agree ah so you know whether
it is fear phishing whether it is social
engineering whether it is malware attack
non-compliance poor policies anything
you know so how do you deal with that
how do you how do you ensure that you
know even after 70% of automation you
know this human factor is still
prevalent let me say this that when I
talked about 70 percent
70% of its this the what goes into the
core of security operations and that's
more to do with automation around the
same part but on a scale of zero to ten
if you were to ask me that how much
percentage of that would take care of
the entire landscape for IT security and
threat management internal or external
in a company like it and I would say
it's less than one person so that
seventy person was a you know so let me
just explain that now coming back to
your core question guys insider threat
continues to remain one of the most most
you know vulnerable pain points and it
could be on account of two reasons one
is a an employee making a mistake is
probably as dangerous an employee in a
in a critical function now just imagine
if they have done something on the
production environment because you have
to cross people there are people who are
working their production environments
and if they have done something in the
production environment and God forbid
you know it's it leaves gaps or at
leaves holes or a vulnerability in the
ecosystem and that itself is a potential
for disaster or somebody makes some
critical changes fine you will detect it
but by the time you detect it it would
have already caused a disruption in your
business continuity then the other
category of insider threat would be
disgruntled employees let's not forget
that and of course those with the
intention of going wrong for the purpose
of some sort of gratification which
could be or-or-or
that's the disgruntled part and the
second is where somebody wishes to you
basically defraud that insider I would
rather put on the fraud you know in the
category of fraud and any large
organization any large organization any
company has to be alert to the
possibility of fraud and data theft IPR
so some some employee walks away with
the important idea that itself is matter
of concern so the first and foremost
thing is that look and since we are
talking about the human factor let me
bring it to that is that when
organizations find a
problem find an incident detected
insulin they are able to pinpoint the
responsibility for the incident how many
ins how many organizations actually take
strict action so when I say strict
action means everybody wants to sort of
you know hush it up push it under the
carpet give a very silent exit because
they think it's bad for the I think it's
about setting the right example if there
is somebody who's done something wrong
it's extremely important that that
person be penalized and a clear message
goes through the through the others that
look this is what happens when you know
you do wrong and meet a very strict
actions we have a zero-tolerance policy
right now so can I just to interrupt you
okay the camouflage this information the
way you want it but can you can you then
tell some incident which has happened
and which is related to the human human
errors as I said I you know any large
organizations will always have incidents
of fraud
so proactively what is it that you do
you one is where you reactively look at
incidents and see okay if this is a case
of fraud how do I and we have never
noticed this earlier because human minds
are very very you know intelligent that
way they figure out how do we get things
done so you figure out and create a use
case out of it see how you can
strengthen your systems your information
systems to either pretend prevent or
detect something like this happening in
future so that you can immediately catch
it and arrested the so that is more
reactive but the proactive part is that
you always have to have a dedicated team
how many organizations and I am NOT
talking at the large a small ones even
large organizations
how many large organizations actually
have a dedicated team working on fraud
management I'm not talking the banks
yeah right I am NOT talking about
business fraud I am talking about
managing fraud through application of
ITC IT and IT security controls so
within the IT team where because today
most of the organizations are roughly
driven by IT systems their life depends
upon it and that's where lots of cause
actually happens that's a dedicated
effort that is needed you talked about
an example yes I can go back in history
somewhere in 2004-2005
I'm sure everybody knows what the Armed
Forces of the country are we had had a
case of some sensitive data leaking from
the headquarters and you know that's a
very long story I don't want to go into
it but the fact of the matter was there
were be controls there was a motive the
motive was financial benefit okay so one
is where you take action which sends a
clear message second is where you make
it economically unviable for anybody
internal or external to do what they
want to do with the Valentine purpose
and the third is you know have better ID
security controls sure I also know what
happened to that you know point that you
have brought out is important that human
factors should include a thorough study
of human who you know human interactions
with information systems human
interaction with networks human
interaction with practices in
information security environment so as
you said training so it's simple plane
training enough do you think that is
that works I don't think that works so
yep just training itself like a node
would not work but see I mentioned two
things right one is like in a training
and then the other is that culture so
it's it's extremely critical I mean that
you know for organizations at least from
a human factor perspective the entire
the culture of security is actually top
down so for example if if the CEO of
your organization is not like you know
he's going to be subject to similar
standards as you are going to subject
like a node to other people for example
I'll give you an example when I conduct
my fishing campaigns I also send it to
the CEO of the company I send it to the
board also because they asked me in the
board meetings right I mean like know
what is your person change etc she's
also got to let them know me like an are
they also clicking on the same link
right and we also tend to target it like
a spearfishing kind of a campaigns so
there seems
standards should be applicable like an
ode to our top management and why I'm
mentioning this culture is if it is top
down then like you know it seeps down
like an ode to the other people in the
company and then they would be able to
take care of a lot of these things so if
it is not for example if if your CEO is
not subject to the same controls and if
he's not going to be security savvy I
mean how can I ask like you know my
JUnit people like in a [ __ ] like you
know handling sensitive information how
can I ask them so as far as possible you
as a CEO have to also have those
one-on-one conversations like you know
with your senior management so that they
are aware like you know that unless
they'd themselves show that behavior and
then he can confidently even go like you
know in a town hall and tell the other
people like you know that this is like
you know is expected of them that'll go
a long way like you know in improving
that
so not just training I mean as such but
training should be very important so
training is still I would say multiple
rounds of reinforcements like you know
for people like you know I think that's
non-negotiable people and that's why I
said that you know all these different
kinds of like a good and different
manners if you've got something like a
Facebook at workplace make it fun make
it entertaining do gamification but at
the end of the day they have to realize
and I said technology also you have to
help them for example we all mentioned
about phishing emails right so phishing
emails like you know usually who it
comes from right if somebody says the
CEO has send a mail like a note to the
the finance CFO like you're not asking
for a payment right but if the if the if
the if the email is coming in from
outside the organization at least from a
technology perspective you can put like
you know a header like in a which is
like a saying external or something like
that which can alert people rather than
expecting them to look through all
aspects it's from a technology
perspective you try to make it easier
for them and then you educate them that
you know use this basis like now use
these as cues like in order to not to
exhibit like you know those behavior so
it's a combination so I would say that
does go along with and and lasting rahul
also I mean let's not also over engineer
these things like behavior aspects right
so the thing is sometimes severe all
organizations of different sizes write a
very large organization may have like
you know the kind of resources and
lichen or to kind of invest like you
know in behavior specialists etc but
that normal organization is not going to
have that so it is your responsibility
of the Caesar to continuously keep
driving that awareness or training down
on a regular it's necessary but not
sufficient and something is like a cyber
war gaming which you know if you if you
read something you know more 10% if you
write twenty percent but if you
experience something and experiential
learning makes you remember and behavior
soap behavior to habit to sort of just
be is part of culture okay I'm I'm
opening up for for questions Brian you
had a question if we can have a mic for
Jackson a few questions you know film
them down best wish can I can I request
one of the mics yeah good afternoon
gentlemen my name is Brian Pereira I'm
the editor of seaso magazine which is
produced by ec-council one of the
discussions I have with internationally
source is the challenge of communicating
security to the board
I know bank it is just touched upon that
and it's especially a challenge to get
you know but to increase your budgets on
board and the board really takes things
seriously when you heard here of an
attack like Capital One and so on then
they start asking questions what is your
strategy for communicating cyber
security to the board and I'm told that
some of them don't even understand some
of the technical terms yeah
so answer this is the question on the
two o clock discussion so please okay
I'll come back for that until X yes in
the next one you just jump the question
of the two o'clock so I just I just try
to put it in a very brief contact it's a
very good question and yes it's a see
resources are always limited you will
always always have to you know pitch for
those limited resources and part of the
job of a seesaw is how to use how
you sell internally and let me not dwell
too much on the word sell it's about how
do you take what is in the interest of
the organization and convince the the
decision makers who control the purses
to give you what you want so that you
can secure the organization I think the
most important thing is that you seek
alignments with business you also do an
impact assessment saying that look this
is where we are this is how we could get
impacted and this could be the possible
negative impact if we don't do this this
this and this and this is sort of
proactively at a very high level
educating the decision makers that look
there is a potential risk of you know a
huge amount of business disruption
negative impact to brand and possible
loss of revenue if at least certain
actions basic security controls and
technologies are not put into place
money so while you write is negative a
modern way of looking is the positive
part if you put better security does it
mean more business it's just not
negative saying if you don't do this
happens wrong but if you do good
security from right this is a bit of
power so you try the first part if that
doesn't work and try the second dish
comes first I'll do two again
okay any other questions here yes I
heard a lot of hands I have yeah so I
will I will curtail my questions now I
think I just wanted to I mean I hope the
audience thought like you know
Burgess point I think that's extremely
important for the modern C so we have
always been thinking security more as a
defensive shield I think we have to get
out of it and start thinking security
more as as a growth driver as a as a
competitive advantage and that's how you
communicate to the poor and in a lot of
our discussions I mean I mean if we can
even take this offline like and also but
but you you gotta have those
conversations where your partner's for
example in case of : like Anna we do
business like no with top companies like
Nestle Mondelez etc I mean like Anna do
they have confidence in you so a lot of
that business like is driven out of like
you know
are you able to protect like another
information I actually started the
saying you have to align with business
so your conversations you have to find
alignment with business if you are not
aligned with business then you're not
aligned with the company Mike there
please my name is Jake amar I work for
Asha security so I accept the point when
today she said so the training is
important we conduct trainings yearly
twice or thrice also we live it in the
name of strike training we have seen the
percentage of people clicking on spear
phishing or phishing emails a lesser but
sometimes we are seen people who click
on like people who hook on cyber
security of example a soccer team so
people work on soft team itself fall for
phishing attacks so they don't have a
proper mindset so one of the thing is
like I work with Burgas in Bangladesh in
a project so we set up a sock there and
we are training people to work on the
sock and they know how to do an alert or
they know how to send an alert to the
customer but they don't have a proper
mindset if they see a different scenario
or different type of attack or something
so I have seen in multiple socks they
don't have a proper mindset from the
beginning they just know how to look at
a document fill it and for the employees
I am fine but what about the security
people so how do they grow the mindset
how can we improve so that's where the
aptitude part comes in and typically
what happens is that if you are
selecting in the industry if you're
conducting an interview you're your
shortlisting people for enroll in a tell
we spend a lot of time and effort in
seeing what is the aptitude of the
person so trainability is a factor
alright in psychology it's called
trainability factor if a person has the
aptitude then you can train him or her
to do a lot more than they currently
know but they could have seven years of
experience and shock but if they don't
have the right aptitude they will never
ever reach an l-3 or a level beyond that
so that's an exercise that we do in fact
the mentor call its students we say
listen I know you want to do this but I
think you're more suited for this and
you will have
much better success in future if you
pursue this particular direction so it's
about aptitude and it's always good to
talk to people who are experts in the
field who really understand where and
what is you know what loss suited most
for okay I have just four or five
minutes left I will take two more
questions can we can we have the
question from here and then I will give
it to you just yeah so Burgess is
offering consulting after this free of
cost so we of course hi good afternoon
everybody my name is Salma and I work
for the blue team in Microsoft first of
all thank you fall for your dispersion
it's very interesting and been very
engaging so my question to you guys a
bug is especially is like you touched
upon looking at between the eyes right
catching up incidents which you don't
usually catch up from an IOC perspective
and things like that right so basically
if I talk about an insider touch insider
threat which every all of you touched
upon right there was the attacks like in
2016 there was a person named Andrew who
work for Google and who took in data
about three plants for about five months
and then moved over and use those things
so as an hunter myself as a blue team
member how do we look at these things
because there's so much data coming in
there IOC s we are looking at their
Intel coming in but the ground reality
is to look at these things to look at
the behavioral models people logging in
at one time people logging off is good
but looking at what a person what an
attacker really wants that will not
really you know ground reality
situations great question I'll answer
first and a funny note forces join
consulting you get to express the
multiple times right you are doing hard
selling but I have a loud sorry the
question is how do you find a blue team
or to hit between the eyes detect the
attacks I think there's nothing but keep
on wargaming keep on wargaming being
paranoid keep on doing industries
different types of attacks keep on doing
different models right keep on
challenging and that's a part is for
bespoke or aptitude
I for attitude when you have what you
are successful headhunter as join our
case you want to be or CGI
but you got to have that kill of knowing
that I really wanna find all I am doing
a shock
watch the watch the voice it are shipped
and go away or you really want to find
that because you want it for the
pleasure you know when a hunter enhance
he hunts for food or he hunts for
shooting wood in the eyes and their
hands what type of a poor hunter are you
that's the difference one more point
since you're closing the attack since my
friend mentioned colleague mentioned I
first financials in the new vector is
what defenses but no one thought about
the attacks the attacks are now going
for the digital life more and more
occurs are going banks telcos are being
attacked so as comic manufacturing but
the digital life what we all enjoy this
is a new sweet spot for attackers the
human element the topic of the human
they're so used to the soft cozy
all-encompassing digital life that is
where the new attacks are going to be
the new attack because I want to come
the only thing I would add is threat
hunting you cannot be a part-time job it
yeah in an organization if you're
serious about it it has to be a
dedicated job by a dedicated team you
keep doing this because it is a
cat-and-mouse game last remission was
just just one last question she let her
given up on I will I will I will read
with permission from unfix I will
certainly get back to you with for the
last question
I cannot say last last last and last but
she wears their hand first I will just
get that thank you so much really talked
about awareness training and things like
that but IT our technology currently is
being used as a tool not as a focus so a
lot of people employees in various
companies focus on what their job is
supposed to be not IT especially which
is used as a tool but what their job is
supposed to be so and you even mention
about people being tech savvy but a lot
of people aren't like that and a lot of
people want to be important college they
want knowledge about their job not ITU
not how to protect themselves that's not
what we all focus on so how do we cross
from what we earn and how we protect how
do employers how is it possible for
employees who are earning to know the
only to get the knowledge about security
to
so I think the first and foremost thing
is it's not just about pushing people I
think there is a lot of positivity that
is required in the messaging that goes
out that look guys the world is changing
right and you have to change along with
the world in order to be better prepared
today if you were to tell a 70 year old
if a 70 year old
I mean 70 in today's world is not a very
big age spring area anymore
but can you imagine today a person of 65
to 70 years of age not even being able
to operate a smartphone a laptop
look at the negative impact in life
there's so many things that they can do
sitting I bought Dom absolutely so I
think it's about personal transformation
which means that it is not for an
individual at least that's how I mentor
people I'm saying it's not just as an
individual or it's not just as an
employee that you need to upskill it is
as an individual for a personal benefit
that you need to upskill because
otherwise world will go on and it'll
leave you behind complete is about
survival once what the company can do
but what are you doing to ensure you are
in the market otherwise okay yeah it's
just fear and just do it up to the point
I mean like no so while while you have a
day job right that's what's your point
right and then you have also have got to
do security I don't think like you know
organizations will have to make this
like you know that security is almost
like second nature say unless that is
that onion fits like a different job I
have to do my day job and then I have to
do half an hour of training then it
becomes like you know much more
difficult that's why I said that the way
you conduct these awareness sessions is
like you know something that you really
want to like you know learn and do along
with your regular job so that's why a
lot of these war games gamification like
you know have fun like in our own
security at your workplace then it
becomes second nature then everybody
learns along with the job okay last last
I'm so sorry this is Jackson part of my
previous life I also had to deal a lot
with insider threat and I wanted this is
not something I come up with and I
worked with Burgesses oil company
and we had come up with a mindset it
said internally what does a person need
to commit fraud or an incident you need
motivation you need opportunity you need
justification I need to be able to be
able to commit the fraud I need to be
motivated enough to do it and I need to
rationalize it back to my friends and
family that why I did what I did as
Caesars we like to believe that we wear
a cape around our neck can we wear or
Underpants over our pants but we are not
Superman we can do only so much with the
controls we can reduce that aspect of it
but the motivation aspect for it the
seaso has to work with your HR
departments with your functional heads
because if the employee let's say is in
finance and his boss is draconian past
master no matter how many controls you
put into place his motivation is still
crap and he's basically going to try to
do something to break the system and if
we can justify it you know because like
Venkatesh mentioned if you have two sets
of standards for the management and
another set for the employees he
justifies it he says the boss can do it
why can't I do it why shouldn't I do it
so it is not enough that and this is my
humble opinion it's not enough as
Caesars that we just employ technology
to put it we are closing one aspect of a
three-pronged attack which is the the
opportunity part of it but there is
still a lot that we have to work with
the HR departments and throughout the
rest of the organization otherwise we
leave motivation and justification open
I think well put motivation
justification opportunity these three go
hand in hand to get the human element I
think well summarize that I think you
did you simplified my job that's why I
thank you so I think a beautiful mind
map is created here you view you saw the
action and thanks to our friend there he
he he did it very you know on the fly
you know were just asked him and he
prepared it and
plug the machine and created it so if
you are interested in knowing knowing
this we will summarize it beautifully
and you know you can you can ask for it
we'll send it to you through through in
so yeah we will put it on El Cajon
website you can download it from there
so thank you very much to the to the
great panelists let me just tell you the
only panelist who was prepared for this
discussion was quorum arrest three of
them I have just forced and and prepared
them overnight so a big thank you to all
of them in a big round of applause
[Applause]