thank you and thanks for having me back
again one of my favorite events of the
year and I'm really delighted that it's
still going ahead despite all the other
things that are not and things being
canceled I hope everyone stays safe and
we don't have any issues use this pink
stuff often don't shake hands when you
meet people I actually my company just
issued no handshake rule so if I don't
shake hands with you when you meet it's
because I'm not allowed to not because I
don't like you okay I shouldn't even be
here to be honest we've also just issued
know going to meetings with more than a
thousand people rule but since I'm
already here I kind of got away with it
but so yeah my name is Adam Lori also
known as major malfunction I work for
x-force read this is not an x-force
sponsored or IBM sponsored talk this is
just me on my own but that's that's my
job
I'm an associate partner and Lee I'm the
lead hardware hacker so I run the
hardware hacking team globally for IBM
I'm also the quartermaster at DEFCON any
of you ever been to DEFCON a few I run
the London DEFCON chapter as well so if
you're ever in London last Tuesday of
the month we have a local meetup it's a
really good place to meet if you're
passing through try and arrange that you
pass through on the last Tuesday of the
month and come and give us an
interesting talk or come and meet some
some other hacker types so
and if you come to DEFCON do look me up
I get kind of lonely in the back room my
job at DEFCON is moving all the
equipment in and out
I hear there's talks there but I never
get to see them so I yeah I'm in a room
probably twice the size of this full of
Pelican cases just moving stuff around
so it's not a huge amount of fun but for
some reason I keep going back so we'll
start with an introduction so I just
want to say right up front this is not
an in-depth super-amazing talk about
some new glitching technique I've
discovered this talk was never designed
to be a main a main room talk again
because of what's been going on and
cancellations and so on I was asked if I
had anything I could present and I'm
happy to to do so but I didn't like
submit this as a as a talk because I've
got some new amazing discovery but I
think it will be interesting for people
who are interested in getting into
glitching certainly in the hardware
hacking panel that we just did an hour
or so ago a lot of the questions that
had come in we were about side-channel
and about how to get started and so on
and so glitch is one of those new tech
newish techniques I mean it's becoming
very very trendy at the moment to do
glitching because it's such a good
technique and it is so successful but
there's still a lot of mystery around it
so think of this as a kind of
introduction and I can show you some
examples of the kind of things you can
do and the things that can go wrong
again I would like to have given it you
know more content but I had some
challenges this this week so as I think
a lot of you know
so I apologize in advance if it's not as
in-depth as you were hoping but and and
do come and talk to me afterwards so I'm
going to be here for the rest of the con
we can hang out buy me a beer I always
like to spill secrets after I've been
bought beer so the more beer the bigger
the secrets so first of all what is
glitching
so basically glitching is very precisely
controlled fault injection so what
you're gonna do is take a chip that is
otherwise running you know running its
normal code and you're trying you're
going to try and introduce a fault
at a very specific time in order to
cause a specific outcome so or usually
to stop the normal outcome from
happening so generally it's for things
like bypassing access control or
bypassing some kind of check or balance
that's in the code so for example if you
wanted to read out the firmware of a
chip the chip is probably locked down at
some point it's gonna internally it's
gonna say are you allowed to do that
read yes or no and you want the know to
become yes
or you want to just skip over that
question somehow and the way you do it
is either by glitching the clock
generally there are other things you can
do but generally it's you glitch the
clock or you glitch the power so you
have some device that allows you to
control so on this screen we glitching
power so this yellow line represents my
voltage which on here is currently set
to 3.8 and and regular intervals I'm
just dropping the voltage so the chip is
going to have like a little hiccup when
it hits that and if you get the timing
right that hiccup will cause the effect
you're looking for you'll get to skip
over the instruction that you're you're
trying to bypass
[Music]
so the tools you need to do this it
sounds simple but when you start
building your toolset you find there's
there's a bunch of things you need to
put together to be able to do glitching
so first of all you need the glitter
itself that the the logic that's going
to create those pulses for you
you need something to trigger the glitch
so decide when you're actually gonna do
your glitch you need something to take
the that glitch signal and turn it into
an actual power signal because generally
the thing that's doing the
decision-making will be just toggling a
GPIO line so it's not going to have
enough oomph to actually drive the
target and provide the power you can
probably drive the clock directly but
you couldn't drive the power directly
basically so you need power supplies to
provide some kind of non-standard
voltage generally when you do glitching
you don't use the the same voltage that
the chip would normally run on there's a
you know there's an ideal voltage for
that chip to run on which is usually you
know 3.3 volts which is then converted
down internally there may be other power
domains within the chip so you need some
means of providing your own voltage
that's going to run at the level that
you want to run it and generally if you
kind of read about this people will say
reduce the voltage until it runs just
about stable so find the point where
you've reduced it too far and the thing
crashes just in normal use and then go
up a couple of points from there so in
this particular target that we're going
to talk about I think I ended up running
at one point seven volts which the
documentation says one point eight is
the minimum it does actually run it
below that you could go down to about
one point five but it wasn't very stable
at that point and then finally you need
an oscilloscope the
you need to see what the hell's going on
so otherwise you're just working blind
so common tools the glitter itself
commercially that the probably the
best-known tools is chip whisperer
Paulino Flynn's device risky or sell
commercial glitches high-end pro stuff
chip Westborough starting to produce
more Pro equipment and I suspect they'll
go down the same path as risk your and
stop producing pretty high-end stuff but
at the moment they've got everything
from like really cheap hobby USB devices
up to the more professional the chip
Whisperer Pro for example or you can
build your own I mean that's a very
common thing these days people are
building them using an FPGA and in fact
internally IBM x-force red have built
their own it's called Radin it is gonna
be open sourced unfortunately that's
being delayed it was going to be
released at blackhat Singapore but
that's cancelled so that's not going to
happen and I think we've agreed to hold
it until it's I think it's happening in
October now is that right yeah so should
get released in October hopefully
there's also two first consulting
published their version of the fpga
glitcher which runs on this device on
the bottom called the RT excuse me this
is a very nice low-cost fpga and to be
honest a lot of targets you don't even
need to go fpga level you can just use
an off-the-shelf dev board and use
standard GPIO ports to do a lot of the
glitching that you you know you'll get
success that way
the next thing you need is a trigger you
need something that tells you when you
want to do the glitch it's not always
just powerup wait a certain amount of
time and then glitch you might be doing
it based on a particular event so like a
GPIO line going high on your target
device maybe an LED comes on just before
the moment you want to perform your
glitch you can use that as a trigger and
then go from there you can buy
commercial trigger devices again risky
or have a thing which is a very
sophisticated trigger can be used can
use power analysis to determine when to
do the trigger or you can use your
oscilloscope again connect it to some
line that does something at just the
right moment or users a decoder so if
you're triggering on a login prompt or
something like that when you send your
password then you want to trigger and of
course you can build your own one of my
favourite platforms for building little
do-it-yourself tools is the bit wacker
32 if you've never used one they're very
cheap it's a pic 32 got tons of memory
reasonably fast and you can write your
own custom decoder on that to do
whatever protocol you want so if you
wanted to trigger on an i2c packet or
UART packet or whatever it would be
relatively straightforward to build a
decoder using that board you need some
kind of amp or switch to convert your
glitch pulse to power very very common
in this world is people use the max for
six one nine so basically what that is
it's a very fast switch you give it two
different voltages and it just flicks
between them so on my first slide where
I had the 3.8 going down the input for
one of those is 3.8 and the lower one
to go all the way down to zero so you
connect it to ground or you connect it
to a lower voltage like if you wanted to
go from three point three down to two
and you just provide two volts to the
other input and it will flick between
the two or you can use an actual amp and
amplify your signal and of course power
supplies again very common these guys on
the right you buy them cheaply on Amazon
or eBay for like 30 bucks if you want to
go a bit more high-end guy on the left
the the little ones are nice and
portable so if you're gonna go and do
this stuff that hacking competitions and
so on you want something really portable
the guys on the left or a proper desk
bench supply so that's a bit heavier and
a bit more painful to move around the
one thing I would say if you do buy
these cheap ones on the right these guys
sorry I keep pointing on a screen that
you can't see these guys on the right
they're really noisy they've got these
horrible horrible cheap fans in them and
I had three of them running at one point
and by the end of the week I was going
insane because the noise was just
horrendous so I actually ended up
spending more on silent fans for the
boxes than the boxes themselves cost but
it was well worth the investment you put
some silent fans in them and and yeah
everything's lovely in it and then
finding a oscilloscope whatever you can
get your hands on
I strongly advise you get at least four
channels is tempting to buy like a
cheapo to channel scope very often they
come with just two sets of probes but
you will quickly run out of probes so
when you start glitching you find you
need to look at all sorts of things at
the same time so you want to look at
power you want to look at your trigger
you want to look at in this case the
tool we're using to monitor the chip
itself now I thought some rye smiles
when this came up because I suspect
people who are into glitching can
recognize that pattern very well they
would have spent many hours looking at
that and playing with it so who can tell
me what chip I'm looking at here just
from there no okay
it became like a fingerprint to me if I
saw that if I ever see that again I
think I'll know exactly what chips being
looked at I've seen it so many times now
so we'll talk about a specific example
so the NXP LPC range is a really good
one to start on because it's it's well
documented it's known to be vulnerable
to glitching attacks and there's a
number of existing again well documented
attacks themselves so if you want to go
and have a go and learn to glitch for
the first time this is a great target
because you there are even tutorials
there's a couple of tutorials there that
will actually walk you through it step
by step but depending there are some
limitations so this particular chip what
they're doing here is what we're doing
here is breaking what's called CRP which
is code read protection so basically
trying to read out the code from from
the chip
and there are three levels of protection
on this chip CLP 1 2 & 3 CR P 1 & 2
basically give you a bootloader that you
can talk to but they don't allow you to
read out the code so you've got
something that you can talk to and
synchronize with in order to do your
glitching attacks and what you're going
to do is try and bypass the read
protection that says no you may not read
out the code CRP 3 however disables the
bootloader altogether so you've got
nothing you've literally got a chip
that's just sitting there so so my
recommendation is get already built dev
board to start with whatever chip you're
going to attack generally and this is
what I always do if I'd got a live
target what I'll do is buy the dev board
for that particular target and one of
the reasons for that or the main reason
for that is it's really quick and easy
to get started you don't have to build a
circuit around a chip you don't have to
attack the physical hardware that you've
got in front of you you know if it's an
IOT device or something and you've taken
it apart and you're looking at the
circuit board you don't have to add
anything to it you don't have to start
figuring out which pins go where and how
to put probes in generally these at
these boards will have all the headers
broken out for you so you know like this
has got every pin handily broken out so
you can just attach to those and do some
experiments generally they also come
with a pretty decent IDE and some
example code so again you can get up and
running really quickly they may even
have the JTAG debugger built in but
they'll have the interfaces so that you
can program and again this guy the this
is actually two boards joined together
here
and the board on the left is a debugger
and the board on the right is the actual
LPC target so you can chop that end off
or you can just ignore it all together
and the example there the other
advantage of buying an off-the-shelf dev
board is the example projects that come
with it will be matched to that hardware
so if it's got LEDs showing you what's
going on they will be on the right GPIO
pins and so on so that the code actually
does what's expected whereas if you just
download the toolset and start writing
code you'd have to figure that all out
for the target board that you're you're
looking at so once you've got a dead
board you can do some reconnaissance and
testing so in this case what we've done
is built a little loop that does
something so the the contents of memory
address to FC is where the CRP value is
set so the the level of copy protection
on the chip is stored in flash at this
address and what I've done is copied the
contents of this into a variable called
CRP and now I can set a a GPIO pin hi do
something and set the GPIO pin low again
and the purpose of that is I can use
that as the trigger so my external
glitching setup is going to look at that
pin so this is purely for reconnaissance
and testing so we're going to look at
that pin see okay it went hi we're about
to do the thing we're trying to glitch
went low we can stop now and look at the
result and the purpose of that is to
find the right voltage and the right
glitch level the width of the glitch the
depth of the glitch and so on that
actually has the desired effect so you
can create a test case that exactly
matches what you're trying to do to the
live target
in a nice safe environment on this dev
board you may also only have one sample
of the device and when you start
Hardware glitching or hardware hacking
it's very possible that you kill the
thing that you're trying to hack you
know if you accidentally jump to some
instruction that says wipe the flash
then that's it your targets gone so you
need to do some initial reconnaissance
and testing and make sure you've got a
glitching setup that actually works
without killing your target so in this
case and also you know is it even
possible in an ideal world where you've
created the perfect environment to do
the glitch does it actually produce a
result if you can't get it to work on
your dev board you're never going to get
it to work on the real target so you
know you can avoid a lot of pain by
figuring out what's working on what's
not working in a nice safe environment
you can spend hours and days trying to
attack a real target and not get
anywhere and one of the first problems
you're fine with a real target so you
come away from your dev environment
where you've set it all up nicely so
it's telling you what's going on on a
real target you know for example here's
a chip doing nothing with no power
here's the same chip powered up running
user code and here's the same chip
powered up running the bootloader
there's no way to tell them apart you
can't actually in this particular case
and one of the targets I was looking at
which is in CRP 3 mode that was
literally the situation I had there were
no LEDs to tell me it was alive there
was nothing going on there was no
interface that I could use to see that I
was having an effect or not having an
effect or whatever so the third that's
the first challenge is how do we figure
out what's going on
and the solution to this is I think
which i think is just pure magic when I
first discovered this it's called a
shunt resistor and it's a really really
simple basic thing basically you put a
shunt resistor between either the thing
you're testing and ground or the thing
you're testing and positive normally you
put it near ground and because that's
always easy to get to because you're
controlling the power supply to the
device whatever it is and in fact I have
this little breadboard which I use for
USB devices it really is that simple
you've got your resistor across ground
and I'm just passing through the other
lines this breadboard also has the
advantage that I can decide not to use
the bus for power I can provide my own
power if I want lower voltages but with
this I can literally plug any USB device
so I can take that dev board off the
shelf plug it through this and what you
do is you connect your oscilloscope
probe to each side of the resistor and
then like magic you get this so when you
power the device up this is kind of like
a fingerprint you know you can't tell
just by looking at it what each pulse
means or what it's doing but you can see
it's alive if you can see it's doing
something and you can use it for
consistency and for measuring you know
how how you're doing if you're achieving
any any effect normally this is used for
a thing called DPA differential power
analysis so by doing multiple captures
and can we get a bit less light on the
screen can you see that okay or is it a
bit bleached out it's kind of hard to
see
can we kill that spot okay it's a bit
better
no okay so anyway you've got this is
basically the T is the trigger so this
is where I reset the device and this is
the boot sequence and then code running
and if you with differential power
analysis what you would do is you would
take multiple snapshots when you do
something so you can measure the power
usage itself so the size of the spikes
for example and that will tell you in
crypto attacks that tells you how many
ones were being processed on our honor
on a bus for example and that can be
used to actually read out the bits that
were being used in the in the key
generation you can also compare timing
so you can watch where a particular
event happens so for example if you were
trying to crack a password and the
routine that checks the password craps
out as soon as it hits the the first
letter that doesn't match you would see
an event move so you send it an
incorrect password out by one letter and
as soon as you get the correct letter
it'll go a little bit further a little
bit further a little bit further and so
on until you've cracked the full
password so that's that's normally what
this kind of power analysis is used for
what we're going to use it for is to
decide when to glitch so again one of
the common techniques that I've seen and
I'm not sure if because of the light you
can actually see but this is multiple
what I've done is set this go to
persistence infinite persistence mode so
behind here there's kind of a dimmer
pink version of that trace I can see a
beautiful Eve I don't think
okay so basically there's two signals
and at one point they diverge so what
we've done is we've started the chip up
in bootloader mode and then we've
started it up in user mode and where the
signals diverge is where that line
called ax is sitting and the common
technique I've seen discussed is do that
and then glitch around there somewhere
because that's where the decisions being
made do I go into user land or do I go
into bootloader and you probably have to
come back a bit from there but that's
what's mostly advised so what I wanted
to do was add some more precision to
that and decide actually though I want
to glitch a specific instruction or a
specific routine and you can't tell from
that picture as I say it's just a bunch
of Wiggles I mean each of those Wiggles
is something doing something but you
don't know what so first thing to do is
decide what it is that we want to glitch
so go to the documentation and this is
the the bootloader process from the
documentation so at the beginning it's
going to decide is CRP enabled do we
enable the debug mode or not is the user
code valid if not then go to to debug
mode and so on so there's a number of
potential places we might want to glitch
so we pick a target and go and look for
it and we do that by extracting the
bootloader because again we've got our
own pet device is not the actual real
target yet we're still working on the
dev board so we can put the dev board in
totally insecure mode with the debugger
switched on we can connect over swd and
just read out the whole memory and in
that memory you can normally the memory
is mapped to the read-only memory as
well so you can just read out the ROM
download
the bootloader itself loaded into
something like Ida Pro or goodra or
binary ninja whatever and find the thing
that you want to glitch so again I don't
think you can read it but here the code
is actually checking the value CRP 3 or
CRP sorry so now what we can do because
we have the source code or not the
source code we have we have a decompiled
version we can actually run a remote
debugger and connect to the target
device put it in debug mode set a
breakpoint so here's the instruction
where it's checking the CRP value and if
we go back to our trace so this is the
code running as normal and then we run
it again with the debug with the trip
with the breakpoint set and bam that
point where it dies the chip just stops
running because it's halted that's the
exact point where we can glitch to hit
that one instruction so we can do really
precise single instruction glitching by
mapping it like that so now I know that
twenty point three microseconds that's
the moment it checked that value so you
can use this to do some really advanced
glitching that you might not otherwise
be able to do and it's really simple you
know we're using a resistor that costs
less than a pound I mean less than a
penny
probably so amazingly simple and useful
technique the other thing you can use
this technique for is figuring out if
your glitches if you're collecting too
hard for example
so here we are glitching away so we
found the point we want to glitch we've
started targeting it and basically I'm
the little blue dip is where my glitch
is going in and you can see it's not
having any effect and then bang I went
too hard
ship dies again so this is not a
breakpoint this is because I've killed
the the chip okay
so happily glitching away point we
killed it and so the solution for that
is well it's good and it's bad it's good
because it means I've had an effect
so my glitch is actually done something
okay but it's bad because the effect was
too too strong I have a pointer okay
thank you so yeah my glitch is too
strong and I've died here okay but I
know I'm in the right place that I or
potentially I'm in the right place but
I'm doing something and I want to keep
doing something so what I can do if I
reduce the width of the glitch we just
go back to an earlier state where it
wasn't doing anything but if I reduce
the the bottom voltage that I'm going
down to then I find I still have an
effect but it's not enough to kill the
chip so I've actually successfully
converted that from a death blow to
something that just causes an effect but
not such a strong effect not necessarily
the case it may be that I actually
glitched correctly and I caused a
decision to be made and that decision
made it jump off into into the void but
I have found that to be a useful
technique that if you kill it go to the
point and you kill it and then back off
on the voltage the other issue that I've
seen fairly commonly is inconsistent
timing so trying to do a very precise
glitch here so this is the second stage
of the attack when we're actually trying
to bypass the read protection so we're
sending a read command so this is this
is you are here so this is the read
command being echoed this is the read
command being sent and this is the reply
saying no you're not coming in so I want
a glitch in this gap here between
sending the command and getting the
reply and in this case my first attempt
was well the simplest form of trigger is
a GPIO line so my TX is kind of like a
GPIO so why don't I just plug into that
and when it goes low that will be my
trigger but this is quite a long command
here so that you can see that T is
saying triggers back here somewhere so
my triggers actually way back here
somewhere so that's a lot of time to get
out of sync when you're trying to do
something down to microsecond or
nanosecond speeds so it didn't work it
was all over the place and you get a lot
of jitter the you are you know behaves
differently you get slightly different
timings so what I found that she worked
better was using the oscilloscope itself
so this time I'm triggering on the echo
so you can see my trigger is right here
so the moment the end of the command
happens and then this is my delay and
then I'm glitching here so I'm
triggering on reading 0a as the echo
back from from the device and that was
much much more effective I'm being
signal to start winding it up so and
actually there's not a lot more going on
I do want to leave time for a couple of
questions apologies to my Italian
friends but spaghetti is the enemy
so all these wires what you'll find when
you start doing this is consistency is
really difficult if you've got stuff
like this because every single wire has
an effect and if you accidentally you
know bump one or move it around I mean
I've had very frustrating periods where
I'm getting a lot of success and then
for some reason but I never figure out
for the whole of the next day I can't
get a single glitch to work and even you
know trying parameters that I know have
worked before and they end up having to
just tear the whole thing apart and
rebuild it because I can't find which
wire has has got itself you know in a
pickle so if you want consistency and if
you want to do a lot of testing and
development then I recommend you go to
you know breadboards find solderless
breadboards fine for getting the thing
working in the first place but if you
want consistency you need to actually
solder so this guy is three of those
circuits all in one so I've got my max
chip which is doing the providing the
power I've got the target chip I've got
a converter here so I can actually use
the USB to convert to 3.3 or I can still
provide my high and low and I can also
use this board as a general-purpose
glitcher for other targets so and once I
built that it was way more consistent I
never had a problem again because yes I
have a couple of wires but these are
like the trigger so it's very easy to
see what's going on and I think yeah
that was it so I've got five minutes for
questions
I was humming you show that you use the
debug mode to get the time for trigger
right
I'm sorry saying user you sure that you
use debug modes to get the timing for a
trigger yeah correctly yeah how do you
convert them to a live device where
you're not burning in debug mode surely
that imposes some timing differences
okay so the question is when I was
running in debug mode I was on my
development board how do I convert that
to the real device that I'm attacking
because that isn't in debug mode because
that's what we're trying to do the
answer is you don't but you it's the
same chip running the same bootloader
because this is flash rom so I'm not
attacking the userland code because I
haven't got the user LAN code yet I'm
attacking the the flash boot rom which
will be the same because it's the same
chip so okay thanks though timing should
be pretty much the same and with
glitching there's always a window anyway
you're gonna have to it's never going to
be exactly you know you're not just
gonna say oh that's the point bang hit
it you will probably have to hit it a
few hundred or a few thousand times
although I did get to the point where I
could get it within 10 goes because it
was so precise you had a question are
you looking in any way in the actual
effect what's going on inside this chip
we insert injecting these iglesias or do
you focus more on the behavioral change
that the glitch causes for example
bypassing your check or opening the
protection so far so basically there's a
couple of us working on this stuff the
other guy is working on looking at the
sort of physical and electronic or
electrical effects that are being caused
I'm more interested in actual practical
outcomes of the glitch so generally what
we're doing this for is to recover
firmware for analysis so we just want to
achieve an effect like bypass read
affection and generally that's you know
that's what we're doing so I don't
really care why it worked we just care
that it did any other question we're
gonna make you fit now hey did you run
into issues where you art isn't precise
enough because it's like a synchronous
it's buffered and if so what other means
of having a trigger do you have it's
quite hard to hear you up here but the I
think the question was did I run into
issues where my timing wasn't precise
enough yeah because you artists a
synchronous and like buffered so when I
did like measuring traces I had an issue
that by the time I received the UART
signal the interesting part was already
over oh I see
yes I'm exactly so the you are example
was to overcome a similar thing and
actually I started when I started with
the UART glitching I started here
because you can see there's there's code
that's doing one thing and then very
clearly there's code that's doing
something different here and so I
started my glitch at this point and I
didn't I didn't really care you know
where I was successful in here but then
looking at the code analysis I realized
that actually the target I wanted was
closer to where the reply comes back and
this is why I needed to move the trigger
to something more reliable for that gap
so I could have triggered off the end of
this line which would put me back here
but yeah I mean you have to find
something that you can trigger from
that's before the event you're trying to
hit there's no way around that
unfortunately and when I was back here
the timing was just way too long so that
glitch was just jumping about all over
the place it was almost random it's like
trying rocks at it so for the witches
you tried
was good enough say again for the
glitches you tried UART was precise
enough I didn't get the last part of the
question the glitches I tried so the
question is whether you art was like
precise and I whether that you are was
precise yeah yes I mean I was successful
yes but it took a long time that the you
are is very jittery so that that glitch
will will hop around but the closer you
can get to the target the less it will
hop around obviously Adam how did you
make the lights go up and down I don't
know if it's me but I really can't yeah
I think cuz the speaker will point in
that way how did you make the lights go
up and down how do I make the lights go
up and down yes a point laser is that
any other questions
that's question we are having i'm just
being curious it's is it is it possible
to use ZigBee I mean relating with
ZigBee xB or something like that some
some kind of those devices is it
possible to click big beat devices Issac
vxb
I mean you can glitch any target you
like there I don't see why you shouldn't
you talking about glitching like the
ZigBee following on from the lights
discussion yeah absolutely I mean pick
your target anything is probably
vulnerable to glitching it depends on
the chipset the thing to do is look at
the chip that you're attacking so go and
look at the documentation for the ZigBee
chip you're interested in and see if
there's something in there that you
would need to use glitching as a
technique to overcome so does it have
code read protection does it have debug
ports does it have something that you
can latch on to that you can use a
glitch as an effect
of way of attacking it but yeah I mean
anything's possible I think we're out of
time as I said by all means calling me
outside I'm happy to have more in-depth
conversations it's a very big topic
we've just scratched the surface here so
Christopher Anna Christopher Oh as well
you should talk to in the front and Ryan
they are also very knowledgeable about
this stuff so thanks Adam thanks for
these references and it was a great a
great session
[Music]