alex j ballan i'm sure that many of you
are familiar with him
um i know that people around here mostly
buy iot devices for research purposes
because uh these are not that secure um
alex has spent the past five years
looking at iot devices his team at
bitdefender found many zero days in um
smart light bulbs webcams and uh
doorbell and we're going to learn more
about his his research but first i want
to um show you my smart watch can i do
that
alex
oh that is so cool
i'm glad you like it
so how were these uh
past five years for you
well i mean
the uh
the
it's easy
to hack smart devices so we we i have to
we need that we went into a field where
the the bar was set very very low
you know
so
a lot of low hanging fruits a lot of low
hanging fruits i mean virtually like
eighty percent of all the things that we
research in eighty percent we found uh
stuff with cvss core eight plus
right so stuff that you have like remote
command execution without any
authentication
device takeover account takeovers
without any any kind of uh
authentication or prerequisites and all
of them like trivially easy uh
unfortunately i mean some of the some of
the most common
attack vectors i'm gonna i'm gonna talk
about them in the slides today in the in
this today's presentation
um but yeah it's been fun we've uh
researched i think about 40 devices
ish
so quite quite a lot um
unfortunately the the one challenge that
we faced was as as lucas said the
interaction with the vendors yeah so the
interaction with the vendors was a
disaster they're like not a handful like
three or five vendors which actually
were very okay in the communication
uh but the vast majority
didn't know what pgp was didn't know
what how to communicate encrypted
they would default us to the support
department or stuff like that so
why do you think this is happening and
then we can go
and and watch the presentation
it's it's the lack of education i don't
think that they mean bad i don't think
that they uh
they are ill intended so to speak i
think that they simply know how to build
that particular device and they don't
know that much about how to handle
security or to have an open channel with
security researchers i think that
unfortunately the vast majority of
companies not just in the iot space but
everywhere the vast majority of
companies don't have that channel open
to internet and security researchers and
if anything i would want to raise an
alarm about that you know
all companies should have a channel open
to security researchers it's only going
to going to make them more resilient
but telling telling companies that you
know let us hack you and tell you about
it just doesn't have that ring that you
know it just doesn't
fit well with their mindset
okay
um wonderful intro
um are you ready to share your screen
let's see
break a leg
let's break some legs
[Music]
so good morning death camp
it's so good to
see you again i guess i just realized
that this is the usual intro and i
usually say it's so good to see you but
um yeah i miss you guys i miss you it's
been like two years
since we've been face to face
it was the 20
2019 edition when it was the last time
we we saw each other so yeah
um so let's dive into it because we have
a lot of content i don't think we have
sufficient time i'm going to try to kind
of squeeze it in
this presentation is about a summary of
the most relevant things we uncovered in
the past five years
and uh also some new stuff that we
published this year
so about me
igbo defender in
you can talk to me about vulnerability
research we have a lot of focus solarity
but we can talk about vulnerability
research in other areas as well
um i'm currently running an almost rock
pen testing team within bit defender
which is kind of cool um
essentially the way i i got them to join
was
i told them that they can blow stuff up
so
they're like really we can blow stuff
exactly like the madagascar penguin
kaboom yes kaboom blow stuff up and they
were like so happy in the start they
started blowing stuff up and it was
great
um
i'm running the defenders back bounty
program if you want to hack us you can
you should
try it the attack surface is huge
at bitdefender
so um
yeah
you should have a look at it run your
passive scans recons active scans and
and talk to us
um the bug bounty program if you want
it's on backroad and we also have a
separate one running on our website if
you do not want to interact with bug
crowd
hang on sorry sorry sorry
okay
um i'm also deeply involved in the
vulnerability management process so all
the vulnerabilities that uh we identify
either in the pen testing team or in the
background program have to go through a
vulnerability management process
and
[Music]
i also
just re-watched cowboy bebop awesome if
you didn't say it strongly recommend
and also i'm a proud def can dinosaur
my first death camp presentation was i
don't know when
i don't remember but i remember there
were like 80 people in total
that were present at the conference
about b defenders vulnerability research
team we started doing vulnerability
research in 2016.
we found vulnerabilities with eight plus
vss score in more than 20 brands so i i
as i was telling andrada earlier
we
researched about 40 devices
um and we found
so eight plus on the cvs core is bad
it's like really really bad it is remote
command execution without any
prerequisites bad
or but can't take over without any
prerequisites back
so
this is the fun part but the not so fun
part is that we only published 12 papers
which amount to like a very very small
fraction of
our total findings
uh in other words
we have
a ton of papers that we're sitting on
and we cannot publish them
because of poor or no reply from vendors
the thing is um some of the things that
we found can be used for mass
exploitation and
um
while i know some of you will say that
just give them the the 60 days and then
publish it because that's going to force
their hand
it's really not that
it's really not the case in iot
in some cases the vendors if you even if
you do publish
they won't patch it
and then that's going to put some people
at risk so we're still trying to kind of
balance that out
and also very important four years ago
we started to focus a lot on iot cloud
platforms and there's a reason for that
um
[Music]
nowadays most iots are starting to move
away from port forwarding so in the old
days you would have a
security camera or a thermostat or
an electrical control system or
something like that
and you would port forward it
uh so you could access it from the
internet now that's thankfully not the
case anymore and most smart devices are
just cloud relayed
have cloud related communication
so
with that in mind we obviously started
to look at how those cloud
implementations work
we published
a lot
thankfully so we managed to publish for
example
we had a very good
communication with august smartlav or
with ring doorbell
when we found when we reported our
findings to them they replied almost
instantly and they patched uh their
entire user base in under a month and
that's that's a very good metric
unfortunately with most others they
didn't
now the first chapter is reusable attack
vectors and common vulnerabilities so
this is stuff that's present in the vast
majority of smart devices
wi-fi password hijack so
this is an attack which enables you to
steal a victim's wifi password if they
have a smart device and the way this
goes is like this
when you initially set up a device the
process this is a description of how
the process looks from uh under the
standpoint when you initially set up a
smart device so step one
i'm sorry i should have put step zero
you plug it in
so step one after you've plugged it in
it boots and then it creates a uh a
hotspot and the manual says you install
the application the setup application
and then it says okay connect to the
wi-fi
hotspot created by the smart device
step two
after you've connected to that smart
device it tells you okay i'm
successfully connected to the smart
device now i want you to select your
home wi-fi
from this list
and enter your wi-fi password
after that there's several other
settings you can set up notifications
whatever the device supports
you know various devices support various
features
and then it goes in configuring mode
and then usually it stucks and then it
fails
i've seen this so many times
and then you try again and it works
now what happens when you're doing that
in that configuration stage is that
everything that you've set up in the
mobile app gets packaged into a json
file or an xml file or a text file why
not
which gets sent to the device well while
your mobile application is still
connected to that
wi-fi network
the device stores that and reboots using
that configuration
part of that configuration is
connect to this wi-fi network with this
password
and the other
settings now the one thing that
happens is that that
access point created by the
smart device is
usually open
it doesn't have a password in 99 of the
cases and little known fact about wi-fi
is that on uh open access point so
access points that do not have a
password
there's also no encryption on that
channel and you can monitor the channel
and see the traffic on that channel
without being associated with that
channel
so you can actually see that file going
from the mobile phone to the smart
device and capture it
in some implementations
that config file is encrypted and
there's
some sort of key exchange between the
smart device and the mobile app but in
most cases it's plain text so the attack
moment is when that exchange happens and
you can steal it
and if you're wondering
about the vulnerability window being
only in setup mode
well
hang on
the way this works involves a little bit
of social engineering as well uh you
simply knock the device out
of the network with the authentication
packets
it's trivial to do so for those of you
who don't know what the authentication
packets are essentially it's a feature
in the wi-fi implementation that enables
somebody from outside of the wi-fi
network
to disconnect a device from the wi-fi
network so you simply keep flooding that
device with the authentication packets
and brick it which will force the user
to reconfigure it
and then you have your windows
vulnerability to steal the wi-fi
password so for today's presentation
we're gonna show you
um
what we did with august log because
august lock is definitely better
implemented than most other devices they
were actually encrypted encrypting that
package
unfortunately the encryption key was
hard coded and it was the same
encryption key for all devices so when
we extracted our decryption key we
purchased another lock just to see if we
can reuse it and we could
so
this is how the attack looked against
august log
you start scanning the wi-fi spectrum
i'm going to fast forward because we
don't have a lot of time we see the
wi-fi network
the aphrodite beauty salon
then we start monitoring that wi-fi
network to catch the mac address of our
victim device
as you can see there's no need to
authenticate or or use that wi-fi
network
so we have the mac address of our victim
device and now we are going to
to kick it off the network
and i know that this
is basic stuff for most of you what i'm
trying to outline here is not
necessarily the fact that you can kick
off the network device with your
authentication packets but the fact that
there's that vulnerability window that
you can actually info
get again from the user you know that
setup moment
so you kick it off and then at some
point we're going to see
uh
there's a reconfiguring the device that
we're gonna we're gonna we're going to
see the hotspot created by the august
the by the
by the smart clock
let's follow it fast forward fast
forward
and there we have it august lock dash
c5wi
now what we're doing we're sniffing and
we're gonna
switch to wireshark to see the packets
exchanged with that
access point
hang on and there we have the file which
is currently encrypted
so all we gotta do is just use the key
to
decrypt so we have this small python
script that is able to decrypt and then
we have
the wi-fi password
for a wrinkle stand so pantone 10 for
adidas
so that's the that's the wi-fi hijacked
password for iot so again 99 of all
smart devices will create that hotspot
all you got to do is just string the 3d
user into reconfiguring the device
capture that configuration file file
being sent over and you have the device
configuration which includes the wi-fi
password
now we come to the cool part because you
know um
getting the wi-fi password requires
proximity
so
you cannot really do it against millions
and millions of devices so we get to the
cool park uh computing cloud
implementations
so
an example of abusing clone
implementation is going to be the um
[Music]
edimax smart power outlet so here's how
cloud works in iot
um
on the mobile phone we say we want to
control something about the device we
want to tell the vacuum cleaner to start
cleaning or we want to tell the
the power outlet to tell us to give us
notifications when we're using too much
power and whatever interaction we want
to have with the smart device that's
inside our house
and we are gone you know we are outside
of the house we are in another country
maybe
and the cloud talks the smart device in
our house talks to the cloud and our
mobile device talks to the cloud
and the cloud we relay
our interactions with the smart device
um
and it facilitate that communication
but the thing is whatever is being
relayed by the cloud is essentially
input right so i'm telling the cloud
abcd the cloud will say will tell the
smart device okay that guy just said
abcd and that abcd is going to be parsed
by code on the smart device and that
code
may be and very often is vulnerable to
buffer overflows command ejection
various types of you know parsing
uh parsing vulnerabilities
maybe miss tragic uh maybe any kind of
other partial vulnerability so it's
really cool because
this is a very uh this is not very
researched there's not a lot of research
done in this direction
and a lot of the code on the smart
devices is insanely vulnerable and also
there is no aslr on smart device so if
you find a buffer overflow
you have a very good chance of getting
predictable remote map execution
so yes most smart devices
have slr enabled but it's not used
because the binaries in in iot are
compiled without pi without position
independent executable
so um
[Music]
we
we have two papers we have a few up more
actually but
for the sake of today the edimax smart
power outlet
had a command injection
so
here's how that worked
wait
so first of all
we set up at least normal test so what
we want to do is we want to tell the
cloud to tell the power outlet
um
about the commands that we want to send
about an information and we want to
trigger a connect back shell from the
power outlet right because it's behind
that it's behind maybe three four
firewalls in this case it was actually
in our offices in cluj
so um we wanted to trigger the power
outlet to send the connect back shell to
us so we set up a listener you know
on a vps i think it was somewhere in
canada
as you can see it's mips little indian
and
this is
our payload our payload is is base64 in
semicolon
go to tmp and get our second stage
payload
and execute it
it was a command injection i'm not going
to detail it now the the paper on
document ejection and how it works is on
our website
but as you can see
we sent it and by the way i forgot to
mention the only uh requirement for
exploiting is the is the mac address of
the power outlet uh fun fact
a lot of researchers after i initially
did a presentation on the rmax smart
power outlet a lot of the researchers
said that they're going to use this in
the red team engagements so essentially
what they were going to do and i think
that what they're actually doing is they
purchase the smart power outlet copy the
mac address from the box because it's
visible on the box and then they just
gift it to their targets and the moment
the target sets it up the attacker has a
foothold in the in the target's home
network it's pretty cool so again the
only thing that you need is the mac
address
you tell the cloud to relay your payload
and then you can see that
the payload was executed it got the
second stage
and then you have a shell session open
and obviously this is just on some stuff
that you can do
on
while you have access on the power
outlet like get the wi-fi password or
use it to pivot and detect the rest of
the network
third thing is mqtt so
for those of you who don't know mqtt is
a
messaging service if you will
that enables quick messaging and
notifications and commands between the
mobile app and the device
so the device can say
i'm on i'm off uh i've just seen
somebody at the door
i've just started vacuuming
i have too much beer in the fridge
whatever
and these are like short messages that
are relayed to the mobile app so you get
that notification on the mobile app that
says there's too much beer in the fridge
there's not enough beer in the fridge
and so on and so forth
so the way mqtt works is that it has a
tree structure
uh you have like slash root slash device
id slash topic but the topic is one of
these events
now ideally you should only be able to
register to your own devices so when you
configure your device
you establish this initial protocol okay
this is the device id from the device
that i own
and then
the mobile app will know that it's going
to register to slash root slash device
id and it's going to be able to access
all the topics and notifications from
that device id
a common mistake that manufacturers make
is that so when we initially saw this
implementation we thought okay why what
if we tried to access the root
uh
what's going to happen then and bam when
we tried that in some cases we started
to see the notifications of all the
devices
made by that vendor
and pretty much the same thing with s3
s3 as most of you probably know is that
storage service from amazon
uh and uh
one of the most common flaws is that
they have something like directory index
of web servers
activated and when that's activated
you can access
all the data from a particular vendor
that uses that s3 bucket so normally
when when you see that a vendor uses s3
you can do this by monitoring what the
mobile application does it's going to
start accessing files in an s3 bucket
a very simple thing that you can try
is okay
can i try and access all the files in
that bucket
and unfortunately in some cases it's
going to work
and this was actually the root cause of
many hacks in the past if you google
s3 bucket
database dump or s3 bucket database
click or s3 bucket company hacked you're
gonna see unfortunately a lot of news
about companies getting hacked simply by
having a an exposed s3 bucket
so moving to today's uh presentation i'm
gonna skip the
description of the product it's just a
baby monitor so mqtt uh the first thing
that we noticed was an unauthenticated
mqtt information link they have their
own mqtt relay server which is publicly
exposed in the internet
uh all you have to do is just um
register to it and you're gonna see the
ids of all the devices that come online
unfortunately unfortunately there's no
authentication necessary and this is how
it looks like there's a tool called
called mosquito
you just use it register
and then bam you're gonna start seeing
events from uh
from that device or from that vendor and
those events include this device id
uh in in most cloud implementations in
iot by the way that cloud id that device
id is the only form of authentication if
you have access to that device id
effectively from that point onwards you
can interact with the device without
having to use any other username and
password
and this this counts for a lot of
implementation of the implementation
that we've seen so far so if you manage
to get that particular information the
device id
it's usually not predictable but for
example with an exploit like the mqtt
leak you can just get access to it
the second thing that we wanted to do is
getting video feeds through um
rstps
so rstp is that that protocol uh that
enables you to you know that facilitates
video streaming rstps is a secure
implementation of that
we notice that in
normal
behavior the camera says i'm upload i'm
uploading my feed to this web location
and then the cloud is going to tell the
mobile app hey you can see the video of
it at this location
and this is how your mobile app is able
to access the video feed of the baby
monitor
however what we discover is that the
mqtt implementation supported a
command
named command
so if you tell slash device slash device
id
slash cmd
you can tell it to change that upload
location to a different location so
essentially you connect to the mqtt
server and you tell a device somebody
else's device
start uploading your video feed to my
location
and
this is how it looks
we set up initially a listener
and then we tell musk we tell the mqtt
stream to
and let me pause it
to send the rstp stream to our rogue
server in our case it's 1001 uh slash
media
and we're gonna we see client connected
and we start getting a video feed so
what we're gonna do with this we're just
going to pipe it to vlc
and this is the other http hijack so
what what we learned here is that that
mqtt was actually the initial problem
the fact that the device ids were
exposed and the fact that it had that
additional feature called cmd which
enabled us anybody to change the
location of the video stream it wasn't
necessary it wasn't needed it was just
there and probably they forgot to take
it out
and there's a buffer overflow
uh
in in the power outlet sorry in the in
the baby monitor
which we also are going to explode uh
through mqtt it just gives us the
possibility to give it input and that
url change uh
command that we sent earlier
the particular code that parses that new
url is also
vulnerable to a stack based buffer
overflow
rc
so we're setting up a listener
and we're creating the payload
the payload is going to be essentially
net cut
with a shell to our attacker ip address
and of course the buffer overflow
payload
and we got a shell on the
on the on the baby monitor so again as
you can see this whole thing is
completely remote completely without any
form of authentication
you can do it behind four firewalls just
by having a vps with publicly accessible
vps that can get a connect back shell
so
as end nodes cloud related attacks
against iots will bypass any counter
measures they're very difficult to to
block
because the communication is encrypted
usually smart devices will talk
encrypted with their cloud the
communication looks legitimate because
it's a communication with the cloud the
only thing that's going to kind of fall
out of place is that connect back shell
that you get
but you may want to run other commands
you may want to drop
an apt
that just periodically checks with the
with the command control server that's
and snoops on the internal
infrastructure and so on and so forth
so
you cannot do the packet inspection and
decrypt the traffic because you usually
cannot drop
your own certificate authority to to
decrypt the traffic
so
i strongly advise that any smart device
that you get that's not from a reputable
brand as i was saying august were great
they patched their stuff instantly we
have we allocated a cv they were okay
with that we just had a small struggle
in negotiating the cvss score they
didn't agree with us initially
but they replied instantly and they had
this very well
uh
you know handle on things they it it
showed that they have the experience to
handle this the same thing with ring
doorbell and anything that we found from
a high-profile company
the moment the device started to become
cheaper so to speak
that that was when the companies don't
reply to the emails they just sent us to
the support department in one case
a company wanted to offer us a discount
for their products they said we are we
are sorry that you are unhappy with our
product we can offer you a 50 discount
guys you don't get it that's not why we
call we don't care about buying your
products we already have it so
uh
military grade encryption provides zero
security against most common attacks
today i just wanted to say this
and
a tricky thing about smart device
vulnerabilities that does not track the
way we're used to in software so
when you have a vulnerability an apache
or a vulnerability in in an unpacked
like winrar or our
labs or a vulnerability in some parser
or in some libraries like image magic
these are tracked by cve so you can
reference them you can use them they're
documented in in smart device world it's
very rarely the case we started
allocating cves for some vulnerabilities
so there's no centralized inventory of
vulnerabilities for iot which
essentially means
that only a fraction of the published
vulnerabilities are known
because some guy publishes a narrative
vulnerability on their blog in some in
some place and some guy publishes on
another blog in some other place but
they're not aggregated at mitre for
example so you have on on the one hand
we only published a fraction of the
papers that we have
because
a defender didn't reply and out of those
papers the visibility that they got was
also limited because they're not
centralized in a
centralized vulnerability repository
and that's about it
thank you alex i was thinking a lot
about what you said and both what uh
lucas said earlier um and i was
wondering whether
you think that there could be some
policy changes that could be enforced in
order for these vendors to listen to you
guys
do you think this could help
i mean i know it's gonna sound
tough but i would make it a requirement
to operate
i would make having a communication
channel with security researchers i
would definitely make it a mandatory
requirement to be able to operate having
that security contact and making sure
that you manage 24 7
because you have a responsibility to
your users and you have a responsibility
to dress up the world let's not forget
that the mirai botnet because of some
telnet open with root and one two three
four s password
or some hard coded password in the
firmware that that was reusable across
hundreds of thousands of devices
caused an attack that amounted to about
650 gigabits per second
so yeah there's this
responsibility that that companies need
to have you have for example a user base
you have a few hundred thousand users
and then somebody finds that that
there's a sql injection that enables
them to kind of pull all the data out of
that database and then they try
contacting and there's no security
contact that's a big deal that the
privacy of the data of those users
is important and it should be
nobody expects you to have perfect
security we don't i mean this is why
we're running the bug bounty program to
have access to all the potential
vulnerabilities that we may have
unfortunately there's only a handful of
companies that do the same thing
so yeah i would make it mandatory to
have a security contact
for being able to operate customer data
and do you think that
perhaps um
international bodies should have
something to say about it such as the eu
or where where do you see um these
changes
well yeah
unfortunately
even ethical hacking is outlawed in most
countries you know
so this effectively gives an edge to the
bad guys because they don't care about
the laws they're just going to switch to
some territory that where nobody can
touch them and just you know
have at it
so i would i would definitely see some
legislature being changed towards
facilitating
grounds for ethical hackers to be able
to you know tamper with critical
infrastructure for example
i'm afraid to look at the critical
infrastructure in romania
because of the law you know the law says
that you're not allowed to do that
however some other guy from another
country is not afraid to do that and
they may find something that i could
have found earlier early on and tell
them about it and i could have fixed it
so yeah i would want to see legislature
kind of facilitating more things for
ethical hackers
and
compelling companies to have a security
contact
so this in this presentation you
basically looked at the last five years
of your work yeah do you think that if
we meet
five years from now
things are going to be different or
we're going to be stuck in this paradigm
you see
many people
are against monopolies
um
for many reasons and the reason i'm
bringing this up is that
one of the problems with iot is
diversity
there's such a big diversity of devices
there's such a big diversity of cloud
implementations there's such a
plethora of companies that provide cloud
support for iot iot platform uh firmware
that's oem for iot and because they're
such a big diversity and not that not
not those many golden standards
and even if they work for the standards
many of these companies don't follow
them then this is going to be an open
case forever
i think you're a mute
yeah hopefully things are going to
change for the better allow me to be an
optimist right now because um everyone
is going through a lot and we don't want
to um
say depressing things at the end of a
depressing presentation
i mean let me let me let me tell you
something else if they let us if they
let us find those vulnerabilities and
they patch them then things are
definitely going to be better this is
the way it works everywhere else you
know um
our infrastructure in our company and
our products are definitely better
because of the contributions
the valuable contribution of security
researchers and we once again thank them
for that all all the companies all the
legislature need to do is facilitate
us with the you know the legislature to
allow us to hack
white uh to do ethical hacking and if
that happens then things are gonna be
substantially better because we're going
to force everybody to patch their stuff
yeah
thank you so much