so um our first presentation of the day
will be from
emanuel
he has been a long time um you know
member of the deaf camp community and i
i it's my pleasure to introduce him and
i'm very keen on learning from him you
know a deep learning approach to
phishing detection which has been top of
mind for everyone in the past year and a
half and will be for a long time radu
we're really happy to have you here
thank you for opening death camp and
let's have an awesome presentation i'll
be standing by for your questions so be
sure to drop them there over to you
radho
thank you andra for the introduction are
you able to hear me well
yes you're coming through just fine
okay thanks so
hello everyone my name is radu i'm a
security research engineer in the
application and right intelligence team
at
keysight i would like to talk about a
project that started as a hackathon idea
really together with some of my
colleagues so we wanted to enrich the
functionality of an internal pipeline
that delivers threat intelligence to our
customers
more exactly we try to find out if a
deep neural network can discriminate
between phishing and legitimate pages
a few words about phishing first based
on the interaction environment between
an adversary and its target
there are multiple types of phishing
attacks for example there is the email
phishing attacks that we all know of
well the other where the adversary sends
an email to its target an email designed
to convince the target to
access uh to access a malicious link or
file
the malicious link usually points to a
phishing page designed to look like a
legitimate page in order to increase the
chance of the target being tricked into
sharing its private information with the
attacker this will be the focus of our
talk
there is also the matter of social
account fishing where an attacker
attempts to impersonate the avatar of a
specific target in order to trick other
people from its entourage to click on
malicious links or actually asking for
payment
another
another type of phishing attack is the
voice fishing or wishing in this type of
attack an adversary usually attempts to
present itself as the target or as a
relative
to obtain private details from entities
that have a contract with the target
now back to website phishing to
introduce the context of the project
allow me to say a few words about rap
sheet one of our products
rap sheet is a system that is designed
to autonomously collect and keep track
of ips that are shown to be related with
malicious activities
this information related to the
activities of a malicious ip
ips is stored in documents that we call
rap sheets one for each ip that the
system finds rap sheets can be created
for phishing pages as well this works
like this
a feature receives an url as an input
and attempts to download the html page
located at that url if something is
found then a screenshot of the render
page is taken as well
then the html page is analyzed by a set
of antiviruses and phishing classifiers
the results are aggregated and a voting
system decides if a rap sheet will be
created
because antivirus antiviruses often lack
signatures for certain phishing pages we
have developed our own phishing
classifiers internally while trying to
improve the predictions for such a
classifier we often found ourselves
looking um both at the screenshot
features and the url
to establish whether the domain is
legitimate or not
then we thought why not train a deep
neural network on the screenshots that
we were already collecting a network
that would apply the same logic that is
taking into consideration both the
screenshot features and the url
that way we could come up with a new
detection in the voting system
studying the literature we came across a
research paper that we considered to be
tangent to our problem
in fact we have decided to consider this
paper's approach as a starting point for
our project and build upon its ideas
the approach is well summarized in this
picture from the paper first we start
with a list of trusted websites the
trust is granted by the website's domain
then we train a neural network with the
purpose of learning a trusted website
identity we train such a network with
various screenshots taken from each of
the legitimate websites they would be
represented by the points in the green
center zone
once the knowledge base is established
pages with vis with similar visual
appearances to the learned ones are
considered phishing attempts
they would be represented by the points
in the in the red zone
pages with different or unknown features
are to be considered other legitimate
pages that are not yet part of the
trusted website zone
one limitation of this kind of approach
is that it might be able to detect only
phishing pages associated with the
websites in the trusted list
but at the same time a large advantage
is that new legitimate websites can be
incorporated without too much effort
into the existing existing model without
changing the neural network architecture
with this approach established it is
time to think about producing a data set
we have consulted alexa to 500 to decide
upon what sites should we start with
to obtain screenshots for legitimate and
phishing sites we mainly had two sources
firstly we used our own phishing sites
collectors
going manually through the data to
curate it
we have also contacted the paper's
authors as they were willing to share
their data set and we have used it
to cross-reference with what we have
since we're starters we wanted to train
a model only with the data from our
collectors
let's see a couple of examples of
phishing pages that we encounter
in this example we have a phishing page
for um
for amazon
website and and with and as we can see
there is um
a large degree of similarity between the
two a bit of a small difference here
they are quite similar
the same can be said about this example
a fishing page for ebay
there are some differences but overall
they're quite similar
but we have also this kind of phishing
pages in which the attacker
would only care about using certain
colors of or logos of the legitimate
website hoping that it will be enough to
treat the target
um
in the same manner here we have a
phishing page for paypal the attacker
only
includes the
paypal logo and a
credential phishing form which is
somewhat similar to the one of the
legitimate page
but we encountered this kind of examples
as well in which the attacker would
include the credential phishing form
that is not at all present normally in
the
in the application
so we can we have this kind of situation
as well
um to conclude uh looking at the
screenshots we have noticed that there
are phishing attempts that try to
closely mimic the legitimate websites as
expected but there are also phishing
sites that
just have some basic identifiers such as
logos and standard text or colors that
you would usually expect to find on the
corresponding legitimate website
there are even cases of attackers adding
fishing forms to applications that do
not have such a feature
as this kind of variation was not enough
the variation is increased by different
website languages and changes in the
page design that need to be taken into
consideration as well when trying to
build
such a model
based on these observations we decided
that in order to learn a website
identity because that is our purpose we
should include phishing samples in the
training step as well such that
the features that are characteristic to
a website can be picked up both from
legitimate and from phishing sites and
this can be regarded as a form of
augmentation
after we collected collected the data we
have split it into three categories
namely training validation and test
the training data set contains the
screenshots from 55 trusted websites
with both legitimate and phishing
samples amounting to 2380 screenshots
to help the model generalize a little
better we have included four forms of
augmentation applied to the training
data
firstly we applied brightness control to
mimic certain pop-ups that show up
sometimes when reaching a website
secondly when we apply the random
cropping to force the model to pick up
certain relevant features and color
palettes
also as i mentioned mentioned earlier we
decided to include the screenshots of
sites in different languages and
phishing samples in the training step as
well so that the model can pick up
relevant features both from legitimate
and from phishing sites
the validation data set contains
different screenshots for the same
websites that are present in the
training data set and the test data set
contains two types of screenshots either
for known sites that appear in the
training set and for unknown sites
and by unknown i mean sites for which
there aren't screenshots in the training
data set
we added new sites because we wanted to
see how the trend model behaves when
facing with screenshots of sites that
are not in the initial list
we added the screenshots with new sites
both for legitimate and for phishing
pages
as for the type of the neural network we
have chosen a convolutional architecture
frequently used for image classification
tasks
convolutional layers are nothing new
they've been around since 89 they've
been proposed by yan le khan which is
now the chief ai scientist at facebook
now meta this is a high level
representation of how a convolutional
neural network looks like
we have an input image that is filtered
with uh with which is iterated with
filters of certain sizes
uh convolution layers are then applied
sequentially to smaller region of the
input image their role is to transform
the input volume in thinner volume with
larger and larger depths each layer is
responsible of learning different types
of features
the shallow layers that have smaller
depths are learning features with small
complexity such as directed edges
while the deeper layers with thinner
volumes are picking up more complex
features such as shapes group of objects
and various patterns
this process of convolving applying
non-linearity and pulling is repeated a
couple of rounds until the spatial
information is extracted from the image
finally you get an output layer
uh that is a
probability over all the categories to
be recognized the training part is
assured by back propagating the
classification error so when you make a
mistake that error is back propagated
throughout the entire network updating
the parameters
one disadvantage of such networks is
that they are very data hungry they need
to train on millions of millions of
samples to perform well
to overcome this a powerful technique is
available which is called transfer
learning
transfer learning allows you to use a
pre-trained network a network that was
trained on a large volume of data for
another somewhat similar classification
task with a smaller amount of data
you do that by basically keeping up
the layer structure of the pre-trained
model and replacing the final deployers
then you must fine-tune the new
architecture to the data available on
the task that interests you
the fine tuning part refers to blocking
the weights of certain layers so that
the propagation won't affect them or
adding new layers or changing the value
of some parameters or all of the above
for our task we took a pre-trained
architecture removed the output layer
and adjusted for our problem
um we tried various pre-trained networks
but the one that showcased better
results with the smaller number of
parameters was efficient net together
with the layers that we added we had the
total of 37 million parameters
[Music]
further on we took this network and
integrated it into an architecture
called cms network the cms network aims
at learning how much different images
are amongst themselves based on a
similarity function
in a cms architecture the input is
represented by a triplet of images the
convention
the convention is that the first image
is called an anchor
this is the baseline image the second
image is called the positive sample and
it represents an image similar to the
anchor
in our case an image of the same website
the third image is called the negative
sample and it should be an image
different than the anchor in our case
the negative sample will be the image of
a website different from bank of america
from which we have chosen the anchor and
positive sample we feed this triplet
into the model based on transfer
learning that we talked about earlier
which we can perceive as an embedding
model since the model will produce
embedding arrays representation of the
website in the embedding space
the learning objective is then to have a
model that outputs similar embeddings
for the anchor and the positive sample
so for image of the same website and
respectively very different embeddings
for the samples of the different
websites to put it differently the model
weights have to be adjusted during
learning such that the distance from the
anchor to the positive sample is small
while the difference from the anchor to
the negative sample is large
to satisfy this condition we have to
define a loss function in the following
manner
giving a triplet of anchor positive and
negative samples
we define d of mp as the euclidean
distance between the bendings of the
anchor and the positive sample in the
same manner we define d of n n as the
euclidean distance between the beddings
of the anchor and the negative sample
a good embedding model would make d of
mp smaller than d of a and n
but in practice we add an alpha
parameter margin to push the distance
further apart from each other and make
the model more robust
as the loss function should return a
value larger or equal to zero we define
the loss as the maximum between the
difference of the distances plus the
margin and zero this means that if the
difference is negative then the loss
will be zero
a negative difference means that d of
amp is smaller than d of n n and this is
exactly what we want
the goal here is to penalize the model
only when the difference is very large
when the negative sample is closer
to the anchor than the positive sample
now that we have finished with the
theory let's see how the training went
we used tensorflow gpu python library to
code this up
the model was trained on a machine with
an nvidia rtx
1319 gpu and 64 gigabytes of ram the
triplets are selected at random from the
existing data respecting the anchor
positive and negative convention and
then they are fed to the model
the screenshots of the unknown websites
in the training set are only used as
negative samples
we can
illustrate the model's training
improvement over time by doing a disney
plot disney stands for t distributed
stochastic neighboring bearing a fancy
name for an algorithm that basically
reduces a high dimensional vector a
representation of the website to a
two-dimensional vector through a series
of repeated projections so that we can
plot it in the 2d space
this will help us visualize how the
embeddings of different websites are
distributed in the embedding space as
the training progresses
initially without any training the
embeddings are distributed quite
randomly across the embedding space but
after a few iterations we can see how
multiple clusters emerge and as the
training progresses the clusters start
to separate separate quite nicely each
cluster representing a specific
website a thing to note here is that the
axis value axis values have no practical
meaning for a disney plot this is just
something that can help us visualize how
the training task progresses
after the training is complete we have
to produce predictions for the
validation and test samples the
prediction is done in the following
manner firstly we compute the embeddings
of all the screenshots in the training
data set
then we fit the test image into the
embedding model
to obtain its embedding then we have to
find the minimum distance
um
between the embeddings of the test image
and the bendings of the training images
the matched site will be the site of the
closest embeddings
this approach worked quite well we
obtained the good preliminary results um
from 40 uh of 489 screenshots of
phishing pages targeting all the 55
websites in the
uh in the initial list in the training
set
in the test
in the in the training set we correctly
in the test set we correctly labeled 390
screenshots of their corresponding
legitimate pages
so um
an accuracy of approximate um
of a of 80 percent
uh the miss label is mislabeling is
mainly caused by the small numbers of
phishing samples for specific websites
um
if if you recall we also included
a number of uh legitimate
of of screenshots for legitimate pages
that were not present in the trusted
list
and from those we correctly labeled
154 screenshots as unknown legitimate
websites in this case the mislabeling is
attributed to some unknown sites being
somewhat similar to the sites in the
trusted list
now let's look how
the model performs against
some
some some screenshots
okay so
um
after you train a model
then
you can load the weights um in order to
um uh to have to make up predictions so
um here in the initial step we are
loading the model that we trained and we
read the embeddings for the training um
for the training samples which are we
are using um
um further on
here we have two functions the first uh
the first one is used to plot the test
image against the most uh similar image
that is found in the most similar
embedding that is found in the training
data set
and here
we are
here we have a function that
sends the embedding of
the test image
to the embedding model creates an
embedding and compares it against all
the embeddings of
the
websites in the training data set
in the first example um
we chose um
on an easier test sample we have a
fishing of adobe
adobe page
in this case the classification was
correct as you can see the predicate
predicted
the model correctly predicted the
phishing page as pertaining to adobe and
the most similar image found was this
which is a um
which is a
phishing sample using the training set
as you can see they are quite similar
although there are a few differences but
the model correctly determined that
this is the most similar image and
correctly assigned it as being a fishing
to the adobe
in the second example we have something
a little different we have a test image
that is a
phishing page of paypal written in
german
we did not have such samples in the
training set and uh even
even though we did not have the model
still managed to correctly predict it as
being a phishing page of paypal
and as we can see the most similar image
found was
a legitimate image of the paypal website
in the third example we have something
even more different we have a phishing
page for netflix
um
but here we have a different language
language and different bankrupt
background as well so we did not have
such this kind of images in the training
set in this case the model again
correctly predicted that is a
phishing page of netflix and the more
similar image as we can see it's um
it's a page of um
it's a
legitimate page of netflix but the
language is different and the background
is different as well
if you recall there are also
cases in which the attacker would add
a phishing form to
applications that do not normally have
one
we decided to test this as well and see
how the model performs
this is the phishing page um and again
the model correctly predicted it as
being official for office excel
and um
we can see that
our decision to include phishing pages
in the training step as well to extend
the identity website
really helped because the most similar
image that was found
is a fishing fishing page
in the fifth
fifth example we have we will see if the
model can distinguish between legitimate
pages and the phishing from the
trustings from the trusted list initial
list
in this case we have a test image which
is a legitimate screenshot of
geeks4geeks
if we ask the model about it he will say
that is on an unknown site which is
correct
and if we
and the most similar image that is found
is a page of a different website but as
we can see there are some similarities
in how the
um
certain objects in the page are
organized another interesting example
for me was this um screenshot of a
legitimate page again the model
correctly correctly predicted as being a
unknown site but as we can see um even
though the
website is different there are some
similarities in how the object objects
are distributed across uh the website
so um again uh the modli correctly
predicted uh what was going on here
okay
now we have to ask ourselves of course
as security researchers if we can bypass
this model
um
for example let's uh think about a model
designed to detect spam emails
usually these models are built uh based
on some keywords in the indicative of or
of spam or non-spam
these keywords are given certain weights
during training and the resulted model
computes a metric for the likeness of an
email being spun
but the spawn motors knowing this
they've started to introduce
misspellings intentionally to certain
words in the email this is the reason
why sometimes spam is written like this
and it's a good way of bypassing such a
detection every stick
and similarly in our situation one
approach is to bypass the mod one
approach to bypass the model is to come
up with
images that visually resemble the
screenshots of legitimate
website but they have some imperceptible
differences such as some added noise or
maybe some small offsets in the position
of certain websites in certain objects
in the website
but this topic of adversarial machine
learning is for another presentation
uh this was my presentation i hope that
you enjoy it thank you very much for uh
your attention
thank you so much
please don't go anywhere this was really
exciting and i think that it is
definitely in thank you for ending this
with
one of the cutest things ever um this
was a very insightful uh and detailed
presentation so thank you for walking us
through your entire research which i bet
there you took a lot of effort and
energy
so
i have just a couple of questions for
you so we can um you know understand
your experience with the community as
well and kind of you know how this
became a key topic of interest for you
so what was the trigger for this
particular piece of research what led
you to devote you know so much time and
and effort uh into this particular topic
um thank you for the question as i've
mentioned at the beginning
this kind of started as a project for um
for hackathon we noticed that
we have something in our pipeline some
kind of information that we pulled
that wasn't used
and
we saw that
there is this repeated the action that
we do we were looking at the url we were
looking at the screenshots to determine
if something is phishing or not and um
we
wanted to see if um
if um
such an approach is
could lead to good results and also i
was trying to get acquainted with
this
this field of machine learning and deep
learning in particular
which i think
um can is a is a help is a tool that can
help you in certain situations
definitely and we definitely need to
scale the impact the positive impact of
technologies like the one that you just
talked about the entire mechanism behind
detecting fishing at scale simply
because we see it we see it generally
not just globally in english but now we
see it a lot happening in romanian as
well uh they've seen an uptick in
in phishing attempts as a user uh and
obviously reporting them but i always
check them i run them through virustotal
and they're always
you know domains they come from domains
that have zero detection so there's
clearly kind of a
cat and mouse game that happens in
security with many many things but this
is at scale and we definitely need a lot
more help with this
have you um
shared any of your research with other
people in the community until this
presentation i want to do what kind of
you know what are their concerns and
worries around fishing and how much does
it impact their jobs from what you know
um
i've
i've worked at multiple blog posts um
during my time at keysight
um i've been posting things about
fuzzing about malware analysis
this is
this was kind of a new project for me as
i wasn't um
i didn't wear myself into this field of
machine learning and deploying before
and
there are a lot of resources online if
you want to learn about it and you want
to see how it can you it can be used you
can see presentations about
deep learning and machine learning in
general being used for
malware detection and for other other
things in
in the security field a lot of books and
blogs
and videos about us and maybe if someone
needs something specific if it's working
out a problem and is thinking whether
this method could be used
uh maybe we can discuss further on on
the specific issue um
[Music]
on
the social media or
to drive through direct contact
i think that would be very helpful
because
obviously collaboration is kind of
fundamental to everyone's work in this
industry and beyond it as well because
we need everyone's help and contribution
to really make a difference um i wanted
to ask you besides you know being an
active member of the community i wanted
to ask you a bit kind of what role dev
cam played for you in your career and in
your personal development as well
because obviously this is not your first
time at deaf camp so um could you tell
us a bit about that
um
um i could say that
there are a lot of
presentations that uh were published
that sparked my interest for a certain
area
and um
seeing them and understanding what the
researcher was confronted with when
trying to solve a specific issue
really
paved the way for
the understanding or maybe
help me in a certain direction so
it's a really good starting point if you
want to understand what is
what are the
how can you talk tackle a specific issue
that's really nice to hear and i think
that it probably helps a lot of people
who maybe don't have yet the courage to
kind of speak uh or share stuff publicly
about their work or their interests
and really glad to see that there's a
lot there's been a kind of an uptick a
bigger number of people sharing what
they learn and sharing their journeys
and ensuring their personal worries or
feelings of imposter syndrome that
everyone gets every now and then as much
as
we're incredibly you know passionate and
interested in trying to do our best day
after day um i think this is very
helpful for others um what was it like
for you to kind of speak at def camp for
the first time do you remember
i actually wanted to um
to talk about that um
you know
speaking in public doesn't come easy for
many people certainly for me
but
i don't know what helps is uh that
is this thing that
you had access to a lot of resources
that were open sourced and
you used to learn and you
you now have
access to everything you need to learn
mathematics to learn machine learning to
learn security to learn penetration
testing and renting and you can find a
lot of them
open source and maybe if you offer just
a little bit of perspective
like what you worked on what was hard
for you and how you approached it maybe
someone will find um
well we'll find that more than
interesting i mean actually helpful
and i think it's a
a way to
give it give it forward so to speak
and it's also a good training because um
in these days you don't have it's not
sufficient
to you actually have to talk and to
people and
you you have to express your ideas
because um
you can
whatever you are working at might have a
bigger impact if you do that
in a positive manner
that is so true and thank you for
mentioning all of these things and for
sharing your experience i think that it
matters a lot and the fact that you're
leading by example and showing people
that it doesn't have to be perfect for
you to start you know getting better at
something whether it's research whether
it's developing your skills whether it's
starting to talk about your work in
public as scary and and you know uh as
intimidating as it can be in the
beginning you start to get more
comfortable with it and it just starts
to be you know the deeper you're
connected with a community the easier it
feels because it becomes familiar
territory and it feels comfortable and
you know that you're among people who
want to learn from you uh and that
really changes kind of the mood and
makes you feel more comfortable so it
was such a pleasure to to have you with
us
thank you for kicking off
um def camp 2021 and i just want to
remind everyone that you can connect
with radu on the platform so reach out
find him um you know read his blog posts
and then we can all uh kind of go from
there so thanks again rano i hope you
enjoyed the rest of the conference
thank you very much for your attention
and have a nice day everyone