um
we've heard a lot about what happens
when uh
policies and proper authentication
aren't well thought out
and now we're going to dive a little bit
into the
mindset of attackers and we're gonna
discuss how
oftentimes highly skilled attackers tend
to avoid reinventing the wheel right and
they tend to keep a low profile
by avoiding leaving a trail of binaries
and files behind them
our following speakers argue that this
is why living off the land is still one
of the preferred approaches to security
professionals
um next up we will listen to tiberius
who is a data scientist and machine
learning engineer and alongside him we
welcome andre a technical lead and
security intelligence and engineering at
adobe
they will tell us all about why it's
hard to detect instances when an
attacker is living off the land
but not all hope is lost because they
will also follow up with an in-depth
look at an approach they made they
created to make such detections
gentlemen you have the virtual stage
hello thank you so hello everybody thank
you very much for joining this talk we
are actually really excited to be here
my name is andrey kotayan and together
with my ass and colleague tiberi boris
we're going to have today a short
discussion a project we recently open
source and that we're actually really
fond of so with no further introduction
a supervised machine learning living of
the rank classifier i know it sounds
fancy
okay so a couple of words about us
we are the security intelligence team at
adobe we are a part of adobe security
coordination center
the acc actually handles monitoring
alerting and is the responsible in other
words the security the reactive part of
the security in the house
the purpose of the security intelligence
team is to do data science research in
the security field
so we mostly focus on reactive security
as the acc and that basically means
identifying threats that cannot be
detected via conventional ways
in other words
we use the logs and the security data we
collect from adobe assets and we try to
find anomalies and of course bad stuff
now we really like sharing our work even
outside of adobe and we have quite a
couple of open source projects
presentation and blogs and we're
actually going to touch base
basis on some of those later in this
talk
okay so for a short intro like what's
leaving over the land so
easily put living of the land means
doing your job with what you have at
your disposal but let's be honest here
this is not the 13th 14th centuries
anymore right those are not the middle
ages and and the truth is what we have
at our disposal is more than enough
now living of the land is not a brand
new concept living after land attacks
persistence lateral moves however you
want to call them have been recorded and
reported for a while since the beginning
of the century at least
all the big kids are doing it attackers
apt groups fantastic purposes and so on
now what's really interesting about
those type of attacks is the fact the
footprint they leave it's really really
really
reduced and the reason is that why is
that because basically you don't have
new binaries you're trying to blend in
and you already have everything you need
at your disposal there
now
the truth is between a security
professional if you have cash python
powershell
curacao whatever you wonder what more do
you actually need on that box
plus in the last cases i i looked like
netcat we became a default admin to run
most of the linux installers there
so
leaving of the lens refers to attack
scenarios where multiple segments parts
of the attack itself are being delivered
with what you already have on the
compromise box on the box you are on
right so no external malicious or
especially crafted tools or malware for
that
for that matter
okay and
again the whole magic is that what you
need is already there and there are some
people who did an awesome job
documenting this right and i'm sure that
are actually really really familiar with
those two links that are there they're
basically leaving off the land binaries
with example documented and a lot of
examples do a lot of stuff right
so for example you need to download
something and you do not know what to
use well go to the link and you're going
to find quite a couple of ways to do
your your job you need to abuse a
religion buyer to execute some code
again go to the link and you're going to
find a couple of ways of doing that you
want to escape a text editor and become
root or whatever user is there again go
to the link and you'll find a really
nice example
now of course
things aren't always so straightforward
right but the fact that what you need is
already there it's a great starting
point
a clear advantage of using on-prem stuff
like
scripting your way in is the fact that
you blend in you are one with the
environment you are the administrator
there right and you can behave like one
maybe you're good enough to put also a
couple of security patches in place
right like stop other attackers from
compromising your already compromised
box and i'm sure all of you actually
heard a story about those kind of
scenarios
anyway uh let's get a little bit serious
so what we want to talk today about
me as a security expert i handled quite
a few couple of incidents and security
investigations in in my in my time so
almost every time i learned something
new something that evaded some of the
measures in place something which on its
own would have bypassed my security
bypass my security mindset right
uh also we at adobe work with petabytes
of data so that's definitely more than
what a couple of dozen of people are
able to parse
and the question is how can i make sure
that what i'm
detecting is everything that's happening
and that nothing is actually bypassing
my security stack
and
the honest answer is i cannot but i can
give it my best try i can and i can
always think outside of the box and
actually that's what this project is
about thinking outside of the box
okay so what we've done we took
thousands of examples of malicious
commands we did some voodoo magic around
them and then we built a classifier
whose entire purpose is is to tell me if
a piece of string looks like
it might be a thread and why
and as you can see really fast our tool
is actually pretty simple to use you
paste it you passed it a command and
it's basically going to generate some
text some meta information and where the
classifier is going to classify the data
right
pretty straightforward regarding the the
environments we're targeting so the
leaving of the lamp project actually
comes with two models a linux one and a
windows one currently the performance of
the windows one doesn't make it qualify
for production greatly and we estimate
we're actually going to have a stable
model
somewhere the
next release the end of this year but
the linux one is actually really similar
with what you're using in our
infrastructure in production targeting
adobe data
so uh let us actually talk really fast
about the magic behind the project
now
we basically can speed the project in
three components data set feature
extraction and machine learning so what
i'm going to tackle today is actually
the feature extraction antivirus is
going to speak more about the
data set and the machine learning part
and i previously said that
the magic behind this project that are
actually the tags
it's all about the text the training
data is critical but the magic is in the
text and my classifier is going to be as
good as my tags are and of course as my
data set is
so what kind of tags we actually
generate
right anything that actually crosses my
mind there a lot so let's not speak
about tags and commands let's actually
speak about myself what can i say about
myself
i can say i'm a male
somewhere in my early mid 30s
i wear glasses i'm starting to get a
little bald here and things like that so
more or less things like that i want to
say about my commands as well
so what can kind of tags i generate
well i care about binaries that are
executed i care about the paths from
where they are executed i care if i saw
that kind of
string in the past
i care with who it communicates if it
communicates with public with internal
ips with localhost i care about keywords
i especially care about those little
dashes that appear there in the commands
in the parameters and i especially care
about patterns and good patterns are
actually game changers in this project
okay so
what i'm going to i'm going to go
through all those uh
special tags we're generating and go a
little deep inside them and try to get
you to understand what's actually
happening there
so
what do we actually mean by binary tags
well the concept actually pretty simple
i'm checking if a particular command
binary executable netcat let's say nc
right if that is a part of the command
itself so i basically made a list of the
most interesting binaries from an
operational security perspective and
every time i analyze a command i check
if that command is actually a part of
the string i'm investigating
if they are we basically add the text to
that event just saying commanded the
command itself so historically when i
actually started to build this project
those were the first feature we built
our initial classifier one
for our example today actually took a
standard python interactive shell
command and i'm pretty sure everybody's
familiar with it it's it's uh really
common right what we did we basically
split it into words and uh
then we check if that command python 3
is actually present in the list of the
keywords that was generated there that's
that's what what we did now the code is
pretty uh the logic on the code on the
slide is the same as the code we have in
the project but the code in the project
is a little more complex but again it's
basically doing the same thing
now the same goes for keywords uh
basically keywords represent a list of
interesting keywords parameters we
actually identified during our research
phase so for for everything we thought
it might have a security implication we
created a list and we do the same check
and as you can see it's pretty
straightforward
now
it doesn't mean that this solution is
not prone to false positives you can
have binaries with different names or
you can have some keywords parameters
that have different impact and different
commands
if you guys are linux
fellows you know that's actually true
but this is not a problem because we
generate so many other tags uh text that
might have a negative impact on the
classification itself can be helped by
the other tags that were generated so
again the magic it's in the text
now
all the static information we're
presenting on the feature extraction
part uh of uh are actually in a python
file called constant pi
so there is half of the magic of this
project so basically the entire security
subject matter expert security knowledge
that we apply to this project and we
made the supervised implementation is
basically in that file you can modify
the constant pi file at any time you can
esta remove stuff repair stuff and so on
and those tags are going to reflect
directly in your results
now it might be it might get ignored by
the machine learning component until the
model is going to be retraced
okay
we're doing the same thing for pad right
we made a list of interesting paths for
different linux processes binaries
interesting that the directories and we
check if those paths are present in the
command line itself straightforward
similar to the previous one okay so this
is useful because it can highlight
interesting activities like since the
files binaries running from wrong
locations so
interesting activities and so on
again all those elements used to
generate tags are present in the
constant.pi file and the list can can be
updated on the fly
so
the development of this project was some
sort of a modular approach like we
initially started with interesting
binaries and keywords we built a
classifier we tested the classifier and
we were disappointed
so next we added an interesting patch
and we did the same again like built a
classifier tested the classifier one
slightly better but still disappointing
and then we added networking information
so basically what the networking
component does is to search if there is
an ip information present in the command
itself right and mark it as public
private localhost whatever
type it is
now
uh for you guys who are actually using
endpoints to collect your data you know
that sometimes the ip itself information
is not going to be present in the
command especially if you have a domain
there right but there is a high chance
that uh
you have another field in the event
generator that contains that uh ip
information so what we do we concatenate
our command with ip information and then
we apply the model now imagine you have
two reverse ssh tunnels in your
infrastructure
uh one is going towards a public ip one
is going towards a private ip so which
one would you investigate first which
one most likely is not an operational
activity right
so basically we try to
enhance the project with the same
security
mindset that
we apply in our work by adding all kinds
of different tags to it
now the networking part had actually a
significant impact in the accuracy of
the classifier
but this was still not good enough sorry
something went slightly wrong here
okay cool
so um
the last component actually who had the
major impact uh in in our uh classifier
was the rage expire right so
the question was what other feature we
can extract and of course the simple
answer was regex so after tagging data
with commands keywords paths network
information we still didn't reach a
production radio accuracy
so the question was what we can do
better and again the answer was regex
uh now
historically i've been working on
content creation alerts notables rules
development and i know that rejects can
generate usually two main problems
uh it can be too strict and it can
ignore interesting stuff or it can be
too broad and that actually might create
a large number for false positives
so
what we actually did well we went with
the second approach to with broad
regexes and
the chance of lots so false positive
but we created many rejected hundreds of
regresses so the idea was to catch as
many features as possible just as a pti
spawn netcat and map netcat flags and
netflix and whatever flags you want
there right and then take all the data
will be generated put it through a
classifier and let the classifier decide
what's malicious or not like what tags
and what pair of tag is going to
turn red
so even if we have a lot of
potentially low confidence tags because
of the regex and again we have many of
them
the regex tags added more and more
context and the machine learning
component behave better and better
now from a technical perspective we
encounter one major problem
the feature extraction component became
really slow
so we switched from regex to regex to
pr2 from google implementation and from
a series execution like one registered
attempt to parallel execution where
actually have sets of projects in
parallel with pipes between them and try
to get the groups from there
and this actually reduced the
computational time almost uh eight times
we had another bug last week which
identified if we have actually multiple
regexes which uh overlap and they are
they are in the same line the same group
they are going to suppress one another
so we did the last rebalance of the
regex data set then again that actually
increased the overall confidence of the
model now
the same goes for the regex all the
information is present in the constant
pi file and anyone can add trajectories
but in order for them to
provide context for the machine learning
model you need to retrain the model so
some of you might need this project just
for the tagging system antivirus is
going to do a great physique about that
right
so you're going to need it for data set
creation analysis rpas implementation or
whatever you actually want and any
modification you're going to do the
constant pi file it's going to reflect
right away in your results but the model
might ignore new tags or might have a
different results
uh depending on how we actually enhance
the tags right because the mentality
behind the text has changed and the
model might behave differently right now
so for the classification part itself
you need to retrain the model
okay so now we're actually going to pass
it to the very who's going to go a
little deeper in the data set and model
part of this project tiberius take it
away
in here
we are going to start talking about data
set and the machine learning model that
we are using in our approach
and i'm going to start by saying that
probably the most important thing about
our machine learning approach is that we
are using supervised algorithms now
these algorithms actually require
label training data and the major
problem is that a large-scale living of
the land data set is really hard to find
so we struggle with this and in the end
we actually had to build our own data
set
almost from scratch
in order to create our system
now the leaving of the lane classifier
is open source and we do provide the
system with pre-trained models
um but we are unable to share the data
set so if you want to create a custom
model
this is no problem because you can
actually do the same steps that we did
and um it's not that hard it just
requires some minor work and a little
bit of effort but it's going to be worth
it because you would be building a model
that is you know suitable for your own
data
so how we got the data set
we started by collecting the
some leaving of the land examples from
the sources that andre mentioned earlier
in the presentation and we got somewhere
around 1600 examples of malicious living
of the land commands now we filtered
them out
we removed something you know command
lines that were a little bit ambiguous
so we wouldn't confuse the model and
then we added to this data set another
7.9 million examples of benign command
lines which were actually you know
extracted from
logging our infrastructure for a couple
of weeks removing duplicates
and you know filter on filtering out
some of the stuff that
wasn't really relevant
now we got a really skewed data set the
ratio between negative examples and
positive examples is somewhere around
0.02
but that's actually okay because this
way we hope to reduce the number of
faults positive during runtime for our
model
now you can imagine that if you are i
mean if you go with um
i know balanced data set and you get a
false positive rate of i don't know two
percent
you have an infrastructure and you are
logging uh what a hundred thousand
command lines per per hour you'd
actually generally be generating 2 000
you know false positives every hour
which somebody would have to go over
filter out and establish if that's good
or bad
so instead i mean by doing so we
actually got a model that is really is
not that paranoid and is really reliable
so when it says that something is uh is
malicious it's worth investigating we
actually have it into production and we
only generate like four to six um
you know
detections per day uh some of them
actually being the results of different
penetration tests uh
which are carried out by our team so
they are not all false positives
so to talk a little bit about the model
we have 7.9 million examples
we after going to the you know tagging
strategy and adding the tags we actually
added 7.5 million
total tags to the data set and you can
imagine that some of the command lines
actually
have multiple labels assigned to them
uh while others don't have any con don't
have any tags assigned to them because
they don't know present anything
interesting from the security point of
view
and the number of unique tags is
500. now this is really good because we
have a lot of
training data and only i mean the
feature space is somewhere around 500
which is uh actually is really good in
reducing data sparsity and you know
preventing the classifier from
overheating the training data you know
generalizing better on previous glancing
data so if we go to the next slide
we are going to talk a little bit about
the algorithms that we
we tested
so we did something which is called
fivefold validation
um this means that we
took the training data we split it into
five folds that actually try to preserve
the same uh distribution
between the negative and positive
examples
and we test train the classifier five
times
using every combination of four folds
and then with each time we tested on the
fifth fold which was kept aside
so we rotated it through them and we
computed the
the mean the standard deviation and the
training time for a single fold for free
classifiers a random forest
an svm and a logistic regressor
now
best results we got using the random
forest and the sdm uh 0.95
there's a smaller standard deviation for
the random forest than for the svm which
is also good and also it's a much
smaller training time it's only 18
minutes compared to 3.5 hours now there
are two important aspects about the
about the classifier so the random
forest was the only classifier which was
able to work with a sparse feature set
which meant that we didn't have to
convert
the
input features into
a dense matrix and this greatly reduced
the memory footprint required to train
the model and the svm the results
reported for dsem are
reported after we
actually applied something called the
intel patch
which made it possible to train the svm
from scikit-learn on multiple threads at
the same time
and we got to 3.5 hours per fold
otherwise
we i mean we virtually weren't able to
train it because it took a
prohibitively amount of time to to to do
a single fold
on the next slide we are going to talk
about one more tag that andre left out
so
we have to mention that while we do rely
on the classifier to establish if a new
example is good or bad
we felt that i mean it
won't be
good to miss things that we know for
sure that are bad they resemble
something that's inside our
data set and it has been labeled
malicious so created a special tag for
this the tag is called looks like
non-lol
and what it does it overrides the
decision of the classifier for examples
that
were labeled as good
but
they resemble something that is bad in
our data set
so in order to generate the tag
um
[Music]
we test every command uh we test a new
command against all the commands inside
our data set and we do a type of fuzzy
comparison so it's not the exact string
matching and there are two obvious
options or the obvious option would be
to use leverage time distance to measure
this but this is very com the level
strength is really complex it's a it has
a n square complexity it runs really
slow and there are many commands that we
have to test against so instead of doing
that we use a different score here a
different my
score function which is called blue
scoring
blue scoring has been previously used in
machine translation
to establish if a computer-generated
sentence
resembles the sentences that are
translated by humans
and
it it's very fast
and what it does is it returns a score
of zero if two examples have nothing in
common two sentences or two command
lines in our case and it returns of a
score of one if they are identical and
everything in between depending on how
different they are
so after playing with the examples in
our data set a little bit we actually
set the threshold of 0.7 so when we do
the test if a new command line
it's you know
resembles something or normal malicious
data set with a score higher than 0.7 we
assign this tag and we override the
decision of the classifier directly you
know setting the command line as being
leaving of the lender bad
on the next slide we'll be talking about
um how you can install lol so there are
two simple options the first one is uh
the easy peep installation one
you just do a pip install lc and it's
going to install
the package as well as train
along with pre-trained models on your
platform can be a virtual environment or
it can be
the global python installation it
doesn't matter the second option
you can clone the repository just create
a virtual environment
activate it and install the requirements
and you have a working installation of
living of the land now the advantage of
doing this is that
by doing so you'll be able to create
your own model if you want to not to
rely on the default ones that we are
deliver providing with the system you
can build your own date that you can
build your own data set and train the
classifier on on it
on the next slide we'll be talking about
how we can uh use the living of the land
classifier so it's pretty easy
we have an api for python we just have
the import the main class and the
platform type for the api from the api
the next step is to create a new
instance where you can specify if you
are targeting linux or windows binaries
command lines
as andre said
the windows model is not really stable
it's not production ready but the new
one works pretty well however we do
provide both models so you can i mean
you have a fully functional living on
the line classify on your system
next you need to get your data and then
you can apply
lol on the commands now you can apply it
on a single command or you can apply it
on a list of commands if you select a
list of commands it's going to do
multi-processing and it's going to
optimize the the way they are
labeled and
um
put to the classifier so it's going to
be much faster
if you have a lot of command lines just
use the batch version and it will do
everything for you
regardless of what you are going to get
two things you are going to get the
classification
and the tags
the tags are the ones that are
represented earlier so you have access
to them
you can use it on
or to do your
own analytics or do some searches with
them
whatever you want to do and the
classification is almost binary so we
have uh the good and bad labels which
are pretty obvious and you also have the
neutral label which we are going to talk
about it during the demo
so
let me just share my screen for a moment
okay
can you can you see my screen
okay perfect
so what i did was create a virtual
environment just installed the jupyter
notebook because it's much easier to do
the show and tell on it
and i'm going to use the package
installation i'm going to run this
command over here it's going to go
pretty fast because it's already cached
on my system
i'm going to create a new instance that
handles linux command lines
and after this
we're actually going to run the leaving
of the line classifier on multiple
commands one at a time so we can easily
read the results
i'm going to do this really fast
okay so
what happened it took the command line
it tried to describe it with tags so you
see that it assigned the ip loop back
here because you have the loopback ip of
course
um
it so it also saw a public ip here the
it contains ssh it has the minus r
keyword and there's also this is the
result of a regular expression that was
triggered which
you know targets ssh with minus r
together all together right
it did this for all the commands so this
one has sudo which install
uh ssh minus d and it also looks like a
non-ripping of the land command because
it resembles something in our data set
this one is pretty interesting
so you're going to see that this apt-get
install python tray was python 3 was
labeled as neutral
so this is because we actually assigned
less than five tags on this command line
and when this happens the classifier
doesn't have enough text to rely on to
make a good decision so we just
remove all the tags enable the example
as being neutral now this is normal if
you have small command lines and common
command lines that you are using on a
daily basis
but if you have a really long string and
you know it gets labeled as neutral it
might indicate that you are dealing with
something obfuscated maybe
and that's why we weren't able to
extract any text from it and you might
want to look into this we do have
another project that targets obfuscation
uh but will not be presented yet here
so most of them have the
looks like known lol
tag
which means that the classifier the
decision of the classifier was overrated
by this flag but if we scroll down we
are also going to have a lot of commands
that were labeled as being bad
but the classifier has never seen them
before so they don't resemble anything
in our training set
but again they were labeled pretty
pretty good
um
two more things about um
about this uh
[Music]
utility so
if you feel lucky you can actually
change the constants that define the
keywords and the command lines and the
paths that we are targeting so there's a
file which is called constants.pi it's
in the main distribution of the
application
you can see here the list of linux
commands the interesting linux paths
the keywords that we are looking for
and there's also this really large
variable here with regular expression
i'm going to get back this one on the
bottom of the
source you're going to see the same for
windows commands
now
those regular expressions you cannot
edit them in place it's impossible
believe me i tried but we do have
another utility here
well you can actually set or i mean
introduce one regular expression at a
time
set the label for it and after you
define all of them it's going to pack
uh make the uh the to pack all the
regular expressions and make them run in
parallel so they would be really really
fast
i guess this is the my poc
i'm gonna
get that give back control to andre so
we can speak about
how you can actually use the lifting of
the line classifier
okay this is this is not you are not
sharing the right screen i guess
so i'm going to start speaking anyway
so you can use it as a standalone tool
um you can integrate it with an er
solution or go over some you know cm
logs and label command lines as being
good or bad
you can use the text for analytics as i
said before
but
the way we use it sometimes it's within
a project a larger project which is
called one-stop anomaly shop osas
this is a previously open source project
um that i mean while you know living of
the land actually looks at at every
command line on its own without any
context what those does
it is able to
take into account multiple
multiple features that describe you know
the context in which that command line
was run so it looks at process names
users
of environment variables and many many
other things
the on the next slide we have the
architecture for oss is pretty
straightforward so it just requires a
data source which can be a csv or a json
data source or it can you know come from
splunk elasticsearch anything you want
and then there's the processing pipeline
and this process processing pipeline is
fully configurable
and
it kind of it kind of applies the same
strategy as the leaving of the land
classifier and it tries to describe
every event with labels
and it's going to
handle numeric labels uh based on the
mean and standard deviation of a value
so it might add so if you are you say
you input cpu usage or memory usage you
might get labels such as uh extremely
large cpu usage or normal cpu usage or
on previously unseen cpu usage
it does the same thing for
multinomial fields which are text fields
that um you know don't take an infinite
number of values uh such as
you know usernames or process names and
you're going to get labels such as rare
user rare process and so on
and you can also apply the living of the
land it can combine any types of fields
between them so it's it might you might
say you want to combine the parent
process with the command line or the the
parent process the username and it's
going to say rare parent process user
combination you get this label as well
so it also
you you might you have the option to
apply the living of the line classifier
on any
text field
obviously you want to run it for command
lines not for no plain text or source
code or anything else because it's not
going to work as expected
when you do that you are actually going
to get the binary decision of the
classifier in the text that also is
generated generating as well as all the
other tags that were you that are used
to describe the process um
by the leaving of the line classifier
and finally oss is going to do an on my
detection it has the option to do
unsupervised anomaly detection with
using using the different algorithms we
support auto encoder local outlier
factor statistical engram and frequent
items and mining and you also have the
option to do supervised analytic
detection
using any supervised classifier which is
present in scikit-learn you can
configure it in the um
in the pipeline but you are going to
provide to your you are going to be
forced to provide training data to it uh
which means that you need to add another
label another column to your data set
which is going to say if an example is
good or bad
and you can train the classifier this
way
well i guess that's it we
thank you everybody for joining us
thank you so much for your demo it was
really exciting to watch it live
and i love the name you gave to some of
those tags i'm also stealing your regex
joke i hope you don't mind
i mean you open source the software
might as well open source the joke
i'm i'm a bit curious have you ever
tested your software against any
honeypots or against any real commands
coming from actual attacks
yes so we have used it also
for internal adobe data
we have a flavor of this model that's
targeting inside adobe data and we're
using adobe
incident data in it and we have the
technical couple of uh
tests from penetration testers from our
purple team and also something regarding
internal incidents
i cannot go more in detail than that but
yeah
awesome um i was wondering and you sort
of uh also segued into my other question
is there anything interesting that
you've left out of your presentation not
knowing whether you'd have enough time
to develop into it
uh yeah of course i guess the windows
model uh so the windows mod we actually
did have a lot of work on it we have a
lot of text we generated
uh the problem is the data set we're
working on it's not
big enough to have a stable model
so
i know most likely some they will come
back again having also the windows model
apparently but for the time being if
anybody actually needs to tag windows
data with this platform it should do the
trick
have you considered doing a sort of call
for participation in the open source
community since you open source the tool
it would be a great time to also say
folks let's gather some data together
especially if you're using this
especially if you're using it you know
against real commands coming from places
where commands usually come from
well
this is one of the main reasons we're
actually doing this talk because we do
want to
get some traction and uh get people
working with us so hika if you guys try
the model and it fails because things
fails in your life as i mentioned in my
previous slides uh
just send us the command like a change
format you don't have to have the actual
indicators in it and we'll try to make
it to fit the model or we can work
together to do that
and that's actually we're sharing the
github link there because we really
wanted back to check it out and if you
like it please give us a start
i think we should uh use this as one of
the models for the conference things
failed but gather the data
yeah that's life
thank you very much andre thank you
um
for the presentation and the awesome
demo and i really hope you get a lot of
traction on your github i'm a huge uh
cheerleader for the open source
community and for collaboration that
spans not countries but even continents
and if you get commands in languages
which the project doesn't know about yet
that's going to be an even better
challenge to tackle
thank you
thank you thank you