next we have a panel that's focused on
women in cyber security about a month
ago i wrote a piece about
our inability to assess the risk of
potential cyber security incidents
and
i looked at some of the psychological
factors and cognitive biases that come
into play
and one of the things that i've learned
was that teams that are more diverse
tend to be better at um assessing risk
and here at deaf camp one of the goals
is to help create a diverse and um
supportive community and if you are here
with us today i'm sure that this is
something that you're thinking a lot
about
we'll hear more about ways to um
encourage diverse voices and mer make
our community more inclusive during the
next panel moderated by valentin mere
yes hi i'm here
okay happy to see you did i pronounce
your name all right
yeah
fantastic um
why is it um
important to you to talk about this
topic why do you think we should spend
more time reflecting on making women uh
more powerful within the cyber security
community
oh that's a tough question but i know
uh i think it's important to um
more to put women forwards um asking
tough cyber security questions and and
just tackling
cyber security challenges with women on
the front because
of representation
um i think it can inspire some younger
generations to
strive for these roles
not only women but just show more
diverse um
yeah diverse people that actually do
some hard work in cyber security and not
just
be there to be some kind of uh
token uh person on a poster or something
that's uh i think that that's more what
i would say about this
um i have
hopes that uh it will change that the
the ratios will change because i've
already seen a lot of teenage girls
highly interested in cyber security so
i'm i'm confident that in a couple of
years we won't need this anymore
as much as we do now
um but in the meantime we should indeed
put women forward and ask the the tough
questions and show that women and
other diverse communities can also do
some hard cyber security i was
just wanting to ask you this specific
thing uh because you mentioned teenagers
how were things when you grew up and
whether
the number of women that had jobs in
science technology medicine economics um
was something that
influenced you
in choosing a career in in this field
um
so when i go when i wasn't in high
school uh being
um
a gamer
um i was the only
girl
in the circles
um
it was uh yeah yeah it was for guys for
for
young for young white guys with glasses
that was uh
those computers that that's what it was
for
um but i think tv helps me a lot some
sci-fi series actually that showed women
as scientists and stuff that helped a
lot um
so that's why i think that
representation is
is just a big motivator for
young girls
to have someone that they can look up to
even if it's not a real person for me it
was uh samantha carter in uh stargate
sg1 but uh
for others it may be uh the the next uh
ceo of avast that's um
yeah
yeah i think it's it's really important
to see that there are people like you
who are doing a great job and you just
don't have to be alone in in all this
and we talk a lot here in in romania
about having systems that help foster
talents that are diverse and
in order to to grow and be a
professional it helps a lot if you're
surrounded by people who who support you
um so that's it from my part please um
enjoy this panel and hopefully i'm going
to write down
a few wonderful ideas that um
everyone
could apply to to make this this
community better
uh
break a leg
thanks um i'll take over from here and i
want to see people's faces so just
changing my view
um so welcome to this panel um the
ladies and cyber security panel uh my
name is valentin as uh you've been
introduced me already as well
i'll be the host of this panel and we'll
be diving into some
some tough questions about the industry
and have some awesome ladies that will
answer them and give their own insights
um we can do a round of introductions
first in a sec and i'll leave everyone
to introduce themselves because they are
the the best able to do that um and if
the audience wants to pitch in at any
moment with questions feel free to do so
in the chat and i'll try to monitor the
chat and answer these questions or at
least ask the questions to the panelists
um so without further ado let's go right
into it
um so i'll start with uh gratz graziella
am i pronouncing this right
yes yes it is very well dracula or you
can call me grace it's much easier for
non-italian or romanian speakers
hi ladies
i'm pleased to be part of this channel
and hi everybody
words about myself
i'm the the president of isaac armenia
chapter for the last five years
um it was a a coincidence um taking um
this disposition but this
led me to a fantastic journey
or an unexpected journey until now
in parallel uh
i have
some
sessions in academic economic studies
where i'm not
an associate teacher
and i'm trying to
share some knowledge around the ipod at
least
an introduction
some basic information about this
and in my day-to-day uh job
or my day-to-day life
i am a business advice and compliance
officer
in a pharma industry um
and i'm a part of the leadership team
and of course uh i think that after the
job i have
is i'm a mother of a toddler three years
old and uh it is funny and exhausting in
the same time
this is about me
thank you it sounds like you have a lot
to do on your plate yes yes true it
feels like this
um next i have lubika if i'm pronouncing
this right
yeah you did it great thank you
greetings from skopje
i'm lubitsa pendaroska privacy and data
protection expert and consultant
currently i'm leading women for cyber
north macedonia chapter which is part of
one of the national chapters of women
for cyber foundation from brussels
which was founded directly by the
european cyber security organization
what i'm doing during my uh more than 14
years of expertise in data protection
and privacy and in the recent few years
in the field of empowering women in
cyber security in different areas
is first of all to raise the awareness
is the key question seen from my side
both for the society and for the
individuals as well and also uh to lead
as an example
following my personal motto inspire and
let yourself be inspired
that's why i will raise here one
question at the beginning not a question
but uh uh thought to think about uh and
maybe to to talk about more later in our
discussion uh related to different kind
of mentorship programs i'm also a mentor
right now
to some few young girls in the field of
cyber security different areas of cyber
security but also the importance of role
models
because when i find very
important and at the same time uh in a
way in a crisis
during this time is the exact role
models female role models which are
going to to serve as a direction a kind
of direction to all the girls and young
women who want to start their careers in
cyber security or where uh or also to
those who want to go deeper
and
especially to those which want to get
higher on the scale because we know
although the percentage of women of
women in cyber security is around
depending on
on the statistics and the analysis but
around 22 to 25
the decision-making and executive
positions and cyber security leaded by
women are even lower around 80 percent
in uh for instance in the european union
countries and that's why
i i'm dedicating my activities
mostly on how to inspire women to see
what are the benefits for them
uh joining the cyber security instead of
only work with society and companies to
see the benefits from having more women
women on cyber security stage because
first of all we need to inspire women
themselves
as someone mentioned uh
to portray differently uh someone
working in cyber security instead of
being a male a boy or a man uh in front
of with glasses with us in front working
in front of something very boring and
working in front of several screens
that's it from me at the beginning
thanks
raising uh the right questions i think
um thank you
next i have dimitro
yes hello
um i'm really happy to be part of this
panel with these amazing professionals i
look up to
my experience in cyber security started
a bit over six years ago
i worked my way through the trenches
from working in stock to building
security services from scratch
and ended up securing uh stacks with the
latest technology
um my current role is that of the threat
hunter at crowdstrike i work in the
endpoint content endpoint platform
content department of crowdstrike and my
main role is to
follow and stop as fast as i can any
attackers adversaries that
target linux based infrastructures
and
switching my focus again to containers
as well
um as everyone has stated i do believe
that it is important for women
and not only women for everyone
to
understand and believe that with hard
work and
with dedication and passion for this
industry
anyone can make it um i think i'm a
pretty good example of that because i my
ba is in political sciences so i
basically had to work from scratch to
where i am
so i really hope that um
my example will um
will encourage
young ladies or not only that are
thinking about switching to cyber
security to do so
that's um a very noble goal i when um
so i host this community in the
netherlands of women in cyber security
and we have so many
um women but also just
random people who come from different
backgrounds we also have someone in
political sciences uh coincidentally um
and they are they feel so insecure that
that they will never make it into the
field that it's really nice to see
other ladies who come from uh completely
different opposite even opposite
backgrounds uh one of my top hacker
friends is from marketing of all places
and um yeah so it's really nice to see
that
um i think we're missing the last plan
speaker
so
andrada you can
introduce yourself as well yeah um i'm
happy to step in i'm andrada i'm a
technology journalist um i was born in
transylvania but moved here to bucharest
15 years ago
i think um i'm super excited to be
talking about women in security because
i think i've written four or five
stories um on this topic so far and i do
feel that um
in romania we are fortunate to have um
to be i think the second eu country when
it comes to the number the percentage of
women who are employed in technology um
i'm a technology journalist and when i
started there were only men covering
technology in romania
and things were a little bit different i
was called harry potter
because i wear glasses and no one
thought that i could do this job
but
i did it um i'm a former night science
journalism fellow at mit i work for
radio station here in bucharest and i
try to to talk a lot about women in
technology with men
because i feel that uh they should be
part of the change and um
if we are meeting and talking about this
issue is one thing but if we try to
involve them then i think the war
uh can be
run
yeah that's true it's not a war it's a
cooperative game right so we should all
work together yeah
that's
better thank you
but um yeah i agree so thank you for uh
for introducing yourselves uh i'll just
then dive right into the questions
um so the questions themselves concern
some cyber security challenges in
general feel free to give your input
a technical input or social input
anything you think that that fits
the answer so the first question
um
so we know that the world is changing
and everything is becoming so
digitalized i mean it's it's or it
already is in a lot of countries that
you cannot do anything if the internet
is down
um so cyber threats and risks are
increasing and just exponentially
um for you what is the biggest security
challenge you're actively tackling in
your job or in your hobby life and um
how what what advice would you give
other companies who face some of these
issues so i'll start in the order of the
introduction introductions and
you can have these discussions how you
want um
but um i'll ask gretzella
to start me first thank you
um
i would um i would use uh different
sources for um what are responding to
the question because um as i mentioned
in my real life i'm more close to the
business and you know those kind of very
high um
things like risk management and ethics
and role modelling and
my my job is not really related to the
security part however
i'm fortunate being a part of the
association of isaka and
i've been involved in different working
groups and uh initiatives uh i feel uh i
feel um i'm part of this universe um i'm
i'm passionate about it
and um i would go anyhow i would go for
the the human part is not
from the technical perspective it is
from many perspectives um that means um
what i want to say
humans are considered as being the
strongest link and the weakest link in
the same time of organizations
and um
taking this into consideration we can
much more easily understand that um
okay defensive we all discuss about
cyber trades and we need to build our
defense in order to own the future for
external any external um challenge but
in the same time the report uh shows us
that um there are a lot of
miscommunications or not a lot of gaps
internally and most of them are related
to human errors
so with this i would i would make the
connection to um to the education of
people both professionally and
personally and this led us to all the
reports that show us
the needs
which is
reported for
cyber security or information security
specialist at this moment and this need
hasn't been um
met by the available specialists at the
moment there are a lot of reports here
and statistics in this regards and this
leads me to
um the idea of
we are finding ourselves in a situation
when
communication awareness and you know
that kind of limited training our
organization are providing for them for
you so for the employees
is not sufficient anymore
then we need a culture for um cyber
security and culture
means a lot of things and
i don't know whether we we shall find
some time to discuss about this but it
is a practical and philosophical
topic in the same time because it is
related to role modeling which is
related to trust it is related to
knowledge it is related to education
um it is related to the passion of
people and um
many other things so um i i made some
links
just pointing out different topics
i'm passionate passionate about it about
them and
yeah we can develop them or build them
later on on
depending on the time
yeah it's it's funny that you mentioned
um
the human error um i think communication
between different fields also
um
what i mean to say so you have all these
technical people but you have also the
management and you have the c-level
people and you have the strategist and
they all have to communicate to each
other with each other and they don't
necessarily know how to especially since
cyber security is a field that involves
everybody
um
i think that's also part of the human
error that that we were not necessarily
taught how to communicate on those
different levels
so
maybe sometimes how to collaborate with
the others um among our peers or in the
same profession or in between the
professions
that's true
anyone else wants to um go at it feel
free to respond
yeah i can i will proceed i absolutely
agree with graziella uh and uh
when i was
when i was thinking about how to how
actually uh what
should be my input here
uh in order and a way to inspire i
recently came to the idea a few days ago
while i was doing a zoom meeting test
preparing for some other meeting it came
in my uh it came in my view uh one
sentence uh they are saying they are
more than meetings and they say discover
how you can elevate the way you work by
combining webinars chat and meetings
so actually what i find in the most
challenging cyber security issue or
concern especially having in mind the
recent
uh
almost two years during the pandemic
time is actually spending too much time
online both privately and especially
professionally which means that
almost in one step through the night
we when i say we i mean as a human
beings but also accompanies institutions
and other legal entities
need to transform absolutely the way
they work the way they approach the
things and the way they are making
decisions and the way they are doing the
task done test done
which means uh it came to my mind that
uh what we need is actually in line with
what graziella said uh we need a kind of
i'm talking since i'm uh privacy and
data protection expert i tried to
concentrate more on more on building uh
privacy and data protection culture
not only for individuals themselves as
being someone in the online environment
but also for companies as well but then
i tried to figure it out
how to make companies to see building
privacy cultures uh privacy culture
championing data
to see championing data privacy not only
as the right thing to do and not only in
a way to be in line with all those legal
and other requirements but how to
present it in a great way to grow their
business because in that case we'll have
a kind of win-win situation which means
uh in the recent months i was working
and doing some trainings with companies
in order to show in practice
to companies and other entities what is
the economic value associated with the
company's privacy investment
and how to motivate them the companies
to do the right things when it comes to
data collection and especially to data
transfers
and i will share here a few points as a
kind of advice and help
and a motivation for companies in order
to
improve their privacy programs because
we know that nowadays even nowadays uh
although the pandemic is not uh
is still a very a large part of our
daily lives but
we are still not fully in line with uh
what we uh we were prior to the pandemic
i'll mention few just
benefits
as i said most often companies are
privacy correct and compliant is a way
to avoid any kind of risks or threats
but what about tangible business
benefits the companies recognize from
continuing investing in different kind
of tools and programs
way beyond harmonizing with those
just to mention few of them
first of all they will gain a
competitive advantage second they will
optimize a personal or
personal data usage
then they will face with less data
breach cases
less costly data breaches and shorter
system stops
also they will achieve a higher
operational efficiency and for instance
if they
if they are in
goods and services business uh they will
shorter sales delays or shorter service
service deliver
so i will stop here with my um
kind of advices uh and i would say
strong recommendations related to uh one
of cyber security challenges of nowadays
which i see is very important
and i purposely not concentrated on
women in cyber security nowadays
in the first
related to first question because uh i
wanted to offer something which would be
at the same time beneficial to each
individual as a human being no matter
no matter the fact whether it is uh male
uh male or female uh person uh and also
to help companies to see the benefits so
at the end uh that will be beneficial
for for the whole mankind
thanks
well thank you i'm sure a lot of people
would benefit from from this wisdom a
lot of companies especially
um
anyone else wants to pitch in uh yeah
so just to build upon uh what the
gratial and lubicas said um any security
infrastructure is
as strong as its weakest link being it a
human
end user or sysadmin that configures uh
the infrastructure
or the i.t hygiene and the risks and
vulnerabilities that company accepts
when it comes to
exposure to threats
so
i believe that
in my personal bubble in my field uh the
biggest security challenge building on
top of that is
building uh or protecting
um infrastructures as i mentioned before
that run on uh stacks that run on
microservices on containers on top of
linux and then taking into consideration
um also that orchestrators might bring
liabilities and risks and credentials
that could be exposed
so uh yeah a defense in depth uh that
would not interfere with any of this
part of the stack
and
maintain availability
but also protect our customers is i
believe the greatest challenge that i'm
facing right now
and um
hopefully we're building the the best
solution out there
and um stopping
adversaries um as they switch their uh
their attention from windows to linux
and yeah
keeping them behind and not letting them
evolve into something worse than they
are already doing
maintainability is indeed a challenge
for a lot of companies i think
but um
yeah thank you uh for those insights um
andrada do you have something um you
want to share from your journalistic
experience yeah as a journalist my job
is to look at what
techies do and try to translate that for
the general audience and two of the
things i'm i'm always thinking about
when i'm writing stories are why is this
important
and why is this important now
and i feel that when we talk to
stakeholders or
or the general public or colleagues and
friends we um
we are better
as women
at explaining things and maybe we should
leverage that more um maybe we should
step up and not be afraid to speak our
mind
and um
because
one thing is to know something another
thing is to to know that but share it to
the audience and we also maybe have to
to make an effort to be better
communicators at what we are doing and
to maybe do a little bit of pr on on the
side
just to
encourage um other women to talk or to
um
basically
say that there are interesting things
that that are happening right now and we
are the um
advocates for for change
another thing i'm trying to do as a
journalist is to include diverse voices
in my stories
um
and whenever possible i'm trying to
interview women
and um
people that have different backgrounds
or come from various geographical
locations so that the picture i'm
painting is not that white uh
males are
the only people working in in cyber
security right now
so um yeah these were my two cents
yeah so i think we can see a
pattern of uh
that that it relates more to the human
actually those uh the cyber security
challenges we talked about are actually
all related to to the human and human
perception
um
i don't know if you lubica if you raised
your hand
intentionally okay yeah
yeah uh i wanted uh yes to share with
you that under uh also andrada had a
great uh
great concern in the issue which she
raised here and also i wanted to add it
here that what we need more and i find
it challenging uh
is that uh with uh actually the
organizers of the conferences and
different kind of events should have in
mind that it's always a good idea to to
organize a kind of a kind of special
session dedicated to women questions in
cyber security but i find it more
valuable if
uh the organizers put
more female speakers or more female
experts within uh specialized sessions
because that way first of all we'll have
the opportunity to present in practice
that we are not just women
with
our female
positive characteristics and threats but
we are also experts in the field and
at the same time we can always use it as
an opportunity
of coming from the back door to say
something more what will inspire more
women to join the to join the cyber
security community so i find it both
great ways to to involve more women in
the story
just to build on what lupita said
building on what i said before which was
built on what everything said earlier um
there are um also two things that i have
in mind one is that it's not enough to
have women in in technology if we don't
have women in leadership positions uh in
technology and i know that uh graziano
maybe um has something to say about this
so um
i think skills are are super valuable in
in this area but we also need to give
people the chance to be the best they
can be
um
so i should
be a journalist for the for the next 20
seconds and and ask graziella if she
feels that if there are enough women in
in leadership positions
sorry val
it is a fantastic topic i wanted to push
them that i can leave
the conversation thank you
uh this with a woman in leadership um it
is another longer conversation
um i'm always mixing up um the wording
is feeling glass or glass ceiling uh
umbrella canyon can you correct me
are you familiar with this is that
um
invisible plus
that you can't uh pass it or you can't
overcome it um while you are thinking on
on
going up in a hierarchy
and there are
many researches and many articles and
many books and a lot of uh resources
written
exactly for this uh ceiling glass or
glass ceiling
regarding women and um while i started a
conversation it was a small project like
um let's discuss about this topic
um when i started to read about this i
was
very
sad and amazing the same time because
somehow humanity started to um to
research about this uh somewhere in
1950s so we are 2021 right now and we
are still discussing about it and we do
not still have some um
real solutions okay
we all talk about this and in the visa
progress
reports and statistics show us that
there is a progress and there is another
level of inclusion and
women started to have the courage to
um
take the word and speak and uh and try
to be visible because all of you have
said
probably um it is true like we do have
um
values or valuable women in different
areas not only in technology but usually
we are going on to the psychological
understand also social part and also
cultural background which has an
entrance uh on on everything
but coming back and just to point out
some some some numbers it is true that
um from distance romania is saying very
well in numbers um it's on the second
one or the third um a few years ago um
place
on
women's
in technology
uh however
i would be maybe we will have andrada
sometimes uh later to discuss i would be
very curious to find
an explanation
of the following
numbers so we are on a very good
shape or a very good position comparing
all the other western countries
where we are looking with high
appreciation from many perspectives
uh one link and
i would be very curious for the
reasoning behind why this happens why
this happens to us and the only
information is like um
factual or um absolute information i got
is
the number of the females um
in the tertiary grade
is much more higher than males
so it's like we have a bigger pool of
professionals in tech education
which have
the opportunity to remain in the field
and to do something
but however um things are um
are not very freed until the very
highest levels of um of the therapy in
the organization but it will be very
interesting to make the link why why
this because i consider for example
speaking about romania because i know
the culture
i intended to say we are much more
traditionalist and not liberal in terms
of supporting women and inclusion and
all those things if you have a point on
this i would be
fantastically curious
yeah um i i wrote something about it i
could um share the link if you want um
one thing is that culturally
there's something there definitely
so the same thing is happening um in
bulgaria so they are number one right
now in europe and a little bit in russia
in i think across eastern europe and um
one explanation is that these were one
of the first countries that pushed for
uh equal rights for men and women within
their constitutions and romania had uh
one of the first engineers um in the
world so who were women so um it allowed
women to go to school exactly uh what
you said um and also uh during the
during communism women had to have a job
which was not true for certain um
western countries
so communists wanted women to go and and
work and be the um
superhero of the working class uh if you
want so that they had to have a job and
if you um
were to graduate with a degree in math
or computer science that would mean that
you're going to be
assigned a job in a city not in the
countryside because all the computing
centers were in in cities so that that
was a passport for having um a good life
for for women
so these are a couple of things that
influenced um
the bigger numbers that are in romania
that are maybe not enough i think we
should do more and uh we should try to
keep the momentum if possible
thank you i think
i have something to add providing this
yeah uh i wanted to share uh my
experience here in north macedonia which
is another part of the european union
but it's following
the latest the the legislation and all
good practices when it comes to
women in cyber security and girls and
the statistics are showing that uh
the percentage of girls
within the
faculty faculty education and car uh
higher education
of different range are even higher than
the male participation than the boys
participation but unfortunately uh the
trouble happened after they finish
although as you said
is the same here with higher grades and
more successful than uh male candidates
but uh the travel happened a bit later
when they come not only in a position to
to get active on the
labor market but uh later uh when when
they usually come in in that period of
their personal life when they want to
become mothers
and to be a professional at the same
time and to to get a higher uh
well-deserved position and having in
mind that the things in cyber security
are happening in information change are
happening very fast and unfortunately
all we as human beings can be in step
with uh with those uh challenges and uh
we are constantly in time race it's even
uh it's even harder for women
in that period of their life and having
in mind uh the changes in cyber security
environment it's even harder for for
women to to follow
that step and what we are right now
doing uh in my country as an
organization is women for cyber north
macedonia we are trying exactly to
figure it out what was the reason
the main reason there are always several
reasons but what is uh the the main
reason why women uh at some stage of
their career had stopped to to go to
want and to be motivated uh
or uh able to to go higher in their
positions so i'll be glad to share when
we get the results we are working it's a
kind of analysis server but
i will i will be happy and for sure we
are going to publish
those results
yes please please share the results
once it gets published um for the sake
of time i need to
get some speed on the questions um i
think we sort of answered the second one
already which was the a hot topic you
wish people talked more about in the
infosec community and we talked about
the human error we talked about more
diversity um does anyone want to add
something to this uh something you wish
that we tackled more
and why do you believe it's important
and do you think we're changing in the
right direction
if somebody wants to pitch in
i can have something to add on the list
for sure we will not reach a conclusion
but
it was something which captured my
attention the other days um
and uh this was related to a statement
like
um
cyber security and e for security is the
approach is a tech function and should
be approached as a business function
and this is somehow related to
the entire story with the shift in the
organizational culture
and
it is a much
linked as well to the education of
people that but not only the one for
performing the ones for performing some
operational
things then um the link to
raising awareness and educating uh the
top management that means
there is a there is a trend uh people in
um
or the specialists who are the
required
in right now for information security or
cyber security
um
they are required not to have
exclusively technical skills then they
need to have some soft skills they need
to have some social skill stations they
need to have
a wider range of skills not exclusively
technical and this is reflected as well
or shall be reflected in much more
visible and transparent way at the top
level of the organization and that means
function business functions or finance
or effective higher executive should
understand more about digital technology
transformation cyber and everything but
in the same time of course we we have
the expectation that everything which
they can take cyber interests in
emphasis and and
the other ones to
a better understanding the business in
order to
ensure that collaboration we were
discussing earlier
so that was my point for um
yeah that's true like we mentioned
before it takes everyone to do cyber
security right and you need to just work
together and
find a way to communicate without um
without miscommunication i think that's
indeed like a huge challenge
um
does anyone else have inputs on this
go ahead jubilee
ah thank you well definitely i agree
what we need to to see is uh we need to
see the the broader
picture
actually what we always uh
need to have in mind is first of all the
complexity of cyber security itself we
are all aware that if we compare what is
seen and uh as cyber security nowadays
is much different what was seen as cyber
security area a few years ago and not to
mention a decade ago
which means that we all
we always need to have in mind
complexity of cyber security itself but
also its multi dimensionality and it
gives an opportunity to uh to more women
to get on board to more women to get on
stage and cyber security
because
there is a plethora of different
characteristics different threads
different
various education
various expertise which is needed in
cyber security and once and for all what
we need is a real i call it a real
amagum of uh male and female
characteristics
as a precondition for complementarity in
practice which means we need complex
that amalgam to to get a complementarity
in practice
so in that case we all as humanity will
benefit
cyber security is actually uh is like a
putting a jigsaw puzzle together which
means if you miss one part
then that you you won't have the whole
picture and it won't be the picture that
you're
trying to to image in front of you
we all know how annoying it is to build
a jigsaw puzzle with more than three
people right
now but it's true and i think it's not
only about uh just men and women but
also just different cultures and teams
from different um count like
you you notice that a security team that
is built of people from different parts
of the world is just performs better
because
they have different experiences if you
put all the same people in the same
team they're only going to talk about
what they've experienced and if they've
all experienced the same things they
cannot build the proper threat model
that actually models the entire planet
earth so um
so i think we should indeed have diverse
teams not only men and women but also
just uh cultural culturally diverse as
well
um
uh let's see dimitra do you have
anything to uh to say about this
oh uh
i i tend to agree uh i'm part of a
multicultural cross-continent steam
and i just tend to gain a lot from it i
get different inputs so many people with
different backgrounds
from different organizations uh coming
with their own experience and with their
own input and that can only help an
organization grow
and
my experience before being here was
similar
i think we were
half of uh
half of the team was female so
uh it was an uh
a new interesting empowering uh way to
work
um so yeah i do agree uh having a
balance uh in both
i mean yeah having a balance of views
from different backgrounds different
cultures different experiences
do uh do help a lot
and i think it's evolving in the right
direction to be honest because there's
more companies that try to have these
diversity initiatives and
they're they're implementing it um in a
good way i think so i'm i'm positive
about what it's going to be in the next
10 years
um
and
be for the last 15 minutes or 10 minutes
even
um
what is something you would advise to a
young security specialist
regardless if it's a woman or a man or
um from a different background just uh
someone who's just starting in the field
and based on your experience what would
you advise them
and um i'll leave the floor to graziella
yes i know i'm the first one um
independently if we are talking about uh
technologies cybersecurity
men with women um actually i think the
same thing i would like to want to share
um if you want is a figure for anybody
and i would encourage them to
to try and to be curious
and this might potentially lead to
some passion
they might discover and
the energy and the enthusiasm and the
invitation you might have when you feel
you are passionate and being curious
about something
is um cannot be compared with anything
so um i believe in intuition and i
believe i don't believe in coincidence
so
um most of the things uh i've done it
was that they were some opportunities
i've taken at that moment
um i don't have any regrets and i am i'm
happy for the the journey i have
um but i
when i do not
feel i am curious and passionate it is
this a a bell somewhere in my head
which is ringing
um and i think it's important
i would say it's
as simple as possible
definitely thank you
um let me try you have a question in the
chat actually just relating to the
previous uh
statements
um
someone in the audience is asking if you
could tell us how diverse points of view
uh
influence threat research or help in
threat research
how you've noticed that it helped in
your team
and then you can answer the next
question
okay
so um
coming from different backgrounds uh we
uh i mean most of the team have had
really diverse experience uh from
military organizations from all over the
world from australia to us to europe
we
complement each other's knowledge
we each have a piece of the puzzle as
lubrica said
and
the
more backgrounds
uh that are working on a profile of an
adversary or analyzing their behaviors
um
the more complete image you get um
and also it's really important to work
with opinions that are
uh
sometimes in opposition to yours
um because yeah we we are
we are all weak to confirmation bias and
we might look at the things we already
know and
we might see things that we want to see
and then having someone with
a different point of view a different
background looking at the same data
might point out something that you might
miss or
make
may help you
complement and complete the image of uh
of the attack
yeah i think it's also
oh sorry did someone want to speak or
yeah i was about to answer the second
question i'm not sure yeah
go ahead go ahead
so yeah uh my advice would be to
uh trust your dream work hard
learn
i don't think i've ever encounter a
community encountered a community as
supportive as infosec community you can
literally reach out to anyone on
linkedin on twitter
ask for help ask for guidance
i've received books i've landed books
courses
gave out advice
if you want to do it you can do it and i
think i'm a proof of that
yeah definitely um educate yourself it's
not
uh to just go back to your point about
the culturally um diverse teams when i
was doing threat research and just
looking at ransomware messages from
threat actors the way they write a mess
when somewhere message you can sort of
know where they're from because if they
forget the articles they're probably
eastern european or these kind of things
so uh yeah that's why it's also in the
language um phases
but um
nubika what do you what do you would you
tell someone who's a complete newbie in
cyber security
uh well uh
after uh during one interview i was
asked how do i feel as a woman in an
environment which is predominantly male
i
uh answered the question with the smile
on my face on my face and i still feel
it that way i answer
i reply i am i feel as a strong
strawberry on the top of the cream
which means and i always use it as a
kind of inspiration to all other young
girls and young women who want to join
uh just to be themselves uh i i always
try to explain that what we need
actually is different approach the
different characteristics the different
uh way how
women in cyber security react and
get decisions
get decisions when it comes to some
problems or when they need to
to offer to recommend something we don't
need to imitate in a way
the way how men approach uh how many uh
men decide when it comes to uh different
kind of cyber security risks threats or
situations actually as i said i will
come back to what i said previously and
we i i'm sure and i think that we all
during our discussion we all confirmed
that that what we need is the
complementarity to see the
multi-dimensionality to see the
complementarity to try to get on the
stage what we as women have
and uh and uh
to try first of all uh uh
on on one side to
to
provoke changes in the mentality in the
country to prove changes in the culture
how the society is
seeing the things when it comes to cyber
security and especially to work with
companies because
having in mind that companies are profit
oriented and they are uh
the entities they are the link
which is making the most money and we we
all know uh although we don't want to
admit uh publicly that the money is is
driving the uh is driving the world so
uh that's why what we need is also to
work on several levels
first of all to work with societies uh
to to change the perception of cyber
security to educate to give the
opportunities for each girl and women to
see what it really means to offer them a
real chance what it means
to be involved in cyber security so as
all previous speakers already said what
we need is a motivation it's a kind of
um
honest approach to ourselves and of
course we need an inspiration and help
coming from others so we are all here
actually discussing about that how to to
be an inspiration
uh because i always when i try to
inspire some girl uh during a mentorship
program i'm also
i think i'm even more inspired than the
girl of the girl because it's a way how
you get the energy and how you give the
positive energy back
actually on um on what she said uh
there's a question in the audience about
um and that's for everybody in this
panel and then i'll get to you andretta
um what will be concrete steps you have
taken in order to ensure the fair
participation of women in the workforce
for example maternity leave or the bias
in hiring and promoting have you taken
these steps in your jobs to ensure that
it gets better and what were those
concrete steps
i think you can start lubricant
well we as an organization women for
cyber we are working on different levels
and activities concretely right now in
north macedonia here we are working uh
and uh
we already succeeded actually to uh to
to get women on board when it comes to
building cybersecurity strategy in the
country to make them very active very
active
in that spirit and also we work on not
only
on legislation measures and legislation
texts and laws in the country
to get to promote women uh possibilities
to get in cyber security but actually uh
when it uh
uh i will mention just one of the
measures uh which is uh which was uh
which find it out it was very important
during the pandemic time
because we all know that the pandemic
had a lot of negative consequences
but
also for men and women but for women
they were even higher the negative
consequences of the pandemic were even
higher for women
so uh we
we get
our success was that
working with our government we get a
position when one of the measures uh
helping women to overcome uh
to overcome the situation with uh with
the pandemics uh when it comes to cyber
security area uh to get uh
more funds and to get together a special
fund which is dedicated to women in
cyber security and actually how to
support them as freelancers and as
someone which is a kind of exporter of
services from home but outside the
country
thank you um
anyone else wants to answer the audience
question
have one question um
are we running out of time or should we
give andrada on the word for asking for
responding to your last question and if
you still some sometimes i don't have
two words about about this as well yeah
go go ahead and answer i'm controlling
time on on this side so
everyone gets five more minutes
um
i wanted to
respond as well to this question because
somehow i feel responsible from um from
from my position of being president of
um isaka and romania chapter uh at the
global level there are a lot of
initiatives and programs for this
i'm not very proud we haven't progressed
too much in implementing them in romania
i would say
we need more energy in the collaborative
part or in the collaboration part we
have discussed about this um today
um
but
in the same time i wanted to to share
with you some
practical actions which have been taken
um part of
an initiative in uh in the corporation
i'm working for and it was um
this is my interphone um i will leave it
um sorry for this
we love beethoven
yes uh which would uh would have been uh
the the coincidence to doing right now
um and um i just wanted to mention that
there are corporations where um some
initiatives has been started uh because
this is the trend in the same same time
in in the society um and uh um we've run
some workshops uh trying to better
understand the
challenges and the needs of
everybody but especially of of the women
and uh from different perspectives from
the founders on the issues of being
professional from the sense of being
a mother for the truth of being planning
to be a mother and
did the scope of the entire workshop for
voice to put together some
um ideas and try to implement them
through um hr function of course without
it we can't do anything in our
preparations
but it was a nice start for uh for this
inclusion
initiative at the corporate level
yeah um
just to to continue that idea i work for
a radio station in in bucharest which is
a like general audience radio station
it's called pro fm and one of the things
that i'm doing is to try to
involve my male colleagues into talking
about issues that are normally applied
to women so i do have one colleague in
the newsroom and every piece of news
that is connected with uh
women's rights is assigned to him
and i told him george it's one thing if
i
go live and talk about breastfeeding in
public places and another thing if you
go there and you do that
because um we need to partner with men
and we need to have a few of them to
advocate for for our rights um and just
by watching this computer screen right
now and and looking at our faces i i
realized that we are five successful
women and maybe a lot more in the
audience were quite accomplished
um we've done great things um
independently or or together but i'm
thinking that for for every person here
in this panel there are thousands
of women who have never had the chance
to to be here or or to have an education
in in stem
maybe many of them have been discouraged
throughout this life their lives maybe
they were told that you're not smart
enough to learn math or or computer
science and this is also a thing we
should tackle and and be
um supportive
and donate our time and resources to to
help the new generation um and perhaps
this is a way of of tackling this
um and another point and i promise this
is the last one i think we should um
involve women in in every possible way
um and men and make women part of of
designing security products of um
helping supporting each other um get a
management position that would impact um
all of us and and everyone who's doing a
good work within the the community and
hopefully um during the following um
editions of deaf camp we'll have more
fantastic women in in the audience and
um
it is super important to grow together
and have like a great vibe throughout
the the community
definitely i think you raise a really
good point here that this we shouldn't
eliminate women from men it's it's we're
all in this together right we're all in
this world together we should work
together and
and um make this a good place for
everyone uh regardless of gender or
culture or anything
um and i'm gonna give the final word to
dimitra
um
and then we'll wrap up this panel i
think if you have anything else to add
about the last question uh yeah my role
doesn't have too much input in uh
in decision making but what i can say
from my experience is that
i was fortunate enough uh to not
experience any gatekeeping
or any disadvantage for being a woman in
cyber security
and
what i would
like to see more is
women to just have
more trust in themselves and in their
technical capabilities and apply for
that job it is for you as well
so we currently have an opening in the
team
uh and i'm pretty sure no women applied
so far so please do so
if if you like threat hunting and cyber
security
um and you'd like to do this job please
apply
yeah and hunting is great
um
yeah so i think this brings us to the
end of our panel there is one more
question in the audience
i don't know andre andrada if we have
time for this last question if we keep
it short you can do sure go ahead
um
how do you think women can receive more
respect when they are in a management
position in the cybersecurity field
um it's a tough question so if you can
answer this if any anyone can answer
this in one sentence i will
worship you
i can say
i don't
i haven't
experienced
situations where uh lack of respect um
was on the table
so
maybe we have had uh
let's see challenges in in discussions
different point of view conflicts but i
would take them as a professional
conflicts not personal one but maybe i'm
fortunate and
i haven't experienced such and hopefully
you i i wish you
cannot experience such situations
one thing if i could add would be to
build alliances because there are um
many people that would support you if
you're good at what you do and they
already
respect you and you can also help create
a culture that respects everyone if
you're on a management position and also
approach journalists
and
talk to them about your work
and raise your profile
i think also the at least from the
accounts that i have heard it was not
uh disrespect from manager to her um
employees but more with other managers
uh that are let's say mostly men and
then she's a manager and they don't take
her seriously
and i think this is this is indeed
linked to company culture this is just a
a culture problem and not a
problem at this small island let's say
um
so you really need to to
i mean try to figure out if your
employees are uh respectful because oh
they all look like this person or they
are respectful in general of everybody
but this is this is a very difficult uh
screening you have to psychologically
profile everyone and see if they could
fit in your culture but like yeah
i do think that if you notice that
there's a culture misfit like another
fit for the culture that you need to
take action at least um instead of
letting it slide if you have such
incidents of disrespect towards anyone
you you need to tackle it you don't let
it slide because otherwise it's going to
stay and it might inspire others to um
to also be distributed disrespectful
that's it's hard to
uh
it's hard to prevent but easy to detect
i think that's uh that's something
um
if anyone has anything else to add then
i guess we can wrap up
um
[Music]
then thank you everyone we were i think
we were a bit late 10 minutes later but
uh that happens all the time in
conferences so
i guess we're fine thank you so much uh
for the panelists to give their valuable
insights and i hope uh we could
um
inspire some people
or just
help them
in their daily jobs
do better security
and better
human error fixing let's say because i
think that's the conclusion of this
panel it's not about the technical
challenges it's more a social challenge
i guess but um yeah thank you so much
for for being there and uh and andrea
for feeling the the empty spots
um
i guess we'll see you around and uh
hopefully at the
death camp physical right next year
yeah yeah thank you
thank you very much ladies it was a
pleasure thank you